<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003740" url="http://pages.stern.nyu.edu/~igiddy/valuationmethods.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:54" support="1" score="0.001271162887665397" bingtitle="Giddy: Methods of Corporate Valuation - New York University" webtitle="Giddy: Methods of Corporate Valuation">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>... companies like banks, consumer loan concerns, brokerages and credit card ... minds -- the fact that nine out of ten people forced to name a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Briefing
 Methods of Corporate Valuation 
Prof. Ian H. Giddy, New York University
 
What is my company worth? What are the ratios used by analysts to determine
 whether a stock is undervalued or overvalued? How valid is the discounted
 present value approach? How can one value a company as a
going concern, and how does this change in the context of a potential acquisition,
 or when the company faces financial stress? 

 
Finding a value for a company is no easy task -- but doing so is an essential 
 component of effective management. The reason: it&apos;s easy to destroy value 
 with ill-judged acquisitions, investments or financing methods. This article 
 will take readers through the process of valuing a company, starting with
 simple financial statements and the use of ratios, and going on to discounted 
 free cash flow and option-based methods.

How a business is valued depends on the purpose, so the most interesting
 part of implementing these methods will be to see how they work in different
 contexts -- such as valuing a private company, valuing an acquisition target,
 and valuing a company in distress. We&apos;ll learn how using the tools of valuation 
 analysis can inform management choices. 
 Outline 
 
 Asset-Based Methods Using Comparables Free Cash Flow Methods Option-Based Valuation Special Applications 
 
 Asset-Based Methods 
Asset-based methods start with the &quot;book value&quot; of a company&apos;s
equity. This is simply the value of all the company&apos;s assets, less its debt.
Whether it&apos;s tangible things like cash, current assets, working capital and
shareholder&apos;s equity, or intangible qualities like management or brand name,
equity is everything that a company has if it were to suddenly stop selling
products and stop making money tomorrow, and pay off all its creditors.


 The Balance Sheet: Cash&amp;Working Capital 
Like to buy a dollar of assets for a dollar in market value? Ben Graham
 did. He developed one of the premier screens for ferreting out companies
with more cash on hand than their current market value. First, Graham would
look at a company&apos;s cash and equivalents and short-term investments. Dividing 
 this number by the number of shares outstanding gives a quick measure that 
 tells you how much of the current share price consists of just the cash that
 the company has on hand. Buying a company with a lot of cash can yield a
lot of benefits -- cash can fund product development and strategic acquisitions 
 and can pay high-caliber executives. Even a company that might seem to have 
 limited future prospects can offer tremendous promise if it has enough cash 
 on hand.

Another measure of value is a company&apos;s current working capital relative to its market capitalization. Working capital is what is left
after you subtract a company&apos;s current liabilities from its current assets
. Working capital represents the funds that a company has ready access to
for use in conducting its everyday business. If you buy a company for close
to its working capital, you have essentially bought a dollar of assets for
a dollar of stock price -- not a bad deal, either. Just as cash funds all
sorts of good things, so does working capital.

 Shareholder&apos;s Equity&amp;Book Value 
 Shareholder&apos;s equity is an accounting convention that includes
 a company&apos;s liquid assets like cash, hard assets like real estate, as well
 as retained earnings. This is an overall measure of how much liquidation
value a company has if all of its assets were sold off -- whether those assets
are office buildings, desks, old T-shirts in inventory or replacement vacuum
tubes for ENIAC systems.

Shareholder equity helps you value a company when you use it to figure 
out book value . Book value is literally the value of a company
 that can be found on the accounting ledger. To calculate book value per
share, take a company&apos;s shareholder&apos;s equity and divide it by the current
number of shares outstanding. If you then take the stock&apos;s current price
and divide by the current book value, you have the price-to-book ratio .

Book value is a relatively straightforward concept. The closer to book 
value you can buy something at, the better it is. Book value is actually 
somewhat skeptically viewed in this day and age, since most companies have 
latitude in valuing their inventory, as well as inflation or deflation of 
real estate depending on what tax consequences the company is trying to avoid.
However, with financial companies like banks, consumer loan concerns, brokerages
and credit card companies, the book value is extremely relevant. For instance,
 in the banking industry, takeovers are often priced based on book value,
with banks or savings&amp;loans being taken over at multiples of between
1.7 to 2.0 times book value.

Another use of shareholder&apos;s equity is to determine return on equity , or ROE. Return on equity is a measure of how much in earnings a company
 generates in four quarters compared to its shareholder&apos;s equity. It is measured
 as a percentage. For instance, if XYZ Corp. made a million dollars in the
 past year and has a shareholder&apos;s equity of ten million, then the ROE is
10%. Some use ROE as a screen to find companies that can generate large profits 
 with little in the way of capital investment. Coca Cola, for instance, does 
not require constant spending to upgrade equipment -- the syrup-making process 
does not regularly move ahead by technological leaps and bounds. In fact, 
high ROE companies are so attractive to some investors that they will take 
the ROE and average it with the expected earnings growth in order to figure 
out a fair multiple. This is why a pharmaceutical company like Merck can 
grow at 10% or so every year but consistently trade at 20 times earnings
or more.

 Intangibles 
Brand is the most intangible element to a company, but quite possibly
the one most important to a company&apos;s ability as an ongoing concern. If
every single McDonald&apos;s restaurant were to suddenly disappear tomorrow,
the company could simply go out and get a few loans and be built back up
into a world power within a few months. What is it about McDonald&apos;s that
would allow it to do this? It is McDonald&apos;s presence in our collective minds
-- the fact that nine out of ten people forced to name a fast food restaurant
would name McDonald&apos;s without hesitating. The company has a well-known brand
and this adds tremendous economic value despite the fact that it cannot
be quantified.

Some investors are preoccupied by brands, particularly brands emerging 
in industries that have traditionally been without them. The genius of Ebay
 and Intel is that they have built their company names into brands that 
give them an incredible edge over their competition. A brand is also transferable 
to other products -- the reason Microsoft can contemplate becoming a power 
in online banking, for instance, is because it already has incredible brand 
equity in applications and operating systems. It is as simple as Reese&apos;s Peanut
Butter cups transferring their brand onto Reese&apos;s Pieces, creating a new
product that requires minimum advertising to build up.

The real trick with brands, though, is that it takes at least competent 
management to unlock the value. If a brand is forced to suffer through incompetence,
 such as American Express in the early 1990s or Coca-Cola in the early 1980s, 
then many can become skeptical about the value of the brand, leading them 
to doubt whether or not the brand value remains intact. The major buying opportunities
for brands ironically comes when people stop believing in them for a few
moments, forgetting that brands normally survive even the most difficult
of short-term traumas.

Intangibles can also sometimes mean that a company&apos;s shares can trade
at a premium to its growth rate. Thus a company with fat profit margins,
a dominant market share, consistent estimate-beating performance or a debt-free 
balance sheet can trade at a slightly higher multiple than its growth rate 
would otherwise suggest. Although intangibles are difficult to quantify, it
does not mean that they do not have a tremendous power over a company&apos;s share
price. The only problem with a company that has a lot of intangible assets
is that one danger sign can make the premium completely disappear
 
 IBM Balance Sheet
	</body>
</document>
