<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003719" url="http://www.forbes.com/sites/melaniehaiken/2011/09/21/5-foods-that-weaken-bones/" time="2012-07-12-19:52" support="3" score="0.004998536052188808" bingtitle="5 Foods That Weaken Bones - Forbes" webtitle="5 Foods That Weaken Bones - Forbes">
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>Simple Table Salt Can Sap Bone Strength ... Is there such a thing as a heathy fast food restaurant? ... The Credit Card Is The New App Platform; Home; Business</description>
	<body>
		FREE TRIAL ISSUE Help | Connect | Sign up | Log in 
Log in with your social account:
 
Or, you can log in or sign up using Forbes.
 
 Real Time +28 posts this hour Most Popular 5 Types Of Innovators Lists Best Places For Business Video Highest-Paid Actors 
 
 Melanie Haiken , Contributor 

I&apos;m insatiably curious about how to stay healthy&amp;where to go next.
 Follow Following Unfollow 
 Lifestyle 

 | 

9/21/2011 @ 3:42AM | 3,919 views

5 Foods That Weaken Bones
 3 comments, 1 called-out + Comment now + Comment now 
Simple Table Salt Can Sap Bone Strength
 
We’ve been told all our lives how important it is to eat right to build strong bones. But most people would be surprised to know that eating the wrong foods can leach nutrients from bones, sapping their strength and blocking the bones’ ability to regrow. Here are the top five foods (and drinks) that weaken bones (and beware: Some of these bone-zappers are foods we eat lots of every day):

 1. Alcohol 

When you drink, alcohol acts like a calcium-blocker, preventing the bone-building minerals you eat from being absorbed. And heavy drinking disrupts the bone remodeling process by preventing osteoblasts, the bone-building cells, from doing their job. So not only do bones become weaker, but when you break a bone, alcohol can interfere with healing.

 What to drink instead: Choose wines and beers that are lower in alcohol; they can taste just as good and aren’t as hard on bones. Limit yourself to one alcoholic drink a day, then switch to water, tea, or juice.

 2. Soft Drinks 

The fizziness in carbonated drinks often comes from phosphoric acid, which ups the rate at which calcium is excreted in the urine. At the same time, soft drinks fill you up and satisfy your thirst without providing any of the nutrients you might get from milk or juice.

 What to drink instead: Milk or calcium- and vitamin D-fortified soy milk or orange juice. Fruit smoothies made with yogurt also contain some calcium and vitamin D. Or plain old water, as long as you’re getting enough calcium and vitamin D from your diet.

 3. Salt 

Over time, salt wakens bones by sapping calcium from the bone matrix. For every 2,300 milligrams of sodium you take in, you lose about 40 milligrams of calcium, dietitians say. Our American diet is unusually salt-heavy; many of us ingest 5,000 milligrams of salt a day, more than double the amount recommended. Where salt hides: In canned soup, canned and bottled sauces, deli meats, frozen meals, canned vegetables, store-bought baked goods, pizza, and fast food such as burgers and fries.

 What to eat instead: Freshly prepared home-cooked food, so you can control the saltiness. Most of us get just 25 percent of our daily salt from table salt — all the rest comes from processed and prepackaged foods.
 Page 1 2 « Previous Page Next Page » 3 comments, 1 called-out + Comment now + Comment now Print Report Corrections Reprints&amp;Permissions 
More on Forbes Right Now
 
Features

 It Takes Google &apos;Now&apos; Three Days To Figure Out Where You Live Five Reasons Britain May Be The Best Place To Start A Company In 2012 7 Tips On Building Your Business With Better Metrics 
 
Post Your Comment
 Cancel reply 
Post Your Reply
 Please log in or sign up to comment. Enter Your Comment Submit Comment 
Forbes writers have the ability to call out member comments they find particularly interesting. Called-out comments are highlighted across the Forbes network. You&apos;ll be notified if your comment is called out.
 
Comments

 Called-Out Expand All Comments 
 
 quantumsignature 9 months ago 
I think you broke the hearts of alot of people, but thank you for the good info!
Is there such a thing as a heathy fast food restaurant?
 Permalink Flag Reply Melanie Haiken , Contributor 9 months ago 
Hmmm… it depends if you’re defining fast food as food you can grab fast, or as the standard popular chains that primarily serve hamburgers, fries and the like. Subway offers some healthy offerings, and even Jack in the Box and MacDonalds now have salads, grilled chicken dishes, and others that are bone-healthy. Also, they now publish the calorie counts and other nutritional information for their dishes. But if you have your heart set on deep-fried items like onion rings and French Fries and burgers doused with sauces rich in saturated and trans fats, it’s pretty hard to find something. If I’m really craving a burger and fries, I make them myself; lean beef for the burger and sweet potato fries baked on a cookie sheet with a little olive oil. Hope that helps!
 
 Called-out comment 
 Permalink Flag Reply sarahhenry 9 months ago 
I did not know that too much Vitamin A could be bad for bones. Thanks for the heads up.
 Permalink Flag Reply 
 
Most Read on Forbes
 
 News People Places Companies 
 + show more Melanie Haiken Contributor Follow Following Unfollow + show more 
As a freelance contributor to a raft of national lifestyle, business and travel magazines, I&apos;ve reported on scientific breakthroughs with potential to cure cancer or stop global warming -- and I&apos;ve told readers where to find the best reefs to snorkel and the best eye creams for puffy eyes. Here at Adventures in Health, I&apos;ll focus on the two things I care most about: healthy living and traveling adventurously. Where have you seen my byline before? Fitness, Health, Business 2.0, Delta Sky, Spa, Yoga Journal, Real Simple, Via, Ladies Home Journal, and many others. At my blog, Health-Conscious-Travel.com, I share my travel and food adventures as they happen; as a Senior Editor at Caring.com I write about all things related to aging. When not glued to the computer, I can be found hiking the mountains and combing the beaches of Marin County, California where I live.
 
The author is a Forbes contributor. The opinions expressed are those of the writer.
 
Melanie Haiken’s Popular Posts

 &apos;Bath Salts&apos; A Deadly New Drug With A Deceptively Innocent Name 260,621 views How Stress And Sleep Loss Are Shortening Your Life 66,546 views New Diet Drug Qnexa Promises 10% Weight Loss-At What Price? 62,441 views 5 Foods that Burn Away Fat 56,637 views Dangerous Beauty: 5 Scariest Beauty Products 38,197 views 
 
More from Melanie Haiken
 
 Follow Melanie on Twitter Follow Melanie on Facebook Melanie’s RSS Feed Melanie’s Profile Melanie’s Recommended Reading Melanie’s Website 
 
Who Just Made a Billion Dollars?
 Our Real-Time Billionaires scoreboard tracks the biggest holdings for 50 of the world’s wealthiest people. See who&apos;s up&amp;who&apos;s down right now» 
Inside Forbes
 
 The World&apos;s Most Powerful Celebrities - Forbes 
 Justin Bieber, Jennifer Lopez and The Rock star in our latest Celebrity 100. 
 
 Justin Bieber, Venture Capitalist: The Forbes Cover Story 
 
 Homes Of The World&apos;s Most Powerful Celebrities 
 

 
 The Rock is Kicking Ass and Saving Franchises 
 
 Forbes Real-Time Billionaires 
 
 
Channels

 Business Investing Tech Entrepreneurs Op/Ed Leadership Lifestyle Lists 
 
Company Info

 About Forbes Advertising Information Self-Serve Advertising Reprints&amp;Permissions Terms and Conditions Privacy Statement Contact Us Sitemap Help 
 
Affiliate Sites

 Forbes Russia Forbes Poland Forbes Romania Forbes Middle East Forbes China Forbes India RealClear Politics RealClear Markets RealClear World RealClear Sports 
 
Data Partners

 Distributed by AT&amp;T; Tested by Spirent Market Data by Morningstar Xignite Thomson Reuters AdChoices 
 
Publications
 
 Free Trial Issue Subscriber Services Buy Back Issues 
 2012 Forbes.com LLC All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
