<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003287" url="http://www.nj.com/hunterdon-county-democrat/index.ssf/2009/04/police_roundup_for_hunterdon_c_1.html" time="2012-07-12-19:25" support="2" score="0.0018446931019836833" bingtitle="Police Round-Up for Hunterdon County - April 2, 2009 | NJ.com" webtitle="Police Round-Up for Hunterdon County - April 2, 2009 | 						NJ.com">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>... several warrants for his arrest from Somerset County ... admitted he bought the phone for $10 in a fast-food restaurant in ... employee said someone had been urinating in a trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign in | Register for free Sign in to NJ.com Username   Password Remember me I forgot my username or password» Don&apos;t have an account?
 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:

 

 AIM    Google    OpenID 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 
 Home News Weather Sports Entertainment Living Interact Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Find n Save 
 Home &gt; Hunterdon County Democrat &gt; Police blotter 
Police Round-Up for Hunterdon County - April 2, 2009

Published: Thursday, April 02, 2009, 10:17 AM   Updated: Friday, April 03, 2009, 8:19 PM 
 By Hunterdon County Democrat Hunterdon County Democrat 
 Follow 0 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print 
 CLINTON 
Credentials Didn&apos;t Check
Police said they arrested three Easton residents after stopping a car on West Main Street around 11:36 p.m. March 25 for tailgating.

Earl Robinson, 25, couldn&apos;t provide a valid driver&apos;s license or identification, police said. They found several warrants for his arrest from Somerset County on charges of forgery and resisting arrest. He was turned over to the Somerset County Prosecutor&apos;s office.

Passenger Joanna Rosado, 23, produced registration information for the car, but police said she had a forged stolen check for $2,000. She was charged with theft, receiving stolen property and forgery. She was released.

Rear-seat passenger Anthony Nixon, 19, was found to be wanted for arrest in Warren County and picked up by the Hunterdon County Sheriff&apos;s Department.
DWI Charge
Kenneth Swanson, 74, of Annandale was charged with drunken driving and failure to signal a turn after he was stopped while driving on Leigh Street by Patrolman Pete Tilstra around 9:55 p.m. Saturday. Police said he failed roadside sobriety tests and tests at headquarters.

 CLINTON TWP. 
Rare Guitar Stolen
A rare acoustic guitar was reported stolen March 26 in a burglary of a house on Hamden Road.
Police said the guitar, a Taylor 810E, is tobacco sunburst in color and valued at nearly $2,700. A number of drawers and cabinets in the house were disturbed but nothing else appeared to have been taken, police said.
Detective Paul Bate is investigating possible suspects in the burglary, which occurred between 8:30 a.m. March 25 and 7:15 p.m. the following day, police said.
Boy Breaks Arm
An 11-year-old boy suffered a broken arm at Round Valley School March 26. According to police, he was standing in the playground around 12:45 p.m. when he was pushed to the ground by a student in a group of boys that rushed him. The victim was treated at Hunterdon Medical Center in Raritan Township.
At the request of the victim&apos;s father, the incident is being investigated by school resource Officer Tom Hash, who police said will file a juvenile complaint.
Rear-End Collision
Two people were injured in a rear-end collision March 26 on Route 31 near Echo Lane.
Police said a 2008 Jeep Grand Cherokee driven by Salvatore Caso Jr., 47, of Washington Township hit the rear of a 2005 Chevrolet Silverado driven by Michael Citarelli, 51, of Glen Gardner around 8 a.m. The airbags in the Jeep went off on impact, police said.
Mr. Caso was taken to Hunterdon Medical Center in Raritan Township with minor injuries as was Julie Hajdusek, 34, of Glen Gardner, a passenger in the Chevy. Patrolman John Tiger charged Mr. Caso with careless driving.
Drug-Related Charges
l Three people from Yardley, Pa., were arrested March 27.
Police said Patrolman Joseph SanGiovanni stopped a car driven by Jason Gaber, 21, on Route 31 near Payne Road for speeding around 2 a.m. During the stop, the officer smelled burnt marijuana and a search produced a small amount of the drug and a pipe with residue, police said. Mr. Gaber was charged with possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, possession of drug paraphernalia, operating a motor vehicle while in possession of a controlled dangerous substance, speeding and failure to signal a lane change.
Passengers Scott White, 21, and Chelsea Kalman, 18, were charged with possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana and possession of drug paraphernalia. All were released.
l Kevin Carrol, 19, of Hopewell was arrested Sunday after his car was pulled over by Patrolman Joseph San Giovanni on Route 31 near Regional Road around 1:35 a.m. The arresting officer was able to smell marijuana and found a bag of pot during a search, police said.
Mr. Carrol was charged with speeding, failure to maintain his lane, and possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, drug paraphernalia and narcotics in a motor vehicle. He was released.
Car Hits Utility Pole
Maria Aurora Barreira-Lopez, 33, of Riverdale, Md., was charged Monday with failure to report an accident on High Bridge-Cokesbury Road.
According to police, a 1992 Toyota sedan driven by Ms. Barreira-Lopez went off the road near Mine Street and hit a utility pole around 4:05 a.m. Jersey Central Power&amp;Light was called to replace the pole.
Patrolman Michael Akers also charged Ms. Barreira-Lopez with careless driving.
Phone Fenced
Nicholas Zamloot, 18, and Zachary Zamloot, 20, both of Clinton Township, were arrested March 20 on charges of receiving stolen property and fencing stolen property.
According to police, Nicholas Zamloot asked a North Hunterdon High School student on March 19 if he wanted to buy a phone. Police said the seller bragged the phone was given to his brother by a friend who no longer wanted it.
After buying the phone for $55, the North student gave it to his girlfriend, who went with her mother to Verizon Wireless in Franklin Township to activate the phone. They found out it was stolen.
Clinton Township police were notified. Police said the phone had been stolen Dec. 1 from a pair of jeans in a locker room at Parsippany High School.
The Zamloot brothers were questioned by Sgt. Mathew Wilson. Police said Zachary Zamloot admitted he bought the phone for $10 in a fast-food restaurant in Paterson two or three weeks earlier.
Both brothers were released on their own recognizance pending a court hearing.

 EAST AMWELL TWP. 
Car, Deer Accident
A 2000 Mercury Cougar driven by Michael Hicks, 18, of East Amwell hit a deer on Wertsville Road east of Dutch Lane on March 24 about 8:15 p.m. Mr. Hicks was uninjured. The Mercury sustained front-end damage.
Chain-Collision Accident
Police say Andrew Garrett, 43, of East Amwell, driving a 1995 Toyota Camry, ignited a three-car chain collision March 26 about 8 a.m. at the intersection of routes 579 and 179.
Mr. Garrett ran into the back of a 2004 Honda Civic driven by Joseph Ninaltowski, 53, of Delaware Township, and pushed it into the back of a 2006 Honda CRV driven by James Stanton, 39, of Holland Township. Both had been yielding to traffic on Route 179. No injuries were reported.

 FLEMINGTON 
Crash On Allen Street
A &apos;97 GMC van crashed into a car at least twice on Allen Street and the driver fled on Saturday just after 9 p.m.
Borough police said Lidier Garro, 32, crashed his van into a car driven by Pratiksha Patel, 30 of Flemington and then rammed it again, pushing it 100 feet into a utility pole in a successful effort to get away. The van was found abandoned on Dvoor Circle by Raritan Township police, and township Sgt. Al Payne found Mr. Garro walking along Park Avenue. His ID says he lives in Phillipsburg, but police think he lives in Flemington.
Mr. Garro failed field sobriety tests and refused to give a breath sample for alcohol testing at police headquarters, police said.
Ms. Patel complained of injuries and was taken to Hunterdon Medical Center by the Flemington-Raritan rescue squad. Her car sustained severe front-end damage.
Mr. Garro has been charged with DWI, two counts of vehicular assault, obstruction of administration of law, criminal mischief and refusing to submit to a breath test.
Theft Charged
A woman was charged with stealing a shopper&apos;s bags of merchandise at Liberty Village Premium Outlets on Saturday at about 11 a.m. Ling Sing Chen of Whitehouse Station accidentally left her bags in the Jones New York store, where they were taken by Frances Miller, 63, of Flemington, according to police. Ms. Miller was arrested by Patrolman Dustin Kydd at the Ann Klein store, where she works. He also recovered the stolen items, police said.
Urination In Trash Can
A Ringoes teenager was charged with disorderly conduct for allegedly urinating in a trash can in the bathroom of Ultimate Tans at 67 Church St.
At 4:30 p.m. Saturday, Patrolman Robert Godown was dispatched to the salon where an employee said someone had been urinating in a trash can in the lavatory and that afternoon&apos;s activity indicated it was Ashley Lynn E. Floyd, 18, police said. Upon questioning, she admitted her misdeed and was issued a summons, police said.
Scuffle Along Highway
A patrolman noticed that a Flemington driver didn&apos;t seem to know his way around his own town and eventually charged him with possession of drug paraphernalia, disorderly conduct and resisting arrest.
Patrolman William Soriano said he was driving behind a Subaru that signaled to turn from Main Street onto Maple Street, then thought better of it because it&apos;s a one-way street. A computer check indicated the car is registered to a Flemington man. The patrolman followed the driver along an inefficient route to reach East Main Street, noticing some drifting within the lane, and pulled the driver over at the Route 31 intersection.
The patrolman approached driver James R. Quinn, 19, of Flemington, smelled raw marijuana and saw an empty plastic &quot;dime bag&quot; behind the driver&apos;s seat, police said. Mr. Quinn failed to comply with the patrolman&apos;s instructions and a scuffle broke out when it seemed Mr. Quinn might flee or run into the highway, according to police. Patrolwoman Mary Mariaschin used pepper spray to subdue Mr. Quinn.

 FRENCHTOWN 
Deer, Car Collide
Louis Farrell, 23, of Frenchtown hit a deer while driving a 2000 Audi on Route 12 on March 20 about 6:45 a.m. Mr. Farrell was uninjured. The vehicle sustained front-end damage.

 HOLLAND TWP. 
Early-Morning Raid
An investigation conducted by the township police and the Hunterdon County Prosecutor&apos;s Office Narcotics Task Force resulted in an early-morning raid on a house on Crab Apple Hill Road on Monday.
Four residents of the house were charged. Arrested in the 6 a.m. raid for possession of under 50 grams of marijuana and drug paraphernalia were Shannon Fusciardi, 21; Lauren Nemeth, 22; and Jeanette Blew, 25, said township police. John Stout Jr., 51, was arrested for intent to distribute marijuana and for possession of drug paraphernalia, said police.
They were released pending a court appearance. John Stout III, age and residence unavailable at publication, was sought in connection with the investigation, and turned himself in to the Prosecutor&apos;s Office, said police. The investigation is ongoing.

 LAMBERTVILLE 
Three Cars In Collision
Bo Fan, 43, of West Amwell was taken to Hunterdon Medical Center by the Lambertville first aid squad after complaining of neck pain following an accident on Bridge Street east of Lambert Lane on March 23, about 6:15 p.m.
Cindy Niederer, 62, of Titusville, at the wheel of a 2003 Chevrolet Tahoe heading east, slowed down for a vehicle making a left turn onto Lambert Lane. Mr. Fan, driving a 2001 Nissan Altima, also slowed and was hit from behind by a 2000 Ford Focus driven by Shannon Renoek, 18, also of Titusville, police said.

 LEBANON TWP. 
Donation Up In Smoke
Califon firefighters were planning to use a donated 1995 Saturn to practice extrication skills. Instead, they drilled on putting out a live fire in the car while it was being towed to Califon.
According to police, the fire broke out around 9:45 p.m. March 26 Tow truck driver Chris Berardo turned onto Route 513 from Sliker Road when he saw smoke coming from the Saturn. He pulled into the A&amp;P;parking lot and used handheld fire extinguishers, but could not quell the fire. Califon firemen arrived to put out the fire. The car was destroyed.
Lebanon Township firemen responded, too, along with township and Califon rescue units. Patrolman Alan Goracy investigated.
Rental Car Stripped
A sedan and a van were found stripped of parts March 16 at Enterprise Rent-a-Car on Route 31.
Lug nuts, wheel covers and the passenger-side mirror were taken off a 2009 Hyundai Sonata which, police said, had no sign of forced entry. The spare tire was removed from the undercarriage of a 2009 Ford E-250 cargo van.
The thefts occurred on the weekend, according to police, who placed the total value of the stolen parts at $709.54.
Anyone with information is asked to call police at 638-8516. Patrolman Dennis Smith investigated.
Furnace Fire
Fire fighters from Lebanon Township, High Bridge and Lebanon Borough responded March 20 to a house fire on Highview Terrace, off Glen Manor Drive.
According to police, the fire appeared to have started when the reset button on the furnace was pushed at 4:45 p.m. The dwelling suffered smoke and cinder damage, with the heat vents scorched by the flames, police said.
Fire Marshal Gary Apgar and Patrolman Alan Goracy investigated. The Lebanon Township Rescue Squad also responded.
Rear-End Collision
Two cars were involved in a rear-end collision March 20 on southbound Route 31.
Police said a 1993 Lincoln Town Car driven by Arlene Blanchard, 65, of Hampton was waiting to turn left onto Cregar Road at 6:04 p.m. when her car was hit from behind by a 2000 Honda Civic driven by Michael J. Anderson, 18, of Cologne, N.J. Ms. Blanchard was taken to Hunterdon Medical Center in Raritan Township with injuries.
Mr. Anderson was charged by Patrolman Michael Thomsen with careless driving. Firemen and rescue squads from Lebanon Township and High Bridge responded.
Parking Lot Dinger
A 2005 Toyota Rav4 driven by Tusharmou Mukherjee, 34, of Lebanon hit a parked car March 21 at Muller Toyota on Route 31, police said. According to police, the accident occurred as Mr. Mukherjee was trying to park at the dealership at 9:54 a.m. He was not injured. Patrolman Dennis Smith investigated.
Arrested On Warrants
Ricardo Guinote, 47, of Basking Ridge was arrested March 22 and turned over to Bernards Township police on warrants from Bernards Township and Edison. He was taken into custody following a traffic stop by Patrolman Michael Thomsen on Route 31 at Cregar Road at 12:32 a.m. Mr. Guinote also was charged with careless driving and driving with a suspended license.
Two Vans In Accident
Two vans were involved in an accident Saturday on Route 513.
Police said a 1996 Ford van driven by Alexander Vilenchik, 48, of Oldwick was pulling into the Califon Exxon station at 9:50 a.m. when it collided with a 2000 Dodge van driven by Tanya L. Perret, 39, of Long Valley. Neither driver was injured. Patrolman Ronald Unkert Jr. investigated.

 RARITAN TWP. 
Seven Arrests From Fight
A fight at the Townsende development on Walter E. Foran Boulevard led to seven arrests in all, according to police reports.
Patrolman Robert Landolina was summoned at 10 p.m. March 24 on a report of a fight and drug activity in progress at the tennis courts. Arrested were Daniel Hernando, 20, of Raritan Township; Manny Hernando, 20, of Raritan Township; Shannon Stanley, 20, of Readington Township; and a 17-year-old Raritan Township boy.
Those four suspects were charged with possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana and possession of drug paraphernalia, which police said was a blunt. Daniel Hernando also was charged with disorderly conduct &quot;for his disruptive actions when confronted by police,&quot; according to a statement.
Police added that the Hernando brothers were threatened by Travis French, 19, of Bridgewater; Kevin Hahn, 19, of Bridgewater; and Loree Truscott, 20, of Raritan Township. Those three suspects were arrested on harassment charges by Patrolman Margaret Hammond at 12:12 a.m. March 25.
Mr. Hahn also was charged with criminal mischief, police said, for using a wooden board to hit the Hernando brothers&apos; car. Mr. French also was charged with possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana.
Mother Charged
Jamie Acosta, 30, of Clark faces charges following a one-car accident Sunday.
According to police, a car driven by Ms. Acosta hit a traffic sign and got a flat tire as she was making a left turn onto Route 31 from Route 523 at 12:25 a.m. Her two children, ages 5 years and three months, were uninjured in child safety seats in the back.
Ms. Acosta was charged with driving under the influence, possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, endangering the welfare of a child, possession of narcotics in a motor vehicle and careless driving. Patrolman Margaret Hammond investigated.
Brass Knuckles Found
Max Micciche, 19, of Milan, Pa., was arrested on drug and weapons charges Monday during a traffic stop on Route 202.
He was pulled over by Sgt. Alfred Payne at 12:45 a.m. for having a loud exhaust and a brake light out. A set of brass knuckles was found in the car during a related search along with a pipe, police said.
Mr. Micciche was charged with possession of a prohibited weapon, possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, possession of drug paraphernalia and possession of narcotics in a motor vehicle, plus the exhaust and brake light violations.
Drug, Alcohol Charge
Brothers Thomas Cookson, 46, of Nutley and Lester Cookson, 42, of Flemington were in a car pulled over Sunday by Patrolman Brian Sutherland at 11:31 p.m. for allegedly going through a red light on Route 202. A pipe and rolling papers were found in the car during a search, police said.
Thomas, the driver, was charged with driving under the influence of alcohol, possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, possession of drug paraphernalia, reckless driving, possession of narcotics in a motor vehicle and running a red light. Lester, the passenger, was charged with possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, possession of drug paraphernalia and drinking alcohol in a motor vehicle.
Underage Possession Charge
l Devan DePhillips, 18, of Basking Ridge and Kyle Jursik, 18, of Raritan Township were charged early Sunday with underage possession of alcohol.
Patrolman Robert Landolina, dispatched at 1:20 a.m. on a report of a suspicious vehicle on Cypress Court, found the two teens sitting in a car with four cans of beer in their possession.
Shoplifting Alleged
Ruth King, 50, of Flemington was arrested at 4:07 p.m. Sunday and charged with shoplifting $15.48 worth of groceries from ShopRite supermarket on Route 202-31. Patrolman Steven Rindock investigated.
DWI Charges
l Kathleen Wilson, 22, of Raritan Township was arrested Friday and charged with driving under the influence of alcohol.
She was taken into custody during a traffic stop on Route 31 by Patrolman Christopher Vallat at 1:01 a.m. for making an improper turn. Wilson also was charged with reckless driving and failure to stay in a lane.
l Ronald Fulcher, 71, of Bad Axe, Mich., was arrested Sunday and charged with driving under the influence.
He was taken into custody by Patrolman Benedict Donaruma during a traffic stop for weaving along Route 202-31 at 8:30 p.m. Fulcher also was charged with failure to maintain his lane, careless driving and littering.
l George DiCostanza, 43, of Raritan Township was arrested Saturday and charged with driving under the influence of alcohol.
He was pulled over by Patrolman Brian Sutherland on a traffic stop at 11:13 p.m. for weaving along Everitts Road. Mr. DiCostanza also was cited for reckless driving.
l Jose Garcia, 30, of Lambertville was arrested on drunken-driving and related charges Saturday. He was taken into custody by Patrolman Matthew Lawrence during a traffic stop on Yorkshire Drive at 12:23 a.m. for alleged speeding. Garcia was charged with DUI, possession of an open container, speeding and driving without a license.
Drug-Driving Charge
Joseph Constandi, 40, of Raritan Township was arrested on drug-related charges during a traffic stop on Case Boulevard for speeding at 3:10 p.m. Sunday.
Mr. Constandi was charged with being under the influence of drugs, reckless driving, speeding and failure to wear a seat belt. Patrolman Steven Smith investigated.

 READINGTON TWP. 
Tractor-Trailer Accident
A tractor-trailer driven by James Cogill, 56, of Brick ran into the back of a tractor driven by Paul Coccarelli, 41, of Pittsburgh around 12:20 p.m. March 26, tying up traffic on southbound Route 31 near Stanton Station Road for hours, according to police. Police said Mr. Cogill told them he fell asleep behind the wheel.
State Police, Whitehouse Fire Department, paramedics from Hunterdon Medical Center, Flemington-Raritan rescue squad and Clinton rescue responded. Clinton rescue spokesman Chad Newsome said Mr. Cogill&apos;s truck was smoking and that there was a &quot;considerable fuel spill.&quot;
Mr. Cogill had to be extricated from the truck. He complained of chest pain and was taken to Robert Wood Johnson University Hospital, where he was admitted. Neither Mr. Coccarelli nor his passenger, Rex McFarland, 44, of Nesquehoning, Pa., reported any injuries.
Marijuana Charges
l Sgt. Christopher DeWire stopped a car driven by Francesco Paone, 56, of Perth Amboy on westbound Route 22 near the Readington Diner around 4:10 a.m. March 22 because he was driving erratically, police said. During the stop, Sgt. DeWire smelled burnt marijuana, which was found on Mr. Paone, according to police. Mr. Paone was charged with possession of less than 50 grams of marijuana, possession of a controlled dangerous substance in a motor vehicle, driving under the influence of drugs and obstructing traffic. He was released.
l Patrolman James Ayotte was patrolling the Hillcrest Road area around 12:30 a.m. March 22 when he saw a car parked along the road. After a brief investigation, he arrested a 17-year-old boy in the car and seized about 25 grams of marijuana, which police said he intended on selling within 500 feet of a public park.
Police said the investigation is ongoing and that charges will be filed by the department&apos;s juvenile officer.
Switchblade Found
Police arrested a Harrisburg, Pa. man around 3:30 a.m. March 14 after Sgt. Christopher DeWire stropped him for failing to stay in a lane, police said.
During the stop, police said Marcel Griffins, 30, kept putting his hands in his pockets, contrary to police orders. A search uncovered a switchblade knife. He was charged with possession of a prohibited weapon and being a person not allowed to have weapons.
Mr. Griffins was wanted on a $3,505 arrest warrant from Jersey City. He was turned over to authorities there after posting bail on the local charges.
Drunken Driving Charges
l Ivy S. Lyons, 53, of New Hope, Pa., was charged with drunken driving after she was stopped on southbound Route 202 by Patrolman Raymond Mackiewicz for failing to stay in a lane around 9:54 p.m. March 17, police said. She failed field sobriety tests and her blood-alcohol level tested above the legal limit, according to police. She was released to the custody of a relative.
Alleged Home Burglars Caught
As police were responding to a Ridge Road home&apos;s burglar alarm and finding a screen removed from a partially open rear window, an alert resident phoned police to report three men in a suspicious black sports car driving slowly along Centerville Road looking at houses.
A police bulletin was broadcast and Branchburg police stopped the car in Readington Township. Readington police said they searched the vehicle and found jewelry stolen from a Readington home last year, along with burglary tools and fireworks.
Charged with burglary, possession of stolen property, possession of burglar tools and possession of fireworks were Giovanni Alvarenge-Guardado 27, of Stirling; Jorge Garcia, 25, of Plainfield and Wistong Corrales, 29, also of Plainfield.
Police said the investigation solves several burglaries on Ridge, Sunset View and Forty Oaks roads in Readington Township.

 SHERIFF&apos;S DEPARTMENT 
Passes Out In Lobby
A man wanted by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement passed out in the lobby of the county Probation Department after being taken into custody just after 3:30 p.m. Friday.
As Hany Mehanny, 43, of Freemansburg, Pa., was being escorted into the waiting room by sheriff&apos;s officers Lucas Schwab and David Bowlby, his family became agitated, according to a release from the Sheriff&apos;s Department. He fainted after a woman and a man lay down wailing, according to the release.
Mr. Mehanny was taken by the Flemington-Raritan Rescue Squad to Hunterdon Medical Center, where he spent three days before being transferred to the county jail on the immigration hold. The two other family members were not hospitalized.
Child Support Warrant
Two men surrendered to sheriff&apos;s deputies Monday on warrants for failure to pay child support.
John Kremp, 49, of Beaver Avenue, Clinton Township, and Lawrence Schier, 46, of Garden Lane, Flemington, turned themselves in to detectives Jesse Winfield and Lamont Garnes around 9 a.m. Mr. Kremp and Mr. Schier were held in the county jail pending a Superior Court hearing on the warrants.
Probation Warrants
l Amy Defazio, 25, of Readington Township was arrested March 25 and held in the Hunterdon County Jail on a warrant for violating probation.
She was taken into custody at 1:45 p.m. by Cpl. Sandra Ford and Sheriff&apos;s Officer Frank Modaffare at the Hunterdon County Justice Center in Flemington.
 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in Hunterdon County Democrat
 Previous story
 Lions At Devils Tonight In Intracounty Contest Next story
 Clinton Democrats Seek Candidates Copyright 2012 NJ.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 0 
Comments Feed 
 
 
Post a comment
 (You may use HTML tags for style) 
 

You must accept the terms of service before you can post a comment.
 
Post a comment
 
Sign in to NJ.com
 Username Password 
  Remember me? I forgot my username or password» 
Don&apos;t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 
 AIM Google OpenID 
 
More Hunterdon County Democrat

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 Hunterdon County Democrat stories with the most comments in the last 7 days. 29 State Police arrest Georgia man who they say was carrying a loaded gun at truck stop in Bloomsbury 20 Trenton teen drowns while swimming in Delaware River at Bull&apos;s Island 18 Readington cops say man stole an air conditioner from Walmart two days in a row 17 Former sub code official sues Tewksbury Township claiming &apos;hostile work environment&apos; 16 In Clinton Township, dog euthanized after severely biting owner 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most NJ.com comments in the last 7 days 172 tangledhair 146 BrassBand5 105 CountyWatcher2 91 oldtimer 88 sage1959 
 

Users We Love
 NJ.com user nl10781 
Posted photos of his Devils collectables More Users We Love 
Connect with NJ.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 Site Map | Advertise | Contact Make us your home page Home | News | Weather | Sports | Entertainment | Living | Interact | Jobs | Autos | Real Estate | Classifieds | Deals | Place an Ad 
 Your Photos Your Videos Blogs Forums NJ Shore NJ Weddings 
 
 Post a Job Post a Free Classified Ad Sell Your Car Sell/Rent Your Home Apartments&amp;Rentals Claim Your Business
   Listing for Free 
 
 Business High School Sports NJ Lottery New Jersey Politics Obituaries Pets 
 
 Subscribe to our content (RSS) Sign up for news alerts NJ.com Twitter feed Ledger Live vodcast View NJ.com mobile site View mobile product offerings 
 Special home delivery offers! The Star-Ledger | The Times, Trenton | The Jersey Journal | Gloucester Co. Times 
 The News of Cumberland County | Today&apos;s Sunbeam 
 Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 New Jersey On-Line LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of New Jersey On-Line LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management .

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
