<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003766" url="http://www.collegehumor.com/video/6429045/suspending-water-without-a-cup-trick" time="2012-07-12-19:55" support="2" score="0.0010708911630191147" bingtitle="Suspending Water Without a Cup Trick - CollegeHumor Video" webtitle="Suspending Water Without a Cup Trick - CollegeHumor Video">
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>Suspending Water Without a Cup Trick ... In High School I worked at a fast food restaurant with my ... Enter your email to receive a weekly newsletter of the ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Videos 
 All Recent Video Playlists Most Viewed Sketch Comedy TV/Movies Originals All Originals Sketch Celebrities Animation Jake and Amir Troopers Hardly Working Very Mary-Kate Dinosaur Office The Six 
 x Pictures 
 All Recent Picture Galleries Most Viewed TV/Movies Categories Animals Art Cars College Epic Facebook Food Foreign Gross Holidays Nerdy People Politics Pop Culture Pranks Relationships Religion Sexy Signs Sports The Internet Words WTF Girls Cute College Girl Hottest College Girl 
 x Articles 
 All Recent Most Viewed TV/Movies Columns CollegeHumor Interview The Graphic Truth Caption Contest TLDNR Exclusive Leaks 420 Special Axe Cop Almost Reading HumorUs 
 x uPick 
 uPick Categories Beach Rants News .GIFs WTF Fail Win Classroom Screencap Rough Love Text Mess Pet Stories Jokes Idiotech Work Sucks Roommate Confessions Polidicks Pranks I Fought the Law 
 x Politics 
 Electoral CollegeHumor Political Timeline Election Cheat Sheet 
 More 
 More CollegeHumor Recent Toplists Surveys Topics CH Live Tour Best of CH CH LiveCast Hotlinks TV/Movies Stalk Us Facebook Twitter Youtube CH Staff Blog Subscribe (RSS) Recent Videos CH Originals Recent Pictures Recent Articles 
 x 
 Submit↑ 
 Sign in | Sign up | 
   Signing in... 
Sign in to CollegeHumor
 

 Use Your CollegeHumor Account Forgot your password? Use Your Facebook Account 
You&apos;ll also be able to post your CollegeHumor activity to your Facebook feed.
 Not registered? Create an account Signing in via Facebook Connect... 
Suspending Water Without a Cup Trick
 Note: Continuous play is disabled while you read the rest of the page. Scroll back up to enable it. Hide Forever Submit a Video 
“That’s pretty cool, man, but can I just have a glass? I’m really thirsty.”
 
 February 18, 2011 
 See More water trick magic how to unbelievable Like this Video Share this Video Share on Tumblr 64k Share on Facebook Tweet Email to a friend Embed 
 CollegeHumor’s Favorite Funny Videos 
 Close 
Customize Embed Options
 400 x 225 600 x 338 750 x 563 900 x 507 
Custom Size
 x px 
Other Options
 Use old embed code 
 Send this page to a friend 
 

 
 Your Name 
 Your Email 
 Friends&apos; Emails (Separate multiple addresses with commas) 
 Send 
 uPick Screencap Funny screen captures See All» Up +8 Down + - &quot;Yes. That turns some girls on.&quot; 

 
 July 12, 2012 

 Be the first to comment!
	</body>
</document>
