<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003627" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Houston/Continental-Manufacturing-Company" time="2012-07-12-19:47" support="1" score="0.0015232095000830925" bingtitle="Continental Manufacturing Company - Fast Food Restaurant Houston ..." webtitle="Continental Manufacturing Company - Fast Food Restaurant  Houston, TX 77034">
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>Continental Manufacturing Company is a Fast Food restaurant located at 9797 Galveston Rd ... Accepts Credit Card: Yes; Parking: N/A; Atmosphere: N/A; Take Reservations: Yes; Serves ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Continental Manufacturing
Company

 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(713) 947-2600

 http://www.cbmwmixers.com/ 
 TX &gt; Houston &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Continental Manufacturing Company listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Continental Manufacturing Company to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Continental Manufacturing Company
 Continental Manufacturing Company is a Fast Food restaurant located at 9797 Galveston Rd in Houston, TX 77034. Continental Manufacturing Company has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Continental Manufacturing Company
 
 
 
All Reviews for Continental Manufacturing Company


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Continental Manufacturing Company:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Continental Manufacturing Company News
 Saturday: Chris Gray Day at the Continental Club In August 1836, two real estate entrepreneurs—Augustus Chapman Allen and John Kirby Allen—from New York, purchased of land along ... of air conditioning provided impetus for many companies to relocate to Houston resulting in an economic ... North Shore Business Calendar 7 a.m., networking and continental breakfast ... www.northshorechamber.org or 978-774-8565. A Malaysian company&apos;s plan to build a $4 billion convention center and big-time casino on the outskirts of New York City could be the biggest shot fired yet ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Continental Can Company - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Continental Can Company (CCC) was an American producer of metal containers and packaging company. The Continental Can Company was founded by Edwin Norton T.G ... Continental Fan Manufacturing Inc. Continental Fan Manufacturing Inc. provides air moving solutions to a broad range of OEM companies, and ventilation products for use in many industrial, commercial ... New York City Restaurants - New York, New York - Yahoo! Travel www.RamsesTours.com Day 0: Pick up in New York and fly to Cairo international airport to start your adventure www.RamsesTours.com DAY 1: Arrive at ... New York&amp;Company Nyandcompany.com - Find trendy, sexy, comfortable, affordable clothing online. Womens apparel, accessories and footwear. Clothing available in sizes 2-18, petites and ... Category:Defunct companies based in New York - Wikipedia, the free ... Subcategories. This category has the following 4 subcategories, out of 4 total. Defunct companies based in Syracuse, New York‎ (32 P, 2 F) 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 72° 
Fri
 
 72° - 88° 
Sat
 
 73° - 88° 
Sun
 
 73° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Continental Manufacturing Company

9797 Galveston Rd

Houston, TX 
 
77034
 
Telephone
 (713) 947-2600 
Continental Manufacturing Company
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Continental Manufacturing Company Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Pizza Hut 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Whataburger 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wingstop Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food The Healthy Lunch Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Whataburger Restaurants 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Popeyes Famous Fried Chicken 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pizza Hut 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Rudi Lechners Restaurant&amp;Bar 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Alley Gallery Antique Prints 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Art Artisans 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries ArtceteraE Foney 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Atelier Jacquinet 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Awards InternationalHouston 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Houston Art Museums Galleries 
See all Houston ATMs 
See all Houston Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Continental Manufacturing Company Coupons 

 Continental Manufacturing Company Houston 

 Continental Manufacturing Company Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Houston Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X Y | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
