<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003947" url="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/bill-that-will-finally-abolish-spectre-of-capital-punishment-tony-farragher-looks-at-the-controversial-history-of-the-death-penalty-on-the-isle-of-man-1532600.html" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="2" score="0.0018781917269982593" bingtitle="Bill that will finally abolish spectre of capital punishment: Tony ..." webtitle="Bill that will finally abolish spectre of capital punishment: Tony Farragher looks at the controversial history of the death penalty on the Isle of Man - UK - News - The Independent">
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>It is the last place in the British Isles to repeal ... That was when the manager of a fast-food restaurant in Douglas was ... on the island - found he had no choice but to order ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday 12 July 2012 
 
 i Jobs Dating Property Shop 
 Click here... 
 News 
 UK 
 Home News UK Politics Crime This Britain 
 World 
 Europe Americas Middle East Asia Africa Australasia World Politics World History Novaya Gazeta (English) 
 Business 
 Business News Business Comment Business Analysis&amp;Features Sharewatch SME Market News Market Epic Market Heatmaps Market Screener 

 Business Directory ES Business Connections 
 People 
 News Profiles Diary 
 Science Environment 
 Climate Change Green Living Nature 
 Media 
 Opinion TV&amp;Radio Press Online Advertising 
 Technology Education 
 News Schools Further Higher Primary Tables 2011 Secondary Tables 2012 Training&amp;Courses MBA&amp;Executive Tutors 
 Olympics Obituaries Diary Corrections Newsletter 
 Opinion Sport OLYMPICS Life Property Arts&amp;Ents Travel Money IndyBest Blogs Student 
 Hot Topics George Osborne Syria Greece Michael Gove Click here... News &gt; UK 
Bill that will finally abolish spectre of capital punishment: Tony Farragher looks at the controversial history of the death penalty on the Isle of Man
 

 TONY FARRAGHER 
Saturday 11 July 1992
 Tweet Print Your friend&apos;s email address Your email address Note: We do not store your email address(es) but your IP address will be logged to prevent abuse of this feature. Please read our Legal Terms&amp;Policies A A A Email 
Latest in UK
 
 Millions face financial woe as debt levels soar 
 
 Stabbed policemen undergo surgery 
 
 Assange&apos;ready to quit&apos;extradition fight 
 
 Father and daughter killed in M5 crash were on way back from funeral 
 
 Miliband:&apos;Fairness is not in Cameron&apos;s DNA&apos; 
 
 God vs Mammon: Britain takes sides 
 
 Inspectors find culture of abuse in NHS trust&apos;s maternity services 
 
 St Paul&apos;s tries to heal rifts and offers to open its doors 
 
 Amy Winehouse&apos;ignored GP&apos;s alcohol warnings&apos; 
 
 Osborne&apos;s anti-green agenda splits Coalition 
 
News in pictures
 
From the blogs
 
 Slavery under our own eyes 

Back in September 2011 a police raid on a travellers’ site in Bedfordshire uncovered a story that le...
 
 On The Road: Bradley Wiggins does a perfect recreation of Alan Partridge’s ‘Dan!, Dan!, DAN!’ 

The more time you spend on the road, the more important those small moments of fun to stop us all go...
 
 Tulisa Contostavlos may have won the sex tape court case, but the damage is irreparable 

Due to legal reasons, any reporting of the case back in March had to assert that Tulisa had believed...
 
 Britain and banking: Back to the 1830s 

Unparalleled levels of imprudent lending; corrupt banking practices; soaring inflation and rising un...
 
Related articles

 
 Three men jailed over gay death call leaflets 
 
 Three found guilty over&apos;death penalty&apos;pamphlet 
 
 US death-penalty support at 39-year low after Davis execution 
 
 Men found guilty of handing out anti-homosexuality leaflets 
 
 &apos;Death penalty for gays&apos;– five accused over leaflet campaign 
 
 Suggested Topics 
 Death Penalty Isle Of Man (uk) Human Rights Punishment 
 (First Edition) 
THE AUTOMATIC sentence of death for murder will be removed from the Isle of Man&apos;s statute book later this year, subject to the support of the Manx parliament.

When the first murder trial the island has witnessed in a decade opened a fortnight ago, the Chief Minister, Miles Walker, announced that the ancient penalty is to be abolished under a new Bill.

It is the last place in the British Isles to repeal capital punishment. When Britain did so in 1965, neither the Isle of Man nor the Channel Islands brought their legislation into line.

As both retained independent legislatures, and are responsible for domestic laws, hanging not only remained an option for courts but was mandatory. The Channel Islands repealed theirs in 1986.

Murders are infrequent on the 227-square mile Isle of Man, and the fact that its laws on capital punishment were going to cause a problem did not arise until 1972.

That was when the manager of a fast-food restaurant in Douglas was battered to death with a fire extinguisher by his head chef. The &apos;Golden Egg murder&apos; gained notoriety not so much for the crime, but the sentence.

When the murder charge was proved, the judge - known as a Deemster on the island - found he had no choice but to order the death penalty.

It created a legal precedent when the Queen exercised her Royal Prerogative and the sentence was commuted to life imprisonment.

It happened again in 1982, when a 28-year-old father beat his baby son to death in Douglas. The same procedure followed and the death sentence was overturned.

That was the last murder proved in a Manx court until yesterday. Now the royal solution is sure to be taken again.

The last execution to take place on the island was more than a century ago. A farmer&apos;s son, living in a croft in the hills above Sulby, became exasperated with his father&apos;s continual winding of their grandfather clock and stabbed him. He was hanged.

The Manx parliament, Tynwald, has also kept corporal punishment on its statutes but local magistrates have been given firm advice not to order birching after the European Court of Human Rights judged it to be &apos;cruel and unusual&apos;.

While there is no sign of change on this issue, there are other indications that the small Crown dependency is bending to the will of the rest of Britain and Europe.

A Bill legalising homosexual acts between consenting adult males in private was finally given Royal Assent on Tuesday.

Now the local Minister for Home Affairs has written to Mr Walker describing the death penalty as &apos;a pointless mandatory sentence which cannot be imposed&apos;. A Bill to repeal it has been prepared for introduction into the House of Keys in the autumn.

&apos;It seems right to put the judiciary in a position where they have to give considered thought to the sentence,&apos; Mr Walker said. &apos;At the moment it&apos;s all rather cut and dried.&apos;

The last executions to take place in the UK were in August 1964, when two men were hanged, simultaneously, in Strangeways, Manchester, and Walton, Liverpool, for the murder of a milkman in Whitehaven, Cumbria. Hanging can still be ordered for a series of offences including treason, the murder of the monarch, offences against the royal family, piracy and certain acts of misconduct in the armed forces.
 Tweet 
 Comments 
 More in UK » Independent Comment Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. blog comments powered by Disqus 
Please provide search keyword(s)
 
 Advanced Search Day in a page Article archive 
 
 Most Viewed Most Commented Most Shared 
 
 1 Hellraising: A toast to Peter O&apos;Toole 2 How riches attract&apos;elite&apos;drug dealers 3 The truth about lying: it&apos;s the hands that betray you, not the eyes 4 News in pictures 5 Einstein&apos;s theory is proved - and it is bad news if you own a penthouse 6 Darren Eadie: Life after football - depression and panic attacks 7 In pictures: The bewildering face of China 8 Ten adverts that shocked the world 9 Chinese&apos;cannibal&apos;attack caught on video as drunken bus driver chews off woman&apos;s face 10 Briton arrested in Thailand after being found with six roasted human foetuses 
 
 1 Top 10 brilliant student money saving tips 2 Einstein&apos;s theory is proved - and it is bad news if you own a penthouse 3 50 things to do before you leave university 4 Thrill of the chaste: The truth about Gandhi&apos;s sex life 5 Darren Eadie: Life after football - depression and panic attacks 6 Revealed: the YouTube rich list 7 Young cannabis users&apos;do not realise the huge danger to their health&apos; 8 Red faces all round as players&apos;murky world is exposed in John Terry racism court case 9 Chinese&apos;cannibal&apos;attack caught on video as drunken bus driver chews off woman&apos;s face 10 Briton arrested in Thailand after being found with six roasted human foetuses 
 Click here... Click here... 
SPONSORED FEATURES
 
 Experience the Heineken Hub 

Get free wi-fi and exclusive i content while you enjoy a tasty pint of Heineken at participating pubs.
 Austrian holiday Networking 2012 Prizes&amp;offers Business videos 
 Win a sumptuous three-night stay in Austria 

Get away from it all in the fresh mountain air at the four-star Hotel Edelweiss&amp;Gurgl.
 Heineken Hub Networking 2012 Prizes&amp;offers Business videos 
 Playing a game-changing role during the Games 

Cisco is providing the solutions for London 2012&apos;s complex IT needs.
 Heineken Hub Austrian holiday Prizes&amp;offers Business videos 
 Enter the latest Independent competitions 

Win anything from gadgets to five-star holidays on our competitions and offers page.
 Heineken Hub Austrian holiday Networking 2012 Business videos 
 Business videos from commercial thought leaders 

Watch the best in the business world give their insights into the world of business.
 Heineken Hub Austrian holiday Networking 2012 Prizes&amp;offers 
Day In a Page
 
 Sun Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri Sat 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 January February March April May June July August September October November December 1992 1993 1994 1995 1996 1997 1998 1999 2000 2001 2002 2003 2004 2005 2006 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 2012 Go 
Tate Modern goes dark
 The Weather Project artist will turn out the lights 
&apos;Disarming and electrifying&apos;Porgy&amp;Bess
 Edward Seckerson&apos;s verdict on the Cape Town Opera&apos;s production 
How to cure the Coalition
 In the final extract from his book&apos;Never Again&apos;about the botched NHS reforms, Nicholas Timmins reflects on how to prevent such disasters re-occuring 
Robert Fisk
 Beirut&apos;s banks – and a money trail from Syria to Iran… 
Investment in the future
 Financier&apos;s £75m gift to help poor into Oxford 
Too good to be true? The Caravaggio conundrum
 Last week, Brescia art experts found 100&apos;new&apos;works by the old master. Their value? €700m. But there&apos;s a catch: their rivals in Milan aren&apos;t convinced 
Named: Britain&apos;s most powerful brands...
 ... but can you spot the big cheese? 
Meet the plant hunters
 The adventurers who transformed our gardens would put Indiana Jones to shame 
Lowdown on Latitude: Pick of the highlights
 There&apos;s more to Latitude than just great music, says Elisa Bray 
Satoru Iwata:&apos;The Wii is so unique&apos;
 This promises to be a rollercoaster year for Japanese video-gaming giant Nintendo... 
Items banned from the Olympics revealed
 Organisers come under fire after releasing list of restricted objects for 2012 venues 
Hellraising: A toast to Peter O&apos;Toole
 We mark the retirement of one of acting&apos;s legends with some of his finest moments of boozy mayhem 
Baker using its loaf as profits are sliced
 Even bread is feeling the pinch in this slump but family-owned giant Warburtons is fighting back 
The 10 Best family science events
 This summer, get your children excited about life, the universe and everything with these scientific voyages of discovery... 
Darren Eadie: Life after football - depression and panic attacks
 When the striker&apos;s career came to a sudden end due to injury, mental illness took a grip – he explains how he has fought through it 
 The Independent 
2 Derry Street London W8 5TT
©independent.co.uk
 
 Terms&amp;Policies Privacy Policy Cookie policy Code of Conduct Email newsletters RSS Contact us 
 
 Subscriptions Apps Work for us Evening Standard Homes&amp;Property iJobs Advertising Guide 
 
 Syndication Novaya Gazeta (English) The Journalism Foundation ES Business Connections 
 
Please provide search keyword(s)
 
 Advanced Search Day in a page Article archive 
 ©independent.co.uk
	</body>
</document>
