<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003225" url="http://www.articlesbase.com/weight-loss-articles/obesity-in-america-678263.html" time="2012-07-12-19:21" support="2" score="0.0028840715261202327" bingtitle="Obesity in America - Free Articles Directory | Submit Articles ..." webtitle="Obesity in America">
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>If it is a fast food restaurant you might find it on the paper insert of the serving tray. ... to put the blame for teen obesity on Bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Login Login via Register 

 My Home Sign Out 
 
 Aerobics Archery Baseball Basketball Bodybuilding Cricket Equestrian Equipment More Categories 
 Advertising Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive Beauty Business Careers Computers Education Finance Food and Beverage Health Hobbies Home and Family 

 Home Improvement Internet Law Marketing News and Society Relationships Self Improvement Shopping Spirituality Sports and Fitness Technology Travel Writing 

 More in Sports and Fitness Extreme Sports Fishing Fitness Football Golf Hockey Horse Racing Martial Arts Muscle Building Outdoor Sports Pilates Rugby Scuba Diving Self Defense Soccer Tennis Track and Field Water Sports Weight Loss Yoga 
 
 
 Home Page Sports and Fitness Weight Loss 
 Print article 
Obesity in America
 
 Dec 10, 2008 0 628 
 
Child obesity in America affects over fifteen percent of adolescents and children over the age of six. Adult obesity occurs in over one-third of all Americans. As a nation we are notorious for making unhealthy food choices which puts us at risk of cancer, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, osteoporosis, and many other diseases. The easiest method to determine if you are overweight or obese is the body mass index calculator. Related Articles Understanding Child Obesity Child Obesity - Effects, Causes, and Solutions Child Obesity in America Child Obesity in America Can Complete Skateboards Be A Solution To Child Obesity? 

Why is obesity in America an epidemic? There are numerous reasons but the main causes are  poor diet and exercise. Americans cook fewer meals at home than they did in the past which leads to a increased intake of high fat and high sodium foods. The typical restaurant in America serves portions that are super sized and high in calories. Even ordering a salad would surprise you after checking the ingredients in the dressing. Many people like to have a soda before their meal arrives and that sixteen ounce beverage starts your caloric intake at 194.

Many consumers are aware of food labeling and restaurants are required to make food labeling available to the consumer. You&apos;d be hard pressed to find the labeling though. If it is a fast food restaurant you might find it on the paper insert of the serving tray. The only problem is it might be too late since you already ordered your meal and you are probably in a hurry - thats why it is called fast food. So searching for the labeling is not a top priority. Also contributing to obesity in America is the processed foods, deep fat frying, and  other flavor enhancers used by restaurants. The biggest problem is the outrageous portion sizes that encourage the intake of empty calories.

Health risks associated with obesity in America are as follows:

Type II Diabetes
Hypertension
High Cholesterol
Liver Problems
Asthema
Cancer
Cardiovascular Disease
Sleep Apnea
Heart Attack
Stroke
Psychological Disorders
Depression

Eating at home has many benefits aside from it is less expensive that ordering out. You control the types of foods being served and know the ingredients. You control the portion sizes and eating as a family gives you the opportunity to spend quality time together and bond. 
Tips for healthy eating habits :

Be willing to experiment by eating a variety of nutritious foods.

Provide three healthy meals a day and create a regular mealtime for the family. Afternoon snacks are fine as long as they are nutritious ( fruit or vegetables) and are not meant to be a meal.

Refrain from eating after dinner. No midnight snacks. And never eat large amounts of food at once.

Know your families serving size and provide just enough to satisfy their needs.

Enjoy your mealtime as a family avoiding confrontation. Unnecessary stress at mealtime can lead to emotional overeating.

Find creative ways of dealing with  emotions avoiding food as a solution.Establish a set location for food consumption in the home. Preferably the dinner table. This will avoid eating in front of the TV, computer, or bedrooms.

Keep only snacks in the home that are high in nutrients and make them readily available. Wash and slice fruits and vegetables and be sure there is easy access to them.

Avoid buying problem foods like doughnuts and cookies. If you do keep them in the pantry out of sight. Never use food as a reward for good behavior.

Some people eat out of sheer boredom or because they were enticed by the food advertisement on TV.  Learn to eat only when you are truly hungry and remind yourself that a snack is not a meal. In other words, eating a full bag of carrots is not necessary. But it is much healthier than a full bag of chips

Obesity in America is an epidemic that ranks second in preventable deaths right behind cigarette smoking. We are approaching the first generation in our history that will have a lower life expectancy  than their parents. Changes in lifestyles, diet, and exercise is needed to combat obesity. Preventing obesity is much easier than treating obesity.
 About the Author 
 Share Subscribe to RSS Contact Author 
 James Rouse 

James Rouse is a personal weight loss coach and author of the popular http://www.helpcurechildobesity.com - a website created out of his passion. Perhaps you have a passion or hobby you&apos;d like to write about. Discover how to turn it into a profitable Web site like James has. Visit http://www.helpcurechildobesity.com/how-i-did-this-bx2 to learn more.

 Tags: 
 obesity in america child obesity family 
 Rate this Article: 1 2 3 4 5 vote(s) 0 vote(s) Re-Publish article Send to friend Author Box 
 Subscribe to RSS Contact Author 
 James Rouse has 23 articles online 
More from James Rouse
 
 Global Obesity 
 in Weight Loss 
 Food Nutrition Facts 
 in Nutrition 
 Blame for Teen Obesity 
 in Weight Loss 
 Teenagers and Obesity 
 in Weight Loss 
Latest Weight Loss Articles
 
 Want To Boost Your Metabolism? Learn These 3 Easy Ways 
 by John J. Albert 
 Keys To Successful Weight Loss 
 by Dennis Weaver 
 Can you lose weight walking on a treadmill 
 by Sean Harland 
 Obtaining the Ideal Weight-Acupuncture for Weight Loss 
 by Stephen Hively 
 8 Foods That Blow Up The Fats 
 by Katie Adams Comments Need Help? 
 Contact Us FAQ Submit Articles Editorial Guidelines Blog 
 Site Links 
 Recent Articles Top Authors Top Articles Find Articles Site Map Mobile Version 
 Webmasters 
 RSS Builder RSS Link to Us 
 Business Info 
 Advertising 
 Other languages: 
 Portuguese Spanish French 
 
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the Terms Of Use and Privacy Policy | User published content is licensed under a Creative Commons License .
 Copyright © 2005-2012 Free Articles by ArticlesBase.com, All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
