<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003865" url="http://www.ebaumsworld.com/jokes/read/14292/" time="2012-07-12-20:01" support="23" score="0.06968958449414332" bingtitle="Sharing a Meal Joke - Funny Videos, Funny Pictures, Flash Games, Jokes" webtitle="Sharing a Meal - Joke">
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000869" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000963" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>As the man begins to eat his fries a young man comes to the table. He ... An elderly couple walk into a fast food restaurant. They order one hamburger, one order of fries ...</description>
	<body>
		SEARCH
 
 
 OBESE MARIO GAME Clinically Obese Mario VIDEO Cat Plays Guitar During Eathquake VIDEO 5000 Ducks Go For A Walk In China FACEBOOK FAILS GALLERY Facebook Wins and Fails FLESHLIGHT IDEAS GALLERY Rejected Fleshlight Concepts VIDEO Tampa Rays Fan Does Faceplant On Field PRANK CALL VIDEO Tenants From Hell BLOG The Juggalo Reproductive Cycle: an Overview B.O.M. VIDEO The Best Of The Month: June 2012 VIDEO Steering Wheel Mishap VIDEO Pacquiao Vs Mayweather VIDEO Dog Dancing Around Guy With Firework Crotch VIDEO Sonic Boom Blows Out Windows VIDEO Rich Forne Shows How to Wall Ride VIDEO UFO Seen in Astrakhan Sky &apos;MERICUH BLOG 10 Ways to Have the 4th-est July Ever VIDEO Ryan Gosling Swag Dance VIDEO 4th Of July Gone Wrong USEFUL VIDEO Message VIDEO Baby Birds VIDEO The All-New World&apos;s Longest Burp VIDEO When Do You Release the New Album? VIDEO Thunder Sends Major League Players Running VIDEO Amazing Game Winning Punt Return
	</body>
</document>
