<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003557" url="http://www.openrice.com/english/restaurant/sr2.htm?shopid=22449" time="2012-07-12-19:43" support="1" score="0.0010118095454665916" bingtitle="Xi Yan Flavours - Jingchuanhu Chinese Restaurant in Tsim Sha Tsui ..." webtitle="Xi Yan Flavours - Jingchuanhu Chinese Restaurant in Tsim Sha Tsui - Hong Kong Restaurants Guide HK Restaurant - OpenRice in English">
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>Requested to pay the bill by the restaurant manager : From 7 :30PM and the manager said ... Xi Yan Flavours is not a fast food restaurant even. I have never expereinced ...</description>
	<body>
		香港(繁體版) 中国 China India Indonesia Malaysia Philippines Singapore Thailand 
 Remember my choice Other Region Login with Facebook Register Login MyOpenRice My Favorite Restaurants 中文版 Select District --Hong Kong-- Aberdeen Admiralty Ap Lei Chau Causeway Bay Central Chai Wan Cyberport Deep Water Bay Happy Valley Heng Fa Chuen Lan Kwai Fong Mid-Levels North Point Pok Fu Lam Quarry Bay Repulse Bay Sai Wan Ho Shau Kei Wan Shek O Sheung Wan Soho Stanley Tai Hang Tai Koo The Peak Tin Hau Wan Chai Western District --Kowloon-- Cheung Sha Wan Choi Hung Diamond Hill Ho Man Tin Hung Hom Jordan Knutsford Terrace Kowloon Bay Kowloon City Kowloon Tong Kwun Tong Lai Chi Kok Lam Tin Lei Yue Mun Lok Fu Mei Foo Mong Kok Ngau Tau Kwok Prince Edward San Po Kong Sham Shui Po Shek Kip Mei Tai Kok Tsui To Kwa Wan Tsim Sha Tsui Tsz Wan Shan Wong Tai Sin Yau Ma Tei Yau Tong --New Territories-- Fanling Fo Tan Kwai Chung Kwai Fong Lau Fau shan Lo Wu Lok Ma Chau Ma On Shan Ma Wan Sai Kung Sha Tin Sham Tseng Sheung Shui Tai Po Tai Wai Tai Wo Tin Shui Wai Tseung Kwan O Tsing Yi Tsuen Wan Tuen Mun Yuen Long --Outlying Islands-- Chek Lap Kok Cheung Chau Discovery Bay Lamma Island Lantau Island Ping Chau Po Toi Island Tai O Tung Chung Advanced Search Map Search Hot Types: Online Reservation Hong Kong Style Western Japanese    OpenRice iPhone App Home : Dining Guide &gt; Restaurant Search &gt; Tsim Sha Tsui &gt; Xi Yan Flavours   
 Xi Yan Flavours 囍宴 滋‧選 (Closed) 
 
 Overview Review (64) Photo (242) Video (0) 
 
 Shop 1027, Elements, 1 Austin Road West, Tsim Sha Tsui 
尖沙咀柯士甸道西1號圓方(Elements)1樓1027號舖
 Jingchuanhu | Chinese Restaurant | Drivers Friendly Dining 

 
 2628 3909 $101-$150 
 28 vs 15 vs 17 
 
 
 Update Restaurant Info Add to Favorites Send to Friends Print Add Photos (Total of 242 Photos) 
 
 
 | 
 View Full Map 
 Report Map 
 3.16 Taste
 Environment
 Service
 Hygiene
 
 Value for Money
 
 

 Phone Reservation Parking 
 
 
 Number of Seats: 50 
 
 Payment Method: Visa, Master, Cash 
 
 10% Service Charge: Yes 
 
 Parking: Yes 
 
 Gourmet Review English only (8) | English&amp;Chinese (64) First to Review: Yan~* Showing 1 to 8 of 8 Reviews 
 Display: Listing View | Full View Search: Filter Options Close 
 
 Member Level All Member Non-member Verteran Level or above Editor&apos;s Choice All Editor&apos;s Choice Review Rating All Smile OK Cry Occasion All Birthday | Anniversary | Christmas | Valentine&apos;s Day | Mother&apos;s Day | Father&apos;s Day | Chinese New Year | New Year&apos;s Eve | Xmas&apos;s Eve | Meal Type All Breakfast | Lunch | Tea | Dinner | Night Snack | Other | 
 
 
 
 
 thehungryegghead 8 Review(s) Not as good as the branch in Pacific Place Mar 14, 2012 
 
 Had a reservation for 9pm and the restaurant was pretty empty by then.

I am a frequent customer at the Pacific Place branch but since my friend was staying at the W, it was easier just to go here.

If you have never had food from Xi Yan before, this branch might not be too bad, but if you did...this branch is not as good as the one at Pacific Place.

Most especially of note the dan dan mian is not as good as the jellyfish with wasabi. The dan dan mian was just not as tasty and the jellyfish was very thick and not too fresh. That is completely not the case...it should be shredded very thinly.

Service was pretty good though. My friend thought it was just okay as well. Table Wait Time: 0 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Feb 26, 2012
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD150
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 3 |  Environment 3 |  Service 4 |  Hygiene 4 |  Value for Money 3 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Peggy328 2 Review(s) Food was either super salty or tasteless May 22, 2011 
 
 My boyfriend&amp;I, we ordered the following dishes plus two drinks. The food was horrible; so horrible that I feel obliged to write this review here.

Jellyfish strips&amp;cucumber in sesame&amp;wasabi sauce 麻醬海蜇青瓜
- the only dish that was ok.... but the jellyfish was rather chewy - I&apos;ve never tasted jellyfish that&apos;s so chewy 

 燻蛋 - absolutely tasteless

 Fried spring rolls with radish and dried oysters 原隻蠔豉蘿蔔絲春卷 - worst dish of the night! It was sooooooooooo salty. Really unfit for human consumption. 

 腐乳脆香雞 - very salty again 

 南丫島蝦醬炒飯 - very salty too! 

 上湯雙翠 - 冬瓜 + 豆苖 - tasteless again 

Will never go there ever again! Absolutely the worst restaurant we&apos;ve been to recently. Date of Visit: May 21, 2011
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD233(Dinner)
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 1 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 2 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 wvillas 24 Review(s) nice desert Jan 12, 2011 
 
 After enjoying my reading time at Metrobooks, I walked through the ground floor, looking for deserts in my teatime. Finally, we found a restaurant opened by Jackie Yu, a famous celebrity chef in Hong Kong. In fact, he used to be a designer but then he changed his mind and founded Xi Yan, which had several shops in HK and one in Singapore.
Although it was already 4 in the afternoon, all seats inside was occupied. Hence, we had to better wait for five minutes. Later, we browsed the menu and decided to order three black sugar dumplings. The desert was actually a red bean paste with some glutinous dumplings and served with skim milk. The taste was somewhat close to the one we ate in Japan, though I was a bit disappointed about its freshness and coldness.
Enjoying the desert and chatting with my mates, I checked and was noticed that it cost us $125. What a surprising number. Nonetheless, I really liked the decoration and service there. Hoped that I can have the chance to try other delicacies. Recommended Dish(es): Okinawa black sugar Japanese dumplings treat
 Table Wait Time: 5 minute(s)

 Date of Visit: Dec 27, 2010
 Occasion: Anniversary
 Spending per head: Approximately HKD43
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 5 |  Environment 4 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 4 |  Value for Money 2 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 motherhen
 (Non-member) Expensive high class fast food store! Oct 22, 2010 
 
 We were excited as we step in, as this shop has positioned itself as a &apos;private&apos; kitchen (c-fong-choy)

We ordered a number of 4 meat dishes (they come in small size), 1 veg, 2 bowls of noodles for 2 adults and 2 young kids under 8.

The food is horrible.

Meat: Duck with sticky rice - It tastes like micro-waved, re-heated fried food. We can only taste oil and the batter (flour).

Noodles - worse than Nissan instant noodles. The $3.5 instant noodles taste better than their so-called hand made (?) noodles

Veg - spinach with garlic is ok, normal. The steam tou-fu has some perserved pickle on top, it is very salty.

The price tag came to HK$700 and is WAY OVER PRICED for the quality it delivers.

One time business for us!! No more. Date of Visit: Oct 19, 2010
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 1 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 3 |  Value for Money 1 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 1 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Peech 160 Review(s) One of the worst meals in recent memory May 27, 2010 
 
 I don&apos;t know how we ended up here, but what a mistake it turned out to be!

Cold tofu with shrimp and crab relish (蝦兵蟹將凍豆腐) - I took one bite and knew instantly it was gonna be a disaster. I was thinking to myself that the dried shrimps (蝦米) were some of the toughest I&apos;ve ever chewed on, when my friend blurted out the exact same thought.

Greenhouse tomatoes in wasabi sesame sauce (芥末胡麻醬拌日本溫室蕃茄) - one of two dishes that tasted OK.

Sichuan spicy chicken (招牌口水雞) - the only other dish that tasted OK to me. Nice chunks of cold chicken marinated with spicy vinegar, served with mung bean pappardelle, century eggs and some peanuts.

Crispy stuffed duck with glutinous rice (香酥糯米鴨) - this was so bad but somehow I ended up having two pieces, and I had to ask myself why I bothered with the second piece. These were really hard as bricks... the duck was tough, made into blocks with glutinous and deep-fried. My friends were smarter...they refused to eat a second piece.

Radish patty in XO sauce (囍宴XO醬炒蘿蔔糕) - another dish when it took one bite to know we&apos;re heading into disaster territory. The cubes of radish cake - stuffed with mushrooms and sausage - were hard. I ended up eating everything else but the radish cake.

Fried spring rolls with radish and dried oysters (原隻蠔豉蘿蔔絲春卷) - the only dish I ordered, and wasn&apos;t great either. While I liked the flavor of the dried oysters, the thing was just too salty.

This really was a disaster. I remember a time when a meal at Xĭ Yàn was something to look forward to. Has the franchise over-expanded to the point where quality control simply went out the window? After this meal, I can&apos;t imagine any of us wanting to come back. Ever.

original blogpost: http://chi-he-wan-le.blogspot.com/2010/05/definitely-not-happy-meal.html Date of Visit: May 27, 2010
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 1 |  Environment 3 |  Service 3 |  Hygiene 4 |  Value for Money 1 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 hohohob
 (Non-member) blackface service Feb 18, 2010 
 
 
we&apos;d been dining at Jacky&apos;s place since his early days of private dining in Wanchai; and were glad to see his cookery being appreciated by lots of people in past few years.
Yet we&apos;d come across a very bad experience in his XiYan shop in Elements for the service standard, either blackface or sleepy voices; and of course lukewarm food.

if this is the drop of standard is the inevitable price of business expansion, we believe Jacky definitely had to lose support of a group of loyal customers.

 Date of Visit: Feb 12, 2010
 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Random Nomad 30 Review(s) did i go to the right restaurant?? Aug 18, 2009 
 
 last weekend we hit elements mall for the first time not to watch a movie (the seating is along a steep slope so your view will not be blocked by the tall guy sitting in front, a very nice feature only available at cyberport, diamond hill and the director&apos;s clubs). it was only 4.30pm when we walked into xi yan, a casual dining room opened by local celebrity chef jacky yu. yu was an architect inspired by different cuisines savored on business travels and later decided to quit his job and focus on his private kitchen xi yan. at that time, fusion was still very new to hong kong and yu&apos;s restaurant became a success overnight, with a waiting list lasted as long as several months, although its popularity has declined dramatically in recent years after a plethora of fusion and molecular restaurants opened in hong kong.

there were only 2 people inside the restaurant, a gweilo and asian chick making out. we were seated 2 tables away from them and separated by a soundproof glass, but the very short distance (~7cm) between each table still allowed us to hear some words that we&apos;d rather not.

entree 1: jellyfish mixed with mustard and sesame sauce. i always like my jellyfish to go with mustard, and surprisingly both go very well with sesame sauce. this set a very high tone for our high tea.

plat principal 1: sichuan spicy chicken with preserved eggs and peanuts. they used chicken breast instead of thigh, which in my humble opinion was a terrible mistake because the chicken was poor quality and the chicken breast therefore was a bit soggy and tasted very bland even though the dish was seasoned with vinegar and soy sauce. unlike traditional sichuan chicken, it was a dry dish without an ocean of red chili oil sitting at the bottom.

plat principal 2: tan tan ramen. a lukewarm dish with LOTS of sesame sauce and peanut butter. so much sesame sauce that it was all i could taste.

the mustard jellyfish was the highlight of our meal and that was it. i read on openrice that the wanchai branch is supposed to be better. i haven&apos;t tried the flagship private kitchen or the wanchai shop yet, but it certain would take me some time to forget my catastrophic experience last week in order to try again.

P/S: i found an eyelash in my spicy chicken! what happened to the chefs nowadays?????

original post with pictures: http://randomnomad.wordpress.com/2009/08/18/xi-yan/ Spending per head: Approximately HKD120
 Other Ratings: 
Taste 3 |  Environment 2 |  Service 2 |  Hygiene 2 |  Value for Money 4 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 The Gourmet
 (Non-member) Xi Yan Favours is NOT the place you want . Dec 31, 2008 
 
 
I and my 2 friends went to 餐廳： 囍宴 滋‧選 Xi Yan Flavours in Elements and I would like to share my horrible experience there.
I have lived in HK for 8years and I am a foreigner who loves food so much and I have been so many famous restaurants in HK. I call myself as a gourmet definately !

Entered in the Xi Yan Favours : around 7PM
Ordered food : 4 dishes ( Price- Quite expensive for such kind of food quality&amp;taste but acceptable in Elements )
Drink : the waitress suggested refilled drinks, so two of my friends had ordered it.
Requested to pay the bill by the restaurant manager : From 7 :30PM and the manager said their booked customers arrived and asked us to pay and leave.
When I have complained strongly that even we never refilled the drink and nobody informed us we needed to leave when their other customers arrived.

I understand the restaurant does not have enough space and table for more customers and the manager could try to request customers to pay the bill who did finish their meal.
BUT the way to treat customers shouln&apos;t be with that way ! Xi Yan Flavours is not a fast food restaurant even. I have never expereinced those rude treatment in any of HK restaurants , even in ChaChanTeng.

Did I stay there for 2hours or 3hours ? $484 was too little to stay over 30mins ? There was totally no manner at all to treat customers.
Every each single dish was IMMEDITELY removed from the table as soon as we finished. Even I wanted some more left sauce from the dish , it was picked up by a waitress without asking us. When we finished main dishes and were enjoying our drinks , the watress and her manager started bringing the bill to make us feel so uncomfortable. When I insisted to stay little longer , she still kept looking at us to make us leave. and FINALLY I have paid at 7:43PM.

Who loves food and wants to enjoy elaborate food and comfortable atmosphere , I can tell you Xi Yan Favours is NOT the place you want . 
 
 Keep it up!
 

 Looking Forward 
 
 Interesting
 
 Touched
 
 Envy
 
 Cool Photo
 
 3 Vote(s) View Results Recommend Message (0) | Leave a Comment | Report 0 Back To Top 
 
 Home | Restaurant Search | Review | Coupon | Recipe | Forum 
 Mobile OpenRice | OpenRice in Chinese | OpenRice Travel | Online Restaurant Reservations | 开饭喇 
 Member Registration | Submit Restaurant Info | About Us | Editor&apos;s Blog | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Site Map OpenRice.com is Hong Kong&apos;s most popular dining guide to help people find places to eat based on the restaurant reviews written by real local people. OpenRice also offers restaurant discount coupons , food delivery directory and recipes .Through our Hong Kong restaurant search engine, users can easily find their desired dining places by districts such as Central restaurants , Causeway Bay restaurants , TST restaurants and cuisines such as French restaurants , Italian restaurants , Chinese restaurants , Japanese restaurants , and buffet . 
Copyright©1999-2012 Openrice Group Inc. All Rights Reserved.
 Hong Kong&apos;s Most Popular Dining Guide,
with restaurant search, restaurants reviews, and dining coupons. 
 Other Group Products 


 
 Gourmet Feed 
 Sorry, no information Loading 
 Quick Display of Restaurants 

 Restaurants Around Living Area Restaurants Around Working Area 
 My Favorite Restaurants 
 
 Share this page: Quick Display of Restaurants:
	</body>
</document>
