<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003360" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/317632-how-many-calories-in-a-1-2-cup-soft-serve-ice-cream/" time="2012-07-12-19:30" support="2" score="0.0014304074076201445" bingtitle="How Many Calories In A 1/2-cup Soft Serve Ice Cream? | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="How Many Calories In A 1/2-cup Soft Serve Ice Cream? | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>Ice cream is an icon of American culture, with per ... small cone of soft serve ice cream at a local fast food restaurant ... guide at any restaurant before placing your order if ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Calories in Desserts&amp;Snacks Calories in Soft Serve How Many Calories in a 1/2-Cup Soft Serve Ice Cream? 
 
 How Many Calories in a 1/2-Cup Soft Serve Ice Cream? 
 Dec 20, 2011 | By Jennifer Hartford Photo Credit Jupiterimages/Photos.com/Getty Images 
Ice cream is an icon of American culture, with per-capita ice cream consumption in the U.S. at about 5 1/2 gallons in 2005. The calories in ice cream varies depending on ingredients and additives in each type of ice cream.
 
French Vanilla

Most French vanilla ice creams are enhanced with the thickness, color and flavor of eggs. This adds more fat and calories. The benefit of choosing soft-serve is that it contains less milk fat and more air than hard ice creams. A half-cup of French vanilla soft serve has 191 calories.
 
Dairy Queen

Half a cup of Dairy Queen soft serve ice cream without the cone contains 140 calories, according to the American Dairy Queen website. A child-size cone, weighing 99 g, has 140 calories, while the small cone, 147 g, has 270 calories.
 
Small Cone

Katharine Branham, writer for the Nutrition Guide on the Food Reference website, states that a small cone of soft serve ice cream at a local fast food restaurant was equal to 135 calories. Katharine advises checking out the nutrition guide at any restaurant before placing your order if calories are of concern. Food establishments often have detailed guides available or a manager can direct you to one.
 
References

 Food Reference: Ice Cream McDonald&apos;s: Nutrition Calculator Food Reference: Nutrition Guide Dairy Queen: Nutrition Guide 
 
Article reviewed by Brian Peters Last updated on: Dec 20, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Calories in a Soft Serve Ice Cream Cone 
 
 Soft Serve Ice Cream Nutrition Facts 
 
 Nutritional Facts for a Soft Serve Ice Cream Cone 
 
 Calories in Peach Soft Serve Ice Cream 
 
 How Many Calories Are in Fat-Free, Sugar-Free Soft Serve Ice Cream? 
 
 How Many Calories are in a Small Soft Serve Chocolate Cone? 
 
 How Many Calories Are in a Soft Serve Cone? 
 
 Nutrition Information for Soft Serve Ice Cream 
 
 Soft Serve or Regular Ice Cream: Which Has Less Calories? 
 
 How Many Calories in a DQ Frozen Ice Cream Cake? 
 
 Chocolate Soft Serve Ice Cream Nutritional Facts 
 
 Can Pregnant Women Eat Soft Serve Ice Cream? 
 
 Soft Serve Ice Cream and Pregnancy 
 
 How Many Calories are in Braums Soft Serve? 
 
 Why Do I Get Diarrhea After I Eat Soft Serve Ice Cream? 
 
 Calories in TCBY Soft Serve 
 
 Calories in Peach Soft-Serve 
 
 Baskin Robbins&apos; Soft Serve Nutrition 
 
 How Many Calories in One Scoop of Ice Cream Strawberry Cheesecake? 
 
 Weight Loss With Ice Cream 
 more Food Manager advertisement 
 You May Also Be Interested In 
 How Many Calories in Soft Serve Ice Cream Half Cup of Ice Cream 1/2 Cup Ice Cream 1/2 Cup of Ice Cream Calories in Hard Ice Cream Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
