<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003504" url="http://www.thesnowconestand.com/blog/" time="2012-07-12-19:39" support="1" score="0.0015143165708678922" bingtitle="Blog | The Snow Cone Stand" webtitle="Blog | The Snow Cone Stand">
			<query id="000401" bing-rank="132"/>
	<description>Even opening something as simple as an ice cream shop, fast food restaurant, or boutique will require the average individual to take out a significant loan.</description>
	<body>
		Home Blog Ebook About 
 Privacy Policy 
 Advertise Here Contact 
 0 
 Snow Cones Machines and Ice Shavers–TheSnowConeStand 
 Posted July 12th, 2011 in Uncategorized by admin 
It’s extremely important that you purchase a quality and reliable snow cone machine that will meet the individual needs of your snow cone stand.

There are two basic types of shavers: cube and block.

Cube ice shavers mean that you are using ice cubes that would come out of any freezer. Block ice literally means very large blocks of ice. Block ice varies have two basic shapes that depend on the two main types of machines you buy.“New Orleans”style block ice are rectangular and weigh roughly 10 to 14 lbs.“Hawaiian”style shaved ice are squat cylinders weighing around 7 lbs. Obviously it is much easier to keep cubed ice on hand, but to ha ve a real, quality snow cone (or shaved ice) then you need to go with the block shaver.

 New Orleans Style Snow Cone Machines (Ice Shavers) are horizontal and bulkier than the Hawaiian style. With the New Orleans style machine, the blades move while the block of ice remains stationary. The blocks of ice used in these machines are roughly rectangular, weighing around 10 to 14 lbs. These machines are stainless steel and will outlast most snow cone owners. That’s why you don’t see a lot of them for sale used. These machines function by using a lever to put pressure on the ice against the blades. The ice then comes out on the right.

 Hawaiian Style Block Machines (right) are more upright or vertical. It shaves round blocks of ice that are roughly 7” in diameter and weigh up to 7 lbs. With Hawaiian Style block ice shavers, the blade remains stationary and the block of ice moves, rotating against the blade. The “Corkscrew” nickname originates from the rotating shaft that applies pressure to the ice block. Instead of a spout like the New Orleans Block Ice shaver, the ice from the Hawaiian Style machines simply falls straight down from the blade. The ice is either caught in a cup or in the operator’s gloved hand. With Hawaiian style block ice shavers, the machine applies the pressure against the rotating block of ice, not the operator making it easier to train new employees. Our most popular Hawaiian Style Block ice Shaver is the Swan SI-100E block ice shaver.

 

A block ice shaver

Obviously keeping a steady supply of cubed ice is

In terms of fluffiness, we often compare the snow cones and the shaved ice on a

 “Fluffiness Rank” from one to ten. One being chunks of ice and ten being like snow. Shaved ice would rank anywhere from a 7 to a 9 depending on the machine you are using (more about this later in the book). Snow cones would rank around a 5 or a 6. You will see our Ice Scale ranking for all of our machines later in this manual. Remember the scale, 10 is like snow and 1 is like chunks of ice.

The following are a few questions you need to ask yourself when deciding which ice shaver is best for your business:

 Is block ice available in your area?  Otherwise you’ll have to buy an expensive block maker or use molds  a cube ice shaver may be your  best choice. If you still prefer a block ice shaver you can make your own ice
blocks with an expensive machine or make blocks manually in a freezer. This requires very large freezer room and enough molds to rotate them on a regular basis. Freezing an ice block requires several days minimum. Who are your customers? The more repeat the customers need to be then the more quality the product needs to be (customer loyalty). A cube shaver is not a good idea for a neighborhood stand. You may get away with this at fairs and festivals for only a day or 2 at a time. How fast do you need to make your shaved ice? While quality is much lower with a cubed machine, it works a lot quicker. You can’t use a block shaver at near the same pace. Is size an issue (or how mobile do you have to be)? A block shaver is large and heavy while cubed ones tend to be much smaller and plastic. How easy of use are you looking for (or how many people will be using it) ? New Orleans style have a bit more of a learning curve. How durable does your machine need to be? This means stainless steel versus plastic. New Orleans style last forever. 

I hope these questions have shed some light and the information provided helps you make a decision. If you found this post helpful, please link to us on your facebook, blogs, or anywhere else. We are trying to reach the top of google.

Thanks,

TheSnowConeStand
 0 
 Daily Duties or How to Make Sure Your Employees Do Their Jobs 
 Posted November 18th, 2010 in Employees , Operating by admin 
 

One of the easiest ways to ensure that your stand is opened and closed consistently, regardless of what employees are working, is to create a standard checklist . These lists should be posted in stand with a clear set of chronological steps to be carried out in the morning at open, at night when you close, and any other specified times of the day.  An example of a solid checklist might be as follows:

 When You Open 

1. Please arrive 30 mintues prior to the time the stand is supposed to open.

2. Turn on the AC.

3. Make sure the tables and chairs are out and neat.

4. Make sure our banners, signs, and lights are clean and in place.

5. Do any necessary cleaning (inside/outside, fridge, freezer, ice shaver, etc…)

A. Wipe down the inside and outside counters

B. Clean up any trash in the parking lots

C. Make sure any seats and tables are clear and dry

5. Mop the floor and clean anything else left.

6. Check that all supplies are adequately stocked and in place. This includes cups,

spoons, napkins, straws, lids, and toppings.

7. Check for ice and syrup adequate for the day.

8. Check that there is adequate cash and change for the day.

9. Call “the owner/manager” about inventory that may be need restocking.

10. Turn the open/closed sign at the correct time.

11. If you expect immediate customers, make sure to temper the ice.

 When You Close 

1. Turn off signs and lights.

2. Clean EVERYTHING.

A. wipe down all surfaces inside stand – walls, countertops, refrigerator, freezer, shelves and the outside counter.

B. Clean shaved ice shaver (inside and out)

C. Wipe down all bottles and jugs

D. Clean refrigerator and freezers.

E. Wipe down tables and chairs for stick syrup.

6. Check all inventory again. If anything is low, call owner (more ice or syrup).

9. Take out trash and put in new bags.

11. Sweep and mop the floor.

12. Turn the lights and AC off.

13. Lock EVERYTHING.

14. DOUBLE CHECK YOU LOCKED EVERYTHING!

Now what I’ve written above is just an example checklist that we used at one stand I was running based on the individual needs of the stand. You may have a completely different set of ideas, but the main point is to make your expectations for your employees to be as transparent and straight forward as possible. You want to be fair to them by making it clear what you expect, and to keep your employees from saying they didn’t know what was required to do their job.

A snow cone stand is not a complicated business, but it is a business nonetheless. Almost any business with repetitive processes should standardize them as much as possible and provide a manual or checklist to ensure your standards are applied. This is more important than every if you do not plan on regularly working the daily hours of open and close for your stand.
 0 
 22 Questions from Entrepreneur.com for Your Snow Cone Stand Location 
 Posted November 16th, 2010 in Location by admin 
 

 Entrepreneur.com has put out 22 questions that every business should ask itself when considering the best location for a retail business. Check out my favorite 10 below or click here to get the entire list.

Answering these questions for each of the sites you’re considering can help you decide on the best retail location for your business:

 Are the lease terms and rent favorable? Is the location convenient to where you live? Can you find a number of qualified employees in the area in which the facility is located? Do people you want for customers live nearby? Is the population density of the area sufficient for your sales needs? Is the facility located in a safe neighborhood with a low crime rate? Is exterior lighting in the area adequate to attract evening shoppers and make them feel safe? Are neighboring businesses likely to attract customers who will also patronize your business? Are there any competitors located close to the facility? If so, can you compete with them successfully? Is the facility easily accessible to your potential customers? Is parking space available and adequate? 
 0 
 What Products to Sell in Your Snow Cone Stand? 
 Posted November 16th, 2010 in concession , Products by admin 
 
 
 

 

There’s no hard and fast rule to what you can sell in your snow cone stand. In fact, you may not even consider your business to be a “snow cone stand”. You may have a concession stand, food cart, concession trailer, or any other number of options. If you have a food cart, then snow cones may be an afterthought. But many concession stands that don’t sell food may have any number of options they want to employ.

Ice cream, lemonade, soft drinks, milk shakes, pickles, sundaes, chips and candy are all options for your stand. Going beyond snow cones can be a smart decision to diversity your revenue streams and potentially bring in new customers. It’s important to note that these various options have different prices and profit margins. Some of the bulkier items also take up a more significant amount of room than the materials for a snow cone. Drinks almost always have very high profit margins (in excess of 90%) as well as some food times. Others may be as low as 20-30%. I would like to note in this article we are not talking about items that require cooking such as corn dogs and nachos all the way up to entire meals. We’ll save a post on that for a later date.

The items you choose to sell should reflect your location and customer base. You also need to consider the additional costs, headaches, and cleanup of more products. Often time more products doesn’t equal more profit and can be more hassle. If you do decide to introduce additional products I suggest trying 1 or 2 at a time and tracking sales and profits for at least a month before taking on more. Below are some margin ranges for various items.

 

 
 0 
 Top 5 Reasons to Start a Snow Cone Stand 
 Posted November 15th, 2010 in Operating by admin 
 

 1.  You can start a snow cone business with no debt 

For many 1 st time entrepreneurs the biggest barrier to entry is either a lack of funds, or a fear of taking out debt that you won’t be able to pay back. In any business there is always a risk of failure and no one wants to risk bankruptcy. Even opening something as simple as an ice cream shop, fast food restaurant, or boutique will require the average individual to take out a significant loan.

Snow cone stands are a business than can be realistically be started for as little as $5,000 and as much as $20,000 depending on how thrifty an individual wants to be. If you are a 1 st time entrepreneur this can be a great way for you to dip your toes in the water without spending your life savings or getting into debt. 

 2.  Snow Cone Stands are scalable 

As mentioned above it is possible to start a snow cone stand for a very reasonable price. $5,000 to start your 1 st business is about as great of a bargain as you can possibly find. Just as many fast food restaurant entrepreneurs continue to fund new restaurants with profits from the old, the same thing can be done with snow cone stands. In fact, it’s easier with snow cone stands than with any other business I know of.

In a typical summer it is completely reasonable to expect to make $5-25,000 in profit, particularly if you are working the stand yourself at least some portion of the time. If this is the case and you continue to be frugal in your capital investments, then you could realistically open at least 1 new snow cone stand each season. With a little time and experience it wouldn’t be impossible to be opening several each season.

 3.  Snow cone stands have a straight-forward business model 

The business is not only scalable from a financial standpoint, but also from a management standpoint. Snow cone stands are simple enough to run that hiring high school kids to work is a common practice. With a few quality employees an owner can run 3 or 4 snow cone stands as easily as a 1. The main work of an owner is making/delivering ice, mixing/delivering syrup, collecting deposits and making payroll. When an owner already has to make ice and mix syrup it doesn’t take much additional time to do this for several stands.

 

 4.  It’s a business you can run in your spare time. 

If you are less ambitious than the type of owners above, then this may just be a business to run in your spare time. If you work a normal 40 hour per week like many of us, then this may be the perfect side-project. Once you are up and running then it is not an issue to hire high-school kids to work during the day and then take care of anything necessary during the evening. The stand I owned most recently was worked by high school kids during the day and weekends, while I gave a percentage of profits to a friend in order to make ice and syrup, pay the rent and payroll, and make deposits. I was running this business putting in less than 10 hours per week.

 5.  Snow Cone Stands have an extremely high cash margin. 

A typical snow cone costs between $2 and $4.50. The cost of goods sold (COGS) of a snow cone include ice, syrup, cup, spoon, straw and napkin. This amount does not include labor, rent, utilities or any other fixed cost.

When you buy supplies in bulk these costs should average no more than 20 to 30 cents per snow cone. At this point you have gross profit of anywhere from $1.75 to over $4 for each snow cone. Then you simply need to sell enough to pay for the month’s labor, rent and utilities.

A solid rule of thumb provided by the 1-800-shaved-ice is to multiply each ounce of a cup by $0.02. Therefore a 12-ounce snow cone would have COGS of roughly 24 cents.
 0 
 the New York Times Talks Snow Cones 
 Posted November 10th, 2010 in Flavor Guide by admin 
 

 Great article in the New York Times about snow cone’s around the world. The author talks about the various names, types, flavors, and recipes. They also discuss some pretty interesting all natural snow cone stands in the US that avoid high fructose corn syrup and artificial flavoring.

Enjoy!
 1 
 Picking a Snow Cone Stand Location 
 Posted November 3rd, 2010 in Location , Operating by admin 
 

In the first part of this series we discussed new versus used stands, mobile versus immobile , and where to buy a stand . In this post we will assume you’ve made that purchase and will be looking for your first location.

So now that you’ve bought your first snow cone stand, I hope you have considered where you intend to locate your new business. Every situation, town and city will be different, so I can’t tell you exactly where you should put your stand, but I can give you some general guidelines and things to consider when making this decision. It’s time to put location at the top of your to-do list. If you’re preparing to open a food or retail business with a storefront, putting your business in the proper location might be the single most important thing you do at startup.

 Location, Location, Location 

In the late 1800’s the late Lord Harold Samuel, a real estate tycoon in Britain, coined the expression: ‘There are three things that matter in property: location, location, location” and that statement still holds true today. Nothing is more important to the success of your stand than the location that you find for your stand.

Of course location isn’t the only issue. You need a quality product, a clean, an inviting stand, and friendly staff. You also need quality, bright, visible signage. But of course none of this will do you any good if you are in an out of the way location or can’t be seen from the road. Careful determination of new sites is critical for most retail and consumer service businesses. Below are some of the things you should consider.

 Demographics 

This can be simple or complicated, but for your basic snow cone stand a little common sense is all you really need. There are software tools that will give you traffic patterns, demographic information and other data, but if you are putting your stand in your own area then you should already have a good idea of where you need to be considering locating your stand.

The major demographic you should be looking for is young families with children or high school kids who can drive. Elementary, middle, and high schools are great places to be near, as well as public parks, pools, and children’s sports complexes. High traffic areas with shopping (such as malls), restaurants, and stores are another important indicator. Depending on your city foot traffic or vehicle traffic will be much more important. Another leading indicator is if there are other kid friendly businesses in the area. Is there an ice cream shop, toy store, or chucky cheese.

Once you’ve ascertained the obvious areas you should be considering then you need to test your locations to see what will actually work best. The easiest way to do this is to just go out, park in the location and watch the traffic. Do you see as many cars as you hoped? Are there lots of kids running around the local park? Are moms and kids coming in and out of the local store? Just sitting and watching on both a weekday and a Saturday can be best way to really get to know an area.

 Leasing and Renting 

Your job isn’t done once you think you’ve found a promising area. Hopefully there is more than one parking lot or corner area that you think would be suitable for your needs. If this is the case then you need to begin the process of contacting the owners and negotiating a lease. Your rental agreement is almost as important as the location itself. A quality landlord can make this a great experience, but a less scrupulous one can cause you a lot of stress and hurt your bottom line.

I’ve found there are two types of business owners one can deal with: individual, small business owners and major chains. You will almost always find it much easier to work with a small business owner. You can typically deal with the owner personally and the rental income you bring in will go straight into their pocket. With a major chain, the decision to rent parking lot space is often handled by a corporate office. In this case you can’t simply walk into your local Wal-Mart, Target, or Best Buy, speak with the manager and draw up a lease agreement. You will be forced to call the corporate office, attempt to find the correct department and individual you need to deal with, and then hope they are nice enough to call you back. The person on the other end of the line has no incentive to do the extra work to make you a deal. He won’t see the money and this will just be extra work for them. There are also a number of chains that have a general policy of not dealing with small businesses or renting out parking lot space.

I would like to give you an idea of how much you should pay for rent, but that is extremely dependent on your individual cities and locations. In my experience $250-400 has been considered reasonable rent but this may not be the case in your area. Ask around to other stands and be sure to get a good idea of the going rate to ensure you aren’t being ripped off. Also be sure to outline if the rental agreement includes the cost of electricity to your stand and the method in which you will be getting your power (by generator, plug-in, or your own line). Other issues that are easy to forget are where you can empty your water tanks, dump your trash, where your customers can park, and the hours you can have the stand open. While you might think the answer to these questions is obvious, a landlord may have different ideas. If you don’t spell this out then a different set of ideas may cause you a great deal of extra work.

You must be aware of all the location costs that can be involved in starting your business. This knowledge will do you great good when problems may arise.  When it comes to starting a business, underestimating the costs and the time involved in is one of the most common and dangerous mistakes new entrepreneurs make, as well as one of the easiest to avoid.

 Conclusion 

There is no perfect answer, but the best advice I can give is to do your homework. Know the city, the area, and the particular location. Test all your assumptions. Check out your exact locations. Good luck and please give a comment if you found this helpful.
 1 
 Buying A Snow Cone Stand – Where to Look? 
 Posted November 1st, 2010 in Buying by admin 
 

So in part 1 and part 2 we discussed what type of snow cone stand to buy and if we should get a new or used one. In this short post we will talk about where to look in order to purchase your first snow cone stand. We have some suggestions you may not find elsewhere and a pretty comprehensive list of websites.

 New Trailers 

 SnowWizard.com 

Snow Wizard has a number of its own brand new trailers that it has for sale. This is one of the better quality websites you will find to view these snow cone stands. Many of the companies in this business badly need an update and better information. Snow Wizard is a nice change from that. Snow Wizard has a SW-710 (7×10) for $20,000 and an SW-714 (7×14) for $23,000 with a large number of options and add-ons. The site also sells start-up packages, shavers, ice makers, syrup and every other option you could need.

 1-800-Shaved-Ice.com 

There are a number of great places to buy a new snow cone stand.  One site that has a pretty comprehensive number of trailers is 1-800-shaved-ice.com. The site offers 4 large trailer options ranging from $12,000 for a 6 x 10 sno-balls shaved ice trailer to $55,000 their “deluxe shaved ice caboose”. The site also offers syrups, snow cone machines/ice shavers, and entire business start-up packages.

 FrigidFrog.com 

The frigidfrog.com also offers a large number of quality trailers ranging from $13,000 for a 6 x 10 up to a $17,000 trailer for a 6 x 14 trailer. The site also offers a large number of add-on’s customizations, ice shavers, and complete business packages.

 SouthernSnow.com 

Southern Snow is another quality option for purchase a snow cone trailer. The company offers similar packages to the two options above, with 6×10 trailers for $13,000 up to a 6 x 14 trailer for $17,000. The company does not offer the comprehensive options that the two above offer, but have a number of add-ons.

 Snowie.com 

Snowie.com sells its own unique brand of snow cone stands. They have a different but unique look. These include their brand new “school bus” option, and 8×5 trailer, 12×5 trailer, and a 10×7 trailer. The stands all have custom graphics, rounded edges, and clear windows all the way around.

 

 Used Trailers 

 Ebay 

Obviously a great place to find anything (snow cone stands included) is Ebay. On the site you can find hundreds of listings from all over the country. The advantage is you can see the ratings of the sellers and the descriptions are usually pretty good. The major disadvantage is that you can’t typically view the stand before putting up the cash. If you decided you don’t like it after pick-up then you may be between a rock and a hard place.

You can also use Ebay to get an idea of how much stands have gone for in the past. If you go to advanced search and click completed listings then only auctions that have ended will be shown. You can see what stands didn’t sell and what did (and for what price).

 Craigslist 

Craigslist is my personal favorite for finding snow cone stands and trailers. The site may be ugly, but its free to list on so its very popular with small business people. Head to the “ for sale ” section, and click “ business ” if you want to search just your local area.

If your interested in searching on a regional or national business I suggest heading over the www.craiglook.com . Craiglook will give you better search options. You can specify price range, location, and even number of miles to a location. So you could search for snow cone stands under $10,000 and within 50 miles radius of Dallas. The site will also show pictures in your search which doesn’t happen on craigslist own search engine.

 Concessiontraileroutlet.com 

Concessiontraileroutlet.com is another great site to check out. The website doesn’t sell any trailers itself but rather looks up all types of concession trailers/stands that are currently listed on ebay and putting them in an easy to read and compare format. Rather than the sites for brand

 FestivalsandFairs.com 

FestivalsandFairs.com is a great place to look for used trailers. They list not only snow cone stands but also massive concession trailers for year-round traveling as well as food carts, concession stands, and other types. The site also lists 100’s of upcoming events around the country by date and state.

 Concessiontrailers.com 

Concessiontrailers.com is a pretty neat place to look for used concession trailers (not just snow cone stands). The site breaks the country down into regions that you can click through to find used concession trailers in your area.  They have a pretty solid number of listings.

 Other 

 CustomConcessions.com 

CustomConcessions.com is a site that actually sells the very large, brand new concession stands for year round traveling (mainly at fairs). This isn’t really for snow cones but if your in the market for a bit of a larger scale business then be sure to check it out.

 SupremeProducts.com 

Supreme Products is another company that does custom concession stands. Not snow cone stands but a cool site to check out.

 Benscarts.com 

Benscarts.com is a great site to get your own hotdog cart or stand.

 Conclusion 

So where should you go to find that snow cone stand? It depends on whether you want to buy used or new. But my suggestion is to first head to Craigslist and Ebay to get a decent idea of what the price ranges are both in your area and nationwide. If you haven’t found what you are looking for there then head over the some of the sites listed above.

By the way, if any of the site owners above are reading this post and are interested in advertising with us, please just send us a note in the contact section.
 1 
 Buying a Snow Cone Stand – New or Used? 
 Posted November 1st, 2010 in Buying by admin 
 
 

In our last post we talked about whether or not to buy a mobile snow cone stand or an immobile snow shack . In today’s post we will talk about whether or not to go buy a new stand or used.

When considering a used versus a new snow cone stand our first consideration is price. 90% of the time an immobile shack will be much cheaper to purchase than a stand on wheels. Mobile stands take much more money to build in order to make them roadworthy. A typical price range for a building can be as low as $3,000 all the way up to $10,000. A typical mobile trailer can range as low as $4,000 but is more typically $8-15,000. So if you are on a budget then you already know you should probably be looking at the cheaper option .

 Mobile Snow Cone Stand 

If budget isn’t your only concern then there are other factors to consider. For a stand-alone shack I will almost always recommend buying used. A brand new shack can easily cost double a used one, while the differences will be extremely minimal. A snow cone stand is a typically a simple wooden structure, similar to a tool shed. The only difference being that it has been ran for electricity and a closed water system has been added. These 2 additions take very little maintenance or upkeep and are unlikely to need serious maintenance after only a few years in use. Because the buildings are so simple there is really no reason to buy a new stand.

A second option for these snow cone stands is to build it yourself . While this is a project well beyond my own personal skill (and many of my readers), I don’t doubt there are quite a few of mechanically inclined individuals who could follow the simple instructions necessary to take a storage building and turn it into a snow cone shack.

Obviously you can always go with the third option to buy new. This has the typcial advantages of knowing exactly where your stand is coming from, often getting a warranty, and knowing where to go if you have any issues. When buying a used stand you have no recourse if the plumbing breaks or the electricity starts to be a problem.

 Snow Cone Trailer 

A mobile snow cone stand is an entirely different prospect from a stand-alone building.  You certainly can’t build one yourself, and there are a few reasons to consider a brand new option. Price differences between used and new stands are much tighter when it comes to quality mobile trailers. If you are able to find a quality used trailer for a good deal then by all means make that purchase. But if the price difference is very close then you may want to consider buying the trailer straight from the dealer. A brand new snow cone stand from the dealer has several advantages. Unlike with used cars, there are no carfax reports for a snow cone stand. So buying straight from the source means you know that the stand is in perfect condition and should run without issue. While a used stand may look great, buyers beware. Just like a used car, it may have problems under the hood that aren’t readily apparent. While this isn’t likely, there is something nice about getting a brand new vehicle that you know has no issues and should work long-term.

 Time horizon is another consideration. If you are buying a snow cone stand for your high school son or daughter, and plan to sell it when they leave for college, then a used trailer should be your choice. If this is a long-term business that you plan on running for decades to come, then a new trailer will likely be the better bet.

 Conclusion 

So what type of stand should you buy? Is that new car smell worth it, or do you go with a quality used option. Being a finance guy, I tend to look at it from an RIO ( Return on Investment ) standpoint. When you consider ROI, the lower your cost of investment, the higher your return. Or in other words, if you buy a trailer for $8,000 and you make $8,000 for the summer then you broke even. If you bought the trailer for $5,000 and made $8,000 then you turned a decent profit. When it comes down to it this is a business. You don’t need to be thinking about what’s shiny and new. You need to think about the bottom line and that’s what brings the best return, or what is your best bang for your buck. So while there is a time and a place for a new stand, when in doubt, go used.
 4 
 Buying a Snow Cone Stand – Mobile or Fixed? 
 Posted October 27th, 2010 in Buying by admin 
 

 

So you’ve decided to purchase a snow cone stand. Congratulations! You are on your way to having you very own profitable, small business.

The first step in buying a snow cone stand is determining what type of stand you are interested in purchasing. Your options break down into 2 simple categories:

 Mobile Snow Cone Trailers Non-Mobile Structures (Snow Shacks)
 

Each of these two options has its advantages and disadvantages. The first thing to determine is what do you plan to do with your trailer? What is your business model? If you haven’t thought about it, then it’s the first thing you need to do. I suggest getting out a piece of paper and really writing down what your goals are. Here are some example questions to ask yourself.

 Do have plan to have a permanent location for the stand (even over the winter)? Do you plan to move the stand in and out of a summer location each year? Do you plan to regularly visit fairs, festivals and other events? Do you hope to be able to do events in the future? Do you want very simple and easy mobility? Do you want a large amount of space and room inside? What is your budget? 

What should you buy? Well that depends on each business individual’s funds, needs, plans, and location options. I hope you think about these 4 issues and the questions above when considering what type of stand to buy. Depending on the answers to these questions, you should get an idea of what type of snow cone stand you are looking to purchase.

 Mobile Snow Cone Trailers 

 

If mobility is of the utmost importance to you, then you have to go with a mobile trailer. Mobile trailers can be used in a permanent location, for regular traveling, or just getting a chance to work your local summer fairs. This can also be used in cities that allow a snow cone stand to set up almost anywhere. In this way you can work different spots during different times of the day, or on weekends.

These snow cone trailers range in size from a 5×10 to 6×14. A 5×10 trailer is going to be more suited to a single worker and a little less high volume. One of the primary disadvantages of many mobile snow cone stands is the size. A stand-along shack is always going to allow more room. If your budget allows we would always suggest going with the larger size because it allows for 2 workers. When your really busy (such as at a fair) then you will be able to move much quicker with 2 individuals.

From a budget standpoint, mobile stands are almost always more expensive than a standalone building. This is due to the obvious reasons that it costs quite a bit of money to build a business on wheels. You will have to contrast the additional cost of a mobile stand compared to the benefits you believe you will receive.

 

 Non-Mobile Snow Cone Shacks 

 

Not-mobile snow cone shacks can also be a great option for your new business! These buildings do not have the advantage of moving from location to location but are typically much cheaper and require less upkeep.

A shaved ice building or location can be set up in one of two ways. The building can be put in as permanent structure or as a temporary structure. Obviously these two options will depend upon each individual’s factors and where your location is. If you are putting a stand on your own property then a more permanent structure may be a better option. If you are renting or have to move the stand each winter then it’s likely you will want a temporary structure.

The buildings themselves will be the same, but the way in which you put them on the ground will vary. Typically with a temporary location you will put down concrete blocks and set the stand down in this spot.

To transport a mobile building at the beginning and end of each season you will need to own or rent a large flat-bed truck. A trailer behind a truck will not typically work because a snow cone trailer is wider than the railing on each side. You will also need quite a few strong hands and driver who knows what he is doing in order to lift and lower the building. This should only be done with all the equipment (besides freezes and fridges) removed, and all ice removed from the freezers. If this sounds to daunting or not worth the hassle, then make sure you have a long-term location or consider a mobile snow cone stand.

 

 Conclusions 

So which should you choose? Well that depends on each business individual’s funds, needs, plans, and location options. I hope you think about these 4 issues when considering what type of stand to buy. Good luck!

In the next post we’ll be discussing buying used versus new and where to look for a snow cone stand.
 «Older Entries 
Advertise Here
 Advertise
Here   
Partners
 
Ebook
 
The SnowConeStand&apos;s Ebook is the #1 guide to creating your snow cone stand business. We will walk you through step by step the entire process, from buying a stand, navigating government regulation, to mixing syrups and shaving ice.

Click above to check out the details!
 
Welcome to TheSnowConeStand
 
Categories

 Buying concession Employees Flavor Guide Location Operating Portfolio Products Uncategorized 
 
Recent Posts

 Snow Cones Machines and Ice Shavers–TheSnowConeStand Daily Duties or How to Make Sure Your Employees Do Their Jobs 22 Questions from Entrepreneur.com for Your Snow Cone Stand Location What Products to Sell in Your Snow Cone Stand? Top 5 Reasons to Start a Snow Cone Stand 
 
Partners
 
Archives

 July 2011 November 2010 October 2010 
 
Tags
 all natural buying concession stand flavors international location opening a snow cone stand open snow cone stand picking a location product options snow cone snow cone business snow cone stand snow cone stand location snow cone trailer 
Search
 
 Home Blog Ebook About Advertise Here Contact 
 ©2009 The Snow Cone Stand. All rights reserved.
Theme by SmashingMagazine and Slimmity
	</body>
</document>
