<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003745" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/is-the-restaurant-wasabi-japanese-or-chinese-food" time="2012-07-12-19:54" support="2" score="0.012139099231512903" bingtitle="Is the restaurant wasabi japanese or chinese food? | ChaCha" webtitle="Is the restaurant wasabi japanese or chinese food? | ChaCha">
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>... most famous in form of a green paste used as condiment ... What should i order from the chinese restaurant? ... What is the most popular non fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
Is the restaurant wasabi japanese or chinese food? 

In: Lifestyle › Dining Out › Restaurant 
 
Rate This Answer
 
Wasabi is Japanese horseradish. It is most famous in form of a green paste used as condiment for sashimi (raw seafood) and sushi. 
 Answered

 
 - 238 days ago at 10:39pm on Nov 16 2011 
Related Restaurant Questions

 
 What restaurant will hire a 16 year old? 

A lot of places will hire a 16yr old. As long a...

in Lifestyle | 2 days ago via Android app 
 
 What are some Halloween restaurants? 

Not sure about Halloween restaurants, but IHOP ...

in Lifestyle | 10 days ago via web 
 
 What is the best restaurant in Chicago today? 

Aline a is located at 1723 N Hals-ted St Chicag...

in Lifestyle | 10 days ago via Android app 
 
 What restaurant should i go eat at? 

What are you in the mood for?

in Lifestyle | 10 days ago via web 
 
 What is the best restaurant in downtown Indianapolis? 

Maxine&apos;s Chicken and Waffles has phone number (...

in Lifestyle | 10 days ago via sms text 
 
 Chinese restaurant angola, new york? 

Angola China Kitchen - 167 North Main Street,An...

in Lifestyle | 13 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is a good restaurant in Wichita, Kansas? 

Carrabba&apos;s Italian Grill is highly rated. It is...

in Lifestyle | 17 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is the best Chinese restaurant in Indiana? 

P.F. Chang&apos;s China Bistro is located at 49 W Ma...

in Lifestyle | 19 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What are Restaurants at Western Kentucky University, 1906 College Heights Blvd, Bowling Green KY 42101? 

Papa John&apos;s Pizza - 1 Big Red Way, Bowling Gree...

in Lifestyle | 33 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Who owns the restaurant The Meat Shop? 

Lee Markholt owns The Meat Shop in Tacoma. It i...

in Lifestyle | 44 days ago via web 
 
 What is the best restaurant to eat in Kap? 

I&apos;m not sure what you mean about eating&quot;in Kap...

in Lifestyle | 72 days ago via web 
 
 What is the best restaurant in Bellevue, Washington? 

One of the best restaurants is Bis On Main. It ...

in Lifestyle | 76 days ago via web 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Week&apos;s Popular Questions for Restaurant 

 
 What kind of food does the Canlis restaurant serve? 

Canlis serves a high end quality of American cu...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via web 
 
 What is a good restaurant in fond du lac, wi? 

Ala Roma, 504 N. Rolling Meadows Dr, Fond du La...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via sms text 
 
 Does the fast food restaurant Wendy&apos;s have WiFi? 

Yes. Each Wendy&apos;s location will be equipped wit...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via sms text 
 
 Where is a 24 hour restaurant? 

Little Purity (718) 369-1722 390 7th Ave Brookl...

in Dining Out | 7 days ago via sms text 
 
 Does T&apos;s Thai restaurant in Santa Monica, California have good reviews? 

Bangkok West at 606 Santa Monica Boulevard, San...

in Dining Out | 2 days ago via sms text 
 
 Which fast food restaurant has the best hamburgers? 

Personally I think that Hardee&apos;s has the best t...

in Dining Out | 6 days ago via sms text 
 
 Which fast food restaurant is the healthiest? 

The healthiest fast food restaurants are Panera...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 6 days ago via web 
 
 What is the most popular fast food restaurant? 

One-in-four adults call fast food chain Wendy&apos;s...

in Food&amp;Drink | 6 days ago via web 
 
 Is there a 24 hour Chinese restaurant in Springfield, MO? 

No 24 hour Chinese restaurants. Ziggies Cafe at...

in Dining Out | 5 days ago via web 
 
 What is the most common fast food restaurant? 

McDonald&apos;s Corporation is the world&apos;s largest c...

in Dining Out | 5 days ago via sms text 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Month&apos;s Popular Questions for Restaurant 

 
 Is Yolo a good restaurant? 

Reviews on the restaurant Yolo say it is a very...

in Dining Out | 16 hr 15 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 Does Chipotle the restaurant sell margaritas? 

Many Chipotles are licensed to sell alcohol and...

in Dining Out | 19 days ago via web 
 
 What is a Nice restaurant to eat for fathers day? 

In Lomita, California, some nice restaurants to...

in Dining Out | 18 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is your favorite restaurant or fast food? 

I would have to say that Wendy&apos;s is my favorite...

in Conversational | 22 hr 44 min ago via sms text 
 
 What kind of food does the Canlis restaurant serve? 

Canlis serves a high end quality of American cu...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via web 
 
 Is that restaurant good? 

Viva Mercado appears to be a well known restaur...

in Dining Out | 7 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is the most popular fast food restaurant? 

One-in-four adults call fast food chain Wendy&apos;s...

in Food&amp;Drink | 6 days ago via web 
 
 What fast food restaurant has the highest profit margin? 

A restaurant is considered successful if after ...

in Dining Out | 18 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Restaurant burnsville north carolina? 

Garden Deli The - 107 Town Sq,Burnsville, NC, P...

in Dining Out | 17 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is the oldest restaurant in america? 

The Union Oyster House in Boston is the oldest ...

in Food&amp;Drink | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Restaurant Galleries

 
 
 
 Strange Restaurant Locations 
 Viewed 392 times 
 
 
 
 Diners Worth Driving To 
 Viewed 133 times 
 
 
 
 World&apos;s Best Competitive Eaters 
 Viewed 294 times 
 
 
 
 6 Unhealthy Fast-Food Kids Meals 
 Viewed 672 times 
 
 
 
 10 Worst Brunch Foods for Your Diet 
 Viewed 833 times 
 
 
 
 13 First Date Fashion Mistakes Men Make 
 Viewed 3689 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Restaurant Quizzes

 
 
 
 Which Foods Are Higher in Saturated Fat? 
 Viewed 3757 times 
 
 
 
 McDonald&apos;s Monopoly Trivia Quiz 
 Viewed 17665 times 
 
 
 
 Should You Eat This or That? 
 Viewed 15839 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Know Your Calorie Counts? 
 Viewed 9074 times 
 
 
 
 Are You Eating Proper Food Portions? 
 Viewed 3113 times 
 
 
 
 Which Foods Are Higher in Calories? 
 Viewed 23093 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
Top Trends in Dining Out 

 Dominos Pizza» Wendys» Applebees» Hooters» Red Robin» Papa Johns» Bob Evans» Cracker Barrel» Drive Thru» Arbys» 
 
Top Trends in Lifestyle 

 Puppies» Makeup» Restaurant» Fishing» Kittens» Fast Food» liquor» McDonalds» Coke» Pizza» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Hurt» Ford» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Lifestyle › Dining Out › Restaurant 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
