<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003237" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/131/1535630/restaurant/Edmonton/Sherwood-Park/Sawmill-Strathcona-County" time="2012-07-12-19:22" support="22" score="0.047244223442990535" bingtitle="Sawmill - Sherwood Park - Strathcona County | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Sawmill Prime RibSteak House - Sherwood Park | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000980" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000780" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000777" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000764" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000339" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001028" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="156"/>
	<description>It should NOT take over 15 minutes for the meal to get to the table from ... managers and staff you would expect behind a register at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Edmonton » Metropolitan Area » Sherwood Park » Sawmill Prime Rib&amp;... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Calgary Los Angeles New York Portland Salt Lake City Seattle Vancouver More... 
 
Sawmill Prime Rib&amp;Steak House (Sherwood Park)

 View all 4 Sawmill locations 
 
(780) 467-1144
 Sherwood Park Park Ave 
 Sherwood Park , AB T8B 
 sawmillrestaurant.com 
 on facebook.com 
 See all 34 reviews Cuisine Steakhouse , Breakfast/Brunch Features Free Wi-Fi , Gluten-Free Friendly , Happy Hour , Kid Friendly , Late Night , Outdoor Dining , Private Parties , Romantic , Sports Bar , Takes Reservations Menu $$$ $15-25 per entree Hot Louisiana style wings, Nachos View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ 
   191 people have voted 54 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 August 2, 2010 It&apos;s a Weird, Wild and Wonderful Life Sherwood Park has a new restaurant. Well, kind of new. Tom Goodchild, who opened his first Sawmill restaurant in 1976 in Edmonton, has added to his chain by setting up shop in the space... More from It&apos;s a Weird, Wild and Wonderful Life 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 12, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Bran ( 25 reviews ) Just like many of the other sawmill locations, our server in the lounge didn&apos;t have much of a personality or seemed like she wanted to be there. However the steak sandwich was very good. Love the sesame steak dressing as well. The Caesar salad was okay, the dressing almost tasted like a veggie dip. The lava cake with the s&apos;more dessert was so tasty which did make up for the terrible chocolate mousse along with it. Overall, good service and good food minus those things. I would go back. May 14, 2012 Likes it Great Food, Beautiful Restaurant and Friendly Service by Diner Gal ( 5 reviews ) My husband and I had dinner at this location on the weekend and we both really enjoyed ourselves. My husband had a ribeye and I had the salmon. The dinners were served hot and they were both very good. Our server was friendly and knowledgable about the menu. The restaurant itself had a beautiful decor and the music was set to a comfortable level. May 21, 2012 Birthday Discount ?? by Maureen McKillican ( 1 review ) 5 of Dined Sunday evening May 20th , We informed the Waitress we had a Birthday at our table. According to the Webpage If there are 4 entree&apos;s ordered the Birthday person will receive $25.00 off their meal, by getting a Loyalty card, non was offered ! Nor did the Waitress deduct the&quot;Birthday discount&quot;. 4 of us had Prime Rib and we had to ask for Horse Radish, which I figure should be offered. The Meal was very good and actually the first time I have ever received the Yorkshire warm. The Restaurant was not busy and I am Very disappointed in the&quot;lack of response to the Birthday person&quot; May 30, 2012 Likes it Thoroughly Enjoyable by Candlesonthetable ( 1 review ) My friend and I decided to have dinner at the Sawmill as she had never eaten there. Are we ever glad we did. Our server was polite and knowledgeable about the menu and was able to help us select two excellent wines to compliment our dinners. Our food was served in a timely manner and was not only visually appealing but absolutely delicious. We shared a dessert and each had a specialty coffee. The manager even came by to make sure everything was well. Service was top notch and prices were reasonable. We will be back! May 16, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Grossed out! by Grossed out ( 1 review ) Watched a server help himself to chocolate dipped fruit right off the dessert bar - no plate or napkin, just picked up strawberries with bare hand and stick it under the fountain of chocolate and then popped it in his mouth right in front of customers at the dessert table - the manager claimed Quality Assurance when called over! Food was cold, old and tasteless - later when trying to get a coffee we found several servers huddled together eating their share of the dessert bar by the coffee machines that had been left in various stages of neglect. Cannot believe that this is what has become of the Sawmill!o May 18, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Thomas ( 1 review ) We had attended the mothers day brunch buffet, as always we were blown away by the selection of food, definitely for the price, we are always well satisfied. From the wonderfully enthusiastic sever, to the caring Managment team. It is always a pleasure dining at The Sawmill Sherwood Park and our family recommends it to all! April 12, 2012 Likes it Decent food, great service by Inukshuk ( 135 reviews ) I&apos;ve been through this place a couple of time now since October 2011. Over all I&apos;ve had pretty good experiences. The food has been consistently good, but not great. I know that the Sawmill carries a reputation for an upscale steak place but frankly I&apos;m quite content to slide over to the lounge for a few drinks in a nice atmosphere with a little of their pub fare. In my experiences the service has been consistently outstanding. While it may not be my first choice for bite out, it&apos;s certainly not my last. May 1, 2012 Likes it by tbertram ( 1 review ) Sawmill Lounge in Sherwood Park is our favourite Thursday Night Date Night place to go. I love the big booths and the waitress are nice and efficient. Great atmosphere. March 16, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Christine of the Bannerman&apos;s ( 7 reviews ) Our server was great except for the odd long pauses between visits. But the food was not as it use to be. There use to be an art to this culinary place but now it&apos;s less than standard. The bernaise sauce was tasteless cool and gelatinous. The lobster was over done, and the fillet had fat on it. We will not be returning. Tom Goodchild has fallen. May 6, 2011 Likes it Good Wings, Nachos and Service by Food Dude ( 268 reviews ) It was a very pleasant experience when I went to the lounge. A lot of TV for watching sports, comfortable booths and plenty of space. The service was attentive but not too pushy. The wings were hot and fresh. The nachos were plentiful with lots of toppings and fair amount of cheese for the price. Based on previous reviews, they must have made some changes because they were exact opposite to what I read which almost kept me from trying this place. I can&apos;t comment on the main restaurant but the lounge was fantastic. I will be back to this location. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful March 5, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Cool not HOT by inisgrace007 ( 5 reviews ) Meals are inconsistantly consistant. The food rarely comes to the table steaming hot as it should be. It should NOT take over 15 minutes for the meal to get to the table from when the order is placed. Addtionally, the desert should come within 5 minutes of it being ordered...not 10 - 15 minutes. Even the coffee is not hot. The ribs especially consistantly arrive with the BBQ sauce dried out, sour cream rather than cream is used in the mashed potatoes - this makes the potatoes sour rather than rich in flavor. Not everyone is a fan of sour cream! My home made baked potatoes never have a 1/4 inch dried potato sticking to the skin as at the Sawmill. Simply put - the cost does not match the quality. I am embarrassed to recommend Sherwood Park Sawmill to anyone. Swiss Chalet is able to bring steamy hot food to the table in a timely manner. I will not eat at the Sawmill again. November 13, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Foodalicious ( 42 reviews ) We keep attempting to try new restaurants since moving here but when it comes to a steak dinner, The Keg comes out on top. Waste of time, money and appetites July 20, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Great Brunch! by o m f ( 20 reviews ) Have only ever visited Sawmill Sherwood Park during brunch; basic breakfast menu, good food. Hoping their lunch/dinner isn&apos;t anything like the Capilano location. Also Beautiful patio! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful +1 more review from o m f August 20, 2010 Dinner Attempt Finally got the courage to try dinner at the Sherwood Park location. They had a couple tables when I arrived around 8pm on a Wednesday, Hostess were very friendly. Server wasn&apos;t very knowledgeable on menu. Very slow service considering we were his only table (as he stated twice.) One server walked by and yawned very loudly, then came back around balancing a tray on top of her head. I don&apos;t think cussing to a table is ever appropriate, but for some reason our server thought it was okay. Loved... more» Finally got the courage to try dinner at the Sherwood Park location. They had a couple tables when I arrived around 8pm on a Wednesday, Hostess were very friendly. Server wasn&apos;t very knowledgeable on menu. Very slow service considering we were his only table (as he stated twice.) One server walked by and yawned very loudly, then came back around balancing a tray on top of her head. I don&apos;t think cussing to a table is ever appropriate, but for some reason our server thought it was okay. Loved the house salad, the rib eye steak was alright. My dinner partner wasn&apos;t too impressed with the mushroom caps, which he sent back in exchange for the crab cakes and didn&apos;t enjoy the chicken supreme. I think I&apos;ll stick to just brunch.. September 6, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Disappointing by MKummer ( 4 reviews ) This Sawmill location is struggling for an identity, experienced managers and staff you would expect behind a register at a fast food restaurant. We parked in front of what appeared to be the main entrance only to find out that was the lounge for the hotel. When we informed them that we had reservations, we were directed down a hotel corridor with kids in wet swimming suits dripping with water. When we arrived and asked where we could have drinks before our guests arrived, we were directed back to the separate lounge. We opted to go ahead and sit down at the table to have a drink. Three tables within sight were feasting on toothpicks after their glutenous all you can eat disease infested salad bar. Flys were crawling all over the salad bar so I opted to switch to ordering alacarte. Unfortunately, the steak was cheap as the service. I ordered a New York Strip and was brought a Top Sirloin&quot;baseball&quot;steak. When I asked to have it corrected, the Manager (who looked 22... more» This Sawmill location is struggling for an identity, experienced managers and staff you would expect behind a register at a fast food restaurant. We parked in front of what appeared to be the main entrance only to find out that was the lounge for the hotel. When we informed them that we had reservations, we were directed down a hotel corridor with kids in wet swimming suits dripping with water. When we arrived and asked where we could have drinks before our guests arrived, we were directed back to the separate lounge. We opted to go ahead and sit down at the table to have a drink. Three tables within sight were feasting on toothpicks after their glutenous all you can eat disease infested salad bar. Flys were crawling all over the salad bar so I opted to switch to ordering alacarte. Unfortunately, the steak was cheap as the service. I ordered a New York Strip and was brought a Top Sirloin&quot;baseball&quot;steak. When I asked to have it corrected, the Manager (who looked 22 years old) stated that I was probably not familiar with meat cuts. I decided not to argue even though I&apos;ve dined at some of the finest and most expensive steakhouses across North America. But for a $30 steal, I guess you get what you pay for. I&apos;d rather pay $40-$50 and have a better steak and service. The wine list consisted of a limited selection of lower end wines at fair prices but could be expanded. The decorations and atmosphere was nice and well appointed; one of a higher end restaurant. Our waitress was a metaphor for the evening; we saw our waitress three times during the evening. I later spotted in the parking lot with her friends sucking down on a cigarette. She muttered&quot;thanks for coming&quot;while exhaling. The manager and bus boy took care of our needs. While they were working hard they were clearly new to the restaurant industry. The bottom line is that this is a good steakhouse for the bourgeoisie who have families who have minimal expectations. You can grab an average baseball steak in a nice atmosphere at a decent price point. For those seeking a better steak or someone who is celebrating a special occasion, spend a little more and go to Chop, Ruth Chris, or another. $200 for 3 people would go alot further in any of these versus the worn out tradition of Sawmill which has become too confident in their name and is showing in their service! 3 out of 4 found this review helpful November 3, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it it was oaky by rockleysrock ( 6 reviews ) My family and I tried the sawmill for the first time on Thanksgiving night. Slow service, maybe not enough servers, but saw lots of bus people walking around, looking for tables to wipe. Food was okay, we all had different meals, but none were outstanding. I highly prefer Steak Village or Ric&apos;s Grille, for my money and experience. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful April 11, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Excellent service, but bad food by Taste Like Chicken ( 53 reviews ) we had steak and lobster, and 8 oz prime rib. The lobster was so brown that it had sun burn. ( Left the fan on too long in the oven ). the prime rib was so bad that it was dry and chewy. The service was excellent.. Price is just like any steak house August 31, 2010 Mobile review by Shawn Dillon ( 1 review ) Bad food. Ordered the rib eye steak and garlic mashed potatoes. Steak was dry and overdone. Garlic mashed potatoes had no flavor. Salad bar was partially closed. I gave feedback to our server and while they received my feedback I never really felt that what I was telling then was a surprise. Avoid this place and spend the money elsewhere , as my steak was 35 dollars. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful February 3, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Will not return by Ashley T ( 1 review ) I went with two other people, and none of our food was right! We went on a Tuesday evening and were one of two tables in the restaurant. We all ordered steak and they were all undercooked. There were two mediums and one medium well ordered, and three rare steaks delivered. On top of that the &apos;seasonal vegetables&apos; was shredded carrots, chunks of zuchinni and poorly cut red pepper. All over-cooked mush. Lastly, one of the sauces had a stray piece of meat in it! Everything just piled up one on the other and it made for an experience that I will never return to. August 7, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Waitresses by RuralReviewer ( 15 reviews ) I think if you are going to open a&quot;new&quot;restaurant/lounge, maybe get some new waitresses as well rather than re-cycling the old ones with a skirt, hairdo and make-up. As they say, you can take the trash out of the trailer park, but.....you get it. The pre-historic waitresses that were working at Franklins (I&apos;m sure when it opened as well) are fine purveyors of adoring sneers and also their ability to walk by 5 times before acknowledging your existence. My glass manages to sit empty for many minutes before I am asked if I would like another. The best part is when they act surprised that they missed you. To a beer drinker, this is the ultimate insult. Rest assured ladies, my tips will continue to reflect your career performances. Regarding the food, I have only ever tried the wing special. It tasted like the same old frozen Box O&apos; Wings special that they used to have on Fridays at Franklins. I like the big screen and the decor, so not all is lost... 1 out of 1 found this review helpful December 17, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Jordan ( 6 reviews ) You have to be careful with the sawmill. Some locations are company run while others are franchised. The sherwood park location seems to suffer from service problems and inconsistant food quality. Im not a fan. 
 Show 12 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Tasker Goodchild Proudly Serving... by Tasker Goodchild Dining Room 
 All 12 photos View larger map Driving directions People reached this page by searching for: 
 sawmill sherwood park the keg sherwood park sawmill restaurant sherwood park sawmill sawmill menu sherwood park 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
