<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003959" url="http://www.magicyellow.com/category/Restaurants_Food_Delivery/Salisbury_MD.html" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="1" score="0.0019079279835836512" bingtitle="Salisbury Delivery Food | Delivery Restaurants in Salisbury, MD" webtitle="Salisbury Delivery Food | Delivery Restaurants in Salisbury, MD">
			<query id="001235" bing-rank="165"/>
	<description>... fine ingredients; Your average pizza shop or fast food restaurant ... The Fountains Table Restaurant And Bar: 1800 Sweetbay ... While some people like to throw parties and have ...</description>
	<body>
		Add Your Business  |  Write a Review  |  Link to this page  |  Business Center 
 
 
 
 
 What? (e.g. Lawn Mowers or Tailors) 
 
 Where? (e.g. Blackfoot, ID or 83221) 
 
 
 
 

   
 Salisbury Restaurants Food Delivery search results Premier Listings 

 
   
 Common Terms Related to Restaurants With Food Delivery 
Ordering food for delivery is an easy way to arrange for your breakfast, lunch or dinner if you don&apos;t have time to cook or leave your home to get take out. Typically, you need to use the telephone or an online resource to place your order and then wait for it to arrive. While restaurant delivery services are usually straightforward, there are some key terms you should know before you dial your phone or click your mouse to order your next meal. Take Out - The general term for getting food from a restaurant to go rather than enjoying it in the establishment&apos;s dining room. The term can apply to any type of food or cuisine, including pizza or Chinese. Carry Out - A take out order that you personally pick up at the restaurant Deliver - A take out order that a worker for the restaurant brings to your location on foot or by bicycle or vehicle Cater - A service that prepares complete meals for a business meeting, party or other event and then delivers it to a location other than where the food was prepared; Catering may be done by businesses that specialize only in the field or by a Chinese, Italian or other restaurant that offers catering in addition to its standard dining room menu. Gourmet - A term used to describe upscale cuisine that uses fine ingredients; Your average pizza shop or fast food restaurant is usually not considered gourmet. Service Area - The region to which a restaurant will deliver food Gratuity - A tip given to the delivery person who brings your order; typically equal to 10 percent of the total price of your meal 
   
 Tim&apos;s Pizza&amp;Subs 
 Salisbury, MD 21804 We take great pride in our Delivery Food. If you are searching for Delivery Restaurants in Salisbury, we are your best solution! Everything comes fresh&amp;hot from our ovens! Come&amp;fill yourself with our pizza parlor in Salisbury! Write a review 
 
 National Restaurant Association Metropolitan Of 
 Washington, DC 20036 Striving to help our members, the National Restaurant Association helps businesses build customer loyalty and financial success. Write a review 
   
 Sort By Default Highest Rated Most Rated Limit By City No Yes Distance Default 5 miles 10 miles 15 miles 20 miles 
 
 Subrunners 
 901 N Salisbury Blvd Ste A, Salisbury, MD 21801 Write a review (410) 742-4111 
 
 The Fountains Table Restaurant And Bar 
 1800 Sweetbay Dr, Salisbury, MD 21804 Write a review (410) 749-6644 
 
 Maho&apos;s Pizzeria 
 720 E College Ave, Salisbury, MD 21804 Write a review (410) 749-9246 
 
 Pittsville Dinette 
 34200 Old Ocean City Rd, Pittsville, MD 21850
11.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 835-2541 
 
 Main Street Hair Design 
 11728 Somerset Ave, Princess Anne, MD 21853
14.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 651-3022 
 
 Castle In The Sand Hotel 
 3701 Atlantic Ave, Ocean City, MD 21842
27.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 289-6846 
 
 Dough Roller 
 4103 Coastal Hwy, Ocean City, MD 21842
27.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 524-9254 
 
 Melvin&apos;s Steak House And Saloon 
 25 Philadelphia Ave, Ocean City, MD 21842
27.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 289-7554 
 
 J Rs Ribs 
 131 Coastal Hwy, Ocean City, MD 21842
27.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 250-3100 
 
 Subway Oc 
 218 Baltimore Ave, Ocean City, MD 21842
27.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 289-0234 
 
 Blue Ox Bar&amp;Grill 
 12601 Coastal Hwy, Ocean City, MD 21842
27.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 250-6440 
 
 Government Offices City of 
 118 N Main St, Federalsburg, MD 21632
28.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 754-9754 
 
 Southern Grill 
 748 High St, Cambridge, MD 21613
29.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 901-6033 
 
 Subway 
 602 Sunburst Hwy Ste A, Cambridge, MD 21613
29.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 221-6465 
 
 Cambridge House Bed And Breakfast 
 112 High St, Cambridge, MD 21613
29.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 221-7700 
 
 Pizza Palace 
 600 Sunburst Hwy, Cambridge, MD 21613
29.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 221-0022 
 
 Caroline Senior Center 
 403 S 7th St Ste 127, Denton, MD 21629
37.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 479-2535 
 
 S&amp;r;Family Restaurant 
 14 Denton Plz, Denton, MD 21629
37.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 479-2824 
 
 Pizza Hut 
 609 N 6th St, Denton, MD 21629
37.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 479-1311 
 
 McDaniel House JS Bed And Breakfast 
 14 N Aurora St, Easton, MD 21601
39.0MI from Salisbury Write a review (410) 822-3704 
 



 Restaurants and food delivery services can be found in abundance in all communities all over the world. In fact, many eateries specialize in foods like pizza, Chinese cuisine and gourmet take out. Orders can be placed by telephone or online, and then meals can either be delivered or picked up. It essentially just depends on the restaurant or eatery and what level of services they offer. Your location also plays a part. After all, most Mexican, Thai food and pizza eateries will not deliver if you are located too far away. 

There are different types of dining options for people to enjoy. While some people like to throw parties and have restaurants cater to their residence or business, others like to simply have pizza delivered to their home. These are both popular options. In fact, there are a multitude of restaurants to choose from in your community alone. Many of these eateries provide breakfast, lunch and dinner menus. Some even offer low fat or diet meals to suit individuals who are trying to cut calories. Just so you are aware, when you have a Chinese or Italian restaurant cater for a party or special event, the cost may increase. This is typically because the restaurant has to deliver a lot of food and often help with serving it. 

If you are interested in learning more about restaurants, food delivery services and take out options, you should check into local eateries. If you reside in a large metropolitan area, there are likely to be a number of restaurants you can order from. 

 Showing Listings 1 - 20 of 31 
     
 
 
   
 
 Related Categories 
 
 Bagels 
 Banquet Rooms 
 Bar Supplies Fixtures&amp;Equipment 
 Barbecue Food&amp;Catering 
 Bistro 
 Buffet Restaurants 
 Cafes 
 Cafeterias 
 Candy&amp;Confectionery Retail 
 Chinese Food 
 Chocolate&amp;Cocoa 
 Family Style Restaurants 
 Flavoring Extracts 
 Food Brokers 
 Frozen Foods Wholesale 
 German Food 
 Hamburger&amp;Hot Dog Stands 
 Ice Cream Parlors 
 Italian Restaurants 
 Pretzels Retail 
 Restaurant Equipment&amp;Supplies Retail 
 Restaurants Asian 
 Soul Food 
 
   
 Maryland Cities 
 
 Allen 
 Barclay 
 Berlin 
 Bethlehem 
 Betterton 
 Bishopville 
 Bivalve 
 Bozman 
 Cambridge 
 Centreville 
 Chester 
 Chestertown 
 Church Creek 
 Church Hill 
 Claiborne 
 Cordova 
 Crapo 
 Crisfield 
 Crocheron 
 Crumpton 
 Deal Island 
 Delmar 
 Denton 
 East New Market 
 Easton 
 Eden 
 Ewell 
 Federalsburg 
 Fishing Creek 
 Fruitland 
 Galena 
 Girdletree 
 Goldsboro 
 Grasonville 
 Greensboro 
 Hebron 
 Henderson 
 Hillsboro 
 Hurlock 
 Ingleside 
 Kennedyville 
 Linkwood 
 Madison 
 Manokin 
 Mardela Springs 
 Marion Station 
 Marydel 
 Massey 
 McDaniel 
 Millington 
 Nanticoke 
 Neavitt 
 Newark 
 Newcomb 
 Ocean City 
 Oxford 
 Parsonsburg 
 Pittsville 
 Pocomoke City 
 Powellville 
 Preston 
 Price 
 Princess Anne 
 Quantico 
 Queen Anne 
 Queenstown 
 Rehobeth 
 Rhodesdale 
 Ridgely 
 Rock Hall 
 Royal Oak 
 Saint Michaels 
 Secretary 
 Sharptown 
 Sherwood 
 Showell 
 Snow Hill 
 Stevensville 
 Still Pond 
 Stockton 
 Sudlersville 
 Taylors Island 
 Templeville 
 Tilghman 
 Toddville 
 Trappe 
 Tyaskin 
 Tylerton 
 Upper Fairmount 
 Vienna 
 Westover 
 Whaleyville 
 Willards 
 Wingate 
 Wittman 
 Woolford 
 Worton 
 Wye Mills 
 
   
 Maryland Cities 
 
 Baltimore 
 Bethesda 
 Cumberland 
 Saint Charles 
 Maryland Statewide
	</body>
</document>
