<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003831" url="http://www.npr.org/2012/01/17/145328929/-45-million-dollar-hospital-bill-startles-n-y-man" time="2012-07-12-19:59" support="1" score="0.00038781083507461833" bingtitle="$45 Million Hospital Bill Startles N.Y. Man : NPR" webtitle="$45 Million Hospital Bill Startles N.Y. Man : NPR">
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>... was treated for pneumonia, and received a bill for ... Who Led Ill-Fated Ted Stevens Case To Leave Justice ... U.S. Foreclosure Activity Near 5-Year Low AP ...</description>
	<body>
		NPR Shop | NPR Social Media | Login | Register 
 
 Find a Station 
 Search close   
 home news arts&amp;life music programs listen 
 
news

 Morning Edition All Things Considered Fresh Air The Diane Rehm Show On The Media On Point Talk of the Nation 

 Talk of the Nation Science Friday Tell Me More Weekend Edition Saturday Weekend Edition Sunday Also heard on NPR stations: Marketplace APM 
 
arts&amp;life

 Ask Me Another Car Talk Radiolab Snap Judgment TED Radio Hour Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Also heard on NPR stations: This American Life PRI A Prairie Home Companion APM 
 
music

 All Songs Considered Alt.Latino Favorite Sessions First Listen From The Top Live In Concert 

 Mountain Stage NPR Music Essentials Piano Jazz Song Travels The Thistle&amp;Shamrock World Cafe 
 
special series

 StoryCorps Planet Money Picture Show Krulwich Wonders... Cabinet of Wonders 
 PUBLIC RADIO PROGRAMS A-Z | close 
hear continuous streams
 
 24-Hour Program Stream 

NPR News and Shows
 View Schedule 
 Find Stations | Music Streams 
 
hear the latest news
 
 Hourly News Summary 
 [4 min 45 sec] 
Latest NPR Newscast
 Public Radio Programs A-Z | close 
 News &gt; U.S. &gt; Around the Nation 
 
 Twitter (9) Facebook (6) Share 
 Stumble Upon Reddit Linkedin Digg 

 What is this? 
 Share Comments 
   
$45 Million Hospital Bill Startles N.Y. Man
 
January 17, 2012
 
 Listen to the Story 

 Morning Edition 
 [27 sec] 
 Add to Playlist Download 
   text size A A A January 17, 2012 
Alexis Rodriguez was treated for pneumonia, and received a bill for nearly $45 million. Grateful as he was for the care, the unemployed doorman complained. The Daily News reports the billing firm printed the invoice number instead of the price: $300.
 
Copyright©2012 National Public Radio. For personal, noncommercial use only. See Terms of Use. For other uses, prior permission required.

STEVE INSKEEP, HOST:

Good morning. I&apos;m Steve Inskeep. Health care costs are rising too fast for Alexis Rodriguez. The New York man was treated for pneumonia and received a bill for almost $45 million. Grateful as he was for the care, the unemployed doorman complained. The Daily News says the billing firm printed the invoice number instead of the price - $300. Mr. Rodriguez says the firm should&apos;ve checked the bill, adding that somebody could&apos;ve had a heart attack. You are listening to MORNING EDITION.

Copyright©2012 National Public Radio. All rights reserved. No quotes from the materials contained herein may be used in any media without attribution to National Public Radio. This transcript is provided for personal, noncommercial use only, pursuant to our Terms of Use. Any other use requires NPR&apos;s prior permission. Visit our permissions page for further information.

NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPR&apos;s programming is the audio.
   
 Twitter (9) Facebook (6) Share 
 Stumble Upon Reddit Linkedin Digg 

 What is this? 
 Share Comments 
   
 More Around the Nation 
 
Podcast + RSS Feeds
 
 Podcast RSS 

 Around the Nation 
Subscribe to Around the Nation podcast via:

 

Or use this URL:

 

 close 
     Morning Edition –   
   
 The Two-Way 

 Cheers For Biden At NAACP Convention As He Contrasts Obama And Romney 

Republicans, he said, see a future where &quot;voting is made harder, not easier.&quot;
 
 Around the Nation 

 Arson: The Motivation And Fire Investigation 


 
 Around the Nation 

 What The Penn State University Report Reveals 


     
Comments





 Discussions for this story are now closed. Please see the Community FAQ for more information.
   Recent First Oldest First Most Recommended 
 View all comments » 
 
NPR thanks our sponsors

 Become an NPR Sponsor 
 
most popular 
 
 Viewed Recommended Commented 

 Paterno, Others Slammed In Report For Failing To Protect Sandusky&apos;s Victims Nightly Glass Of Wine May Protect Boomer Women&apos;s Bones Fake Pot Is A Real Problem For Regulators Wake Up Call To Grocery Stores: Young People Shop Around 
 
Special Series

 Family Matters: The Money Squeeze 
 
Multigenerational households face difficult financial decisions surrounding elder care, paying for college and retirement.
 
 Your Turn 

 Sights And Sounds: The &apos;Heart&apos; Of Your City 
 
All urbanites have a place they think of as the heart of their city. Show us the heart of your city.
 
 Crisis In The Housing Market &gt; 
 
 Homebuilding Pushes Up Construction Spending   AP Contracts For Home Sales Rose Sharply In May Morale Takes A Hit At Beleaguered Fannie, Freddie 
   
 npr always on 

 Newsletters Podcasts Mobile RSS Feeds Widgets API Radio 
 
 news 

 U.S. World Opinion Politics Business Technology Science Health Sports 
 
 arts&amp;life 

 Books Movies Pop Culture Food Performing Arts Games&amp;Humor 
 
 music 

 Music Articles Music Videos NPR Music Radio Browse Genres Browse Artists A-Z 

 All Songs Considered Alt.Latino First Listen Live In Concert NPR Music Essentials Marian McPartland&apos;s Piano Jazz The Thistle&amp;Shamrock World Cafe 
 
 programs a-z 

 All Things Considered Ask Me Another Cabinet of Wonders Car Talk The Diane Rehm Show Fresh Air Morning Edition On The Media On Point Talk of the Nation TED Radio Hour Tell Me More Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Weekend Edition Saturday Weekend Edition Sunday 
 
listen

 Hourly News NPR Program Stream Schedule Find Station Streams 
 
more

 Multimedia Columns Blogs Analysis Commentary NPR Ombudsman StateImpact 

 about 

 This Is NPR Support and Sponsor Press Room Careers NPR Shop Contact Us 
 
 Copyright NPR Terms of Use Privacy Policy Permissions Corrections Text-Only Site Help Contact Us Donate Our partner in public broadcasting
	</body>
</document>
