<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003420" url="http://www.mypartyplanner.com/search/vendor/Catering_-and-_Food-or-Beverage/Chicago_find99.html" time="2012-07-12-19:34" support="1" score="0.0013657970610264423" bingtitle="Chicago Catering, Chicago Event Catering, Wedding Caterers in ..." webtitle="Chicago Catering, Chicago  Event Catering, Wedding Caterers in Chicago Illinois IL">
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>We offer a delicious selection of carefully crafted ... Dedicating Sushi/Japanese fast food restaurant in downtown area ... Make a list of available caterers on that date ...</description>
	<body>
		Loading...    Please Wait While We Process Your Request.... 
 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 Keywords: Location: 
 
 Home Weddings Party Tips Party Themes Party Supplies 
 
 

 
 Home -&gt; Catering -&gt; Illinois Catering -&gt; Chicago Catering
 Vendor Registration  |  Vendor Login 

 
 
 
 Your Location Select Event Type --Select-- Anniversary Bachelor/Bachelorette Bar/ Bat Mitzvahs Birthday Bridal Shower Corporate Entertainment Graduation Party Wedding Bachelorette Party Casino Party Children&apos;s Party College Events Ethnic Events Fundraiser Halloween Party High Schools Honeymoons / Destination Weddings Picnic/Luncheon/BBQ&apos;s Pool Party Private Party Retirement Party Reunion School Event Senior Events Sporting Event Valentines Day 
 
 
 
 Sponsored Vendors Barbara&apos;s Elegant Touch Staffing,Inc. View Website (630) 341-3337 
 Other Vendors In Your Area A / V Equipment&amp;Rentals Accommodations Adult Parties Bachelor Party Bachelorette Party Bakeries Balloons Banquet Halls Bartenders Belly Dancers Bridal Gowns&amp;Accessories Bridal Shoes Bridal Shows Calligraphy Caricature Carnival Games Casino Party Celebrity Impersonators Centerpieces Charter Bus Cleaning Services Clowns Comedians Corporate Event Entertainment Costumes Creative Writing Dancers Day Spas Decorations DJs / Disc Jockeys Dove Release Entertainers Event Planners&amp;Coordinators Face Painting Fireworks Florists&amp;Flowers Formal Wear Game Shows Gifts Hair&amp;Make-up Horse Carriages Hotels&amp;Motels Hypnotists Inflatables&amp;Moonbounce Invitations&amp;Printing Jewelry Karaoke Lasers Lighting Rentals Limousine Service Linens&amp;Chair Covers Live Animals Live Bands Magicians Make-up Artists Mimes Mind Readers Models&amp;Actors Murder Mystery Party Musicians Novelty Officiants Outdoor Movie Party Party&amp;Wedding Favors Party Invitations Party Rentals Personal Trainer&amp;Fitness Photo Booth Photo Montage Photographers Psychics Real Estate Restaurants Security Companies Singers Stationery products Talent Agency Tent Rentals Theme Parties Trade Show Transportation Travel Agent Tuxedo Rental Valet Parking Car Rentals Ventriloquists Videographers Wedding Cakes Wedding Decorations Wedding Dresses Wedding Gifts Wedding Invitations Wedding Photographers Wedding Planners Wedding Supplies&amp;Accessories Wedding Venues Wholesale Party Equipment Venues Production Mechanical Bull Rentals Honeymoons / Destination Weddings Disc Jockey 
 
 
 Name Email 
 
Chicago Wedding Catering

Catering in Chicago, Illinois (61 Vendors)
 
 
 
 
 Carol Peters Dinner Shows 
 
The best dinner parties in San Francisco
 
 
 
   
 view website contact us   (1 review) view phone # 
 
 
 
 
 
 Find it at Localpages.com 
 Making Customer Service Our Top Priority 
Looking for music download? Find it at Localpages.com 
 Sponsored Advertiser   
 view website localpages.com 
 
 
 
 
 
 Find it at Cheapstuff.com 
 Making Customer Service Our Top Priority 
Looking for music download? Find it at Cheapstuff.com 
 Sponsored Advertiser   
 view website cheapstuff.com 
 
 
 
 
 Chocolat Elegant Fondue, Inc. 
 
Chocolate fountain rental services in Chicago&amp;suburbs
All-inclusive packages, includes dipping items&amp;server
Unbeatable packages, service and specials
NO WORRIES!! Service, each and every time...
Event Planning, calligraphy, invitations&amp;favors
 
 
   
 view website contact us write a review view phone # 
 
 
 
 
 Chicago Rootbeer 
 
Let us do the heavy lifting for you at your next event. Chicago rootbeer, delivers mouthwatering beverages in a Keg 1/2 barrels and 1/4 barrels directly to your door. Leave a greener footprint on your... more info 
   
 view website contact us write a review view phone # 
 
 
 
 
 Corky&apos;s Catering 
Corky&apos;s Catering has provided the Chicago area with excellent food for weddings, picnics, corporate events and social occasions since 1978. As a caterer of some of the largest picnic and wedding... more info   
 view website contact us write a review view phone # 
 
 
 
 
 Party of Two? Catering, LLC 
&quot;Party of Two?&quot; The Ultimate Dining Experience for Couples! 
A Personal Chef will prepare a Quiet, Romantic intimate Dinner for two. 
Think of Yesterday and Cherished Memories of Long Ago...Enjoy a ... more info   
 view website contact us write a review view phone # 
 
 
 
 
 Barbara&apos;s Elegant Touch Staffing,Inc. 
We provide quality servers, bartenders ,and chefs for any type of event you can think 
of. Need help with catering? We provide customized menus to suit your taste, style,
 and price range. From te... more info   
 view website contact us write a review view phone # 
 
 
 
 
 Jewell Events Catering Jewell Events Catering has built its reputation for exquisite food and impeccable service through four decades of extraordinary service. A leader in Chicago catering since l967, we have offered our... more info
	</body>
</document>
