<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003933" url="http://www.buyerzone.co.uk/computers/pos-uk/qz_questions_local.jhtml" time="2012-07-12-20:06" support="7" score="0.016670243367148906" bingtitle="www.buyerzone.co.uk" webtitle="">
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>(for kitchen or bar orders, etc.) Receipt printers: Credit card terminals ... Please respect their time and effort by keeping them informed of your purchasing ...</description>
	<body>
		Are you interested in a complete EPOS system or only hardware or software components? [required] 
 Yes - Complete EPOS system No - EPOS system hardware only No - EPOS system software only 
 What type of business will use this EPOS system? [required] 
 Clothing or footwear Bar/Pub or nightclub Convenience store Off-license Hospitality (resort, spa, hotel, etc.) Institutional (education, government, etc.) Restaurant: fast food Restaurant: full service Restaurant: fine dining Restaurant: other Supermarket or grocery Retail or other shop 
 Is this request for a new system or an upgrade of a current point of sale system? [required] 
 New system Upgrade/replacement to current system 

If applicable, list current hardware/software:
 
 Do you require help with installation or wiring? [required] 
 Yes No Prefer a system that does not require installation Please help us select wiring or installation options 
 Would you like information about service contracts? [required] 
 Yes No Not sure 
 How many business locations do you need the EPOS system for? [required] 
 1 2 3 4+ 

If 4+, please note exact number: 
 Note: this question is asking for the number of distinct business locations, not the number of terminals or registers within one location.
 
 What is your buying time frame for this point of sale system? [required] 
 ASAP 0-3 months 4-6 months 6 months or longer Not sure   
 What type of reporting capabilities do you require? 
 Not sure Standard (full reports, PLU reports, hourly or group reports) Advanced (consolidated reports for multiple locations) Web-based (enterprise-level reports)   
 What input device will your EPOS system use? 
 (Please tick all that apply) 
 Not sure 
 Keyboards 
 Touch screen Monitors 
 Barcode scanners 
 Scales 
 Wireless devices 
 Other (please specify):
      
 If known, please say how many of the following EPOS equipment you need for each of your locations. 

 Hardware Quantity EPOS terminals with cash drawers EPOS terminals without cash drawers
(order stations) Remote printers
(for kitchen or bar orders, etc.) Receipt printers Credit card terminals 
 
 What is your business postcode?  [required]  
   
 Please share any additional needs you may have so that our suppliers can customise your EPOS solution. 
 
 NOTE: there is a 1,000 character limit for the above.
 
 Serious requests only! You will receive responses directly from up to 5 EPOS suppliers via phone and/or email. Please respect their time and effort by keeping them informed of your purchasing intent and time frame. 
 
 Do you have questions about using this form? Click Here .
	</body>
</document>
