<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003173" url="http://www.skyscrapercity.com/archive/index.php/t-825580-p-3.html" time="2012-07-12-19:18" support="3" score="0.0073793811356951036" bingtitle="Projects &amp; Discussions | Retail, Lifestyle, and Food [Archive ..." webtitle="ProjectsDiscussions | Retail, Lifestyle, and Food [Archive]  - Page 3 - SkyscraperCity">
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>I think they mean &apos;fast food&apos; restaurant Miensie. ... initial $200 fine, while repeat offenders could receive ... understand English that well so I had to repeat my order ...</description>
	<body>
		SkyscraperCity &gt; Continental Forums &gt; OZScrapers &gt; Urban Spaces &gt; Archives &gt;Projects&amp;Discussions | Retail, Lifestyle, and Food PDA 
View Full Version : Projects&amp;Discussions | Retail, Lifestyle, and Food 
 Pages : 1 2 [ 3 ] 4 5 6 Sanj April 9th, 2009, 05:28 AM i didnt see it last night but ive seen that episode before. by the way the one i have a man crush on is neil perry. i admire tetsuya and really wanna eat there but neil perry is the one who makes me slide off my chair

in a non gay way of course


It was pretty cool. Very interesting to see just how much tradition and work goes into making something as simple as sushi and miso soup.



exactly,which is why ive always gone out about proper sushi chefs being artists - some of their dedication to what they do is truly amazing miensie April 9th, 2009, 05:53 AM i didnt see it last night but ive seen that episode before. by the way the one i have a man crush on is neil perry. i admire tetsuya and really wanna eat there but neil perry is the one who makes me slide off my chair

in a non gay way of course

LOL

But this a new series?


exactly,which is why ive always gone out about proper sushi chefs being artists - some of their dedication to what they do is truly amazing

It got me to thinking about what you say regarding the chefs at Taka. Not to say that I don&apos;t still like the food there but in many ways, none of them would be able to compare to the level of skill and mastery I saw last night.

Just things like how the correct sashimi knife can completely change the taste of it. One of the chefs they were interviewing has over 150 knives that were passed down in his family and he was saying that he can tell straight away whether a bad knife has been used to make the sashimi.

It really opened my eyes. Really, really cool. crazyknightsfan April 9th, 2009, 06:01 AM excuse my ignorance, but how does a knife affect the flavour? miensie April 9th, 2009, 06:08 AM excuse my ignorance, but how does a knife affect the flavour?

It&apos;s not ignorant, CKF. I had no idea either.

A sashimi knife is straight on one side and curved on the other side. There&apos;s also a correct way of cutting it.

The chef was saying that the taste of sashimi should be sharp so the knife itself has to be the same.

It&apos;s similar to when people say the texture of chopsticks can affect the taste of what you eat. Many prefer wooden chopsticks over the plastic ones. Sanj April 9th, 2009, 06:21 AM there are lots of programs that show some of the dedication. an interesting one was called&quot;rick stein and the japanese ambassador&quot;. check that one out, not sure if u can download it etc. rick stein is an english seafood chef who has been around for a very long time and is highly regarded and even he was amazed at what they do in japan and the dedication etc. http://www.guardian.co.uk/travel/2006/dec/16/japan.saturday.restaurants

another one would be an episode of&quot;chef abroad&quot;where he follows a bluefin tuna caught in canada all the way back to japan, to the fish market where it is sold to the wholesaler then to the chef who bought some of it and he then goes to eat the sushi made from that very fish he saw getting caught in canada. fascinating stuff.

there is lots of amazing stuff out there re the dedication shown by top japanese chefs and once your eyes are open it is amazing. one of the coolest things ive ever done was to do a tour of the tsukiji fish markets in tokyo. ill never ever forget how cool it was and jsut what is involved in order for diners to get top quality sushi and sashimi miensie April 9th, 2009, 06:23 AM Aren&apos;t you off to Tetsuya&apos;s this week, Sanj, no? Sanj April 9th, 2009, 06:27 AM nah i was meant to be going to quay tonight but my trip has been delayed (had some work emergencies). still going to sydney but now going on monday. might still be going to melbourne but wont know til later today/tomorrow.

tetsuyas is a long process that would take at least 3 hours, more likely closer to 4 but i dont have the time this trip Sanj April 9th, 2009, 06:36 AM found this on a forum.


Itamae-san (master chef) training for sushi chefs

Traditional sushi-chef training takes about 10 years of instruction under a master. In old days the apprentice enters at high school age, and if proven to have talent, becomes a chef by mid 20s. These days the apprentice usually start after high school (unless family restaurant) and the length of apprenticeship may be shorter, but it still take years to become a good chef.

An apprentice (minarai) starts by doing basic kitchen chores and learn by observation for few years. After a while he is taught how to gut fish and cook sushi rice properly. If he doesnt exhibit any decent skills, this is where hed stay, with pay below or equal to the serving staff. This is also where youd find the restaurant owners friends kid and the daughters boyfriend/husband with no job skills, washing rice in the back and kept out of the customers view.

If the apprentice shows skill, he is allowed to work in the front as shimoita (below the board), an assistant to the sushi chef. This stage typically take 3 years, where hed learn how to use various Sashimi hōchō&amp;other knives properly. Knife skill is very important as it impacts the quality and texture of the nigiri. At this stage the apprentice is not allowed to make sushi for the customer without supervision, though he could make other stuff that require less skill, such as cut rolls and hand rolls. At this stage he is paid at or above the servers wages.

If the student chef is good enough, hes promoted to nakaita (middle board) where he is allowed to make sushi for the customers without supervision. At this stage he is paid about twice the servers wages or better. The skill level of chefs at this stage can vary widely, from barely acceptable to very good. Foreign sushi chefs who didnt receive proper training but learned through years of experience may be evaluated at nakaita level by their Japanese peers.

A properly trained nakaita, after years of experiences, may attain the status of Itamae-San. A popular master chef can make 6 figures from salary and tips, and get a cut from the sushi bars daily bill. At this stage he may also open his own sushi bar and train apprentice.

This kind of time-consuming dedication is not always feasible in chef training overseas. In America the typical sushi academy is a 3-6 months program. Only about 20% of the graduates from these schools go work in traditional sushi restaurants, the rest end up in some kind of fusion restaurant where more emphasis is placed on cooked dishes. A small % of graduates from these compressed courses have good talents and can make good sushi.

In cases where the chef isnt highly trained/skilled, the restaurant tend to favor fish thats more forgiving, like salmon and spicy tuna. Ive had sushi at many restaurants, and some of these had chefs with skills lower than the Mexican lady working at Sushi Boy.

Many sushi chefs are actually not experts at picking fish. They depend on specialized middle-man merchants to pick through wholesale markets and find them the best fish, delivered to the restaurant. crazyknightsfan April 9th, 2009, 06:59 AM It&apos;s not ignorant, CKF. I had no idea either.

A sashimi knife is straight on one side and curved on the other side. There&apos;s also a correct way of cutting it.

The chef was saying that the taste of sashimi should be sharp so the knife itself has to be the same.

It&apos;s similar to when people say the texture of chopsticks can affect the taste of what you eat. Many prefer wooden chopsticks over the plastic ones.

sounds a bit wanky to me tbh

much like the wine buffs who comes up with stuff like&quot;it tastes like a long walk the beach with the subtle fragrance of lighting a candle and gentle undertones of whales frolicking in the ocean&quot; ryan79 April 9th, 2009, 08:12 AM I had absolutely no idea so much effort went into sushi. 10 years to become a proper sushi chef - really?? Sanj April 9th, 2009, 08:31 AM yeah traditionally 10 years. someone in japan was telling me u do see it shortened a bit in some cases now, but u are still talking 8 years or so.

that is why i have always gone on about places like takas or even wagamama not being able to do what speciality places can do. it isnt possible for a place that serves sushi/sashimi along with tempura, teriyaki, katsu, some udon etc to serve sushi as well as a place that only serves sushi. Sanj April 9th, 2009, 08:32 AM sounds a bit wanky to me tbh

much like the wine buffs who comes up with stuff like&quot;it tastes like a long walk the beach with the subtle fragrance of lighting a candle and gentle undertones of whales frolicking in the ocean&quot;

yeah i suppose flippantly dismissing something which has been around for a very very long time just cos u dont&quot;get it&quot;makes sense...


:lol: miensie April 9th, 2009, 09:09 AM sounds a bit wanky to me tbh

much like the wine buffs who comes up with stuff like&quot;it tastes like a long walk the beach with the subtle fragrance of lighting a candle and gentle undertones of whales frolicking in the ocean&quot;

LOL

I had a feeling you&apos;d say something like that, CKF.


it isnt possible for a place that serves sushi/sashimi along with tempura, teriyaki, katsu, some udon etc to serve sushi as well as a place that only serves sushi.

Exactly what they were saying on the show last night. They were talking about some places that specialise in maybe a certain kind of ramen or maybe even just a certain kind of sushi.

A lot of it is practise that allows them to hone and fine-tune their skills. A bit hard to do that when you try to do too many things at one time.

I was waiting for her to mention a place in Perth so I could go and try it but nope...:ohno:



yeah i suppose flippantly dismissing something which has been around for a very very long time just cos u dont&quot;get it&quot;makes sense...

:lol:

And I had a feeling you&apos;d say something like that, Sanj.


:lol: samboy April 9th, 2009, 09:13 AM I guess it boils down to someone&apos;s idea of what food is. From a purely taste perspective perhaps it doesn&apos;t take that much time to train a sushi chef however for the Japanese (and many others) food is not just about taste. There&apos;s the visual, cultural and traditional element to it and all the senses have to be stimulated for a thoroughly enjoyable experience.
Hey I can do a mean sashimi that is normally scoffed down in 3 mins but I&apos;ve been to places in Japan where it&apos;s an &apos;experience&apos; not just something to fill you up. acc521 April 9th, 2009, 09:20 AM In Milan my brother and I went to this place which supposedly does the best pasta in Milan. It was hard to find the recommendation and the place was well out of the city centre and, after eating the food, I couldn&apos;t argue. My brother and I were seated next to a middle aged Japanese couple, and the 4 of us were the only foreigners there. They were foodies and we had a great discussion on Japanese and Australian food. They never knew anything about Australia apart from the fact that it has the best wines that they like to import. I think I convinced them to come to Australia.

Preparation of the food and using the right&quot;tools&quot;can be just as important as the ingredients used. It&apos;s a lot more than just wanky talk to justify higher prices. Of course if you want a quick, cheap, but still good quality meal, no-one is going to expect that level of care.

Oh and Bourdain was filming in Melbourne in Feb so expect a No Reservations: Melbourne episode later on this year. It will be interesting to see how the changed food scene is discussed (he was last in Melbourne in 2003). Ondine, their amazing restaurant, had to close for a lack of customers - I think it would survive if opened today. Quite interesting to watch in hindsight (Cook&apos;s Tour 2003 Melbourne episode that is). miensie April 9th, 2009, 09:21 AM I guess it boils down to someone&apos;s idea of what food is. From a purely taste perspective perhaps it doesn&apos;t take that much time to train a sushi chef however for the Japanese (and many others) food is not just about taste. There&apos;s the visual, cultural and traditional element to it and all the senses have to be stimulated for a thoroughly enjoyable experience.
Hey I can do a mean sashimi that is normally scoffed down in 3 mins but I&apos;ve been to places in Japan where it&apos;s an &apos;experience&apos; not just something to fill you up.

Yeah pretty much, samby.

The presentation of the food and how things are arranged are a crucial element, even something as inconsequential (to most) as a bowl has to be carefully decided upon. I was watching the guy put about 8 different types of offerings on this one plate and he was so precise and specific about it, making sure he was accounting for &apos;negatives&apos; and things like that.

The chefs were also having a good chuckle over the way&quot;Westerners&quot;tend to drown their sushi in soy sauce and the general way they eat it.

I suppose from a Japanese sushi chef&apos;s point of view, he would need to get even the smallest detail 100% correct and it would be an insult to his cuisine if it were prepared and eaten &apos;wrong&apos; but to your normal person, one who enjoys Japanese food but is neither aware of the tradition or effort behind it, they wouldn&apos;t think so much about it.

But like you said, it all comes down to the individual. ryan79 April 9th, 2009, 09:22 AM I guess I have to experience it to understand. But I don&apos;t eat sushi anyway. acc521 April 9th, 2009, 09:23 AM ^^You have to give it a go. People have a very narrow definition of what&quot;sushi&quot;is and can be. My cousin never ate sushi until my brother and I&quot;forced&quot;him to in Hong Kong 2 years ago. Now he eats it all the time. Sanj April 9th, 2009, 09:38 AM ^^You have to give it a go. People have a very narrow definition of what&quot;sushi&quot;is and can be. My cousin never ate sushi until my brother and I&quot;forced&quot;him to in Hong Kong 2 years ago. Now he eats it all the time.

do u greek/macos have any cured or raw dishes?

i know the italians have carpaccio as well as crudo, but i dont know all that much about greek and maco food Sanj April 9th, 2009, 09:51 AM all this talk re sushi has made me want some, but im off to jus burgers tonight. might go to fuji or jaws mint this weekend.

has anyone here been to satsuki? that new sushi focused place in subi owned byt the dude who owns halu? miensie April 9th, 2009, 09:57 AM has anyone here been to satsuki? that new sushi focused place in subi owned byt the dude who owns halu?

Nope but if he&apos;s incorporating the same elements into it that Ha-Lu has then it&apos;s a guaranteed winnah :okay:

Is he a chef or just the owner? acc521 April 9th, 2009, 10:08 AM do u greek/macos have any cured or raw dishes?

i know the italians have carpaccio as well as crudo, but i dont know all that much about greek and maco food

Nah not really. dallastexjr April 9th, 2009, 12:03 PM Oopsy-daisy - article nearly posted in totally wrong thread... Dilaz89 April 15th, 2009, 02:03 PM Retailers in strong negotiating position
Property: 16-April-09 by Janelle Macri



NEW BUSINESS: The first stage of retailers in the Wesley Quarter development have opened their doors. Photo: Grant Currall
RETAILERS have taken the whip hand in negotiations for tenancies, with rental growth expected to stabilise and even drop in some precincts.

According to the CB Richard Ellis December quarter retail market report, softening trading conditions will limit any growth in retail rents this year as business confidence reaches an all-time low.

But WA&apos;s retail sector should be relatively well placed to weather the storm of the global economic downturn, with high occupancy rates remaining in most retail centres and precincts, and continued demand from national retailers.

Prime locations in the Perth CBD and suburban shopping strips are the best placed, while shopping centres in secondary locations could experience a drop in rents and increased vacancies.

About 35,000sqm of new retail space will be delivered to the Perth CBD over the next two to three years including major developments enex100, Wesley Quarter, One40 William and Raine Square.

CBRE associate director of retail services Fred Clohessy said while the level of enquiry for tenancies was still strong, retailers were more cautious than they were 12 months ago.

&quot;Because of what&apos;s happened with the economy globally and nationally, there is a degree of caution there. But we&apos;re still doing deals,&quot;he said.

Mr Clohessy said while rents had held up so far, some retailers were looking for incentives such as fully or partially funded fit-outs.

&quot;What we&apos;re seeing is the national retailers are still prepared to pay rents but are looking for incentives. For an A-grade [location] 12 months ago, you were getting rent and little to no incentives,&quot;he said.

Positive rental growth was evidenced across all retail sectors during 2008 after strong growth during 2006 and 2007, according to the report.

CBD super prime locations were in high demand, with indicative gross face rent of $4,500 a square metre at December 2008.

Among the prime suburban shopping strips, including Bay View Terrace in Claremont, Rokeby Road in Subiaco, and South Terrace in Fremantle, rents ranged between $900/sqm and $2,100/sqm.

Regional shopping centre rents showed steady growth, ranged between $1,165/sqm and $2,000/sqm.

Vacancy rates remained at a low 2.3 per cent in the CBD and 1.3 per cent in prime suburban strips.

Stage one of enex100 opened in December with retailers Veronika Maine, Guess, Mimco, Witchery&amp;Hardy Brothers opening stores.

The next phase of retailers, including Woolworth, JB HiFi and other fashion and upmarket eateries, will open in stages, with St Georges Terrace level to open on June 2 and the Hay Street and podium levels on August 20.

The first stage of retailers in the Wesley Quarter development, including Review, Alannah Hill, Wittner Shoes and Metalicus, have also opened their doors, while luxury labels Burberry, Giorgio Armani and Karen Millen are expected to open shortly.

Mr Clohessy said while space in the major CBD developments was in very high demand in early to mid-2008, there was now some possibility of an oversupply once these developments were completed.

&quot;Prior to Christmas I would have thought all new development and current existing developments would be filled. A couple of developments might take a little longer to fill,&quot;he said.

Lease Equity managing director Jim Tsagalis said prime locations were still in demand and would hold their value, with the firm recently completing deals in the Hay Street Mall for $5,300/sqm and in the Murray Street Mall for $4,000/sqm.

&quot;We&apos;ve had as much [rental] growth per year in the five years that we&apos;ve had in the past 15 years, so it has to be at least stabilised and in some instances even come off a little bit,&quot;he said.

Retail trade figures from the Australian Bureau of Statistics showed WA retail turnover rose 3.7 per cent in February to reach $2 billion, but was down 2.7 per cent on the same month last year.

Supermarket and grocery, liquor, food and pharmaceutical, cosmetic and toiletry retailing all recorded an increase in turnover compared to the same time last year, while department stores, clothing, domestic appliance and household good retailing all fell.

http://www.wabusinessnews.com.au/story/9/71763/Retailers-in-strong-negotiating-position miensie April 16th, 2009, 10:04 AM Was meant to post this earlier, sorry.

http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/255_001.jpg miensie April 16th, 2009, 10:06 AM What about the stores in Australia???

-------------------------------------------------------
New look for Cotton On
16 Apr 2009

Australian fast fashion chain Cotton On has developed a new store format to drive its international expansion strategy.

As first reported in Ragtrader magazine, the retailer had expanded its network of Australian and New Zealand stores to include the Asian market. Cotton On now operated around 400 sites regionally, including new stores in Singapore and Hong Kong.

UK-headquartered design group Dalziel&amp;Pow (D&amp;P), which counted High Street retailer River Island and several footwear retailers at the Westfield London shopping centre in White City as clients, was commissioned to create new formats for the stores.

As part of its venture into the two regions, the retailer had taken on larger, multi-level sites to accommodate its broad portfolio of offerings. These included Cotton On Kids, Cotton On Body and footwear line Rubi shoes.

D&amp;P had retained the brand&apos;s signature red colour for its stores&apos; fascia while shades of grey distinguished separate areas inside. A bespoke merchandising system had also been developed to allow for high volume, flexible and cost effective solutions.

&quot;The decision was made to move away from generic off-the-shelf products and a freestanding, bespoke system was developed,&quot;D&amp;P said.&quot;Also with a functional aesthetic, its white, clean finish clearly defines product stories. Timber cladding to the entrance and cashdesk provides texture and warmth.&quot;

Further store openings across the Asian market, particularly in China, were expected this year. samboy April 16th, 2009, 10:28 AM it sounds very similar to the &apos;bench&apos; concept in some parts of Asia. miensie April 17th, 2009, 03:10 AM it sounds very similar to the &apos;bench&apos; concept in some parts of Asia.

What bench concept, samby? miensie April 17th, 2009, 03:39 AM The Buddha Birthday will be on this weekend at Supreme Court Gardens if any of y&apos;all are interested.

It&apos;s pretty much a whole day affair but If I remember from last year correctly, fireworks start at 8.30-9.00pm.

They have food stalls, some arts and crafts and performances.

I&apos;ll be going :okay: miensie April 17th, 2009, 04:36 AM Small-bar industry gets a new voice to help cut government red tape
17th April 2009, 6:00 WST

When small-bar owner Emma Panier opened King Street venue Etro Bar last November it came after a long, expensive and arduous application process.

Among the first small bars to open in Perth after the former Labor government’s“change of scene”liquor reforms in 2007, she said an onerous public interest assessment was among criteria she had to satisfy under State and local government rules.“It did take a long time to get and it was an expensive process,”Ms Panier said.

But WA’s burgeoning small bar scene is about to get a welcome boost with the formation of an association to lobby government and raise the niche industry’s profile.

Dan Mossenson, a liquor industry lawyer of 40 years, is behind the Small Bar Association of WA that includes“licensee, professional, industry and sponsor”members.

He said yesterday that streamlining the processes now in place for prospective small-bar owners was among issues the association would be addressing.

Councils have been a stumbling block for many applicants, with many assessing applications under categories such as taverns, which required more stringent and often unachievable parking provisions, as well as reacting to residents’concerns.

“Some councils are receptive to the introduction of new licences and others are rather obstructive and unhelpful,”Mr Mossenson said.“The association is designed to help facilitate the process of more of these diverse licences being available to the general public.”

Mr Mossenson said the association, which will be launched officially on Monday, had already had a win, with the director of Liquor Licensing agreeing to process small-bar applications without the sign-off first from local authorities.

So far, 18 small bars have opened in WA, with six to open soon and seven applications before the director of Liquor Licensing.

BEATRICE THOMAS Dilaz89 April 17th, 2009, 05:29 AM 12778 Soho House Pty Ltd Application for the grant of a Small Bar licence in respect of premises situated in Perth and known as Wolfe Lane. 22/04/2009 27/03/2009 tbor April 17th, 2009, 06:20 AM Nice. I heart Wolfe Lane.
:banana: :banana: miensie April 17th, 2009, 08:35 AM I just came back from 45 minutes of just wandering around NB, taking a look at the different places to eat, the various boutiques around and the upgrades being made to the area. This is the first time I had the feeling that I was back in KL or Bangkok. I don&apos;t get that same vibe walking around the city during lunchtime. There&apos;s just so much going on right now in NB and so many things to look at - I could&apos;ve kept walking but had to go back to work.

There&apos;s some awesome little boutiques and cake shops around.

Tried looking for some sake for you, Sanj, but no luck.

I managed to find a pair of ivory leather gloves, a packet of corn chips I used to eat as a child back in Thailand, a green rolled sweet with mungbean, and a homemade cupcake with pink icing. All in the space of 30 minutes and within shops located a few streets down from each other.

I&apos;ve decided NB beats West Perth, heads down, thumbs up :banana: Sanj April 17th, 2009, 12:54 PM I just came back from 45 minutes of just wandering around NB, taking a look at the different places to eat, the various boutiques around and the upgrades being made to the area. This is the first time I had the feeling that I was back in KL or Bangkok. I don&apos;t get that same vibe walking around the city during lunchtime. There&apos;s just so much going on right now in NB and so many things to look at - I could&apos;ve kept walking but had to go back to work.

There&apos;s some awesome little boutiques and cake shops around.

Tried looking for some sake for you, Sanj, but no luck.

I managed to find a pair of ivory leather gloves, a packet of corn chips I used to eat as a child back in Thailand, a green rolled sweet with mungbean, and a homemade cupcake with pink icing. All in the space of 30 minutes and within shops located a few streets down from each other.

I&apos;ve decided NB beats West Perth, heads down, thumbs up :banana:

good to hear. i love NB.

james st is a shithole on weekend nights and i avoid it but apart from that NB is great. im there quite regularly for food as u know.

there is a place that has opened near icey ice that does taiwanese style buns filled with stewed pork for around $4.50. pretty damn tasty as well (altho the bun itself could be better).

thanks for looking for the sake too. ive tried to go that place that nate recommended twice but both times they have been closed by the time i got there after work. jackso April 19th, 2009, 05:27 PM A little google search has told me that a company called page kirkland is heading up the project management for Prada&apos;s move into perth. They value the project at $11 million.

http://www.pagekirkland.com/home.asp?pageid=1BD2BEB963118660&amp;projectid=DD4CC9559B1624D7 samboy April 20th, 2009, 02:11 AM they have to sell a lot of handbags to get some ROI ;) miensie April 20th, 2009, 03:37 AM Metalicus taken on Friday 17th with my phone:
http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/Metalicus.jpg

The pavement of Wesley Quarter. This is only a few, there&apos;s a lot more. I think it&apos;s fantastic:
http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/Wesley1.jpg
http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/Wesley2.jpg
http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/Wesley3.jpg jackso April 20th, 2009, 03:41 AM I think a couple of the stores in Wesley might be rgeretting opening early, parlicularlu Jan Logan. I think just because not many peole know its there. I rarely see people in there. miensie April 20th, 2009, 03:49 AM I went to Zekka on Saturday. Had a mocha and a slice of the mudcake. $9.50. Mocha wasn&apos;t strong enough for me and the cake had too much of a somewhat bitter cocoa taste. Presentation was great though. I will be going back though, it&apos;s a cool little place, very much as if you&apos;re in your own little world. Service was good and I was very impressed with the sense of style of the barista. Not many guys can pull off the long-sleeved shirt tucked into bermuda shorts with loafers look :)



Went to the Buddha Birthday and was supremely disappointed. Food was bad. Not sure why but very different from last year. We bought so much food but none of it was good and we were still hungry so decided to try Siena&apos;s in Leederville.

BAD IDEA.

Siena&apos;s told us we&apos;d be waiting an hour+ for a table. Tried Cafe Villa who told us we needed a reservation as they were all booked out. Finally went to Monza and were able to score a table. The place was half empty/full and that it itself should&apos;ve set us off. The entire experience was horrible. The waitress that served us was very abrupt and rude and the food was bad. I understand that you could be busy, especially on a Saturday night, but the place wasn&apos;t that full so there&apos;s no excuse for that kind of behaviour.

I won&apos;t be going back there again :ohno:



And Leederville gives me the same feeling that NB does on a weekend night. Just as many skanks and idiots running around.

And I only remembered Jus Burgers (which I&apos;ve been dying to try) was in Leederville when our food arrived :hammer: miensie April 20th, 2009, 03:57 AM thanks for looking for the sake too. ive tried to go that place that nate recommended twice but both times they have been closed by the time i got there after work.

Where&apos;s the place, Sanj? If it&apos;s not too far away I could wander down and get some for you.


I think a couple of the stores in Wesley might be rgeretting opening early, parlicularlu Jan Logan. I think just because not many peole know its there. I rarely see people in there.

Not sure if I&apos;d say they regret it as Wesley is still half-empty but I do agree that not many people know it&apos;s there. I went past on Friday night around 6pm and it was shut. Review and Alannah Hill get a good crowd though and I think once the new stores going there have opened, it should pick up.

I did see a group of guys working on the store right on the corner of Wesley Quarter on the Hay St side. I ducked my head in to have a look and the place is HUGE. Burberry or Armani maybe? jackso April 20th, 2009, 04:02 AM Yeah that&apos;s what I mean. I think they would have been better of waiting till June/July like the rest. At first I thought the hay st side was Burberry, but then last week dilaz mentioned it was Armani. Its massive though! miensie April 20th, 2009, 04:08 AM Yeah that&apos;s what I mean. I think they would have been better of waiting till June/July like the rest. At first I thought the hay st side was Burberry, but then last week dilaz mentioned it was Armani. Its massive though!

:rofl:

Yeah, you did put the word &apos;early&apos; in there. I&apos;m sorry jackso, it&apos;s early Monday morning and I&apos;m still drinking my coffee.

I saw the store on Friday night, they&apos;d left the door open but I didn&apos;t have my camera with me and the one on my phone wouldn&apos;t cooperate so I thought I&apos;d just get a photo on Saturday as I&apos;d be in the city again anyway. Then I went there and it was shut :bash:



Also, I was dragged to Wasteland on Friday night. Can I just say that place probably has some of the most over-priced stuff around. $1,000+ for a puffy men&apos;s jacket? No thanks. And to make it worse, I was then in Hugo Boss half an hour later and they had a divine men&apos;s wool jacket for $899.

WHERE&apos;S THE LOGIC?!

I also wandered into Realm to have a look at the Fred Perry polo. Wasn&apos;t overly impressed. That material&apos;s still too stiff for me. I actually did see a lovely men&apos;s polo in Wasteland (ha!) in the softest material that was retailing for $220. Sanj April 20th, 2009, 04:22 AM Where&apos;s the place, Sanj? If it&apos;s not too far away I could wander down and get some for you.






its on fitzgerald st, in that first row of shops running from corner of fitzgerald and roe til james st. it is in between a vietnamese restaurant (with a yellow and red sign) and the northbridge pharmacy which has recently closed down and relocated to tyne.

if u are able to wander down one day that would be great. any slightly dry sake up toaround $40-$45 would be fine, but if the guy doesnt know which sakes are dry etc any one will do.

thanks! miensie April 20th, 2009, 04:24 AM I know this is in NSW but OMG :ohno:

--------------------------------------------------------
Retailers“disrespectful”to fallen Diggers: RSL
April 20, 2009 09:25

The RSL has lashed out at retailers who have applied to the NSW government to trade on Anzac Day morning.

State RSL president Don Rowe said the retailers were being disrespectful to fallen soldiers.

Under current law, larger stores in NSW cannot open until 1pm on the day.

&quot;We do certainly have a hassle that major retailers are trying to open on Saturday morning,&apos;&apos; Rowe told The Sunday Telegraph.

&quot;Anzac Day morning is for us to commemorate, reflect and remember those who gave sacrifice. It is disrespectful for shops to open.&apos;&apos;

While TAB outlets and pubs and clubs are allowed to operate, laws governing retail outlets insist shops with more than five staff must remain closed for half the day.

German supermarket chain Aldi is among dozens of retailers which have applied to trade on Anzac Day, citing tough economic conditions. Aldi was knocked back.

According to a list obtained by The Sunday Telegraph, 22 retail outlets applied for trading exemption. Others included surfwear store Surfection and clothing outlets YD and Tarocash.

Children&apos;s wear store Pumpkin Patch Originals and lingerie shop Bras N Things, at Castle Towers and Westpoint Blacktown, also applied to trade.

The Office of Industrial Relations has not approved any of the applications.

Meanwhile, an independent retail analyst says that allowing people to spend on pokies and alcohol on Anzac Day is“ludicrous”.

Stirling Griff said that in South Australia, department stores and supermarkets were forced to stay closed for all of Anzac Day. The law depicted South Australia as a backwater state, he added.

His views were supported by Business SA, which has called for total deregulation of shopping hours. miensie April 20th, 2009, 04:26 AM its on fitzgerald st, in that first row of shops running from corner of fitzgerald and roe til james st. it is in between a vietnamese restaurant (with a yellow and red sign) and the northbridge pharmacy which has recently closed down and relocated to tyne.

if u are able to wander down one day that would be great. any slightly dry sake up toaround $40-$45 would be fine, but if the guy doesnt know which sakes are dry etc any one will do.

thanks!

Yeah, that&apos;s not too far down. I&apos;ll see what I can do :) ryan79 April 20th, 2009, 04:33 AM they have to sell a lot of handbags to get some ROI ;)

:lol: Not really. 11 mill will buy you about 10 handbags :) ryan79 April 20th, 2009, 04:39 AM I know this is in NSW but OMG :ohno:

--------------------------------------------------------
Retailers disrespectful to fallen Diggers: RSL
April 20, 2009 09:25

The RSL has lashed out at retailers who have applied to the NSW government to trade on Anzac Day morning.

State RSL president Don Rowe said the retailers were being disrespectful to fallen soldiers.

Under current law, larger stores in NSW cannot open until 1pm on the day.

&quot;We do certainly have a hassle that major retailers are trying to open on Saturday morning,&apos;&apos; Rowe told The Sunday Telegraph.

&quot;Anzac Day morning is for us to commemorate, reflect and remember those who gave sacrifice. It is disrespectful for shops to open.&apos;&apos;

While TAB outlets and pubs and clubs are allowed to operate, laws governing retail outlets insist shops with more than five staff must remain closed for half the day.

German supermarket chain Aldi is among dozens of retailers which have applied to trade on Anzac Day, citing tough economic conditions. Aldi was knocked back.

According to a list obtained by The Sunday Telegraph, 22 retail outlets applied for trading exemption. Others included surfwear store Surfection and clothing outlets YD and Tarocash.

Children&apos;s wear store Pumpkin Patch Originals and lingerie shop Bras N Things, at Castle Towers and Westpoint Blacktown, also applied to trade.

The Office of Industrial Relations has not approved any of the applications.

Meanwhile, an independent retail analyst says that allowing people to spend on pokies and alcohol on Anzac Day is ludicrous.

Stirling Griff said that in South Australia, department stores and supermarkets were forced to stay closed for all of Anzac Day. The law depicted South Australia as a backwater state, he added.

His views were supported by Business SA, which has called for total deregulation of shopping hours.

Shit, if shops can stay closed on Easter and Xmas day they can well and truly stay closed on Anzac Day morning.

This country is just plain backwards. Sanj April 20th, 2009, 04:40 AM I went to Zekka on Saturday. Had a mocha and a slice of the mudcake. $9.50. Mocha wasn&apos;t strong enough for me and the cake had too much of a somewhat bitter cocoa taste. Presentation was great though. I will be going back though, it&apos;s a cool little place, very much as if you&apos;re in your own little world. Service was good and I was very impressed with the sense of style of the barista. Not many guys can pull off the long-sleeved shirt tucked into bermuda shorts with loafers look :)



Went to the Buddha Birthday and was supremely disappointed. Food was bad. Not sure why but very different from last year. We bought so much food but none of it was good and we were still hungry so decided to try Siena&apos;s in Leederville.

BAD IDEA.

Siena&apos;s told us we&apos;d be waiting an hour+ for a table. Tried Cafe Villa who told us we needed a reservation as they were all booked out. Finally went to Monza and were able to score a table. The place was half empty/full and that it itself should&apos;ve set us off. The entire experience was horrible. The waitress that served us was very abrupt and rude and the food was bad. I understand that you could be busy, especially on a Saturday night, but the place wasn&apos;t that full so there&apos;s no excuse for that kind of behaviour.

I won&apos;t be going back there again :ohno:



And Leederville gives me the same feeling that NB does on a weekend night. Just as many skanks and idiots running around.

And I only remembered Jus Burgers (which I&apos;ve been dying to try) was in Leederville when our food arrived :hammer:

fucking hell. 1 hour wait for a table at siennas and fully booked at cafe villa? ive eaten at both places and neither deserve to be that successful.

mind u im probably suffering one of those&quot;why is similar food so much cheaper and better in sydney and melbourne&quot;phases after just coming back

i had a work lunch in wetherill park which is an industrial area around 40kms out of sydney and i had the most stunning scampi linguini which was only $22.

i cant imagine getting a similar thing in malaga at any price let alone $22. it was really really good as well. ryan79 April 20th, 2009, 04:41 AM I went to Zekka on Saturday. Had a mocha and a slice of the mudcake. $9.50. Mocha wasn&apos;t strong enough for me and the cake had too much of a somewhat bitter cocoa taste. Presentation was great though. I will be going back though, it&apos;s a cool little place, very much as if you&apos;re in your own little world. Service was good and I was very impressed with the sense of style of the barista. Not many guys can pull off the long-sleeved shirt tucked into bermuda shorts with loafers look :)



Went to the Buddha Birthday and was supremely disappointed. Food was bad. Not sure why but very different from last year. We bought so much food but none of it was good and we were still hungry so decided to try Siena&apos;s in Leederville.

BAD IDEA.

Siena&apos;s told us we&apos;d be waiting an hour+ for a table. Tried Cafe Villa who told us we needed a reservation as they were all booked out. Finally went to Monza and were able to score a table. The place was half empty/full and that it itself should&apos;ve set us off. The entire experience was horrible. The waitress that served us was very abrupt and rude and the food was bad. I understand that you could be busy, especially on a Saturday night, but the place wasn&apos;t that full so there&apos;s no excuse for that kind of behaviour.

I won&apos;t be going back there again :ohno:



And Leederville gives me the same feeling that NB does on a weekend night. Just as many skanks and idiots running around.

And I only remembered Jus Burgers (which I&apos;ve been dying to try) was in Leederville when our food arrived :hammer:

I&apos;ve been to Monza before and I agree the service is very ordinary but the food I had was quite decent.

Leederville has very little to offer in terms of decent nightlife. The busiest place there is the Hipp-e club. Says it all.

Niche bar is ok. Sanj April 20th, 2009, 05:02 AM have u been to double lucky ryan? i havent been there yet. miensie April 20th, 2009, 05:12 AM fucking hell. 1 hour wait for a table at siennas and fully booked at cafe villa? ive eaten at both places and neither deserve to be that successful.

mind u im probably suffering one of those&quot;why is similar food so much cheaper and better in sydney and melbourne&quot;phases after just coming back

i had a work lunch in wetherill park which is an industrial area around 40kms out of sydney and i had the most stunning scampi linguini which was only $22.

i cant imagine getting a similar thing in malaga at any price let alone $22. it was really really good as well.

Siena&apos;s was chock-a-block though. I couldn&apos;t see an available table anywhere. Cafe Villa had a few open but they were reserved or so I was told.

How was the trip? You didn&apos;t end up at Tetsuya&apos;s did you?

$22 is reasonable. My pasta was $26.50 and it was bleh. I remember the ravioli was only $18.50 at Galileo&apos;s. I&apos;d rather pay $45 for the ravioli at Perugino than eat at Monza again. desperaterobots April 20th, 2009, 05:28 AM I am now officially hooked on www.apartmenttherapy.com

The places featured on that site make me drool with envy - something i never thought I&apos;d do with tiny studio apartments. Sanj April 20th, 2009, 05:31 AM Siena&apos;s was chock-a-block though. I couldn&apos;t see an available table anywhere. Cafe Villa had a few open but they were reserved or so I was told.

How was the trip? You didn&apos;t end up at Tetsuya&apos;s did you?

$22 is reasonable. My pasta was $26.50 and it was bleh. I remember the ravioli was only $18.50 at Galileo&apos;s. I&apos;d rather pay $45 for the ravioli at Perugino than eat at Monza again.

$22 is very reasonable considering there was a fair bit of scampi and the pasta was very well made. that was also their most expensive pasta. stuff like their angus rib eye etc was all also a good 20% cheaper than what u would get here.

the trip was good, but really tiring and busy. didnt have any major meals in sydney due to a schedule change (had to rush to mudgee and back in 2 days). tetsuya was never on the cards due to a lack of time.

had 2 good meals in melbourne tho, at movida and ezard, which ive been to before.

what pasta did u have at monza? miensie April 20th, 2009, 05:47 AM $22 is very reasonable considering there was a fair bit of scampi and the pasta was very well made. that was also their most expensive pasta. stuff like their angus rib eye etc was all also a good 20% cheaper than what u would get here.

the trip was good, but really tiring and busy. didnt have any major meals in sydney due to a schedule change (had to rush to mudgee and back in 2 days). tetsuya was never on the cards due to a lack of time.

had 2 good meals in melbourne tho, at movida and ezard, which ive been to before.

what pasta did u have at monza?

Yeah I know what you mean. It&apos;s exactly the same thing I go through when I come back from a holiday overseas. Those horrible withdrawal symptoms.

Movida is that place that&apos;s really hard to get into, no? The one that acc went to last year?

I had a linguine dish with a simple roasted tomato and bean sauce. The linguine was tossed in a kind of butter. I thought, ok, this is a simple dish; shouldn&apos;t be that hard to pull off. Wrong! The thing is though, I could easily see it being done well at other places.

It really irks me when you go out and have either really bad food or have a bad service experience. Sanj April 20th, 2009, 05:52 AM $26 for a vegetarian pasta dish? no wonder they are struggling.

Also the problem with simple dishes (for average chefs) is that there isnt much to hide behind, so it is easier to screw up.

yeah movida is the place acc went to. it was very good but didnt blow me away. if i did live in melb i would probably go there fairly regularly miensie April 20th, 2009, 05:59 AM $26 for a vegetarian pasta dish? no wonder they are struggling.

Exactly what I was thinking! Bastards...
I could&apos;ve made pasta myself at home. At least I would&apos;ve liked it.
I ate less than half of the dish :puke:


Also the problem with simple dishes (for average chefs) is that there isnt much to hide behind, so it is easier to screw up.

:lol: I never thought about it that way. Makes complete sense though.
The ravioli at both Galileo and Perugino were so simple yet so amazing.


yeah movida is the place acc went to. it was very good but didnt blow me away. if i did live in melb i would probably go there fairly regularly

I remember the photo&apos;s acc posted of his trip there. Looked very good and all very cheap. I think less than $100 for 2 people. ryan79 April 20th, 2009, 06:09 AM have u been to double lucky ryan? i havent been there yet.

No haven&apos;t actually. I keep forgetting its even there. Sanj April 20th, 2009, 06:10 AM yeah simple food is by definition easier to do than complex and complicated dishes but any imperfections are pretty obvious. i remember one of the best pasta dishes ive had in years was a lobster linguini dish at zafferano and i wouldve been surprised if there were more than 5 things in the whole dish. it was just lobster in a very simple tomato sauce with chilli and garlic and it was beautiful but it only worked cos every component of it was perfectly cooked and seasoned. miensie April 20th, 2009, 06:20 AM I&apos;m still sad about this. I love Morrissey :(

----------------------------------------------------
Morrissey: From fast fashion to fast food
20 Apr 2009

By Assia Benmedjdoub

Retail stores will soon no longer bear his name, but that hasn&apos;t stopped Peter Morrissey from sampling other fashion ventures.

The fashion designer has been commissioned to create uniforms for staff at fast chain giant McDonald&apos;s. The commission followed news earlier this year that fashion group M Webster Holdings, which had owned the Peter Morrissey label since 2006, would gradually close its small network of &apos;Morrissey&apos; stores across Australia.

Morrisey&apos;s latest commission would represent his first venture into uniforms, having created corporate attire for staff at airline provider Qantas.

As reported in Ragtrader magazine, couture designer Daniel Avakian had also entered the restaurant game this year with a major uniform commission for high-end Sydney restaurant Rockpool Bar&amp;Grill. ryan79 April 20th, 2009, 07:01 AM Staff in Berlin MacDonalds have cool uniforms. alvse April 20th, 2009, 07:27 AM I&apos;m still sad about this. I love Morrissey :(

----------------------------------------------------
Morrissey: From fast fashion to fast food
20 Apr 2009

By Assia Benmedjdoub

Retail stores will soon no longer bear his name, but that hasn&apos;t stopped Peter Morrissey from sampling other fashion ventures.

The fashion designer has been commissioned to create uniforms for staff at fast chain giant McDonald&apos;s. The commission followed news earlier this year that fashion group M Webster Holdings, which had owned the Peter Morrissey label since 2006, would gradually close its small network of &apos;Morrissey&apos; stores across Australia.

Morrisey&apos;s latest commission would represent his first venture into uniforms, having created corporate attire for staff at airline provider Qantas.

As reported in Ragtrader magazine, couture designer Daniel Avakian had also entered the restaurant game this year with a major uniform commission for high-end Sydney restaurant Rockpool Bar&amp;Grill.



the current uniforms are Mossimo yes? acc521 April 20th, 2009, 02:13 PM Lol miensie I thought Morrissey (the singer) had died or something!

Ryan, I&apos;ll go into one and take a pic next week! ryan79 April 20th, 2009, 02:36 PM Lol miensie I thought Morrissey (the singer) had died or something!

Ryan, I&apos;ll go into one and take a pic next week!

:lol: Cool! Their Maccas are cool buildings cool. Everything in Berlin is cool really. miensie April 21st, 2009, 04:06 AM Lol miensie I thought Morrissey (the singer) had died or something!


Haha, sorry!

I probably should&apos;ve said I was still sad that we won&apos;t be seeing Morrissey&apos;s designs in shops anymore. That&apos;s good quality designs gone buh-bye :( Sanj April 22nd, 2009, 04:55 AM haha dont u love how wine and tapas are now the buzzwords?

it annoys me that u read the word tapas every other day yet there is bugger all proper tapas in perth. miensie April 22nd, 2009, 05:01 AM Duende, Sanj? BartBart April 22nd, 2009, 05:03 AM haha dont u love how wine and tapas are now the buzzwords?

it annoys me that u read the word tapas every other day yet there is bugger all proper tapas in perth.

I don&apos;t get tapas either - it is just people making noise on wooden floors with their shoes, for f@#ks sake! Sanj April 22nd, 2009, 05:04 AM yeah duende would be one of them. gypsy tapas is meant to be ok altho ive heard mixed reports and im hoping for good things when pata negra opens (and i would expect it to be good).

apart from that its a joke. tapas isnt meant to be a wanky expensive meal, and most places here that have tapas options cant seem to grasp the concept correctly.

look at the pony club. i dont know anyone who has left there full without spending at least $80 per head. tbor April 22nd, 2009, 06:45 AM apart from that its a joke. tapas isnt meant to be a wanky expensive meal, and most places here that have tapas options cant seem to grasp the concept correctly.


100% agree, tapas is not meant to be expensive! I would love to know what spanish people think when they go to a tapas restaurant here. It would be the equivalent of going to a resturant in Spain and paying $80 for a vegemite sandwich :nuts: miensie April 22nd, 2009, 06:46 AM 15/04/2009
683-703 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Shop fitout - Mishanghi
220,000.00
BA-RF 2009/116

15/04/2009
&quot;CITY RAILWAY PHARMACY&quot;
Shop 8/378 Wellington Street PERTH WA 6000
Shop Fitout - Priceline Pharmacy
200,000.00
BA-RF 2009/117

15/04/2009
&quot;CITY WEST&quot;
66-84 Railway Street WEST PERTH WA 6005
Installation of 5 new Harvey Norman&amp;Domayne Signage to building.
85,000.00
SIGNDA 2009/6523

16/04/2009
840 Wellington Street WEST PERTH WA 6005
Shop Fitout - ISPA Kebabs
70,000.00
BA-RF 2009/122

16/04/2009
166-170 Murray Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Retail Fitout - Gloria Jeans Coffee
198,000.00
BA-RF 2009/123

17/04/2009
166-170 Murray Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
1X Suspended Illuminated Sign - Gloria Jeans Coffee
19,000.00
SIGNBA 2009/6010

16/04/2009
&quot;MCNESS ROYAL ARCADE&quot;
611-619 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Refurbishment shop 5 - Just Spectacles
120,000.00
DA 2009/2095

17/04/2009
&quot;CARILLON CITY&quot;
674-678 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
fitout 90,000.00
BA 2009/128 crave April 22nd, 2009, 07:47 AM morrissey lost tha plot years ago... miensie April 22nd, 2009, 08:05 AM You talking about the man or his designs, crave?

If it&apos;s the man, it doesn&apos;t really matter. He can be as weird as they come just as long as his designs are good. acc521 April 22nd, 2009, 11:53 AM haha dont u love how wine and tapas are now the buzzwords?

it annoys me that u read the word tapas every other day yet there is bugger all proper tapas in perth.

I was just about to post the same thing. It&apos;s the same in Europe. Lots of places trying to pass off overpriced finger food as tapas.

Also, the trendy thing nowdays seems to be to drink Strongbow, which I noticed in the few months before I left Perth. Amazing what a packaging refresh and a youthful advertising campaign can do. samboy April 22nd, 2009, 12:17 PM Next time you go to a restaurant, order a main and ask them to give you a bunch of small plates so you can re-arrange the contents and voila you&apos;ve got cheap tapas, no worse than a lot of other so called tapas joints around Perth.
Like Sanj said though it seems to be the buzzword these days, winebar and tapas. Hey as long as people are willing to pay for it then good luck to them I say. Ipggi April 22nd, 2009, 01:31 PM Clearly that CityWest development is dead. But on a positive side Perth is getting its first Domayne furniture store. It&apos;s still basically more expensive Harvey Norman furniture, but more choice is always a good thing .. http://www.domayne.com.au dallastexjr April 22nd, 2009, 06:18 PM Clearly that CityWest development is dead.

That&apos;s sad - I really liked that building design; had an art deco feel about it. BartBart April 23rd, 2009, 04:22 AM http://www.thewest.com.au/default.aspx?MenuID=77&amp;ContentID=137472
Shop hours not open and shut

23rd April 2009, 6:00 WST

Perth shoppers face a confusing mix of trading hours this Anzac Day long weekend, retailers have warned.

Under WA’s retail trading laws, small retailers can open all weekend in the metropolitan area but general retailers, shopping centres and big supermarket chains are not permitted to trade on Saturday.

(link to Long weekend hours)

Most shops have been granted a permit to trade on the Monday public holiday but opening hours will vary. Shops permitted to open on a normal Sunday will be able to open this Sunday.

Retail Traders Association boss Wayne Spencer said the situation was complicated and that it could be confusing for shoppers.

Mr Spencer said the last time Anzac Day had fallen on a Saturday was 10 years ago and that the process to get permits to trade on the Monday was absurd.

The State Government announced in February that individual retailers, industry bodies and designated tourism precincts would be able to apply for permits to trade on the Monday. It is understood the possibility of losing six trading days in April because of Easter holidays as well as Anzac Day falling on a Saturday persuaded the Government to act.

Shops in the Perth and Fremantle tourism precincts and in Rockingham and Two Rocks are allowed to open on Monday.

Shopping Centre Council executive director Milton Cockburn said trading restrictions in WA on the Anzac Day long weekend were frustrating.

He said only WA and the ACT had a public holiday on Monday and that most other States allowed trading all weekend after 1pm on Saturday.

Property Council WA executive director Joe Lenzo said shoppers faced confusion about trading hours this weekend and that was detrimental to the shops.

“People aren’t sure whether their local shopping centre is open or not and they might not go,”he said.“It’s a bit ludicrous because it’s the only State that had to go through this sort of detail to be able to open on the Monday.”

Returned and Services League president Bill Gaynor said he didn’t believe general retailers should be able to open on Saturday after 1pm.

“If they can’t afford to give up one day of trading in remembrance of those who gave their lives then it’s a pretty poor show,”he said.

Pubs and restaurants can open all weekend but are not permitted to serve alcohol before noon on Saturday.

Lotterywest outlets not in shopping centres will open on Saturday.

Nightclubs and the Burswood Casino are required to close at 3am on Saturday but can reopen from noon.

PHILIPPA PERRY miensie April 23rd, 2009, 06:53 AM Retailers facing &apos;tenancy crisis&apos; - ARA
April 22, 2009 14:57

Retailers are facing&quot;a tenancy crisis&quot;says the Australian Retailers Association, which has urged the Federal Government to take action.

ARA&apos;s executive director Richard Evans said the Federal Government must act on the advice in the Productivity Commission&apos;s (PC) Market for Retail Tenancy Leases final report (released in August 2008)&quot;to help alleviate spiralling occupancy costs caused by the global financial crisis&quot;.

&quot;There has been no action on the issue of retail leasing since the well overdue recommendations from the PC over eight months ago, including a nationally-consistent retail leasing legislation and the introduction of a voluntary code to curb robust behaviour,&quot;said Evans.

&quot;Retailers - who have been struggling with low consumer confidence and increasing costs for over 12 months - are still waiting for the Rudd Government to take action on unfair and restrictive retail leasing legislation,&quot;he said.

&quot;Occupancy costs totalling over 15 per cent of retail turnover are simply not sustainable. With low consumer confidence and falling retail sales, tenancy costs are rising through the roof at the moment.

&quot;Retailers are hurting and while landlords are trying to assist some individual tenants the larger issue of lease renegotiation still remains. The government must step in and take long overdue action to help retailers reduce spiralling occupancy costs in tough economic times.&quot;

Evans said governments have been told for many years that shopping centres operate in a virtual monopoly due to planning laws and have restrictive competition practices within their negotiations with retail tenants.

&quot;As yet no Federal Government has had the courage to resolve this issue.

&quot;Retail tenants are disadvantaged at the negotiation table due to one-sided disclosure requirements and this issue can be remedied by:

. Separating legislation for major shopping centres from suburban high street retail outlets.
. Simplifying retail leasing legislation nationally through harmonisation of state laws.
. Applying a code of conduct to the sector administrated by the ACCC.
. Disclosure of turnover figures to independent third party to be reported at category level.

&quot;The Rudd Government - with its policy of reducing the cost burden of differing state legislations - must take immediate action on retail leasing,&quot;Evans said. BartBart April 27th, 2009, 04:20 AM http://www.thewest.com.au/default.aspx?MenuID=77&amp;ContentID=138206
Holidays fuel Myer call for shop hours summit

27th April 2009, 6:00 WST

Myer has called for a summit to fix WA trading law anomalies highlighted by the Anzac Day long weekend.

All Perth retailers are able to open from 8am to 6pm today while Fremantle and Rockingham can trade from 10am to 5pm, though opening times are up to individual shops.

Myer’s WA stores received State Government permission to open from 10am to 5pm in what Myer communications general manager Mitch Catlin describes as an extended trading hours experiment. He said it was time major retailers, the WA Government and the Opposition put all options on the table. WA and the ACT are the only areas of Australia that have a public holiday on a Monday if Anzac Day falls on the weekend.

“There are some differences on WA trading restrictions and laws (to) other parts of Australia,”Mr Catlin said.“Everyone has different opinions, different options, different avenues and the best thing would be for everyone to sit down and come up with a uniform approach.”

Retail Traders’Association WA executive director Wayne Spencer said trading restrictions around Anzac Day were problematic because they followed Easter public holidays.

“The Government has got to do something to remove these anomalies because if retailers close for one day there is a lot of expense and chaos created, two days is mayhem and three days you just don’t want to know,”he said.

Mr Spencer said restricted trading for four days over Easter followed by three days for Anzac Day was inconvenient for consumers and did not give shops a chance to recoup.

Premier Colin Barnett said he would not take part in Myer’s proposed summit. He hoped extended weeknight trading, where shops could open until 9pm from Monday to Friday, would be in place by September.

He called on Myer, David Jones and other retailers to take up the challenge of opening during the evening.

A spokeswoman for Opposition Leader Eric Ripper said he would meet retailers but would not take part in a summit.

STEPHANIE PAINTER BartBart April 29th, 2009, 01:45 AM http://www.thewest.com.au/default.aspx?MenuID=77&amp;ContentID=138785
Carrots dangled as WA retail rental growth halts

29th April 2009, 6:15 WST
Rental growth in WA retail has ground to a halt in some sectors and gone backwards in others in the first three months of the year, prompting a flourish of incentives such as funding for fit-outs and rent holidays.

And retail space supply is shrinking, thanks largely to finance drying up and the effects of a generally tougher retail environment.

Jones Lang LaSalle’s March quarter statistics for the retail commercial property market show that average rents slipped 0.5 per cent in prime CBD spots.

In sub-regional areas rents fell 0.1 per cent, compared with growth of 5.7 per cent during the the last calendar year.

In regional areas growth was only 0.4 per cent compared with last year’s impressive 6.4 per cent.

Average rents in neighbourhood shops grew 0.2 per cent this quarter but were flat in bulky goods outlets. JLL research director Leigh Warner said the results showed a significant slowdown in rental growth and owners were increasingly offering incentives that would not affect the valuation of their property.

“It is quite expensive to fit out a shop so it’s quite a common thing for landlords to offer a contribution to the fit-out,”he said.“They are keen to make sure they keep the occupancy up.”

Rent-free periods were another form of incentive. However, owners were often loath to lower the asking rent because it affected the valuation of the property.

JLL’s national head of retail, Tony Doherty, said owners were keen to work with struggling retailers to maintain higher levels of occupancy and so the number of rental incentives was on the rise.

But he warned that requests for rental discounts by tenants who could not demonstrate hardship would not be well received by owners.

&quot;We have had examples of opportunistic retailers requesting across the board rental reductions in their national stores,”he said.“Retailers doing this should think twice as owners will only respond to genuine requests to help those retailers struggling in the current economic conditions.”

Nationwide, nine new retail space projects were completed in the quarter, three of which were in WA. They were stage one of the extension to Claremont Arcade shopping centre (14,000sqm), a new 5000sqm neighbourhood shopping centre at Carramar and the Albany Central shopping centre, which is a new 10,000sqm bulky goods centre.

Throughout Australia seven new developments started to come out of the ground, two of them in WA. They were stage 2 of the Claremont Arcade extension (16,000sqm) and a new 4000sqm neighbourhood centre in Beechboro called The Springs.

Retail space under construction in WA is relatively evenly distributed across the sectors and no single sector is over-represented. The breakdown is regional centres (26 per cent), CBD centres (22 per cent), bulky goods (17 per cent), sub-regional (16 per cent), neighbourhood (13 per cent) and other (6 per cent).

“Over the past year there has been a clear shift in the construction pipeline away from building smaller new centres towards extensions to larger regional and CBD centres,”Mr Warner said.“In particular, it has been the bulky goods sector that has become much less desirable to developers because the sub-sector is particularly vulnerable to weaker discretionary spending in the current economic downturn.”

PERTH
CATHY SAUNDERS samboy April 29th, 2009, 02:09 AM May be one day (as consumers) we&apos;ll stop paying for someone&apos;s over-inflated lease and start paying for good products and competent service in WA. I have a dream.... Sanj April 29th, 2009, 02:45 AM May be one day (as consumers) we&apos;ll stop paying for someone&apos;s over-inflated lease and start paying for good products and competent service in WA. I have a dream....

crazy old man. id be happy with better products and less incompetent service.

baby steps samboy April 29th, 2009, 03:05 AM crazy old man. id be happy with better products and less incompetent service.

baby steps

lol! forget about that. At my age I&apos;d be happy to get out of bed without my knees buckling. :lol: miensie April 30th, 2009, 03:48 AM http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/SCAN0274_001.jpg
http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/SCAN0275_001.jpg Dilaz89 April 30th, 2009, 04:34 AM has anyone heard anything about peter bell opening up a club in mt lawley? GAbE27 April 30th, 2009, 05:15 AM has anyone heard anything about peter bell opening up a club in mt lawley?

Nope, unless its the one next to soto?

But the owners of Highs and Lows were opening a second bar at the old Ritches tapas resturant.

Any word news on that one? miensie April 30th, 2009, 05:17 AM Nope, unless its the one next to soto?


Soto, as in soup??? gotime April 30th, 2009, 05:31 AM Nope, unless its the one next to soto?

But the owners of Highs and Lows were opening a second bar at the old Ritches tapas resturant.

Any word news on that one?

as far as i know, it&apos;s been canned. a few of the partners involved aren&apos;t on the best of terms any longer... GAbE27 April 30th, 2009, 06:48 AM Soto, as in soup???

:ohno: no not as in the soup....

Gotime u talking about the one next to soto or the HALs one? or both... :-P miensie April 30th, 2009, 06:50 AM :ohno: no not as in the soup....

Haha...just making sure. You never know nowadays - lemon leaf, red cabbage :nuts:

P.S. You are sooo Asian, Gabs :P GAbE27 April 30th, 2009, 06:58 AM Haha...just making sure. You never know nowadays - lemon leaf, red cabbage :nuts:

P.S. You are sooo Asian, Gabs :P

i am asian by assocation!! hehe. my Gf tells me I get a lil more asian every day!! gotime April 30th, 2009, 09:02 AM :ohno: no not as in the soup....

Gotime u talking about the one next to soto or the HALs one? or both... :-P

whoops. meant the richies restaurant one. miensie May 1st, 2009, 03:15 AM Saba strategy shift
29 Apr 2009

By Assia Benmedjdoub

Unisex fashion retailer Saba can add another branding coup to its name: the label has secured Scott Schuman, aka The Sartorialist, for a campaign shoot this week.

As reported in Ragtrader magazine, Schuman was in the country as part of a marketing drive by Tourism Australia and Rosemount Australian Fashion Week (RAFW).

A pioneer of street-style fashion photography, his website &apos;The Sartorialist&apos; attracted three million visits per month and Schuman himself was named as one of the 100 top design influencers by Time magazine.

His most recent commercial venture was an advertising campaign for American powerhouse DKNY jeans.

While Schuman&apos;s inaugural visit to Australia was centred around coverage for RAFW - which would wrap up on May 1 - the photographer confirmed he was headed to Melbourne after the event to undertake promotional work for Saba.

This was the second coup of its nature for Saba, which secured Yasmin Sewell for a six-month consultancy contract last year. Sewell had worked as a buying director for British department store Browns and was regularly featured as a style inspiration on The Sartorialist website.
--------------------------

Great stuff. This is the guy who used to work in Men&apos;s Fashion for Bergdorf Goodman. His blog is worth checking out too - lots of images of well-dressed/uniquely-dressed men and women on there from all over the world. miensie May 1st, 2009, 03:18 AM Retailer succeeds in ballsy argument
30 Apr 2009

A surf and skatewear retailer has successfully argued the use of the words balls when not applied to sporting equipment or toys is neither crude nor offensive.

Sole trading company Ramp 2 Ramp was asked to explain its use of the term in a recent television advertisement it created to promote its street and skatewear stock.

The ad showed images of store products, including clothing, board shorts, wallets, shoes, belts and caps with the final image showing details of the store and its location.

However it&apos;s tagline &apos;Have you got enough balls?&quot;attracted the ire of at least one complainant who wrote to the Advertising Standards Bureau (ASB) arguing the term was used solely for shock value.

The unnamed complainant said as there were no balls or&quot;ball game merchandise&quot;in the ad, they could not see any relevance.

&quot;I and my wife find it offensive to be repeatedly assaulted with that term, especially on a mass media, and another indication of slipping standards. I guess we left it to others to complain, but maybe they accept it as progress in lowering standards.&quot;

For its part Ramp 2 Ramp stated that it believed it market was targeted to those in the general public who liked to&quot;live life on the edge&quot;.

The question asked in the ad was intended to be rhetorical and designed to let customers ask themselves whether they had the fortitude to go to the store and look around.

The ASB board ruled that although the use of the &apos;balls&apos; phrase was not specifically relevant to the product being advertised, its use was consistent with its colloquial usage in Australia therefore the ad did not breach the Advertiser Code of Ethics.

The complaint was dismissed.
-----------------------------

lawl samboy May 1st, 2009, 03:19 AM This is why longer life expectancy is not a good thing. miensie May 1st, 2009, 03:21 AM This is why longer life expectancy is not a good thing.

To borrow a saying from Sanj, what u on about? samboy May 1st, 2009, 03:24 AM I just assumed the sad bastard who made the complaint was most likely part of the bored geriatric brigade. Get with the program miensie :lol: miensie May 1st, 2009, 03:26 AM I just assumed the sad bastard who made the complaint was most likely part of the bored geriatric brigade. Get with the program miensie :lol:

:lol:

I thought you meant the longer you live, the more you&apos;ll see this kind of rubbish. True either way I suppose. ryan79 May 1st, 2009, 03:27 AM OMFG! Seriously, one complaint and it makes news. Why?

These people need to be ignored so feel like the dipshits they are. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 04:07 AM This is why longer life expectancy is not a good thing.

haha nice samboy May 1st, 2009, 06:44 AM Despite vowing never go to there, curiosity got the better of me and decided to try a chicken burger at the &apos;burger bistro&apos; (shafto lane). It wasn&apos;t bad, bread good (new norcia), chicken well cooked/seasoned and the garnish ok BUT $13.80 can not be justified. It&apos;s worth $10. But judging from the packed lunch crowd I don&apos;t think my opinion really counts. What recession. ryan79 May 1st, 2009, 06:52 AM I&apos;ve wanted to try there for a while now. Its either closed, closing or way too packed whenever I&apos;ve been past.

Does sound a bit rich for a chicken burger. Unless it has cheese and bacon as well maybe. samboy May 1st, 2009, 07:00 AM naah no cheese and bacon. That&apos;s the cheapest chicken item on the menu. Their opening hours is a little stupid. something like 11-3pm weekdays and 6-7:30pm Friday nights (or something similar) really targeted at &apos;busy hours&apos; in the city. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 07:09 AM yeah i only went to burger bistro once when it was about 10 mins before they opened. the vacuous bitch asked me to wait a few minutes which i didnt have an issue with then proceeded to spk to someone for close to 20 mins about what they were doing that weekend. i ended up walking off. it is criminal to charge the prices they do and have such terrible service.

ill probably end up trying it out of curiosity one day but sincerely doubt ill become a regular due to their attitude and high prices. oh and their opening hours samboy May 1st, 2009, 07:18 AM haha Sanj I must have got the same women. Vacuous is the best way to describe her. I stood there for a minute before she came out. I opened my mouth 3 times without being able to order as she seemed to have the attention span of a lizard on drugs. The first time she turned around and started shifting some boxes, then she interrupted me again to play with the ipod (which controls the music inside), then she started shuffling the order pads and stacking them up in various random orders. I think she has OCD. For once it didn&apos;t bother me that much as I was sort of amused at what she might do next.
I don&apos;t think I&apos;ll be going back there. Nothing special really. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 07:25 AM hahaha yeah i can just picture trying 3 times to order only having to shut your mouth as she has wandered off again. must be the same idiot. Dilaz89 May 1st, 2009, 07:31 AM i don&apos;t go there that often but i&apos;ve always been satisfied when i have. I&apos;ll have to keep an eye out for this vacuous woman next time i&apos;m in there. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 07:32 AM i don&apos;t go there that often but i&apos;ve always been satisfied when i have. I&apos;ll have to keep an eye out for this vacuous woman next time i&apos;m in there.

yeah blonde girl, pretty young. would probably be attractive if she didnt have as much make up on or had at least a double digit IQ samboy May 1st, 2009, 07:39 AM It looks like we have dumb and dumber. Mine was brunette, asian. May be it&apos;s the criteria. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 07:46 AM haha yeah the same 2. the blondie was the star during my visit but the asian one was the one talking to her about the weekend plans ryan79 May 1st, 2009, 08:59 AM I just don&apos;t understand the mentality in closing before 10pm (midnight might be too much to ask for) on a Friday night in the middle of an area full of pubs. Seems rather stupid. samboy May 1st, 2009, 09:03 AM who knows...take ur pick

1. Lazy
2. Making enough money as it is
3. Don&apos;t want pub clientele
4. Can&apos;t get staff
5. PERTH ryan79 May 1st, 2009, 09:14 AM Yeah but if your running a business how could you turn customers away? The night I went there there were 3 other lots of people who also walked away whilst I was arguing my point about it being open longer.

Thats just bad business, regardless of those reasons. acc521 May 1st, 2009, 10:15 AM Burger Bistro has nothing on Jus Burgers. Doesn&apos;t come close. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 10:23 AM hey acc u had any good burgers on your trip so far? i did an estimate and i reckon im somewhere between 20-30 burgers from jus burgers. acc521 May 1st, 2009, 10:29 AM Not yet but I haven&apos;t really sought them out. Supposedly there is an awesome place in Berlin so I&apos;ll probably be checking it out. They do a 29€burger with a 750gm beef patty and you get it for free if you can finish it! Not a chance I&apos;m trying that lol. Sanj May 1st, 2009, 10:32 AM Not yet but I haven&apos;t really sought them out. Supposedly there is an awesome place in Berlin so I&apos;ll probably be checking it out. They do a 29 burger with a 750gm beef patty and you get it for free if you can finish it! Not a chance I&apos;m trying that lol.


perhaps some hashish before? jarkti May 1st, 2009, 10:32 AM Not yet but I haven&apos;t really sought them out. Supposedly there is an awesome place in Berlin so I&apos;ll probably be checking it out. They do a 29 burger with a 750gm beef patty and you get it for free if you can finish it! Not a chance I&apos;m trying that lol.

I thought KFC was pricey:lol:
Take a picture of it when you get there :D perthgazer May 3rd, 2009, 10:49 AM &quot;In Perth, we&apos;re moving in on Hay Street, Wesley, with an Emporio store. It&apos;s a smaller store, so we&apos;ve taken 250 square metres there with a view to having some smaller stores. We have another brand going in next to us and which has taken quite a large store. We’re pleased about that. I think it&apos;s opening up a different area. There are some exciting things going on in Perth. We feel quite confident about the city and about the project we&apos;re undertaking over there. So we&apos;re continuing with our plans and we&apos;re not really nervous about them at this stage.&quot;

http://www.theaustralian.news.com.au/story/0,25197,25283098-5017468,00.html miensie May 5th, 2009, 03:53 AM http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v299/Miensie/SCAN0286_001.jpg miensie May 6th, 2009, 05:28 AM Cash splash lifts retails sales
Chris Zappone
May 6, 2009 - 11:07AM

The Government&apos;s cash splash is paying off with consumers driving retail sales higher than expected in March. Department stores were the big winners.

Sales climbed 2.2%, seasonally adjusted, in March as consumers spent $19.3 billion for the month, Australian Bureau of Statistics figures show, reversing a 2% slump in February. Economists had expected a 0.5% increase.

&apos;&apos;It&apos;s a big shock in retail sales,&apos;&apos; said JP Morgan economist Helen Kevans. &apos;&apos;It was a lot stronger than expected.&apos;&apos;

&apos;&apos;In anticipation of the cash handouts that were to be received in April and May, consumers went out and spent a lot on discretionary items,&apos;&apos; she said.

The Federal Government announced a second fiscal stimulus in February, aimed in part at shoring up consumer demand and averting a deeper recession. Big cuts in interest rates by the Reserve Bank and lower petrol prices have also freed up household budgets.

&apos;&apos;The RBA has been stressing that they want to assess the impact of the stimulus on the economy and it looks from these numbers today that (it is) are working,&apos;&apos; she said.

Department store surge

Department store sales jumped 13.2% in March, while clothing and soft goods sales climbed 6.4%.

David Jones missed out on some of that sales leap, though, reporting today a 9.2% fall in year-on-year third quarter sales. The upmarket retailer said, however, that it was on track to post flat to 5% after-tax profit growth in the year to June.

&apos;&apos;We&apos;ve still got the impact of tax cheques to fully come through and so can anticipate a decent result in April as well,&apos;&apos; said ICAP economist Adam Carr.

&quot;These were fantastic results,&apos;&apos; he said.&quot;Looking through the volatile monthly retail sales, they are holding up quite nicely,&apos;&apos; he said.

In the three months to the end of March, seasonally adjusted retail sales rose 1%, the ABS said.

The result &apos;&apos;completely vindicates the Reserve Bank&apos;s decision to keep rates on hold,&apos;&apos; Mr Carr said. &apos;&apos;The issue now is to think about how to best have a sustainable recovery and the RBA&apos;s decision yesterday was a very good one.&apos;&apos;

TD Securities senior economist Annette Beacher said March&apos;s surprise gain was &apos;&apos;no doubt boosted by $900 landing directly into bank accounts, as part of another stimulus package by (Prime Minister Kevin) Rudd.&apos;&apos;

&apos;&apos;These &apos;cheques&apos; continued flowing into households in April, which will also boost spending in that month.&apos;&apos;

Most regions rise

Sales of household goods rose 1.3%, seasonally adjusted, for the month while business at cafes and restaurants increased 1.4%, the ABS said.

Retailers in every state but the ACT benefitted from the Government&apos;s imminent cash outlays, with Victoria&apos;s retail sales climbing 2.7%, seasonally adjusted, while New South Wales&apos; gained 1.2%.

Queensland&apos;s sales gained 3.2% in the month, while South Australia&apos;s rose 2.4%. Tasmania&apos;s retail sales rose 2.2%.

In the Australian Capital Territory, retail sales declined 0.1%, the ABS said.
------------------------------------------------------------------------

Well, I definitely did my part - my $900 has come and gone :D miensie May 6th, 2009, 05:34 AM Also, does anyone like/know of Jack London?

We&apos;re getting a new store on Hay St.

Looks very preppy? samboy May 6th, 2009, 05:48 AM must be for the emo kids who want to look grown up

http://www.jacklondon.com.au/ crazyknightsfan May 6th, 2009, 05:51 AM &apos;tis horrid miensie May 6th, 2009, 05:54 AM Is it what the kewl kids wear, CKF? crazyknightsfan May 6th, 2009, 06:40 AM most definitely

when they aren&apos;t wearing industrie of course miensie May 6th, 2009, 08:45 AM 29/04/2009
&quot;ACKROYD BUILDING&quot;
30-38 King Street PERTH WA 6000
Removal of Tenancy wall at rear of premises.
10,000.00
DA 2009/2106

30/04/2009
1238 Hay Street WEST PERTH WA 6005
Shop Fitout - Optus&apos;
249,563.60
BA-RF 2009/147

30/04/2009
Shop 8/60-66 Roe Street NORTHBRIDGE WA 6003
Eating House/Restaurant -Shop 8
30,000.00
DA 2009/2108

30/04/2009
&quot;PICCADILLY ARCADE&quot;
700-704 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
4 x Signs - &apos;Rubi Shoes&apos; Shop 35/37
3,000.00
SIGNBA 2009/6016

30/04/2009
&quot;WESLEY BUILDING&quot;
95 William Street PERTH WA 6000
1 x Illuminated Horizontal sign (Tenancy 6) - &apos;Karen Millen&apos; England.
12,000.00
SIGNBA 2009/6017

30/04/2009
1238 Hay Street WEST PERTH WA 6005
4 x Signs - Optus&apos;
11,723.00
SIGNDA 2009/6526

30/04/2009
91 James Street NORTHBRIDGE WA 6003
Sushi shop
0.00
HEALTH 2009/9590

01/05/2009
&quot;CITY WEST&quot;
102 Railway Street WEST PERTH WA 6005
Installation of Esculators - Harvey Norman
120,000.00
BA 2009/149
&apos;Esculators&apos; lawl engrish ftw

01/05/2009
189-199 William Street NORTHBRIDGE WA 6003
Licensing of Outside Laneway adjoining the shops 14 - 17.
0.0
DA 2009/2111

01/05/2009
&quot;WESLEY BUILDING&quot;
95 William Street PERTH WA 6000
1 x Bulkhead Sign, 1 x Front Glazing Sign - &apos;Paul&amp;Joe&apos;
12,000.00
SIGNBA 2009/6018

04/05/2009
683-703 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Retail Shop - Quick Service Restaurant
300,000.00
BA 2009/153
What the hell?!

04/05/2009
514 Murray Street PERTH WA 6000
Change of Use - From Retail to Retail Food ie Lunch Bar/Cafe
0.0
DA 2009/2114 samboy May 6th, 2009, 08:52 AM 04/05/2009
683-703 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Retail Shop - Quick Service Restaurant
300,000.00
BA 2009/153
What the hell?!



I think they mean &apos;fast food&apos; restaurant Miensie. I doubt there&apos;ll be a restaurant by that name. then again who knows.. jarkti May 6th, 2009, 09:05 AM Also, does anyone like/know of Jack London?

We&apos;re getting a new store on Hay St.

Looks very preppy?

Only thing there I&apos;d wear is the jacket top right hand corner
and three rows down and three in the grey jacket haha
Might have other good clothes, need to stock up on my londonish clothes :lol: Sanj May 6th, 2009, 09:18 AM im a bit nervous re the sushi place opening on james st. i walked by the other day and they had a sign up for a chefs job, part or full time. the place is close to opening and they dont have a chef yet?? GAbE27 May 7th, 2009, 02:27 AM im a bit nervous re the sushi place opening on james st. i walked by the other day and they had a sign up for a chefs job, part or full time. the place is close to opening and they dont have a chef yet??

Walked past it last night, they had a&quot;few&quot;customers... But that place is so big its always gonna look empty. My bro in-law had his chinese wedding reception there only a year ago. samboy May 7th, 2009, 02:33 AM are you guys talking about the same place? doesn&apos;t add up Sanj May 7th, 2009, 02:36 AM we must be. it used to be a chinese restaurant which closed down, by the sounds of it the japanese kaiten sushi place that has taken over the space has opened.

for me the only time kaiten works is when there is enough regular business to ensure that nothing stays on the conveyor long and everything is fresh. the chef would also have to know what he&apos;s doing of course.

i could be wrong but id be surprised if this ended up being good samboy May 7th, 2009, 02:41 AM ah ok I might poke my head in and have a sniff at some stage. so your doubts were even more warranted if the place is actually open and they&apos;re looking for a chef. may be the old one has handed in their notice ;) miensie May 7th, 2009, 03:46 AM New anti smoking laws proposed
May 07, 2009 10:15

A proposed new anti smoking bill for Western Australia will ban smoking in alfresco dining areas at restaurants and cafes, with tobacco advertising in shops also to be banned.

With the exception of specialist tobacconists, stores in WA will no longer be able to display tobacco related advertising, with the Health Department to issue fines of up to $200 for non-compliance.

Pubs and clubs would also be requires to make half their outdoor areas smoke free.

The bill was proposed by independent MP Janet Woollard, and has the backing of the WA Government and Opposition. miensie May 7th, 2009, 03:53 AM Only thing there I&apos;d wear is the jacket top right hand corner
and three rows down and three in the grey jacket haha
Might have other good clothes, need to stock up on my londonish clothes :lol:

I&apos;m guessing the target market is younger boys who are on the cusp of manhood? That black and white striped tie is really hideous. And how skinny is the model?!

Jackets are good. I&apos;m a huge fan of blazers.

I like Warehouse, which originated in London, which is another brand we can&apos;t get here. I went mental in KL when I came upon it :crazy2:

- EDIT -
On second look, that&apos;s actually his t-shirt poking out from his shirt. Even worse.

ah ok I might poke my head in and have a sniff at some stage. so your doubts were even more warranted if the place is actually open and they&apos;re looking for a chef. may be the old one has handed in their notice ;)

I&apos;m gonna wander down too. Soonish. Tomorrow even.

Maybe there&apos;s more than the one chef? ryan79 May 7th, 2009, 04:38 AM New anti smoking laws proposed
May 07, 2009 10:15

A proposed new anti smoking bill for Western Australia will ban smoking in alfresco dining areas at restaurants and cafes, with tobacco advertising in shops also to be banned.

With the exception of specialist tobacconists, stores in WA will no longer be able to display tobacco related advertising, with the Health Department to issue fines of up to $200 for non-compliance.

Pubs and clubs would also be requires to make half their outdoor areas smoke free.
The bill was proposed by independent MP Janet Woollard, and has the backing of the WA Government and Opposition.

Fantastic news. I also heard it will be banned on beaches too.

But how do you make half outdoor area non smoking? That wouldn&apos;t work. samboy May 7th, 2009, 04:45 AM In the days where smoking was allowed on planes (shit that makes me feel old) I&apos;ve travelled with airlines where one side of the aisle was smoking zone and the other non-smoking :lol: Genius!! ryan79 May 7th, 2009, 04:50 AM In London they used to have smoking sections in restaurants. I couldn&apos;t really see the point as the smoke just drifts through the place. They also have smoking fenced off areas in the middle of Heathrow but they are open air.

I can&apos;t even imagine what it would be like on an airplane.

Guys used to tell me about smoking on the tube. Theres already no oxygen down there as it is.

Smoking is just the wierdest habit/culture in our society. I just don&apos;t get it. miensie May 7th, 2009, 05:37 AM A little bit more on it:

------------------------------------------------------
AMA applauds proposed anti-smoking laws
Joseph Sapienza
May 7, 2009 - 11:00AM

The Australian Medical Association WA has applauded planned anti-smoking laws that will see anyone lighting up at the beach, in alfresco areas of pubs and restaurants or in cars carrying children fined up to $2000.

However, the Australian Hotels Association said it would not become the&quot;smoke police&quot;when it came to regulating smoking in outdoor areas of pubs.

Independent MP Janet Woollard yesterday reached a compromise with the State Government over the Tobacco Products Control Amendment Bill.

Under the new laws, smoking would be banned within 10 metres of playgrounds, between the flags at the beach and in alfresco areas of cafes and restaurants.

Smoking would also be banned in cars carrying children under the age of 16 years and cigarette advertising would be banned in all shops.

In the original bill, Dr Woollard had also wanted a total ban on smoking in licensed outdoor areas of hotels.

Police and council rangers will be expected to take details of anyone breaking the law and report them to the WA Health Department, who would then consider a penalty.

People found flouting the law could face an initial $200 fine, while repeat offenders could receive a penalty of $2000.

A report in December last year showed Australia&apos;s smoking rate has dropped from 34 per cent in 1980 to 19 per cent in 2007.

AMA WA president Gary Geelhoed said the would legislation improve the health of many West Australians, and also save the community millions of dollars each year.

&quot;The toll from second-hand smoke not only claims lives but leads to hundreds of West Australians being hospitalised with heart disease, lung cancer and respiratory illnesses,&quot;he said.

&quot;Extending smoking restrictions to all alfresco dining areas, in cars carrying children and in a range of other public areas will result in a whole generation of young kids growing up in a much healthier and safer environment.

&quot;The consequent savings in health costs will be enormous.

&quot;When the laws are finally enacted, WA will regain its position as the leading state in the nation for smoking reform.&quot;

Professor Geelhoed said he was still disappointed about exemptions that would allow smoking in open areas of hotels. He said non-smokers and staff would still be exposed to second-hand smoke.

Under the bill, smoking will be banned in 50 per cent of all licensed outdoor areas.

&quot;The AMA appeals to WA publicans not to take advantage of these loopholes and to make their hotels totally smoke-free in line with all other eating and drinking establishments,&quot;he said.

&quot;Hopefully, responsible hoteliers who aren&apos;t in the pocket of the tobacco industry, will do the right thing and provide a safe and pleasant environment for their customers.&quot;

AHA chief executive officer Bradley Woods said he was disappointed by yesterday&apos;s announcement, claiming there was a lack of consultation with the industry.

&quot;... We will now focus on ensuring that all hotels and taverns throughout WA will have outdoor areas to provide for smoking and non-smoking patrons,&quot;Mr Woods said.

&quot;Some venues will need the support of local government authorities to ensure they can comply with the restrictions and the public will need to be educated in regards to these restrictions.

&quot;We don&apos;t need to add to the plethora of regulation the industry has to operate within and we are not going to become the smoke police.&quot; Perth4life May 7th, 2009, 06:47 AM at the beach? whos going to enforce that, is someone going to call the cops on you? I understand the ramafacations of passive smoking, but the beach is a ridiculous place to ban smoking its one of the most open areas you can get, WA - Nanny state. Nate Von Longneck II May 7th, 2009, 07:26 AM The smoking law has nothing to do with whether you agree with smoking or not. I rarely even smoke in an alfresco area, if I did, I would ask every time if it was OK. Its just common sense, but nimbys think its great that we have a new law against something else pathetically insignificant.

Its all about personal freedoms, which are just constantly being eroded in WA. You may see this as a biased smokers rant, but, unfortunately, it is just another aspect of the nanny state.

You can&apos;t even be trusted to take a drink from the door at the scotto, to the table one metre away. The law says a staff member must do it for me.

Drinkers, smokers, are suffering due to the actions of just a handful of people.

Fantastic.

I&apos;m, not going to debate this point - its undebatable. PerthCity May 7th, 2009, 08:24 AM Smoking is just the wierdest habit/culture in our society.

Why is that?

As for the Flying Scotsman Nate, there really shouldn&apos;t be tables out near the footpath anyway. Bullswool May 7th, 2009, 08:33 AM Because it doesn&apos;t seem to provide any benefits, apart from feeding an addiction that you wouldn&apos;t have if you didn&apos;t smoke in the first place... Sanj May 7th, 2009, 08:39 AM As for the Flying Scotsman Nate, there really shouldn&apos;t be tables out near the footpath anyway.

u are such an arseclown sometimes.

yoo shoulds appresheate us addictions likes drink outsides! miensie May 7th, 2009, 08:42 AM u are such an arseclown sometimes.

yoo shoulds appresheate us addictions likes drink outsides!

lawl

ftw baby, ftw :okay:



I&apos;m gonna regret this probably but why shouldn&apos;t there be tables outside near the sidewalk, PC? Baurice May 7th, 2009, 08:54 AM You can&apos;t even be trusted to take a drink from the door at the scotto, to the table one metre away. The law says a staff member must do it for me.

I think that this is to do with insurance reasons, and the fact that the alfresco area coexist with a public footpath.

The staff must carry drinks across the path and deliver them to your table, so the average patron doesn&apos;t accidentally drop a load of glass on Joe Public. Same goes for other bars with a similar setup like Carnegies and The Belgian.

Places like the moon have their alfresco areas within private property so patrons are free to carry drinks wherever they like inside the licensed area.

As for the smoking ban, I think its fantastic. Nanny State or not, every man and his dog knows the health risk behind tobacco, so those who continue to choose to smoke should not be able to do it in places becoming of passive smoking. jackso May 7th, 2009, 09:05 AM I think that this is to do with insurance reasons, and the fact that the alfresco area coexist with a public footpath.

The staff must carry drinks across the path and deliver them to your table, so the average patron doesn&apos;t accidentally drop a load of glass on Joe Public. Same goes for other bars with a similar setup like Carnegies and The Belgian.

Places like the moon have their alfresco areas within private property so patrons are free to carry drinks wherever they like inside the licensed area.

As for the smoking ban, I think its fantastic. Nanny State or not, every man and his dog knows the health risk behind tobacco, so those who continue to choose to smoke should not be able to do it in places becoming of passive smoking.

I think it is actually licensing issues. I know that at the belgian beer cafe you are allowed to hold a drink in the alfresco area of the side walk, but the area between the actual building and the alfresco half of the sidewalk is not licensed, therefore you are not allowed to hold a drink. I was told that its due to liquor licensing rules not insurance. acc521 May 7th, 2009, 11:03 AM The worst I&apos;ve experienced was in a shopping centre in Vienna. All the dining places had people smoking in the seated areas outside the places so anyone who was just walking around the shopping centre had to put up with the stench. In Spain it was pretty bad as well because you can smoke in all restaurants and cafes, but the shopping centre thing really threw me. ryan79 May 7th, 2009, 06:02 PM Why is that?

As for the Flying Scotsman Nate, there really shouldn&apos;t be tables out near the footpath anyway.

Just is. samboy May 8th, 2009, 01:59 AM You&apos;re leaving yourself wide open Ryan (especially with PC). For someone who&apos;s not bothered by recreational drug use, it&apos;ll be difficult to justify why you find smoking absurd except of course as a personal choice.
Warning: Troll factor - I&apos;m bored trying to start a fight :lol: ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 03:21 AM You&apos;re leaving yourself wide open Ryan (especially with PC). For someone who&apos;s not bothered by recreational drug use, it&apos;ll be difficult to justify why you find smoking absurd except of course as a personal choice.
Warning: Troll factor - I&apos;m bored trying to start a fight :lol:

Ok, I&apos;ll answer you properly ;)

Mate I&apos;m open, tolerant and understanding of just about everything in the world but smoking I just simply don&apos;t get. Its never made sense to me. I don&apos;t have a problem with people doing it, its their own choice, but its just one thing I&apos;ll never get nor understand.

But, like alcohol and drugs, there should be a time and a place for it. Either keep it at home or have designated places (like smoking rooms, similar to pubs). ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 03:27 AM The smoking law has nothing to do with whether you agree with smoking or not. I rarely even smoke in an alfresco area, if I did, I would ask every time if it was OK. Its just common sense, but nimbys think its great that we have a new law against something else pathetically insignificant.

Its all about personal freedoms, which are just constantly being eroded in WA. You may see this as a biased smokers rant, but, unfortunately, it is just another aspect of the nanny state.

You can&apos;t even be trusted to take a drink from the door at the scotto, to the table one metre away. The law says a staff member must do it for me.

Drinkers, smokers, are suffering due to the actions of just a handful of people.

Fantastic.

I&apos;m, not going to debate this point - its undebatable.

Unfortunately Nate you are very much in a minority. Smokers quite frequently light up next to me while trying to lunch or you cop a face full of ash from someone walking past. Plus ciggie butts just do my head in. Why some smokers thinks its ok to just flick them every is beyond comprehension.

If more smokers were courteous of others then we might not need these laws. PerthCity May 8th, 2009, 03:45 AM I&apos;m gonna regret this probably but why shouldn&apos;t there be tables outside near the sidewalk, PC?

I just don&apos;t think it is appropriate to have no barrier between the footpath and those drinking at the hotel. A small fence with some potted plants would do. I can imagine some women would find it not too pleasant to be walking past a venue like that spilling onto the street. PerthCity May 8th, 2009, 03:47 AM You&apos;re leaving yourself wide open Ryan (especially with PC). For someone who&apos;s not bothered by recreational drug use, it&apos;ll be difficult to justify why you find smoking absurd except of course as a personal choice.
Warning: Troll factor - I&apos;m bored trying to start a fight :lol:

Very clever samboy. :lol: Sanj May 8th, 2009, 03:49 AM I can imagine some women would find it not too pleasant to be walking past a venue like that spilling onto the street.

to which i say what kind of women are u referring to? last i checked (mind u things couldve changed in the last 2 weeks) women not only are allowed in but in fact regularly frequent the flying scotsman miensie May 8th, 2009, 03:58 AM How do places get away with charging $5 for TWO pieces of toast?!?!

Sometimes I feel like just toast but I ain&apos;t putting up with that.

Gah! :bash:



It&apos;s Friday, I&apos;m staying out of the above discussion. PerthCity May 8th, 2009, 04:04 AM to which i say what kind of women are u referring to? last i checked (mind u things couldve changed in the last 2 weeks) women not only are allowed in but in fact regularly frequent the flying scotsman

It&apos;s opposite the areas IGA, its close to residential areas, a very wide range of people around that area at most times of the day.

Anyway that&apos;s my personal view, there&apos;s nothing more to debate. ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 04:07 AM to which i say what kind of women are u referring to? last i checked (mind u things couldve changed in the last 2 weeks) women not only are allowed in but in fact regularly frequent the flying scotsman

What!? Next they&apos;ll be giving the women the right to vote. Now theres something to whinge about PC. Sanj May 8th, 2009, 04:07 AM to which i say my grandmother is a 77 year old lady who was born in india and is fairly conservative. she has never had an issue with walking past the scotto.

granted late on certain nights it can get rowdy but lets face it the people who are likely to get offended/be uncomfortable arent going to be there that late anyway.

P.S- im loving the&quot;to which i say&quot;. i reckon ill get a full day or 2 out of it. ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 04:19 AM I went to the Flying Taco for lunch yesterday. Nice food but a bit pricey. Will definitely be going back.

Went next door to the Pantry Door for a Mocha and was really good. Nice little spot that Angrove St/Fitzgerald St area. Sanj May 8th, 2009, 04:26 AM the pantry door has absolutely stunning banana cake. they call it banana bread but it seems more like banana cake. one of the best ive ever had, costs $7.50 for around 8 small portions or so.

their ginger cake is nice as well. ive been wanting to big up the pantry door as they&apos;re a new business but i forgot so thanks for reminding me

flying taco is very nice, i agree. it only gets expensive if u get the condiments etc like if u end up getting tortilla chips and guacamole as well as your main. miensie May 8th, 2009, 04:31 AM P.S- im loving the&quot;to which i say&quot;. i reckon ill get a full day or 2 out of it.

lawl

Inspired by jhurn I see. ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 04:37 AM the pantry door has absolutely stunning banana cake. they call it banana bread but it seems more like banana cake. one of the best ive ever had, costs $7.50 for around 8 small portions or so.

their ginger cake is nice as well. ive been wanting to big up the pantry door as they&apos;re a new business but i forgot so thanks for reminding me

flying taco is very nice, i agree. it only gets expensive if u get the condiments etc like if u end up getting tortilla chips and guacamole as well as your main.

I thought they were quite new. Has a very warm and welcoming feel about the place. Good service too.

There is another place there called Milkd (I think). Looked rather pretentious and wanky (but not in a good way). hack404 May 8th, 2009, 04:40 AM to which i say what kind of women are u referring to? last i checked (mind u things couldve changed in the last 2 weeks) women not only are allowed in but in fact regularly frequent the flying scotsman


When did this happen? samboy May 8th, 2009, 05:07 AM I thought they were quite new. Has a very warm and welcoming feel about the place. Good service too.

There is another place there called Milkd (I think). Looked rather pretentious and wanky (but not in a good way).

I&apos;ve been meaning to check out the pantry door for a while, i might do it now. As for Milkd it seems to be always busy, the service i had there was great but didn&apos;t enjoy the coffee at all so I haven&apos;t been back. The place and attitude of the staff isn&apos;t pretentious but sometimes you get the wannabe crowd there. stadiumdesigner May 8th, 2009, 05:21 AM What!? Next they&apos;ll be giving the women the right to vote. Now theres something to whinge about PC.

where did you hear such rubbish ryan? im shocked and appalled if this is the case gotime May 8th, 2009, 05:35 AM ryan, i&apos;ve always found milkd in north perth to be friendly with an alright atmopshere, but like samboy, find their coffee pretty rough. strangely enough i&apos;ve had some great coffee from milkd on eighth ave maylands. Sanj May 8th, 2009, 05:35 AM I&apos;ve been meaning to check out the pantry door for a while, i might do it now. As for Milkd it seems to be always busy, the service i had there was great but didn&apos;t enjoy the coffee at all so I haven&apos;t been back. The place and attitude of the staff isn&apos;t pretentious but sometimes you get the wannabe crowd there.

yeah i agree with samboy. i dont find milkd to be pretentious but some of the crowd can be a bit wanky i guess. ive always found the staff to be good but i do think it is overrated. people rave about the coffee and breakfast there but i dont think it warrants the hype.

as for pantry door - they dont have a hell of a lot of things but i do enjoy the vibe, the lady who i assume runs it is very nice and then theres the banana cake of course miensie May 8th, 2009, 08:24 AM Quickly ducked into the new sushi place on James St.
That place is HUGE. I&apos;ve always liked how the waitors/waitresses call out&quot;Irrashaimase!&quot;to you when you walk in :)
The conveyor belt/chairs take up the majority of the space but there are a few tables if you want to order something else. Had a quick look at the menu but didn&apos;t have time to really browse through it properly.

Not sure if I like the neon pink/green they&apos;ve gone for and there&apos;s no real effort made in terms of decoration, look or style but I&apos;ll go there for lunch one day and check it out.


I had the margherita pizza from Sorrento&apos;s for lunch. $16 for the main size. I actually wanted the entree size but the waitor assured me it was &apos;very small&apos; so I took his advice :eek: Way too big for the one person I think. I ate half. It was very nice though, the tomato base they used was divine - that tangy, ripe taste. Great choice of cheese on it, not too strong. Crust and pizza base was good.

I was very happy with it :)


samby, was that you with the pram? :P samboy May 8th, 2009, 08:29 AM if it was a dashing tall dark and handsome man then yeah ;) Sanj May 8th, 2009, 08:31 AM samby, was that you with the pram? :P


nah we&apos;re still trying for one miensie May 8th, 2009, 08:32 AM if it was a dashing tall dark and handsome man then yeah ;)

:naughty:



Oh, and the sign advertising for a chef is gone. However, the 2 guys in the middle of the conveyor belt (which I&apos;m assuming are the 2 chefs) were very young. Early-20&apos;s. Maybe give it a miss, Sanj :)


nah we&apos;re still trying for one

:rofl: crazyknightsfan May 8th, 2009, 08:32 AM samby, was that you with the pram? :P

i thought samby was a guy :tongue2: samboy May 8th, 2009, 08:32 AM :lol:

nah we&apos;re still trying for one Sanj May 8th, 2009, 08:33 AM miensie so u didnt try any? u couldve at least taken one for the team miensie May 8th, 2009, 08:35 AM i thought samby was a guy :tongue2:

Men don&apos;t push strollers? :tongue2:


miensie so u didnt try any? u couldve at least taken one for the team

I&apos;d already ordered the pizza so no, I couldn&apos;t. I&apos;ll have lunch there next week :okay: crazyknightsfan May 8th, 2009, 08:45 AM Men don&apos;t push strollers? :tongue2:

it&apos;s called cradle-snatching, isn&apos;t it :tongue2: miensie May 8th, 2009, 08:47 AM it&apos;s called cradle-snatching, isn&apos;t it :tongue2:

Ahahahahaaha

:tongue2: ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 09:24 AM I&apos;ve been meaning to check out the pantry door for a while, i might do it now. As for Milkd it seems to be always busy, the service i had there was great but didn&apos;t enjoy the coffee at all so I haven&apos;t been back. The place and attitude of the staff isn&apos;t pretentious but sometimes you get the wannabe crowd there.

Thats probably fair enough. It was more the crowd I was talking about so I didn&apos;t bother going in.

where did you hear such rubbish ryan? im shocked and appalled if this is the case

Yeah don&apos;t go on about it too much. Some haven&apos;t figured it out yet. ryan79 May 8th, 2009, 09:29 AM Went to Claremont today, to check out the Claremont Quarter bit that has opened.

I&apos;ve never really paid too much attention to Claremont and now I know why. Its nothing special really, don&apos;t what all the fuss is about.

Anway, the Claremont Quarter is a real disappointment. Its just another soulless suburban shopping mall. They had a great opportunity to create an open gallery style shopping centre similar to the one in Milan.

I certainly won&apos;t be bothering going to Claremont again. jackso May 8th, 2009, 09:39 AM Went for a walk around the city today. A couple of things stood out.

The T[life] store is MASSIVE. Looks like it doesn&apos;t have too much longer until its ready.

It looks as though the shop next to Ruth Tarvydas on King St is under going a fitout.

Watches of Switzerland looks very close to opening. Most of the cabinets and everything are installed do shouldn&apos;t be too far away.

And the work going on with the retail tennancies at Wesley Quater seems to be going pretty slow. Anyone heard any news on more this? miensie May 8th, 2009, 09:42 AM It looks as though the shop next to Ruth Tarvydas on King St is under going a fitout.


Periscope or the old Cino To Go? jackso May 8th, 2009, 09:53 AM Periscope or the old Cino To Go?

Periscope i think, its the same building as Tarvydas, just the other half.
Cino to go was on the corner of king and wolf right? That&apos;s where watches of Switzerland is moving. miensie May 8th, 2009, 09:57 AM Periscope i think, its the same building as Tarvydas, just the other half.

Ah, must be Periscope then. Next to Wheels&amp;Dollbaby.


Cino to go was on the corner of king and wolf right? That&apos;s where watches of Switzerland is moving.

Yep. Directly opposite King St Cafe.

Erm...ain&apos;t that quite a small space? Or adequate for their needs? jackso May 8th, 2009, 10:02 AM Ah, must be Periscope then. Next to Wheels&amp;Dollbaby.



Yep. Directly opposite King St Cafe.

Erm...ain&apos;t that quite a small space? Or adequate for their needs?

Yep the building next to wheels&amp;dollbaby.

The corner tennancy where Watches of Switzerland ate opening is actually quite large. It has a very narrow street frontage but goes back a fair way. miensie May 8th, 2009, 10:05 AM The corner tennancy where Watches of Switzerland ate opening is actually quite large. It has a very narrow street frontage but goes back a fair way.

Aha...kewl! :okay: acc521 May 8th, 2009, 09:33 PM How do places get away with charging $5 for TWO pieces of toast?!?!

Sometimes I feel like just toast but I ain&apos;t putting up with that.

Don&apos;t ever come to Copenhagen then. The prices in this country for everything are out of this world. I kid you not, Paris and Zurich look cheap compared to this city. Also, many stores don&apos;t accept international credit cards - a first out of all the places I&apos;ve visited!

E.g. (From my browsing. I didn&apos;t purchase all of the below!)
1.5 ltr bottle of Pepsi from supermarket = AUD$5
Small box of cornflakes from supermarket = AUD$6
Regular whopper meal = AUD$16
Kebab, chips and a 500ml drink = AUD$13
Crappy small hot dog from a street vendor = AUD$4
250ml Carlsberg from a cafe (remember it&apos;s the local beer here) = AUD$8
Ben Sherman polo that goes for around AUD$60 in most countries) = AUD$100
New release Xbox360 or PS3 game = AUD$130

GST is 25% and the lowest tax bracket is over 40%!

The accomodation I have here is probably the worst out of this trip but also the most expensive as well.

This is the first place I&apos;ve been to where I genuinely have no idea how the average person can afford to live. acc521 May 8th, 2009, 09:38 PM They had a great opportunity to create an open gallery style shopping centre similar to the one in Milan.

That area is the only good part of Milan. That city is such a shit hole. I don&apos;t think the people who live there or the local government have any pride in the city at all. Out of all the random people I have met on this trip from around the world, there is one thing that every single one of them has agreed on, and that is how utterly crap and terrible Milan is.

For shopping, London and Berlin have been the only two cities that really have the entire spectrum from cheap to designer at good prices. Berlin has an insane number of concept stores as well as normal stores for all the mid range brands like Adidas, Ben Sherman, Fred Perry, Swatch, Paul Frank etc. acc521 May 8th, 2009, 09:43 PM I went to the Flying Taco for lunch yesterday. Nice food but a bit pricey. Will definitely be going back.

Went next door to the Pantry Door for a Mocha and was really good. Nice little spot that Angrove St/Fitzgerald St area.

Have you tried the Quesadilas from Flying Taco yet? Sublime!

Milkd has a not bad atmosphere but their coffee is nothing special. Not bad, but not great.

Pantry Door is new right? I think I remember being disappointed that I wasn&apos;t going to get to try it out the last time I went to Flying Taco.

That whole area is going to get better and better I think. I like how this part of North Perth and the northern part of Northbridge where Rochelle Adonis is are getting more and more places to eat. The whole &apos;zone&apos; is becoming more vibrant. Like Nate has said before, if you are looking for property, NB is the place to by - so close to everything good in Perth. aaronaugi1 May 9th, 2009, 01:58 AM Regular whopper meal = AUD$16

GST is 25% and the lowest tax bracket is over 40%!



Do they have a&quot;fat tax&quot;over there?

I know in Japan, a regular chips/fries, is about double the cost, when purchased individually, compared to their BigMac/Whopper becuase it is considered confectionary (though the burger isn&apos;t).

As for the taxes, they may be high but look at the countries standard of living, health, education and crime. Some lessons could be learn&apos;t there. city_thing May 9th, 2009, 04:45 AM Don&apos;t ever come to Copenhagen then. The prices in this country for everything are out of this world. I kid you not, Paris and Zurich look cheap compared to this city. Also, many stores don&apos;t accept international credit cards - a first out of all the places I&apos;ve visited!

E.g. (From my browsing. I didn&apos;t purchase all of the below!)
1.5 ltr bottle of Pepsi from supermarket = AUD$5
Small box of cornflakes from supermarket = AUD$6
Regular whopper meal = AUD$16
Kebab, chips and a 500ml drink = AUD$13
Crappy small hot dog from a street vendor = AUD$4
250ml Carlsberg from a cafe (remember it&apos;s the local beer here) = AUD$8
Ben Sherman polo that goes for around AUD$60 in most countries) = AUD$100
New release Xbox360 or PS3 game = AUD$130

GST is 25% and the lowest tax bracket is over 40%!

The accomodation I have here is probably the worst out of this trip but also the most expensive as well.

This is the first place I&apos;ve been to where I genuinely have no idea how the average person can afford to live.

I don&apos;t remember it being that expensive. But yes it was more costly than other European cities. Is the exchange rate still $1AUD = 4.5Kr- ?

Have you ridden on the Metro yet? :cheers: ryan79 May 9th, 2009, 07:16 AM Don&apos;t ever come to Copenhagen then. The prices in this country for everything are out of this world. I kid you not, Paris and Zurich look cheap compared to this city. Also, many stores don&apos;t accept international credit cards - a first out of all the places I&apos;ve visited!

E.g. (From my browsing. I didn&apos;t purchase all of the below!)
1.5 ltr bottle of Pepsi from supermarket = AUD$5
Small box of cornflakes from supermarket = AUD$6
Regular whopper meal = AUD$16
Kebab, chips and a 500ml drink = AUD$13
Crappy small hot dog from a street vendor = AUD$4
250ml Carlsberg from a cafe (remember it&apos;s the local beer here) = AUD$8
Ben Sherman polo that goes for around AUD$60 in most countries) = AUD$100
New release Xbox360 or PS3 game = AUD$130

GST is 25% and the lowest tax bracket is over 40%!

The accomodation I have here is probably the worst out of this trip but also the most expensive as well.

This is the first place I&apos;ve been to where I genuinely have no idea how the average person can afford to live.

Its an all acc affair this post! :)

You know, apart from Burger King, those prices are not that far off Perth. Its the only city I went to in Europe that I didn&apos;t really like and would never go to again. I found it dirty, dreary, expensive and dull. Lots of disaffected youth just hanging around too.

At the airport we were going to catch the train into the city but as we went to do it these teenagers threw a bike over the power line and broke them so obviously the train couldn&apos;t run.

They also play classical music around the central train station to keep the youth away. But I like the hotdogs and some good food there. Tivoli Gardens were a highlight even if somewhat dull.

That area is the only good part of Milan. That city is such a shit hole. I don&apos;t think the people who live there or the local government have any pride in the city at all. Out of all the random people I have met on this trip from around the world, there is one thing that every single one of them has agreed on, and that is how utterly crap and terrible Milan is.

For shopping, London and Berlin have been the only two cities that really have the entire spectrum from cheap to designer at good prices. Berlin has an insane number of concept stores as well as normal stores for all the mid range brands like Adidas, Ben Sherman, Fred Perry, Swatch, Paul Frank etc.

Milan is an interesting city. One that doesn&apos;t really live up to its hype. The Duomo is amazing though. But I didn&apos;t mind it, just couldn&apos;t see what the fuss was about.

Berlin is awesome for shopping, but London beats it. Paris is great also, but moslty just higher end stuff.

Have you tried the Quesadilas from Flying Taco yet? Sublime!

Milkd has a not bad atmosphere but their coffee is nothing special. Not bad, but not great.

Pantry Door is new right? I think I remember being disappointed that I wasn&apos;t going to get to try it out the last time I went to Flying Taco.

That whole area is going to get better and better I think. I like how this part of North Perth and the northern part of Northbridge where Rochelle Adonis is are getting more and more places to eat. The whole &apos;zone&apos; is becoming more vibrant. Like Nate has said before, if you are looking for property, NB is the place to by - so close to everything good in Perth.

I had a Quesadilas. Was very good. Still felt a bit over priced for what it was. The crowd at Milkd kinda put me off. Way too wanky for my liking.

Pantry Door is new. Had a good Mocha and good service.

The more strips and active areas we can get the better. TRS-80 May 9th, 2009, 07:26 AM The prices at Flying Taco have gone up - used to be $8/$10/$12 for taco/quesadilla/burrito, now it&apos;s $9/$12/$14. samboy May 9th, 2009, 07:35 AM I had no idea Milan was that bad. I&apos;ve never been but always wanted to visit based how people seem to romanticise it. (the usual Paris Milan NY etc). I guess it&apos;s just BS. ryan79 May 9th, 2009, 07:40 AM Thats it samboy. Thats why I insisted on going. But its nowhere near the league of Paris/NY/London.

Ironically, its more like a big country town :) acc521 May 9th, 2009, 08:51 AM I don&apos;t remember it being that expensive. But yes it was more costly than other European cities. Is the exchange rate still $1AUD = 4.5Kr- ?

Have you ridden on the Metro yet? :cheers:

The Oanda rate is 1:4.40 but the real rate is 1:4. I didn&apos;t catch public transport here - not worth it lol. I must have walked a good 25km over 2 days - but I don&apos;t mind - it lets you see random areas you would normally miss. Sanj May 9th, 2009, 08:52 AM went to pantry door today to pixck up some of that banana loaf for tomorrow, ended up having a coffee and a slice of their fig bread and butter pudding with yoghurt on side. coffee was ok, nothing great but the pudding was pretty good. ideally i wouldve had it with creme fraiche instead of yoghurt but was still nice. acc521 May 9th, 2009, 09:03 AM I had no idea Milan was that bad. I&apos;ve never been but always wanted to visit based how people seem to romanticise it. (the usual Paris Milan NY etc). I guess it&apos;s just BS.

Well and truly BS Samboy. Like Ryan said, Duomo (the main centre) is the only good area, and they haven&apos;t even managed to bother to clean up the metro station there. You would think at least the metro station underneath the main fashion centre of Milan would be decent but no - I&apos;ve never seen so much tagging in my life. I&apos;m talking even vending machines so tagged up that you can&apos;t even see what&apos;s inside of them. Even some of their trains were so tagged that you couldn&apos;t read any of the signs of see out of the windows.

The overall impression you get when walking around the city is just one of neglect and a complete lack of pride or respect in their city by the Milanese.

It really is amazing just how universal everyone I&apos;ve met is on how crap the place is. It can count itself very lucky that most of the Italian designers base themselves there. The only plus was that I had arguably the best traditional pasta meal I&apos;ve ever had at this random restaurant that was out of the main area. Sanj May 9th, 2009, 09:13 AM hey acc if u come across any info with regards to noma could u copy it or whatever for me? im extremely intrigued by it.

P.S - its a restaurant in copenhagen getting a lot of buzz. im especially interested in their different approach to fine dining




At noma, we aim to offer a personal rendition of Nordic gourmet cuisine, where typical methods of cooking, fine Nordic produce and the legacy of our common food culture are all being subjected to an innovative gastronomic approach. Carrying this line of thinking further, we view it as a challenge to play a part in bringing forth a regeneration of Nordic culinary craft, in its capacity to encompass the North Atlantic region and to brighten the world with its distinctive tastiness and special regional character.

What you will find here at noma is not centered so much on olive oil, foie gras, sun-dried tomatoes and Mediterranean black olives. We’ve been busy traveling around in the Nordic regions and we have been finding a number of simply phenomenal ingredients that we have flown into town for our use: Horse mussels, deep-sea crabs and langoustines from the Faeroe Islands, which are living right up until the moment they are served to our visitors. Halibut, wild salmon, cod and seaweed and curds from Iceland. Lamb, musk ox, berries and the purest drinking water from Greenland. In much the same fashion, we are constantly scanning for new sources of inspiration in Denmark, especially, as well as the other Nordic regions, for purposes of securing reliable sources of top-quality raw produce. This pertains both to very costly ingredients and also to ingredients of a more everyday character that we feel have come to be overlooked in the formulation of a salient Nordic approach to cooking: cereals, hulled grains and legumes, which you will come to experience here in the context of surprising preparations.

We want to go into depth with the matters before us. We are paying careful attention to the qualities in our culinary legacy, but we also aim to generate something new and innovative. We are exploring the potential of milk and cream in today’s modern cuisine. We are developing new ways of preparing the well-known and other not so well known kinds of cereal grains. We are constantly on the lookout for berries and herbs in the natural environment, including certain varieties that other people do not generally feel like gathering. We are also interested in working with raw ingredients which have no part in any systems of formalized cultivation and which therefore cannot be obtained through the ordinary channels of distribution.

We are smoking, salting, pickling, drying, grilling and baking on slabs of basalt stone. We are also preparing our own vinegars and concocting our own distilled spirits. However, we are making use of the most up-to-date kitchen appliances and“cutting-edge”techniques, of course, because we are paying just as much attention to the food’s consistency as our colleagues are busy doing at today’s top international restaurants.

Whereas others are using wines in their sauces and soups, we are making a systematic use of beers and ales, fruit juices and fruit-based vinegars for imparting a lively freshness and“edge”to ours. Vegetables, herbs and spices and wild plants in season play a decidedly prominent role in our cooking. Consequently, they take up more room on the plate than what is generally served in traditional gourmet restaurants.

Our intention at noma is to create and to prepare a distinctly advanced kind of cuisine, while nonetheless conjoining our patently Nordic approach with a manner of purity and simplicity in the approach. We are also busy infusing our new Nordic cuisine with a markedly curative potential. These values are all reflected in our menus’ultimate articulation and manifest themselves both in the construction and presentation of the individual courses and in the means of preparation and ingredients upon which they are based. acc521 May 10th, 2009, 01:40 AM ^^Too late mate, left Copenhagen this (or should I say yesterday) morning! Sanj May 10th, 2009, 04:23 AM Thanks for nothing&quot;mate&quot; miensie May 11th, 2009, 06:41 AM I went to Bellavista for dinner on Saturday night. Wasn&apos;t overly impressed.

I had the ravioli (again. Yeah, huge fan of ravioli). Obviously didn&apos;t read the menu properly because if I had&apos;ve seen that it came with a tomato cream sauce, I would not have ordered it. The sauce was too strong for it, so much so that I couldn&apos;t even taste the spinach and ricotta.
The ravioli itself wasn&apos;t fresh. Still quite tough so I could tell they must&apos;ve had it stored for a while or that perhaps it was pre-made.
Didn&apos;t like the pine nuts that were sprinkled on top. It was weird and didn&apos;t really mesh well.
Huge portion though for $23.50. I could only get through half and I was really hungry.
Had a garden salad and mixed vegetable as a side. $7 and $8 respectively.
The garden salad was mediocre with a bit of balsamic vinegar which I didn&apos;t like.
The mixed vegies were good though, very well roasted with subtle herb flavours throughout.

My boy had the scotch beef fillet and calamari. $32-something and $28-something respectively. Haha...he thought he could eat it all but the fillet itself was a substantial size and so too was the calamari.
He was happy with the fillet but didn&apos;t like the calamari. Even just looking at it, I could tell they&apos;d fried it in either really old oil or oil that wasn&apos;t hot enough so the batter was a strange off-white colour and not crispy.

Service was a bit slow but they were packed. There wasn&apos;t a spare table in the whole place and when I booked, I was told they only had one table outside. But by the time we got there (8.30pm) a table of 4, that was inside, had left so we took that table.

The waitress we had didn&apos;t really understand English that well so I had to repeat my order 3 times until she asked me to point at what I wanted. They could&apos;ve had a couple more people on the floor as it was quite difficult flagging someone down to get the bill.

$108-something which wasn&apos;t bad for how many dishes we ordered but don&apos;t think I&apos;ll be going back there again. crazyknightsfan May 11th, 2009, 06:43 AM lol,&quot;my boy&quot; miensie May 11th, 2009, 06:45 AM lol,&quot;my boy&quot;

:lol:

What do you guys want me to call him?! :poke: never happy. Humph.

P.S. hai CKF x crazyknightsfan May 11th, 2009, 06:50 AM life partner? interim CKF?

P.S. hai miensie!!11 hack404 May 11th, 2009, 06:51 AM Mon amour? miensie May 11th, 2009, 06:52 AM life partner?

I&apos;ve never liked it when people refer to their other half as their &apos;partner&apos;. Sounds like a joint venture or some such thing.


interim CKF?

Now this one I like ;)


P.S. hai miensie!!11

:hug:


lawl hack Sanj May 11th, 2009, 06:59 AM I went to Bellavista for dinner on Saturday night. Wasn&apos;t overly impressed.

I had the ravioli (again. Yeah, huge fan of ravioli). Obviously didn&apos;t read the menu properly because if I had&apos;ve seen that it came with a tomato cream sauce, I would not have ordered it. The sauce was too strong for it, so much so that I couldn&apos;t even taste the spinach and ricotta.
The ravioli itself wasn&apos;t fresh. Still quite tough so I could tell they must&apos;ve had it stored for a while or that perhaps it was pre-made.
Didn&apos;t like the pine nuts that were sprinkled on top. It was weird and didn&apos;t really mesh well.
Huge portion though for $23.50. I could only get through half and I was really hungry.
Had a garden salad and mixed vegetable as a side. $7 and $8 respectively.
The garden salad was mediocre with a bit of balsamic vinegar which I didn&apos;t like.
The mixed vegies were good though, very well roasted with subtle herb flavours throughout.

My boy had the scotch beef fillet and calamari. $32-something and $28-something respectively. Haha...he thought he could eat it all but the fillet itself was a substantial size and so too was the calamari.
He was happy with the fillet but didn&apos;t like the calamari. Even just looking at it, I could tell they&apos;d fried it in either really old oil or oil that wasn&apos;t hot enough so the batter was a strange off-white colour and not crispy.

Service was a bit slow but they were packed. There wasn&apos;t a spare table in the whole place and when I booked, I was told they only had one table outside. But by the time we got there (8.30pm) a table of 4, that was inside, had left so we took that table.

The waitress we had didn&apos;t really understand English that well so I had to repeat my order 3 times until she asked me to point at what I wanted. They could&apos;ve had a couple more people on the floor as it was quite difficult flagging someone down to get the bill.

$108-something which wasn&apos;t bad for how many dishes we ordered but don&apos;t think I&apos;ll be going back there again.

fuck me. $28 for entree calamari???? $23.50 for prebought spinach and ricotta ravioli?

i get so angry when i see shit like this. thanks for the heads up. ill be avoiding this place alvse May 11th, 2009, 07:20 AM I can&apos;t believe how expensive Snow Crab is :(

should have asked how much it would be before ordering :( Sanj May 11th, 2009, 07:25 AM haha where from? was it good tho? im a big fan of the black pepper crab at hawkers

by the way hawkers is closed until 3rd june. hack404 May 11th, 2009, 07:40 AM lawl hack

That&apos;s a laugh with a drawl? alvse May 11th, 2009, 07:42 AM haha where from? was it good tho? im a big fan of the black pepper crab at hawkers

by the way hawkers is closed until 3rd june.

City Garden... done in 2 styles

Hong Kong Style Chilli Crab, and some Egg Yoke batter thingo crazyknightsfan May 11th, 2009, 07:43 AM it&apos;s pronounced&quot;heeeeyuck&quot; Nate Von Longneck II May 11th, 2009, 08:10 AM Snow Crab is probably my favourite sea food.

I have seen it jump from (average chilli crab dish price) about $70 through to closer to $200 last time I had it...plate of gai lan, some rice, and a chilli snow crab was close to $200.

...been hitting up Hawkers a bit lately - had a buttery sauced crayfish, and would highly recommend it.... miensie May 11th, 2009, 08:16 AM fuck me. $28 for entree calamari???? $23.50 for prebought spinach and ricotta ravioli?

i get so angry when i see shit like this. thanks for the heads up. ill be avoiding this place

The calamari was actually a main, so not too bad I guess.
Sorrento&apos;s do a good calamari, or so I&apos;ve been told.

Bellavista is just around the corner from both our houses too. I thought it&apos;d be cool to find a good restaurant so close to home. Asking for too much I suppose.


That&apos;s a laugh with a drawl?

1337 speak :)


it&apos;s pronounced&quot;heeeeyuck&quot;

:lol: alvse May 11th, 2009, 08:17 AM yeah... the snow crab last night was $42 per pound... we had a 4.6 pounder :( Nate Von Longneck II May 11th, 2009, 08:25 AM yeah... the snow crab last night was $42 per pound... we had a 4.6 pounder :(

....was it worth it? Sanj May 11th, 2009, 08:28 AM Snow Crab is probably my favourite sea food.

I have seen it jump from (average chilli crab dish price) about $70 through to closer to $200 last time I had it...plate of gai lan, some rice, and a chilli snow crab was close to $200.

...been hitting up Hawkers a bit lately - had a buttery sauced crayfish, and would highly recommend it....

i actually think mud crabs are a little tastier but snow crabs are soooo much easier to eat as their shells are a lot softer.

havent had the buttery sauced crayfish but taking the whole family there on 5/6 as my grandparents are in town so might try it then.

any idea how much it is roughly? im already going to be paying for around 10 people with crab (grandparents love crab so i always order it) so need to prepare myself if its going to be a meal over $400-$500 alvse May 11th, 2009, 08:31 AM ....was it worth it?



oh... we where so merry and enjoying ourselves... then we got the bill... :lol:


I knew in the back of my mind that it would be expensive.... Nate Von Longneck II May 11th, 2009, 08:36 AM Pretty sure the cray was about $90, we had five people and everyone had a good amount shared around.

Connie at Hawkers remembers my name now - after waiting so long a couple of times to get it, I name dropped sanj....&quot;oh yeah the guy who brings the family in&quot;... haha, I get in much quicker now (special gwi-lo) (fuck, how do you spell gwi-lo?)

..Alvse, it was worth it then! Sanj May 11th, 2009, 08:51 AM hahahaha so i get name dropped now? i feel all special and shit.
someone did that at galileo once too (a while back tho).

she mentioned you a few months ago (not by name tho but i assume it was u) cos she was impressed that you ordered dishes more likely to be ordered by asians as opposed to whitefellas.

i saw her the other day when i popped in to get the rainbow tofu and thats when she said she would be closing for 3 weeks or so. alvse May 11th, 2009, 08:54 AM why is Hawkers closing for those weeks? They where so busy last night... there was a massive line outside. Sanj May 11th, 2009, 08:55 AM just for a break. she&apos;s going back to kl for a holiday etc i think. alvse May 11th, 2009, 08:57 AM lol... that place must be making truck loads of cash :lol: miensie May 11th, 2009, 09:00 AM (special gwi-lo) (fuck, how do you spell gwi-lo?)


lawl

Gweilo :okay: Nate Von Longneck II May 11th, 2009, 09:00 AM [QUOTE=Sanj;36480802] she mentioned you a few months ago (not by name tho but i assume it was u) cos she was impressed that you ordered dishes more likely to be ordered by asians as opposed to whitefellas.[QUOTE]

haha I got yellow fever.

..but seriously, I have a really developed SE asian palette. My favourite cuisine by far comes from SE Asia / China / Japan.

Nothing is too spicy, ever.

Dog is no problem.

This year, I would really like to explore Indian a bit deeper.

Are we still talking about food?

..also, there aint many whitefellas at hawkers, its a good whitey ratio. Nate Von Longneck II May 11th, 2009, 09:02 AM lawl

Gweilo :okay:

thanks miensie! alvse May 11th, 2009, 10:13 AM I&apos;m going to be trying Jus Burger for the first time tomorrow night... any recommendations? Also... is it hard to get a table for 4 at about 7:30? acc521 May 11th, 2009, 11:08 AM ^^At the risk of being boring - cheeseburger with Avocado is great. BartBart May 11th, 2009, 02:19 PM haha where from? was it good tho? im a big fan of the black pepper crab at hawkers

by the way hawkers is closed until 3rd june.

Thanks for that info - have been meaning to get there at some stage. stadiumdesigner May 11th, 2009, 03:01 PM I&apos;m going to be trying Jus Burger for the first time tomorrow night... any recommendations? Also... is it hard to get a table for 4 at about 7:30?

a) the mullet
b) somewhat miensie May 12th, 2009, 04:27 AM They don&apos;t do reservations, do they? Sanj May 12th, 2009, 06:56 AM I&apos;m going to be trying Jus Burger for the first time tomorrow night... any recommendations? Also... is it hard to get a table for 4 at about 7:30?

tuesday is their quietest night, which is why i tend to go on tuesdays. u shouldnt have much trouble trying to get a table at that time, maximum wait of 10 mins, if u have to wait at all.

i&apos;d definitely go one of their beef options. the cheeseburger with mushrooms (and blue cheese) is good, but u cant go wrong with the wagyu either, thats probably my favourite.

p.s - i normally ask for my patty to be cooked medium rare instead of medium. if u dont mind your meat pink id recommend that as it is juicier. miensie May 12th, 2009, 08:23 AM Does anyone know of any vintage shops in Perth other than Winifred and Bance in Inglewood and Retail Therapy in Wembley?

Also of any markets that are likely to have vintage? I missed the one in February and the one in April :(

Any help would be greatly appreciated as I&apos;m going through a huge vintage phase at the mo&apos; :) stadiumdesigner May 12th, 2009, 08:37 AM tuesday is their quietest night, which is why i tend to go on tuesdays. u shouldnt have much trouble trying to get a table at that time, maximum wait of 10 mins, if u have to wait at all.

i&apos;d definitely go one of their beef options. the cheeseburger with mushrooms (and blue cheese) is good, but u cant go wrong with the wagyu either, thats probably my favourite.

p.s - i normally ask for my patty to be cooked medium rare instead of medium. if u dont mind your meat pink id recommend that as it is juicier.
i love a bit of pink meat ;) oops, i should mention im a league player :banana: BartBart May 12th, 2009, 02:16 PM tuesday is their quietest night, which is why i tend to go on tuesdays. u shouldnt have much trouble trying to get a table at that time, maximum wait of 10 mins, if u have to wait at all.

i&apos;d definitely go one of their beef options. the cheeseburger with mushrooms (and blue cheese) is good, but u cant go wrong with the wagyu either, thats probably my favourite.

p.s - i normally ask for my patty to be cooked medium rare instead of medium. if u dont mind your meat pink id recommend that as it is juicier.

And what is the best day to go to Hawkers and what would be 3-4 dishes that you&apos;d recommend? I am sure I would like the majority of them anyway, &apos;cause I like that type of food. Dilaz89 May 12th, 2009, 05:44 PM Went to Maya in fremantle tonight. Probably the best indiant i&apos;ve had although very pricey. Good service too. miensie May 13th, 2009, 04:25 AM Budget: grossly inadequate says union
13 May 2009

By Tracey Porter

The union representing the textile clothing and footwear (TCF) industry has accused the government of spending more money conducting a review on the industry than it will securing its future.

The attack by Textile, Clothing&amp;Footwear Union of Australia national secretary Michele O&apos;Neil comes in response to last night&apos;s (May 12) federal budget in which Kevin Rudd&apos;s government announced a seven-year $401 million investment in TCF.

However O&apos;Neil, a member of the TCF Review reference group, said the government had abandoned the industry and ignored its own platform commitments.

She described the budget as being&quot;grossly inadequate&quot;to support the future of textile clothing and footwear jobs in Australia.

&quot;In order to thrive as it should, the industry needs $184 million per annum and this assistance needs to continue until at least 2020. I suspect that the government has spent more money conducting a review of the TCF industry than they will in securing its future,&quot;she said.

Key highlights of the government&apos;s announcements for the sector include:

The introduction of a new $30 million TCF Strategic Capability Program;
The introduction of a Clothing and Household Textile Building Innovative Capability Program to support investment and innovation with $25 million in additional funding;
The establishment of a TCF Industries Innovation Council bringing together businesses, unions, researches and government;
The establishment of a National TCF Innovation Network;

The commissioning of the TCF Industries Innovation Council to provide further advice on the introduction of a voluntary ethical quality mark, voluntary national sizing standards for clothing and footwear, and a national human measurement database

As recommended by the author of last year&apos;s Review of the Australian TCF Industries, Professor Roy Green, the new package will be partially funded by discontinuing the TCF Product Diversification Scheme and not proceeding with the TCF Supply Chain Opportunities Program, due to start in 2010. Sanj May 13th, 2009, 05:04 AM Went to Maya in fremantle tonight. Probably the best indiant i&apos;ve had although very pricey. Good service too.

ah havent been there in a few years. in my opinion it is the best north indian restaurant in perth altho i had heard recently ppl had slightly disappointing experiences.

good to hear u had a good time, ill let my mate know (he owns it with his brother).

how much was it? did they still have the whiting entree? that was fantastic the last time i was there. my favourite thing on the menu from memory miensie May 13th, 2009, 05:12 AM Sanj, you&apos;ve probably already been there but I only just saw a Steamboat place yesterday on my walk around NB. It&apos;s opposite Maya Masala?

You been? ryan79 May 13th, 2009, 07:39 AM Went back to Flying Taco with my mexican food loving mate.

Had a Burito with steak - quite nice and very filling. Better value for money.

Will try the chicken next. miensie May 13th, 2009, 08:32 AM 07/05/2009
&quot;YATES CHAMBERS&quot;
37 Barrack Street PERTH WA 6000
Retail Fitout - &apos;Saigon Bakery House&apos;.
50,000.00
BA-RF 2009/155

07/05/2009
&quot;YATES CHAMBERS&quot;
37 Barrack Street PERTH WA 6000
Change of Use from Travel shop to Bakery plus alteration to front of building.
45,454.55
DA 2009/2117
YAY for this bakery :banana:

07/05/2009
&quot;PICCADILLY ARCADE&quot;
700-704 Hay Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Retail Fitout Shop 20/22- &apos;Zubias Threading Studio&apos;
15,000.00 BA-RF 2009/158
What exactly is a &apos;Threading Studio&apos;?

08/05/2009
166-170 Murray Street Mall PERTH WA 6000
Refurbishment of Gloria Jeans
0.0
HEALTH 2009/9602

There&apos;s a new Vitamin shop opening up on Hay St too but thought maybe the excitement might be too much for y&apos;all. Sanj May 13th, 2009, 08:41 AM Sanj, you&apos;ve probably already been there but I only just saw a Steamboat place yesterday on my walk around NB. It&apos;s opposite Maya Masala?

You been?

i havent been actually, didnt know about it. i know there is steamboat on james st as well but havent been to that either. to be honest i havent eaten steamboat in a few years, definitely overdue.

where exactly opposite maya masala is it? i cant think of where it could be. miensie May 13th, 2009, 08:54 AM i havent been actually, didnt know about it. i know there is steamboat on james st as well but havent been to that either. to be honest i havent eaten steamboat in a few years, definitely overdue.

where exactly opposite maya masala is it? i cant think of where it could be.

Directly opposite Maya Masala is a pub. It&apos;s the building next to that (the pub), on the same side of the street, going west. Sanj May 13th, 2009, 08:56 AM Directly opposite Maya Masala is a pub. It&apos;s the building next to that (the pub), on the same side of the street, going west.

where toro used to be? has that closed down? i assume u&apos;re referring to francis st not lake st? Dilaz89 May 13th, 2009, 09:08 AM what&apos;s steamboat?

Sanj, the bill was $210 for 4 people. That included wine, starters and dessert. miensie May 13th, 2009, 09:10 AM where toro used to be? has that closed down? i assume u&apos;re referring to francis st not lake st?

I have no idea where or what Toro is/was.

Yep, Francis St.

what&apos;s steamboat?


*dies* samboy May 13th, 2009, 10:03 AM what&apos;s steamboat?



Asian Fondue ;)

I quite like the Seafood one at the Vientnamese place on William St (for the life me I can&apos;t remember the name. The OLD Yen Do) samboy May 13th, 2009, 10:08 AM 07/05/2009
&quot;YATES CHAMBERS&quot;
37 Barrack Street PERTH WA 6000
Change of Use from Travel shop to Bakery plus alteration to front of building.
45,454.55
DA 2009/2117
YAY for this bakery :banana:


There&apos;s a new Vitamin shop opening up on Hay St too but thought maybe the excitement might be too much for y&apos;all.

Sign of the economic times ;)


Yup the vitamin shop would be great for the same people who load up on junk food, grease, Sweets and wash it all down with a DIET Coke. 
 vBulletin®v3.8.7, Copyright©2000-2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
