<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003377" url="http://makegoodcoffee.com/coffee-talk/fear-and-latte-in-las-vegas/" time="2012-07-12-19:31" support="3" score="0.0038461601264148043" bingtitle="Fear and Latte in Las Vegas « Coffee Talk with Marc at Make Good ..." webtitle="Fear and Latte in Las VegasCoffee Talk with Marc at Make Good Coffee">
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>... to help you make the perfect cup of coffee at home. If you want to make ... Only a tourist like me would pay that ... in Vegas than anywhere and with fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		About Marc Ask Marc Contact Us 
 
 Make Great Coffee 
 
Buying Coffee
 Store Bought Coffee Buy Coffee Online 

 
Storing Coffee
 Keep it Fresh Keep it Simple 

 
Grinding Coffee
 Two Common Grinders Type of Grind 
 
 
Brewing Coffee
 Drip Brew French Press Espresso Turkish 

 
Serving Coffee
 Black Whitened Sweetened 

 
Coffee Maintenance
 Clean Brewer Clean Mug and Spoon Clean Water Residue of Flavor 
 Marc&apos;s Coffee Talk Our Coffee Tidbits 
 Golden Rules of Coffee Coffee Taste Terms Roast Style and Flavor Kinds of Coffee Cafe Mocha Recipes 
 Marc&apos;s Report Card The World of Coffee 
 Brazillian Coffee Columbian Coffee Costa Rican Coffee Ethiopian Coffee Guatemalan Coffee Hawaiian Coffee 

 Jamaican Coffee Kenyan Coffee Peruvian Coffee Sumatran Coffee Yemeni Coffee 
 Shopping Guide 
 
Marc&apos;s Coffee Talk

The Blog
 
Marc blogs about everything related to coffee, including answering the questions you’ve asked, keeping you posted on special coffee deals, and letting you know what he’s serving up hot from his own coffee bar.
 
Get Our Updates

Receive the latest coffee reviews
from Marc, as well as special offers and updates.
 User Name: Email:   
Got a question about coffee?

Ask Marc
 Full Name: * E-mail: Do not type in this field (spam-check) * Give Marc Your Best Shot 
 Search the Blog 
 Archives
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 October 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 
 Topics
 Brewing Coffee (61) Buying Coffee (89) Coffee and You (9) Coffee Gear (2) Coffee History (4) Coffee Maintenance (5) Coffee News (18) Coffees of the World (22) Fair Trade and the Environment (15) Make a Good Cafe Mocha (6) New Content (6) Serving Coffee (5) Storing Coffee (4) Uncategorized (15) 
 
 Current Trending Topics | Brewing Coffee (61), Buying Coffee (89) 
November
9,2010
 
 Fear and Latte in Las Vegas 
 Author | Marc Wortman 
 
 A savage journey to the heart of bad coffee… 

I don’t know why coffee is so bad in Las Vegas.  The city doesn’t mind giving you free booze and we all know why.  But since caffeine doesn’t counteract alcohol, you’d think they would want to keep us as caffeinated as they do inebriated so that we make bad gaming decisions but even later into the night.

 It starts in your hotel room.  I take it as standard fare that a hotel room has a coffee maker in it.  In Vegas, the hotels mostly all have casino floors so they do everything in their power to make sure you don’t stay in your room.  That includes not providing you with a coffee maker.  This forces you to leave the room sooner, exposing you to the gaming and gift shop sooner.

Like Hunter Thompson’s hero, I was in Vegas to cover a show and habitually late getting there.  So the quickest way to get my fix instead of waiting in lines was to grab a can of Monster Energy and drink it as I walked. The price: $6.48 / can. Only a tourist like me would pay that.

I ordered coffee with room service a couple times and the equivalent of two cups of coffee cost me $8.  And at best, I would rate it 6/10 coffee.

As I was passing through Treasure Island early in the week, I remembered they had a Starbucks.  I carry around a Starbucks gift card that was bought for me as a present.  So while I knew I’d still overpay, at least it was a gift from somebody who knew how badly I’d need a good coffee one day.

 When I walked in, the big sign let me know that Starbucks Cards were not redeemable at this location.  The cashier (sorry, barista) could not explain why they wouldn’t take the Card, only that they were not a“participating location”.  Read: What are you gonna do, tourist? Nothing!

And so, I paid $4.50 cash out of my pocket for this highly-trained barista to dispense already-brewed black coffee into a cup and hand it to me.  I don’t even want to know what the Pumpkin Spice Latte would’ve cost me.

Each of the major hotels has a 24-hour“cafe”with complete menu.  They all offer a coffee of some kind and while the price is definitely better than the room service coffee, it’s still the room service coffee.  They just know I’m into them for a whole meal too.

I wonder if there’s an opportunity for a local roaster to develop a brand among Vegas tourists and sell to these cafes.  The problem could be that Vegas tourist marketing is mass marketing (anybody and everybody from anywhere and everywhere), so the opportunity seems to be with the big established brands.  Meanwhile, Starbucks is more overpriced in Vegas than anywhere and with fast-food restaurant type service to boot.  I didn’t see any of the other big players.  I would have made a trip to visit a Peet’s, or settled for a $3 coffee at Seattle’s Best if I knew where to find one.


And in the end, the only cafe worth mentioning was a place called Coffee Corner in the Las Vegas Hilton.  But don’t go out of your way to find it, it’s only open during select conventions like the one I was at.  The gentleman working the coffee bar was a true barista and I didn’t mind paying him $4 for my straight black coffee.  The company I was with ordered lattes that were professionally made and well received.  If a select convention isn’t on, your next option is Hilton’s Paradise Cafe where they serve room service coffee at a much lower price.
 Share | (4) comments Categorized In | Buying Coffee 
 
4 Comments » 

 
We wished we knew that you were in the States…can’t wait to see you.
Now about the coffee, Even though we don’t live in Vegas I have to say…as an American.. sorry about your lack of a great cup of coffee.

 Comment by Robin—November 10, 2010 @ 6:03 am 
 
Try Delights which is a cafe on the lobby floor of tower two in the MGM Signature Towers. It’s better and less expensive than Starbucks.

 Comment by Joni—November 13, 2010 @ 7:34 pm 
 
@Robin, believe me I would NOT judge all coffee in the States by what they serve in Vegas. I know too well that you have some serious coffee markets and I can’t wait to visit them all!

 Comment by Marc Wortman —November 13, 2010 @ 8:02 pm 
 
@Joni, I love recommendations and I will definitely be back in Vegas soon enough. I cabbed it to the Mandalay a couple times but otherwise didn’t get that as far down the trip as the MGM Grand. Next time, I’ll have a reason to. Thanks for the recommendation.

 Comment by Marc Wortman —November 13, 2010 @ 8:04 pm 
 

 RSS feed for comments on this post. TrackBack URL 

Leave a comment
 Name Mail (will not be published) Website 
 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
Marc&apos;s Report Card
 I want to see Marc&apos;s Report Card 
About Make Good Coffee

Founded in 2006, Make Good Coffee is dedicated to helping people make better coffee at home. This site will provide you with all of the information you need, including the different coffees of the world, your best sources for coffee, the right process on how to make it, and other tidbits of simple information that will make your coffee better. Let your coffee tour begin.
 
Need Assistance?
 Sitemap 
 Contact Marc 
 About Marc 
 
Coffee Process
 Buying Coffee 
 Storing Coffee 
 Grinding Coffee 
 Brewing Coffee 
 Serving Coffee 
 Coffee Maintenance 
 LEARN MORE ABOUT MARC © 2006-09 MakeGoodCoffee.com
PORTLAND, OR, USA - ALL RIGHTS RESERVED

 SITE DESIGNED BY J.LINASDESIGN
	</body>
</document>
