<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003516" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/chick-fil-a-chino-hills?start=40" time="2012-07-12-19:39" support="13" score="0.030100461705813056" bingtitle="Chick-fil-A - Chino Hills, CA" webtitle="Chick-fil-A - Chino Hills, CA">
			<query id="000659" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000003" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001005" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001445" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000128" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000785" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001319" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000753" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000628" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000848" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001036" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000503" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001131" bing-rank="36"/>
	<description>Far and away the best quality, mass ... other restaurants hide napkins and condiments ... I hold this place to a higher standard than a &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant because I ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Chick-fil-A
 105 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Fast Food Fast Food   [Edit] 
 3640 Grand Ave 
 Chino Hills , CA 91709 
 (909) 628-4000 http://www.chickfila.com 
 
 Add Photos Hours: 
Mon-Sat 6:30 am - 10 pm
 Takes Reservations: No
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Price Range: $ 
 Delivery: Yes
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: Free
 Good For: Lunch, Dinner
 Alcohol: No
 Drive-Thru: Yes
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: No
 Caters: Yes
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 Dogs Allowed: Yes
 First to Review Sonny C. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
105 reviews for Chick-fil-A
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;Chicken sandwiches and waffle fries are mmmm yummy.&quot; In 25 reviews &quot;Can you say superb customer service .&quot; In 13 reviews &quot; eat mor chikin .&quot; In 2 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
105 reviews in English

 
Review from natalie t. 
 
 6 friends 196 reviews 

 natalie t. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 10/12/2010 
LOVE CHICK FIL A! if i could give it 7 stars i would!

first off, i used to eat this when i was a kid every weekend...so it just takes me back to my youth.

secondly, while i was a vegetarian for 7 years everyone always asked me what my first meaty meal was going to be when i decided to eat meat again and id tell them CHICK FIL A!  **still no sure why i was a vegetarian bc i love meat....stupid move as a kid!**

i am a huge chick fil a advocate!!

i LOVE their chicken strips with chick fil a sauce.

best place ever!! except for the fact that they arent open on sundays, due to religious reasons **rolls eyes**

service is friendly which is surprising because a lot of teens with there. theyre clean, efficient and GREAT!!

if i had a last meal, it would be chick fil a!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Scot B. 
 
 32 friends 4 reviews 

 Scot B. 
 
Claremont, CA
 3/23/2011 
The service at this restaurant is exemplary! Every time that my family eats here, we are treated like royalty. The staff is attentive, caring, and enthusiastic.

Not only is the customer service excellent, but the food is outstanding. I highly recommend the Chick-Fil-A Chicken Sandwich Combo #1. Sauces are available at the counter, and there are free refills on all drinks. Staff members often come to your table to ask if you would like a refill.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joe R. 
 
 21 friends 64 reviews 

 Joe R. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 3/6/2012 
Literally as good as it gets :-)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from April R. 
 
 0 friends 18 reviews 

 April R. 
 
Chino, CA
 12/9/2011 
Yum is all I have to say :) My kids love it!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jessica C. 
 
 15 friends 120 reviews 

 Jessica C. 
 
Hacienda Heights, CA
 6/29/2011 17 Check-ins Here 
&quot;It&apos;s my pleasure,&quot; to write a review for chick-fil-a.  So lets keep this review short and sweet.  Chicken sandwiches and waffle fries are mmmm yummy.  Their chick-fil-a sauce is something I would slather on anything, it&apos;s really THAT good.  Service and prices are stellar.  Only problem is that this Chick-fil-a is always packed especially during lunch time, so I have to hurry my ass back to work.  But it&apos;s all good because I will be a Chick-fil-a fatty for life!
 
 Listed in: Eating through Chino and the… , Best bang for less than 10… 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (5) Funny (6) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joseph A. 
 
 197 friends 132 reviews 

 Joseph A. 
 
Walnut, CA
 3/17/2008 
The first time I visited a Chick-fil-A restaurant was when there used to be one on the 2nd floor of Puente Hills Mall.  Whenever you would walk by, there almost always was an employee giving out samples of their chicken on toothpicks.  Back then, it was certainly a cut above the chicken patty at school and the stuff you would pick up in the grocer&apos;s freezer.

Since I was in the neighborhood, I decided that I&apos;d get my 2nd meal of the day here.  The huge inflatable mascot that my &quot;virtual sister-in-law&quot; wrote about was not available for vandalization.  Perhaps a warning from the Bob&apos;s Big Boy people made it out to them.

I wasn&apos;t really feeling for a chicken sandwich, so I picked a 6-count box of Chick-n-Strips and some medium Waffle Potato Fries.  Without counting calories from ketchup and the dipping sauces, that&apos;s already 820 kcal.

Like Alli N. mentioned, service was quick and friendly.  However, as I took my tray to my table, I felt like something was missing.  Condiments were available at this bay where you could pick up utensils, napkins, etc.  As I scanned the counter, all I could see was ketchup, mayo, and tabasco.  Since I was eager to eat, I just said &quot;F-it, I guess they don&apos;t do dipping sauces!&quot;.  So, I relegated myself to enjoying the chicken tenderloins with ketchup.

Half way into my chicken, which happened to coincide with Diet Soda Refill Time, I could not accept the idea that Chick-fil-A did not have dipping sauces.  McDonald&apos;s has dipping sauces.  KFC has dipping sauces.  Denny&apos;s has dipping sauces.  It just did not add up.  So, when I went to get my refill, I asked.

Guess what?  Yeah, they have a lot of dipping sauces.  Damn, and I was almost finished with the chicken.  The sauces go well with the Waffle Potato Fries.  They are nice, light,  and crispy, but not quite as tasty as the Criss-Cut Fries for Carl&apos;s Jr.

The restaurant itself  has a pleasant decor.  It actually comes off as really spacious because there seems to be more seating here than I would expect.  They&apos;ve got a playground for the kiddies, with a special Tuesday night Kid&apos;s Meal thingy going on.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from krissa m. 
 
 92 friends 103 reviews 

 krissa m. 
 
Diamond Bar, CA
 6/1/2009 10 Check-ins Here 
I love this place. Their chicken nuggets are freaking amazing. The Polynesian sauce is my favorite! And the waffle like fries are a perfect combination with the chicken nuggets.

I&apos;ve also had the new spicy chicken sandwich and it&apos;s so good! It has enough spice to kick you in the mouth but not too much that you need to gulp gallons of milk to ease the spice! I&apos;d recommend trying it at least once!!

And my favorite thing of all, is their great great customer service!!! Seriously, hands down, one of the best customer services I have ever experienced. I went with my friend who has never been there before. I told the guy that it was her first time. So after getting our food and sitting down, he came back to us and gave my friend a free chicken strip. So she can taste the difference between the two. How awesome is that??

We were asked once how we were doing and if we needed anything. How nice of them!!

Go to this Chik-fil-a and you won&apos;t be sorry!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (5) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Monty P. 
 
 34 friends 12 reviews 

 Monty P. 
 
Diamond Bar, CA
 2/8/2010 
I used to go to the 24 hour fitness that&apos;s located right by this Chick-Fil-A.  Now, I just skip the gym and go straight for the food!

This restaurant is incredibly well maintained, although this is the rule rather than the exception here in Diamond Bar.  The service is fantastic, and the food comes fast.

As far as taste, the waffle fries get 5 stars ... they&apos;re by far the hottest item on the menu in my opinion.  The chicken sandwich?  Well that&apos;s only a 3-pointer.  The meat is juicy but the breading is a bit soggy.  I wouldn&apos;t be able to get through the sandwich were it not for all they amazing dipping sauces they stock at the place.  Which dipping sauce to use?  The ChickFilA sauce is definitely the best.  It&apos;s some mix of honey mustard and mayonaisse.  Delicious!

They have this posting on the wall of the restaurant which gave ChickFilA an A for health consciousness.  Don&apos;t know where they came up with that, but I demand data!  I doubt they&apos;d top that list, although they do have some healthy eats on the menu.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Cindy P. 
 
 2 friends 18 reviews 

 Cindy P. 
 
Chino, CA
 1/31/2010 
Oh God, don&apos;t even get me started on how good those tiny chicken nuggets are.  They have so many different dipping sauces, you will become dizzy trying to figure out which one is the tastiest.

I go on the treadmill for an hour after we eat there.  I can&apos;t stop shoveling those delectable morsels in my mouth.  The meal MUST always be completed with a super duper, tasty and moist brownie.  mmmm, the only negative I can think of about Chick fila is that they&apos;re closed on Sunday.  I respect their reasons, but WISH I could eat there on Sunday.  :)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from alli c. 
 
 106 friends 158 reviews 

 alli c. 
 
Walnut, CA
 2/4/2008 
All you food snobs can flog me for loving a chain fast food restaurant on Yelp, but bring it on.  I will always love you, Chick-Fil-A.

Chick-Fil-A is so stinkin&apos; good.  I would leave early from my house in the morning just to make sure I had enough time to go to Chick-Fil-A for breakfast.  Their service is pretty quick and their employees are always very polite.  They&apos;ve been trained well!  Their chicken sandwiches are so good, they are even loved by my red-meat eating friends.

Their battered chicken sandwiches are fried in peanut oil which gives it a special taste that sticks it to KFC and other fried chicken joints.  Their chicken is rarely dry and REAL - none of that formed chicken patty crap.  They&apos;re served up on a bun with some pickles, and then you top it off with your choice of condiments.  There&apos;s always the basic ketchupmustardmayo, but if you&apos;re feeling especially deviant (you daredevil you), ask for different sauces - honey mustard, polynesian, ranch, etc..  Yummy lemonade too, but skip the fruit cups - they&apos;re very meager portions. And seriously, if you&apos;re gonna get a big hunk of fried chicken you might as well get the waffle fries :)

This Chick-Fil-A has kid-friendly Tuesday nights with discounted meals for kids, bingo, raffles, balloons, and a huge Eat-More-Chikin cow - udders and all.  Fun to go to but noisy.
 
 Listed in: time to wear the fat pants 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from K B. 
 
 9 friends 46 reviews 

 K B. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 8/21/2007 1 photo 
Chick-fil-A&apos;s huge inflatable mascot is hilarious (check out the photo! :P) and one of the main things that attracted me into the facility.

The restaurant is clean, customer service is good, and their milkshakes are decent, however I was a bit disappointed by their chicken salad sandwich.  It was like tasteless mush pushed between two thin slices of bread and I can&apos;t really see how anyone could get full off of it unless they ordered 2 or 3 of them.  I left feeling that it would&apos;ve been better sticking to the Original chicken sandwiches since they&apos;re cheaper and taste much better.

I&apos;ll never get that sandwich again, but the place is worth a revisit.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Angie P. 
 
 19 friends 17 reviews 

 Angie P. 
 
Pomona, CA
 8/31/2011 4 Check-ins Here 
Love love love this chick-fil-a. The food is amazing and so is the service!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Viel C. 
 
 4 friends 16 reviews 

 Viel C. 
 
Chino, CA
 1/23/2011 9 Check-ins Here 
Hands down one of my favorite fast food places... although it never really seems like a fast food restaurant too me. All of the staff are very friendly, and there&apos;s something about them saying &quot;my pleasure!&quot; after you thank them for your food. And props to them for sticking to their values (they are closed on Sundays) and not just for profit.

My absolute favorites are the chicken nuggets as well as their milkshakes... delicious! And the oh so many dipping sauces you can pick and choose... Their signature Chick-fil-A sauce is the best!

And don&apos;t forget the waffle fries... its worth going to the place by itself!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tania S. 
 
 25 friends 52 reviews 

 Tania S. 
 
Downtown, Los Angeles, CA
 9/16/2010 5 Check-ins Here 
Best nuggets in the world.
PERIOD.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tracy G. 
 
 159 friends 443 reviews 

 Tracy G. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 3/22/2007 
Ok, I love Chick-fil-A.  Especially their Chicken Minis, which is basically chicken nuggets on Sister Shubert&apos;s Rolls.  If you are not from the South, you may not know the wonderfulness of Sister Shubert&apos;s Yeast Rolls.   But, they are great.  For lunch, I like the original chicken sandwich.  Very good.  Nothing like the chicken sandwiches at other fast food establishments.

The majority of my Chick-fil-A experiences involve the mall food court.  So it was nice not to have to go to a mall.  Very big (maybe thats just comparing it to what I am used to), has a family night every Tuesday.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jason A. 
 
 63 friends 55 reviews 

 Jason A. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 6/13/2009 10 Check-ins Here 
From what I hear, Chick-fil-A has alot of hype for a fast food joint and after visiting a view times, I&apos;m still not that excited about the hype.

One of the great things that highlight this place is that they have excellent customer service. Staff was extremely courteous and polite. A nice thing about their menu options is the different side items you can choose besides the typical soda and fries. Nice to have choice.

Chicken is one of the hardest foods to give flavor too and it still remains so. Nothing really exciting about their chicken sandwiches or their chicken nuggets. What I am excited about and willing to come back for is their delicious waffle french fries, several sauces to choose from, and their sweetened ice tea. I&apos;ll actually come back for those cravings rather than their chicken sandwiches. I haven&apos;t tried neither their salads nor their breakfast menu yet. Since I live not too far, will visit again to check out the ones I haven&apos;t eaten yet.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tamar F. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 113 friends 516 reviews 

 Tamar F. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 6/20/2009 
Last year J wound up with about a 100-coupon stack of &quot;be our guest&quot; cards.  Luckily, I was living in Redlands, home of a Chick-fil-A.  But J rarely ventured to the boonies, and since I would come to LA straight from work, the coupons were largely untouched.  Then, as I began my move to LA, I realized that the closest one en route was the Chino Hills location.  So me&amp;my carpool buddy, P, decided to make a weekly Wednesday stop to this place.

J had also wound up with a copy of the &quot;How&apos;d you do it, Truett&quot; book, which I read one weekend when I was just that bored.  In it, he mentions all of the ways in which he trains his staff.  For example, if you say &quot;Thanks&quot;, they&apos;ll respond with &quot;My Pleasure.&quot;  I thought this was really hilarious at first, but it&apos;s really caught on.  Go to McDonalds and say thanks and the response will be &quot;no problem.&quot;  &quot;My pleasure&quot; just has some better ring to it.

Although I won&apos;t eat the chicken here (not kosher, obviously), J and P love the chicken sandwiches and nuggets.  Yes, it&apos;s fast food, but it&apos;s much fresher than what you&apos;ll get at KFC or Burger King.  The fries are yummy and I&apos;m not a big fan of waffle fries, in general.  And the shakes are awesome.  You can actually recognize ingredients, not the sludge that you get at Mickey D&apos;s.

I always get my food to go, but it seems like they keep this place really clean.  And they have lots of specials here, too.  I&apos;m a fan!
 
 Listed in: The Chain Gang , Lunch Spots in the I.E. 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kristen R. 
 
 26 friends 206 reviews 

 Kristen R. 
 
Mountain View, CA
 8/21/2008 
Long, long ago when I was a wee little one I remember eating at a place called Chick-fil-a. Then, suddenly, it disappeared and was pretty much non-existent in California. Years later, out of the clear blue, Chick-fil-a locations started popping up again in Southern California. This was like a dream come true. After so many years, Chick-fil-a still tasted as great as I remember it as a kid.

Many people mistake Chick-fil-a as any other fast food joint. This is not true at all. I don&apos;t eat much fast food, but I absolutely love Chick-fil-a. This is definitely a place for chicken lovers! I don&apos;t know what it is about their chicken nuggets, but they are so addicting. They&apos;re always nicely crisp and so moist and juicy. What other place makes chicken nuggets with such good quality white meat? Also, they make a polynesian sauce that is to die for. It goes so well with the nuggets.

Another thing that makes Chick-fil-a stand out is the customer service and the cleanliness of their locations. They&apos;re also closed on Sundays! Make sure you don&apos;t start craving those nuggets on a Sunday, otherwise it&apos;ll be a rough end to your weekend.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Erik D. 
 
 1 friend 6 reviews 

 Erik D. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 10/5/2011 
5 Stars. Spicy Chicken Deluxe for me everytime. Super tasty and their Chick-fil-A sauce puts it over the top.  Service is great too.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ara S. 
 
 31 friends 28 reviews 

 Ara S. 
 
Glendale, CA
 6/7/2011 
The best tasting chicken EVER.  My favorite sandwich is the spicy chicken sandwich with Chick FIL A sauce.  The waffle fries are very tasty and not greasy and salty like other fast food restaurants.  The chicken strips are also amazing, and its fun to eat them with the wide variety of FREE dipping sauces.  Don&apos;t you just hate it when fast food joints charge you for sauce? I know I do...  The dipping sauces are not placed behind the counter so you don&apos;t have to ask an employee if its ok to get extra.... You can just grab as many as you want
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Keli K. 
 
 10 friends 17 reviews 

 Keli K. 
 
Hemet, CA
 8/19/2011 
I LOVE this CHIK-FIL-A !!!  These employees must really be taken care of b/c they are SUPERB at customer service!!...SUPER friendly&amp;FAST!! LOVE the sauces threy provide, FOOD is DELISH!! and it&apos;s very CLEAN,&amp;kid-FRIENDLY TOO!!  If I could afford it, I&apos;d eat here all the time!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alice C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 972 friends 347 reviews 

 Alice C. 
 
Laguna Hills, CA
 12/12/2010 1 Check-in Here 
i learned that all chick-fil-a are closed on sundays the hard way :(  after stopping in front of the drive thru intercom:

(via recorded message)
man:  thank you for visiting chick-fil-a, we are open from monday-saturday...  blah blah.
me:  wtf?!

(via text message)
me:  are all chick-fil-as closed on sundays?!
friend:  yeah the owner is religious, gotta get your fix on saturdays.

fml.  eff my sunday.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (7) Funny (9) Cool (7) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Power N. 
 
 32 friends 21 reviews 

 Power N. 
 
Sacramento, CA
 1/27/2008 
I used to live around Chino Hills before moving up to Sacramento.  This is the Chick-fil-a that overall has stood up to my expectations.  (The one near where I currently live is disappointing)

Anyway, I kinda consider Chick-fil-a the In-and-Out of chicken sandwiches.  I enjoy their waffle fries as well as their basic chicken sandwiches without having to pay a lot extra just for a piece of lettuce and tomato.  Their diet coke mixture is always perfect as well.

The drive-through is usually super-fast for some reason.  The service is usually very polite and on-top of things too.  Kids working the drive-thru are generally good at remembering everything and asking for condiments.  They trained most of them well for a change.

I started going to this place even more after I started internship and I&apos;d be driving home from my night shifts in the morning for their breakfast meals which aren&apos;t half bad.  Occasionally, I&apos;d dine-in because they give out free samples of ice cream or other goodies such as their breakfast items.

Unfortunately, they don&apos;t open on Sundays keeping in tradition with the owner&apos;s desire for employees to have their day of rest.

I highly recommend stopping by this Chick-fil-a.  (You can also stop by Henry&apos;s Marketplace for some groceries before you pick up your hot food to go home too!)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ali R. 
 
 2 friends 2 reviews 

 Ali R. 
 
Diamond Bar, CA
 1/14/2012 
This place is delicious! Especially for a fast food chicken sandwich; in my opinion, it blows all other spicy chicken sandwiches out of the water.  Although, their Achilles heal has to be their sides.  The criss cut fries are among the dukiest on the planet and the other choices are carrots and raisins or Cole slaw, which I&apos;m not a big fan of.  Overall great fast food and a super friendly staff.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Bernadette S. 
 
 4 friends 85 reviews 

 Bernadette S. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 6/16/2011 1 Check-in Here 
For a fastfood joint, this place couldn&apos;t get any better.  The service is the first thing that people notice and I must say that the staff are genuinely nice and helpful.  The place is super clean and food is surprisingly fresh!  And, unlike McDonald&apos;s, you can have as much of the dipping sauces as you want and, yes, at no extra charge :) .
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Daniel Z. 
 
 42 friends 20 reviews 

 Daniel Z. 
 
La Puente, CA
 7/9/2010 1 Check-in Here 
Parking can be a pain during lunch rush.

The food is great!!! My cashier guy was awesome someone give him a raise! I was very pleased with his service and how he spoke to me!

Try the new spicy chicken sandwich it&apos;s very good
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from O Z. 
 
 0 friends 7 reviews 

 O Z. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 8/21/2011 1 Check-in Here 
My family and I love Chick-fil-A. The quality of the food, especially the chicken strips is fabulous! I would go there more, but they&apos;re a bit pricey.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Juliette W. 
 
 0 friends 10 reviews 

 Juliette W. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 8/14/2011 
Expensive for what you get. Nothing special. Exceptional service. Generous sauce allowance, through which you can try to earn back the money that you overpaid for the food itself.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tammy L. 
 
 83 friends 39 reviews 

 Tammy L. 
 
Walnut, CA
 1/20/2011 
waffle.....FRIES?!?!?! Needless to say, I get my nom nom on everything I come here. Everything here tastes good to me! I&apos;d come here 8 days a week if #1 there was such a thing, #2 they weren&apos;t  closed on Sundays, #3 I won&apos;t die from cardiac arrest. The chicken is juicy, the place is clean, the staff is friendly, and most of all, there is automated hand-sanitizer in he bathroom. That spells win to me!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from BRiTNEE H. 
 
 3 friends 15 reviews 

 BRiTNEE H. 
 
Arcadia, CA
 7/8/2009 
I love love love Chik-fil-A!!

I wish their was one near by (the SGV), but unfortunately I can only eat here when I&apos;m in the area.

I have had everything from their AWESOME breakfast,
and their delicious lunch combos.

The chicken has a great flavor WAY better than any other chicken joint.
The fries&amp;the dipping sauce (Polynesian) are to die for.
Seriously, Chik-fil-A is probably one of the best fast-food places I have been too..

Their food is of GREAT quality (I am always satisfied)
Their service is EXCELLENT (the workers go out of their way to welcome you)
Best of all, it&apos;s not the expensive!

And then, when I thought it couldn&apos;t get any better.....

Their SWEET ICE TEA is THE BEST I have ever had!!!
(and they sell it BY THE GALLON!!!
omg. I think I just had an orgasm.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jerald S. 
 
 78 friends 231 reviews 

 Jerald S. 
 
Moreno Valley, CA
 1/12/2011 5 Check-ins Here 
Really how do you rate this place anything lower than a 5? You absolutely can&apos;t go wrong with anything on their menu. Spicy Chicken FTW! Those Fries have win all over them get them extra crispy there DDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDDAAAAAAAAAANNNNNK. The oreo milkshake man i&apos;d get that shit all the time, but I&apos;m not trynna OD on it. This location though is probably the best one I have ever been too what sets them apart from any other one is there service. They offer different specials as well that other locations don&apos;t which is cool.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Danielle A. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Danielle A. 
 
Chino, CA
 1/6/2012 
I LOVE THIS PLACE!!! They have amazing service and food. They are also kid friendly and my nieces love when I take them there. They go out of there way to make sure there costumes enjoy there visit.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Danielle P. 
 
 14 friends 17 reviews 

 Danielle P. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 8/29/2010 
My favorite fast food! It&apos;s not greasy and tastes delicious with just the pickles and no condiments. It&apos;s delicious, and offers one of the healthiest menus around. They&apos;re also one of the few places left that don&apos;t work on Sundays, which is kind of a bummer, but it&apos;s funny to see people lined up at the drive thru waiting to order :D lol!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Shari M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 393 friends 392 reviews 

 Shari M. 
 
Inland Empire
 10/17/2009 12 Check-ins Here 
So I waited awhile to review this place because this place was my very first job, but screw that! That was 5 years ago, my review shouldn&apos;t be considered bias because there&apos;s an entirely new batch of people.

Man I freaking LOVE this place!!!  I have tried EVERYTHING on the menu [[except for the shakes, besides cookies and cream]].  Breakfast is absolutely great and lunch/dinner is even better. I came here today and I am NEVER dissapointed.  Chick-fil-a is probably the only place I would order a salad from [[but I didn&apos;t get that today]].  They are always so nice. The signature &quot;my pleasure&quot; phrase is something I still say when someone thanks me while I&apos;m at work.  My food is always fresh and hot also!

They have kids night for the little ones, which I will say, started when I worked there and was MY friend&apos;s idea.  You buy a regular meal and get a kid&apos;s meal free.  They also have games or art for kids to do inside.  Can I say the play place is amazing?!  It doesnt smell like pee either. We also had the idea of bringing in a milk shake machine because so many people were coming through the drive thru asking if we have them since In-N-Out is down the street.  Oh, and the black shirt, khaki pants uniform ...::raises hand::... us once again.  It started out with checkered red and black shirts and black pants and we told management &quot;nuh uhn, we need to change this. can we do [[literally]] black polos and khaki pants?&quot; I feel like we should be getting compensated or something haha.  Granted they have milkshakes machines at the ones in the south and im sure the uniforms were different, but those certainly werent a part of this place until we pointed it out.... just sayin

They dont charge for extra condiments, you can get the tasty sweet tea and lemonade by the gallon, and it&apos;s pretty much healthier than any of the fast food chicken you&apos;d get.  I hold this place to a higher standard than a &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant because I actually know what goes on behind the scenes and the staff is actually taught to be respectable.
 
 Listed in: The I.E. Born and Raised! 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (10) Funny (5) Cool (7) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ana R. 
 
 0 friends 6 reviews 

 Ana R. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 4/19/2011 
I love this place. When I am in a rush and short of time, Chick -fil-A is tops in my list. Their Grilled chicken sandwich is the best! Prices are very reasonable. Place is super clean. Best of all, service is very courteous and efficient and makes you feel vital to their business! Five stars!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Bonnie Y. 
 
 47 friends 359 reviews 

 Bonnie Y. 
 
Chino, CA
 7/10/2009 
ah... BEST chicken sandwich at a fast-food place i&apos;ve ever had!!! i finished the original chicken sandwich in like 3 minutes and i was still hungry! lol... the quality is awesome... so worth it though it&apos;s a little more expensive than the &apos;regular&apos; fast food place...

waffle fries is the bomb too! and the sauces... i eat everything with it... yum! ah... i wanna go back now...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Steve P. 
 
 21 friends 15 reviews 

 Steve P. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 8/23/2010 6 Check-ins Here 
Have driven past these for years and always told myself - &quot;self, one day we&apos;re going to try that place&quot;. Today, I took self to eat here for the first time. The quality and freshness of the food was outstanding. The grilled chicken was very juicy and tasty. The cashier entered our order wrong (I ordered a #8 but she thought I asked for an eight piece nuggets), but the staff went out of their way to make it right including bringing it to my table and waiting while I checked to be sure it was what I wanted. The salad dressing could stand to be colder but otherwise an excellent lunch and the start of a long term relationship. I will definitely bring self back to eat here...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from asmita j. 
 
 15 friends 99 reviews 

 asmita j. 
 
Chino Hills, CA
 9/1/2010 
this is seriously one of the best fast food restaurants i have ever been to. the service was incredibly welcoming (even though it was near closing time). after asking what is good here, i decided on the spicy chicken sandwich and some waffle fries (all to go). I picked out some sauces (of course!) and headed home. i was shocked to find my sandwich made so perfectly -- only the freshest lettuce, juicest tomatoes, and most succulent  chicken. it was all breast meat, and very crispy (but not too oily). the sauces were all awesome, though my fave were the buffalo and bbq.

i will definitely be coming back!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from David K. 
 
 10 friends 104 reviews 

 David K. 
 
San Gabriel, CA
 7/17/2008 
Chick-Fil-A is one of those chains I just don&apos;t get around to very often because they are just not close to where I normally am.
I&apos;ve always liked this chain, its just got that friendly mojo.
This location also happens to be one of the nicer ones that I&apos;ve been too, the staff is friendly and helpful and its pretty clean with a good amount of seating. The parking lot is pretty good size as part of the shopping center but during peak time it will probably be overly crowded.
The chicken is just good eats, though I know it can be a little bland for some people. The waffle fries and sweet tea also get a big thumbs up.
I know a lot of people that really like their shakes, though personally I&apos;ve never ordered one.
It&apos;s interesting how this chain has been expanding so much lately that mc donalds has now made southern fried chicken biscuits and sandwiches to copy them due to increased fast food market competition.

#1 Personal Recommendation:
Get some kind of fried chicken, like the nuggets or a sandwich, and an order of waffle fries too.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joshua B. 
 
 2 friends 3 reviews 

 Joshua B. 
 
Chino, CA
 8/5/2009 
I really don&apos;t get the hype on this place.....Tried it when they opened a few years ago and thought overpriced, plain, dry, and not very tasty for a chicken sandwich.  Tried it again this week and again I would describe it the same way.  And closed on Sunday,?  had to wait a couple days for this meal and now give it 1 star because of the wait.  Farmer Boys has better chicken sands and so does, shall I say it, Mickey D&apos;s.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 41 to 80 of 105 ( 19 Filtered )

 |   
 Page: 1 2 3 
 Write a Review View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 Corner Bakery Cafe  62 reviews &quot;cause I luv the Roasted Tomato Basil.&quot; Chick-Fil-A  145 reviews &quot;the waffle fries dipped in icecream yumMAY.&quot; Roscoe&apos;s Famous Deli  203 reviews &quot;Curly fries are so good and a huge portion.&quot; Jack In the Box  2 reviews 
Chino Hills, CA
 Shoboo Kitchen  138 reviews &quot;We started with the miso soup which was absolutely...&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 The I.E. Born and Raised! 
Stopping hating on the I.E! We&apos;re more than just cows, deserts, lifted trucks, and meth labs! haha
 Best bang for less than 10 bucks 
The places I visit when I&apos;m broke... but if I am broke than maybe I should stop going out?
 5 Star Status! 
I&apos;m picky&amp;not very generous with my 5 stars, so these places are surely special!
 Breakfast Hating 
Here&apos;s where I like to come to eat a non breakfast breakfast
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Chik Fil A Chino Hills Delivery Food Chino Hills Food Delivery Services Chino Hills 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Chino Hills Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
