<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003235" url="http://www.melaniecooks.com/rezas-restaurant-in-chicago-review/904/" time="2012-07-12-19:22" support="4" score="0.020591742450656553" bingtitle="Reza’s Restaurant Review | Melanie Cooks" webtitle="Rezas Restaurant Review | Easy Recipes With Pictures">
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>... red tablecloths on the tables and red cloth napkins. ... tomato-lentil soup that is included when you order ... » Chipotle Mexican Grill Fast Food Restaurant Review</description>
	<body>
		Melanie Cooks 
 
 Home Contact Privacy Policy 
 
Reza’s Restaurant Review
 By Melanie Mendelson 
 
 
Reza’s Restaurant In Chicago is my favorite place to get Middle-Eastern Food.  The cuisine is Reza’s in Persian.  Reza’s restaurant has a buffet and a menu, and both options are excellent.

Reza’s restaurant is quite big, with 2 separate large rooms.  There are red tablecloths on the tables and red cloth napkins.  The walls feature unique original artwork.

The portions of the entrees from the menu are huge…really huge.  Most restaurants tend to have oversized portions, but Reza’s portions are truly large.  No matter how hungry I am, I can never eat more than half of the dinner portion, so I take the other half home with me for the next day’s dinner.  Sharing a portion for 2 people is also an option.

The food on the menu is pretty inexpensive.  For example, kabab combination plate (that is enough for 2 people) is $14.95.

The menu entrees come with the radish plate (fresh radishes, parsley and feta cheese), pita bread, grilled vegetables (tomatoes, bell peppers and onions) and tomato-lentil soup.  Tomato-lentil soup is full of flavor–really tasty!  The entrees are served with a choice of white rice, dill rice or grilled potatoes.  My favorite is dill rice–it’s quite unique, nothing like any other rice I’ve tried.

I always order baba ganoush –that’s my favorite appetizer!

Here’s the photo of Reza’s baba ganoush:
 
 
Here are the things that I tried at Reza’s and absolutely loved: baba ganoush, hummus, tauboulli, falafel, filet mignon beef kabob, ground beef kabob, chicken kabob, ground chicken kabob, vegetarian shami (falafel balls coated with pomegranate-walnut sauce) and stuffed grape leaves.

Here’s a photo of tomato-lentil soup that is included when you order an entree:
 

Here’s the photo of the chicken combo–chicken breast kabob and ground chicken kabob, served with dill rice and grilled vegetables:
 

Here’s the photo of the beef kabob combo–fillet mignon kabob and ground beef kefta kabob, served with dill rice and grilled vegetables:
 

For your drink, order the ice tea–it’s really good at Reza’s.  If you have room for dessert, go for the baklavah!

There are 2 Reza’s locations in Chicago: 5255 N. Clark St and 432 W. Ontario St.  There is also a Reza’s location in Oakbrook (West Chicago Suburb) and the address is 40 N Tower Rd, Oak Brook, IL 60523.  I’ve been to all 3 Reza’s locations and the food is very similar.  In fact, I didn’t notice any difference in food quality, quantity or presentation.  All 3 Reza’s restaurant locations are equally good.
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 
 

 Enter the code shown on the above image: * 

 

 
 Hi! I&apos;m Melanie Mendelson.
Welcome to my kitchen!
 ARE YOU HUNGRY? 
 
Categories

 Appetizer Recipes Beef Recipes Bread Recipes Breakfast Ideas Breakfast Recipes Chicken Recipes Coffee Convenience Foods Cooking Tips Cooking With Kids Costco Foods Dessert Recipes Dough Recipes Drink Recipes Egg Recipes Fish and Seafood Fish Recipes Food Safety Food Storage Foods&amp;Ingredients Fruits Fuzzy Logic Rice Cooker Recipes General Holidays Kids Meals Kitchen Gadgets Knife Skills Pasta Recipes Pizza Recipes Restaurant Reviews Salad Recipes Salsa Recipes Sandwich Recipes Sauce Recipes Seafood Recipes Shrimp Recipes Side Dish Recipes Slow Cooker Recipes Snacks Step-By-Step Guides Turkey Recipes Using Leftovers Vegetables Vegetarian Main Dishes Wrap Recipes 
 
Search Melanie’s Recipes:
 
Featured Recipes

 Stir Crazy Restaurant Review (Northbook, Chicago Suburbs) Signature Room At The 95th Floor Of John Hancock Building Restaurant Review Chicago Botanic Gardens Garden Cafe And Grille Restaurant Review Great Karoo Restaurant Review At Kalahari Resort, Wisconsin Dells WI Dengeos Restaurant Review (Skokie and Buffalo Grove, IL, Chicago Suburbs) Las Palmas Mexican Restaurant Review (Highland Park IL, Chicago Suburbs) Benihana Restaurant Review (Wheeling IL, Chicago Suburb) My Pie Pizza In Northbrook IL - Review Senoya Buffet Restaurant Review (Niles IL, Chicago Suburbs) The Cheese Factory Restaurant Review (Wisconsin Dells, WI) 
 Copyright©2012 Melanie Cooks . All Rights Reserved.
 
 Reza&apos;s Restaurant In Chicago is my favorite place to get Middle-Eastern Food.  The cuis Pin It
	</body>
</document>
