<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003967" url="http://www.spain-info.com/madrid/Madrid-Restaurants.html" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="1" score="0.0013180881856765729" bingtitle="Madrid Spain Restaurant Guide - Spain Info com" webtitle="Madrid Spain Restaurant Guide">
			<query id="000705" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>Madrid Car Rental: Living in Madrid: Madrid Forum : Madrid Links: Information on ... Madrid Restaurants: Madrid Restaurants. With options ranging from the oldest continuously ...</description>
	<body>
		Madrid Spain Guide, Culture in Spain, a map of Spain, history 
of Spain, Spain discussion forums, and more!! All the information on Spain you could want. 
 
 
 

 
 Information 
on Madrid Madrid 
Guide Home Madrid Maps Madrid 
Museums and Cultural Attractions Madrid 
History Madrid 
Hotels Madrid 
Restaurants, Cafes and Terrazas Madrid 
Shopping Madrid 
Car Rental Living 
in Madrid Madrid 
Forum Madrid 
Links Information 
on Spain Home Culture in Spain Map of Spain History of Spain Area 
Guides Tourism Guide Living in Spain Guide Property in Spain Guide   Spain 
Forums Search 
This Site Directory About 
Us Newsletter Contact 
Us 
 
 Madrid 
Restaurants 
 Madrid 
Restaurants. With options ranging from the oldest continuously operating restaurant 
in the world to the standard fast food fare, Madrid offers food choices for any 
taste and budget. 

 Cafes are a perennial favorite in Madrid, and the selection is so rich we have given 
them a page of their own. 

 For 
the fast food addict, local chains such as Rodilla, Museo de Jamon and Pans&amp;Co. can put tasty sandwiches or salads on a plate in a matter of minutes. Also 
popular are the growing number of doner kebab stands. Major American chains such 
as McDonalds, Burger King, Kentucky Fried Chicken, Subway, and Starbucks are present 
throughout the city. 

 Stepping 
up a level in quality and style, tabernas and cafes throughout the city offer 
tasty, inexpensive meals. Particularly good bargains are the menu del dia luncheons, 
which generally offer a three course meal for prices between 6 and 10 euros. Tapas 
and snacks are available throughout the day. If you don´t know what you 
want, point at a tasty looking item behind the glass, and it will be served up. 

 Classic 
Madrid restaurants include Casa Botin, hailed by Hemingway as the best restaurant 
in the world, and which is certainly one of the oldest, having been operating 
from the same location since at least the early 1700s. Other local favorites include 
Caso Paco for steaks, Casa Mingo for roasted chicken with Asturian cider, and 
Champagnerie Gala for paella. 

 Click 
here for a list of our favorites. For types of cuisine, check out Andalucian, Asturian , Basque, Castilian, Paella 
and Tapas spots. 

 
 
 
 
 
 Web spain-info.com 
 
 
 
 
     
 
 
 
 
 Copyright 
1999 - 2006 Spain-Info.com All Rights Reserved. 

 Privacy 
Statement
	</body>
</document>
