<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003937" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/things-remembered-store-review-recommended-store-for-personalized-gifts-for-every-occasion-and-need/" time="2012-07-12-20:06" support="3" score="0.015057697913308988" bingtitle="Things Remembered Store Review – Recommended Store For ..." webtitle="Things Remembered Store ReviewRecommended Store For Personalized Gifts For Every Occasion And Need!  | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>Things Remembered Store Review – Recommended ... then had a associate help me fill out the order form. ... Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Kickasstorrents torrent download website review - one of my favorite places to get movie torrents, books, documentaries and more! USPS, postal workers, happy medication and absolute craziness - its a wonder that anyone actually receives their mail! Walt Disney store review - shady service and selling broken Mulan dvds! The Hampton Inn and mildewed carpets - a bad review and a bad time in Myrtle Beach! Will the iPhone be released to Verizon?? Air Wick Freshmatic Ultra Kit Complaint - Horrible and Expensive Air Freshener Product Lysol No-Touch Hand Soap Dispenser Compliment - Cheap and Amazing Automatic Soap Dispenser Wal-mart, racism and rude employees at the deli counter! Dish Network and AT&amp;T;price gouging of established customers - is it illegal and is it fair? Value City Furniture review - do they have good quality furniture at great prices or do they sell junk? 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Things Remembered Store Review–Recommended Store For Personalized Gifts For Every Occasion And Need!
 By Upstate4124 
 





For this Valentine’s Day, I wanted to get something special and different for my girlfriend.  We have been dating for a couple of years now and I have bought her jewelry and the normal gifts, but this year I wanted to be different.  I decided to go into my local mall and go to Things Remembered.

As I looked around I was really impressed with all the selection they have that you can personalize.  As I looked around I knew that this would be something special I could do that would be different and out of the normal gifts I buy year after year.  I had thought that I could do a picture frame that could have a picture of us and also had a personalized message in the heart that was attached to the frame.

 Learn how our readers are saving big money restoring their cloudy and ugly headlights to new again! 

Once I had selected a picture fram I liked, I then had a associate help me fill out the order form.  The form was easy to fill out and it was easy to customize the frame to my liking.  They have options such as colored writing, symbols, and the choice of font/style.  I had chosen a short saying that was 3 words long and then i had the date of Valentine’s Day underneath the saying.


 Your Ad Here 


When the associate had rung up the order she had told me the title and I was shocked at the amount because I had little engraving done.  Things Remembered charges $3 per word and then a flat $6 for the date.  I didn’t have it colored because they told me that the writing was too small to fit in the space that was allotted.

When I returned the next day to pick up the frame, I was really happy the way it came out.  I guess in the end it is worth the pricey prices if it is something special.  Another great thing was I would have been able to pick up my order later on the day I placed the order, but I had to be somewhere else that evening.

 Have younger, cleaner, clearer skin easy as 1,2,3! Click here to find out how! 

I was really happy with the entire experience.  The customer service was really good and the associate actually made good suggestions to me.  I would recommend Thing Remembered to anyone that wants to create a really special gift for any holiday, special day, or any need.  The products are well made and the engraving is amazing when finished!




 
Posts Related to Things Remembered Store Review - Recommended Store For Personalized Gifts For Every Occasion And Need!

 
 IKEA Home Furnishing Store Compliment–Amazing, Great Quality, and Affordable Products 

// Are you a college student? Are you someone who has just moved into a new home or apartment?  If so, you probably don’t have ...
 
 True bargains can be found at Real Deals 

// I live near Lyons NY and there have been a lot of stores that were recently opened.  One store I love is called Real ...
 
 Bloom grocery store review–nice and convenient but prices are way too high! 

// I decided to go to a different grocery store today. I remembered that there was a bloom grocery store nearby my house on North ...
 
 Shutterfly Photo Book Creator Website–Easy, Cheap, and Fun Way To Personalize Your Photos 

// Last month I was surfing the internet trying to find a website that I could store my photos online. There were three things that ...
 
 Black Friday Shopping–Are the deals worth the hassle of early shopping times and over crowded stores? 

// It’s that time of year again!  How many of you have waited all year for this day to come around again?!  Well it’s ...
 
 
 Tags: amazing customer service , compliment , gifts , highly recommended , holiday gifts , personalized gifts , review , special memories , stores , things remembered , things remembered store , valentines day , valentines day gift 
 
2 Responses to Things Remembered Store Review–Recommended Store For Personalized Gifts For Every Occasion And Need! 

 Meghan on February 15, 2011 at 12:10 PM 

This place is awesome, especially if you need last minute gift ideas. I would recommend this place to anyone who wants to personalize their gift idea a little more!

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Sandra on December 16, 2011 at 9:42 PM 

I went to the store at Willowbrook Mall today, I picked out the perfect gift for my boss, I paid for it, and they said it will be ready in 2 hours. I called work to let them know i’ll be a little bit late since I had to wait for the gift to get engraved. I walked around the mall with no purpose for 2 hours. I went to go pick up the gift and it was still not engraved. They said they will engrave it no, so I waited ten minutes, then they tell me, this is the final gift in stock and they can’t engrave it. They wasted almost 3 hours for me just because they are not organized. This store needs more organization. If something is not in stock, they should tell you before you pay and wait 3 hours. I was very, very disappointed.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
