<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003178" url="http://www.cookinglight.com/eating-smart/smart-choices/best-restaurant-salads-00412000067839/" time="2012-07-12-19:19" support="3" score="0.004495066009561747" bingtitle="The Best (and Worst) Restaurant Salads - Cooking Light" webtitle="The Best (and Worst) Restaurant Salads - Cooking Light">
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000862" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000465" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>That bowl of greens may not be as good for you as you think. We navigate the best and worst restaurant salads and share our top picks. By: Holley Grainger, MS, RD</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Main Content Cooking Light 
 Main Food 
 Food Main In Season Recipe Finder Everyday Menus Quick&amp;Healthy World Cuisine Vegetarian Top-Rated Recipes 
 Entertaining 
 Entertaining Main Menus for Entertaining Holidays&amp;Occasions Supper Clubs Wine 
 Cooking 101 
 Cooking 101 Main Techniques Essential Ingredients Resources Blog: Simmer&amp;Boil 
 Eating Smart 
 Eating Smart Main Nutrition 101 Smart Choices Recipe Makeovers 
 Healthy Living 
 Healthy Living Main Fitness Travel Health Healthy Habits Blog: The Twelve 
 Community 
 Community Main Message Boards Cooking Light Blogs Recipe File 
 Magazine 
 The Magazine Main Current Issue Magazine Archive Tablet Edition Magazine Customer Service Advertising &gt; Subscribe &gt; Give a Gift Subscription 
 Summer Cooking 
 Search Cooking Light.com 
 Superfast Cooking Healthy Habits Blogs Video Delicious Deals 
 
Nutrition Made Easy

Our nutrition experts and registered dietitians translate the latest nutrition research into tips you can use to eat healthier
 every day.
 
 Nutrition Guide Food Choices Smart Shopping Nutrition News Dining Out Videos 
 
The Best and Worst Restaurant Salads

That bowl of greens may not be as good for you as you think. We navigate the best and worst restaurant salads and share our
 top picks. By: Holley Grainger, MS, RD
 
 

 Print | Email | Add Comment | 
 Photo: Dan Dalton/Digital Vision/Getty Images , Text: Holley Grainger, MS, RD « 1
 of
 12 » View all 
Restaurant Salads

When the temperature starts to soar, a cool crisp salad seems like the ideal meal. But if you think you’re getting a light,
 healthy bowl of greens when you&apos;re eating out at favorite restaurants like Romano&apos;s Macaroni Grill, California Pizza Kitchen,
 or Applebee&apos;s, you may want to take a closer look. While many restaurant salads are low in calories and loaded with healthy
 ingredients, others are diet disasters packed with calorific ingredients like fried chicken, full-fat cheese, and creamy dressings
 that are overflowing with hidden fat, calories, and sodium.
 
 
 Loading comments... 
 
 
Add your comment
 
The rules: Keep it clean, and stay on the subject or we might delete your comment. If you see inappropriate language, e-mail us . An asterisk * indicates a required field.
 
 Your Name 

 Your Comment * 500 characters remaining 

 
 
More Ways To Get Cooking Light

 Books Email App 
 
 Advertisement 
 

 
JavaScript must be enabled to use this Calendar module.
 
MOST POPULAR
 1 7 Healthy&amp;Delicious Seeds 
Seeds of all varieties—from chia and flax to sesame and sunflower—seem to be popping up everywhere these days. Learn the nutrition
 basics of seeds with ideas for how to incorporate into your diet.
 2 Superfast Summer 3 100 Easy Chicken Recipes 4 Blueberry Desserts 5 Summer Salads Cooking Light 
 Main Food Entertaining Cooking 101 Eating Smart Healthy Living Community The Magazine Delicious Deals 

 Site Map About Us Blogs Video Message Boards RSS Content Feeds Frequently Asked Questions Newsletters Contact Us 

 Advertising Careers Subscribe to the Magazine Tablet Edition Magazine Customer Service Special Promotions Sweepstakes 

 Become a fan of Cooking Light on Facebook Follow Cooking Light on Twitter 
 A Part of the MyRecipes Network 
Copyright © 2012
 Time Inc. Lifestyle Group.
 
 All Rights Reserved. Use of this site constitutes acceptance of our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy ( Your California Privacy Rights ). Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
