<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003992" url="http://sites.google.com/site/eatwellbymealplanning/" time="2012-07-12-20:12" support="1" score="0.002082488351724978" bingtitle="Meal Planning - Google Sites - Free websites and wikis" webtitle="Meal Planning">
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>... With menu planning, you can have dinner on the table in a ... taste as good as what I can get at a fast food restaurant or ... one to argue with. If you can afford to eat ...</description>
	<body>
		Meal Planning 
 Search this site 
 
 
 Home 
 About Me Advantages Blog Creating A Menu Plan Links Meal Planner Recipes Test 
 Sitemap 
 
 Home 
 
 
Do you find yourself struggling to decide what to make for
dinner after a long day of work? Because
of this difficult and daily ritual, do you find yourself eating out, or not
eating as healthy as you’d like? Perhaps
you find yourself throwing out a lot of food because you never get a chance to
cook it before it goes bad. Menu
Planning is the key to solving all of these problems.
 This site will help you make menu planning easy and
enjoyable. I have studied all the
obstacles to planning meals and eating well, and I have developed ways to
overcome them. I have learned ways to minimize
the time and effort needed to plan menus. I have broken the whole menu planning process down into simple,
manageable steps, and have created this site to share with you a plan that you
can easily follow. With the info in these pages, you will learn how to easily create a menu
plan that you and your family will love. In addition, it will save you from stress, let you eat a more balanced and
healthy diet, and save you money. There are so many advantages to spending a little time planning your meals. 
 This site is based on a book I wrote called Plan To Eat Well .  You can purchase it here: 
 Questions?  Comments?  Please contact me (Eric) at thechef@lifestylecooking.com 
 
 
 The Benefits of Unprocessed Foods 



Menu Planning works best when you are prepared to do a
little cooking and use unprocessed foods (like raw meats and vegetables) instead
of convenience food. Stocking your
freezer and fridge with meats and vegetables as opposed to frozen entrees gives
you the most flexibility. For example,
boneless chicken breasts can be used for a variety of dishes, whereas a
prepared entrée can only be used for one meal. 



We should cook with food that is as unprocessed as
possible. These foods are healthier for
you, taste better, cost less, usually have fewer calories, and arrive home with
less packaging to clog our landfills. This
process will be different for everyone, especially for those who are dependent upon
convenience foods. There is no need to
go “cold turkey”. If you are trying to
do something new, or change a habit, it almost never works to change things too
quickly. The secret to success is to
make changes in baby steps. Yes, it
takes a little patience. But more
importantly it takes an acceptance that you are human, and you need to give
yourself permission to take the time to change things slowly. So if you are a convenience food junky,
consider taking baby steps. A good step to
start with is tomato sauce. It is easy
to make, costs so much less if you make it yourself, and tastes much fresher
than the bottled products in the store.



 This Site Is About Planning Dinners 



This site concentrates on dinner because that is the meal
most people have difficulty in getting on the table. The techniques described can be extended to
planning other meals such as breakfast and lunch. But you have to start somewhere, and starting
with dinner will provide you the most benefit.



In college I studied Computer Science and pursued a career
in it after I left the military. Through
my jobs I became proficient at understanding how to make use of information in
the most efficient way possible. You
will see later in the site how we manipulate and relate small bits of
information to allow us to put together a meal plan in the least possible time.



In addition to jobs in computer science, I am a certified
project manager. I manage projects and I
also manage other project managers. Over
the years, I’ve learned that a little planning can save you a lot of time down
the road, and this is certainly true of meal planning.



My experiences in cooking, information management, and planning
finally produced the skills and insight to solve a problem that was on my mind
for years: “How can I prepare delicious,
healthy meals in a minimum amount of time?” I hope this site solves this problem for you.



 What If You Hate To Cook? 



This site is for you if you like to cook, or realize the
importance of cooking for yourself and your family. If you don’t want to take the time to cook, I
suggest you look at your options. If you
eat out all the time, you spend more money for food that is not as healthy as
the food you can prepare yourself. Most
restaurant food is loaded with fat, sugar, and salt, to make it appealing. So, even if you don’t love to cook, let
better food for less money be the seeds of motivation to start cooking
more. As you build your confidence in
the kitchen, save money, eat better and healthier, you may find that you do
indeed love to cook! 



If your only obstacle is that you “can’t” cook, remember all
great chefs started out as people who “couldn’t cook”. If you plan to cook a few days a week, you
can’t help but get better. Once you get
the basics, then you can start looking at specific aspects of your cooking, such
as seasoning, and you will find your food gets incrementally better. The notion of “not be able to cook” is a
false on. Can you scramble eggs or make a
grilled cheese sandwich? If you can, you
already have some of the cooking basics. In fact, much of cooking is actually just assembling ingredients. Surely you can do that. So while there is artistry involved with some
forms of cooking, for most of us, cooking is just basic, no-frill skills.



You can come up with a number of reasons why this won’t work
for you. For instance, you may “hate” to
cook. Well, if you “hate” to cook, you
should take a look at why you don’t like cooking. You really can’t say you don’t like to
cook. It is like saying you don’t like
to work. The term is too generic. It would be helpful look at the aspects of
cooking you don’t like. Here I provide
some aspects you may not like and potential solutions.



 “I hate grocery
shopping.” 



No problem. When you
use my menu planning system, you can shop infrequently (as little as once a
month), and the shopping list you get from my system will get you in and out of
the market in a minimum amount of time. Also, services such as home delivery of groceries are well worth the
small added expense, especially if you normally eat out all the time. The money you save by eating in will more
than offset the cost of having your groceries delivered. Also, if you live in a city where you don’t
have a lot of storage space, but you pass by a market every day from work, you
can gear your menu plan and shopping list to make a quick stop on the way home.



 “When I get home, I’m
too tired and hungry to cook.” 



Again, no problem. With menu planning, you can have dinner on the table in a little as 15
minutes. With a little more preparation,
you can have dinner in even less time. Also, consider bring a snack to work that you can eat an hour or so
before you leave, so you are not so famished when you get home.



 “I don’t know how to
cook.” 



This problem corrects itself over time. A big mistake to make is to try to cook
something you have never made before when you get home from work. If you are trying new recipes, these should
be done on your days off and away from the dinner hour. This way you can cook in a fun, relaxed
atmosphere, and if the dish doesn’t work out, you can go to Plan B, which is to
cook a quick and easy meal, or at last resort, order a pizza. Try planning a cooking day, a few hours
blocked off in the morning of a Saturday or Sunday where you can cook a few
meals.





 
 Your Food May Be Tainted…With Guilt 



Another issue to remember, is that unless you are in
 perfect shape, you may find your consumption of fast food is slightly
 tainted. It is tainted with a little
 guilt. It may only appear after the
 meal, or when you look at yourself in the mirror, but it is still
 there. So in addition to enjoying
 healthier foods on their own, you can enjoy the fact there is no guilt
 associated with them.


 
 “I hate to clean up.” 
 

No problem. With menu
planning, you can minimize the pots and pans you use, and plan it so you have
almost no dishes on weeknights.



 “I have a small or
unusable kitchen.” 



With menu planning, you gear your menu to what you have
available. So even if you only have a
hot pot and a small fridge, you can still plan delicious, healthy meals.



 “The food I cook doesn’t
taste as good as what I can get at a fast food restaurant or other restaurant.” 



 We need a different
perspective on this issue. First,
restaurant food, especially fast food, is loaded with fat, salt, and
sugar. Very few people can ingest that
type of food regularly without at best adversely affecting their weight, or at
worse affecting their health. So we
can’t eat like that on a regular basis.



Why should something loaded with these ingredients taste
better? I would argue that you acquire a
taste for them because our bodies naturally want to ingest as many calories as
possible and also because we associate these foods with happy feelings. You would find if you started cutting out
some (not necessarily all) of these foods, you would start to find foods with
less of these ingredients more tasty. Over time, you may even find food loaded with fats, sugars, and salts less
appealing. I have a recipe for oven
fried fish that is low calorie and absolutely delicious. The taste is fresher, lighter, and crispier
than fast food. 





 “I hate eating alone.” 



This is a hard one to argue with. If you can afford to eat out frequently both
financially and health wise, then I say go for it. If, however, your waistline or your wallet
suffers, you may want to consider alternatives. One thing to consider is that you may find “eating” becomes the process
of cooking and then enjoying the products of your labor. So the first part of the activity is very
active which you may find doesn’t feel like a “lonely” activity. You are listening, tasting, smelling,
feeling, working with your hands, and moving around the kitchen. Also, consider having potlucks or having
friends or neighbors over one or two nights a week. Your friends will probably appreciate eating
healthier dishes for less money.



 “I hate cooking just
for myself.” 



With menu planning, I will help you to make cooking a fun,
relaxing experience. Plus, you won’t
have to cook every night. The leftovers
will become new, delicious meals on other nights of the week. You also might consider inviting a friend
over one night a week to dinner. I am
sure they would appreciate a home cooked meal. They even may want to help cook. Feeding
a few people at home can be much less expensive than eating out for one.




Next: Creating A Menu Plan 






 
 
 
 My latest Recipe: 
 
 Light&amp;Buttery Cupcakes 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Subpages (8): About Me Advantages Blog Creating A Menu Plan Links Meal Planner Recipes Test 
 Comments 
 _displayNameOrEmail_ - _time_ - Remove 
_text_
 
 
 Sign in | Recent Site Activity | Report Abuse | Print Page | Remove Access | Powered By Google Sites
	</body>
</document>
