<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003261" url="http://www.job-applications.com/nordstrom-job-application/" time="2012-07-12-19:23" support="5" score="0.00977106462639084" bingtitle="Nordstrom Application Online - Print Job Employment Form" webtitle="Nordstrom Application Online - Print Job Employment Form">
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>Job-Applications.com is the place to find employment ... Today, Nordstrom is a chain of high-end department ... 16 and I want to fill out the application for the cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		The #1 Independent Online Job Application Resource Website 
 
 
 
 
 Home » Department Store Jobs »Nordstrom

Nordstrom Application
 
 
 
Nordstrom Application Online–Print Job Employment Form 

 
 
 
 
 Apply for Jobs at Nordstrom Online 

 Application for Nordstrom: Nordstrom does not provide a printable job application. If you want to get a job at Nordstrom, you must apply for employment on the website by following the link above. Full-time or part-time positions may vary depending on the location.

 Interview Tips: Go to the Nordstrom job interview questions&amp;tips page.

 Available Positions at Nordstrom: Cashier, Customer Service Representative, Stock Team Member, Retail Sales Associate, Accessories Sales Associate, Massage Therapist, Fitting Room Attendant, Kid’s Shoes Sales Associate, Women’s Apparel Sales Associate, Men’s Sportswear Sales Associate, Cosmetics and Fragrances Sales Associate, Shoe Shiner, Taylor, Jewelry and Watches Sales Associate, Cleaning Specialist, Wedding Stylist, Loss Prevention Associate, Customer Service Specialist, Department Supervisor, Assistant Manager, Store Manager, Administrative Assistant, Maintenance Technician, Merchandise Handler, Sales Counter Manager

 Minimum Age to Work at Nordstrom : 16 years old (How old do you have to be to work at Nordstrom?)

 Nordstrom Hours of Operation: Mon-Sat: 9:30am-9:00pm; Sun: 11:00am-7:00pm

 More Information: Nordstrom Job Info 
 Related Jobs :

 Big Lots 
 
BJs Wholesale Club 
 
Bloomingdale’s 
 
Costco 
 
Dillard’s 
 
Family Dollar 
 
Goody’s 
 
JCPenney 
 
Kmart 
 
Kohl’s 
 
Macy’s 
 
Marshalls 
 
Meijer 
 
Neiman Marcus 
 
Ross 
 
Saks Fifth Avenue 
 
Sam’s Club 
 
Sears 
 
T.J.Maxx 
 
Target 
 
Walmart 
The Nordstrom application presents you with employment opportunities in the retail industry. To find Nordstrom jobs in your area, apply online.

Nordstrom officially began as a shoe store called Willan&amp;Nordstrom in Seattle, WA. The company built a long-standing, reliable customer base due to an effective business philosophy: offer the customer the best possible service, selection, quality, and value. Over the years, the Nordstrom chain grew and the company began to delve into other areas of the retail market. Today, Nordstrom is a chain of high-end department stores. The retailer focuses on selling upscale apparel, but also offers customers furniture, housewares, jewelry, beauty products, and much more.

Currently, the Nordstrom chain operates 115 department stores nationwide as well as a number of retail outlets under other banners, like Nordstrom Rack, Jeffrey Boutique, and Last Chance. As of 2009, Nordstrom employed over 52,000 workers. The retailer also had revenues of over $8 billion that year. Nordstrom is a publically held company and is traded on the New York Stock Exchange under the ticker symbol JWN.

Based out of Seattle, Washington, Nordstrom is a high-end department store chain with locations across the country. Starting as a retailer focusing in footwear, the company now sells clothing, jewelry, beauty products, home décor, and furniture. Nordstrom is always hiring entry-level employees to work as sales persons in the aforementioned departments as well as in other capacities throughout retail stores.

Presently, Nordstrom stores around the country are looking to hire sales associates, cashiers, and merchandise handlers. These positions present a valuable opportunity for new workers: the chance to gain retail and customer service experience. Plus, the chain only requires that you be at least 16 years old to fill out the Nordstrom job application. With this useful experience, there is plenty of room for advancement into management or further your career in retail sales.

Employees who work an average of at least 129 hours a month are eligible for benefits packages in addition to regular pay. Employment perks include medical, dental, and vision insurance as well as a 401(k) plan and profit sharing. Qualified Nordstrom workers also receive paid time off and in-store discounts. Another perk available to all sales associates is commission pay. On top of base pay, employees earn back a certain percentage of their sales.

How would you like to find work with one of America’s fastest growing department store chains? If you want to enter a rewarding job in a casual and fun work environment, then fill out an application today. Nordstrom prefers that you apply online. It’s quick and easy. So what are you waiting for? Begin your retail career with Nordstrom today.
 12 comments: 
 Olivia C: 



 Top Comment 
 
I am 16 and I want to fill out the application for the cashier position at Nordstrom, will they be willing to train me in this position. Also is there any dress code requirements?
 

 
 Isis Molina: 



 Top Comment 
 
I am very interested in working for Nordstrom. I love fashion I am curious to know what a merchandise handlers day to day duties would include. It sounds very interesting and I think it may be a good fit for me. I am going to fill out an application for Nordstrom right now!
 

 
 CYNTHIA B. CALDERON: 





I would like to be part of your team.


 
 iliyana Dieaa: 





Iliyana Dieaa:
I am seeking to obtain a long-term FT/ or PT position in a professional skin care clinic were I can dedicate my time as a professional esthetician and make up artist. I am also open to other employment positions in your department store.
i am eager to participate in any career training requirements to achieve employer’s profitable goals&amp;clients’ satisfactions.
i am looking forward to hearing from you thank you.


 
 Valeria: 





Where can I find the job application?


 
 DeRiyonna: 





hi i’m 17 years old and i want to fill out an application.


 
 Adam Robuck: 





If I was an employee here would I be able to get a good salary or not? I don’t like working in the industry I’m in now only making minimum wage. I need a job to be able to support myself. I’m going to apply at a lot of different department stores. Nordstrom seems seems like a really nice place.


 
 Barbara McCoy: 





I would like to apply as a Customer Service Representative. What are the equirements to becoming one? I have worked in Sales at Sears Department Store, Receptionists through temporary services, and office work to different offices throughout Orange County, also through temporary services: Select, Remedy, Volt, and others. I have also worked for 3 1/2 years for a chiropractor as receptionists and physical therapists. I went to Fullerton College, Cypress College and Cal State Fulleton and also Sierra College in Rocklin, California.

I am very good with people. I can type, file, and know MicroSoft 2001, and phones.

My name is Barbara M; my telephone number is or you can reach me at, Brea, California #92822


 
 Victoria E. Johnson: 





Victoria

I would like to apply for a retail sales position. I worked for the State Department of Assessments and Taxation for Anne Arundel County for 40 years as Supervisor of my department. Have good customer service skills in person or on the phone. I can type, file, and do what is needed to have a good presentation for the department. I also worked part-time for Sears department store at the Parole Plaza and at the Annapolis Mall. Education: graduated from Wiley H. Bates High School, Annapolis, Md. and did 2 years at Coppin State College, Baltimore, Maryland.

My name is Victoria.


 
 tonga nguyen: 





Hi my name is Tonga. I would like to work for Nordstrom, but I dont know how to get an application. I know how to sew and I would like to apply for an alterations position. Can anyone help me get an application?


 
 Calen Gonzalez: 





I just want to work for nordstroms, full time. I’ll work every day if I have to! I just need a stable job.


 
 Sylvia Jones: 





I am interested in working for Nordstrom. I am experienced in sales for cosmetics and fragrance. I was a cosmetic manager for Dermablend at Macy’s and I also was sales representative for Tommy Hilfiger Fragrances.I love to work with people.


 
 
 Most Popular Jobs Retail Store Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Career Research Employee Benefits 
 En Espanol 
 Interview Tips 
 Interview Questions 
 Job Descriptions 
 Job Finding Tips 
 Salary Info 
 Job Newsletter We&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name: Email: Zip Code: Select Category: Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery 

 Sign Up Job Categories Airline Jobs 
 Amusement Park Jobs 
 Armed Forces Jobs 
 Automotive Store Jobs 
 Banking Jobs 
 Book Store Jobs 
 Casino Jobs 
 Childcare Daycare Jobs 
 Coffee Shop Jobs 
 Computer Store Jobs 
 Cruise Ship Jobs 
 Delivery Driver Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Fashion Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Fitness Health Jobs 
 Furniture Store Jobs 
 Gas Station Jobs 
 Grocery Store Jobs 
 Hardware Store Jobs 
 Healthcare Jobs 
 Home Decor Jobs 
 Hospital Jobs 
 Hotel Jobs 
 Ice Cream Shop Jobs 
 Insurance Jobs 
 Mechanic Jobs 
 Movie Theater Jobs 
 Office Supply Jobs 
 Pet Store Jobs 
 Pharmacy Tech Jobs 
 Pharmacist Jobs 
 Pizza Delivery Jobs 
 Rental Truck Jobs 
 Rental Car Jobs 
 Restaurant Jobs 
 Retail Management Jobs 
 Retail Store Jobs 
 Shoe Store Jobs 
 Smoothie Maker Jobs 
 Specialty Foods Jobs 
 Sporting Goods Jobs 
 Telecommunications Jobs 
 Temp Agency Jobs 
 Tools Jobs 
 Tutoring Jobs 

 All Job Categories 
 
   

 
 Sign up - we&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name:
 Email:
 Zip:
 Select Category:
 Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery Sign Up 
 
 disclaimer 

 privacy policy 

 terms of use 
 
 
Copyright © 2011, 2012 Job-Applications.com
	</body>
</document>
