<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003107" url="http://sammysredhots.net/" time="2012-07-12-19:13" support="8" score="0.023425892774548044" bingtitle="Sammy&apos;s Red Hots Chicago | Sandwiches, American, Grill | Order ..." webtitle="Sammy&apos;s Red Hots Chicago | Sandwiches, American, Grill | Order Online | 238 W Division St">
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000601" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="29"/>
	<description>Order online from Sammy&apos;s Red Hots for pickup or delivery or visit us at 238 W ... - No, this fast-food restaurant is not named after the popular Cubs slugger.</description>
	<body>
		More photos 
Sammy&apos;s Red Hots
 Get a hot dog! 238 W Division St Chicago, IL 60610 312-266-7290 Get Driving Directions 
Delivery Hours:

 Sun 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM Mon 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM Tue 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM Wed 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM Thu 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM Fri 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM Sat 9:00 AM - 1:30 AM 
 See all days See today only See our menu 
Order Delivery&amp;Pickup Online
 
Popular Items

 Large Milk Shake Cheese Sticks Gyros Sandwich Gyro Dinner Pizza Puff 
 
Specialty Items

 Italian Beef Sandwich Chicken Tenders Gyro Burger Double Dog Italian Sausage Sandwich 
 Order Online 
About Sammy&apos;s Red Hots

- No, this fast-food restaurant is not named after the popular Cubs slugger. In fact, Sammy&apos;s Red Hots has been around since before Sammy Sosa was even born.

Sammy&apos;s does mostly a carryout and delivery business, although patrons can stand and eat at the counter inside the store if they choose. The specialty of the house is Vienna beef hot dogs and Polish sausage, but Sammy&apos;s also doubles as a chicken shack. Offering 16 kinds of chicken combination meals. If you&apos;re in the mood for fish, Sammy&apos;s has catfish, perch, jack salmon and shrimp. There also are sub sandwiches, gyros and Italian beef. Early risers can grab breakfast between the hours of 4 a.m. and 10 a.m.
 
Sammy&apos;s Red Hots
is a leading Chicago Sandwich Restaurant on Grubhub.com 
 
Reviews and Ratings

 Reviews 
 Food is very well prepared and tasty. Delivery is prompt. Will order from again. Kevin Kevin (29 reviews | 458 orders) i enjoyed the meals from sammy&apos;s red hots..ordered their catfish steaks and it was very good...cost me for delivery but for the distance and that the meal arrived quickly for the distance it was worth it pat (14 reviews | 223 orders) Always Good Tom (9 reviews | 53 orders) Read more reviews... 43 Yelp! Reviews Read Yelp! reviews of Sammy&apos;s Red Hots
	</body>
</document>
