<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003414" url="http://www.windsorgardensdenver.org/Discussion/Discussion.asp?forum_id=3738&amp;assn_id=15778" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="1" score="0.00023954441849556764" bingtitle="Windsor Gardens - Discussion Group" webtitle="Windsor Gardens - Discussion Group">
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Choose your fast food restaurant. Cost: $11 per person (the fare ... For trip details, and to reserve your seat, E ... Identity theft is more than a credit card. Join us and ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Welcome Stay Connected Resident Services Resource Center Classifieds Contacts 
 
 Discussion Board If you are able to see and or reply to this please do so as we are having continued troubles with the discussion board. Thank you! ~ Tami Blake Simply click on the Topic or Reply you wish to view. If you would like to add 
 your own response, click on the Reply button. 

   Displaying 1 to 24 of 148 Topics
(25 Posts)
 ( Refresh ) [ Next ] 

 Topics/Replies Total Replies Last Reply Date 
 
  July 26, 2012 Thursday. lunch at Denver Museum of Nature&amp;Science 0 7/3/12 12:22am 
 July 26, 2012 Thursday. Bus Buddies are going to: 

 T-Rex Cafeteria at the 

 Denver Museum of Nature&amp;Science 

 10:30 AM Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium Lobby 

Only one transfer is needed to travel to the Denver Museum of Nature&amp;Science. From the bus stop there is a ¼ mile walk to the museum entrance. No need to pay admission to the museum. The cafeteria is indoors, before reaching the museum ticket booth. You need to be able to carry your food to your table. There is just one busy street crossing, at a traffic light.

Pay your bus fare directly to the bus driver. Pay for your lunch directly to the cafeteria.

 Optional: If you wish to stay after lunch to see museum exhibits, you can easily return home on your own, simply reversing the route we take to get to the museum. Museum admission is $10 for people 65 years of age and older. $13 for people under 65. Extra charge for IMAX movies and planetarium.

Bus fare each way is $1.10 if you are 65 years old or older, $2.25 if you are under 65. You need to have your exact fare (or more) Drivers do not make change.

Sign up for this trip by E-mail to wg.bus@aol.com. Or call Paul Steinhauer 303-341-0056. You may just show up at the Auditorium lobby if you wish. But if no one signed up, there will be no guide there.

For last minute cancellations, Paul Steinhauer&apos;s cell phone is 303-909-5144.

In addition to Windsor Life , Bus Buddies information is on Facebook. Search for :Windsor Gardens Bus Buddies.&quot;


DETAILED ITINERARY



Denver Museum of Nature and Science

2001 Colorado Boulevard 80205

303-370-6000 www.dmns.org

Open 9AM-5PM daily, except Christmas

10:30 AM Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium Lobby

10:45 AM RTD#3 leave westbound from Windsor Gardens

10:59 AM arrive Alameda Avenue&amp;Colorado Boulevard

11:09 AM RTD#40 leave Colorado Boulevard&amp;Alameda Avenue

11:25 AM arrive Denver Museum of Nature and Science

Lunch in the T-Rex Cafeteria

Return to Windsor Gardens

Return trip choices

1:47 2:31 3:02 RTD#40 leave Denver Museum of Nature&amp;Science

2:04 2:48 3:19 arrive Colorado Boulevard&amp;Alameda Avenue

2:25 2:56 3:26 RTD#3 leave Alameda Avenue&amp;Colorado Boulevard

2:40 3:11 3:41 arrive Windsor Gardens

 Optional: On the return trip, individuals may shop at Colorado&amp;Alameda. Walgreens, PetSmart, Target,&amp;Wells Fargo Bank. If you board the #3 bus before your transfer expires, there will be no extra bus fare to pay. Return to Windsor Gardens without a guide.

Description of cafeteria menu:

§ Hot entrees, with an ethnic flair

§ Fresh salad bar and soups

§ Grill, with hamburgers and other hot sandwiches

§ Kids meals

§ Pizza and calzones
Vegetarian and low-carb options 
 Paul Steinhauer - 7/3/12 12:22am 
 

  DOG MUST WEAR SHOES 0 6/23/12 7:26am 
 HOT 

 PAVEMENT 

 BURNS FEET 

 If you need to cross pavement to reach your car, carry your dog. 

 It&apos;s the loving thing to do. 
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 6/23/12 7:26am 
 

  June 23, WG Parade &quot;side effects&quot; 0 6/16/12 9:49pm 
 JUNE 23, 2012, SATURDAY, 10:00 - 11:30 AM. 

 WINDSOR GARDENS PARADE 

 POSSIBLE PROBLEMS DUE TO STREETS BEING CLOSED 

 

 MAIL DELIVERY AND PICK UP 

Will mail delivery simply be delayed, or cancelled on June 23? Outgoing &quot;time sensitive&quot; mail, like bills you are paying, should go out on Friday, or taken to a mail box somewhere besides the building lobby, just to be safe. 
(UPDATE) The Windsor Gardens anniversary parade will delay our letter carriers. But they will be here Saturday.
 source: Tammy Blake, Windsor Gardens Business Manager. 

 

 RTD BUS SERVICE ON ROUTE 3 

 Bus service affected:

The eastbound trips due at South Alton Way and South Clinton Street at 10:28 AM and 11:28 AM.

The westbound trips due at South Alton Way and South Clinton Street at 10:18 AM and 11:18 AM.

The most logical thing for RTD to do is stay on Alameda Avenue and not turn into Windsor Gardens. Plan your bus trips accordingly. And warn people who visit you by bus (such as care givers/housekeepers) about the service disruption.

I attended an Anniversary Committee meeting on June 6, and presented these questions. I have not yet heard back what is going to happen. Hopefully we will hear soon. Be prepared for parade &quot;side effects.&quot;
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 6/16/12 9:49pm 
 

  June 19, 2012 GOP speaker has changed 0 6/9/12 8:52pm 
Mr. Robert Hardaway will now be speaking on July 17. A family matter required his rescheduling. Congratualtions to his parents on their 75th wedding anniversary.

 JUNE 19, 2012
TUESDAY 7:00PM
WINDSOR GARDENS CENTERPOINT
 597 East Center Avenue 80247


 
WENDY WARNER
 

 
Chairman, Denver Republican Party
 
www.denvergop.org
 
 chairman@denvergop.org     303-782-9555 

 

 
 
 Wisconsin has shown us the way - what we in Denver must do to win this state for Romney in November! 
 
 
 Before the program, join some of your neighbors for dinner in the Emerald Grill at 5:45 PM

Questions? gopwg@aol.com or 303-366-0753 Linda Weems, Chairman, Republican Club

Find us on Facebook: Windsor Gardens Republican Club
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 6/9/12 8:52pm 
 

  July 17, meet GOP candidate for CO legislature House District 6 (includes WG) 0 6/3/12 4:26pm 
 This program was prevously scheduled for June 19. It was rescheduled due to a family matter for Mr. Hardaway. Congratulations on his parents&apos;  75th wedding anniversary. 

The WINDSOR GARDENS REPUBLICANS are hosting a public introduction for all our voting neighbors, for Robert Hardaway, our candidate for the Colorado legislature, House District 6. This is Tuesday, July 17, at 7:00 PM in CENTERPOINT. Hardaway began his education at Amherst College Law School and continued on at New York University where he again excelled. He served in the U. S. Navy JAG as both a prosecutor and defense lawyer. In Denver he met new challenges practicing civil litigation. He has been the Arapahoe County District Attorney and rounded out his litigation career as Colorado Deputy Public Defender. He is a tenured Professor of Law from the University of Denver, the author of 14 published books on law and policy plus numerous articles for professional journals. More recently Professor Hardaway has included law-related fiction and novels. As a Club we strive to invite candidates so our residents can get to know them and become informed voters.

For more information about Robert Hardaway see: law.du.edu/index.php/profile/robert-hardaway 

Also, in an effort to get to know our neighbors better we invite you to join us at 5:45 PM in the Emerald Grill before the program. Everyone may choose off the menu and pay for their own order. Please E-mail gopwg@aol.com , or call Paul Steinhauer (303-341-0056) or Linda Weems (303-366-0753) in advance so they can make reservations.

More information about the Windsor Gardens Republican Club is on Facebook. Seach for &quot;Windsor Gardens Republican Club.&quot;
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 6/3/12 4:26pm 
 

  June 27, Wednesday bus to Cherry Creek farmers market 0 5/25/12 10:04am 
 June 27, 2012 Wednesday 

 Farmers Market at Cherry Creek Shopping Center 

 Followed by lunch at the Cherry Cricket 

 9:30 AM Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium Lobby 

From Windsor Gardens, the Cherry Creek Farmers Market requires no transfer. It is easy to get to on your own by bus. You may wish to do that often as the growing season progresses and more Colorado produce becomes available. Admission is free. You do not need to buy anything.

The Cherry Cricket is a popular bar, offering salads and sandwiches. The sidewalk tables are great for people watching. There is plenty of indoor seating in the event of hot weather, or a tornado. Each person pays for their own meal.

This trip requires about 3/4 mile of walking. We will have traffic lights to cross busy streets three times, University Boulevard once, and First Avenue twice.

Option: With no transfers required, if you wish to continue shopping in Cherry Creek after lunch, returning to Windsor Gardens alone might be a good experience for you.

Option going to Cherry Creek: If you are comfortable getting on the #3 bus by your home, just catch the westbound bus that turns into Windsor Gardens about 9:40 AM. The rest of us will join you on the bus as it leaves Windsor Gardens. If you are confused by what I just wrote, meet the excursion guide in the Auditorium lobby at 9:30 AM to begin a new adventure.

You are welcome to just show up for this trip. But the guide prefers that you sign up ahead of time by E-mailing wg.bus@aol.com or calling Paul Steinhauer at 303-341-0056. If the guide knows you are going, he/she can make an accurate reservation for the Cherry Cricket. And if you sign up, and we end up changing the time or cancelling the trip because of that tornado, we can let you know.


 DETAILED ITINERARY 

 

The farmers market is parking lot of Cherry Creek Shopping Center, 1 st Avenue&amp;University Boulevard. www.ColoradoFreshMarkets.com

 

Cherry Cricket, 2461 East Second Avenue, Denver 80206

In Cherry Creek North on the northwest corner of 2 nd Avenue and Clayton Lane

303-322-7664 wwwCherryCricket.com Hours: 11AM-2AM daily

 9:30 AM gather at Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby
 9:45 AM leave westbound route 3 bus from Windsor Gardens
10:08 AM arrive at First Avenue&amp;University Boulevard

Shop at the farmers market.

11:30 AM lunch at the Cherry Cricket (We can arrive as early as 11AM, if we wish)

 RETURN TO WINDSOR GARDENS 

1:15 PM leave eastbound route 3 bus from First Avenue&amp;University Boulevard.
1:39 PM arrive Windsor Gardens.

When leaving Cherry Creek several bus lines serve those bus stops. Be sure the front of the bus you get on says &quot;3 CENTERPOINT&amp;SABLE.&quot;

Optional: On your way home, if you want to stop at Colorado Boulevard to shop at Walgreens, Target, etc., just ask for a transfer when you get on the route 3 bus at Cherry Creek. You can do your shopping, then get on another eastbound route 3 bus to take you home. When you get on the first route 3 bus, make sure the transfer does not expire before the next

 To ask questions and/or sign up for this trip, contact
 Windsor Gardens Bus Buddies    wg.bus@aol.com 
Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056 home.
690 South Alton Way #6A, Denver CO 80247-1640

Betty Tidwell 970-434-5739
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 5/25/12 10:04am 
 

  June 21, &quot;How to Ride Buses and Light Rail&quot; seminar at WG 0 5/25/12 9:58am 
 
June 21, 2012 Thursday Centerpoint West 

9:00 AM: Meet
Bill James, RTD Board Member, District A (includes Windsor Gardens)
&amp;Claudia Folska, candidate for District E&amp;advocate for handicapped services.



9:30 AM Seminar: How to Ride Buses and Light Rail
Conducted by Denver&apos;s Regional Transportation District (RTD)

Information for people who have never been on an RTD bus. This seminar will start with basic information on understanding printed schedules and how to figure out how to get where you wish to go. What kind of information is available in print form and on RTD&apos;s web site. RTD will bring a bus to the seminar so you can see how handicapped people and bicycle riders are accommodated. We will ride the bus to the Alameda light rail station for a demonstration of how to transfer to light rail, and how to make your return trip by paying your fare in the light rail station. We should be home about 12:30PM.

If you already know how to ride, but have neighbors who do not, please suggest they participate in the seminar. You are welcome to come with them.

You are welcome to just show up on June 21. But if you sign up in advance we will have printed material for you. Sign up by E-mailing wg.bus@aol.com. Or call 303-341-0056 Paul Steinhauer, or 970-434-5739 (cell) Betty Tidwell.

Learning to use public transit is like learning to walk. There are lots of details to learn. But they are logical and easy. Once you learn them they become automatic and do not require the attention you will give them while learning. And now that you are old enough to read, learning how to ride transit will take much less time than it took you to learn to walk.

 

 

 

 

Bill James, Regional Transportation District Board Member - District A
 bill.james@rtd-denver.com 303-316-6768
1600 Blake Street, Denver, CO 80202



Claudia Folska - candidate for RTD Board of Directors, District E
(in the November 2012 election)
 Claudia@Claudia4RTD.com 303-753-1099
 www.Claudia4RTD.com 

Questions?
Windsor Gardens Bus Buddies
 wg.bus@aol.com 
From: Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056 home. 303-909-5144 cell
690 South Alton Way #6A, Denver CO 80247-1640

Betty Tidwell 970-434-5739
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 5/25/12 9:58am 
 

  June 14, Thursday lunch at the Aquarium with WG Bus Buddies 0 5/25/12 9:50am 
 JUNE 14, 2012 THURSDAY 

 AQUARIUM RESTAURANT 

 9:30 AM meet in Auditorium lobby 

 

The Aquarium Restaurant has the best floor show in Denver. The dining room is along the floor to ceiling walls of the Plexiglas fish tanks. Waiting for your meal is no problem with the view of all those fishies to enjoy. And don&apos;t worry. None of the pretty fish you see in the tank will be on anyone&apos;s dinner plate that evening. (But their cousins will.)

Everyone will choose his/her own lunch off the menu, and pay the restaurant directly. Lunch will cost about $20 per person.

AARP members save 10% on food and non-alcoholic beverages.

This trip requires two blocks of walking. No busy streets need to be crossed on foot.

You might want to invite some grandchildren on this trip. Watching the kids watch the fish is part of an enjoyable experience. WARNING! The only entrance to the dining room is through a large gift shop.

Option: Consider staying after lunch to go through the Aquarium. There is much more to see besides the view from the dining room. Going home alone should be easy. At the two transfers you need to make, you catch the next bus at the same stop where you got off. It will be hard to get lost.

If you are 65 years old or older, aquarium admission costs $15.00. Age 12 - 64, $17. Ages 3 -11, $10, Age 2 and under, free admission. It captivates youngsters. (If you think &quot;Nemo&quot; is the Captain from &quot;20,000 Leagues Under the Sea&quot; you are old enough to resist the temptation.)

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus. If you are at least 65 years old, your fare is $1.10 in each direction. If you are 65 years old or less, your fare is $2.25. You need to have the exact fare (or more) to put in the fare box.

If you have questions and/or wish to sign up, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056.
 
 
 

 

 ITINERARY DETAILS 

Aquarium Restaurant, 700 Water Street,
303-561-4450 downtownaquarium.com

9:30 AM gather in the Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby
9:45 AM leave RTD route 3 westbound from Windsor Gardens
9:59 AM arrive Alameda Avenue&amp;Colorado Boulevard
10:28 AM leave RTD route 83L Alameda Avenue&amp;Colorado Boulevard
10:45 AM arrive Lincoln Street&amp;13 th Avenue
11:10 AM leave RTD route 10 Lincoln Street&amp;13 th Avenue
11:24 AM arrive Aquarium.

11:30 AM lunch Aquarium Restaurant

Option 1 Option 2 RETURN TO WINDSOR GARDENS

12:40 1:10 PM leave RTD route 10 from the Aquarium.
12:57 1:27 PM arrive Broadway&amp;13 th Avenue
 1:01 1:37 PM leave RTD route 83L Broadway&amp;13 th Avenue
 1:12 1:42 PM arrive First Avenue&amp;Fillmore (Cherry Creek Shopping Center) 
  1:15 2:15 PM leave RTD route 3 First Avenue&amp;Fillmore
  1:40 2:40 PM arrive Windsor Gardens

Optional, on the way home, you may stop anywhere along the route to shop. You will not have to pay another fare, as long as you board the next bus before your transfer expires.

 TO JOIN THIS TRIP , E-mail wg.bus@aol.com
or call Paul Steinhauer 303-341-0056
or Betty Tidwell, 720-434-5739
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 5/25/12 9:50am 
 

  May 26, Saturday learn how to ride buses to Boulder 0 5/15/12 3:49pm 
BUS BUDDIES ARE GOING TO PEARL STREET IN BOULDER MEMORIAL DAY WEEKEND

 May 26, 2012 Saturday 9:00 AM gather in Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby. (Or get on the westbound #3 bus that starts through Windsor Gardens about 9:05 AM at any bus stop.) We will transfer 3 times to get to downtown Boulder about noon. On summer weekends there are many buskers (street entertainers) on Pearl Street. Year &apos;round there are many shops and restaurants. You have 3 ½ hours to look, shop and lunch on your own, or with the group, before we return to Windsor Gardens. Choose the restaurant of your choice for lunch. Since Monday is Memorial Day, we may avoid a huge crowd by going on Saturday. But if the weather is good there will be a lot of people. There can be a lot of walking. But there are many benches where you may sit and people watch, if you wish.

In Boulder and downtown Denver the bus terminals provide plenty of seating and restrooms upon our arrival and departure.

We will be back in Windsor Gardens about 6:30PM. You may return earlier or stay later, if you are comfortable traveling on your own.

Bus fare in each direction $5.00. You need to have $2.25 to board the bus in Windsor Gardens. Get a transfer from the driver. Then you need $2.75 and the transfer to board the bus to Boulder.

Returning to Windsor Gardens, when boarding the bus in Boulder, pay the driver $5.00 and get a transfer. The transfer will get you home to Windsor Gardens.

 For trip details, and to sign up for this trip, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056 or Betty Tidwell, 970-434-5739. 


 

 

 ITINERARY DETAILS 

 

9:00 AM gather at Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby

 9:18 AM leave route 3 from Windsor Gardens

9:33 AM arrive at Alameda&amp;Colorado Boulevard

9:51 AM leave route 83L Alameda&amp;Colorado Boulevard

10:07 AM arrive Civic Center Station

16 th Street Mall Shuttle to Market Street Station

11:08 AM leave route B Market Street Station

11:59 AM arrive Boulder Transit Center, 14 th Street&amp;Walnut Street


 RETURN TO WINDSOR GARDENS 

 3: 31 PM leave route B from Boulder Transit Center, 14 th Street&amp;Walnut Street

4:26 PM arrive Denver, Civic Center Station

16 th Street Mall Shuttle to Civic Center Station

5:30 PM leave route 83L from Civic Center Station.

5:41 PM arrive First&amp;Filmore Streets

6:05PM leave route 3 First&amp;Filmore Streets.

6:30 PM arrive Windsor Gardens

 For trip details, and to sign up for this trip, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056 or Betty Tidwell, 970-434-5739. 

 
 Paul Steinhauer - 5/15/12 3:49pm 
 

  UPDATED recycling and reuse information for WG 0 5/9/12 9:22am 
This information is easier to read in the Microsoft Word document in which I keep it. If you want an electronic copy of that, E-mail your request to building43@aol.com .  -Paul Steinhauer 

In parking lot #13, on the golf course side, near the northeast corner, is a dumpster for aluminum, glass, plastic (#1 - #6 some, but not all. See &quot;not accepted&quot; below&quot;), tin cans, newspapers, magazines, office paper, junk mail, and flattened cardboard. Please DO NOT put in plastic bags. (Most supermarkets take plastic bags back.) Your recyclables can be dropped in loose or in paper bags.

 RECYCLE THESE! 

Recycle rigid plastic bottles, jugs, jars, tubs, cups, trays and containers marked with the # 1 through #7 in the recycling symbols in the Denver Recycles program. Please empty all liquids and food when possible. Remove plastic caps and lids and foil tops; they are not accepted for recycling.

Aluminum&amp;Tin Cans (must be free of food residue)

Cardboard boxes (must be broken down)

White&amp;Colored Paper (including Newspapers and their inserts)

Books (hard of soft cover) Magazines Junk Mail Envelopes (windows OK)

Brochures&amp;Pamphlets Coated paper (shiny) Computer printouts

Carbonless receipts Post-It Notes Manuals with Glue Bindings

File folders (with metal hangers) File Folders (with plastic tabs)

Wires&amp;Plastic spirals Staples, Paper Clips&amp;Clamps

 TRASH THESE! 

Candy Wrappers Carbon Paper Carpet or Cloth

Glass (if not a bottle or jar) Window glass Light bulbs

Mirrors Drinking glasses Tissue paper

Food or any organic waste Saran Wrap Dishes

Liquids Lids, caps, or tops. Full aerosol cans

Paint cans Napkins Paper towels

Photographs Waxed cardboard (milk carton, for example)

Waxed paper Disposable dishes - plastic&amp;paper

Styrofoam (except clean &quot;peanuts.&quot; Please leave &quot;peanuts&quot; at unit 6A for Paul)

 METROPOLITAN DENVER RECYCLING DIRECTORY 

 http://www.denvergov.org/trashrecycling 

&quot;We have created this directory to assist residents of the City and County of Denver in locating the nearest drop-off recycling center for a wide range of materials. While some of these centers may accept large quantities of materials, this information is intended primarily to facilitate the recycling of materials generated by households.&quot;

http://www.denvergov.org/trashrecycling/TrashandRecycling/Recycling/RecyclingDirectoryDropoffLocations/tabid/440907/Default.aspx

 

 MEDICINE&amp;MEDICAL ITEMS 

 Drop boxes are provided by the Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment. (last time list on web site was checked, 13 June 2010) 

Denver Health, Wellington E. Webb Center for Primary Care, 301 W. 6th Ave, Denver

King Soopers, 2810 Quebec St, Denver

King Soopers, 4271 S. Buckley Rd, Aurora

King Soopers, 9551 S. University Blvd, Highlands Ranch

Tri-County Health Department, 4857 S. Broadway, Englewood

 

 Allowed: 

Prescription Medications (except for narcotics or controlled substances)

Over-the-counter Medications

Medication Samples

Pet Medications

Vitamins

Liquid Medication in Glass or Leak-proof Containers

Medicated Ointments and Lotions

Inhalers

 

 Not Allowed 

Narcotics and Other Controlled Substances

Bloody or infectious waste

Personal Care Products

Hydrogen Peroxide

Aerosol Cans

Thermometers

IV Bags

Needles or Other Sharps

Plastic Shopping Bags

Empty Containers

Business Waste

 

For latest information on the proper disposal of household medications, visit

http://www.cdphe.state.co.us/hm/medtakeback/index.htm

 

 PACKING MATERIALS (BOXES, STYROFOAM, BUBBLE WRAP) 

Cardboard boxes suitable for use when moving, packing materials are almost always in demand by Windsor Gardens residents. Leave them at the door of unit 6A (Paul Steinhauer). He will pass them on to a neighbor moving out or take them to Project C.U.R.E., a charity that can use them when sending medical supplies to third world countries. Styrofoam peanuts will be used. Unfortunately custom molded sytrofoam pieces go into the trash dumpster.

 REUSABLE BOOKS, TOYS, CLOTHING,&amp;HOUSEHOLD GOODS 



Arc Thrift Stores. Call to arrange a pick up 303-238-5263

Drive Thru Donation Station open from 9am-5pm, 7 days a week,

560 S. Holly #5, Denver, CO 80246 (303-322-6476)

Call for other convenient drop off location: 303-231-9222

 http://www.arcthriftpromotions.org 

 

Gone For Good Store

7600 S Grant Street #A2, Littleton, 80122

303-736-2387 www.GoneForGoodStore.com 

Picks up your stuff

Tries to sell it online for 30 days, giving you 30% of sales price.

Tries to give it away.

Takes it apart to recycle what can be recycled.

? Also has free directory of garage sales on the web site.



 REUSABLE APPLICANCES FURNITURE, 

 BUILDING MATERIALS&amp;TOOLS 

Greeting for Humanity Home Improvement Outlet

70 Rio Grande Blvd., Denver, CO 80223 www.HabitatOutlet.org

303-722-5863 call for pick up.

To drop off: Open 9 AM - 6 PM Monday - Saturday. Closed Sunday.

 REUSABLE OFFICE&amp;HOUSEHOLD FURNISHINGS 

Providers Resource Clearinghouse

14200 E 35 th Place #105, Aurora CO 80010 www.PRCcolorado.org

303-962-2270 call for pick up of furniture you wish to donate

Furniture must be in to good to excellent condition. Furniture needed: sofas, chairs, end or coffee tables, lamps dining or kitchen tables and chairs, mattresses, box springs, and dressers.

 BATTERIES: LEAD ACID&amp;RECHARGEABLE 

Batteries Plus (www.BatteriesPlus.com)

2600 S Colorado Boulevard, Denver 80222 303-504-0101

994 S. Abilene Street, Aurora CO (just north of Mississippi) 303.745.3333

check web site for additional metro Denver locations

 



Car-go Batteries

3860 Blake Street, Denver 80205 303-296-8763

 

 BATTERIES: ALL TYPES 

Hensley Battery

2031 Bryant Street 303-455-3643

 

 BATTERIES: RECHARGEABLE 

All or most Radio Shack stores accept rechargeable batteries for recycling.

Phone: 1-800-8-Battery

Web Address: http://www.rbrc.org/consumer/uslocate.html

Rechargeable Batteries (Ni-Cd, Lithium Ion, etc.) Commonly found in cell phones, power tools and cordless phones.

Drop off location close to Windsor Gardens: Colpar Hobbies, 804 South Havana, Aurora. 80012. 303-341-0414

There are more than 250 locations in the City and County of Denver most of which are housed in retail stores. Call or visit web site for other locations.

 APPLIANCES 

Windsor Gardens referral: 303-430-7142

 

 DO MORE RECYCLING 

4200 Gaylord Street (43rd and York) Denver 80216 303-292-4841

Accepts appliances, cars, car batteries, aluminum, and other scrap metal

 BEDS 

Colorado Coalition for the Homeless 303-297-2217

Uptown Partnership (ask for Dawn DeAno) 720-434-2938

 BLANKETS&amp;TOWELS 

Saint Francis Center 303-297-1576

Broadway Assistance Center 303-893-4108 

 ELECTRONICS 

E-cycle Coupon Program The City of Denver, in partnership with Metech Recycling, is now offering an Electronics Recycling Coupon Program. The E-cycle coupon will allow Denver residents to drop-off their televisions, monitors and other electronic items at Metech Recycling&apos;s facility at a significantly discounted rate. Denver residents may request an E-cycle coupon by completing the online form below or by calling 3-1-1. Scroll down below the E-cycle form for Electronic Recycling Fee information.

http://www.denvergov.com/trashrecycling/TrashandRecycling/Recycling/ElectronicsRecycling/EcycleCoupon/tabid/441004/Default.aspx

Mountain Electronics Recycling 303-287-0060 www.mountainrecycling.com 

4120 Brighton Blvd. Unit A-1, Denver, CO 80216

Acccepts: Electronics, computers, monitors, batteries, faxes, cell phones, hard drives, servers, laptops, printers and copper wire. There is a charge for some of these items and a fee for pick up. Call for details.

 ELECTRONICS - COMPUTER HARDWARE 

Action Computer Hours

2890 S Colorado Boulevard, Denver 80222 10:00 AM - 5:00 PM Sunday

303-759-1668 10:00 AM - 7:00 PM Monday Friday 

 www.ActionPC.com 10:00 AM - 6:00 PM Saturday 

Action Computer staff may pay you, accept for free or charge you to responsibly dispose of used computer hardware; depending on whether they think the hardware can be resold, donated to a non-profit, or needs special hazardous waste handling. 

 

Best Buy (north of I-25, one block east of Colorado Boulevard..)

4100 East Mexico Avenue, Denver 80222 closed Sunday

303-758-5805 10:00 AM - 9:00 PM Monday Saturday 

www.BestBuy.com

Best Buy has bins in the store entrance collecting CDs, DVDs, and their plastic cases; cell phones; cables, and other small electronics. Just drop them in. No charge.

 

Office Depot stores accept electronics for recycling. You pay a fee.

 

 EYE GLASSES&amp;HEARING AIDES 

Optimist Club collection box in Centerpoint lobby, by the newspaper racks.

 

 MAGAZINES, VIDEO TAPES,&amp;DVDs 

Windsor Gardens Library, above Centerpoint, second floor

University of Colorado Hospital, Volunteer Services. 720-848-1886

 

 MEDICAL EQUIPMENT AND SUPPLIES 

Project CURE. Call to have donated items picked up 303-291-1242

Or call a Windsor Gardens volunteer, Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056

Project CURE (Commission on Urgent Relief and Equipment) accepts donations of used (&amp;new) medical supplies for shipment&amp;use in &quot;third world&quot; countries&apos; hospitals. Examples of what CURE accepts: wheel chairs, walkers, adult diapers, unused diabetes supplies. Medicines must be in manufacturer&apos;s original packaging (no pharmacy prescription bottles) and an expiration date at least one year into the future. Your donation can be a charitable donation on your federal income tax return. www.ProjectCURE.org

 

 PLASTIC FLOWER POTS 

Plastic garden pots are also accepted for recycling anytime at participating local garden stores.

Those closest to Windsor Gardens are:

Nick&apos;s Garden Center 2001 S. Chambers Road Aurora www.nicksgardencenter.com 

City Floral Garden Center 1440 Kearney St. Denver www.cityfloralgreenhouse.com 

Groundcovers Greenhouse 4301 E. Iliff Denver

The Garden Patch 2101 S Washington St Denver

For a full list go to www.GardenCentersOfColorado.org .

 

 SHOES 

Reusable shoes can go to many &quot;used clothing&quot; charities listed, starting on page 3.

Athletic shoes are the only shoes for which there are recyclers. Other go in the trash. Athletic shoes (no more than 10 pairs at one time) are accepted for recycling at:

Runners Roost

1685 South Colorado Boulevard, Unit J

303-759-8455

Nike Town at Denver Pavilions

500 Sixteenth Street 303-623-6453

http://www.nikebiz.com/responsibility/community_programs/reuse_a_shoe

Both stores will help in recycling more than 10 pairs of shoes at one time, if you call first for information.

All brands of athletic shoes are processed into a grind that is used in athletic courts and playground surfaces. (Information last updated April 28,2012.) 

 

 MISCELLANEOUS 

1-800-GOT JUNK

Charges to pick up almost anything. Reuses, recycles, or land fills it.



 

 

 

 HOME HAZARDOUS WASTE 

For most recent information check: http://www.denvergov.org/Recycle/tabid/425783/Default.aspx

Household Hazardous Waste Program Criteria Due to recent budget cuts, the City has changed its program criteria in order to efficiently use our limited funding, while ensuring we serve the most residents possible and provide disposal options for those hazardous products for which a retail drop site option does not exist.
 
 Table 1, Column A 

Brake Fluid, Carburetor Fluid, Chlorine Bleach, Cleaners, Corrosive Chemicals, Drain Openers, Gasoline, Fluorescent Tubes, Herbicides, Hobby Chemicals, Household Batteries, Insect Sprays, Muriatic Acid, Oil//Fuel Mix, Non-Latex Paint, Paint Thinner, Pesticides, Polishes, Pool Chemicals, Rust Remover, Solvent, Spray Paint, Stains, Stripper, Thermometers, Thermostats, Used Oil Filters, Waxes, Weed Killers, Wood Preservatives
 
 Table 1, Column B 

Antifreeze, Automotive Batteries, CFLs, Latex Paint, Motor Oil
 
Before calling 1-800-449-7587 to make a door-to-door or drop-off appointment, please make sure that you have:

1. A minimum of 25 pounds of any one material listed under Column A in Table 1 (above); or

2. A minimum of 3 different types of material from Table 1 with at least one material type being from Column A.

If you only have items from Column B in Table 1, then you are not eligible for a collection subsidized by the City. You have three disposal options:

1. Call the hotline and request to make an appointment for which you will pay the entire disposal cost, ranging between $90 and $114.

2. Take your antifreeze, motor oil, automotive batteries, latex paint and CFLs to free retail drop sites. (Go to the web site above for more details)

3. If all you have to dispose of is latex paint, please go to the web site above to learn more about your disposal options.

UNACCEPTABLE MATERIALS The City&apos;s Household Hazardous Waste Program cannot accept:

1.Asbestos (including linoleum tiles containing asbestos from older homes)

2.Explosives

3.Ammunition

4.Commercial Chemicals or Commercial Quantities (Business Waste)

5.Bio-Waste (Medical Waste)

6.Sharps (needles)

Due to the possible health risks associated with handling materials containing asbestos (such as linoleum tiles), please consult the Air Pollution Control Division Asbestos Unit to learn more about safe handling and disposal for asbestos. http://www.cdphe.state.co.us/hm/hhw/howto/asbestos.htm or 303-692-3150

If you have any of these other materials listed and have questions about proper disposal methods for them, then please contact the Colorado Department of Public Health and Environment (CDPHE) Customer Technical Assistance Line 303-692-3320.

 www.Earth911.com 

Extensive directory of recycling, reuse, and other information.

 If your find information here that is wrong, or know of additional resources, please let Paul Steinhauer (me) know. E-mail: Building43@aol.com or call(303)341-0056. 
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 5/9/12 9:22am 
 

  COLORADO HISPANIC REPUBLICANS at WG May 15, at 7PM 0 5/6/12 4:56am 
May 15, 2012 Tuesday. 7 PM Centerpoint
Appearing: PAULINE OLVERA, COLORADO HISPANIC REPUBLICANS
A grass roots organization with the vision to get Hispanics to vote for the party that best aligns with their values of Faith, Family and Freedom.
 http://www.coloradohispanicrepublicans.org 

This is sponsored by the Windsor Gardens Republican Club
Questions? gopwg@aol.com or 303-366-0753 Linda Weems, Chairman, Republican Club

 
 Paul Steinhauer - 5/6/12 4:56am 
 

  Post office in Windsor Pharmacy 1 4/10/12 12:14am The post office in the Windsor Pharmacy has now closed permanently. The closest post office is on Ironton near Mississippi. 
 Hollice Stander - 4/5/12 3:17pm 

 
Route 3 bus serves US Post Offices at:
 201 Columbine Street, Denver 80206 (303) 355-7160
in Cherry Creek North (north of the Sears store.)


225 South Broadway, Denver 80209 (303) 698-2948
(in the block just north of Alameda). West side of the street)

 Paul Steinhauer - 4/10/12 12:14am 
 
 

  Table of Contents for March 28 BRA meeting 0 4/4/12 11:33am 
TABLE OF CONTENTS

Page Topic

1. Treasurers Report.

2. Emerald Grill report. Michael Schettler.

. Windsor Gardens Association Board of Directors President, Rusty Reece.

4. Centerpoint remodeling. Larry Brady, Chairman, Windsor Gardens

Association Long Range Planning Committee.

6. Coupon Information. (Monthly maintenance fees.) Nancy Barké.

Wastewater Management. Bill Berger, Manager of Customer Service,

Wastewater Manager Division, City&amp;County of Denver.

10. Real Estate Taxes. Nancy Barké.

11. Security Report: Michael Piccin.

12. 50 th anniversary of WG. Volunteers will be activated as planning is

finalized. Linda Hargrave, Windsor Gardens Association Board

member.
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 4/4/12 11:33am 
 

  &quot;How to Ride RTD&quot; bus trips for April 0 4/4/12 10:48am 
 RIDE! LUNCH&amp;LEARN AP RIL TRIP 

 April 26, 2012, Thursday. 10:15AM meet in the Auditorium lobby.
 Denver International Airport: Lunch in the food court. Choose your fast food restaurant. Cost: $11 per person (the fare is $9 per person and is included in price). Lunch is on your own. We will return around 4p.m. Reserve and pay for the bus with the Windsor Gardens Activities Office. 
 BUS BUDDIES APRIL TRIPS 
 April 15, 2012, Sunday. Noon: Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby. (Or get on the westbound #3 bus that starts through Windsor Gardens about 12:15 PM at any bus stop.) PARAMOUNT CAFÉ. We will go downtown, transferring to the #83L bus in Cherry Creek North. This trip requires about two city blocks of walking. All pedestrian street crossing are with traffic lights, except within Windsor Gardens.

We will have lunch downtown at the Paramount Café. Pay for your own meal. Order what you wish from the menu. Many meals are under $20.00. The Paramount is noisy. If this will spoil your meal, do not go on this trip. The menu is available at www.ParamountCafe.com.

At our leisure we will go into the Paramount Theatre for the pipe organ concert that will be in progress, and ends at 4PM. The concert is free. We will return to Windsor Gardens, arriving back at 5:30PM.

The free concert at the Paramount Theatre is part of the Doors Open Denver weekend fair. The concert starts at 10 AM and ends at 4PM. The audience comes and goes when they wish.

You may simply meet the group for lunch, and go downtown on your own early. And you may leave anytime you wish. Just let a tour guide know you are leaving.

Doors open Denver includes a lot of activities. For details go to www.denvergov.org/doorsopendenver. If you do not use the Internet, the Denver Post will probably print details sometime in early April.

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus. For details, and to sign up, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056. 


 



 (The April 29, trip is cancelled. Only one person signed up.)

 April 29, 2012, Sunday 11AM: Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby. (Or get on the westbound #3 bus that starts through Windsor Gardens about 11:15 AM at any bus stop.) ROCK BOTTOM BREWERY . We will go downtown, transferring to light rail.

At the Rock Bottom Brewery. Pay for your own meal. Order what you wish from the menu. Expect to pay about $20 for lunch, more if you drink a lot of beer. The menu has many options. The menu is available at http://rockbottombrewery.com/denver-downtown. This trip requires about 3/4 mile of walking. All street crossings are with a traffic light, except within Windsor Gardens.

We will return to Windsor Gardens, arriving back at 3:30PM.


Optional side trip. The Denver Center for the Performing Arts offers two plays at 2:00PM, &quot;Wicked&quot; and &quot;I Love You. You&apos;re Perfect. Now Change.&quot; Go to www.DenverCenter.org, for show information. Or call 303-893-4100 for tickets. Or just walk up to the box office before the show and buy tickets there.

On past trips, since most members of Bus Buddies groups have chosen to return home right after eating, if you stay downtown for a show, you need to be comfortable getting home on your own. Simply reverse what we did to get downtown. Catch light rail on the south end of the Denver Center for the Performing Arts. (Ask other passengers in the station to show you how to get a ticket before getting on the train.) Transfer to the route 3 bus at the Alameda light rail station. Remember to board a #3 bus going east, to the Centerpoint&amp;Sable Transfer Center.

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus, and when returning home, at the light rail station. For trip details, and to reserve your seat, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056 .

Bus Buddies only needs for you to sign up so that we can make a reservation for lunch. If you sign up we can call you and tell you if the trip is cancelled. You pay nothing in advance and lose no money if you cancel.
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 4/4/12 10:48am 
 

  Denver walking tours with historian Phil Goldstein 0 4/3/12 4:44am 
http://www.leonardleonard.com/neighborhoods/walkingtours.shtml
 
 2012 Walking Tours by Phil Goodstein - 303.333.1095 
 
Saturday, April 7: Quality Hill, 11:00 am-1:00 pm
 
Meet at the Zang Mansion, 709 Clarkson Street. (Clarkson Street is eight blocks east of Broadway). The cost is $10.00.


 
Saturday, April 14: Jefferson Park, 11:00 am-1:00 pm
 
Meet in front of the Adams Mystery Playhouse at the northeast corner of West 24th Avenue and Federal Boulevard..


 
Sunday, April 15, 2012: The History of North Denver, 12 Noon&amp;1PM&amp;2PM
 
This is a free half-hour lecture at the Gardens at St. Elizabeth&apos;s, 2835 West 32nd Avenue (the highrise two blocks east of Federal Boulevard). It is part of Open Doors Denver, including a chance to peak in the historic chapel and an overview of the neighborhood.


 
Saturday, April 21, 2012: Platt Park, 11:00 am-1:00 pm
 
Meet in front of the Decker Library at the southwest corner of Florida Avenue and South Logan Street. (Florida Avenue is four blocks south of Mississippi Avenue and six blocks north of Evans Avenue. Logan Street is four blocks east of Broadway.) This tour is $10.


 
Saturday, April 28, 2012: The Smiley Neighborhood, 11:00 am-1:00 pm
 
Meet in front of Smiley Middle School on the east side of Holly Street between 25th and 26th avenues. (Holly is one mile east of Colorado Boulevard and one-half mile west of Monaco Street.) This tour is $10.


 
Wednesday, May 2, 2012: Morgan&apos;s Addition/Congress Park, 6:00-8:00 pm
 
Meet in front of the Fred Mazzulla House at the southwest corner of Eighth Avenue and Race Street. (Race Street is three blocks west of York Street.) This tour is $10.


 
Wednesday, May 9, 2012: Sloans Lake/West Colfax, 6:00-8:00 pm
 
Meet at the torpedo near the northeast corner of Sheridan Boulevard and 17th Avenue. This tour is $10.


 
Saturday, May 12: Ghost Walk, 7:00-9:00 pm. Also June 9, July 14, August 25, September 15, October 19, October 20, October 26, October 27, and October 31, 2012.
 
Meet in front of the statue of the Indian on the east side of the Capitol on Grant Street between 14th and Colfax avenues. The cost is $20.00.


 
Wednesday, May 16, 2012: South of the Country Club, 6:00-8:00 pm
 
Meet in front of Steele School on the east side of South Marion Street between Alameda and Dakota avenues. (Marion Street is one block east of Downing Street.) This tour is $10.


 
Wednesday, May 23, 2012: Park Hill, 6:00-8:00 pm
 
Meet at the gazebo of Ferguson Park at the southeast corner of 23rd Avenue and Dexter Street. (Dexter Street is seven blocks east of Colorado Boulevard) This tour is $10.


 
Thursday, June 7, 2012: Park Club Place, 6:30-8:30 pm
 
Meet at the real estate offices of Leonard Leonard&amp;Associates, 420 Downing Street. This tour is $10.
~~~~~~~~~

http://yourhub.denverpost.com/denver/denver-historian-phil-goodstein-getting-back-his-old/U0AyA5BGZUXDUnsKfkxU8L-story?source=DPWidget

Denver historian Phil Goodstein getting back to his old haunts

With his &quot;Ph.D. in useless information,&quot; Goodstein has resumed his slate of spirited bicycle and walking tours of Denver&apos;s neighborhoods
 
March 27, 2012. Denver Post
 
One by one, the curious approached the gazebo in Cheesman Park, looking for the bespectacled man in a Hawaiian shirt who was waiting for each of them with the same, familiar greeting.

&quot;Hello, you&apos;re looking for a tour, aren&apos;t you?&quot; Phil Goodstein told them as the group assembled for a walking tour of the area. &quot;I&apos;ll take your money.&quot;

In his role as one of the city&apos;s resident historians, Goodstein has revived his schedule of walking and bicycle tours of Denver neighborhoods, offering his voluminous knowledge of the city&apos;s past for $10 a pop. For the man who describes himself as having &quot;a Ph.D. in useless information,&quot; it&apos;s a tradition going strong since July 1986.

Starting right at 11 a.m. Saturday, Goodstein welcomed his group with a solid 20 minutes of background, detailing the &quot;sky-high&quot; death rate and rampant disease in the booming Denver of the 1870s, all which led to a rapidly filling city graveyard.

Without skipping a beat, Goodstein advised that someone&apos;s vehicle was illegally parked near a bus stop - having led this particular tour since 1987, he seemed to know the area as well as anyone.

The clutter of cars and large group may have had something to do with Goodstein&apos;s appearance earlier this month on Travel Channel&apos;s &quot;Ghost Adventures,&quot; as the show&apos;s paranormal investigators sought him out for details about the Peabody-Whitehead Mansion. Goodstein said he hadn&apos;t seen the episode for himself.

&quot;These ghost hunters are full of malarkey,&quot; Goodstein said, noting that it&apos;s highly unlikely to be able to capture evidence of ghosts with equipment &quot;based on our contemporary laws of physics.&quot;

Tom Noel, a professor of history at the University of Colorado-Denver who has known Goodstein for about 20 years, also appeared on the episode and said he and others such as Goodstein see it as a means for drawing attention to the state&apos;s past.

&quot;(We) do it because it gets some people interested in history that wouldn&apos;t be otherwise,&quot; Noel said. &quot;I do a lot of cemetery tours for kids who might find history dull.&quot;

As Noel put it, he and Goodstein &quot;share a niche,&quot; one that requires hours of sifting through library archives. Goodstein claims he spends four or five hours each morning writing and compiling facts.

&quot;We learn from him,&quot; Noel said.

Goodstein elicited an array of chuckles and disgusted faces from the tour group as he talked about Edward McGovern and the gruesome process of relocating the corpses of Mt. Prospect Cemetery and the 2,000 to 5,000 bodies (by Goodstein&apos;s estimate) left behind to spend &quot;eternity in the park.&quot;

As the group meandered past the historic homes on Humboldt Street, residents peeked out their front doors, some to see the commotion, others to confirm the claims of hauntings.

&quot;Every now and then, people are convinced (ghosts) are there and don&apos;t like me joking about them,&quot; Goodstein said. &quot;Sometimes tours get chased away by the current owners.&quot;

But Goodstein keeps going 25 years since he started, offering the mobile lectures in conjunction with Colorado Free University, something for which CFU President Helen Hand is grateful.

&quot;There&apos;s no one who knows Denver better, who&apos;s walked every inch of the city with stories to tell with tremendous flair,&quot; Hand said.

MORE :: For a full schedule of Phil Goodstein&apos;s upcoming tours, visit http://dpo.st/H44htb.

Christopher Harrop: 303-954-2465 or charrop@denverpost.com
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 4/3/12 4:44am 
 

  March 20, Tuesday 7PM: Identity Theft program in Centerpoint 0 3/18/12 12:23pm 
 &quot;May I see your I.D.?&quot; 

 Identify theft is in the news often. 

 Identity theft is more than a credit card. 

 Join us and learn the different types of identity theft 

 and tips on how to reduce your chances of becoming 

 A victim of identity theft. 

 presenter: Cheryl Blum Garcia

Vice President, Group Marketing-Colorado

Legal Shield&amp;Identity Theft Shield.

This is a program of the Windsor Gardens Republican Club

Questions? gopwg@aol.com or
303-366-0753 Linda Weems, Chairman, Republican Club
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 3/18/12 12:23pm 
 

  Upcoming WG bus trips using RTD&apos;s route 3 bus 0 3/14/12 12:15am 
 March 20, 2012, Tuesday . 10:30AM meet in the Auditorium lobby. BUCKHORN EXCHANGE: This famous Denver eatery has an extensive menu, which includes a wide variety of salads, sandwiches and soups, with entrees starting at $10 per person. Cost: $5 per person for the bus, round trip. Lunch cost is on your own. Reserve and pay for the bus with the Windsor Gardens Activities Office. This is a RIDE! LUNCH&amp;LEARN trip. There is very little walking on this trip. Most walking is in Windsor Gardens. We cross no busy streets as pedestrians on this trip.

The trips below are all hosted by &quot;Bus Buddies&quot; the all volunteer group in Windsor Gardens.

Feel free to copy and paste the information on this trip and send it to friends. Friends who will not ride the bus are welcome to join us for lunch. They need to sign up with Bus Buddies to be included in the restaurant reservation.

 March 16, 2012, Friday, meet in the Auditorium at 10:25AM. OLIVE GARDEN RESTAURANT: We will catch the eastbound bus and then transfer to the #105 to continue to the restaurant. This trip is sponsored by Bus Buddies. We walk two blocks from the bus to Olive Garden. We will walk across Havana on the way to the Olive Garden. (Busy street, but with traffic light)

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus, and when returning home. For trip details, and to reserve your seat, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056.

Bus Buddies only needs for you to sign up so that we can make a reservation for lunch. If you sign up we can call you and tell you if the trip is cancelled. You pay nothing in advance and lose no money if you cancel.


 

 March 22, 2012, Thursday , we will meet in the Auditorium at 10:30 a.m. RED LOBSTER RESTAURANT: for our trip east just a few blocks to Red Lobster. There is very little walking for this trip. We will walk across Alameda when leaving Red Lobster. (Busy Street, but with traffic light.)

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus, and when returning home, at the light rail station. For trip details, and to reserve your seat, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056.

Bus Buddies only needs for you to sign up so that we can make a reservation for lunch. If you sign up we can call you and tell you if the trip is cancelled. You pay nothing in advance and lose no money if you cancel.

 April 15, 2012, Sunday. Noon: Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby. (Or get on the westbound #3 bus that starts through Windsor Gardens about 12:15 PM at any bus stop.) PARAMOUNT CAFÉ. We will go downtown, transferring to the #83L bus in Cherry Creek North. This trip requires about two city blocks of walking. All pedestrian street crossing are with traffic lights, except within Windsor Gardens.

We will have lunch downtown at the Paramount Café. Pay for your own meal. Order what you wish from the menu. Many meals are under $20.00. The Paramount is noisy. If this will spoil your meal, do not go on this trip. The menu is available at www.ParamountCafe.com.

At our leisure we will go into the Paramount Theatre for the pipe organ concert that will be in progress, and ends at 4PM. The concert is free. We will return to Windsor Gardens, arriving back at 5:30PM.

The free concert at the Paramount Theatre is part of the Doors Open Denver weekend fair. The concert starts at 10 AM and ends at 4PM. The audience comes and goes when they wish.

You may simply meet the group for lunch, and go downtown on your own early. And you may leave anytime you wish. Just let a tour guide know you are leaving.

Doors open Denver includes a lot of activities. For details go to www.denvergov.org/doorsopendenver. If you do not use the Internet, the Denver Post will probably print details sometime in early April.

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus. For details, and to sign up, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056.

Bus Buddies only needs for you to sign up so that we can make a reservation for lunch., We can also call you if the trip is cancelled. You pay nothing in advance and lose no money if you cancel.

 April 29, 2012, Sunday 11AM: Meet in Windsor Gardens Auditorium lobby. (Or get on the westbound #3 bus that starts through Windsor Gardens about 11:15 AM at any bus stop.) ROCK BOTTOM BREWERY . We will go downtown, transferring to light rail.

At the Rock Bottom Brewery. Pay for your own meal. Order what you wish from the menu. Expect to pay about $20 for lunch, more if you drink a lot of beer. The menu has many options. The menu is available at http://rockbottombrewery.com/denver-downtown. This trip requires about 3/4 mile of walking. All street crossings are with a traffic light, except within Windsor Gardens.

We will return to Windsor Gardens, arriving back at 3:30PM.

Optional side trip. The Denver Center for the Performing Arts offers two plays at 2:00PM, &quot;Wicked&quot; and &quot;I Love You. You&apos;re Perfect. Now Change.&quot; Go to www.DenverCenter.org, for show information. Or call 303-893-4100 for tickets. Or just walk up to the box office before the show and buy tickets there, they are available.

On past trips, since most members of Bus Buddies groups have chosen to return home right after eating, if you stay downtown for a show, you need to be comfortable getting home on your own. Simply reverse what we did to get downtown. Catch light rail on the south end of the Denver Center for the Performing Arts. (Ask other passengers in the station to show you how to get a ticket before getting on the train.) Transfer to the route 3 bus at the Alameda light rail station. Remember to board a #3 bus going east, to the Centerpoint&amp;Sable Transfer Center.

You will pay your own bus fare when boarding a bus, and when returning home, at the light rail station. For trip details, and to reserve your seat, E-mail wg.bus@aol.com, or call Paul Steinhauer, 303-341-0056.

Bus Buddies only needs for you to sign up so that we can make a reservation for lunch. If you sign up we can call you and tell you if the trip is cancelled. You pay nothing in advance and lose no money if you cancel.

 MISSION STATEMENT 

 

Bus Buddies first goal is to introduce people who do not know how to ride Regional Transportation District buses and light rail to public transportation, so that they can travel on their own comfortably. We teach people the details that make a trip run more smoothly, so they do not have to &quot;learn how&quot; by trial and error.

Bus Buddies second goal is to provide our neighbors with guided group bus trips as a social gathering. Usually lunch is involved, along with shopping, a performance, museum, or other event.

Bus Buddies third goal is to increase ridership on RTD&apos;s route 3 bus, so that we can have service increased from the current &quot;once per hour.

Bus Buddies s always looking for new volunteers to plan trips and guide people on those trips.

Questions? E-mail: wg.bus@aol.com. Call Paul Steinhauer 303-341-0056, or Betty Tidwell.
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 3/14/12 12:15am 
 

  In WG: Daily protests against rising gasoline prices 0 2/23/12 9:22am 
 IN WINDSOR GARDENS YOU ARE INVITED TO PARTICPATE IN AT LEAST ONE OF THE 28 DAILY DEMONSTRATIONS TO PROTEST HIGHER GASOLINE PRICES. 



THAT IS HOW OFTEN THE REGIONAL TRANSPORTATION DISTRICT (RTD) ROUTE 3 BUS TRAVELS THROUGH WINDSOR GARDENS.*



Each time you leave the car parked and ride the bus, some gasoline (and money) are saved.



If driving a car is a reflex action anytime you go someplace, start considering if taking the bus might be cost effective for this trip.



Remember what Greyhound advertised when we were kids?

&quot;It&apos;s such a comfort to take the bus, and leave the driving to us.&quot;

(That applies to RTD too.)



*There are even more bus trips Mondays - Saturdays.

Car pooling is good too.



Paul Steinhauer
Windsor Gardens Bus Buddies volunteer

2/23/2012
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 2/23/12 9:22am 
 

  post office&amp;gift shop remain open at Windsor Gardens Pharmacy 0 2/5/12 11:56am 
 Windsor Gardens Pharmacy&amp;Gifts
 9660 E Alameda Ave Ste 110
Denver, CO 80247 | Phone: 303-364-9319
www.WindsorGardensPharmacy.com

The pharmacy is closed. We are deeply grateful for your continued loyalty throughout the years.

We are happy to announce that the gift shop and post office will remain open.

copiejd from the web site
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 2/5/12 11:56am 
 

  GOP candidate for Congress in Centerpoint Feb 21 at 7PM 0 1/29/12 7:56pm 
WG Republican Club (WGRC) program. Speaker: Danny Stroud, candidate for Congress for Denver and Chairman, Denver County Republicans.
 
 Stroud is running on a platform of: 

 . expanded opportunity, 

 . limited government, 

 . a strengthened America, 

 . fiscal responsibility. 

 

 http://dannystroudforcolorado.com 

 5650 W. Quincy Avenue, Unit #5 Denver , CO 80235 

 (303) 973-1247 
 
 stroud@DannyStroudforCongress.com 


Questions. E-mail gopwg@aol.com. Or call Chairman Linda Weems, 303-366-0753.
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 1/29/12 7:56pm 
 

  Republican caucuses February 7, Tuesday 6:30PM in WG&apos;s Auditorium 0 1/29/12 7:51pm 
All voters registered as Republicans may participate in this exercise in democracy. If you live in Windsor Gardens, it can&apos;t much more conveninet that the Auditorium, unless you want to hold a caucus in your living room.

Questions? E-mail them to gopwg@aol.com . Or call Paul Steinhauer 303-341-0056
 
 Paul Steinhauer - 1/29/12 7:51pm 
 

  RIDER ALERT #3 WG LOOP 0 1/21/12 1:50pm 
 RIDERS

For those who ride #3 Eastbound or Westbound 

 Effective January 22 Sunday... 

 Share the information at rtd-denver  at SCHEDULES
and see the once an hour NEW schedule as of tomorrow. 

 The new #3 RTD printed schedules so far is not printed out.
Centerpoint Bus only - Federal Center. Inside the WG LOOP. 

 Check it out...or share this information online and RTD Schedules
with your neighbors who ride and your building reps.......
RIDER ALERT...the schedule for once an hour via WG Loop is
tweaked and pass it on in your buildings. Print it out if possible. 

 Private pay or Medicaid with Amazing Wheels LLC
 amazingmedicaltransport.com  ask for Teresa. WG will NOT
provide any group discounts. Ambulatory vans and wheelchair
accessible vans and buses. One Buick sedan for party night. 

 Ride on! 
 
 Nancy Machin - 1/21/12 1:50pm 
 

  Amazing Wheels 2 uplifting meeting! 0 1/16/12 10:09am 
A new opportunity for those who need alternative, even handicap
transportation. Medicaid and non-Medical. Insurance or private pay
or...possibly group Windsor discounts. Stay tuned.
******************************************

 contact Teresa, Dispatcher , amazingwheels@gmail.com 
 CALL 720.276.0824 office or 720.495.0256 cell

Amazing Wheels met at the Clubhouse this weekend and listened
to the concerns of residents here on transportation issues. Teresa
and one mini van (with a ramp) showed up and some of us got the
grand tour with a ride. The fleet is diverse at Amazing Wheels..
mini van with a handicap ramp, shuttle type for 10
with a w/c lift, Buick sedan or airport trips, etc. Trained drivers.
 www.amazingmedicaltransport.com  
Non-medical and medical. Perhaps, a senior group discount?
Teresa said will begin talks with WG management.

Maybe a solution for those who truly need a service like this!
Support this transportation alternative at Windsor Gardens.

Contact me if you like      ...lifecoach.nancy@gmail.com  
 
 Nancy Machin - 1/16/12 10:09am 
 

  Informal Meet with Amazing Wheels on Saturday 0 1/12/12 9:46pm 
Teresa of the AMAZING WHEELS LLC Transportation Service
will be able to meet with us informally this Saturday January 14th 
at the main area of Community Center at 10:30 AM...open meeting to all about
WG becoming more accessible, the services Amazing Wheels provides,
and private pay (and Medicaid) options. A BBB Accredited business.
 www.amazingmedicaltransport.com   Their fleet includes ambulatory
sedans and wheelchair-accessible vans. The recent flyer we found
at the WG Pharmacy says their transport services helps seniors and those with
disabilities &quot;live life and make wonderful memories.&quot;

If you can, please spread the word in your building, post a sign, give a ride
and bring your questions to this open, informal meeting. We&apos;ll do our best
to have some interested residents present on this short notice. 
 
 Nancy Machin - 1/12/12 9:46pm 
 
 
 - New or updated Topic/Reply since last login  [ Next ] 
 
 
 Home | For Buyers | About Windsor Gardens | For Residents 595 S. Clinton•Denver, CO 80247•Phone: 303 364 7485•Fax: 303 364 3341 
 Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Rules and Regulations | Site Map 
 Homeowners association management software by AssociationVoice ©2012. All rights reserved. 
 
 
 Emerald Grill Emerald Greens Golf Course&amp;Club Community Pools Fitness Center Community Gardens Business Center Windsor Gardens History Surrounding Area Community Map 
 
 Activities, Groups&amp;Clubs Discussion Groups Photo Gallery Resident Directory News and Announcemetns Windsor Life ~ The News of Windsor Gardens Windsor Gardens Writers Group Calendars Search For An Event 
 
 Resident Sign In ACH Automatic HOA payment form New Resident? Sign Up Here Management Office&amp;Forms Association Terminology FAQs 
 
 All Classifieds Items For Sale Help Wanted Lost and Found Real Estate Listings Services Submit A Classified 
 
 Preferred Realtors Units for Rent 
 
 Management Contacts Board Members BRA Executive Board Committee Members Resident Directory
	</body>
</document>
