<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003915" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/does-panda-express-have-good-food" time="2012-07-12-20:05" support="3" score="0.0032763529591990073" bingtitle="Does Panda Express have good food? | ChaCha" webtitle="Does Panda Express have good food? | ChaCha">
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>How much is a party tray of food at Panda ... Panda Express is a fast food restaurant specializing in Asian ... When it&apos;s your night to pick the place, what&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
Does Panda Express have good food? 

In: Lifestyle › Dining Out › Panda Express 
 
Rate This Answer
 
For fast food standards, they&apos;re pretty good Chinese food , with fresh ingredients and new dishes like Thai Cashew Chicken. 
 Answered

 
 - 262 days ago at 2:38pm on Oct 23 2011 
Last Week&apos;s Popular Questions for Panda Express 

 
 What is the price of a Panda Bowl at Panda Express? 

Prices vary by location, but a Panda Bowl at Pa...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Is panda express bad for you? 

Several items at Panda Express score well on be...

in Food&amp;Drink | 4 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is the Closest panda express to 38th street in Austin? 

Panda Express is located at 4400 N Lamar Blvd A...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via iPhone app 
 
 Is Panda Express healthy? 

Most dishes at Panda Express are high in fat, s...

in Dining Out | 2 days ago via web 
 
 Is there a Panda Express in Terre Haute, IN? 

There is no Panda Express in Terre Haute, but y...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 How much is a Panda Bowl at Panda Express? 

Panda Express does not list menu prices online ...

in Shopping | 1 day ago via sms text 
 
 Does panda express fast food have MSG? 

No MSG is added to any of the items at Panda Ex...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 Does Panda Express have sesame chicken? 

The menu for Panda Express does not list Sesame...

in Dining Out | 2 days ago via web 
 
 What kind of food does the restaurant Panda Express cook? 

The restaurant Panda Express serves gourmet Chi...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via sms text 
 
 What are Panda Express pay rates? 

The average salary for Panda Express jobs is $3...

in Dining Out | 2 days ago via Android app 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Month&apos;s Popular Questions for Panda Express 

 
 Does panda express deliver? 

No, unfortunately Panda Express does not delive...

in Corporate Info | 3 days ago via Android app 
 
 How many calories are in the shrimp from Panda Express? 

The tangy shrimp has 150 calories, the Kung Pao...

in Dining Out | 14 days ago via Android app 
 
 What is the price of a Panda Bowl at Panda Express? 

Prices vary by location, but a Panda Bowl at Pa...

in Dining Out | 4 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Is Panda Express considered fast food? 

Panda Express does consider themselves to be fa...

in Dining Out | 3 days ago via web 
 
 What is better Chipotle or panda express? 

Although Chipotle is very good, I am much more ...

in Dining Out | 26 days ago via web 
 
 What is the best deal at Panda Express? 

The orange chicken is the best deal. You get a ...

in Dining Out | 16 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How many calories are in panda express orange chicken? 

There are 500 calories in a serving of Panda Ex...

in Food&amp;Drink | 14 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How many calories are there in a small chow mein at Panda Express? 

An 8 oz. serving of chow mein at Panda Express ...

in Dining Out | 14 hr 58 min ago via sms text 
 
 What is the Closest panda express to 38th street in Austin? 

Panda Express is located at 4400 N Lamar Blvd A...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via iPhone app 
 
 What can you get at panda express for $ 1.83? 

The prices vary from store to store, but you ca...

in Dining Out | 6 days ago via web 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Panda Express Galleries

 
 
 
 How to Eat Healthy at Summer Sporting Events 
 Viewed 70 times 
 
 
 
 Local Spots for Romantic Dates 
 Viewed 1239 times 
 
 
 
 Reasons Eating Is Better Than Dieting 
 Viewed 1309 times 
 
 
 
 5 Alternatives to Traditional Gym Equipment 
 Viewed 371 times 
 
 
 
 Choosing the Healthiest Salad Dressing 
 Viewed 231 times 
 
 
 
 How to Overcome Bad Eating Habits 
 Viewed 770 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Panda Express Quizzes

 
 
 
 What&apos;s Your Food Weakness? 
 
 
 
 Do You Know the Facts About Secondhand Smoke? 
 
 
 
 Do You Know Your Calorie Counts? 
 Viewed 9074 times 
 
 
 
 Are You Eating Proper Food Portions? 
 Viewed 3113 times 
 
 
 
 Which Foods Are Higher in Calories? 
 Viewed 23093 times 
 
 
 
 How Should You Celebrate Mother&apos;s Day? 
 Viewed 8740 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
About Panda Express 
 
Panda Express is a fast food restaurant specializing in Asian cuisine.

 More about Panda Express »
 
About Fast Food 
 
&apos;&apos;Fast food&apos;&apos; has become a regular part of people&apos;s vocabulary since the 1950&apos;s. The convenient, fast, and relatively cheap prices of fast food restaurants have made them some of the most popular stops for people on the move. Offering typical American foods like burgers, fries, and soft drinks, fast food restaurants have a definite American vibe and foothold.

 More about Fast Food »
 
About Food 
 
Food is fuel, take in as many calories as you burn and food will be good to you.

 More about Food »
 
Top Trends in Dining Out 

 Dominos Pizza» Wendys» Applebees» Hooters» Red Robin» Papa Johns» Bob Evans» Cracker Barrel» Drive Thru» Arbys» 
 
Top Trends in Lifestyle 

 Puppies» Makeup» Restaurant» Fishing» Kittens» Fast Food» liquor» McDonalds» Coke» Pizza» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Hurt» Ford» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Lifestyle › Dining Out › Panda Express 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
