<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003950" url="http://www.yellowpages.com/belleville-il/mip/popeyes-louisiana-kitchen-5272511" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="5" score="0.006899827774201661" bingtitle="Popeye&apos;s Chicken &amp; Biscuits Belleville, IL, 62226 - YP.com" webtitle="Popeyes Louisiana Kitchen Belleville, IL, 62226 - YP.com">
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>(618) 233-4654 · Business Details Edit info for this business Hours: Not available Extra Phones TollFree: (877) 767-3937 AKA Popeyes Chicken &amp; Biscuits Popeyes ...</description>
	<body>
		Join
 
 Thanks! Click the link in the email sent to activate your account.
 
Check your email at Email Inbox to activate your account. No email? Check your spam/junk folder or Resend It» Resend It» 
 X 
 White Pages Mobile Apps Advertise with Us 
 
 Sign In Join Sign in with Facebook 

 Welcome, User 
 » My Profile » My Locations » My Reviews » My Photos » My Searches and Listings » My Deals 
 Sign Out 
   YP.com What are you looking for? near Where? Home&gt; Belleville Yellow Pages &gt; Fast Food Restaurants in Belleville, IL &gt;Popeyes Louisiana Kitchen 
 Popeyes Louisiana Kitchen 
 38.537414 -90.019845 2.5 stars 
 4 Ratings 2 Reviews 
 » 
 Do you love this place? 

Help others by recommending it!
 X Not Now 
 Thanks! 
 Now see what others are saying» 

 
 X 
 » Close 
 Quickly rate your faves! 

Just point at the stars and click. Simple.
 
stars

 1 stars 2 stars 3 stars 4 stars 5 stars 
 
Your Rating
 
 (618) 233-4654 

 4130 W Main St, Belleville , IL 62226 

 View Menu Visit Website 
 
 Save Email Send to phone Facebook Twitter 
 
Videos&amp;Photos

 Add a Photo 
 


 Be the first to add a photo» 
 
Business Details

 Edit info for this business 
 Hours: Not available Categories: Chicken Restaurants, Take Out Restaurants, American Restaurants , Fast Food Restaurants 
Extra Phones

 TollFree: (877) 767-3937 

AKA

 Popeyes Chicken and Biscuits Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Popeyes Famous Fried Chicken 

In Business Since 1972
 
Reviews&amp;Recommendations

 Write a Review 
 2.5 stars 
4 Ratings
 
stars
 
Your Rating
 
0 recommendations
 
 
 


 

 See all recommendations» 
 
 
 1 stars 

 erreece 01/08/2009

Incompetant Management&amp;employees!!

Visited the restaurant at 7pm on 1-8-09. There were no customers inside. When I entered, two ladies were working on a drive through order, one young man was sweeping up in the back, one employee was (on break) eating in the seating area, and one young woman was behind the counter talking on the phone. NO ONE acknowledged my presence; NO ONE signalled to me that they would be right with me--nothing. I was too shocked to turn on my heel and leave. After about 3 minutes the woman hung up and asked if she could help me. I asked for the manager. SHE STATED THAT SHE WAS THE MANAGER!!! I told her that no one had offered to help me, and how dare she keep a customer waiting while she finished her personal call at the counter! She offered no apology--just kept asking for my order. I got the telephone number from the drive through window 1-877-POPEYES and called to register my complaint as soon as I returned to my car. It gets better: the cusotmer service person asked for the city and state, and when I said Belleville , she replied that the store was not in the database! The customer service rep asked for the telephone number from the receipt, and get this--there was no telephone number listed! It DID have a store number which I gave along with copious amounts of other info such as the nearest major cross street and numerous ways to get in touch with me. I don&apos;t know if this is a franchise or a corporate entity, but executive management needs to know how atrocious the service is....i&apos;ll wait a few days for someone to contact me before I write headquarters a scathing letter. Oh, and just in case anyone is wondering.....I discovered my order was wrong when I got home.

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 1 stars 

 sldofbelleville 09/17/2008

Very Unsatisfied customer...

I visited the new restaurant last night, 9/16. Paid $34 and some change for 16 pieces family meal of white meat, 2.50 for 2 extra breasts, 2 large mashed potatoes/gravy, and a large order of french fries.

When I got home, I had 6 pieces of dark meat, only 4 breasts, and 6 wings. And, only one order of mashed potatoes.

I called and spoke to a manager by the name of Samantha. I explained the above to her and her reply was &quot;And??&quot;

The service was horrible. Samantha, who waited on me was too busy having fun. She was slower than mud and her solution to my problem was to &quot;save the dark meat and bring it back this weekend, Friday night or Saturday, and she would replace it with 6 pieces of white meat&quot;. Last night was Tuesday!!!! I&apos;m supposed to save this chicken and then bring it back to her for a replacement. I&apos;ve never experienced such utter nonsence with a fast food restaurant in my entire life!

Not only will I not return the dark meat, I will not return to their restaurant at all.

I will be following up with their corporate office to get some type of satisfactory refund.

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 
 YP Mobile Page for Popeyes Louisiana Kitchen, Belleville, IL
 » Map&amp;Directions Paid Advertisement 
About

 About YP.com Contact Us Advertise with Us Careers Legal | Terms of Service and Use Privacy Policy Small Business Advertising Advertising Choices 
 
Site Directory

 Home Find a Business Maps&amp;Directions Find a Person White Pages Mobile Apps Reverse Phone Lookup Site Map Mobile YP 
 
City Guides More Cities » 

 Atlanta Austin Baltimore Boston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver 

 Detroit Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Memphis 

 Miami Milwaukee New York Oklahoma City Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Saint Louis 
 
AT&amp;T Family

 AT&amp;T AT&amp;T Wireless AnyWho Ingenio Yellow Pages Keen 
 
 Find Us on Facebook 

©2012 YP Intellectual Property LLC. All rights reserved.
YP, the YP logo and all other YP marks contained herein are trademarks of YP Intellectual Property LLC and/or YP affiliated companies.
AT&amp;T, the AT&amp;T Logo and all AT&amp;T related marks are trademarks of AT&amp;T Inc. or AT&amp;T affiliated companies.
All other marks contained herein are the property of their respective owners.
 Submit
	</body>
</document>
