<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003545" url="http://www.complaintnow.com/kentucky-fried-chicken-Complaints/complaint/business/Business_ID/display/13595" time="2012-07-12-19:41" support="9" score="0.03853877458028899" bingtitle="Kentucky Fried Chicken Complaints - Complaint Now: Consumer Complaints" webtitle="Kentucky Fried Chicken Complaints">
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>Restaurant-&gt; Fast Food Restaurant: E-Mail: Address: Brewerton Rd ... They set the tray on counter &amp; didn&apos;t call but ... for burned chicken not good - Never get what you order</description>
	<body>
		Complain Dialog Box X 
 
 
   
 Home | About | Contact | Help | Login  
 
 
 Complaints Businesses Post A Complaint Category My ComplaintNow 
 

 
 
 
 
 
Kentucky Fried Chicken Complaints

 
 

 
 Category Restaurant -&gt; Fast Food Restaurant E-Mail Address Brewerton Rd Mattydale USA www www.kfc.com Phone Stock Symbol KFC 


 Post A Complaint for Kentucky Fried Chicken See all Kentucky Fried Chicken Complaints 

 
 
Recent Complaints

 - never go back again!  
 by Guest, on Dec 12, 2010 
 My husband&amp;I bought 2 Liciou sand. ONLY
&amp;order 2 sm. drinks. took home 6 pics of
chicken. They set the tray on counter&amp;didn&apos;t call but I finally went
up&amp;I also had 2 fried potato wedges. I told him I didn&apos;t NOT want the pot. wedges, I ordered s 


 - nasty dining area  
 by Guest, on Dec 04, 2010 
 went in kfc to eat supper in etwah tenn found mold on window seals tile over head were molded air cond vents were molded door hadles were dirty from not being clean lots of cleaning needed in the dining area could not enjoy my meal for thinking about how t 


 - burned chicken  
 by Guest, on Dec 04, 2010 
 went through the drive thru order our meal , got home our chicken was burned , we live to far away to take it back , we paid $ 26 dollars for burned chicken not good 


 - Never get what you order  
 by Guest, on Nov 13, 2010 
 I never get a complete order when going to KFC in fremont. This time it was biscuits that I paid for and didn&apos;t receive. I called a told the manager that I didn&apos;t get the biscuits. She promised to send me a coupon for free biscuits the next time I was in, 


 - Potential Food Poison  
 by Guest, on Aug 02, 2010 
 Approximately 11AM on 8/1/2010 I went to purchase some Snacker Sandwiches. I had to wait several minutes before being served the food. My wife consumed 2 of the Snacker Sandwiches and within a couple of hours vomited. The vomit was very strong in coming 


 - cold food and been sitting to long  
 by Guest, on Jun 02, 2010 
 asked for 2 piece dinner they did not have any thighs and replaced it with a 2 drum stick that had been sitting to long.also got 2 piece grilled chickens dinner and the chichen was cold and i complaned and they microwaved it and gave it back to me hard 


 - Not honoring price listed for food order  
 by Guest, on Dec 29, 2009 
 My friend and I went into KFC for lunch. There was a special listed for $3.99. (5 firey wings,side&amp;soda) When it was rung up; the price showed $6.99. The person at register brought it to the Manager&apos;s attention. He refused to honor price posted. He s
	</body>
</document>
