<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003047" url="http://quma.us/index.html" time="2012-07-12-19:09" support="1" score="0.0006159667697738448" bingtitle="Mexican American Immigration" webtitle="Mexican American Immigration">
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>an outstanding number when one considers the state ... think about whether there&apos;d be anyone in that fast-food restaurant ... But even if you want to count only the 13 &quot;founding ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About QUMA Show Your Support 

Answers to Common Objections
 Terrorism Taking our Jobs Bad for the Economy Mexican Flag Waving A Nation Without Borders Abusing our System Drug Dealing Breaking the Law by Crossing 
 
Mexican Immigrants in the United States - It&apos;s a Good Thing

The impact of Hispanic immigrants-both legal and illegal-- on our American economy has been demonstrated time and time again on the various days when they have stayed home from work, to prove their clout by their absence.

This began most notably on May Day in 2006, the famous Day Without an Immigrant (which was itself inspired by the 2004 satirical film &quot;Day Without a Mexican.&quot;) ABC News, early that day, predicted a million participants, but Anita Hamilton (writing in &quot;Time&quot; magazine) did not want to estimate the number more specifically than &quot;hundreds of thousands&quot;-- even though she listed 300,000 engaged in the day&apos;s walk-out in Chicago alone!

Still, wrote Hamilton, the day&apos;s events &quot;clearly conveyed their message that immigrants are essential to the U.S. economy and deserve the right to continue living and working here.&quot;

Rallies in more than 50 cities from the east coast to the west coast demonstrated that Latino immigrants were not just Mexican but came from all over the Spanish and Portuguese-speaking world, and also showed that huge areas of American commerce-- from fast-food restaurants to factories to agriculture-- would come to a screeching halt without their participation.

Yet another beneficial impact of immigrants on U.S. economic health was seen in the once-flourishing border economies which have begun to be disrupted by the harsher border strictures that have come with the new fence. Where it was once easier to live on one side of the border and work on another, this has become more and more difficult.

An article in &quot;The Economist&quot; (June28/July4 &apos;08 issue) notes that &quot;El Pasoans, like most people in South Texas, are uniformly opposed to the border fence that the federal government is building. &apos;Everybody around here thinks it&apos;s a pretty foolish endeavor,&apos;&quot; the article quotes Toby Spoon, an American businessman, &quot;We interact like one big community.&quot;

Although the amount of arrests of those attempting to cross at the border does indeed seem to be declining slightly, &quot;The Economist&quot; admits that this is an &quot;imperfect measure&quot; of the actual amount of migrants who are successfully crossing. A better measure might be seen in the amount of money being sent home by migrants to their home countries-- and here the figure is stunning! The amount sent home to Mexico alone (only one of the countries from which the migrants come, remember) is estimated by &quot;The Economist&quot; to have declined only 2.9% from last year&apos;s high of $24 billion in the first quarter for which figures are available an outstanding number when one considers the state of both the U.S. and the Mexican economies (and unemployment statistics!) during the past year!

This amount, remember, is only the amount SENT HOME: it doesn&apos;t take into account what must be the far greater amount spent right here in the United States by these same migrants so if anyone needed to know how much they contribute to the American economy, consider this figure! Don&apos;t think about whether there&apos;d be anyone in that fast-food restaurant to serve you, if they weren&apos;t here think about how much worse off our struggling economy would be, if they weren&apos;t here spending those billions of dollars!

Fortunately, the border fence does very little to keep them out.

David Von Drehle (a reporter for &quot;Time&quot; magazine, writing in their June 30, &apos;08 issue) observed a group of &quot;ordinary&quot; Mexicans, &quot;one a grandmotherly woman, another a 10-year -old boy&quot; cross the border about five miles west of Naco, Arizona and he said they were able to &quot;cope with the U.S. government&apos;s new $1 million-per-mile border-security fence&quot; with ease, by first tossing their packs over the twelve foot barrier of steel mesh, and then having the stronger members of the group give the weaker ones a boost, at a place where a supporting post gave a foothold. And this was broad daylight and there was nobody there to observe them but a couple of AOL Time Warner journalists.

Considering that only about one third of the U.S./Mexican border is even proposed to be included in this new &quot;high tech&quot; barrier at all (about 650 miles, for which Congress voted $1.2 billion last year) one can be forgiven for wondering if everyone in the government is really entirely serious about closing this border.

After all, the United States is not only under an economic necessity for accepting these migrants: our country has always been culturally diverse, from the moment we were founded. We are the one nation on earth which was not founded based on an ethic or geographic basis, but on the basis of ideals, and we have always welcomed new blood.

Just to look at one strand of this diversity, Hispanics today are becoming an increasingly important part of our population, surpassing African-Americans as the largest ethnic minority with over 15% of our population.

With Christians the largest religious affiliation in the United States, and Roman Catholics the largest group of Christians, Hispanics number 64.4 million of the American Catholic Church&apos;s membership today, according to &quot;U.S. News&amp;World Report&quot; (April 7/14, &apos;08, p.40) -and it&apos;s expected they will make up 50% of U.S. Catholics by 2030.

An American Hispanic who grew up in Mexico City-- Bill Richardson-- has been a major player in this year&apos;s Presidential elections, and there&apos;s no doubt that the clout of immigrants will be felt in countless ways in the future.

Let us not forget that we are a nation of immigrants.

The United States is unique among the nations of the world because for us, the word &quot;nationality&quot; doesn&apos;t imply any particular kind of ethnicity: when you say you&apos;re an American from the United States it doesn&apos;t say anything at all about your race, color, religion or where you or your parents were born. Our country wasn&apos;t even created based on a geographical boundary, because our boundaries have changed many times from 1776 up to 1959, and they can always change again if new states are added.

With the the exception of the Native Americans, all of us came from somewhere else... and they came from somewhere else, too, just longer ago! The Pueblo peoples have been in the Southwest for thousands of years, apparently, but the Navajo and the Apaches only arrived in those areas shortly before the Europeans, according to some scholars.

The African Americans&apos; ancestors were brought against their will, with very few exceptions (a few free blacks did come, but very few) --but it&apos;s also true that the great majority of Hispanic immigrados who are flooding across the borders are being (in a sense) driven against their will by the necessities of poverty.

So, we&apos;ve always been a nation of immigrants, and we&apos;re not a nation with an &quot;ethnic&quot; identity. It&apos;s a myth that we were founded by white, English-speaking protestants. This leaves out of history all those places like Florida, the Louisiana Territories and the Western and Southwestern Territories, many of which were founded even earlier than the 13 so-called &quot;original&quot; colonies.

But even if you want to count only the 13 &quot;founding&quot; colonies who wrote the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution, you really have to count the many enslaved people who lived in them (even if the founders themselves forgot to count them.) And it&apos;s also important to remember that the founders would never have won their independence without the help of the French and the Spanish... and that the first Congress of the new U.S. debated whether to print the laws in German as well as English (and the proposal only lost by one vote!)

Abe Lincoln said we were a &quot;creedal&quot; nation, meaning that what held us together was our common beliefs. One of these is (or always used to be) that people could come here if they couldn&apos;t make a go of it in their original country, and we would give them a chance to make anew start, and become Americans.

This is why the Statue of Liberty (also an immigrant-- from France!) bears these words by Emma Lazarus: &quot;Give me your tired, your poor,
Your huddled masses yearning to breathe free...&quot;
Emma Lazarus herself, although a native-born citizen, was of Portuguese Jewish ancestry and (again!) hardly part of the typical &quot;Anglo-Saxon&quot; stereotype.

So this really only leaves two questions: should we finally say &quot;That&apos;s all we can hold&quot;? and should we say &quot;We welcome legals, but no illegals?&quot;

As far as the first question, we do have quotas, but this really doesn&apos;t address the question of true hardship cases: even for non-Christians, you can quote from Matthew 25:35-40 &quot; &apos;For I was hungry and you gave me something to eat, I was thirsty and you gave me something to drink, I was a stranger and you invited me in, 36I needed clothes and you clothed me, I was sick and you looked after me, I was in prison and you came to visit me.&apos; 37Then the righteous will answer him, &apos;Lord, when did we see you hungry and feed you, or thirsty and give you something to drink? 38When did we see you a stranger and invite you in, or needing clothes and clothe you? 39When did we see you sick or in prison and go to visit you?&apos; 40&quot;The King will reply, &apos;I tell you the truth, whatever you did for one of the least of these brothers of mine, you did for me.&apos; &quot;

For the second question (The illegals) the answer is more pragmatic: obviously, some very powerful group (or groups) in the U.S. WANT them in, or they would not have been allowed in for all these past years. If we really wanted to seal the border, the most powerful nation in the world could seal it. Anyone who has noticed the results of the Hispanic &quot;strikes&quot; when immigrados have stayed home from their &quot;visible&quot; jobs like fast-food restaurants, knows what a large part of the wage-slave work force they are, and it&apos;s easy to guess what a large part of the &quot;invisible&quot; work force they are, in factories and fields. Since the big owners were forced to give up their chattel slaves, they have come to rely more and more on their wage slaves.

But the U.S., which is a nation of Ideas, not of Races, should be arguing about the justice of this new enslavement, not about the ethnicity of our new immigrants.
	</body>
</document>
