<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003732" url="http://eric135.typepad.com/eric135/durango-jail/" time="2012-07-12-19:53" support="3" score="0.0024890130407188332" bingtitle="eric135: Durango Jail" webtitle="eric135: Durango Jail">
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000732" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>... width chair on each side (again, same as you&apos;d find at a fast food restaurant). On one side of the table is ... One morning they weren&apos;t calling out numbers (but didn&apos;t ...</description>
	<body>
		eric135 

... cogitating the possibilities by the sound of my own keystrokes ...
 
What am I doing?


 follow me on Twitter 
 About 
 
 Archives 
 
 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 August 2011 

 More... 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed 
April 24, 2009
 
 Free At Last 
 
Our friend has finally been released from Jail. The whole process was done logically and timely, and all parties were kept informed of when and where the release would take place   The whole process was FUBAR but we expected as much. We were told that, once the release was a&quot;go&quot;, the process would take anywhere from four to eight hours to go through.

Prisoners are not usually released from the Jail they are housed, but rather all releases happen at the Lower Buckeye Jail. The paperwork was on the judge&apos;s desk at 9am, our friend heard about his release at 3pm, and he finally walked out the door at 8pm.

There is an airconditioned lobby at the main entrance of the Lower Buckeye Jail, but prisoners are not released there. Instead, they are released on the East side of the building, where there is basically a cement slab with chairs where you can wait out in the elements for the prisoner to be released.

There were no updates about the specific timetable. We could not leave any money for him to use the pay phone. We just had to hang out. This entrance is also used for folks who are self-surrendering. It ain&apos;t pretty.

I had to miss a day of work, because there was no way to tell what time things would be done. Foolishly, I had hoped things would be over with by say 11am, but it took far longer.

But, at last, the whole jail experience is now over. I look forward, with relish, to erasing the Maricopa Superior Court parking, the 4th Ave Jail, the Durango Jail and the Lower Buckeye Jail from my Garmin Nuvi GPS. I also look forward to erasing all the Jail and Court information numbers from my cell phone.
 
 07:52 AM in Durango Jail | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 
 
April 14, 2009
 
 Visiting the Durango Jail, Maricopa County Arizona 
 
 

We went to visit our friend at Durango Jail yesterday. This was the first time I myself went back to visit, I&apos;ve been letting my roomie visit while I sat out in the waiting room or in the car. I just didn&apos;t want to go back there. Also, there is a sign on the window where you sign in and they take your driver&apos;s license and check to see if there are any Wants or Warrants out for you. For some reason, as ridiculous as it sounds, I had this strange anxiety that they&apos;d run my license and then I&apos;d get arrested. Then, I guess I could get a really up-close-and-personal exposure to the Maricopa Jail experience.

Of course, that didn&apos;t happen, I registered for my visit without any problems or surprise arrests.

So after all these weeks, I finally know what happens when you actually visit.

 When you visit, if you don&apos;t have someone that can hold your stuff for you, plan to leave everything in the car except for your car key, your ID and 2 quarters. You are called by name to the door, where you are reminded that you can&apos;t have on any belts, earings, jewelry, hair ties, bracelets, short pants (shorter than your lower thighs), etc. You also can&apos;t have any kind of jacket/sweater/coat with a hood or a zipper. No sleeveless shirts or shirts with plunging necklines. You are allowed to bring back one single key. Everything else has to be locked up in a locker or returned to your car. Once you are allowed past the door, you pass through a metal detector. Then you go back into a large room with, oh, about 40 tables (about the size as what you would see at a fast food restaurant). Each table has a double-width chair on each side (again, same as you&apos;d find at a fast food restaurant). On one side of the table is the prisoner, in striped black-and-white prison garb. His hands are handcuffed at the wrist and attached to the table. His ankles are also chained. Across the table is a 4-inch tall wood barrier. Prisoner and visitor(s) are not allowed to reach over the barrier. No touching, kissing, hugging, holding of children, passing of any items whatsoever from visitor to prisoner. Children can visit with the parent but they can&apos;t be running around the place, they have to remain seated and have to behave well enough to be in control during the visit. Even though the visits have been for 30 minutes, we notice the guards have let visits last as long as 45 minutes. At the end of the visit, a guard comes up and taps the table with his/her fingers and tells you&quot;time&apos;s up&quot;and you leave. 

Other interesting facts I learned about life in the jail:

 Durango Jail was originally built as a mental institution, and there is currently some litigation going on because the facility is filled with asbestos and lead paint. Prisoners are housed in&quot;pods&quot;with 16 prisoners per pod. There are no locked doors or bars separating the pods. Prisoners can walk around at their leisure but must be in their cots for&quot;body count&quot;for an hour each night. Guards (both male and female) walk around the pods every 12 minutes. To use the commissary, prisoners place an order for miscellaneous items on Sunday for the following week. Sodas are about $1.50, which I thought was pretty reasonable since I&apos;ve paid as much as $2.50 in high-priced hotels. However, sodas are warm and they don&apos;t have access to ice. There is a network where prisoners share their books that they&apos;ve bought from the commissary. There&apos;s no way for a prisoner to call a phone number without using a long distance per-minute account. So even if you have a local non-cellular land line, they can&apos;t call it without spending about 25 cents/minute. 
 
 08:39 AM in Durango Jail | Permalink | Comments (12) | TrackBack (0) 
 
April 08, 2009
 
 4th Ave Jail, Durango Jail, Maricopa Superior Court: A How-to Guide 
 
We&apos;ve had an awful lot of exposure to local law enforcement. To make an incredibly long and sorded story short, one of our friends is in jail, and we&apos;ve been dealing with the aftermath.

It has been an eye-opening experience. Generally, trying to keep up with someone who is incarcerated can be pretty dehumanizing and even scarey. We started off at the Scottsdale Jail (whose lobby looked like the lobby of a mid-priced hotel, with nice wood flooring, and plenty of brass fixtures and potted plants). But it turns out that prisoners are never kept at that jail, and are summarily transferred to the Maricopa County Jail.

 Basically, the Maricopa County Jail facility is, to be indelicate, a shit hole. Located on 4th Ave south of Madison, it is a four-square block of Hell transported on Earth. We didn&apos;t know the area well enough to find safe parking, and had to park on the street and feed quarters into the marking meter (which were inexplicably sticky and malfunctioned often).

This is not a happy place, and generally everyone there was pretty mad. We couldn&apos;t meet with our friend, and we ended up sitting in the waiting room (where all the seats were bolted into the cement floor, both bathrooms were out of order, and all of the deputies were behind bullet-proof glass) for almost 6 hours. For much of the time, I held a cap-less ball point pen in my fist to use as a weapon.

 After three days, our friend (who at this point we had yet to be able to visit) was transferred to the Durango Jail , located off Lower Buckeye Road in south Phoenix. This facility is not nearly as scarey as the 4th Ave Jail, and now that we have been there several times to visit, we&apos;ve gotten the hang of things and know where to go and where to park (they have a very nice free of charge gated parking deck across the street from the lobby). This place is more family oriented, and there were plenty of regular folks, and even the children were pretty safe.

Some thoughts:

 In the name of the Holy Lord Jesus Christ, you don&apos;t want to be arrested and you don&apos;t want to go to jail. We&apos;ve made excellent use of our Garmin Nuvi GPS. We&apos;ve driven to&quot;the nasty part of downtown&quot;several times now and it is almost old hat. The best place to park for the Jail is a parking deck located on 4th Ave just north of Madison but we never parked there. The best place to park for Maricopa County Superior Court Building  101 W Jefferson is a parking garage on the north side of Jefferson between 4th Ave and 3rd Ave . It&apos;s something like $2 per hour with a max of $12 per day. I&apos;m going to start parking here for my Jury Duties. It&apos;s a fairly close walk to the 4th Ave Jail. When you visit someone at the Jail, no one gives you any instructions, and there are very few signs. For some reason, they just assume you know what to do. 1) Go directly to the window and get a visitation form. 2) Go fill it out. If you don&apos;t have the prisoner&apos;s booking number, you have to call a number which leads to voicemail hell and it will totally mess you up so try to call before and get the booking number. Once filled out, wait for them to call the number they wrote at the bottom of the form. 3) Once your number is called, go up to the window where you will show your ID. If you are not a US citizen, you have to show an immigration ID. You will also have the opportunity to put cash into the prisoner&apos;s cash account. One morning they weren&apos;t calling out numbers (but didn&apos;t make an announcement) and it was assumed somehow that you would know to just bring the form to the window when you were done. 4) Wait until they call your name. You can only have your ID and a single key. Everything else must be locked up in a little locker that takes (I believe) 2 quarters, similar to the type of lockers they have at bus stations. You can&apos;t have any belts, any type of jacket/sweater/coat, no hair bands/clips/ties. Interestingly, if you allow your GPS to navigate a straight line from Paradise Valley to the Durango Jail, you go right through the center of downtwon Phoenix, now known to us as Shitsville. Your best move is to get to 35th Ave and head south until you get to Gibson where you can make a left, and the garage is on the left. I have really gotten to love Google Maps, especially the Street View. It&apos;s been very helpful being able to look up the address and then even get street views so I know what some building looks like from the street. I&apos;ve heard that Google Maps now downloads to Garmin Nuvi&apos;s but the street view gives the approximate street address for anything you find, so I can just enter that into the Nuvi and go. I&apos;m still getting over the fact that two of my Favorite Places on my GPS are&quot;Durango Jail&quot;and&quot;Maricopa Superior Court.&quot; 
 
 08:28 AM in 4th Ave Jail - Maricopa , Durango Jail , Maricopa Superior Court | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 
 
Search
 
Recent Comments
 
 Charlie on Converting DVDs to play on the Kindle Fire using Handbrake and DVD43... David on Converting DVDs to play on the Kindle Fire using Handbrake and DVD43... how to get rid of pimples on White Citrus Skin Care Products Karen on My boyhood home in Hopewell, VA, in Pen&amp;Wash;and Pastels... Karen on Extreme couponing... well not so extreme really... Eric135 on Converting DVDs to play on the Kindle Fire using Handbrake and DVD43... Tom on Converting DVDs to play on the Kindle Fire using Handbrake and DVD43... Flowers Online Melbourne on Orange flowers amanda on Visiting the Durango Jail, Maricopa County Arizona Karen on Converting DVDs to play on the Kindle Fire using Handbrake and DVD43... 
 
Recent Posts
 
 More on couponing... Some gave all; all gave some... Happy Memorial Day Extreme couponing... well not so extreme really... The Avengers America&apos;s Got Talent: I really liked Howard Stern! My boyhood home in Hopewell, VA, in Pen&amp;Wash;and Pastels... Bob Ross... ; Godshill... More painting Three tomatoes... Watercolor9 x 12 Farmer&apos;s Market... en pleine air... 
 
 Categories 
 
 4th Ave Jail - Maricopa Blackberry Blogs Books BoyKitty Christmas 2007 Christmas 2008 Christmas 2009 Christmas 2011 Couponing Current Affairs Daily Log Durango Jail DVD Eating out Film Fish Food and Drink Free Jean Watson Caring Theory Jury Duty Kindle Kindle Fire Kindle Keyboard LadyKitty Maricopa Superior Court Missy Movies Music Nursing Nursing collaboration pets Pictures podcasts Politics Product Review Productivity Restaurants Science Shopping Sketch Sports Stock Market Technology Television Travel Videos Watercolor Web/Tech Weblogs 
 
My Delicious List
 
 My Delicious List 
Click here for a list of blogs I read. From del.icio.us, a public space to store bookmarks...
	</body>
</document>
