<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003404" url="http://www.srmax.com/industries/fast-food-shoes" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="10" score="0.04922235721519575" bingtitle="Slip Resistant Fast Food Shoes - Food Service Shoes :: SR Max" webtitle="Slip Resistant Fast Food Shoes - Food Service Shoes :: SR Max">
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000682" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>... to reduce injuries from falling pans, dishes, trays ... to provide you with added safety in the work place. ... A corporate shoe program allows a fast food restaurant owner to ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Men&apos;s Footwear 
 Styles 
 Boots Clogs Dress Overshoes Oxford Slip-On Sneakers 
 Brands 
 Converse Crocs Dickies Dr. Martens FootHolds Genuine Grips Keen MEGAComfort New Balance Rockport Skechers SR MAX Timberland PRO Five Star 
 Features 
 Steel Toe Vegan Waterproof Wide Width 
 Closeout Styles 
 Women&apos;s Footwear 
 Styles 
 Boots Clogs Dress Overshoes Oxford Slip-On Sneakers 
 Brands 
 Converse Crocs Dickies Dr. Martens FootHolds Genuine Grips Keen MEGAComfort New Balance Skechers SR MAX Timberland PRO Five Star 
 Features 
 Steel Toe Vegan Waterproof Wide Width 
 Closeout Styles 
 Industries 
 Fast Food Grocery Stores Healthcare 
 Doctor Nursing 
 Hospitality 
 Hotel Casino 
 Manufacturing Restaurant 
 Chef Wait Staff 
 
 Corporate Programs 
 Benefits Profit Calculator Payroll Deduction Slip&amp;Fall Indemnity Shoemobile Start a Program 
 Education Center 
 Slip Resistant Testing Sizing and Fit Comfort Technologies Blog 
 Find a Store 
 Search 

 
 Questions? Call us today at 1.877.SRMAX33 
 
Shoe Finder
 Select Gender Men&apos;s Women&apos;s Select Brand Converse Crocs Dickies Dr. Martens FootHolds Genuine Grips Keen MEGAComfort New Balance Rockport Skechers SR MAX Timberland PRO Five Star Select Color Black Brown Other White Select Size L M M+ S S+ XL XS XXL XXS 03.0 03.5 04.0 04.5 05.0 05.5 06.0 6 TO 6.5 06.5 7 TO 7.5 07.0 07.5 08.0 8 TO 8.5 08.5 09.0 09.5 10.0 10.5 11.0 11.5 12.0 12.5 13.0 14.0 15.0 16.0 More Info Click Here 
Fast Food Shoes
 
Most fast food employees are aware of the unique dangers their particular work environment presents, but most don’t know the benefits that wearing quality slip resistant shoes can provide.

Wearing a good pair of slip resistant fast food shoes can reduce the chances of slip and fall accidents caused by spilled water, dropped food, greasy or slippery kitchen floors and many other fast food hazards.

Benefits for Fast Food Workers

New evolutions in fast food shoes provide numerous benefits to fast food workers:

 Great styles from well known name brands. Supportive, comfortable shoes designed for those who are on their feet all day. Durable uppers designed to withstand spills and wear associated with working in a fast food restaurant. Up to size 16 shoes in wide and extra wide styles for those with larger feet. Steel toe and composite toe options to reduce injuries from falling pans, dishes, trays, cutlery and so on. 

SR Max offers a large selection of shoe styles and colors from the brands you know like Skechers, Crocs, Converse, New Balance and more. Our own line of SR Max brand shoes feature the industry leading outsole technology to provide you with added safety in the work place.

Looking to buy slip resistant shoes? Browse our selection of slip resistant shoes for men and slip resistant shoes for women today.
 
Benefits for Fast Food Owners / Managers

Eliminating workplace accidents in a fast food restaurant is important for employees, managers and fast food owners alike. Slip and fall accidents can cost thousands of dollars in medical costs, loss of income, rising insurance premiums and even legal fees. Wearing the right type of slip resistant shoes can reduce the occurrence of slip and fall accidents and save fast food franchises money.

A great way for fast food managers and owners to reduce slip and fall accidents is to implement a slip resistant shoe program with SR Max Slip Resistant Shoe Company. A corporate shoe program allows a fast food restaurant owner to provide their employees with easy access to quality slip resistant shoes designed specifically for the hazards the fast food environment presents. Learn more about our corporate safety shoe programs and how they can benefit your company today.

 Contact us today for more information and to see how we can help your reduce slip and fall workplace accidents.
 
Connect With Us
 
 About Us Brands Meet Our Team Testimonials 

 Contact Us Catalog Request Start a Program Quick Order 

 Our Policies Disclaimer Payment Privacy Returns Shipping 
 
 
 
©2012 SR Max, all rights reserved. Site Map
	</body>
</document>
