<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003958" url="http://www.eatright.org/Public/content.aspx?id=6442464588" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="3" score="0.015964768564082275" bingtitle="Simple Tips to Eat Healthy Away from Home - From the Academy" webtitle="Simple Tips to Eat Healthy Away from Home - From the Academy">
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001025" bing-rank="138"/>
	<description>Order one appetizer for the whole table and then ... Start with a small serving like a cup of soup, a ... your inner child: Order a kid&apos;s meal at a fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		The world&apos;s largest organization of food and nutrition professionals. Formerly 
 the American Dietetic Association 
 Site HTML Documents Images Multimedia Forums Tags 
 
 Advanced Search | View Top Searches Home | About Us | Site 
 Map | Shopping Cart 
 
Your Food and Nutrition Source

It&apos;s About Eating Right
 Home &gt; Public 
 
 
 In This Section 
   Popular Diet Reviews 
 Cinch! Conquer Cravings, Drop Pounds and Lose Inches 
Written by Cynthia Sass, MPH, RD; Reviewed by Judy Caplan, MS, RD The Dukan Diet 
Written by Dr. Pierre Dukan; Reviewed by Karen Ansel, MS, RD, CDN Full: A Life without Dieting 
Written by Michael A. Snyder, MD, FACS; Reviewed by Jessica Crandall RD, CDE 
 More Diet Reviews » Tip of the Day 




 View Entire Text 
 
 More Tips: 
 
 Tip of the Day Index 
 Question of the Day 




 View Entire Text 
 
 More Questions: 
 
 Question of the Day Index 
 Featured Product 
Special Feature
 
 Professional Skills Review - Save 10% in July 

This new online tool includes best practices, the nutrition care process, current research articles and professional content, plus more than 650 multiple choice questions to help you assess your professional competence.
 
 2009 FNCE Call for Abstracts Title Appears Here and Could be This Length Posters and original contributions now open! Additional text may appear here, approximately this long in length... 
 
Tip of the Day

Healthy Eating On the Go

While eating away from home can be challenging, simple tips can help you eat right while enjoying every bite!

Becoming sensible about serving sizes is an important way to maintain a healthy weight—and it&apos;s good for your wallet too:

 Instead of a large entrée, order an appetizer and a leafy green salad or choose two appetizers for a meal. Share an entrée. You can ask your server to split the meal in the kitchen or divide it up yourselves at the table. Ask for a to-go box as soon as your meal is served. Put half your food into the container for a second meal. That&apos;s two meals for the price of one! Savor your steak twice. Eat half at the restaurant and take the other half home to enjoy sliced onto a green salad or in a sandwich on whole-grain bread. Share from start to finish. Order one appetizer for the whole table and then order one dessert with multiple forks. Sometimes, just a bite or two is perfect. Start with a small serving like a cup of soup, a junior burger or a small order of fries. If you are still hungry, order something else. Indulge your inner child: Order a kid&apos;s meal at a fast-food restaurant. Many now offer a choice of low-fat milk and fruits or vegetables instead of fries. 

For more tips on eating healthy while away from home, consult a registered dietitian in your area and visit the Eating Out section on www.eatright.org. For tips on keeping your leftovers safe, visit www.homefoodsafety.org&apos;s Leftover Safety information.

 Receive the Tip of the Day RSS Feed! 
 

 
 
 
 
QUICK LINKS

 Join Academy Shop Tip of the Day KidsEatright FNCE Food&amp;Nutrition Magazine Journal of the Academy 
 The Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics Foundation is the world&apos;s largest charitable organization (501c3) focused on food, nutrition and dietetics. Academy Foundation is dedicated to working with the Registered Dietitian to help kids and their families eat right. Participate 
 in the only political action committee broadly focused on food, nutrition and 
 health. If dietetics is your profession, politics is your business! Through accreditation of more than 600 undergraduate and graduate didactic, dietetic technician and supervised practice programs, the Accreditation Council for Education in Nutrition and Dietetics ensures entry-level education meets quality standards. The 
 Commission on Dietetic Registration awards credentials to individuals at entry 
 and specialty levels who have met CDR&apos;s standards for competency to practice in 
 the dietetics profession. 

   Visit site   |   Make 
 a donation Visit site   |   Make 
 a donation Visit site Visit site 

 
Copyright © 1995-2012 | Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics, All Rights Reserved. Privacy Statement | Terms and Conditions | Site Map | Advertising&amp;Sponsorship | Careers | Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
