<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003638" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/crab-house-seafood-restaurant-edgewater" time="2012-07-12-19:48" support="1" score="0.0018317734840600129" bingtitle="Crab House Seafood Restaurant - Edgewater, NJ" webtitle="Crab House Seafood Restaurant - Edgewater, NJ">
			<query id="001082" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>This restaurant definitely has great views of the city and ... management train their servers anymore on what utensils ... the balls to come by to drop off the check and collect ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Crab House Seafood Restaurant
 70 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Seafood Seafood   [Edit] 
 541 River Rd 
 Edgewater , NJ 07020 
 (201) 840-9311 http://www.crabhouseseafood.com/ Menu 
 
 Add Photos Price Range: $$$ 
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Takes Reservations: Yes
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: Yes
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: No
 Good For: Dinner
 Alcohol: Full Bar
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: Yes
 Caters: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: No
 First to Review Edward I. 
 Edit Business Info Work Here? Unlock This Business Page 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
70 reviews for Crab House Seafood Restaurant
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;Amazing view of NYC .&quot; In 4 reviews &quot;2) 1/2 dozen East Coast Oysters .&quot; In 7 reviews &quot;The view of upper Manhattan with the river park and all of...&quot; In 11 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
70 reviews in English

 
Review from Melanie P. 
 
 1 friend 2 reviews 

 Melanie P. 
 
Union County, NJ
 2/15/2012 
We love going out to dinner and trying new seafood restaurants. Hubby made reservations for V day at 8:00 p.m.

We typically go to Chart House for Vday (they are extremely organized) but we decided to try a new place.

The only negative aspect of the night was the customer service from the hostess&apos; upon arrival we were told they were a little backed up but that it would only be a 20 min wait... she took my name down and said she had me and would call my name out because they ran out of buzzards.
we are pretty understanding and understood it was busy. after all whats 20 minutes? I followed up after about 25 minuted to be sure she didn&apos;t forget me. she assured me she had me... 15 more minutes pass and this time my husband decided to follow up since a total of 40 minutes had passed. she told him we were next. Unfortunately all the young ladies in the front are not on the same page. they sat 4 more couples. at that point I was really frustrated. I approached the hostess and asked if she had any idea when we would be seated, she said we were NEXT lol so I said you said that 4 dinner parties ago! so she said OK I&apos;LL SIT YOU NOW! (58 minute wait with reservations)

I was confused and relieved... How is it all of the sudden she could just sit me? As we walked to get seated she made a very distasteful comment. I was appalled!!! How dare she ruin our Valentines day??? She has very poor customer service skills and no class...

I immediately approached the manager who apologized and handled the situation smoothly. Our waiter was amazing! very tentative. and the food was delicious. LOVED the lobster bisque... and the stuffed shrimp was really good.

this is a scenario that was properly turned around. hopefully the young lady re visits her training. As far as the restaurant we loved the food!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brian U. 
 
 2 friends 62 reviews 

 Brian U. 
 
Forest Hills, NY
 6/19/2012 
My folks still live in NJ but I&apos;ve been living in NY for some time.  We seem to have 4 or 5 common restaurants we go to in NJ for lunch and this was one of them.

We were here over the weekend. This place starts and ends with the view, which admittedly is very pretty.

The food itself is exceedingly average, considering the price point.

The service leaves something to be desired.  We had a party of ten and 2 of us arrived early.  We were waiting for our parents and extended family and wished to be seated so we can begin ordering appetizers for the family to not waste any time and once they arrived (which wound up being a few, short minutes later) they&apos;d quickly be served food.  The woman at the front instructed me that she couldn&apos;t seat us until the entire party was there.  I reluctantly agreed but when we were eventually seated, the place was half-empty with nobody waiting!  Rules for the sake of rules are utterly ridiculous.  The woman who eventually seated us was pleasant.

Then we waited for ten minutes until someone finally greeted us at our table and asked us for drink orders.  TEN. MINUTES.  In a half-empty restaurant.  But wait!  Before she left to get our drinks, our waitress spent some good amount of time educating us on some ridiculous points/cash-back card that has some annual(?) fee.  I graciously listened while she finished her speech, but starting off our dining experience with this sales pitch was ultimately tacky and lacking class.

The food came and went (nothing worth describing) and before we received our bill the waitress kindly asked us if we considered the points card to which I replied we were not.  She then continued to ask if we&apos;re sure, beginning to list reasons why to sign up and I had to interrupt her to thank her but we weren&apos;t interested and she kind of stormed off.  She also asked for the brochure back, which is weird because it was sitting on a table, wet from drinks, probably splashed by seafood/shellfish.  It made me wonder if she was going to give that to another customer and how many times that same brochure was distributed (gross!).

I don&apos;t know why they don&apos;t advertise this card in the lobby or just give you one in the beginning and also with the bill.  This would be far less intrusive and obnoxious.

I think it&apos;s time we crossed this place off our list of usual restaurants.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Meghan M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 127 friends 768 reviews 

 Meghan M. 
 
New York, NY
 3/20/2012 
Here&apos;s the skinny:
* Awesome view
* Good crab cake and stuffed crab; tasty coconut shrimp, minus the big dollops of marmalade on each one
* Craaaaazy expensive (over $70 for lunch...one salad, two entrees, two non-alcoholic drinks)
* Got my order wrong (resulting in me eating my entree after the other one was completely finished)
* Good happy hour menu which may or may not be available outside

Would I come back? Maybe for appetizers and a drink out on the patio to admire the view but like others on here have mentioned, that&apos;s pretty much the highlight of what you&apos;ll get here.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Carmela D. 
 
 0 friends 4 reviews 

 Carmela D. 
 
Glen Rock, NJ
 7/12/2012 
We were finally seated at 8:00 pm with a 7:30 reservation. The hostess sat 3 other parties before us, and only one of those parties was there before us. We asked her why we weren&apos;t seated, and she said we would be next and it will only be a minute longer, but we obviously weren&apos;t.
we ordered the crab stack salad and the scallops dynomite, which were both very good. I ordered the grilled salmon with a beurre blanc sauce, which was obviously grilled right after a hamburger was grilled, and i do not eat meat.  The sauce was more like plain melted butter.  I barely ate it. We also ordered the fried platter, which was ok. And we also ordered a side of dungeness crab. It was obviously steamed much earlier in the day, because it was completely dry and barely lukewarm.
we were seriously dissapointed in the place and we will definitely not be returning.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Frank B. 
 
 13 friends 50 reviews 

 Frank B. 
 
Fair Lawn, NJ
 6/11/2012 2 photos 1 Check-in Here 
Visited this place twice and the food was excellent both times. They did overlook the first order of crab legs and crab orzo but they fixed it quickly. Raw oysters are amazing. The drinks are very well priced for the area but the food is expensive for the quality. Still worth the trip.
Excellent view of NY city
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joy K. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Joy K. 
 
Bergen County, NJ
 6/18/2012 
I&apos;m really not a person who complains or gives staff at any business a hard time...knowing how difficult it is to be working at any customer service oriented business. However, Crabhouse absolutely blew my mind and I could not ignore their unprofessional, rude demeanor.

I made reservations for my family, a party of 5, for 6pm. We arrived around 5:50 and waited around. As soon as we walked in, we were not greeted by the hostesses (3 of them) who were chatting away. I had to wait for them to finish their conversation which was irrelevant to anything work related. I finally told them that we had a reservation for a party of 5 and they said they would call us when our table was ready.

It was nearing 6:30 and I politely asked one of the hostesses at the stand when our table would be cleared and again let her know that I made a 6 oclock reservation. She said all the reservations were backed up so they would call us when our table was ready. About fifteen mins later I realized that most of the parties were seated, even ones who came in after us. So I asked them about our table again and the hostess apparently mixed my family up with another Asian group who had a party of 11. We didn&apos;t get a single apology. In fact, they made it seem like they didn&apos;t take the fault for it at all. They also did not accomodate us with a table even after this...I was extremely agitated at this point but let it go.

For the entire time we were waiting, an older blonde hostess with a bad attitude, continued to walk from the dining room back to the front of the restaurant and said the same thing every time...&quot;Your table is being cleaned&quot; Really, it takes 45 minutes to clean off a table? She did not apologize for the delay..not once. She did however, continue with defensive remarks. The worst part was that she continued to roll her eyes. You treat people with respect to get respect, so after this point I was no longer saying my please and thank yous.

About an hour into waiting (which was ridiculous especially because it was not even that busy, I had reservations, and apparently the wait for those without a reservation was an hour...so what was the point of making a reservation if I had to wait just as long) I overheard another party of 5 who just walked in, say that they did not have a reservation. Five minutes later, that party was seated. When I confronted the hostesses about the situation, they said the party must have had reservations. This is when my family walked out. When my dad finally told the older blonde hostess with the horrible attitude that we will not be eating here she snapped at us with an &quot;Ok, fine&quot;, then walked away with another hostess ranting about us...even before we walked out of the restaurant

I regret not complaining to the manager but we were all so angry and frustrated at the moment that we had to walk out. Now, here I am writing this review to warn everyone about the staff at The Crabhouse.

I have never in my life been treated with such disrespect at a restaurant. The hostesses here all have HORRIBLE attitudes. (especially the older blonde woman) I really don&apos;t understand how this restaurant still gets business with its dysfunctional staff.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ana P. 
 
 0 friends 1 review 

 Ana P. 
 
Cliffside Park, NJ
 6/30/2012 
The Crab House is really not half as bad as some of the reviews describe it. I&apos;ve eaten at this restaurant a few times and truly consider it as one of the most pleasant restaurants in the North New Jersey area. The seafood&apos;s amazing (and not to mention the appetizers and desserts!) and the view doesn&apos;t get any better. The restaurant environment is both lively, classy and welcoming. I usually don&apos;t write reviews, but after seeing negative comments about this restaurant I felt that it would be a pity to let people be scared away by such a nice place for absolutely no reason.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kelly F. 
 
 1 friend 10 reviews 

 Kelly F. 
 
Cliffside Park, NJ
 6/28/2012 
If I could give this location less than one star I could, but Yelp does not allow. I actually had an event here and boy did I regret every penny that was spent. Unfortunately my mother had booked and made a deposit to have her 50th birthday here before I even saw the location. She was mesmerized by the views of NYC, which I can agree are beautiful, but the only attraction to this place. To start off, the price per person for the event we had was about $42(thats including the the taxes and tip). Now the space that they have for events has a beautiful view of the skyline but other than that it sucks. Its on the second floor, but the room is open and you can hear the restaurant below and visa versa. Because of this, we could not have a DJ or play loud music. For the banquet price that I payed, i could have had my event at the Chart House in Weehawken, which is much more accomadating, similar in pricing, and more privacy, which is what is expected for the price i was paying. throughout the planning of the event, the person we dealt with, Elsa, seemed somewhat nice. I had gotten somewhat annoyed when I had asked if I could go and decorate the night before and another banquet person, Amy, said it was fine. Later on when I had spoken to Elsa, she had an attitude about it and told me that I should have informed her. Sorry I was not aware that your staff does not communicate with eachother! This really pissed me off. There are nicer ways of stating things. The day of the event, Elsa seemed to be in a good mood and was attentive with the set up. But during the event she had a scowling face in the corner. Im not sure if it was because we had some people singing for my mother or because of our radio, which was playing music, since we could not have DJ. Her stupid scowling face made for an uncomfortable evening. She even had come up to us to turn down the music because it could be heard from downstairs, and when we had gone downstairs you could not hear anything besides the crowd. Besides Elsa, although the waiters were nice at the beginning, they were absolutely horrible. The plan I had purchased included coffee, soda, and tea. I only had gotten one cup of soda becuase the waiter was nowhere to be found or would ignore us at our table. Even my mother, the birthday girl, was ignored when she asked for coffee to drink with her cake. I had to stand up and go get the waiter to get her coffee and even when i asked he looked at me like I had two heads. The food, was absolutely horrible. I had ordered the steak, and it tasted like cardboard and the salad had no flavor. All in All, i absolutely hate this place and am still kicking myself for spending any money at this location. I advise people to stay away from this place like the plague and spend your money elsewhere. I could only wish that not a single person support them by spending money there and for them to go out of business. I know this sounds harsh, but I had such a horrible experience with them.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mike M. 
 
 0 friends 25 reviews 

 Mike M. 
 
Bronx, NY
 5/20/2012 
As far as seafood goes, CH has decent food. Nothing spectacular. Food&apos;s good and so is the service, usually. What makes CH good is where it&apos;s located. Scenery is fantastic. After your done eating, you can stop by a multitude of shops, grocery store, liquor store.... you get the point. Not to mention walking on the River Walk. Nice and relaxing. Keep walking south past the apartments and condos, past the movie theatre and you come upon City Place. They also have a couple of restaurants at City Place. Trust me, it&apos;s better to leave your car parked @ Edgewater Commons and walk. Traffic on River Road on Saturdays is a huge headache.

Our target is Haagen Dazs. Great ice cream there.

CH is worth at least 1 visit. Before you know it, you&apos;ll be back again to enjoy eating, walking and relaxing.

Try not to get smashed at the bar there by Staples. Too much going on car wise. Not to mention cops. Not much for them to do but monitor traffic and the parking lot.  It is Edgewater we&apos;re talkin about here. Not a whole lot to do but eat and hang out. Gets a little nuts at night with the hot rodders and sports bikes by Starbucks.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Restaurant T. 
 
 0 friends 1 review 

 Restaurant T. 
 
Alpine, NJ
 6/22/2012 
We went there specifically for the crabs. Ordered king crabs, dungeness, and some shrimp. You could tell right away the crab meat was not fresh and seemed as if it was kept in the freezer for 2 months and then reheated and served to us. The taste was stale and dry. Even the butter they gave seemed more like oil with no taste whatsoever. For a place that calls itself the crab house, it certainly did not live up to expectation.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Henry E. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 17 friends 60 reviews 

 Henry E. 
 
Fairview, NJ
 4/23/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
CRABHOUSE isnt half as bad as the reviews below have mentioned...  Really the only gripe I have is that the sourdough bread they bring out isn&apos;t/wasn&apos;t warm... But there is no question that the QUALITY of food that is served is great, and it tastes great... If you happen to come on a nice day sitting outside on the deck is a treat on its own... I love this place I&apos;ve been coming here for years and it&apos;s been great
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jeong K. 
 
 15 friends 78 reviews 

 Jeong K. 
 
Butler, NJ
 2/9/2012 
Theres a reason for rating this a 3 star....

If you&apos;re down for food, I wouldn&apos;t recommend this place as much however; I&apos;ve learned from my mistakes.
I would recommend coming to this place only when the weather is nice outside so that you can enjoy sitting on the deck (in the back).  Please only order several appetizers and get your drink on.

I only recommend this place for lounging with cocktails and small eats on the deck.

Food: 2 star
My recommendation list (above): 3.5 star
Avg: 2.75 -- round up to 3

Wow, the math is perfect!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nick B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 11 friends 151 reviews 

 Nick B. 
 
Middle Village, NY
 1/14/2012 1 Check-in Here 
While I will let others speak of the food and restaurant, I came in for a quick drink and was fascinated by the ambiance.

To compliment the friendly services are  hours of viewing and reading the walls of the bar.  Now, if you have zero interest in boxing, you will be bored.  However, if the topic of boxing interests you somewhat, then it is worth the trip to this farthest part of western Queens.  The primary sources of history lining the walls will bring the boxing fan back to the golden ages of the sport.

Enjoy your beer and stay for a few rounds.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Dee B. 
 
 65 friends 325 reviews 

 Dee B. 
 
New York, NY
 12/4/2011 
As for the views, this place sits right on the river with unobstructed views of Manhattan. Views like that from the Manhattan side would cost you big time. I went one Saturday afternoon for lunch. The clam chowder was disappointing; Tasted like something I would open out of a can at home with no seasoning. The crab and shrimp salad wasn&apos;t much better; Too much iceberg lettuce, shrimp looked like they had been precooked and thawed to serve (resulting in a tough texture). The toast was hard and cold. My glass of Malbec was warm and tasted like it had been sitting around in an open bottle (stale).

I understand the river is teeming with Striped Sea Bass (there is a fishing pier right behind the restaurant and the fishermen back there were pulling in some nice catch!) so I might revisit for the nighttime view and some fresh striped bass!  I hope to add more stars on my next visit. Service was decent. It was early in the day and I sat in the bar area so it wasn&apos;t very busy. I will give me another chance next time I have visitors from out of town.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Courtney M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 96 friends 149 reviews 

 Courtney M. 
 
Jersey City, NJ
 12/5/2011 
Came here on a Friday night after work for a nice dinner to help combat a stressful day. The view of NYC is fantastic, but I don&apos;t go to restaurants for the views.

The food was awesome -- we ordered crab stuffed mushrooms to start, cooked perfectly and with an interesting remoulade sauce. For dinner, we split the Baltimore platter and the shellfish steamer. The Baltimore platter was fried shrimp, fried fish (fish&amp;chips style), stuffed crab, crab cake and fries. everything was cooked well, and nothing was overly fried. All the seafood tasted fresh and of good quality. The steamer was mussels, clams, shrimp, sausage, corn&amp;potatoes -- all was good, but my feeling was that they should have listed that the shrimp were eat&amp;peel (I HATE PEELING SHRIMP!!!), and also the mussels were a bit small. Not bad tasting, just teeny tiny. The clams, on the other hand, were huge!

We split the bread pudding for dessert -- holy crap. So rich and filling! Service was great too -- very attentive.

I&apos;d definitely come back to try some more things on the menu! Really good quality seafood :)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brian N. 
 
 480 friends 158 reviews 

 Brian N. 
 
Montclair, NJ
 8/16/2011 2 photos 
So, it was my first evening out with this amazing (looking and otherwise) girl I had just met 16 hours earlier. Being it had been an unexpected day of releasing much pent-up energy since the wee hours of meeting in the morn (blame it on the full moon,) it was good to get out and get some fresh air and much needed rejuvenation of good food. So we crossed the GWB to dip our toes into Edgewater for a spot she enjoys, yet I had never been.

There seemed to be a good number of people waiting for seating, but for some reason we didn&apos;t have to wait at all. Maybe it was because it was just the two of us. Maybe it was because we looked so good together...and tired...and in need of nourishing replenishment...

We were seated upstairs right next to the window (which I highly recommend.) After taking pictures of the view, and each other (I know, I know, but what do you want? It was the wrap up to our first date,) we ordered a couple glasses of wine, and decided on what to eat:

Appetizer:
crab&amp;shrimp stuffed mushrooms, baked with parmesan in a white wine sauce. (bangin!)

Her Entree: &quot;Shrimp Madrid&quot;
sauteed shrimp with asparagus, tomatoes and spinach in a garlic butter, tossed with angel hair pasta. (pretty tasty.)

My Entree: &quot;Snapper Milanese&quot;
parmesan crusted snapper topped with jumbo lump crab in lemon butter sauce, served with asparagus and a tasty vegetable/rice combination. (bigiddy-bangin! word is bond, son!)

The bread they had brought out beforehand was excellent as well. or maybe it was our famishedness...

It&apos;s just now dawning on me that we didn&apos;t get dessert. WTF? I ALWAYS get dessert! I was stuffed though. We both were. And really, the service was pretty slow. And we were ready to get out of there, nahmean? Dessert was waiting at the crib...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (8) Funny (6) Cool (7) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Andy P. 
 
 1 friend 44 reviews 

 Andy P. 
 
Edgewater, NJ
 3/12/2012 
Go out of business already. This place is a sad excuse of a restaurant and their staff has a horrible attitude. food is overpriced, bad value.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jade V. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 44 friends 147 reviews 

 Jade V. 
 
Philadelphia, PA
 8/23/2011 1 Check-in Here 
The view is one of the most valuable assets this place has in terms of ambiance. It was even a ~*~dark and stormy night~*~ and everyone was commenting on how cool the lightning looked.

Not sure what other Yelpers are talking about with food coming to the tables cold or inattentive waiters. We had a party of seven and everyone&apos;s food was fresh. The only thing, though, it took so long for the people who ordered the steamers to eat because of opening the crab and peeling shrimp compared to the people who ordered knife-and-fork dishes. I recommend that everyone in the party coordinates what they want when they order, otherwise you might have a bunch of bored people sitting around talking while others (...like myself) voraciously attempt to quickly finish their pots of shellfish.

Besides the entrees, I loved the oysters from the raw bar. Considering how large our party was, I&apos;d say that the food came out at a reasonable pace. They have a full bar, too, and the wine selection is pretty good. The whole place is clean, down to the bathrooms. If you&apos;re with one other person, I&apos;d imagine it feels pretty intimate. The dim lights and the view make for a slightly upscale, but not overly pompous atmosphere. Coupled with a great selection of quality seafood, I&apos;d say you&apos;re in for a solid experience.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jessica K. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 11 friends 234 reviews 

 Jessica K. 
 
Hillsdale, NJ
 7/20/2011 
Quite an excellent view from almost every seat in the house, including the bar. While the food is nothing exceptional, it&apos;s hardly poor fare. My personal fave&amp;recommendation for lunch: the fried seafood platter. It&apos;s deliciously unhealthy and artery clogging.

The place isn&apos;t known for their prompt service, but it&apos;s friendly&amp;attentive enough, all my orders have always come out correctly. Waiting to get seated tends to be a problem, but if you have reservations your patience won&apos;t run out.

While the location&amp;outdoor scene is ideal, the restaurant itself is much more casual than it would probably care to admit. It&apos;s like an Applebee&apos;s for seafood, nothing special or outstanding, but hits the spot when you need it.
 
 Listed in: Les Poissons 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Luca T. 
 
 2 friends 183 reviews 

 Luca T. 
 
West New York, NJ
 7/24/2011 
Food not so special, sometimes cold when it arrives to the table.
Not very expensive
Great Mango crab appetizer and chocolate lava cake.

Very great view
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Holly C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 133 friends 508 reviews 

 Holly C. 
 
New York, NY
 6/2/2011 1 Check-in Here 
2.5 stars

Started the night with mango sangria which was good - not too weak nor strong. Our server was nice but was MIA half the time (and forgot our order of salad).

They bring out sourdough bread which was nothing noteworthy.
They&apos;re located right on the water so that alone sets a nice atmosphere. The restaurant itself is very simple and casual.

Appetizers:
1) Calamari: Meh. I&apos;ve had better.
2) Spring rolls were okay.

Entrees:
1) Maryland Crab Vegetable Soup: it was good but rather small for the price.
2) 1/2 dozen East Coast Oysters. One was blue point which is an oyster I like, and I forgot what the other one was. You can&apos;t mess up this order too much?
3) Lobster tail: overcooked

Overall was a mediocre experience. I would come here for their Crab House Feast - a big bucket of seafood. I&apos;ve had it in the past, and it&apos;s fun to eat with a friend if you&apos;re in the mood for seafood.
 
 Listed in: Restaurants (NJ) 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Lauren F. 
 
 15 friends 40 reviews 

 Lauren F. 
 
Cresskill, NJ
 5/7/2011 
Such a disappointment.

Service was extremely slow. I didn&apos;t have enough confidence in the place to actually order seafood, and I&apos;m glad that I didn&apos;t. I tried someone else&apos;s Calamari appetizer. The squid tasted fishy and was so overcooked that it was dry and shriveled. On the same platter, were various deep fried fruits and vegetables. What I thought was a fried yellow squash turned out to be a fried slice of lemon complete with the seeds and rind. : /

My meal was the Southwest Chicken Sandwich; grilled chicken, avocado and bacon on a ciabatta roll. It tasted fine, however when it was served to me, I was informed that the prep cook forgot to put lettuce and tomato on the sandwich. The same explanation was also given to another patron at our table who ordered the Crab Cake Sandwich. Not a big deal but it didn&apos;t help improve my impression of the place.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Stella Y. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 116 friends 331 reviews 

 Stella Y. 
 
New York, NY
 12/30/2010 
This place was disappointing! I live in the area and had been looking to stop by for some time. I recently went for an impromptu dinner and was thoroughly unimpressed.

To start, while the service is very genuine and friendly, it&apos;s not great. The wait for everything takes a while. I went on a weeknight, and there weren&apos;t too many parties there, however, service was simply slow. It took forever to get some water.

They start you off with a loaf of bread and butter which was delicious -  until we cut through to the center and realized that the bread was still frozen inside. I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve ever experienced that before. We kindly told the waitress about the bread and she was apologetic, but we didn&apos;t ask for another loaf.

We ordered a steak and the Snapper Milanese (topped with jumbo lump crab and a lemon butter sauce). Both were tasteless to mediocre. The steak was bland and rubbery. We first tried it without any sauce but was unimpressed with the meat that we decided to douse it in A1. The snapper was heavily breaded for fish. I asked for the butter sauce on the side, but they forgot to bring it out, and I didn&apos;t want to wait around for it so I just ate it. The fish was very bland and soggy, with way too much breading. The sides were bland as well...

Overall, nothing stood out. Oh, except the fish tacos! Those were pretty good - I do recommend the fish tacos, and I would probably stick to just apps and drinks if I ever revisit this place again.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kitty C. 
 
 14 friends 48 reviews 

 Kitty C. 
 
Oakland Gardens, NY
 4/19/2011 
Location is pretty important I guess. This place is right across the city, just a river away. When you dine here at night, the views are gorgeous (especially during the summertime).

Obviously, by all the other reviews you can tell that it&apos;s not the best seafood/crab house out there but it&apos;s worth a try. The service isn&apos;t too great and the food is just alright but HEY you got a pretty view going on!!!

Make sure to check the weather before you make reservations. It&apos;s not worth going at all if it&apos;s foggy out because it defeats your whole purpose of dining here! Enjoy
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alex A. 
 
 18 friends 4 reviews 

 Alex A. 
 
North Bergen, NJ
 11/17/2011 2 Check-ins Here 
Nobilo Sauvignon Blanc, a dozen Blue Point oysters, Crab House Feast, King Crab add-on, finished off with a chocolate truffle cake. The lady and I called it a night after that. Good seafood dinner as always. No bib though? Moist towelettes for our hands? Smile and genuine hospitality from our server? Tsk tsk. Hence, the 3 stars.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Patty T. 
 
 83 friends 194 reviews 

 Patty T. 
 
New York, NY
 5/18/2010 
I had past this place a dozen times and didn&apos;t think much of it.  Based on the reviews I wasn&apos;t expecting much either.  But I am a totally sucker fro any outdoor outside dining area.  Bonus that this one is right on the water with a NYC view.

The food isn&apos;t really anything but if you go for soup, crabs and drinks you are golden.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Lina K. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 94 friends 176 reviews 

 Lina K. 
 
Edgewater, NJ
 2/11/2008 
This restaurant definitely has great views of the city and is a popular spot, as is evidenced by the always full parking lot.  The bar is also a big hit for the locals, at one point, myself included.  So, my review is primarily for the happy hour, which I was surprised to see ran from noon to 7PM.  That&apos;s a lot of drinking time!  My friend and I were big fans of the Bloody Mary (garnished with shrimp) and the half priced martinis (I was in such a green appletini phase back then!).  I think they were $2.75 or $3.00 ... talk about VALUE!.

The bar food was very good and super economical:  chicken wings, clams rockefeller, shrimp cocktail and the like were all very tasty.  I think all bar specials during happy hour were $2.99 for each portion (6).    They also feature an AYCE seafood bar with king crab legs, shrimp, various other seafood ... but I have never tried it.  I have had the crabcakes which were average.

All in all, the Crab House can be a good value and I have heard from friends, that this is a good place for kids.  Don&apos;t come here looking for extraordinary seafood as this is a chain after all.  But then again, I don&apos;t like Legal Seafood either and many people swear by that chain.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kendra T. 
 
 62 friends 179 reviews 

 Kendra T. 
 
Jersey City, NJ
 9/17/2010 
Came here with a date and was impressed by the views. Unfortunately it was too cold to sit outside but I was happy with our window seat.

The drinks were good and pretty potent. I opted for fried shrimp and fries which I crave once in a blue moon so it was nothing of a culinary stand out but it satisfied my craving.

My date had... well who cares because we are not seeing each other any more.

It is best to try to get to this place a little later in the evening to miss the crowds and the wait.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kate C. 
 
 18 friends 161 reviews 

 Kate C. 
 
New York, NY
 7/11/2008 
I&apos;ve always liked going here when I was younger for a nice big crab dinner and great view of the bridge and Manhattan... While that&apos;s been replaced by other places for me now, I stopped by the Crab House before a movie to check out their happy hour, and was really well impressed.

All appetizers are half off, as are the drinks. That means beers for $3, flavored martinis for $4, well drinks for $4. It was all a really great deal.

The food was pretty good - calamari was standard, the crab dip was nice and a generous portion, the coconut shrimp was tasty though there were only 4, and the oysters on the halfshell were the only disappointment in that they were way too salty and tasted as if maybe they weren&apos;t cleaned with the utmost of care.

Overall, I got a couple of drinks and stuffed with food for $20, so that is enough for a good review and a return visit from me.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tim R. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 200 friends 679 reviews 

 Tim R. 
 
Chicago, IL
 1/12/2009 
A platter which sounded good on the menu was disappointing: gritty stuffed crab, greasy, floppy battered fish, funky tasting shrimp (tasted like they were fried in really dirty oil), and a fishcake which combined all the unpleasant qualities of the previous items (to recap: gritty, greasy, floppy, and funky-tasting). The dungeness crab was nothing special, the bread was sourdough at its chewiest (seemed like another 10 mins baking time may have helped), and two small glasses of different unpleasant wines were over $7 each.

In its partial defense, we did visit the Crab House at 3pm on a Saturday, and were one of three groups in the large space. Still, if you can&apos;t keep food standards up all day, don&apos;t stay open all day. The view of Manhattan would be amazing on a clear day. Service was attentive, if a little creepy. Wouldn&apos;t go again.
 
 Listed in:
	</body>
</document>
