<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003581" url="http://drdolgoff.com/blog/2011/06/28/how-to-eat-healthy-at-a-fast-food-restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-19:45" support="4" score="0.025828923242331006" bingtitle="How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant | Red Light, Green ..." webtitle="How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant | Red Light, Green Light, Eat Rightdrdolgoff.com">
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant ... Fast food restaurants are often the cheapest option when eating out, but unfortunately, not usually the ...</description>
	<body>
		ONLINE STORE   |   BUY THE BOOK   |   BLOG   |   ABOUT DR. DOLGOFF   |    PRESS   |   CONTACT US 
 « How To Fulfill Nutritional Needs When Kids Veg Out DIY Healthy 100 Calorie Munchies » Tweet 
How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant
 
 
 

 

You said you would never eat fast food again, but then came begging kids and busy schedules, and before you know it, your pulling up to the McDonald’s Drive-Thru. If this sounds familiar, you have come to the right place. Fast food restaurants are often the cheapest option when eating out, but unfortunately, not usually the healthiest. Eating just one fast food meal can pack enough calories, sodium and fat for an entire day, but the quick-and-cheap temptation can be hard to resist, especially when you are on the go. As an informed customer, you can make healthier choices and still enjoy the convenience of fast food restaurants. Whether it’s burger chains, sub sandwich chains, or fried chicken chains, these guidelines are great for you and your kids:

 Make careful menu selections – pay attention to the descriptions on the menu. Dishes labeled deep-fried, pan-fried, breaded, creamy, or crispy are usually high in calories, unhealthy fats or sodium. Order items with more vegetables and choose leaner meats.

 Keep it Clean. When choosing items, be aware of calorie- and fat-packed salad dressings, spreads, cheese, sour cream, etc. For example, ask for a grilled chicken sandwich without the mayonnaise. Instead, ask for a packet of ketchup or mustard and add it yourself, controlling how much you put on your sandwich. 

 Don’t be afraid to special order. Many menu items would be healthy if it weren’t for the way they were prepared. Ask for your vegetables and main dishes to be served without the sauces. Ask for vinegar for your salads or order the dressing“on the side”and spoon only a small amount on at a time. If your food is fried or cooked in oil or butter, ask to have it broiled or steamed. 

 Watch portion size– an average fast food meal can run as high as 1000 calories or more, so choose a smaller portion size, order a side salad instead of fries, and don’t supersize anything.

If you must succumb to the wrath of happy meals, here are some your best bests:

*= Red Light, Green Light Best Bets

 Chick-Fil-A 

Info from: http://www.chick-fil-a.com/#nutritiondata

 Type Serving Size (oz) Kcal Total Fat (g) Sat. Fat (g) Trans Fat (g) Carbs (g) Fiber (g) Sodium (mg) Protein (g) *Chargrilled Chicken Garden Salad 10.5 170 6 3.5 0 10 4 860 22 *Chargrilled Chicken Sandwich 7.75 260 3 0.5 0 33 7 1300 27 Chicken Sandwich 6.3 430 17 3.5 0 39 3 1370 31 Chick-n-Strips 7.59 470 23 4.5 0 22 3 1390 44 Chargrilled Chicken Cool Wrap 10.28 410 12 4 0 49 9 1510 33 Chick-n-Strips Salad 13.69 450 22 6 0 26 6 1160 39 *Southwest Chargrilled Salad 11.5oz 240 9 4 0 17 5 750 25 

 KFC 

Info from http://www.kfc.com/nutrition/pdf/kfc_nutrition_april09.pdf

 Type Serving Size (g) Kcal Total Fat (g) Sat. Fat (g) Trans Fat (g) Carbs (g) Fiber (g) Sodium (mg) Protein (g) *Chicken Breast w/o skin or breading 108 140 2 0 0 1 0 510 29 *Roasted Chicken Caesar Salad w/o croutons or dressing 251 190 6 3 0 5 2 530 29 *Grilled Chicken Breast 119 180 4 1.5 0 0 0 440 35 Hot and Spicy Chicken Breast 179 470 28 6 0 15 4 1310 38 Tender Roast Sandwich w/o Sauce 204 300 4 1.5 0 28 0 660 34 Popcorn Chicken-Kids 95 290 19 3.5 0 16 2 850 16 Hot Wings Snack Box 169 470 27 6 0 41 4 1190 16 *Roasted Chicken BLT Salad w/o Dressing 304 200 7 2 0 7 3 720 30 

 Share on Facebook 
 
 
 
Tags: calories , eat , fast , food , healthy , meal , portion , restaurant 

 This entry was posted
 on Tuesday, June 28th, 2011 at 11:30 pm and is filed under weight loss .
 You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed.

 Both comments and pings are currently closed. 
 
Comments are closed.
 
 Subscribe in a reader 
Allow Your Child to Lose Weight Now!

 Red Light, Green Light, Eat Right: Child and Adolescent Weight Management Program: SIGN UP NOW! 
 
Basic Information About Red Light, Green Light, Eat Right!

 Red Light, Green Light, Eat Right: Child and Adolescent Weight Management Program 
 
Connect With Dr. Dolgoff

 Facebook Free Weekly Newsletter Linked In Twitter 
 
Dr. Dolgoff&apos;s Thoughts

 Child Obesity Overview Diet Tips Don’t Wait! Exercise Health Risks Top Parent Mistakes Why Kids Gain Weight Worst Teen Foods 
 
Recommended Websites

 Basil and Spice Camp Shane: Weight Loss Empower Me Photo Jared&apos;s Blog Metropolitan Acupuncture&amp;Herbal Medicine The Healthy Moms Ziggity Zoom 
 
Recent Posts

 Control Your Cravings To Sugarcoat or Not To Sugarcoat Fat: Is It Brain Food? Want Your Kids To Eat More Fruits and Vegetables?: Use Your Creative Side When It Comes to Their Plates SMALL AND STEADY CHANGES WINS THE HEALTH RACE 
 
Archives

 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 March 2008 February 2008 
 
 

 
Copyright©2009 Joanna Dolgoff M.D.P.C         Privacy Policy         Terms and Conditions
	</body>
</document>
