<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003091" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Fuddruckers4.html" time="2012-07-12-19:12" support="42" score="0.07331551446769843" bingtitle="Fuddruckers, 3575 Chain Bridge Rd, Fairfax, VA - Restaurant ..." webtitle="Fuddruckers, 3575 Chain Bridge Rd, Fairfax, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000157" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001101" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000380" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001195" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="001442" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000134" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001513" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000318" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000854" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000804" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000755" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000130" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001007" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001384" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000505" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000787" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001347" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001321" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000067" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001221" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001410" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000792" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>Have the menu board corrected by this time as well. A follow-up will occur at this time ... drink cup on counter in kitchen without lid or straw Always drink from lidded cups ...</description>
	<body>
		Fuddruckers, 3575 Chain Bridge Rd, Fairfax, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: Fuddruckers 
Address: 3575 Chain Bridge Rd, Fairfax, Virginia 
Total inspections: 26 
Last inspection: May 5, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 
 3-202.15 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food item(s) from damaged packaging were found offered for sale or service: Dented Jalapeno can not removed or separated from food supply. 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food item(s) were observed cold holding at improper temperatures using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: Raw chicken breast at butcher walk-in cooler=55-F. 
 May 05, 2009 Critical Procedures - - Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. November 06, 2008 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 2-301.12(A)-(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Observed food employee using improper handwashing procedures. No warm water and less than 20 seconds. 2-401.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Open drinking container, cup of soda with a straw, stored in a manner that may contaminate food and food contact surfaces. 43.1-3-4(a)-(h) - The Person in Charge (PIC) has an expired Certified Food Manager card. 7-201.11(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed that poisonous and toxic material, bucket of sanitizer, is not properly stored to prevent the contamination of equipment. In a food container. 
 August 28, 2008 Critical Procedures 3 1 Details / Comments 
 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Critical (CORRECTED DURING INSPECTION): The following food items were observed cold holding at improper temperatures using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: 1. Walk-in: milk, 45F; cheese, 46F; chili, 45F2. Reach-in: homemade ranch dressing, 67F3. Prep top: hardboiled egg, 48F4. Reach-in: sliced canteloupe, 47F5. Toppings bar: homemade salsa, 65F6. Meat walk-in: hot dogs, 46F; beef, 48FNote: Most items discarded. Some maintained in refrigeration based on time out of temperature determined by conversation with person-in-charge. 4-501.114(C) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Quaternary ammonium compound sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. Observed a bucket with sanitizer solution with a concentration less than 50ppm. 4-601.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: hamburger doneness picks. 4-703.11(C) - Critical Due to improper operation of the low temperature chemical sanitizing mechanical warewashing machine, equipment food-contact surfaces and utensils are not sanitized after cleaning. Observed the dishmachine with a sanitizer concentration below 50ppm. 7-102.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Observed an unlabeled spray bottle of a cleaning solution. 
 June 06, 2008 Critical Procedures - - Details / Comments 
 2-301.12(A)-(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed food employees using improper handwashing procedures: less than 20 seconds. 2-301.14(A)-(I) - Corrected During Inspection Critical A food employee failed to wash his or her hands between glove changes. 2-401.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed open employee food stored on top of the microwave. 3-302.11(A)(4) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Unwrapped or uncovered food in the following location where the food is subject to contamination: stack of burgers directly on shelving in the 2 door reach-in. 3-501.19(B)(1)-(4) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food item for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control was not cooked, served or discarded by the expiration time as indicated: sliced cheese on ice at the cookline and sliced tomatoes at the customer self service area. Note: Discarded. 7-102.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed an unlabeled spray bottle of a cleaning solution. 
 January 16, 2008 Critical Procedures 6 0 Details / Comments 3-603.11(A) - Critical Repeat A review of the menu with the foodservice operator indicates that there is no consumer advisory for the following food item(s) that may be served raw and/or undercooked: burgers. Poster of &quot;footnote&quot; statements are incorrect. November 15, 2007 Follow-up 1 0 Details / Comments 
 2-401.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Open drinking containers stored in a manner that may contaminate food, food contact surfaces or utensils. 3-202.15 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food item from damaged packaging were found offered for sale or service: dented can stored with undamaged ones. 3-302.11(A)(1) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Raw animal (chicken) food stored over ready-to-eat food (bread) in the walk-in freezer. 3-304.12(A)-(F) - Corrected During Inspection Dispensing and/or in-use utensils improperly stored between use as follows: ice cream scoop stored in the dipping well at the ice cream station that was turned off. 3-501.16(A)(1) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food item was found hot holding at improper temperatures using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: chili at steam table, 116F. Note: Removed for reheating. 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat The following food item was observed cold holding at improper temperatures using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: chicken, 51-55F. Note: Chicken had just been thawed prior to placing in the refrigeration unit. Focus on this process. 3-501.19(B)(1)-(4) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food items for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control was not observed marked with an expiration time: sliced cheese and sliced tomatoes. 3-603.11(A) - Critical Repeat A review of the menu with the foodservice operator indicates that there is no consumer advisory for the following food items that may be served raw and/or undercooked: 1/2 and 1/3 lb beef and buffalo burgers, chopped steak, ribeye steak sandwich and petite filet medallions. No disclosure or advisory on the carry out menu and the advisory at the menu board is incorrect. 4-402.11(A) - The following equipment is not installed in a manner that allows accessibility for cleaning, nor is it installed with closely abutting surfaces to minimize the need for cleaning: all sinks and drain boards in the dishroom. 4-501.114(C) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Quaternary ammonium compound sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. Observed a sanitizer bucket at 50ppm. 4-601.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following equipment/utensils were observed soiled to sight and touch: color indicator picks stored in a container at the cookline with food debris. 5-501.113(B) - Observed the dumpster with the side doors left open. 5-501.115 - Litter, leaves and a large piece of wood were observed adjacent to the refuse container outside the facility. 6-202.11(A) - Light bulbs in the following are not covered by a protective shielding: fluorescent tubes by the door in the meat walk-in. 6-202.15(A)(1)-(3) - The self-closing device on the back door is unattached/damaged. 6-501.11 - Observed that the following is not maintained in good repair.:1. Wall tiles near the back door2. Threshold on the walk-in freezer is missing the metal cover and now is just exposed, unfinished wood3. Coving tiles in the men&apos;s room4. Damaged and moldy walls in the soda syrup room 7-102.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed 2 unlabeled spray bottles on cleaning solutions. 
 August 17, 2007 Routine 10 7 Details / Comments 
 2-301.12(A)-(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed food employees using improper handwashing procedures. Observed employee washing only one hand. 2-401.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed open employee beverage without lid and straw stored on shelving over food items. 3-302.11(A)(2) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Different types of raw animal foods stored in such a manner that may cause cross contamination as follows: Observed raw chicken over french fries in the RI freezer and raw chicken over bread dough in the WI freezer. 3-302.11(A)(4) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Unwrapped or uncovered food in the following location where the food is subject to contamination: Observed cheese and lemons uncovered. 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Critical Repeat The following food item(s) were observed cold holding at improper temperatures using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: Observed sliced tomatoes at the customer self-service area @ 53-55F and cheese in ice bath @ 42-66F. 3-603.11(A) - Critical A review of the menu with the foodservice operator indicates that there is not consumer advisory for the following food item(s) that may be served raw and/or undercooked: Burgers and steak on the carry out menu and display board. 4-501.114(C) - Critical Quaternary ammonium compound sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. Observed sanitizer in bucket at a concentration below 200ppm. 7-202.12(A)(1)-(4) - Critical The concentration of the chlorine solution in the dishmachine was measured above 100 ppm. 7-208.11(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical First Aid Supplies are not being stored in a kit or container. Observed bottle of cold medicine stored above food on shelf. 
 April 11, 2007 Critical Procedures 9 0 Details / Comments 
 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Turkey burgers at 60F. 4-301.11 - Repeat The 2 drawer unit at the cookline with an ambient air temperature of 58F. 46-36(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical No CFM onsite. 
 October 05, 2006 Follow-up 2 1 Details / Comments 
 3-302.11(A)(1) - Critical Raw chicken was stored over mozzarella in WIF. 3-302.11(A)(4) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Container of flour was uncovered on metal shelf in center of kitchen. 3-304.12(A)-(F) - Corrected During Inspection At grill, noted several utensils stored in container of ice water. Next to chicken nugget dipping station, utensils were stored in 56 F water. 3-304.14(B)(1) - Corrected During Inspection Wet wiping cloth was stored on cutting board at shake station. 3-501.14(A)(1) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Taco meat in WIC #1 which was 102 F, 2.5 hours after cooking was noted not been adequately cooled to prevent the growth of bacteria. Cooking time was determined by asking CFM. (CFM was advised to either discard food or rapidly reheat to 165 F and cool to 70 F within 2 hours and then to 41 F within 4 hours.) 3-501.15(A)(1)-(7) - Taco meat was observed cooling in WIC #1 in deep container that was covered with plastic wrap. (Advised CFM to either discard or rapidly reheat to 165 F and begin cooling process again) 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Critical REPEAT OBSERVATION The following foods were cold holding at improper temperatures:1. RIC at grill: ostrich burger 45 F, buffalo burger 43 F2. CH drawer under grill: hot dogs 52 F, raw chicken 50 F3. Salad prep: sliced eggs 52 F, butter 52 F, pico de gallo 48 F4. Self-service area: sliced tomatoes 60, 70 F(The above items were placed in units that were able to maintain adequate temperatures.) 3-501.17(A)(1) - Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) ranch dressing in WIC #1 was marked with a discard date of 8 days after day of preparation. 3-501.17(B) - Critical The ready-to-eat (RTE) commercially processed cheese sauce in the WIC #1 was mislabelled 9/2. CFM stated it was opened yesterday. 3-603.11(B) - Critical A placard exists at front registers but there are no disclosures marked on the large menu banners or on the take out menu. 4-202.16 - Repeat Milk crate(s) found used for the following: elevating food in WIF.The nonfood contact surface of the paper used to line metal shelf is not designed or constructed to be easily cleanable. 4-301.11 - Repeat REPEAT OBSERVATION The RIC at the grill, refrigerated drawer at the grill, the meat WIC, and the salad prep top are not maintaining ambient air temperatures of 41 F or below. 4-402.11(A) - The 3 vat sink is not sealed to the wall. 4-502.11(C) - The ambient air temperature gauge in the RIC at the grill is not not accurate in the range of use. It was reading 70 F. 4-602.11(E)(4) - REPEAT OBSERVATION Inside of ice machine was in need of cleaning. 4-602.13 - The nonfood contact surface of the tray holding doneness markers and the container holding the ice scoop at the ice machine had accumulations of grime and debris. 4-702.11 - Critical The food-contact surfaces of the following equipment were not observed sanitized by dishmachine due to no sanitizer being dispensed. (Instructed to manually wash wares and have machine serviced immediately.) 4-703.11(C) - Critical Due to improper operation of the low temperature chemical sanitizing mechanical warewashing machine, equipment food-contact surfaces and utensils are not sanitized after cleaning. No chlorine sanitizer was detected at dishmachine. 4-901.11(A) - Metal pans found stacked wet at vegetable prep station. 5-205.15(B) - Corrected During Inspection Drain pipe under sanitize basin was observed in disrepair and would not properly drain into the designated drain. 5-501.113B - Outside dumpsters were not covered. 5-501.115 - The outdoor dumpster area needed to be cleaned. Dirty water was pooling in the enclosure. 6-101.11(A) - The ceiling tile located in public restrooms do not meet the standard of: 1. smooth, durable, and easily cleanable and 2. non-absorbent. 6-202.11(A) - Lights bulb(s) in the center of the kitchen, in front of WIC #1, and in room with ice machine are not covered by a protective shielding. 6-301.14 - There was no handwashing sign at handsink near mopsink. 6-305.11(B) - Lockers or other suitable facilities are not provided for employees clothing and other possessions. Observed employee items throughout the facility; purse on shelf in kitchen, articles of clothing on food/equipment storage shelf in ice machine room. 6-501.11 - Cement and tile floor has erroded in front of WIC #1. Tile flooring throughout kitchen needs to be re-grouted. Tiles are coming loose. Coving, and corner of doorway is damaged in dish room. There are holes in wall in soda syrup closet. Damaged shelving in ice cream area. 6-501.114(A) - Facility is storing unnecessary, damaged equipment in dumpster enclosure. 6-501.12(A) - Walls in soda syrup room have accumulations of mold. 6-501.16 - Repeat Mops not hung up to air dry outside of WIC #1. 7-102.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Bottle of glass cleaner was not labelled next to soft-serve machine. 
 October 03, 2006 Routine 10 21 Details / Comments 
 3-302.12 - Unlabeled food containers (e.g. ingrdients along the bakers rack). 3-305.11A3 - Repeat Food stored on the floor and/or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor (e.g. observed fresh lettuce being stored on the floor of the walk-in refrigerator). 3-501.16B - Critical Repeat Milk (61F) cold holding at improper temperatures. 4-202.16 - Milk crate(s) found used for the following: Elevation 4-204.112A - The temperature measuring device in the 2-dr prep unit directly across from the grill on the cookline was not properly located in the warmest part of the unit. 4-301.11 - The following pieces of equipment did not meet the food storage demands of the establishment.- 2-Dr Prep Unit (65F) ---store front- 1-Dr Prep Unit (44F) ---cookline 4-402.11A - The hand sink near the kitchen entrance is not installed in a manner that allows accessibility for cleaning, nor is it installed with closely abutting surfaces to minimize the need for cleaning. 4-501.11B - Repeat The door gasket of the 1-Dr Victory Prep Unit (cookline) is damaged. 4-602.11E - Repeat Surfaces of the can opener was in contact with non-potentially hazardous food items that were observed soiled with accumulations of grime and debris. 4-703.11C - Critical When tested, no sanitizer or a low concentration of chemical sanitizer was found in the wiping cloth bucket. 4-903.11D - Repeat Observed single service items (e.g. food trays, cups, etc) stored on the floor of the dry storage room. 5-205.11B - The handwash station near the kitchen entrance is being used for purposes other than washing hands (e.g. observed, wiping cloths and utensils being stored in sink). 6-501.11 - 1-Dr Victory Prep Unit is not maintained in good repair. The door is misaligned which causes a gap that may effect the ambient temperature inside the unit. 6-501.16 - Corrected During Inspection Repeat Mops and brooms not hung up to air dry. 
 April 28, 2006 Routine 2 12 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. October 25, 2005 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 2-401.11A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Open drinking containers stored in a manner that may contaminate food, food contact surfaces or utensils. 3-301.11B - Critical Repeat Employees observed handling ready-to-eat (RTE) food with their bare hands (food handler at the grill wore no gloves or use utensils when handling RTE foods). 3-302.11A1 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Raw beef stored over ready-to-eat (RTE) foods (i.e. cheese/hot dog) in the refrigeration unit. 3-304.14B2 - Repeat Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. 3-305.11A3 - Corrected During Inspection A box of chicken fingers were stored on the floor (WI) and/or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. 3-501.16B - Critical Repeat Raw eggs (52F) Boiled Eggs (50F) cold holding at improper temperatures. 3-501.16C - Critical Walk-In Refrigeration unit (52) found to be capable of holding potentially hazardous food items in cold hold in a temperature range of 41-45F. Unit is not able to maintain internal items at a temperature of 41F or less. 4-501.11B - Repeat The door gaskets of all prep units are damaged. 4-602.11C - Critical Food contact surfaces of the slicer used to prepare/store potentially hazardous food items were observed soiled with accumulations of food residues. 4-602.11E - Repeat Surfaces of the can opener was in contact with non-potentially hazardous food items that were observed soiled with accumulations of grime and debris. 4-903.11D - Observed a box of single-use cups being stored on the floor. 5-501.113B - Corrected During Inspection Repeat Outside refuse container was uncovered. 6-201.11 - Repeat Ceiling tiles within the restroom were absorbsent, not smooth, nor easily cleanable. 6-202.11A - Repeat Lights bulb(s) in the dry storage area are not covered by a protective shielding. 6-301.14 - Corrected During Inspection A sign or poster that notifies food employees to wash their hands is not provided at all lavatories used by food employees. 6-303.11C - Inadequate lighting was noted in the the hood system. 6-501.16 - Repeat Mops and brooms not hung up to air dry. 
 October 25, 2005 Routine 6 11 Details / Comments 
 3-302.11A4 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Unwrapped or uncovered cut lemons observed at self-service area. 3-304.12 - Dispensing utensils improperly stored between use --- observed: 1. ice crean scoops in standing 68F, water; and, 2. plastic cups stored in &quot;spud spice&quot;. 3-306.11 - Food on display, lettuce, tomatoes, onions, peppers, etc., found not adequately protected from contamination by the use of packaging; counter, service line, or salad bar food guards; display cases; or other effective means.**The sneezeguard found is too high above food, and is horizontal to table surface, and thus would not adequately catch sneeze or cough contaminants. 3-501.16A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Found fried chicken strips at 118F, at cookline, under heat lamps, hot holding at improper temperatures. 3-501.16B - Critical Found the following foods cold holding at improper temperatures:1. grilled, chopped chicken at 73F, on salad for service;2. grilled chopped chicken at 72F, holding in pans on top heated drawer cabinet;3. Ranch dressing at 57F, and boiled eggs at 63F, each in pans on top of heated drawers cabinet;4. raw chicken at 47F in drawer at cookline;5. vegetable patty at 52F, in drawer at cookline. 4-501.114A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Chlorine sanitizing solution in bucket near front area, was not at an acceptable concentration --- it was found too low at less than 50 PPM chlorine. 4-501.11B - The door gaskets of the LP refrig. units found torn. 4-501.12 - Repeat The cutting boards leaning at Bunn machine, and large one inside walk-in, were observed with gray/black staining, and heavily scratched and scored. The food contact surface is no longer easily cleaned and sanitized due to condition. 4-601.11C - The nonfood-contact surfaces of the following equipment were observed soiled with an accumulation of dust, dirt, food residue, and/or other debris: filters of hood system observed with scorching and accumulated grease. 4-903.11B - Clean single-service cups, and glasses, were observed stored on front bare countertop. 5-501.113B - Outside refuse container was uncovered, and refuse observed overflowing from dumpster. 6-202.13B - Insect control device (light)on wall is located over the prep/service area of kitchen, directly over food storage and prep. 6-501.12A - Repeat Physical structure noted in need of cleaning, to include:1. dining area window area behind benches;2. dining area flooring at edges and around corners, under tables;3. black mold along edge of warewash room ceiling. 7-102.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Working containers, squirt bottles,of cleaners (blue liquid, and orange liquid) on ledge over/beside front handsink, were found with no labels. 7-202.11A - Corrected During Inspection The following poisonous or toxic material, bottle of ant bait, was found stored on ledge beside fron handsink. 
 May 16, 2005 Routine 5 10 Details / Comments 
 6-201.11 - Acoustic ceiling tile installed in kitchen prep area 2-401.11A - Critical Observed employee drink cup on counter in kitchen without lid or straw 3-305.11A1 - The following foods are not protected from contamination:1. Uncovered bulk containers of spices in kitchen 3-602.11C - Observed no label on bulk container of spices in kitchen 4-501.114C - Critical Measured quaternary ammonia compound in wet-wiping bucket at 150ppm 4-501.12 - Observed cutting board on food prep unit in kitchen scored, soiled 3-304.14B2 - Observed wet-wiping cloths left on counter in between use 6-501.14A - Observed vent baffles on hood system unclean with grease and debris 3-301.11B - Critical Observed the folloiwng instances of barehand contact with ready to eat foods:1. Cook using barehands to portion cheese onto hamburgers on grill immediately prior to being plated2. Observed employee slicing bread rolls with bare hands 4-202.16 - The following non-food contact equipment is observed uncleanable:1. Observed sheet tray liners in kitchen are unclean with food debris, grease2. Observed rusted shelving under food prep sink in kitchen holding equipment 5-203.14A - Critical Observed draink pipe from food prep sink dips below flood level rim of floor drain 6-301.11 - Observed no handsoap at handsink next to mopsink 3-302.11A1 - Critical Observed raw ground hamburger stored on top of ready to eat cheese in the 2-door refrigerator in the kitchen 6-501.16 - Observed mop left to dry on top of bin full of unclean wet wiping cloths 6-202.16 - Observed visible light and gap &gt;1&quot; under back door 6-202.11A - Observed unshielded light bulbs at back door of kitchen 4-602.13 - The following equipment is observed unclean :1. Interior of proofer in kitchen unclean with debris 4-204.113 - No visible dataplate on the Jackson ES 2000 single-tank chemical sanitizing dishmachine 4-402.11A - Observed dishtable unsealed to wall in kitchen 5-205.15B - Critical CFM states that grease trap under 3-vat sink in kitchen is cleaned by same company as vent hoods, but there is no visible record of cleaning. In addition, during inspection, observed grease trap overflowed when both compartments of 3-vat sink were opened to drain. 4-302.14 - Facility does not have any quaternary ammonia test strips to measure strength of QAC sanitizer 6-501.11 - Observed the following physical structures in disrepair:1. Observed missing wall tiles by the food prep sink in kitchen2. Missing floor tile by walk-in walk-in freezer3. Observed missing floor tiles by dishmachine 4-302.12 - Observed facility does not have any working food temperature thermometer in kitchen. CFM states that thermocouple needs to have batteries replaced 6-501.12A - Observed the following physical structures unclean with debris:1. Food debris, grease behind the cookline equipment 2. Observed floor unclean in walk-in freezer3. Black mold growing on wall above dishtable in kitchen4. Soda syrup leaking onto floor in storage room holding syrup boxes 4-602.11E - Observed black mold growing on splash guard inside ice machine 6-501.114A - Observed unused coffee urn in storage room with ice machine 3-401.11A2 - Critical When asked to cook hamburger to &quot;medium rare&quot; (lowest cook temp allowed according to cooks), internal temperature is only measured to be 148F 4-703.11C - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed that Jackson ES 2000 dishmachine single tank chemical sanitizing unit is NOT sanitizing dishware 
 December 27, 2004 Routine 8 20 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. April 30, 2004 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. March 01, 2004 Routine 0 0 Details / Comments 4-901.11A - silverware was observed stored in self serve containers wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. February 20, 2004 Complaint 0 1 Details / Comments 
 5-205.11B - The handwash station in the ice cream service area is being used for purposes other than washing hands (observed dirty ice cream and shake containers. 2-103.11K - Employees are not aware of or are not using suitable utensils with ready-to-eat food to prevent cross-contamination. Observed a food handler handle sandwich bread with bare hands after handling raw meat with the same hands. 2-401.11A - Critical Repeat Open drinking containers stored in a manner that may contaminate food, food contact surfaces or utensils. were observed in the ice cream service area. 2-103.11D - Poor handwashing procedures observed during food preparation and food service. 2-301.14A - Critical A food employee (MANAGER IN CHARGE)failed to wash his or her hands before engaging in food preparation, after touching bare human body parts, after coughing, sneezing, eating, after handling soiled utensils or after engaging in any activity which may have contaminated his/her hands (VISITING THE DUMPSTER AREA). 7-202.12A - Critical The chlorine sanitizing solution in front counter area was at toxic levels of concentration when tested and is not being used in accordance with law or the manufacturer&apos;s use directions. 5-203.14A - Critical Observed a plastic material extension attached to the sink drain air gapped at the floor in ice cream service area. The extension extended below the flood rim level of the floor drain. 6-301.12A - Observed that no paper towels were available for handsink near food service counter. 6-501.111D - Harborage conditions exist in the exterior area of the building (AROUND AND BEHIND DUMPSTER AREA). Observed that the area around exit door and dumpster was acummulating trash and other unneccessary items. IN ADDITION, SEVERAL RODENT TUNNELS WERE NOTED IN THIS AREA OF THE BUILDING. 6-202.15 - Openings to the exterior of the building are present along the base and edges of kitchen exit. The door has large rust holes and it does not fit tightly. 
 February 20, 2004 Follow-up 4 6 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. January 13, 2004 Routine 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. November 24, 2003 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 4-703.11C - Critical The mechanical warewashing unit had no sanitizer or a low concentration of chemical sanitizer was found in the sanitize basin. 4-204.112B - Repeat There was no temperature measuring device located in the upright cooling units in cook line. 7-201.11A - Critical Containers of degreaser are not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food, equipment, utensils, linens or single service items. They were stored next to bread at cook line and next to spice rack 2-401.11A - Critical Observed an open drinking containers (soda bottle) stored in a manner that may contaminate food, food contact surfaces or utensils. Observed employee eating in food prep area where they may contaminate food, clean equipment, utensils or other items needing protection. 3-304.14B2 - Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. Stored on top of counters throughout facility. 3-304.14D - Heavily soiled wiping cloths in use in the kitchen. 3-302.11A1 - Critical Raw animal food (burger pattie) stored over ready-to-eat (RTE) food (hot dogs) in the front display refrigeration unit , and in cooling unit. 3-305.11A2 - 3-305.11A3 - Food stored on the floor and/or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. Box of potatoes in walk in freezer and onions in walk in cooler. 4-602.11E - Obeserved the following equipment surfaces that may come in contact with non-potentially hazardous food items were observed soiled with accumulations of grime and debris.1. Can opener blade2. Ice machine interior upper surface 6-501.110B - Employee clothing and other possessions (cell phones keys) have been found stored in (kitchen food prep area) areas that may contaminate food, food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items. 6-501.11 - Repeat The following areas in the facility is not maintained in good repair. 1. Men&apos;s bathroom wall needs repair2. Wall around kitchen exit door (next to utility sink). 4-501.11A - Repeat Observed the following equipment in a state of disrepair and damaged.1. The filters in the hood system.2. The ware washing mechanical unit was not sanitizing. 5-501.116B - Refuse containers (GREASE BARREL) is soiled an accumulating grime and debris. 
 November 21, 2003 Routine 4 10 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. August 08, 2003 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. August 08, 2003 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. July 18, 2003 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. July 18, 2003 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
