<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003039" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/11/art_basel_food_guide_food_truc.php" time="2012-07-12-19:09" support="1" score="0.0007758138426886045" bingtitle="Art Basel Food Guide: Food Trucks - Miami Restaurants and Dining ..." webtitle="Art Basel Food Guide: Food Trucks - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000425" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>At each stop, 40 performers will pop out of the cars ... opportunity to pose for Sketchy Miami artists and receive ... The Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Food Art 
Art Basel Food Guide: Food Trucks
 By Laine Doss Mon., Nov. 28 2011 at 11:12 AM Categories: Food Art , Gastronomic Gatherings , Truck Tracker 
 Pin It 
 
 Aleloop Food trucks will follow the Aleloop Minis around town for Art Basel. 
​ Art Basel is coming to town, turning the entire city into a roving band of art connoisseurs. Each year, we travel to pop-up art galleries and tents filled with shards of broken glass, painted bananas, interactive tunnels, and sometimes even the occasional paint-on-canvas.

Pondering all this art gets us hungry. After stopping at 37 galleries (with another 50 more on the list), we need to stop for some refreshment. Unfortunately, sitting down at a restaurant can infringe on our gallery time. Which is why food trucks come in handy.

Food trucks will be out and about -- at galleries, roundups, and as part of an art installation. We&apos;ve put together a list of roundups and where to find individual trucks at Art Basel events. The list will be updated as we get more locations. As always, it&apos;s a good idea to follow your favorite trucks on Twitter and Facebook and check Short Order daily.
 
 Roundups and Caravans 

Throughout the weekend, a rotating caravan of food trucks will be traveling throughout the Design District, Midtown, and Wynwood following the Aleloop Mini&apos;s with the Aleloop Mobile Art Installation . From December 1-4, a caravan of ten Mini Coopers will travel the streets of Miami. At each stop, 40 performers will pop out of the cars and create a multisensory flash mob.

Rotating trucks include Dim Ssam a gogo , Latin Burger, The Fish Box , Ms Cheezious , CheeseMe , gastroPod , Sugar Rush , Sugar Yummy Mama , Latin House Grill , and Cheesesteak Gourmet

 Food trucks will be set up in Wynwood at the food truck roundup location at 2200 NW Second Avenue. Trucks will be serving lunch and dinner daily. Truck schedule as follows:
 
Thursday, December 1 
Food trucks serving include Clarabelles Cupcakes,

Red Koi,

Tango Grill,

Churro Mania,

Dolci Peccati Gelato,

Latin Burger,

Dim Ssam a gogo,

Chef on 4 Wheels,

Wrap it up Food Truck,

Latin House Grill,

Sugar Rush,

Cool Haus Miami,
Mac &apos;n Food Truck,

Ms Cheezious,

Boba Station,

Gastropod,

Sugar Yummy Mama,

Los Chamos,

90 Miles to Go, 

Aphrodisiac Ice Cream, Arepa Box,


Cheesesteak Gourmet, 

Taco Fresh,

Palate Party,
and Bite Gastrotruck.

 Friday, December 2 
Trucks at Wynwood today are The Mexzican,

Grill Master Cafe,

Mangia Mia,

Slow Food Truck,

Purple People Eatery, 


Latin Burger,

Dim Ssam a gogo,

Chef on 4 Wheels,

Wrap it up Food Truck,

Latin House Grill,

Sugar Rush,

Cool Haus Miami,

Mac &apos;n Food Truck,

Ms Cheezious,

Boba Station,
Gastropod,
Sugar Yummy Mama,

Los Chamos,





90 Miles to Go, 


Cheesesteak Gourmet, 

Taco Fresh,
and Bite Gastrotruck.
 
Saturday, December 3 
Sakaya Kitchen&amp;Aleloop will be hosting a music festival called the Aleloopapalooza Music, Dance and Performing Arts Festival from 6 p.m. to midnight. Forty
 live acts and a DJ will perform. Trucks include:

The Mexzican,

Dolci Peccati Gelato,
Papas Tapas,

Grill Master Cafe,

Mangia Mia,

Slow Food Truck,

Purple People Eatery, The

Rolling Stove.

Nacho Mama,

Over Load Extreme Street Food, Manila Rice,

Mr. Good Stuff,

Che Grill, 


Latin Burger,

Dim Ssam a gogo,

Chef on 4 Wheels,

Wrap it up Food Truck,

Latin House Grill,

Sugar Rush,

Cool Haus Miami,

Mac &apos;n Food Truck,

Ms Cheezious,

Boba Station,

Gastropod,

Sugar Yummy Mama,

Los Chamos,

90 Miles to Go,
Aphrodisiac Ice Cream,

Malanga Cafe,

Pardos Grill,


Cheesesteak Gourmet, 

Taco Fresh,

Palate Party,

Bite Gastrotruck,

Jefe&apos;s Original Fish Taco, and

Doggie Style.

 Sunday, December 4 
Food truck lineup includes Tango Grill,

Churro Mania,

Dolci Peccati,

Papas Tapas,

Grill Master Cafe,

Mangia Mia,

Purple People Eatery,

Slow Food Truck,

Che Grill,






Guiseppes Italian Sausage,
Latin Burger,

Dim Ssam a gogo,

Chef on 4 Wheels,

Wrap it up Food Truck,

Latin House Grill,

Sugar Rush,

Cool Haus Miami,

Mac &apos;n Food Truck,

Ms Cheezious,

Boba Station,

Gastropod,

Sugar Yummy Mama,

Los Chamos,

90 Miles to Go,

Aphrodisiac Ice Cream,

Arepa Box,

Malanga Cafe,

Red Koi,

Cheesesteak Gourmet, 

Taco Fresh, and

Bite Gastrotruck.

 The Adrienne Arsht Center for the Performing Arts will host Food Truck Friday on Friday, December 2nd from 11:30 a.m. to 2:30 p.m. Free performance by ELEW, a Rockjazz pianist who recently tourded with Josh Groban at 1 p.m. Attendees will have the opportunity to pose for Sketchy Miami artists and receive instant complimentary portraits. In addition, street chalk artist Betty Dominguez will be on-site to create a mural inspired by the upcoming performances of Shrek:The Musical . Free admission, Parking $3. N.E. 2nd Avenue, Between 12th and 13th Streets, Miami 
 
Individual Trucks 
 
The Veuve Clicquot Clicq&apos;Up Cafe and Champagne Bar is a mobile food truck and pop-up Champagne lounge. Chef Jeremiah Bullfrog has designed a gourmet menu which includes chipolte cream corn cake, pork tacos, and conch salad. Of course, Veuve Clicquot will be available for your sipping pleasure. Schedule as follows:


 Tuesday, November 29th - Design Miami Pavilion 4 to 9 p.m. Wednesday, November 30th - Art Basel Outdoor Art Exhibit 7 p.m. to midnight Thursday, December 1st - The Stage in The Design District, 38th Street and First Court, 12 to 5 p.m. Friday, December 2nd - The Stage in The Design District, 38th Street and First Court, 12 to 5 p.m. 
 
Big Kahuna and Nacho Bizness will be at the Multiversal Studio in Wynwood December 1st - 4th. 193 NW 24th Street, Miami 
 
Purple People Eatery will be serving lunch in front of the Museum of Contemporary Art in North Miami December 1-4. 770 NE 125th Street, North Miami
 
 Kona Ice will be serving up sno-cones through Wynwood and The Design District during Art Basel.
 
The Real Chill will be at Hardcore Art Contemporary Gallery December 1, 2, 3,&amp;10. 72 NW 25th Street, Miami 
 
 The Fish Box will be at the Art Basel opening party at the W South Beach Hotel&amp;Residences on November 30th from 6 p.m. to midnight. W South Beach Hotel, Collins Avenue&amp;21st Street, Miami Beach 
 
 Sugar Yummy Mama is presenting some new cupcakes for Art Basel. The La Fete is a Champagne and St. Germain-infused cupcake topped with a French vanilla buttercream and a cherry. The LG cupcake is a moist chocolate cupcake with caramelized jalapenos, topped with a chocolate mousse buttercream and caramelized jalapenos. Look for SYM at Wynwood and The Design District throughout the weekend.

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Location Info
 
Venue



Map
 
 Wynwood Art District 

Wynwood Art District, Miami, FL

Category: General 
 
 2 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Aleloop , Art Basel Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
we are drivin  in from out of town,  will any food trucks be near the Basel Art site?
 
This talk of food is making me hungry
 

TotalComments: 2
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Kings County Pizza
 View Ad | View Site 
Our pizza is simply an honest diversity of all-nat
 View Ad | View Site 
Mo&apos;s Bagels&amp;Deli
 View Ad | View Site 
Salsa Fiesta Urban Mexican Grill
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
