<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003594" url="http://familyfood.hiddenvalley.com/easy-meals/" time="2012-07-12-19:45" support="1" score="0.0071814641073102555" bingtitle="Easy Meals | Family Food | Hidden Valley" webtitle="Easy Meals | Hidden Valley">
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>... meals in less time than it takes to go to a fast-food ... more personal affair by hosting a potluck reception. ... safety during meal preparation and choose foods that will keep ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. Hidden Valley: The Original Ranch. Makes Everything Taste Better Show Menu 
 Join Hidden Valley 

 Home Products Recipes Your Veggies Videos Family Fun Family Food 
 Show Menu Family Food 
 Appetizers&amp;Snacks | Breakfast&amp;Brunch | Diet&amp;Nutrition | Dinner&amp;Main Dishes | Entertaining&amp;Party Foods | How to Cook | Lunch&amp;Picnics | Meals Plans&amp;Menus 
 
 Family Food » Meals Plans&amp;Menus » Easy Meals 
 
Easy Meals
 

 
 Easy Family Meal Ideas 
 
 Easy Meal Ideas for Students 
 
 Ideas for Quick, Easy Meals 
 
 Easy-Fix Summer Meal Ideas 
 
More Easy Meals Picks
 
 Easy Anniversary Meals 

Treat every wedding anniversary like a holiday by celebrating all day long. Even if the anniversary falls on a weekday, make it special by preparing romantic dishes for each meal. Get your kids involved in the meal planning and preparation. Prepare as many elements as possible ahead of time so you can put each meal together in minutes and have more time to savor it with your spouse.
 
 Easy Weekly Meal Planners 

Weekly meal planning makes preparing healthful meals as quick --- and nearly as easy --- as waiting for a take-out order. Cooking at home is better for your health and your pocketbook than ordering a pizza when you are short on time. Planning ahead also makes quick work of preparing easy, healthful breakfasts and lunches. Mix and match your family&apos;s favorite dishes and ingredients to create a stockpile of meal ideas. Build weekly menus before you shop and you won&apos;t find yourself dashing to the store for missing ingredients at the last minute.
 
 Easy Daily Meal Ideas 

The demands of daily life can drain away any mom’s energy and leave you clueless when it comes to ideas for easy meals. However, that brain drain doesn’t have to stop you from whipping up tasty food for your family. A collection of basic meals and a pantry stocked with basic goods are your ultimate weapons against difficult dinners and laborious lunches.
 
 Easy Weekly Southern Meals 

Whether or not you live in the South, biscuits, grits and barbecued meat can satisfy a hungry family. Try to incorporate easy weekly Southern meals into your menu to add flavor and variety. Southern menus are all about down-home, simple foods with laid-back presentation -- perfect for feeding the entire family.
 
 Seven Easy Meals for the Week 

On top of all your other responsibilities, making sure that your kids have a well-balanced dinner every night can feel more like an obligation than a joyful gift. Preparation is the key to minimizing the frustration that builds when you stand in front of an open pantry wondering what you should cook for dinner. On the weekend, spend an hour studying what’s on sale at your grocery store, plan meals around those sales, make your list and shop. All that’s left to do is to fulfill your plan.
 
 Easy Skillet Meals 

Skillet meals are easy to cook and easy to clean up, as you only need one pan. Many skillet recipes combine a wide variety of ingredients, which can help you use up leftovers and lower your grocery budget. Best of all, cooking the ingredients together ensures that your meals always have a rich flavor.
 
 Cheap&amp;Easy Country Meals 

When you think of country meals, you might picture big, elaborate dinners filled with fried foods and carbohydrates. This may have been true 100 years ago when farm families needed extra fuel for physical labor, but country cooking has changed. Today&apos;s country meals are cozy and flavorful but acknowledge the importance of a healthy diet for growing children. Combine frugal cooking methods with healthy comfort food and you get modern country cooking that your entire family will enjoy.
 
 Quick and Easy Meals for the Start of School 

The mad scramble to get kids ready for a new school year can leave any mom frazzled. Family members hustle to get out the door in the mornings, and afternoons and evenings become a jumble of homework and activities. Lean on some helpful techniques that take the pinch out of staying organized, especially when planning meals. Turn the breakfast and dinner hours into calmer moments with some quick and easy meals for the start of school.
 
 Easy Weeknight Meals 

After a long day of being in an office or running a busy household, the idea of spending lots of time in the kitchen fixing dinner will likely not fill you with feelings of unmixed delight. Bringing nutritious and delicious weeknight meals to the table is easy, however, if you follow three simple rules: prepare as much of it as you can ahead of time, choose entrees that require little supervision and encourage participation from family members.
 
 Creative&amp;Easy Meal Ideas 

Even if you are pressed for time in the kitchen, you can still get creative with meals. If you&apos;re tired of the same old dinner options, customize basic recipes for your family using new and fresh ingredients. Experiment with your favorite flavors and spices. Creative meals can be just as easy to make as traditional dinners.
 
 Healthy, Easy Meals for Toddlers 

Toddlers, like everyone else, need a healthy diet. Unfortunately, some toddlers can be difficult to please, even at mealtime. Patience, preparation and planning can lessen any frustration over toddler mealtime and keep healthy meals within easy reach. Offer toddlers choices and plenty of time to eat, so mealtime is not a battle. Always supervise toddler mealtimes and serve foods that are small enough to avoid choking hazards.
 
 Ideas for Easy Meals 

While science can’t prove that eating together contributes to a happier home environment, many moms can vouch for the benefits of eating meals together. Eating together as often as possible ensures that your family eats well-balanced meals. And if you don’t tire yourself spending hours on dinner, you’ll have more moments to reconnect at the end of the day and whittle informational nuggets out of your kids.
 
 Easy Freezable Meals 

If you don&apos;t have time to cook from scratch every night after work or if it&apos;s a challenge to get everyone in your family around the dinner table at the same time, freezable meals are an easy solution. Since many of these dishes can be prepared in bulk, they may also save you some money on your monthly grocery bill. Clean-up is simplified, too -- a bonus if you&apos;re making these simple meals for household guests. Add a salad with creamy dressing, bread and beverage and dinner is on the table.
 
 Meals Made Easy 

Cooking a healthy meal at home can be a simple process if you approach it mindfully. Planning ahead will make mealtimes less chaotic and maybe even save you some money because you don&apos;t have to eat food prepared outside the home as frequently. Plus, you and your family will get to relax more as you enjoy a variety of flavorful meals.
 
 How to Plan Easy Meals 

If your first thought about dinner occurs an hour or less before the food is supposed to be on the table, chances are, you will have a hectic hour. Shopping for and preparing food, all while keeping an eye on your children, is a tough task if you don&apos;t plan ahead. The best solution is to plan easy meals beforehand, usually for at least a week at a time. That way you can shop all at once and have a plan in place for dinner each night.
 
 Easy Meals That Contain Cream Cheese 

If you have been limiting your use of cream cheese to the occasional bagel, you have been severely underestimating the power of this soft, flavorful cheese. Not just for breakfast anymore, cream cheese can be put out at lunch and dinner as well. You may be surprised to find how versatile it actually is.
 
 Easy High-Protein Meals 

Whip up high-protein meals easily by choosing foods that cook quickly and selecting recipes that use canned or frozen ingredients. Children need from 2 to 6 1/2 ounces of protein daily, depending on their age and gender, while men and women need 5 to 6 1/2 ounces per day. If you regularly include meat in your meals but want to avoid high-fat, high-cholesterol choices, stick to fish and poultry or choose only the leanest red meats on occasion.
 
 Easy American Favorite Meal Ideas 

In a country that takes great pride in its melting-pot of cultures, it’s not always easy to identify quintessential American cuisine. We love to create fusion dishes from the various cultures that make up our nation, such as Asian, Italian, Mexican, Indian or Vietnamese. Still, there are easy, family-friendly dishes that various American regions call their own, even if they hold a hint of influence that harkens to a foreign cuisine.
 
 Easy Meals on a 1500-Calorie Diet 

One sure way to foil your weight loss efforts is to over-complicate things. If cooking is a chore you tend to dislike and avoid, then planning a diet that keeps you in the kitchen half the day may be doomed from the start. After a while, you&apos;ll want to get back to your normal life. Good news -- it doesn&apos;t mean you&apos;re doomed to salads and yogurt for the rest of your days. There are healthy meals you can prepare quickly and easily, and still keep under 1,500 calories per day.
 
 Fancy Easy Gourmet Meals 

If you let your kids plan the menu, you might be eating macaroni and cheese and hot dogs until they left for college. Instead, take some time to introduce your kids to the world of gourmet food, broadening their taste buds and adding excitement to family meals. Gourmet dinners don&apos;t have to be complicated or time-consuming. Sometimes the fanciest dishes are among the easiest to make.
 
 How to Make Easy Healthy Meals 

Serving healthy meals to your kids doesn&apos;t have to involve hours of chopping, prepping and slaving over a hot stove. Even moms with packed schedules and minimal kitchen skills can prepare nutritious, kid-friendly dishes in a pinch. Take advantage of ready-to-eat ingredients like cut and washed veggies from the grocery store, shredded cheese and prepared meats to make wholesome meals even simpler.
 
 Healthy, Inexpensive and Easy Meals 

Preparing meals that nourish your family but also fit in your budget may seem impossible, especially if you don&apos;t have all day to cook. However, there are plenty of healthy, inexpensive meals you can prepare quickly if you plan ahead and stock your home with the right ingredients.
 
 Quick Easy Meals for Hot Days 

On a hot summer day, the last thing you want to do is turn on the oven to prepare a piping hot meal. Unfortunately, your kids’appetites won’t wait until your body temperature drops 20 degrees. Some quick, easy meal ideas help keep your family satisfied, while allowing you to avoid the oven.
 
 Easy Meals to Freeze 

It’s almost 6 p.m., and you know you’re going to get the question any minute:“Mom, what’s for dinner?”If you plan ahead, and spend some time cooking and freezing meals for the week or the month, you can answer that question by naming a delicious casserole or meat dish, instead of“Do you want pizza or Chinese?”
 
 Easy Potluck Meal Ideas 

Entertaining can be a challenge for busy moms, especially those with younger children. One way to ease the load on everyone is with a potluck dinner party, in which every guest brings a dish. These can be anything-goes affairs or themed to a season or a specific holiday, such as Halloween or Christmas. Whether you&apos;re the host or guest at a potluck, get acquainted with a number of quick, easy-to-make dishes you can prepare.
 
 Quick Easy Meals for a Group of 50 Kids 

Although cooking for a group of 50 kids will require a little more preparation time than whipping up a meal for your family of four, it can still be a fairly simple task. Knowing how much you&apos;ll need of each ingredient you plan to use will help you to avoid a last-minute run to the grocery store. To save money and time, buy foods in bulk or items packed in multiples at warehouse clubs or discount stores.
 
 Meatless Meals Made Easy 

Whether you are converting your family over to a vegetarian lifestyle or just trying to incorporate meatless Mondays into your routine, cooking without meat doesn&apos;t have to be complicated. In some cases, it can be as simple as substituting a vegetarian ingredient for the meat in a recipe you use every day. If you are adding meatless meals to your menu on a regular basis, consider incorporating foods that are high in protein and iron, so that you&apos;ll never go lacking.
 
 Easy Family Meals for One Week 

American women with children under the age of 18 spend more than 90 minutes every day preparing food and cleaning up, according to 2009 U.S. Department of Agriculture statistics. If you&apos;re interested in spending less time in the kitchen, double up when you cook meals and freeze the extra for future meals. Experiment with the hot foods offered at your favorite grocery store for days when you just don&apos;t have time to cook, and incorporate ingredients such as canned chicken breast or tuna in quick-to-prepare casseroles.
 
 Easy But Impressive Meals 

If the in-laws are coming over or you&apos;re hosting a holiday party for your friends, you&apos;ll probably want to make an impressive meal. Unfortunately, most people don&apos;t have the time to dedicate an entire day to cooking dinner. The solution is to use some simple tricks and substitutions to create impressive meals without spending a lot of time. Go the easy route to surprise your guests with food they&apos;ll be raving about.
 
 Easy Meals to Cook While Camping 

Cooking over a campfire or a campground charcoal grill is part of the fun of camping. With a little planning before the trip, you&apos;ll enjoy tasty meals without a lot of fuss or cleanup. Pack dry ingredients such as pasta, rice and cereals in plastic storage bags to save space. Take along convenience foods such as instant mashed potatoes and instant rice. Bring along seasoning mixes and dip mixes for rich flavor variety in a lightweight format. Include canned chicken breast, tuna and other high-protein foods that need no refrigeration. Don&apos;t forget sandwich ingredients for quick lunches when you&apos;re going on a hike or relaxing by the water.
 
 Easy Meals in Less Than 30 Minutes 

Homemade and healthy doesn’t have to mean you’re stuck in the kitchen for hours on end. When life kicks into high gear, keep some quick meals in your arsenal for fast and easy preparation. Prepare easy meals in less than 30 minutes to feed the family nutritious and delicious fare that will disappear before your eyes.
 
 Easy Meals With a Grocery List 

Making meals for your kids that are healthy, delicious and easy can be a challenge. So many lunches and dinners that you want to make simply require too many ingredients that you don&apos;t have on hand. Fortunately, preparing a nutritious and yummy meal using only items that you would find on a regular grocery list is easier than you might think. Keep your kids happy and well-fed with a variety of quick meal ideas that won&apos;t stress you out or send you back to the grocery store for that one missing ingredient.
 
 Easy to Freeze Meals 

A freezer full of prepared meals can be a busy mom’s lifesaver. Known as freezer cooking, preparing meals ahead of time and freezing them can simplify a busy dinner hour immensely. As you consider using this menu strategy, opt for easy to freeze meals to ensure that the foods you pull from the freezer are tempting and tasty. When you heat these meals, add a tasty salad with creamy dressing for a fresh element.
 
 How to Prepare Easy Meals 

You don&apos;t need to slave over a stove for hours a day to prepare wholesome, tasty meals for your family. With a little planning, wise shopping and creativity you can have a healthy meal on the table in less than the time it would take to have takeout delivered to your door. Focus on ingredients and recipes that suit your busy lifestyle to make preparing a homemade meal fun and easy instead of overwhelming.
 
 Easy Meals With Baked Chicken Breasts 

It&apos;s dinnertime and you&apos;ve gotten as far as baked chicken breasts for dinner. If you&apos;re reheating them, don&apos;t forget to add some moisture to your meal to combat the dryness. If they&apos;re fresh baked, though, you don&apos;t have to just toss them on a plate with fries or slice them up for a salad topping. With those baked chicken breasts, a little imagination and just a few ingredients, you can whip up a tasty, no-fuss meal that will have your family clamoring for more.
 
 An Easy Meal With Boneless, Skinless Chicken Breasts 

Chicken is a cinch to make, and you can do pretty much anything with it. In particular, you can cook boneless, skinless chicken breasts relatively quickly, especially when you slice them thin. Whether you bake, microwave, steam, saute, stir fry, broil or grill the chicken, the only requirement is that you cook it to an internal temperature of 165 degrees for safety reasons. Use a meat thermometer in the thickest part of the meat to check to see if it&apos;s done.
 
 Easy Meals That Stretch Days 

If the combined demands of work and home life leave you little time or energy to cook entrees for yourself or your family from scratch every evening, consider meals that can be prepared in bulk and will stretch several days when properly refrigerated. If you shop for your ingredients at wholesale markets such as Smart&amp;Final, Sam&apos;s and Costco, these meals can also stretch your monthly food budget.
 
 Easy Beef Meal With Vegetables 

Roasted, baked, stewed or grilled, beef is versatile and available in a variety of cuts and prices. It&apos;s also popular; according to the U.S. Department of Agriculture, Americans eat an average of 61 lb. of beef each year. Beef combines well with vegetables of all types, from the classic comfort combination of mashed potatoes and meatloaf to a steak salad topped with a creamy peppercorn dressing. For easy beef-and-vegetable meals, choose recipes that let you prepare some items ahead of time or even cook everything in one pot. Protect your loved ones from foodborne illnesses by cooking steak to an internal temperature of at least 145 degrees F. Ground beef must reach a temperature of 160 degrees.
 
 Easy Party Meals 

Whether you&apos;re celebrating a toddler&apos;s birthday, a kindergarten graduation or the final game of your preteen&apos;s baseball season, keep the party food simple. Children like bite-size, tasty foods created with familiar flavors. Leave the gourmet puff-pastry creations for an evening with your adult friends. Kids want fun-to-eat, flavorful foods.
 
 Easy Healthy Freezable Meals 

One of the biggest pitfalls to healthy eating is running short on time and resorting to unhealthy convenience food. To help fit healthy eating into your busy schedule --- and keep it there --- plan meals that you can make ahead of time and freeze. Choose a slow, event-free day to cook several meals that can be frozen and reheated later. These meals are priceless time-savers during crazy weekdays when you need to feed the kids a nutritious, sit-down family meal but don&apos;t have time to cook.
 
 Incredibly Easy Weeknight Meals 

Even if you are a typically busy mom, you may recall an earlier era when your own mother worked to make a mouthwatering meal from scratch and called everyone in to sit down together and enjoy it. In a different world of work inside and outside the home, such traditions may go begging. Still, &quot;even in the face of a busy lifestyle, I refuse to give up the family dinner tradition,&quot; writes editor Elizabeth Taliaferro in &quot;Busy Moms Weeknight Favorites.&quot; The solution is incredibly easy weeknight meals that gather the family -- just like in the days of more elaborate preparations.
 
 Easy Meals a Husband Can Make 

While three-quarters of professional chefs are male, that dominance doesn&apos;t extend to husbands who serve as chefs for the family. Men prepare only 18 percent of evening meals at home, the research company NPD Group found. If you are not yet among the treasured category of husbands who can plan and prepare a gourmet multi-course meal without help, get started in the kitchen with easy meals that can earn just as much gratitude and affection from the family.
 
 Easy Cornish Game Hen Meals 

Cornish game hens -- whole, young hens that weigh only about 2 lbs. -- are just the right size for individual servings. Because the plump little hens consist primarily of lean, white meat, they often appeal to children and finicky eaters. Versatile Cornish game hens cook quickly using a variety of simple methods.
 
 Easy&amp;Cheap Meals for Big Groups 

While cooking for a large group may sound costly and time-consuming, you can trim costs and prep time -- and serve a nutritious meal to boot -- with savvy food choices. Group meals are not the time for elaborate gourmet meals. Take advantage of bulk cooking methods, convenience foods and low-cost ingredients to make group meals that cost little but taste great.
 
 Quick&amp;Easy Meals for Your Mother&apos;s Birthday 

Kids love to spoil mom on her birthday. Plan to make her a special meal -- and clean up the kitchen -- as a birthday surprise. The meal doesn&apos;t have to look gourmet to taste great. Keep the meal quick and easy by focusing on your mom&apos;s favorite foods. Remember, it&apos;s her day.
 
 Quick&amp;Easy Grilled Chicken Meals 

Not only is grilled chicken a quick and easy dish, side dishes that go well with it are also simple and fast to prepare.With the right selection of menu items the entire meal can be cooked at one time in one place, which makes cooking and clean up especially easy.
 
 Easy Vegetable Meals 

A diet rich in vegetables will provide you and your family with a variety of nutrients your bodies need to function properly. Vegetables also help adults and children maintain a healthy weight and aid in preventing a number of health conditions. Fixing vegetable-based meals may seem more time-consuming than heading out to dinner, but if you consider a few quick options, you may find that you save time and money eating at home.
 
 Easy Wedding Potluck Meals 

Wedding costs have gotten out of control for many couples. Some newlyweds choose to cut down on costs and make their wedding a more personal affair by hosting a potluck reception. Provided guests are willing to take part, a potluck is a fun, casual idea that eschews fussy catered food for favorite family recipes and comfort foods.
 
 Easy Meat&amp;Potato Meals 

Meat and potatoes are the foundation of satisfying, nutritious meals. Those meals can also be easy to prepare and cook. Casseroles of all types use just meat and potatoes together, or in combination with other vegetables. Slow cookers, popular for their everything-in-one-pot method of cooking, are an ideal way to combine meat and potatoes for an easy meal. Other meat and potato dishes are best baked in the oven for low-fat, convenient meal preparation and simplified cleanup.
 
 Easy Three-Course Meals 

Whether it&apos;s handling work, raising kids or both, busy moms can still make easy three-course meals for their family or friends. The three courses you choose to serve remain up to you, but quick and easy options, including dessert, offer healthy alternatives. Multiple ready-made ingredients found at the supermarket provide health-conscious benefits as well.
 
 Easy Peasy Meals 

When you work full time and are busy toting the kids to and from after-school activities, you may find yourself relying on fast food and pre-packaged meals. Though you probably realize these aren&apos;t the healthiest options, they&apos;re easy and filling. However, you don&apos;t have to be Julia Child and put in hours of labor to make a nutritious meal. Some very healthy meals are easy peasy to throw together.
 
 Easy Meals With White Beans 

A can of white beans boosts the iron, folate and fiber content of meals. Navy, cannellini and Great Northern beans are readily available white bean varieties that work well in a range of dishes. Using the canned version instead of dried beans saves you time on your meal prep. Try adding white beans into your child&apos;s favorite meals for a healthy improvement.
 
 Easy Good Pork Chop Meals 

With advanced farming techniques and the efforts of modern pork producers, today&apos;s pork chops are no longer fat-laden and unhealthy. Most lean pork chops are similar in fat content to a skinless chicken breast. In addition, pork provides plenty of important minerals and vitamins, including potassium, magnesium, iron, zinc, and certain B vitamins. Combined with whole grains and vegetables or fruit, pork chops are easily incorporated into a healthy meal plan.
 
 Easy-to-Freeze Healthy Meals 

Home-cooked frozen meals can enable you to serve your family a healthy, quick and convenient dinner in just minutes. During the week, all you need to do is reheat the meals in the oven or microwave and add your family&apos;s favorite salads or side dishes. To serve your family the best-tasting meals possible, pay careful attention to food safety during meal preparation and choose foods that will keep their taste and texture while spending time in the deep freeze.
 
 Easy Outside Potluck Meals 

Eating outdoors on a warm summer night is one of the great pleasures of life. Choosing the perfect dish to bring to the party can be less pleasurable. Keep it simple with dishes you can make in advance or put together quickly. Remember to consider how a dish will hold up in warm weather; skip mayonnaise-based foods, which can go bad quickly, and pick foods that won&apos;t melt in the sun.
 
 Fast&amp;Easy Three-Course Meals 

When you want to impress your family or guests with a three-course meal but don&apos;t have much time, choose a menu that you can put together quickly, even with kids underfoot. A three-course meal usually features a starter, a main dish and a dessert, all with a cohesive theme or style of cuisine.
 
 Healthy, Easy-to-Make Meals 

Healthy meals do not need to be complicated. In fact, less-complicated recipes with fewer ingredients are both healthy and easy to make. Stick to lean meats balanced with fresh fruits and vegetables. Add a helping of whole grains to round out a quick and simple healthy meal.
 
 The Valley Delivered
 
Register and get our newsletter featuring recipes, tips and special offers. Plus get the power to rate, review and comment.
 Join Now 
Related Topics
 
 Menus 

 A Menu with Baked Salmon A Menu With Eggplant Parmesan Menu for a Low-Fiber Diet 

 Fast Meals 

 Fast Skillet-Fried Meals Fast Pasta Meals Fast Skillet Meals 

 Meal Plans 

 Custom Meal Plans 30-Day Meal Plans A Daily Meal Plan With Protein, Grains, Vegetables,&amp;Fruits in 5 Meals 
 
 What&apos;s for Dinner Tonight? 

 Hidden Valley Minestrone Pasta Bake 
 See more recipes Food Tips Index Driven by Demand Media 
 Contact Us Our Story News FAQ Terms of Use Privacy Policy Promotion Rules Where to Buy Site Map Facebook ® You are now exiting this site. We are not responsible for the content or data collection practices of the site you are about to visit. Twitter You are now exiting this site. We are not responsible for the content or data collection practices of the site you are about to visit. 

©The HV Food Products Company. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
