<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003264" url="http://boston.citysearch.com/profile/4715748/boston_ma/wendy_s.html" time="2012-07-12-19:24" support="2" score="0.0016327276669925745" bingtitle="Wendy&apos;s - Boston, MA, 02108 - Citysearch - Boston, MA City Guide ..." webtitle="Wendy&apos;s - Boston, MA, 02108 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>100.0% positive “Wendy&apos;s is, without adoubt, my favorite fast food restaurant.” service: 100.0% positive “Prices are low, taste is good for fast food, and the ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Boston, MA Metro &gt; Boston &gt; Restaurants &gt; Wendy&apos;s 
Wendy&apos;s
 (617) 451-2328 
 349 Washington St , Boston , MA | Directions  
 02108 42.356601 -71.059400 View Website 
 Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 86 % 100 7 7 Votes Add a Photo Neighborhoods: Downtown, Central Cuisine: Fast Food , Hamburgers Price: $ Categories: Restaurants 
 View More 
 Payment Methods: MasterCard, Discover, Visa, American Express Restaurant Special Features: Cheap Eats , Carry Out , Family-Friendly Dining , Lunch Spot 
 View Less 
 At a Glance ? 
 100% food quality
 “The burgers are fresh, the fries are delicious - what more could you ask for in a burger joint?” 
 100% overall
 “Wendy&apos;s is, without adoubt, my favorite fast food restaurant.” 
 100% service
 “Prices are low, taste is good for fast food, and the service is extra speedy.” Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (7) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Wendy&apos;s 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Wendy&apos;s
 Contributor Joined 9 years ago August 04, 2008 
 Square burgers, chicken sandwiches and creamy desserts served in a homey setting.. In Short
 Named after the daughter of amiable founder Dave Thomas, this Ohio-based chain is more inviting than your typical fast-food joint, thanks to comforting touches like carpeted floors, Tiffany-style lamps and plenty of foliage. The signature square burgers are made-to-order; chicken sandwiches are available grilled or fried. Thick fries, meaty chili and stuffed baked potatoes round out a menu that includes a cool, ultra-thick chocolate Frosty. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends silencedotcom Joined 8 years ago 5.0 August 04, 2004 
 Very good. Wendy&apos;s is, without adoubt, my favorite fast food restaurant. I always get fast, friendly service. The food is also very hot, and very well priced.
 0 Heart Recommends lexluthor Joined 9 years ago 5.0 July 13, 2004 
 Good and cheap. You can get a delicious, full meal here for $3! Wendy&apos;s is by far the best fast food joint there is. Service is also more friendly than any other chain. The burgers are fresh, the fries are delicious - what more could you ask for in a burger joint? … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends tripleb789 Joined 9 years ago 3.0 November 04, 2003 
 Good cheap lunch. Prices are low, taste is good for fast food, and the service is extra speedy. Good choice if you are pressed for time on a lunch break.
 0 Heart Recommends bRwNiE Joined 9 years ago 5.0 February 07, 2003 
 tastylicious. I luv Wendy&apos;s fries there the Bomb!!And i also lke their jr.bacon cheese burger...yummm...that&apos;s all the time i think about,and with realy good sauce(honey musterd).
 0 Heart 
 See more tips for Wendy&apos;s 
 Write a Tip for Wendy&apos;s 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 50 % Burger King 1 Ctr Plz Ste E 
 Boston, MA 
0.3 mi away McDonald&apos;s 702 Washington St 
 Boston, MA 
0.4 mi away 100 % Milk Street Cafe 50 Milk St 
 Boston, MA 
0.1 mi away 
 
Things to do near Wendy&apos;s
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
