<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003408" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/mcdonalds-rude-service-and-employees-that-dont-speak-english/" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="19" score="0.028701266307891323" bingtitle="McDonalds - rude service and employees that don&apos;t speak English ..." webtitle="McDonalds - rude service and employees that don&apos;t speak English | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000877" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001065" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001190" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>I wanted to confirm with the lady that we had ... some of the worst food out there for any fast food restaurant. ... or item, and it is always the person on front counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 How to file a complaint on the number one, most trusted consumer complaints website - ReportYourComplaint.com! AT&amp;T;and their slimy service Walgreens Pharmacy Photo Developing Center - Had horrible customer service and dealt with old photo machines that froze up Sokolove law firm and Accutane – are they for real or is this all a scam? NASCAR Hall of Fame Review - This Is An Amazing Hall of Fame Filled With Interactive Activities And Educational Information! Moldy buns at Hardees on University Blvd. Charlotte, NC CNN Tower Tour Review - Atlanta Georgia CNN Is A Must See For Everyone Of All Ages! Kickasstorrents torrent download website review - one of my favorite places to get movie torrents, books, documentaries and more! Hot fast food restaurant complaints here on ReportYourComplaint! Best Buy and Toshiba Complaint - They Wouldn&apos;t Fix My Laptop And Tried Telling Me I Personally Damaged My Computer! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
McDonalds–rude service and employees that don’t speak English
 By buddybrown 
The double arches at McDonald&apos;s stand for rude service and no English!
 



Earlier today I went to the McDonald’s on Harris Blvd. in Charlotte North Carolina. My sons were hungry and wanted a happy meal. So we pulled up to the drive-through and proceeded to order two happy meals. Both with four pieces of chicken, french fries and apple juice. Apparently the person taking order either didn’t hear me straight or never listened in the first place.

When they repeated back my order they told me that had ordered porkies of chicken french fries and apple juice but not as a part of a happy meal. So I kindly corrected them and said that we wanted two happy meals and that they were each to have four pieces of chicken, french fries and apple juice. At this point the person taking our order got curt and rude with my wife. She said,“I got that, bye!”It was as if we had done something to offend or bother her and that would be far from the truth as we were as polite as we possibly could have been.

 Been taken advantage of? Want to get even? Leave your own complaints and reviews here on ReportYourComplaint.com and help others avoid businesses and companies with which you’ve had terrible experiences! 

But that’s not the end of it, then we pulled up to the next window to pay for it. I wanted to confirm with the lady that we had ordered two happy meals and she said,“yah, we got your order give me your money…”she wasn’t too polite and so I handed her $10 and she gave back my change and never answered me as to whether they had corrected the order and made sure it was two happy meals. When I asked her again all she would do is point to the next window.




 Your Ad Here 


So we pulled up to the window to pick up our stuff and this time the lady at the window spoke absolutely no English whatsoever. At least she was honest though, she said,“No English.”She did however give us the two happy meals.  My wife opened them and found that there was no toys in the two happy meals which are supposed to be in there.  My kids aged 2 and 4 were really upset at this as they liked the toys that were always a part of McDonald’s happy meals.   So at this, I parked our car and walked up to the McDonald’s and went inside and asked if we could get the toys that are supposed to come with the happy meals.

 Learn how to download the latest movies, music, software and games 100% free and safe with a VPN! 

The lady I talked to said that they were out of toys for the happy meals.  She then asked if I would like an apple pie for the kids instead.  She went to get the apple pies and apparently they were out of those also.  All she could do was say that she was sorry and I had to go back out to the car right kids were screaming and upset that they didn’t have toys in their happy meals–boy that was a fun ride home.  I don’t think I’ll be going back to that McDonald’s for quite some time.



 
Posts Related to McDonalds - rude service and employees that don&apos;t speak English

 
 McDonalds employees review and complaint–bad customer service and rude behavior towards customers. 

// I went to this McDonald&apos;s restaurant located on El Camino Real in Sunnyvale and had the worst cashier you could possible imagine behind the ...
 
 Aldi’s has racist employees that knowingly discriminate against ethnic groups like Spanish Americans! 

// I have always enjoyed shopping at ALDI&apos;s store as they do have very low prices. But that all changed today; the service I had ...
 
 DELL Customer Support 

If you want to talk to someone in India or someone from far across the seas, then this is your customer support you ...
 
 Walmart–Employees that suck!, Rude Customer Service and Untrustworthy Employees! 

// Everytime I have to go into Walmart I cringe.  The only reason I shop here is because its the only store in town.   I ...
 
 Walmart Customer Service Complaint–Rude Employees Whom Don’t Know Company Policies and Practices 

// Today I needed to go to Wal-Mart to pick up a couple things before the work week began.  As I was walking through the ...
 
 
 Tags: bad customer service , complaint , Customer service , fast food , fastfood , Horrible , horrible service , McDonald&apos;s , Not recommended , restaurant , rude , sucks , Terrible 
 
11 Responses to McDonalds–rude service and employees that don’t speak English 
 Newer Comments→ 
 Moreen Jacobs on May 28, 2010 at 8:35 PM 

McDonalds sucks. Their fries taste like cardboard and need loads of salt just to eat them. Their burgers are loaded with fat and mean just go look at the movie Supersize Me and just see how healthy McDonald’s is for you. I would never venture into a McDonald’s. Besides I used to work in one when I was a teenager. The things I saw some of the other employees do would make me never want to eat there again. They would spit on burgers or picked their nose and wipe it on a bun for angry customers or people they didn’t like. When you pay employees minimum wage that is what you get and nothing more. I don’t want spit in my burgers so I will not go to McDonald’s.

Like or Dislike: 2   2 
 Ronnie Jackson on May 30, 2010 at 9:07 PM 

I agree–McDonald’s is probably the worst fast food out there. It sucks and I can’t understand why so many people still go there.

Like or Dislike: 1   1 
 Winston Daigle on June 1, 2010 at 1:50 PM 

You know what? McDonald’s has some of the worst food out there for any fast food restaurant. So why would you even bother going there when you have far better places like Hardee’s, Jack-in-the-Box and even Burger King out there? I think that if enough people start avoiding McDonald’s they will start to change their ways.

Like or Dislike: 1   2 
 mika on August 6, 2010 at 7:31 PM 

yeah I hate mcdonalds like that.. but your kids seriously sound like brats. Crying over not getting a toy? haha

Like or Dislike: 4   1 
 Oh Really? on October 22, 2010 at 8:49 AM 

Hey, I just had to chime in on this subject here . And I know from my personal experience that since I’ve stopped eating McDonalds I feel a whole hell of a lot better. It was like it had me so overweight&amp;just feeling lazy and fatigued all the time, I just had to put an end to it. Iits been almost a year since I’ve ventured in a MD drive thru&amp;I feel great! Parents’please don’t feed that crap to your kids. I’m not judging, because I don’t have any children of my own, but I just know that I was given that junk at a very early age and it was a hard habit for me to kick

Like or Dislike: 2   1 
 Mariah on November 5, 2010 at 9:45 AM 

I understand that you had a bad McDonalds experience, and there was certainly no reason for the person in back to treat you with such disrespect but as an employee of McDonalds I feel obliged to say something in regards to this.

Generally, crew members are treated horribly by the general public and it can really upset a person. That still doesn’t excuse the person for being so rude, but it could be a possible explanation.

It isn’t always the fault of McDonalds if they are out of a product or item, and it is always the person on front counter catching the angry drive thru customers. However, if you had gotten home and called McDonalds to tell them something was missing from your Happy Meals you would have been entitled to two free ones next visit.

It also is not acceptable that you were not told ahead of time that the store had no toys. That McDonalds should probably be reported, but this should not be representative of the company as a whole.

Like or Dislike: 4   2 
 Alyssa on November 29, 2010 at 11:44 AM 

I have worked at McDonalds for a year and a half. n just that time you see a lot of stupid arrogant people. People sit on their computers talking about sevice and food. And hey you think it’s nasty tasting–dont freaking eat there. Just cause it’s there dosent mean you need to shove it in your face. And I love how people complain on employees. When over half you idiots don’t understand most all regulations are set by corporate.

Or how it’s a minumum wage job that can ultimatly suck half the time. I love my job tho. I do really well at it it was just the way I was raised. Like respecting the person giving you your food. I have learned something in this job try to be friendly and fast and I am almomst all the time. I make the food and run up and bag it. Because some people do have their heads up there butts.

One day I tell my managers where out of reg buns. For those who don’t know what that is its a bun used (for the cheaper sandwichs like hamburgers.) They just keep going don’t say anything to me like heres my keys go get them. Cause they know theirs no doubt I would have gotten it.

Then 1 hour later where in a rush. And guess what happens. So now the people in drive thru have been sitting their 600 seconds and counting. While my managers trying to unthaw the buns. And the better thing I was in grill. When we ran out she went into grill and put me in drive. So I could deal with all yo #@$ holes. When it would have gone alot faster with me back there but whatever.

Than this customer comes up to me window pissy. I tell her I am really sorry. Give her her food truly right when she pulled up to my window and she starts getting pissy. Well if I could talk to cusomers with the sam respect they talked to me I would have said“excuse me mam but I didn’t f### up it was my manager and now sh stuck me up here to deal with you and your bi###ing. Get your @@@ out my window so these customers dont get so pissed.”

And stay out of the drive thru. Go figure half the waits atthe speaker because you have no freaking clue what you want. than you cant see the menu its to far. Yeah right its like 5ft away dumb@@@ learn how to read. Want faster service learn how to order. And another hint for you idiots order sauceses at the box. Not when you get to my window cause that slows me down so it slows everything down and I will charge you 25 cents cause most people will just leave when if you orderd at the box I wouldn’t care no charge. Just use your brain.

Worst custome of the year- I had a 5 year old in drive scraming her head of while her moms ordering. Cant hear you mam. Sorry still cant hear you. When you wnt to shout your the worst fuc@@@@ parent shut her up and dont get her a frappe. She is 5 getting a coffee drink cause shes throwing a tantrum thats a great way to handle.

One last thing this whole happy meal ban thing.wtf. Chidren eat these right. I don’t think I have ever had a child come in by themselves and buy themselves one. It’s the parents etc…. They decided to buy their child that so can some one explain why some places are making the toys outlawed. Seriously its not us its the parents its you.

Like or Dislike: 1   4 
 Tyson on May 10, 2011 at 4:39 AM 

i would like to see the people who complain about mcdonalds emplyoees: work in a hot greasy environment, with constant beeping and people yelling at you, while enduring relentless rude customers, while doing degrading things like dig through trash for someones watch or clean messy bathrooms, oh and while being treated like shit, and all for min wage or less. oh yea they do that

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Jade on July 14, 2011 at 9:07 AM 

Look, I used to work in fast food and yes, it’s a horrible job.
BUT Alyssa and Tyson the job is a CHOICE. If you don’t have the balls to deal with angry/rude people all day then stop whining, get your head out of you ass and find another job. You JOB is to make people happy, whether you like it or not. That’s what customer service is, kids. You suck it up, smile, and give people what they want, within reason of course.
You get treated like shit, yes. The environment you work in is deplorable, yes…but it’s also money going in your pocket.
I worked at a McDonald’s for three years until I could start going to college and never had to step foot in there again. HOWEVER I still am working closely with clients in my new profession, and you know what? There are rude people I have to deal with here as well. Am I rude back? No, because that simply isn’t tolerated when your handling clients that spend millions of dollars on a companies product. So stop whining, kids and do your job. It honestly doesn’t get much different.

Like or Dislike: 2   0 
 ANNIE on July 4, 2012 at 7:14 PM 

FUCK YOUR CHILDREN, TELL THEM TO SHUT THE FUCK UP. SCREAMING CHILDREN MAKE ME SICK,I WAS AT THAT MCDONALDS AND YOUR THE RUDE ONE BITCH AND CAN TAKE YOUR LITTLE TURDS AND GO SOMEWHERE ELSE, NO WONDER WHY I HATE KIDS SO MUCH THEY SCREAM OVER NOTHING ITS ONLY A FUCKING TOY, STUFF A SOCK DOWN THERE THROAT TO SHUT THEM UP, GEEEZ

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 Newer Comments→ 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
