<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003410" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Ardmore/Burger-Ranch" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="2" score="0.0012420633718997131" bingtitle="Burger Ranch - Fast Food Restaurant Ardmore, OK" webtitle="Burger Ranch - Fast Food Restaurant  Ardmore, OK">
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="67"/>
	<description>Burger Ranch is a Fast Food restaurant located at 708 S Lake ... Five Napkin Burger, New York City - Restaurant ... Welcome to Bill’s Bar &amp; Burger, New York Burger ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Burger Ranch
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(580) 226-1700

 
 OK &gt; Ardmore &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Burger Ranch listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Burger Ranch to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Burger Ranch
 Burger Ranch is a Fast Food restaurant located at 708 S Lake Murray Dr Se in Ardmore, OK . Burger Ranch has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, American, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Burger Ranch
 
 
 
All Reviews for Burger Ranch


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Burger Ranch:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Burger Ranch News
 A galaxy of stuffed pizzas awaits diners at Chris&apos;s But at Chris&apos;s New York ... chicken ranch with chicken, bacon, cheese and ranch dressing. There are stuffed pizzas that include the taco pizza with seasoned beef, lettuce, tomato, sour cream and black olives, and the bacon cheddar burger with ... Best Eats On The Beach burgers and more, Dead Freddies Island Grill’s menu was created with years of experience for this new location. Open daily at 11 a.m. Decor and atmosphere are definitely ranch. The sounds are laughing children and happy families, and the food ... A year of great eating: The top 11 restaurants of 2011 I get to reread all the restaurant reviews I&apos;ve written throughout 2011 ... “The Harvest Dog” began with the same weiner but it was gussied up with warm apple slices, New York cheddar, local maple bacon and maple syrup. Celebrate New Years with tempting comfort foods at Jack Callaghan&apos;s Some of the best dressing selections are ranch, bleu cheese ... are the granny smith apple pie and New York style cheesescake. All of the above are delicious selections. So, the next time you are looking for a great restaurant with excellent food and ... Ski Gourmet: Ultimate Guide To Luxury Ski Town Dining I love après ski burgers ... San Francisco or New York, and wants the same level on their ski vacation. With the exception of my insider picks at “Local Knowledge” below, these are not cheap. Also, since I only include restaurants of ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Jackson Hole Burgers, New York: 7 oz Burger Restaurants and ... Jackson Hole Burgers New York - Home of the 7 oz Burgers, Restaurants and Catering Services in New York City, we offer famous Bronco Chicken Sandwich, best and ... Five Napkin Burger, New York City - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor &quot;I think we got our food before we ordered!!! LOL Really, the service was incredibly ...&quot; · &quot;Good burgers, very popular place, best to book beforehand and ... Mini Burger Restaurant | New York, NY | 10009 | Burgers Delivery Order Chinese Cuisine online from Mini Burger Restaurant in 10009. Best Online Food Delivery in New York, NY. New York Restaurants Known as the city that never sleeps, New York offers a truly spectacular range of restaurants. We review a wide selection of the best New York Restaurants covering ... Bills Bar&amp;Burger Restaurant New York | Burger Restaurants in ... Welcome to Bill’s Bar&amp;Burger, New York Burger Restaurants in Meatpacking, Rockefeller Center and Beyond 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 88° 
Fri
 
 73° - 95° 
Sat
 
 73° - 91° 
Sun
 
 73° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Burger Ranch

708 S Lake Murray Dr Se

Ardmore, OK 
 

 
Telephone
 (580) 226-1700 
Burger Ranch
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Burger Ranch Photos
 
 Fast Food American American 
 
 Local Places
 
 Crystals Catfish Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Baldwins Restaurant&amp;Drive in 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Cafe Alley 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burgers&amp;Fries 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Comet Drive Inn 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Arby&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Ponders Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger Ranch 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Art Shop 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Goddard Center Art Studios 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Studio Catalonia 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Gene Autry Museum 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Merritt Young 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Ardmore Art Museums Galleries 
See all Ardmore ATMs 
See all Ardmore Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Burger Ranch Coupons 

 Burger Ranch Ardmore 

 Burger Ranch Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Ardmore Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P R | S | T | W | Y 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
