<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003819" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Atascadero/InNOut-Burger_7" time="2012-07-12-19:58" support="2" score="0.003743182677856442" bingtitle="In-N-Out Burger - Fast Food Restaurant Atascadero, CA" webtitle="In-N-Out Burger - Fast Food Restaurant  Atascadero, CA">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000981" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>In-N-Out Burger a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 6000 San ... Order a bare meat pattie as a road snack for the dog! ... California, Illinois, and New York, offers a number ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
In-N-Out Burger
 
Average User Rating
 
8
 
Great

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(800) 786-1000

 http://www.in-n-out.com/ 
 CA &gt; Atascadero &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim In-N-Out Burger listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by In-N-Out Burger to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About In-N-Out Burger
 In-N-Out Burger is a Fast Food restaurant located at 6000 San Anselmo Rd in Atascadero, CA . In-N-Out Burger has been described as an Great Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 8 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, American, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for In-N-Out Burger
 
 
 
All Reviews for In-N-Out Burger

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
8
 
Decor
 
8
 
Service
 
8
 
I eat here often. The food and service is excellent.. They know us there now and when we walk in the door they know what we want to drink without asking..
 
Overall Rating
 
8
 
&quot;Great&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about In-N-Out Burger:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
Tweets from In-N-Out Burger
 
 January 01, 1970   Reply 
 
 January 01, 1970   Reply 
 
In-N-Out Burger Tips
 Order a bare meat pattie as a road snack for the dog! Or break it up and mix it with the kibble like I do! Only $0.75!
 
Andrew S. Best Fast Food Chain known to man. Try a Double-Double Cheeseburger, and don&apos;t forget the fries and milkshake! (Strawberry milkshake is the best ever)
 
Timothy M. &quot;Protein Style&quot; = burger wrapped in lettuce instead of a bun
 
slonews Animal style!
 
Noah N. Get the flying dutchman and the root beer float
 
StuCat S. 
In-N-Out Burger News
 Can landmark steak burger chain beat In-N-Out? Steak &apos;n Shake, which plans to add units in Southern California, is expected to open a new takeout concept next month in New York City ... retro interior) and In-N-Out Burger (drive-through, addictive burgers, inexpensive menu). An international foodie&apos;s annual list of the year&apos;s best (and worst) food Here&apos;s my look back at the Best&amp;Worst Food of 2011: Best steak: New York strip, Ore House ... of cellophane and the texture of beetle larvae. Worst fast food: In-N-Out Burger, 3801 Inglewood Ave., Redondo Beach, Calif., 800-786-1000. Top 7 Quick Serve Trends for 2012 Rather, Hahn-Griffiths says that customers will turn to premium sandwiches like the burgers by Five Guys or In N Out to reward themselves without ... which has locations in California, Illinois, and New York, offers a number of online ordering options ... 2011: The people and stories that captivated us most The driving force was the North Texas invasion of In-N-Out Burger ... patty from Pop&apos;s Burgers&amp;Grill, an upstart tucked in a strip mall in far west Fort Worth. In the end, Pops rocked our socks off and, in August, a new burger king was ... FIRST Food&amp;Bar Serves Up Neighborhood Bar Concept To The Las Vegas Strip “White Castle Buns, In-N-Out flavors, and Big Mac composition. It’s the Sammy D flavor, which is coming to our new burger project later this year at the Venetian. Burger joints beware.” The restaurant ... 10 years in New York City. 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing In-N-Out Burger - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia In-N-Out Burger is a regional chain of fast food restaurants with locations in the western United States. Founded in 1948 by Harry Snyder and his wife Esther ... Jackson Hole Burgers, New York: 7 oz Burger Restaurants and ... Jackson Hole Burgers New York - Home of the 7 oz Burgers, Restaurants and Catering Services in New York City, we offer famous Bronco Chicken Sandwich, best and ... Five Napkin Burger, New York City - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor &quot;Good burgers, very popular place, best to book beforehand and even then I reckon you ...&quot; · &quot;Went for early lunch before afternoon play. Great burgers ... IN-N-OUT Burger In 1948, the first In-N-Out Burger was founded by Harry and Esther Snyder in Baldwin Park. Harry&apos;s idea of a drive-thru hamburger stand where customers could order ... New York » Restaurants » Burgers - Yelp 534 businesses reviewed for Burgers in New York on Yelp. Read about places like:Carnegie John&apos;s, The Burger Bistro, Juniper, Dubuque, Feed Your Hole Truck... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 77° 
Fri
 
 52° - 97° 
Sat
 
 50° - 86° 
Sun
 
 52° - 84° 
 
Address
 
In-N-Out Burger

6000 San Anselmo Rd

Atascadero, CA 
 

 
Telephone
 (800) 786-1000 
In-N-Out Burger
 
 Rating :  8 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
In-N-Out Burger Photos
 
 Fast Food American American 
 
 Local Places
 
 A&amp;W Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food In-N-Out Burger 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Adobe Plaza Shopping Center Carls Jr Restaurants 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway Sandwiches&amp;Salads 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway Sandwiches&amp;Salads 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs Atascadero Federal CU 
Cuisine: ATMs ATM Merchant Systems 
Cuisine: ATMs Automated Financial LLC 
Cuisine: ATMs 
 

See all Atascadero ATMs 
See all Atascadero Bars and Pubs 
See all Atascadero Day Spas 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 In-N-Out Burger Coupons 

 In-N-Out Burger Atascadero 

 In-N-Out Burger Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Atascadero Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
