<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003509" url="http://www.ichoosefit.org/top-10-worst-foods/" time="2012-07-12-19:39" support="1" score="0.0005643935581372601" bingtitle="Top 10 Worst Foods | Boot Camps | Cross Training | Fitness" webtitle="Top 10 Worst Foods | Boot Camps | Cross Training | Fitness">
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>#6 store bought baked goods – filled with sugars ... ***If you go to the fast food restaurant and get a hamburger, drink ... Leave a Reply Cancel reply. You must be logged in to ...</description>
	<body>
		Boot Camps | Cross Training | Fitness 

Dallas – Fort Worth – Arlington – Mansfield – Midlothian – Plano – Irving–Waxahachie–Burleson–Southlake
 Search 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 iChoosefit Training Boot Camps DFW Boot Camp Locations About Us Contact Us Sign Up For Boot Camp 
 
Post navigation
 ← Previous Next → 
Top 10 Worst Foods
 Posted on October 19, 2011 by atucker 
 Top 10 worst foods 

I got this from Natalie’s nutrition, check her out, she has great nutrition tips for people who are trying to get better.

 

 # 10 Fried Cat Fish is a bottom feeder fish, full of toxins. Not nutrient rich like salmon. You have a filet, cover it with white flour, which is also devoid of nutrients and deep fry. FILLED WITH FAT, CARCENIGENS, CALORIES

 #9 canned Soup – “Soup is good food” no. Too high in sodium.  Has MSG, which is a preservative. And filled with trans fats. Back to sodium. The recommended daily intake is 2400mg maximum. You can get 1100 mg from one cup!

 #8 Bacon AKA fried salt and fat.  2 strips of drained bacon =10g fat!

 #7 Fast Food Hamburgers – lets not eat this for lunch. Jack in the box ultimate cheeseburger has 1010 calories, 71g fat, 1580 mg sodium&amp;12g sugar. Averaged person needs 2000 calories a day.

 #6 store bought baked goods – filled with sugars and high fructose corn syrup

# 5 Potato chips – “you can’t just have 1!” Yeah because they are so addictive! Processed to the max, dipped in transfats covered with hydrogenated oils. Not the best option.

 # 4 Hot Dogs&amp;lunchmeat AKA mystery meat! Unless it says nitrate free then it will influence cancer. There was a study in Hawaii studied 200000 people. Those who ate the most lunchmeats had a 67% higher chance of Pancreatic Cancer— You can find nitrate free at Whole Foods

 #3 Fast Food French Fries . are nothing more than a glue or paste that they fry.  Excess calories, excess sodium that you do not need. A large French fry contains 300 times the recommended amount of acrylamide by the EPA, which will lead to potential health problems

 #2 Donuts – pick your flavor! Sprinkles, coconut, chocolate, glaze etc…—1 Donut is filled with 300 useless calories and 19g fat.  And you will eat more than 1 when you do.

 #1 Soda – all soft drink varieties. Filled with sugars and high fructose corn syrup, which reduces your feeling of fullness. Loaded with caffeine, preservatives if you get the 42-ounce, it has a whopping 400 calories. This is Liquid candy; you are just sucking down sugar. If you are trying to lose weight then this is the first thing you want to eliminate. You will have more energy and you will lose weight.

***If you go to the fast food restaurant and get a hamburger, drink with fries, then you got 3 things on the list. This is why you may feel bad all day. I will end this by saying if you eat better you will feel better!!!
 This entry was posted in Diet&amp;Healthy Eating and tagged aj tucker , Mansfield Boot Camp , nutrition tips , weight loss by atucker . Bookmark the permalink . 
2 thoughts on“ Top 10 Worst Foods ”

 Freeman08 on October 19, 2011 at 4:15 pm said: 
I did not no that about the lunchmeat. does that include lunch meat cut at the deli?
 Log in to Reply 
 atucker on October 20, 2011 at 9:47 am said: 
It includes some lunch meats, it depends on which kind it is. Jump into one of our grocery tours to get the nitty gritty
 Log in to Reply 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 

You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
Fitness Training
 Boot Camp 
 Get Started Today! 
 iChoosefit Kits 
Lifestyle Management
 Weight loss
Nutritional plans
Boost energy levels 
Get Started Today!
 SIGN UP NOW! 
 Contact Us 
817.774.6552 As always, you should consult a licensed physician before beginning any exercise program. iChoosefit is not responsible for any injury sustained while exercising at your gym, house, or elsewhere. Copyright©2011 iChoosefit.net All Rights Reserved. Powered by Tier 1 IP
	</body>
</document>
