<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003864" url="http://www.restaurantjobboard.com/cashierstation-attendant/" time="2012-07-12-20:01" support="5" score="0.01470889410088955" bingtitle="CASHIER/Station Attendant | Cashier in Jackson, Mississippi" webtitle="CASHIER/Station Attendant | Cashier in Jackson, Mississippi">
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>CASHIER/Station Attendant Jackson-Evers International ... Select Hourly Positions, then enter Job # 101594 ... Restaurant Jobs</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Jobs Easily search for hospitality jobs in your area. 
 FAQs Contact TOS&amp;Privacy 
 May 4, 2010 
CASHIER/Station Attendant
 
At HMSHost, we have exciting career opportunities for customer friendly people. With more than 200 locations in the U.S., including airports, motorways, malls and specialty destinations, we have a place near you where your career can take off. HMSHost operates in more than 100 airports around the globe, including the 20 busiest airports in North America. With annual sales in excess of $2.7 billion, we employ more than 34,000 sales associates worldwide.

CASHIER/Station Attendant
Jackson-Evers International Airport
(JOB # 101594)

The Station Attendant is responsible for performing a variety of duties within a fast food establishment which may include cleaning the food or stock areas, assisting in the kitchen area, and maintaining inventory; performing all other responsibilities as directed by the business or as assigned by management. This is a non-exempt position and typically reports to the Store Manager.

Specific duties include:

* Cleans and stocks customer eating area(s)
* Greets all customers with a smile and friendly greeting and follows all HMSHost customer service policies and procedures
* Maintains a solid knowledge of product and services available in unit
* Transfers supplies and equipment between storage and work areas by hand or cart
* Assists with a variety of kitchen-related functions as needed
* Receive, inventory, move and lift food and beverage products and supplies
* Cleans and sanitizes work stations and equipment

Requirements:

* Demonstrates the ability to interact with the public and coworkers in a friendly, enthusiastic and outgoing manner Ability to bend, twist, and stand to perform normal job functions
* Ability to bend, twist, and stand to perform normal job functions
* Requires the ability to speak, read and comprehend instructions, short correspondence and policy documents, as well as converse comfortably with customers
* Customer service and cash handling experience preferred

At HMSHost, we supply our team members with the ability to maximize their potential so that they can achieve each of their goals. Join us today and get your career moving forward!

To apply, visit us at www.hmshost.com/careers. Select“Hourly Positions,”then enter Job # 101594

HMSHost
Making the Traveler’s Day Better.
www.HMSHost.com
EOE M/F/D/V A Drug-Free Environment
Pre-employment drug screenings and background checks will be performed on all candidates. Additional pre-employment testing based on brand requirements may apply.

Ads
 Written by oneclick45 Posted in Cashier 
Comments are closed.
 COOK Shift Supervisor/Lead–Commissary 
Search
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 F&amp;B jobs–Job Fair March 15th&amp;16th Starbucks Job Fair–Memphis Cashiers/Snack Bar Attendants F&amp;B Opps Cooks, F&amp;B Opps Job Fair, March 5-8 
 
Categories

 Asst. Manager Baker Bar Back Barista Bartender Bus Person Cashier Chef Cook Counter Help Deli Clerk Dishwasher Entertainment Fast Food Cashier Fast Food Cook Food Runner Host(ess) Kitchen Helper Manager Other Server Sous Chef
	</body>
</document>
