<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003527" url="http://www.millenniumseating.com/breakroom-furniture.html" time="2012-07-12-19:40" support="8" score="0.010278728609740776" bingtitle="Breakroom Furniture, Breakroom Seating" webtitle="Breakroom Furniture, Breakroom Seating">
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>Whether your needs are booths, tables and chairs, trash ... stand ready to assist you to layout the room and pick ... Availability: Build to Order Ships in 3-4 Weeks</description>
	<body>
		Breakroom Furniture, Breakroom Seating
 TOLL FREE: (866) 379-8422 
 Mon - Fri, 9am - 5pm EST My Account | Quote Cart 
 
 
 Restaurant Booths Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Tables Cafeteria Seating Breakroom Seating Outdoor Furniture 
 
 PRODUCTS Cluster Seating Restaurant Benches Waste&amp;Trash Receptacles Outdoor Restaurant Furniture Restaurant Booths Restaurant Booths Contour Booths Upholstered Booths Wood Restaurant Booths Retro Diner Booths Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Chairs Metal Restaurant Chairs Wooden Restaurant Chairs Stacking Restaurant Chairs Retro Diner Chairs Outdoor Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Tables Restaurant Tables Table Bases Laminate Table Tops Wood Table Tops Retro Diner Tables Commercial Bar Stools Commercial Bar Stools Metal Bar Stools Wood Bar Stools Retro Bar Stools Outdoor Bar Stools Diner Furniture Diner Furniture Diner Booths Diner Chairs Diner Stools Diner Tables Customer Service Have Questions? 

 (866) 379-8422 
Mon-Fri 8-5 EST

» Send an email Home &gt; Breakroom Furniture 
Breakroom Furniture
 Like 




Millennium Seating got its start designing corporate breakrooms for vending companies and businesses. We are the unsurpassed leader in this field. No job is too big or too small for Millennium Seating — we are your one stop source for all your breakroom furniture needs — both indoor and out.

Whether your needs are booths, tables and chairs, trash receptacles, custom cabinets or highly durable outdoor furniture, our customer service design specialists stand ready to assist you to layout the room and pick style, color and frame selection which most meets your needs for durability and yet stays within your budget. Our design specialists can also help you develop a theme design such as a Retro 50&apos;s look or NASCAR, etc.

Browse our site and contact us — we are here to assist you.

Our #1 goal at Millennium Seating is your second order. We will not be undersold!


 
 Show 24 Per Page 48 Per Page 72 Per Page 96 Per Page 120 Per Page Breakroom Furniture Products 1-11 of 11 
 Ergonomic Shell Stack Chair 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: In Stock 
Ships in 1-2 Days List Price: $69.00 Price: $18.99 
 See options. Fiberglass Shell Seat Stack Chair 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $154.99 Price: $86.99 
 See options. 42-inch Wall Style Contour Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $1,117.00 Was: $558.99 Sale: $499.99 
 See options. Quick Ship 42-inch Wall Style Contour Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 2 Weeks List Price: $1,117.00 Price: $558.99 
 See options. 42-inch Island Style Contour Booth 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $1,231.00 Was: $615.99 Sale: $531.99 
 See options. Fiberglass Shell Seat Stacking Chair 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $201.00 Price: $100.99 
 See options. Shell Stacking Chair w/Leg Base 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 4 Weeks List Price: $61.00 Was: $31.99 Sale: $30.99 
 See options. 6 Seat Round Outdoor Cluster Seating 
 

 [more info...] 


 Availability: Build to Order 
Ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $2,711.00 Was: $1,355.99 Sale: $1,253.99 
 See options.
	</body>
</document>
