<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003383" url="http://community.tasteofhome.com/community_forums/f/30/t/280117.aspx" time="2012-07-12-19:31" support="3" score="0.0027936548316682868" bingtitle="Maid-Rite Sandwich | Taste of Home Community" webtitle="Maid-Rite Sandwich | Taste of Home Community">
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>... only mustard, pickles, and/or onions for condiments. ... as all the pink in the meat is gone, add 1 cup ... A fast-food restaurant chain originating in Iowa is wellknown for ...</description>
	<body>
		Shop Taste of Home Free Newsletters Digital Editions App Share Your Recipe 
 
 Log In Join Us 
 
 Subscribe &gt; Digital Edition &gt; Give a Gift &gt; Customer Care &gt; 
 
 Recipes 
 Advanced Search Course Ingredients Holidays Top 10 Recipes More... 
 Healthy 
 Recipe Makeovers Healthy Menus Special-Diets Comfort Food Diet Live-Well Healthy Cooking Plus 
 Community 
 Forums Groups Cooks Who Care 
 Videos 
 Playlists Search Videos Submit Videos Taste of Home Videos 
 Cooking Schools 
 About Us Find a Show Meet Our Staff FAQs How to Cook 
 Contests 
 Hide&amp;Seek Sandy’s Wand Carrie’s Carrot Recipe Contests 
 Cookbooks 
 Taste of Home Baking&amp;Desserts Comfort Food Diet Slow Cooker Kitchen Gadgets Healthy Cooking eCookbooks More... 
 Magazines 
 Taste of Home Plus Simple&amp;Delicious Plus Healthy Cooking Plus 
 
 
 My Recipe Box 
 All Saved Recipes Add Personal Recipe My Grocery List My Newsletters 
 
 [X] 

 Holiday Callout TOH 
 Summer Entertaining 
 
 Summer Recipes Top 10 Zucchini Recipes Grilling Recipes Tomato Recipes Corn Recipes 
 
 THE SEARCH FOR MRS. HOLIDAY 
 
Show off your holiday spirit and you could receive $50,000! Learn More&gt; 
 Adblock RightSide Mbox RightSide TOH 
Top Recipe Collections
 Graduation Recipes , Chicken Recipes , Pasta Salads , Burger Recipes , Appetizers , Grilling Recipes , Hot Dogs , Taste of Home&apos;s Blog , Rhubarb Recipes , Asparagus Recipes , Trifle Recipes , Potluck Recipes Advanced Search &gt;    Browse Recipes &gt; Facebook Widget TOH 
 Holidays&amp;Celebrations Newsletter 

 Recipes, menus and entertaining ideas! 
 
 Invalid e-mail 
 Follow Us 
Follow Us
 Home &gt; Taste of Home Community &gt; Community Forums &gt; Recipes &gt; Maid-Rite Sandwich 
Maid-Rite Sandwich

Last post
 Jul 17, 2011 7:26 PM
 by dutchmom4MI .
 28
 replies.
 
 
  Share 
 Forum Jump: Select Forum Appetizer Recipes Bread Recipes Budget Living Canadian Corner Comfort Food Diet Cookin&apos; Seniors Cooking for 2 Cooking Techniques Cooks Who Care Cookware Country Woman Magazine Crafters Chat Depression Support Dessert Recipes Diabetic Connection Gluten-Free Zone Grannie Neighborhood Healthy Choices Healthy Cooking Magazine Healthy Living Group Hints and Tips Holiday Recipes Ingredients June Cleaver Club Kitchen Chat Main Dish Recipes Mary&apos;s Tea Room Mom2Mom Recipe Chat Recipes Secret Sisters Circle Side Dish Recipes Simple&amp;Delicious Magazine Snack Recipes Soup/Salad Recipes Swap Spot Taste of Home Cooking School Taste of Home Forum Help Taste of Home Magazine The Old Country Corner The Rose Room * GO 

 Post reply Page 1 of 2 (29 items) 1 2 Next&gt; 
 Berri 
 
 Joined: Mar 2002 Posts: 35 Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:29 PM in Recipes Post # 1 Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 I am looking for the recipe for maid-rite&apos;s that we used to have growning up. It is a Sloppy Joe without a tomatoe base and it seemed to be steamed. Thank you for trying to find this recipe for me. False 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:31 PM in Recipes Post # 2 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: Need Recipe for Loose Meat
Posted by: MissEllie Posted on: 12/30/2004 11:58:31 AM
#R4946014

Faux Maid-Rite

1 lb. Ground Beef
1 tsp. ground pepper
1 tsp. sugar
2 tsp. prepared mustard
6 oz. beer, water or beef broth
salt (to taste)

Combine ground beef, pepper, sugar, mustard, salt in the top of a double-boiler and add beer or other liquid. Cover top and heat for one-half hour, stirring occasionally. The longer it cooks, the more the flavors blend together. Toward the end, uncover to allow some of the liquid to boil off.

Use a slotted serving spoon to serve on hamburger buns with mustard, dill pickles and chopped onion. Serves 6.

Notes: Use prepared yellow salad mustard, such as that for hamburgers or hot dogs. Do not use dry powdered mustard, or a Dijoni or Poupon style mustard. Use a good quality, low fat ground beef. A genuine Maid Rite is steam cooked and is very finely ground beef.

My note: I don&apos;t use a double boiler; just a regular saucepan and let the liquid cook out. I like to use beef broth.


 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:32 PM in Recipes Post # 3 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
Posted by: HDMac Replies: 13 Posted on: 5/25/2004 10:23:06 AM
#T356976

The Blue Mill Tavern Loosemeat Sandwich

1 lb of real good ground chuck or ground beef round or ground sirloin
1 tablespoon fat like lard or Crisco (if meat is round or sirloin)
2 teaspoons salt, just enough to lightly cover bottom of your skillet
1 onion, chopped fine
1 tablespoon prepared yellow mustard
1 tablespoon vinegar
1 tablespoon sugar
water, to cover
salt and pepper, to taste

1. Get out a cast iron skillet-they are the best for loosemeats-or other kind if you have no iron skillet.
2. Meltfat over medium heat and lightly salt bottom of skillet.
3. Break ground beef up in skillet and start crumbling it with the back of a wooden spoon-this is very important-the meat must end up being cooked up into small crumbles.
4. Add chopped onion while browning meat.
5. Keep working with the back of spoon to break up meat.
6. When meat is browned, drain off any fat and return meat to skillet.
7. Add mustard, vinegar, sugar, and just enough water to barely cover meat in the pan.
8. Cook, at a simmer, till water is all cooked out-between 15-20 minutes.
9. Adjust salt and pepper to taste.
10. Heat your hamburger buns-they&apos;re traditionally steamed for loosemeats-I like mine toasted lightly-do it the way you like it.
11. When buns are warm, put yellow mustard on them and add some dill pickle slices-I put on lots!
12. *Ifyou start changing this recipe and using things like olive oil for the fat and dijon or honey mustard for the yellow mustard, you will not get the traditional yummy taste of a loosemeat sandwich.
13. Likewise, don&apos;t add any liquid smoke or worcestershire sauce.
14. Make them just like this the first time so you can sample the simplicity of this famous Midwestern treat.
15. If you want to start making changes after that by all means do so but I&apos;d like you to taste the original recipe at least once.
16. Serve with homemade potato salad and chips.

 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:32 PM in Recipes Post # 4 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: Maid- Rites
Posted by: cinnamama Posted on: 2/9/2004 7:29:10 AM
#R3017267
This is the only one I use and it tastes just like the maidrites served in Iowa.

Maidrites

1 lb. ground beef
1 tsp. pepper
1 tsp. sugar
2 tsp. mustard
6 oz. beef broth
salt

Combine beef, pepper, sugar, mustard and salt in a double boiler and add broth. Cover top and heat for 1/2 hour stirring occasionally. Toward the end uncover and allow some liquid to boil off. (A genuine Maidrite is steam cooked).


 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:33 PM in Recipes Post # 5 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
Here is a description of the genuine Maid Rite OR Loose Meat sandwich.



RE: WHAT is a Maidrite Sandwich??
Posted by: Norse4 Posted on: 5/25/2005 3:10:53 PM
#R5773720

Marshalltown, Iowa is the &quot;Maid-Rite Capital of the Nation&quot;. I believe that a maid-rite is simply cooked ground beef. Maid-rites are served with NO KETCHUP--only mustard, pickles, and/or onions for condiments. I grew up in Marshalltown and love those sandwiches!


 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 PeeBee 
 
 Joined: Jan 2004 Posts: 199 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:33 PM in Recipes Post # 6 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 Maid Rites

1 1/2 # Ground beef fried and chopped fine
1 tsp. black pepper
1 tsp. dry mustart
1 finely chopped onion
1 cup beer
2 Tbl. sugar

Cook until all the liquid is gone

Put on hamburger bun , with mustard and a sliced hamburger pickle OR with mustard, hamburger pickle and American Cheese.

A friend at work gave me this from down South....Really good...Just the combination of it all including the mustard really makes it taste like a White Castle...Everyone likes it...
 False 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:34 PM in Recipes Post # 7 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
Subject: Maid- Rites
Posted by: amgranny8 Replies: 22 Posted on: 2/8/2004 3:31:52 PM
#T300666

when I was growing up in Dodge City Kansas there was a Maid-Rite shop and they gave my mother this recipe that they used there. it is good.

MAID-RITES


1 1/2 pounds ground beef, twice ground
1 medium onion, minced
1 can chicken broth
Salt and pepper

Crumble meat in a skillet over medium heat, then add onion. Brown meat and cook until onion begins to turn clear. Drain off fat. Meat should be very crumbly. Add broth and cook, stirring constantly, until the liquid evaporates. Season with salt and pepper.

Serve on buns with slices of dill pickle. Add mustard, if desired.

 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:35 PM in Recipes Post # 8 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: Tastee sandwich
Posted by: TexasroseII Posted on: 6/9/2003 11:44:24 PM
#R1664927
Remember when Roseann and Tom opened a restaurant in Iowa? They loved &quot;loose meat&quot; sandwiches and served them there. I&apos;ve got a recipe I can share. I have made this and like it as much as sloppy joes. Loose meat is more juicy and less tomatoey.

Loose Meat

2 lbs lean ground beef
1 cup condensed beef broth
1 med onion, minced
4 T tomato sauce
salt&amp;pepper to taste
dash of dry mustard
2 shakes Tabassco sauce
2 shakes Worcesterhire sauce

Brown beef with onion; drain. Add remaining ingredients ans simmer until liquid is absorbed. Serve on fresh buns.

 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 PeeBee 
 
 Joined: Jan 2004 Posts: 199 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:36 PM in Recipes Post # 9 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 Just wanted to add that was not my recipe. I copied and pasted from a previous thread and missed copying the original poster. False 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:36 PM in Recipes Post # 10 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
Subject: Special Maid Rite Sandwiches
Posted by: Sinclairwife Replies: 4 Posted on: 1/18/2005 9:55:58 AM
#T464160
Special Maid Rite Sandwiches

2 lbs. ground beef,
½ cup Coca-Cola,
1 tsp. Mustard,
1 clove garlic,
1 cup catsup,
1/3 cup onion flakes (or more or less--to your taste)

Brown ground beef with onion flakes.
Drain meat.

Add remainder of ingredients and simmer for 15 minutes.
Serve on hamburger buns.
Serves 10-12.

Brenda


 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:40 PM in Recipes Post # 11 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: TSR Weekly Maid Rite Loose Sandwiches
Posted by: KaciA Posted on: 9/12/2005 8:08:03 PM
#R6382809
Part III


INGREDIENTS:

1 pound lean ground beef (15% fat is best)
1 cup water
1/4 cup beef broth
1/4 teaspoon salt
4 plain hamburger buns
yellow mustard
minced white onion
dill pickle slices

INSTRUCTIONS:

1. Brown ground beef in a large skillet over medium-low heat. Use a potato masher to help get the ground beef into small pieces. Drain any excess fat. If you use lean meat (15% fat or less) you won&apos;t need to drain the fat. As soon as all the pink in the meat is gone, add 1 cup of water and 1/4 cup beef broth plus 1/4 teaspoon salt. Simmer the meat uncovered for one hour or until all the liquid is gone, stirring every 10 minutes or so.

2. Build each sandwich by pressing the hot ground beef into a 1/2 cup measuring cup. Dump the meat onto the bottom of a plain hamburger bun. Add mustard on the top bun, along with pickles and minced onion if desired. Put the sandwich, and heat it up in your microwave oven for 10 to 15 seconds to warm the buns. Serve with a spoon as they do in the restaurants.

Makes 4 sandwiches.


 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:41 PM in Recipes Post # 12 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: Lost maidrite recipe
Posted by: bebeblues Posted on: 1/27/2003 8:23:21 PM
#R1064442
I went to www.google.com and did a search for &quot;Maid-Rite&quot; recipe and got over 700 hits. Here are a couple of the recipes.

Maid Rite Loose Hamburger
Recipe By :
Serving Size : 1 Preparation Time :0:00
Categories : Sandwiches
Amount Measure Ingredient -- Preparation Method
-------- ------------ --------------------------------
2 lb. hamburger (85% lean)
1/2 cup hot water
1 Tbsp. beef bouillon crystals
1 Tbsp. garlic powder
1/2 tsp. Accent
1/2 tsp. Worcestershire sauce
salt
pepper


Have ready diced onions, pickles, mustard, ketchup, and cheese, if you want a Cheeserite. Fix buns on squares of wax paper. Add hamburger and other ingredients, fold up and let set at least 3 minutes.
 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:45 PM in Recipes Post # 13 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: Maid- Rites
Posted by: kansascakedecorator Posted on: 2/8/2004 4:29:27 PM
#R3013723
We had a little drive up in McCook Nebraska that serve a similar sandwich. They called them jiffy burgers and they had mustard in them.

Jiffy Burgers
1 lb. hamburger browned and drained
1/c cup onion
1 Tablespoon sugar
1 tsp. pepper
2 tsp. prepared mustard

These were a favorite around the area....

 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 zakons Illinois 
 
 Joined: Feb 2006 Posts: 16,195 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:46 PM in Recipes Post # 14 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 

(Tastes like a White Castle Hamburger)

Maid Rites

1 1/2 # Ground beef fried and chopped fine
1 tsp. black pepper
1 tsp. dry mustard
1 finely chopped onion
1 cup beer
2 Tbl. sugar

Cook until all the liquid is gone

Put on hamburger bun , with mustard and a sliced hamburger pickle OR with mustard, hamburger pickle and American Cheese.

A friend at work gave me this from down South....Really good...Just the combination of it all including the mustard really makes it taste like a White Castle...Everyone likes it...
 False 
 
 Reply 
 
 dutchmom4MI 
 
 Joined: May 2003 Posts: 29,796 Reply Posted: Jun 25, 2006 4:49 PM in Recipes Post # 15 RE: Maid-Rite Sandwich 
 
 
RE: Need Recipe for Loose Meat
Posted by: laureljean Posted on: 12/31/2004 7:36:34 AM
#R4951266
This is the one I use. Note that it doesn&apos;t tell you to brown the meat before you put it in the slow cooker, but I always do. The first time I made it, I didn&apos;t and I thought it was nasty. Cooked first, it&apos;s very good.

From April 2000 Pillsbury Classic Cookbook

*Slow-Cooker Crumbled Beef Sandwiches*

A fast-food restaurant chain originating in Iowa is wellknown for its &quot;loose meat&quot; sandwiches.

2 lbs. extra-lean ground beef
2 tsp. instant minced onion
2 tsp. seasoned salt
1/4 tsp. pepper
1-1/2 cups water
8 sandwich buns, split (Hamburger Buns)

In a 3-1/2 to 4-quart slow cooker, combine all ingredients except buns; mix until ground beef is very moist and crumbly.

Cover and cook on low setting for 7 to 10 hours.

Stir mixture to crumble ground beef. Drain. With slotted spoon, spoon beef mixture into buns. Serve with desired condiments.

Condiments traditionally served with hamburgers are great on these &quot;loose-meat&quot; sandwiches. Try ketchup, mustard, barbecue sauce, mayonnaise, tomatoes, pickles and lettuce.


 False 
 
 
 
 Reply 
 
 
 
 
 
 Taste of Home 
 
 About Us Help Press Room Advertising Tasty Tidbits Contact Us Site Map Terms&amp;Conditions NEW Your Privacy Rights 
 
Taste of Home Family

 Healthy Cooking Simple&amp;Delicious Cooking for 2 Country Woman Cookbooks Newsletters Mobile Shop Taste of Home Taste of Home Cooking Schools Host a School Event Reiman Publications Career Center Reader&apos;s Digest 
 
Recipe Finder

 Recipe Search Advanced Search Browse Recipes Submit a Recipe Recipe Contests Recipes 
 
Recipe Category Index

 Appetizers Beverages Bread Recipes Breakfast Recipes Chicken Recipes Winning Recipes Dinner Recipes Desserts Seasonal Recipes Halloween Recipes Thanksgiving Recipes Christmas Recipes Christmas Cookie Recipes New Year&apos;s Recipes Bake Sale Recipes Italian Recipes Potluck Recipes Diabetic Recipes Slow Cooker Recipes Salads Sandwiches Side Dish Recipes Soup Recipes Vegetarian Recipes Grilling Recipes Top 10 Recipes How to Cook 
 
Healthy Living and Cooking

 Recipe Makeovers Healthy Menus Special Diet Recipes Comfort Food Diet Live Well Healthy Cooking Plus 
 
Community

 Forums Groups Follow us on 
  facebook  Twitter 
 
My Account
 
 Register My Page My Recipe Box Mail My Profile Log In 
 
©Reiman Media Group, LLC., 2012
	</body>
</document>
