<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003753" url="http://www.takeawaylancaster.co.cc/?p=258" time="2012-07-12-19:54" support="6" score="0.019753686484375498" bingtitle="Food on Campus Lancaster University | Takeaway Lancaster" webtitle="Food on Campus Lancaster University | Takeaway Lancaster">
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="128"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Takeaway Lancaster UK « ... LUSU Central Store . Another LUSU-operated enterprise. ... You can leave a response, or trackback from your own ...</description>
	<body>
		Takeaway Lancaster 
 Fast Food Restaurant Takeaway Lancaster UK « Lancaster Takeaways Starvin Marvin Takeaway Restaurant introduces Lancaster to the Parmo » 
Eating on Lancaster University campus
 
 Food on Lancaster University campus 

One of the main advantages of working on a campus such as Lancaster’s is the wide variety of places to buy food and drink either to eat in or take away. The following is a rough guide to what’s available, and it covers independent operators as well as the services provided by the University Hospitality and Catering division. Most venues have reduced opening hours outside term time, though many will be open for busy periods such as Intro Week and Graduation Week.

Please also note that there are a number of fast food takeaway restaurants, pizza, Italian, Chinese and Indians takeaway restaurants in Lancaster that offer free delivery to campus, such as Domino’s Pizza, Starvin Marvin, The SuperChef, Flames, Fired Wok, The Moghuls, Delhicious etc…

 North Campus 

 The Spicy Hut 

County South, directly opposite Nuffield Theatre entrance. A classic Indian restaurant, the Lancaster outpost of a well known Manchester curry house. Excellent food at reasonable prices, in very attractive surroundings.

Opening hours: Monday to Friday 4 .00 pm – 11.00 pm, Sunday 1.00pm – 9pm. Special/varying hours outside term time.

 County Diner and Takeaway 

Located in County South, next to County College JCR. Hot food, sandwiches and baguettes. A favorite breakfasting place.

Opening hours: Monday to Thursday 8.00 am – 5.00 pm, Friday 8.00 am – 4.00 pm term time

 Food For Thought 

Ground floor of the Institute for Advanced Studies building, North Spine. This café provides coffees made from freshly ground Fair-trade coffee beans, which guarantees a better deal for third world producers. Healthier snacking using Fair-trade and organic products. Freshly filled organic baguettes and plated salads.

Term time opening hours: Monday to Friday 9.00 am till 4.00 pm During and out of term except summer.

 Bowland Deli 

Situated in Bowland College JCR. Offering the ever popular breakfast buns, hot roast sandwich (carved while you wait) along with a wide selections of filled rolls and jacket potatoes with a choice of filling.

Term time opening hours: Monday to Friday 9.30 am – 4.00 pm. Closed out of term

 Global Cafe 

Located in the Chaplaincy Centre, Bowland Avenue. Serves toasted sandwiches, baked potatoes, hot meals.

Opening hours: Monday to Friday 8.30 am-4.30pm

 The Atrium 

Located in the Geography department. Tea/coffee Soup and sandwiches

Monday-Thursday 9.00am-4.00pm, Friday 9.00am-3.30pm

Eating on Lancaster University campus

 Alexandra square area 

 Greggs 

Situated east end of Alexandra Square. Takeaway hot pies and rolls, baguettes and sandwiches, cakes and hot drinks. Sometimes queues, but very fast service.

Opening hours: 8.00 am – 7.00pm everyday during term time. Varying hours outside term time.

 LUSU Shop 

Just off Alexandra Square, next to Slaidburn House. A recent example of student enterprise is the hot soup counter, offering a choice of two fresh-made soups every day to take away. Soups available between 11.00 am and 3.30 pm daily. Not open out of term.

 Spar shop 

Just off Alexandra Square, further on from Slaidburn House. As well as the usual range of provisions there is a take away counter offering hot and cold food, and hot drinks from machines.

Opening hours: Monday to Friday 8.00 am – 10.00 pm; Saturday 9.00 am – 6.00 pm; Sunday 10.00 am – 2.00 pm open out of term

 Diggles 

Just off Alexandra Square, next to travel shop. Takeaway hot food and drinks

Opening hours: 8.00 am – 4.00 pm during weekdays in term time.

 The Sultan Experience 

Located under the Spar next to LUSU

An off-shoot of Lancaster’s famous Sultan of Lancaster restaurant. High quality hot food from many cultures to eat in or take away.

Opening hours: 10.00 am – 4:00 am (really!) all week and out of term time

 South Spine 

 The Venue 

Located down the steps leading from Alexandra square. A modern coffee shop that provides high quality coffee and a range of teas and herbal infusions. A broad range of sandwiches, wraps and jacket potatoes with a wide selection of fillings, and high quality cakes are also on offer.

Term time opening hours: 8.00 am – 8.30 pm Monday to Friday, 10.30 am – 6.00 pm on weekends

Vacation opening hours: 8.00 am – 6.00 pm Monday to Friday, 10.30 am – 6.00 pm on weekends

 Atkinsons Fish and Chip Shop 

Classic fresh fish and chips, a great student favourite.

Opening hours during term time: Monday to Friday 11.30 am – 2.00pm and 4.30 pm – 10.00 pm, Sat/Sun 4.30 pm – 10.00 pm.

Eating on Lancaster University campus

 Pizzetta Republic 

Part of a national chain. Pizzas, burgers, kebabs, eat in or take away. Also houses Café Republic providing coffees, sandwiches/baguettes with a choice of fillings.

 Fylde Sandwich Bar 

Situated in Fylde College. Offers toasted teacakes or tasty cheese on toast for a mid morning snack, followed at lunchtime by a wide and varied selection of fresh baked rolls and fillings.

Term time opening hours; Monday to Friday 9.30 am – 4.00 pm during term only

 The Hub Café 

Situated on the ground floor of the Management School, accessible from the South Spine or South West Drive. The Hub area is a social space for students, staff and visitors, with the Café providing an atmosphere for networking with relaxed surroundings and high quality food and beverages, with emphasis on local produce.

Term time opening hours: 8.30 am – 4.30 pm Monday to Friday.

Vacation opening hours: 8.30 am – 4.30 pm Monday to Friday.

 Wong’s Chinese Restaurant 

George Fox building. Wide range of Chinese dishes to eat in or take away. Special set lunch offers. Big favourite with Chinese students on campus.

 Wibbly Wobbly Burger Bar 

High quality burgers, chicken dishes and vegetarian meals, made to order. Makes a point of using locally-produced fresh produce.

Opening hours: 10.00am – 11.00pm daily

 LUSU Central Store 

Another LUSU-operated enterprise. General store, provisions, sandwiches and food

Opening hours: 8:30pm – 11.00pm Monday-Friday, 9:00am-11:00pm Saturday and Sunday

 Café 21 

Situated on the top level of the Infolab 21 building, this offers additional seating on the roof terrace with spectacular views. Cooked to order full English breakfast, hot baguette of the day and homemade soup are some of the delights available.

Café 21 is open 8.30 am – 4.00 pm Food is served until 2.00pm Open all year out of term

 Barker House Farm 

The open food court provides an ideal meeting space where you can grab a coffee or have a more substantial meal. During the day Barkers offers a range of made to order sandwiches, homemade soup and the very popular filled panini. From 4 pm you can dine in the restaurant choosing one, two or three courses from the menu or you have the option to dine in a less formal atmosphere and select a dish from our Bar Snacks Menu. The food court is open from 10am till late Monday to Friday. No out of term opening but this may change in the near future

Updated: December 2007
 
Related posts:

 Pizza Takeaway Lancaster Pizza Delivery Lancaster Takeaway Lancaster The Best Fast Food Lancaster Takeaways Free Delivery Lancaster–Pizza Takeaway Delivery, Indian Takeaway and Chinese Takeaway 

Tags: Campus , Domino&apos;s , Food On Campus , Free Takeaway Delivery Lancaster , Greggs , Lancaster , LUSU , Pizza , Pizzetta Republic , Restaurant , Starvin Marvin , Sultan , Takeaway Lancaster , Takeaway Lancaster University , University , Wibbly Wobbly Burger Bar 

 This entry was posted
 on Friday, June 25th, 2010 at 1:35 pm and is filed under Takeaway Lancaster University .
 You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed.

 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site. 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
Takeaway Lancaster is proudly powered by WordPress 
 Entries (RSS) and Comments (RSS) . Install Wordpress
	</body>
</document>
