<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003972" url="http://www.groupsmore.com/cities/multiple-cities/deals/loving-hut" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="1" score="0.0009147511632956438" bingtitle="Groupon Malaysia | [54% Off] Vegetarian Meal + Dessert for 2 ..." webtitle="Groupon Malaysia | [54% Off] Vegetarian Meal + Dessert for 2 people at Loving Hut for RM15 instead of RM32.80. Halal">
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>Main dish and dessert for two people. Vegetarian fast food restaurant. Choose from ... Valid for 1 Groupon per receipt and per table.</description>
	<body>
		Groupon Malaysia 
 
 Today’s Discounts Past Discounts How Groupon Works Groupon Blog My Vouchers 
 
Oh no, you&apos;re too late for this Groupon discount :(
 Close Tweet 
 [54% Off] Vegetarian Meal + Dessert for 2 people at Loving Hut for RM15 instead of RM32.80. Halal 
 RM15 Value RM 32.80 Discount 54 % 
Ended on Jun 21, 2011 
 Vouchers will be available for print by Jun 22, 2011 . 344 bought 
The deal is on!

 Unlocked on Jun 18, 2011
 
Share with friends
 Tweet 2 locations 
 Previous Next 
 
Highlights
 
 Main dish and dessert for two people.  Vegetarian fast food restaurant.  Choose from three main dishes.  
 
The Fine Print

 Expires Sep 23, 2011 Redemption begins Jun 23, 2011.  Valid daily: 11am–10pm. Valid on public holidays. May buy and use many.  All day dine-in only. Valid for 1 Groupon per receipt and per table. Service charges included. 1 day prior reservation required.  Last date for prior reservation: Sep 22, 2011.  Redeemable at Puchong and Kota Damansara outlets only. See the rules that apply to all deals. 
 
In order to combat high rates of divorce, the Domestic Affairs Ministry banned meat altogether, thus eradicating all arguments over who gets the last chicken dumpling. Share the love with today’s Groupon: for RM15, you get a vegetarian meal plus dessert for two people at Loving Hut (up to RM32.80 value) and good at two locations. Meal consists of: 

 

Choose up to three different main dishes to divide and conquer with a comestible comrade and wash down with a non-stick dessert, ensuring coffers are filled without clogging up pipelines. Indulge in a serving of Taiwanese style Basil Delight Rice; brown rice served with vegetables and soy meat cooked in three different types of secret sauce. Malachite moss-huggers may opt to try the Olive Fried Rice; brown rice served with olive leaf and vegetables, or the Green Curry Rice which is brown rice served with long beans curry, eggplant, ladies finger, bean curd skin and vegetables. Bloated human skin rip into tau fu fa drizzled with ginger syrup for dessert smacks as nimble fingers access the free Wi-Fi available on the premises. 

 Facebook : Loving Hut Malaysia 

 
Kota Damansara branch

 
Bandar Puteri Puchong branch 

Reviews


 Looks suspiciously like stir fried beef slices with basil, I can guarantee you that this is definitely vegetarian. The &apos;meat&apos; is soy based, wonderfully prepared to have a slight crisp skin and coated with sticky, sweetish basil infused sauce. Went perfectly with the rice. – May 3, 2011. SC ‘Basil Rice Set’ as the sauce taste good and the basil taste doesnt over power the gravy taste. Just nice.” – Oct 25, 2009. Taufulou This is one restaurant I love bringing my friends and family to enjoy nice food, good service, lovely ambience!– Oct 29, 2010. alohamolly 
 Still unclear? Discuss this discount— responses 
 
The Retailer

Loving Hut

 www.lovinghutmalaysia.com/ 

This deal can be redeemed at these places:

 Loving Hut (Kota Damansara) 
No.19, Jalan PJU 5/6, Dataran Sunway, Kota Damansara, 47810 Petaling Jaya, Selangor.
Phone: 03-6142 1676
 Loving Hut (Bandar Puteri Puchong) 
No.15, Jalan Puteri 2/7, Bandar Puteri Puchong, 47100 Puchong, Selangor.
Phone: 03-8062 7769
 
 Choose another discount→ 
Share this discount

Pass this around, will you?
 Tweet 
We Have Moved
 
Don’t see today’s deal here?

We have migrated fully to our brand new site. To see today’s deal, head over to groupon.my . If you&apos;re looking for your previously purchased vouchers, you would be able to find them there too.
 
More Discounts

 
 [58% + 10% Off] Multipurpose Aluminium Card Holder for RM22.50 instead of RM60. Available in 7 Colours. Free Nationwide Delivery 
 RM 22.50 58 % OFF [58% + 10% Off] Multipurpose Aluminium Card Holder for RM22.50 instead of RM60. Available in 7 Colours. Free Nationwide Delivery 
 
How Groupon Works

 1 Everyday, a new deal is featured on Groupon. 2 Buy the voucher and we&apos;ll email you when it&apos;s ready. 3 Show the voucher to redeem your deal. 
 *Full refund will be given if minimum number of buyers is not reached. 
Company

 About Groupon Malaysia Press Contact Privacy Policy 
 
Learn More

 FAQ Jobs How Groupon Works? 
 
Groupon Countries

 Argentina Australia Austria Belgium Brazil Canada Chile China Colombia Denmark Finland 

 France Germany Greece Hong Kong India Ireland Israel Italy Japan Korea Mexico 

 Netherlands New Zealand Norway Peru Philippines Poland Portugal Romania Russia Singapore South Africa 

 Spain Sweden Switzerland Taiwan Turkey United Arab Emirates United Kingdom Uruguay USA 
 
©2011 Groupon, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
