<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003181" url="http://federalsoup.federaldaily.com/forum_posts.asp?TID=27020&amp;title=vehicle-contract-station-bribery-charges" time="2012-07-12-19:19" support="1" score="0.00043086206837390095" bingtitle="Vehicle contract station bribery charges. - FederalSoup.com" webtitle="Vehicle cntract statin bribery charges. - FederalSoup.com">
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>... Postal Inspectors did an investigation on all vehicle ... Kevin J. Basil handed the government official fast-food restaurant ... to meet him at a different spot in College Park.</description>
	<body>
		Home Topics 
 Benefits Financial Planning and Retirement Jobs and Careers Management Military Pay Policies and Practices Postal Service Workplace Technology 
 Resource Catalog 
 2011 Federal Employees Almanac Disability Retirement: Understanding the Federal Rules Divorce Planning for Federal Employees Federal Employees Retirement Guide Federal Employees News Digst Long Term Care Mike Causey Unleashed Taxation of Federal Retirement Benefits Your CSRS Retirement Your FERS Retirement Your Thrift Savings Plan Understanding the Federal Government&apos;s Survivor Benefits Complete Catalog 
 Federal Soup Blogs 
 Gov Career Federal Coach Government 2.0 Inside DOD Workforce Wonk 
 FEND 
 Current Issue Past Issues Subscribe Now Renew Your Subscription 
 Almanac 
 2011 Edition Subscribe Now 
 Job Listings Free Newsletter 

 
   Forum Home &gt; AGENCIES/ORGANIZATIONS/MILITARY &gt; Postal Employees    New Posts    FAQ    Search    Events    Register    Login 
 
 
 
Vehicle contract station bribery charges.
 

  Post Reply 

 Author Message     Topic Search    Topic Options Post Reply Create New Topic Printable Version Translate Topic retiring20soon Members Profile Send Private Message Find Members Posts Add to Buddy List 
Senior Member
 


Joined: 30 Nov 2008
Points: 1918 Post Options Post Reply Quote retiring20soon Report Post    Thanks(0)    Quote    Reply Topic: Vehicle contract station bribery charges. 
    Posted: 16 Aug 2010 at 2:27pm If the OIG or Postal Inspectors did an investigation on all vehicle maintenance contract stations they would save the USPS millions of dollars. The over billing and the crooked repair costs which these contract stations are involved in is proven in just one example below. It is happening nationwide...
	</body>
</document>
