<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003797" url="http://deliciouspoutine.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:57" support="2" score="0.0024020199327118848" bingtitle="Delicious Poutine" webtitle="Delicious Poutine">
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>... table near the door rolling cutlery into napkins, a ... place is basically a slightly classed-up fast food restaurant ... The Saint John Ale House; The Snooty Fox; William&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		Delicious Poutine 
 News and reviews for a dangerously underweight planet 
 Swiss Chalet, Fredericton 
 November 27, 2009 
Full disclosure: This was my first visit to Swiss Chalet.  Not just the Fredericton location, but ever .  It’s nowhere near my house, and my parents are a little bit insane about dining out, so I never got to go when I was growing up.  Case in point: I was 18 before I visited a burger place that wasn’t McDonald’s, and my mother insists to this day that KFC’s chicken is too spicy.  You can’t make that up.

 The Contender: Swiss Chalet, 961 Prospect St., Fredericton, New Brunswick

 When were you there? November 19th, 8:00pm

 How much? I don’t know!  Keep reading for the explanation.

 The Experience: So, it turns out 8:00pm on a Thursday is not an optimal time to go to Swiss Chalet.  When we arrived there was a server sitting at a table near the door rolling cutlery into napkins, a sure sign it’s closing time.  The posted hours say they’re open until 10:00, so whatever.

We were seated at a booth next to what turned out to be a very drafty window, and were subjected to way-louder-than-necessary holiday-themed pop music.  (“Is this Justin Timberlake?” “I dunno, I think N*sync had at least one Christmas album, so maybe it’s that.”)  Ugh all around.  The whole place is basically a slightly classed-up fast food restaurant, but I guess that’s what Swiss Chalet is all about.

I was disappointed to note poutine isn’t listed anywhere on the menu, not as a stand-alone dish, nor as a side.  I’d heard Swiss Chalet served it, but saw no direct evidence to support this.  I ordered the much-hyped Festive Special, and enquired whether poutine on the side was an option, and the waitress confirmed it was.  Okay, we’re in business!

 

The poutine ended up being the best part of my meal.  The fries were fresh-cut style, but definitely weren’t fresh out of the fryer.  The gravy was warm-ish and not over-salted like what you seem to get at many restaurants.  The cheese curds weren’t fresh at all.  They were ice cold and had a slightly sharp taste to them similar to medium cheddar, which says to me they’d been sitting around for quite some time.  Suggestion: maybe if poutine was listed on the menu, they’d sell more of it and wouldn’t wind up serving old cheese.

 The Verdict: This definitely isn’t the worst poutine I’ve ever had, but it wasn’t great either. Deluxe is right across the street, I suggest going there for your uptown Fredericton poutine needs instead.

 
 
Tags: Festive Special , Fredericton , Swiss Chalet 
Posted in reviews | 1 Comment» 
 
 Poutine and Cupcakes 
 November 25, 2009 
Together at last!

On Sunday, Montréal hosted its first Cupcake Camp , a fundraiser for Kids’Help Phone . Though the Cupcake Camp concept originated in San Francisco, several Montréal bakers put a decidedly Québécois spin on their creations:

 via @ LauraCarmosino 

 

 via @ lesleychestrman 

 Clever Cupcakes submitted the winning entry in the“Best Montreal Theme”category. Yes, that’s Youppi emerging from a poutine. On a cupcake . My mind is blown.

Hat tip: @ Mark_Black 
 
Tags: Clever Cupcakes , CupcakeCamp , dessert , Montréal 
Posted in photos | Leave a Comment» 
 
 Eggs Benedict Poutine 
 November 23, 2009 
 

You know what would increase the deliciousness by, like, 30%? Some crispy bacon crumbled on top. That’s a powerful breakfast, right there.

Updated: actually, now that I look closely, it looks like there might already be some bacon on there, hidden under the hollandaise. They thought of everything!

Via This Is Why You’re Fat 
 
Tags: breakfast , eggs benedict , This Is Why You&apos;re Fat 
Posted in photos | 1 Comment» 
 
 The Cake Is A Lie 
 November 20, 2009 
A delicious, delicious lie .

 

 

Ronna is a poutine blogger in her own right and she created this poutine cake to celebrate the birthday of her incredibly fortunate partner.
 
The“french fries”are Sara Lee pound cake cut into fry shapes and toasted. The“cheese curds”are made out of white chocolate and the“gravy”is dulce de leche .
 
Can I get an om-nom-nom?
 
Tags: cake , dessert 
Posted in photos | 7 Comments» 
 
 Gravy Fail 
 November 18, 2009 
I’ve consumed some questionable gravy in the course of this project, but if this showed up in front of me, I’d send it back. And I never send food back.

 

What. In the. FUCK.

via @ fourstringfuror 
 
Tags: photos , Twitter 
Posted in crimes against poutine , photos | 1 Comment» 
 «Older Entries 
 
Pages

 About 
 
Recent Comments

 Swiss Chalet: The Fe… on Swiss Chalet, Fredericton Swiss Chalet, Freder… on Deluxe Fish&amp;Chips, … Natalie on Eggs Benedict Poutine Natalie on The Cake Is A Lie Dave on The Cake Is A Lie 
 
Categories

 crimes against poutine (4) photos (22) recipes (1) reviews (11) Uncategorized (1) videos (3) 
 Search: 
Blogroll

 Bacon Today Bake&amp;Destroy Curdsade Food Funk Food on the Offence Freaking Out Over Dinner Let&apos;s Get Baked Lord of the Wings Montréal Poutine Portland Poutine Poutine Chronicles Serious Eats Tasty Fish and Chips This Is Why You&apos;re Fat You Never Know Unless You Fry 
 
My Other Projects

 Busted Head Gunshy Music Zine Our Word of Mouth 
 
Poutine Reviews

 Deluxe Fish&amp;Chips Jack&apos;s Pizza Luna Pizza Swiss Chalet The Garrison District Ale House The Garrison District Ale House II The Saint John Ale House The Snooty Fox William&apos;s Seafood 
 
 
Theme: Kubrick . Blog at WordPress.com .
 Entries (RSS) and Comments (RSS) .
 Follow 
 Follow“Delicious Poutine” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
