<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003162" url="http://www.essexcountystandard.co.uk/news/localnews/9204708.Chelmsford_A_Level_results_joy/" time="2012-07-12-19:18" support="2" score="0.002405935592005276" bingtitle="Chelmsford A-Level results joy (From Essex County Standard)" webtitle="Chelmsford A-Level results joyFrom Essex County Standard)">
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>&quot;University will be a big change from school and home ... Maldon: Men commit crazy theft from fast food restaurant ... Fireworks back on table for Wivenhoe&apos;s jubilee event</description>
	<body>
		Jump to main content News Sport Weather forecast 
 


 Mobile site News feed E-Newsletters 

 Site map Register Log in 
 
 Chelmsford A-Level results joy(From Essex County Standard) 
 
 Get involved: send your pictures, video, news and views by texting ECS to 80360, or email » 
 Search: 
 News Sport Leisure Local Info Events Announcements Family Contact Us Advertise Directory Buy&amp;Sell Dating Cars Homes Jobs 

 Local news Standard rambles Cassie&apos;s Law Save Our Centre Countywide news National news Business Travel news 
 
 
 Essex County Standard » News » Countywide news » 

Countywide news RSS Feed 
 
 
Chelmsford A-Level results joy

 7:46pm Thursday 18th August 2011 in Countywide news By Lauren Hockney 
 Moulsham pupils celebrate 
HUNDREDS of high flyers secured their spot in the A-team as well as university.

A number of students at schools across Chelmsford were celebrating straight A success when A-Level results were dished out as the pass rate nationally rose again for the 29th year in a row.

Chelmsford High School for Girls, in Broomfield Road, was open from 7am so its students could contact UCAS (Universities and Colleges Admissions Service) and their chosen universities as quickly as
 possible due to competition for places this year being &quot;fiercer than ever&quot; according to headteacher, Nicole Chapman.
 
She said: &quot;It&apos;s because of the fees going up next year. Students who may have chosen to take a gap year have chosen not to because of the situation, which is a shame as gap years are very enriching
 for youngsters.

&quot;I think it&apos;s sad, I understand why they&apos;re doing it but it&apos;s not a good way to start working life, to be saddled with huge debts.&quot;

A number of the high school&apos;s students were jumping for joy, including Charlotte Bush, 18, of Broomfield Road. She achieved five A* grades in german, latin, art, maths and general studies. She was
 also awarded a level seven, which is equivalent to an A*, in International Baccalaureate (IB) Russia and is off to Cambridge University to study linguistics in September.
 
She said: &quot;I enjoy studying languages and the structure of languages. I&apos;m really pleased, I didn&apos;t think I would get such high grades so it was a nice surprise.&quot;

Charlotte was also accepted in the Royal Society of Portrait Painters this year and had a painting of headteacher, Nicole Chapman, displayed in the Mall Galleries in London for two weeks.

Jessica Lees, 18, from Great Dunmow, was also celebrating and won her place at St John&apos;s College, Oxford, to study chemistry after gaining four As and one A* in physics, chemistry, maths, french
 and general studies.

She said: &quot;I&apos;m over the moon, to get the results I needed is just the best feeling. &quot;University will be a big change from school and home life but I&apos;m ready to make the move and take on the
 challenges of a degree.&quot;

Students at Chelmer Valley High School, in Court Road, Broomfield, achieved a 100% pass rate in 22 subjects with an overall pass rate in all subjects in excess of 99%.

Rebecca Stephens and Elliot Brooker both achieved four A* grades. Rececca plans to study modern and medieval languages at Cambridge University while Elliot will be joining Southampton University to
 study french and german.

Vicky Lucas, head of sixth form at the school, said: &quot;I&apos;m really proud of all the efforts of the students. They&apos;ve all done extremely well.&quot;

Headteacher, David Franklin, added: &quot;Over 30 staff are here with the students and that says everything about Chelmer Valley, there&apos;s a real family atmosphere.

&quot;The success is down to a combination of students working hard and staff being so supportive, they know the students so well and students feel that level of support and individuality.&quot;

Moulsham High School, in Brian Close, Chelmsford, celebrated its best ever A-Level pass rate of 99.2%. Nearly half of all grades received in more than 13 subjects were A* to B.

Hannah Stern, 18, of Lister Tye, Chelmsford, worked hard alongside her duties as head girl at the school to achieve three A* in geography, government and politics, and IT, she was also awarded an A
 grade for AS level history.

She said: &quot;I&apos;m so happy, I was so worried about it, my results were a complete surprise but a good surprise.

&quot;I put a lot of pressure on myself and get quite stressed about exams so it has been hard work but it has been worth it.&quot;

Hannah plans to take a year out to go travelling in Australia and volunteering in the Third World before applying to do a pre-medicine course which will hopefully take her onto a degree in
 medicine.

Lucy Sellen, 18, of Longstomps Avenue, Chelmsford, secured her place to study law at Sussex University after achieving four A grades in government and politics, english, graphics and general
 studies. She said she felt happy and relieved but her initial plan had been to take a gap year and go travelling after getting her results.

&quot;I didn&apos;t feel I was ready to go to uni, I needed a break and I wasn&apos;t set on what subjet I wanted to do,&quot; she said.

&quot;But when the new fees came out I thought I needed to go this year.&quot;

This year is headteacher, Mark Farmer&apos;s, first at the school.

He said: &quot;It&apos;s absolutley phenomenal, this year far outweighs previous results.

&quot;Our focus has been on achieving higher grades and the percentage of A* to B grades has gone up by nine per cent - nearly half of all grades achieved were A* to B.

&quot;We have the commitment of staff, students and their parents which really helps youngsters to achieve the grades they get.&quot;
 
 Email Print this page Comment(0) 
 
Comments are closed on this article.
 
 Email Print this page Comment(0) 
 
click2find
 Education 
 Search» 
 
Most popular
 
 
 
 Jobs 
 
Search for hundreds of jobs in Essex and beyond
 Search Now» 
   
 Dating 
 
Bring love into your life! Find a date in Essex
 Search Now» 
 
 Homes 
 
Homes for sale, and to let, in Essex
 Search Now» 
 
 Cars 
 
New and used cars in Essex and across the UK
 Search Now» 
   
 
 News Sport Leisure Local Info Events Announcements Family Contact Us Advertise Directory Buy&amp;Sell Dating Cars Homes Jobs 


 Cookie Policy Contact Us Subscribe Photo Sales Advertise AdChoices Archive Topics Announcements Site Map Buy&amp;Sell 


 Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy ©Copyright 2001-2012 
 

 This site is part of Newsquest&apos;s audited local newspaper network A Gannett Company 
 


Newsquest (Essex) Ltd, 58 Church Street, Weybridge, Surrey. KT13 8DP|3102787|Registered in England&amp;Wales
 
About cookies

We want you to enjoy your visit to our website. That&apos;s why we use cookies to enhance your experience. By staying on our website you agree to our use of cookies. Find out more about the cookies we use .
 I agree
	</body>
</document>
