<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003302" url="http://www.boston.com/business/ticker/2010/02/herrells_readie.html" time="2012-07-12-19:26" support="1" score="0.0008274981187574146" bingtitle="Herrell&apos;s readies secret fudge sauces - Daily Business Update ..." webtitle="Herrell&apos;s readies secret fudge sauces - Daily Business Update - The Boston Globe">
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="230"/>
	<description>In extolling hamburgers, fast-food restaurant chains sometimes tout secret sauce. ... Be sure to ask these questions before getting a new credit card</description>
	<body>
		Local Search Site Search   Home Delivery 
 Home Today&apos;s Globe News Business Sports Lifestyle A&amp;E Things To Do Travel Cars Jobs Homes Local Search 

 Technology Healthcare Markets Personal finance Columnists 
 
Herrell&apos;s readies secret fudge sauces
 February 26, 2010 03:07 PM E-mail | | Comments 
( ) | Text size – + 
Globe Staff

In extolling hamburgers, fast-food restaurant chains sometimes tout secret sauce. Now it seems there&apos;s also secret fudge sauce - two kinds, in fact.

 Herrell&apos;s , a local brand long known for ice cream, is spreading the word that the dessert scientists at its Northampton R&amp;D facility have perfected two new variations on the hot fudge recipe that founder Steve Herrell created in his Somerville Ice Cream Shop back in 1973.

 Herrell still sells ice cream in eponymous scoop shops in such places as Northampton, North Adams, and Huntington, N.Y., according to his company&apos;s website. But a few years ago, Herrell&apos;s also decided to branch out and sell its fudge sauces in some supermarket chains and specialty food stores, including some local Whole Foods stores, said Judy Herrell, president of Herrell&apos;s Development Corp. (The image that appears with this post was taken from Herrell&apos;s website.)

The fudge sauces are currently available in four varieties: Original, Peppermint, Almond, and Orange. They&apos;re made in small batches with all natural ingredients, and a 10-ounce jar can sell at retail from roughly $7 to $9, Judy Herrell said.

So what new fudge flavors are in the works to expand that line-up? Judy Herrell is mum on the subject, saying that plans call for the announcement to be made at the Summer 2010 Fancy Food Show in June.

Though left in suspense for now, fudge sauce lovers can rest assured that Steve Herrell remains true to his chocolate mantra: &quot;I set out to create an extraordinary hot fudge sauce that would simply make people happy every time they tasted it.&quot;
 
 Comment Permalink E-mail 
 
Email this article
 To: Invalid email address Add a personal message: Your e-mail: Invalid email address 
Sending your article
 
Your article has been sent.
 «all business news updates 
   Previous entry Next entry   
 
 
LOG IN TO COMMENT
 Sorry, we
could not find your e-mail or password.
Please try again, or click here to
retrieve your password. Existing users 

 * E-mail: * Password: * Screen name: 
 (*
fields are required) Login Forgot your
password? 
 New users 
Please take a minute to register. After you register and pick a screen name,
you can publish your comments everywhere on the site. Posting Policy .

 Register 

 
 Your comment is
subject to the rules of our Posting Policy 
This comment may appear on your public
profile. Public
Profile FAQ next article in business updates Thermo Fisher completes $145m deal for Ahura previous article in business updates Airline will add another Hub-Lisbon flight 
 Globe Biz on Twitter 

Loading from twitter...
 Follow GlobeBiz on Twitter 
 
 Follow other Boston.com Tweets | What is Twitter? 
 
 News as it happens. Send your tips or comments to breakingnews@globe.com get updates My Yahoo RSS Feeds 
 Learn about RSS 
 
INside Boston.com

 Thrilling rides Amusement park rides found across New England Route 128&apos;s evolution See how the heavily traveled highway has changed Celebrity Scientologists Stars who follow the religion founded by L. Ron Hubbard Bill Brett&apos;s party pictures Scenes from an &quot;Art Stars&quot; party in Boston Plus... 
 Blogs | Crossword | Comics | Horoscopes | Games | Lottery | Caption contest | Today in history 
 
 Boston.com Most Emailed Subscribe to Slice Bookmark Boston.com Most Emailed 120 
 MOST E-MAILED» 
 
 10 foods that naturally whiten and brighten your smile What landlords should look for in a tenant and how to be a good renter How to know if your child is really sick - MD Mama - Boston.com Broiled chicken salad with orange vinaigrette Tour de France 2012: Part one Free things to do around Boston San Fermin 2012: Running of the Bulls 
 Follow this list on Twitter: @BostonPopular Col3 
 Home | Today&apos;s Globe | News | Business | Sports | Lifestyle | A&amp;E | Things to Do | Travel | Cars | Jobs | Real Estate | Local Search 

 Contact Boston.com | Help | Advertise | Work here | Privacy Policy | Your Ad Choices | Newsletters | Mobile | RSS feeds | Sitemap 

 Contact The Boston Globe | Subscribe | Manage your subscription | Advertise |
	</body>
</document>
