<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003969" url="http://www.sleekhair.com/20112.html" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="3" score="0.024274075051196442" bingtitle="AG Fast Food - leave on condition" webtitle="AG Fast Food - leave on condition">
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>This is the next in a long line of leave in conditioners that I have tried and I have yet ... © 2012 SleekHair.com All Rights Reserved. Yahoo Store Designed and Developed by ...</description>
	<body>
		Home  &gt;   &gt;  AG Fast Food - leave on condition 
 Home  &gt;  Hair Products  &gt;  AG Hair Cosmetics  &gt;  AG Fast Food - leave on condition 
 Home  &gt;  More Ways to Shop for Hair  &gt;  Shop by Brands  &gt;  view all brands  &gt;  AG Hair Cosmetics  &gt;  AG Fast Food - leave on condition 
 
 
AG DV8 Texture Spray
 
AG FastFWD Dry Shampoo
 
AG Fast Food - leave on condition 
 
VIEW ALL PRODUCTS BY AG Hair Cosmetics 
 
Item Code : 20112 
     Tweet 
 (29 Reviews) 
 Product Price   Qty Add To Cart 
Size : 2 oz / travel size
 item # 20112-2-oz-travel-size 
$4.99
 Send me an email when Back in Stock 20112-2-oz-travel-size 
Size : 6 oz
 item # 20112-6-oz 
$11.99
 Send me an email when Back in Stock 20112-6-oz 
Size : 12 oz / pump
 item # 20112-12-oz-pump 
$19.99
 
Size : 33.8 oz / liter
 item # 20112-33-8-oz-liter 
$28.79
 
Size : 135 oz / gallon
 item # 20112-135-oz-gallon 
$92.79
 
 Description 
 AG Fast Food is a leave on conditioner that nourishes and detangles dry, lifeless hair. Ultralight formula helps prevent split ends, adds moisture, shine and vitality. Leave in for lasting protection. Recommended for long lasting nourishment and protection of the hair. Do not rinse!
Contains Hydroxypropyl- trimonium honey which is a naturally derived humectant that penetrates the hair allowing long term moisturizing benefits, also helps to repair split ends. Features Aloe Barbadensis Extract Derived from the Aloe Vera plant which is Used for its reputed therapeutic, moisturising and healing properties. Features Silk, Keratin and Wheat protein that improves moisture, strength, elasticity and shine.

Herbal Extracts soothe, stimulate and add shine to your hair.

 
Related Products
 
 12 Benefits Instant Healthy Hair Treatment 

Price: $17.99 

 

 (14 ratings) 
 
 12 Benefits Rapid Blowout Argan Oil Blow Dry Spray 

Price: $23.99 

 

 (4 ratings) 
 
 Alterna Bamboo Volume 48 Hour Sustainable Volume Spray 

Price: $20.39 

 

 (3 ratings) 
 
 ABBA Exacting - Medium Hold Working Hair Spray (original formula in blue bottle) 

Price: $31.99 

 

 (2 ratings) 
 
 Abba Firm Hold Hair Spray 

Price: $15.99 

 


 
Recently Viewed Items
 

 
 Reviews Ask&amp;Answer 
 
Overall Rating 
 (based on 29 reviews) 
 
AG Fast Food...AMAZING!
 
By Angelica from Bronx, NY on April 29, 2012 
 I love all AG products. I recommend this product to everyone I know. Leaves my curls soft and manageable. 
 
Pros:
EVERYTHING!!! 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Nice leave-in
 
By Hair product junkie from WI on April 13, 2012 
 This leave-in is just right for my long, wavy, fine but a lot of it, colored hair. It tames down the frizz and fly-aways when I air dry my hair. When I scrunch it while blow-drying with a diffuser I like to use the recoil curl cream also and get nice waves/curls with this combo. 

 
Works Great
 
By Samantha from Big Lake, MN on January 12, 2012 
 This product smells great and makes brushing damp hair easy. It doesn&apos;t weigh the hair down either. Easy to use every day. 
 
Pros:
Fragrance
detangle assistance
conditions well 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
very good
 
By maria from tampa, fl on October 2, 2011 
 very good leave in condition for dry long hair but dont use too much of it .... 
 
Pros:
detangles and conditions 
Cons:
my hair still feels dry after several hour then have to use the anti frizz serum stilll.... 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Healthy natural shine
 
By Kavitha from Fremont, CA on September 28, 2011 
 Love this product. Had been searching for something that would hair a healthy shine but not stiff hair. 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
soft hair
 
By linda from aubrey, tx on August 18, 2011 
 this product makes my hair very soft and does not weigh it down. I actually had got one of the other AG products and was happy with it and decided to give this one a try. Very good results! 
 
Pros:
makes my soft 
Cons:
pricy 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
does its job
 
By Rachel from rochester, ny on August 15, 2011 
 If you have thin, limp hair I would not recommend using this product every day. It definitely does its job by giving your hair a deep conditioning but it leaves my hair pretty lifeless. I only use it when my hair feels like it is desperate for moisture after being in the pool or sun all day. 
 
Pros:
leaves your hair feeling silky smooth and soft. 
Cons:
Leaves hair lifeless 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Great Product!!
 
By Patty from Utica, Kentucky (KY) on August 7, 2011 
 I purchased this product upon someone&apos;s suggestion. I am very pleased with the manageability it has given me without being too stiff. My hair is very long, waist length, but also very fine. Finding a leave-in product that doesn&apos;t weigh my hair down is rare. Thanks Sleek Hair for providing a great product at an exceptional price!! 
 
Pros:
Goes on without leaving hair stiff or sticky
Adds volume to my fine hair
Nice fragrance

 
Cons:
No problem with the product so far but a 1 Liter bottle is rather difficult to manage while squeezing out the product with one hand into the other. I need to find a smaller container to transfer it into to eliminate this issue. 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Very nice
 
By Penny from Golden, BC, Canada on July 25, 2011 
 I was concerned that it might leave my hair greasy but no, very soft and lively. 
 
Cons:
I&apos;m really not sure of how much too use. 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
great leave-in conditioner
 
By Ye from Sunnyvale, CA on June 24, 2011 
 gives my hair shine and silk texture instantly, and can be used on both damp or dry hair which makes it my HG product! 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Love it
 
By Andrea from Ann Arbor, MI on June 7, 2011 
 I&apos;ve been using Fast Food for almost five years. This stuff is amazing. I put it in right after I wash my hair, which usually starts to fuzz up as soon as it hits the air. Fast Food has made my hair unbelievably healthy. 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Absolutely the best leave in conditioner I have tried
 
By April from Rockwood, TN on May 19, 2011 
 This is a lightweight conditioner that really works and doesnt leave my hair feeling weighted down or heavy. This is truly a wonderful conditioner and smells great too. No icky residue feeling on your hair after use adn I use it daily. my hair feels soft and smooth. 
 
Pros:
This is one of the best leave ins around 
Cons:
NONE 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Great Product
 
By Sunshine from NY on April 24, 2011 
 It worked great after washing with AG Xtramoist shampoo and Ultramoist conditioner. Fast Food made my hair smooth and easy to detangle plus it smells nice. 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
LOVE IT !!!! :)
 
By jennifer from brooklyn, ny on March 2, 2011 
 I can HONESTLY SAY i absolutley LOVE LOVE LOVE THIS PRODUCT !!! its the best thing thats happened to my hair like i hvae good hair, it has natural curls and wen blown and straighten looks dead like chinese hair but wen i decided to do my hair myself o put sum of this amazing stuff on n finished blowing and straightening my hair i touched the top to love the hair around n it was FLUFFY i loved it ! it gives me movement like the fluffyness is amazing i can live wit out it ! its a must have if u do ur own hair ! 
 
Pros:
- leaves hair fluffy on top
- gives shine
- afordable becuase its long lasting
- softens hair 
Cons:
- biggest bottle is too expensive :( 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Nothing great
 
By momof2 from hockessin, de on January 13, 2011 
 This is the next in a long line of leave in conditioners that I have tried and I have yet to find the right one. It was a nice pump and pleasant smell, but I don&apos;t think it was that great. My hair was still tangled and not as soft as I would have expected. I will continue to search for a leave in conditioner that actually does make a difference 
 
Pros:
pump and smell 
Cons:
did not detangle or make hair soft 
 
Great Product
 
By Mary from Hampton, VA on September 6, 2010 
 I have very fine hair that I get permed often. Fast Food keeps my hair from being frizzy and does not weight my hair down. I love it! I use it every day. 
 
Pros:
Can use every day 
Cons:
None 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Doesn&apos;t weigh my thick,fine hair down
 
By Jonelle from Calif on August 18, 2010 
 I have lot&apos;s of hair, but it is fine and curly. This product does not weigh it down. I use one pump for my shoulder length hair. 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Great Conditioner
 
By Charlotte from Lincoln City, OR. on June 3, 2010 
 I have colored hair and use this product daily. It is not greasy and is very light, smells great. While it is a leave-in-hair conditioner, I use it in the shower and rinse it out. It works great either way. 
 
Pros:
Non-greasy
Light
Smells Great 
Cons:
None 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Works Great and is Light!
 
By Lisa from Albuquerque on May 12, 2010 
 I used thsi AFTER the color shampoo and conditioner. My hair is soft and shiney and not weighed down at all. I only wash my hair every 3 days or so and can not stand build up - this works great. My hair is still light and bouncy! 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Awesome!
 
By Carolina from Coral Springs, Florida on April 19, 2010 
 Awesome! 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Love it!
 
By Analynn from new york, ny on March 10, 2010 
 This is such a great leave in conditioner. It is not greasy. It leaves hair soft and manegable. I &apos;ve been using it for about six months and i love it. It finished and i couldn&apos;t find it anywhere. I am so glad sleekhair carries this product. 
 
Pros:
smells great, makes her soft but not greasy 
Cons:
no cons 
 
AG FAST FOOD - LEAVE ON CONDITIONER
 
By Lori from Canada on February 24, 2010 
 I HAVE NATURALLY FINE CURLY HAIR, AND I REALLY, REALLY, RECOMMEND THIS LEAVE - IN - CONTIONER. I HAVE TRIED MANY IN THE PAST, MOROCCAN OIL LEAVE IN WAS WAY TO GREASY. THIS CONDITIONER IS ONE OF THE BEST!! IT IS NOT GREASY OR STICKY, SO I HIGHLY RECOMEND THIS PRODUCT! 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
Unbelieveable!!!!!!!!!
 
By Gwendolyn from Spring, Texas on February 12, 2010 
 Absolutely one of the best products I have ever used! I was getting what I call &quot;old lady hair&quot;. You know, the kind that is just frizzed and lifeless-forget air drying! After about a week of using this product, I was getting the results that I had been looking for , for a long time. 

 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
I highly recommend it!!
 
By Tatiana from Cleveland, Ohio on August 6, 2009 
 I have very fine oily hair that I&apos;ve been dying for over 20 years and gets tangled easy. I tried many many products to keep my hair from being a tanlged mess and keep soft and shiny without weighing it down or getting too greasy. My stylist recommended this product and I am hooked! I have tried to use some other salon products when I ran out of this the 1st time....never again! I now keep it in stock. I highly recommend it!! 
 
Pros:
Weightless, non-greasy 
Cons:
No cons :) 
 
I would recommend this item to a friend.
 
 
I&apos;ve been using Fast Food for almost a year now, and I swear by it
 
By Taytay on July 21, 2009 
 I&apos;ve been using Fast Food for almost a year now, and I swear by it. I have been searching for a leave-in that isn&apos;t heavy, thick, greasy, etc. This stuff is amazing. I put it in right after I wash my hair, which usually starts to fuzz up as soon as it hits the air. I&apos;m a natural blonde with very fluffy, goldilocks hair that has been curly, straight, heat-styled, platinum, black, and every shade in between. Within a year Fast Food has made my hair unbelievably healthy. I&apos;m going to purchase the big bottle of it this time! 

 
I love this product
 
By Arlene on May 27, 2009 
 I love this product, and I&apos;m on my third tube. I have fine straight hair, which does need a little conditioning because it&apos;s colored, but regular conditioner makes it flat as a pancake - just awful. Unless the weather is tinder dry, this product provides reasonable body. YEAH! 

 
I recommend this product!
 
By kori on May 19, 2009 
 have very thin hair and my hair dresser told me I needed to use strengthening treatment every week. She recommended this for everyday use and I have followed her advice.

I&apos;m usually hesitant towards leave-in products but this feels natural, not sticky at all and it doesn&apos;t lave any stains or traces on my clothes. My hair has more volume and feels stronger. I recommend this product! 

 
this product worked well for me
 
By roxanne on May 19, 2009 
 I am a black american with relaxed hair and this product worked well for me. Although it is a bit drying, it does prevent snapping and shedding from occurring when I blow dry. 

 
Two days of use and my hair looks and feels healthier.
 
By Gab on May 19, 2009 
 Two days of use and my hair looks and feels healthier. I use a dime size with a dime size amount of the iron repair and that gives me bouncy silky hair like no body&apos;s business. 

 
 AG Fast Food - leave on condition $4.99 
 
 AG Fast Food - leave on condition 20112 http://ep.yimg.com/ca/I/sleekhair_2220_6447562 4.99 In Stock 
Shop by category

 Hair Products Skin Products Make-Up Cosmetics Nail Products Hair Color&amp;Salon Treatments 

 Flat Irons / Straighteners Curling Irons Hair Dryers Brushes, Tweezers&amp;Beauty Tools 
 
General Links

 Bookmark This Site 

 Gift Certificate 

 
 
Quick Links

 About Us Customer Services Terms of Use&amp;Policies Privacy Policy Order Status Contact Us 
 
Testimonials
 

 Read More... 
Newsletters
 Shopping cart ( 00 Items ) My Account | Login | Register | Customer Service 
Like us on
 (800-921-4813) 
 Hair Products 

Shop by Brands
 view all brands 
Extra
 New Arrivals Sale 


Shop by Hair Product Type
 argan moroccan oils dry shampoos leave-in conditioners lotion / cream leave-in conditioners spray pump shampoo conditioner treatments&amp;hair masques styling - curl creams&amp;curl gels styling - hairsprays aerosol styling - hairsprays non-aerosol styling - hair gels&amp;styling creams styling - mousses, foams&amp;root lifters styling - pastes&amp;hair glue styling - pomade&amp;hair waxes styling - sea salt sprays styling - serums for smoothing&amp;shine styling - shine sprays&amp;creams styling - straightening gels&amp;creams 


Shop by Solution
 black ethnic hair children&amp;baby&apos;s hair curly hair dandruff men&apos;s hair short hair thinning or hair loss 
 Skin Products Make-Up Cosmetics Nail Products Hair Color&amp;Salon Treatments 

Shop by Product Type
 hair color developer&amp;peroxide hair coloring tools in-salon hair treatments perms straighteners / relaxers 
 Flat Irons / Straighteners Curling Irons Hair Dryers Brushes, Tweezers&amp;Beauty Tools 
 Search 
 
 Shop by Brand View All Brands Twelve 12 Benefits 911 Hayashi ABBA Affinage Salon Professional AG Hair Cosmetics Agadir Argan Oil Alfaparf Milano Alpha Hydrox Alter Ego Italy Alterna Alto Bella Aloxxi American Crew Amika AminoGenesis Amir Argan Oil Amplify by Matrix Anuva Cosmeceutic Haircare Anasazi Aphogee Aquage Ardell Lashes Arimino Artec Texture Line by L&apos;Oreal Aveda Avigal Henna Avlon Hair Care B Beaute - Beauty Instruments B&amp;C;Skin Tight Product Babo Botanicals Back to Basics Bain de Terre Barex Italiana Batiste Dry Shampoo Bed Head by Tigi Big Sexy Hair Bio Ionic Bioken Biolage by Matrix Biolustre Biosilk by Farouk Biotouch Nutri-Care by Wella Black 15 in 1 blinc skin care&amp;cosmetics Blow New York Body Drench Bonacure by Schwarzkopf B:OCE by Molto Bene Bosley Professional Strength Brazilian Blowout Brocato Bumble and Bumble Cadiveu Professional Carol&apos;s Daughter CHI - Cationic Hydration Interlink Christian Cosmetics Circle of Friends Clay Esthe Clairol Professional CND Nail Products Color Me by Giuliano Color Preserve by Wella Color Smart by Matrix Couvre Crede Creme of Nature Croc by Turbo Ion Crome Curl Friends Curl Junkie Curl Life by Matrix Curlisto CURLS Curly Hair Solutions Curly Sexy Hair Davines Dermalogica Skin Care DermMatch Hair Loss Concealer DermOrganic Deva Hair Products Diane Beauty Accessories Difiaba Dikson ArgaBeta Line d:fi hair Dr. Miracle&apos;s DS Laboratories Dudley&apos;s Q Earthly Body Hair Care ECRU New York ELC Dao of Hair Emani Minerals Cosmetics Enjoy Essations Excelsior Eufora Hair Fake Bake - Sunless Tanning Fantasia IC Fairy Tales Hair Care for Children Faster Hairspray Company Fekkai FHI Heat Folicure Framesi Milan Fudge Fullmore Colored Hair Thickener Fusion - Energy of Beauty Geleration by Jessica Cosmetics Gelish - Hand&amp;Nail Harmony GHD Giesee SUN Tanning Products Gigi Wax - Hair Removal Global Keratin GK Gloss Moderne Godefroy Goldwell got2b by Schwarzkopf Graham Webb Gray Magic by Ardell Groganics Products Grund / Pro Design H2T Head to Toe HAI Hair Rules Hairtech International Hair Toys Texture Hair U Wear - Extension Shampoo Halo Hask Hayashi Head Games Healthy Hoof by Gena Healthy Sexy Hair Hempz by Supre Hinoki by Hayashi Huile de Niche ICE Hair by Joico I.C.O.N. Iden Bee Propolis Image Infusium 23 Professional Inphenom Iso Hair IT&amp;LY;Hair Fashion It&apos;s a 10 Ten Jane Carter Solution J Beverly Hills Jerome Russell Jessicurl JLife Haircare John Masters Organics John Paul Pet Joico Kadus Imunal Kenra KeraCare by Avlon Kerastase by L&apos;Oreal Paris Keratin Complex Smoothing Therapy by Coppola Keratin Express Keune Kevin Murphy Kim Vo Kin Cosmetics Kinky-Curly KIS - Kreative Innovative Smart Kiss Me Mascara&amp;Eyeliner Kiwi Coloreflector by L&apos;oreal Artec KMS California Kusco-Murphy Australia Label.M Professional Haircare Lanza Healing HairCare Leonor Greyl Liquid Hair by Wella Liquid Keratin Living Proof LS&amp;B;Lock Stock and Barrel Grooming Logics - Color DNA System Loma L&apos;Oreal Professionnel Paris L&apos;Oreal Serie Expert Loretta by Molto Bene Macadamia Natural Oil Mane &apos;n Tail Marcia Teixeira Brazilian Keratin Treatment Mastey Mason Pearson Hair Brushes Marrakesh Oil Matrix Michael O&apos;Rourke Milbon Mixed Chicks Mizani MoltoBene Hair Care MOP Modern Organic Products Model in a Bottle Murad Skin Care Murad Hair Care Nail Tek Nailtiques Nairobi Naked Glow Cosmetics Nature&apos;s Therapy by L&apos;oreal Nexxus Nigelle by Milbon Nioxin Nolita Nucleic-A Number 4 Hair Obliphica Ojon One &apos;n Only by Jheri Redding Onesta OPI Nail Polish&amp;Treatments Organic Root Stimulator Oribe Original Little Sprout by D&apos;Organiques Orofluido OSiS by Schwarzkopf Osmo Essence Paul Brown Hawaii Paul Mitchell Pearatin by Loma Philip B Phyto Organics by Nexxus Phyto Pravana Prejume Prive - formule aux herbes Profound Beauty Hair ProRituals by Jingles PureHair The Pure Shop Pureology QTICA Quantum by Zotos Queen Helene Redken Redken for Men Rejuvenol Rene Furterer Rescue EMS Haircare Emergency Retro Hair Revitalash Eyelash Conditioner Revivogen Hair Loss Solution Roux Hair Products Rusk Salerm Saryna Key by Onyx Natural Satin Hair Color by Developlus S-Factor by TIGI Schwarzkopf Professional Scruples Sebastian Senscience Liquid Luxury Sexy Hair Shimmer Lights by Clairol Shu Uemura - Art of Hair Silkology Silque Hair Shine by Croc Simply Organic Simply Smooth Sleek Look by Matrix SkinMedica Science of Beautiful Skin Soma Hair Sorbie by Trevor Sorbie Sorme Cosmetics Spencer Forrest St. Tropez Tan Stript Mineral Make-Up Sudzz FX Treatments SunGlitz Super Million Hair Super Nail Supernatural Ecoly Formulas T3 Hair Products TanTowel Tate&apos;s The Natural Miracle Tea Tree Tecnica Brushes Tend Skin - Razor Bumps Terax Hair Care Therapro MEDIceuticals Therapy-G for thinning or fine hair TIGI Toni&amp;Guy Toppik Hair Building Fibers Tosca Hair Tressa Tri Hair - Institute of Trichology TurboIon Hair Appliances Tweezerman Uspa Supernatural Vavoom by Matrix Via Hair Brushes VitaTress by Nexxus Wahl Professionals Wella White Sands Woody&apos;s Men&apos;s Grooming XFusion Keratin Hair Fibers Y Serum by Nexxus Youthair Yu Be Skin Cream Yuko Zerran Hair Care Zoya View All Brands Brands 
SleekHair.com is the premier source for professional hair products with top brands such as Avlon, Paul Mitchell, Redken, Farouk Biosilk Chi, Abba Hair, Schwarzkopf, Goldwell, Graham Webb, Alterna, Artec, Joico, Croc, GHD, Rusk, Kevin Murphy, Nioxin, Matrix, Kerastase, Bumble and Bumble, Deva Curl, Moroccan Oil, Tigi, Back to Basics and much more!
 Home | About Us | Customer Service | Contact Us | Order Status | Resources | Product List | Testimonials | Terms of Use&amp;Policies | Privacy | Sitemap | View Cart 
©2012 SleekHair.com All Rights Reserved.

 Yahoo Store Designed and Developed by Ydeveloper.com 
 AG Fast Food - leave on condition
	</body>
</document>
