<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003018" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100807024451AA7SKSa" time="2012-07-12-19:07" support="4" score="0.018325246900210177" bingtitle="Why am I not seeing resturant tips show up on my credit card ..." webtitle="Why am I not seeing resturant tips show up on my credit card statement? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="132"/>
	<description>If you keep your receipt, you will see where the total ... Leave tips on credit card, not on table. ... When was the last time you ate at a fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Other - Dining Out &gt; Resolved Question 
 AA Member since: March 15, 2009 Total points: 576 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Why am I not seeing resturant tips show up on my credit card statement?
 I&apos;ve been eating out alot lately, and paying with a credit card.

The tips I&apos;m leaving are not showing up on my statement even days later. It still just says the amount of the food for 5+ items 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Motortro... Member since: February 19, 2008 Total points: 8,245 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Always leave tips as CASH monies and draw a line through the tip space if you use plastic.Put the cash on top of your signed credit card receipt when you pay.You will notice improved service from the waiter or waitress if you return to the place often.Only tools tip on a credit card. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 80% 4 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (1)
 
 by MAGGIENI... Member since: June 22, 2006 Total points: 1,327 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 the tips and the price of the meal are added. The waiter gets his from the management since most people use credit cards. If you keep your receipt, you will see where the total includes meal charge and tip. Watch your statement and keep the copies of signed receipts and compare. If not in order,call a govt agency(Start with FBI) don&apos;t call restaurant, because it may be a scam run by the restaurant or an employee. It is hard to tell. Leave tips on credit card, not on table. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Dining Out 

 Why do I get food poisoning from fast food places? My boss serves up old out of date food , what to do ? What do you usually get at Panera? Where to buy good cheesecake thats NOT from Cheesecake Factory? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
