<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003310" url="http://travel.ciao.co.uk/Nando_UK__Review_5941721" time="2012-07-12-19:26" support="2" score="0.0008876837494731448" bingtitle="Nando, UK - Review - The Chicken Master - Travel : Read reviews ..." webtitle="Nando, UK - Review - The Chicken Master">
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>... United Kingdom Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Restaurant United ... menu each and then goes off to seat the ... chicken with two sides) as you get a good value for that and also order one ...</description>
	<body>
		Join Ciao | Login | Help | Mobile 
 Ciao - for people with opinions 

 Latest reviews Latest questions Write a review Latest videos 
 Home &gt; Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Restaurant United Kingdom Restaurants 
 Nando, UK &gt; Reviews (15) 
 next review The Chicken Master 51 of 51 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Rating from Suavilous ( 21/10/2010 ) 
 Advantages Great food, good value for what you get

 Disadvantages None apart from that they get real busy! Or when they run out of CHICKEN!!!
 
This is a general review on Nando&apos;s and not a specific one I have been to, as I have been to quite a few :-). a Nandos fan for quite a while now, so much so that I get in a huff when someone says to me &apos;Nandos is not all that&apos;. How can they say that!!!!! (I am not crazy and I have reduced my sugar intake!). I go there a few times and not someone who goes there very often.

What is Nando&apos;s

Well first off, Nandos is a chain of restaurants specialising in chicken dishes of portuguese origin and now the odd vegetarian and steak dish.

The Joint

When entering the restaurant you are greeted with a smile by one of the employees, they ask the usual how many people then take you to your seat. When seated they ask if you have been here before (which I say yes but have been tempted to say no and see what he/she says), gives us a menu each and then goes off to seat the other customers. Before he/she leaves a green chicken is placed on to our table. This I am assuming is to indicate whether or not we have received our food as it tends to disappear when eating my Free whole chicken.
The overall look of the place is quite natural looking. The tables are a dark brown wood, the same with the seats (can be quite uncomfortable!). The lighting in the place is not too bright. The overall feel is quite mediterranean. I quite like it.
The chickens are cooked on an open grill so you can see it being cooked which is always a nice touch, instead of sitting there wondering what they are doing to your food at the back!

What&apos;s there to eat

The menu is like any other menu, starters (appetisers), mains, platters to share, salads, sides, fino sides (posh side orders) and drinks. They also have a little section on the bottom left of the menu for the little ones called Nandinos. A dessert menu is separate from the main menu. They mainly offer chicken (as you might of guessed), from the actual chicken on the bone (wings, a quarter chicken, half chicken or the whole thing), chicken in a bun, chicken in pitta, in a wrap or in a salad. They have also now got a steak roll in their specials section along with chicken liver in a roll. There is also a good amount for vegetarians in a form of pitta, burger and wrap. So everyone is catered for.

How do I order

When you have decided what to eat, YOU then go to the till and place your order. Yep nobody comes to you, you go to them. This seems to be a real bad point in Nando&apos;s as most people would like there order taken by an employee instead of going up to the till to order. You tell them your table number, place the order and pay. When ordering your chicken you can choose to have it how hot you want. It called the Peri-ometer. It starts off like this:
Lemon&amp;Herb or Mango and Lime (Level 1)
Medium (Level2)
Hot (Level 3)
Extra Hot (Level 4)
Being a person who likes his hot food I tried the Hot once and it was HOT, so I tend to go for the medium nowadays. Please let me know what the very hot one is like please lool.
If you have ordered drinks, you will be given glasses and then directed to the section where the knives and forks are along with extra plates and the sauces.
 
So in a sense you do all the work apart from cook the food for Nandos lool. I usually order half a chicken, with chips and spicy rice.

How long is the wait?

You usually wait for about 10-15mins depending on what branch your in (I waited for about an hour in the Westfields branch,never again!!!) and how busy they are. You are then served, with all the food together, you also get a toothpick with your spice on it for decoration.

The taste

I am always happy with the quality of the food of Nandos, the chicken is always cooked, the rice is always hot and the chips and not to greasy. The chicken might be now and again but that could be due to them painting the peri peri sauce all over when cooking. Mid way into your meal they come and ask if everything is ok (perfect timing when I have a chunk of chicken in my mouth! and all I can do is mumble Yes thank you) and thats when the green chicken disappears!! Only on one occassion did I have a problem (Westfields again!) where my posh side order (sweet potatos) came cold. I told them and they apologised and gave me a new hot one.

How much?!

The overall total price for Nandos is pretty good. Two people eating with spend about £20 altogether and we come out of there very full so for my good value. It all depends on how hungry you are and what you want to eat.

Overall experience of Nandos is very nice, the employees are very helpful and very polite and try to do their best for you. The overall look of the place is very nice, it&apos;s clean and they also have a sink for you to wash you hands in which is nice. Thankfully they dont make us wash up to lool.
If you go as a couple I would recommend the platter (Whole chicken with two sides) as you get a good value for that and also order one bottomless drink, you can save £1.99 :-). Plus it will look quite romantic :-P.

Loyalty Card

If like a few friends I know like Nando&apos;s a bit too much, they have a loyalty card which rewards you. It&apos;s a little paper card just like the ones you have in starbucks. Everytime you spend £5 or more you will get the card stamp. When you reach a certain amount of stamps you will be rewarded with chicken. The first is a quarter chicken, the next a half chicken and then when you fill in the whole card, you get a WHOLE chicken, for FREE!!! Good times. The cards can be attained at the till. If they are not there, ask someone and I&apos;m sure they will be happy to give you one.
At Nando&apos;s they have
Thank you for reading and hope you find it useful. Thie review can also be found on Dooyoo. Page 1 of 2   Next page   See next review 
Detailed Rating

 Value for Money Standard of Menu Atmosphere Standard of Service Cleanliness Family Friendly 
 Nando, UK 
User rating

 15 Reviews 
 Ask a question Write your own review more 
 Upload video review Receive review alert Comment on this review Add Suavilous to my Circle of Trust Subscribe to Suavilous&apos;s reviews Print review Add review to Favourites 
 
The Author
 Suavilous since 29 Apr 2010 
Need to get back into Ciao Shape! Hey guys please go through all reviews and not just the most... more 
 17 Members trust me 
   Add to Circle of Trust 

   Send a Message 
 
Author&apos;s newest reviews

 
 10/04/2012 
 Simply Brilliant... 
 
 
 23/09/2010 
 Silently taking over! 
 
 

 See all 21 reviews 

   Subscribe to reviews 
 
 Write your own review Print 
 See next review&quot; Cluck along to Nando&apos;s! &quot; 
Rate this User Review
 How helpful was this review to you? Rating guidelines 
   Exceptional   Very Helpful   Helpful   Somewhat Helpful   Not Helpful   Off topic 
 







 





 
Attention, this is the first review from this author

Instead of giving a negative rating, consider:

 
Help this member by giving your advice
 
Report fraud (for example plagiarism) or other issue with the review to the Ciao support team
 
 Activate low rating buttons 
Add your comment
 This action can only be performed by logged in members.   Post comment   Post comment 



 
 51 Ciao Members have rated this review on average: Very Helpful View all ratings 
 
JavaScript should be enabled to rate or post a comment.
 
Comments
 Maybe you have a question about Nando, UK? Ask here Page 1 of 11 | 1 - 5 out of 51 comments 
 Show only Comments Filter by: All ratings 
 
 
 All ratings (51) 
 
 (0) 
 
 (51) 
 
 (0) 
 
 (0) 
 
 (0) 
 
 (0) 
 
 
 Gingerkitty 26/04/2012 08:41 
 Rated this review as Very Helpful 
 harveydog52 15/04/2012 08:43 
 Rated this review as Very Helpful 
 trayrope 15/04/2012 01:18 
 Rated this review as Very Helpful 
 Alyson29 14/04/2012 20:29 
 Rated this review as Very Helpful 
 
Well covered x
 CelticSoulSister 14/04/2012 20:18 
 Rated this review as Very Helpful 
 
 Page 1 of 11 | 1 - 5 out of 51 comments 
Sponsored links
 for Nando, UK 
More reviews
 for Nando, UK 
 Most helpful reviews Best/Worst reviews Newest reviews 
 
 Hot Chicks Review with images 15/07/2007 211 of 211 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Not just your average chicken 18/03/2012 49 of 49 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Nando&apos;s - I Don&apos;t Quite Get It Review with images 29/01/2011 64 of 64 Ciao Users found the following review helpful 
 
 Hot Chicks Review with images 15/07/2007 211 of 211 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Not just your average chicken 18/03/2012 49 of 49 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Just eat with your hands 22/12/2007 16 of 16 Ciao Users found the following review helpful 
 
 My local Nando&apos;s (Guildford, Surrey) 12/07/2012 24 of 24 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Not just your average chicken 18/03/2012 49 of 49 Ciao Users found the following review helpful Nando&apos;s - More Than Chicken? 16/09/2011 62 of 62 Ciao Users found the following review helpful 
 
Similar Offers
 for Nando, UK 
 
 
 Ricosta Junior Nando Schoko Brown Snow Boot 52329-284 13 Child UK, 32 EU 

Ricosta Boys waterproof boot, Ricosta Nando 52329-284, Brown with red trims, Wool Polyester lining, WMS Fitting System Wide W fitting, Sympatex...
 
 £51.99 

   Visit Shop  &gt; 
 
amazon marketplace shoes

 
 108 
Reviews 
 
 
 Shipping:  £4.00

 Availability:  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days
 
 
 
 Ricosta Junior Nando Schoko Brown Snow Boot 52329-284 10 Child UK, 28 EU 

Ricosta Boys waterproof boot, Ricosta Nando 52329-284, Brown with red trims, Wool Polyester lining, WMS Fitting System Wide W fitting, Sympatex...
 
 £51.99 

   Visit Shop  &gt; 
 
amazon marketplace shoes

 
 108 
Reviews 
 
 
 Shipping:  £4.00

 Availability:  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days
 
 
 
 RICOSTA NANDO 52229/284 Unisex-child Boot, Brown 6.5 UK 

RICOSTA NANDO 52229/284 Unisex-child Boot, Brown 6.5 UK
 
 £76.96 

   Visit Shop  &gt; 
 
amazon marketplace shoes

 
 108 
Reviews 
 
 
 Shipping:  £2.00

 Availability:  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days
 
 
 See all Similar Offers 
 See next review: 

 Cluck along to Nando&apos;s! 

by GemmaC25

 See all 15 reviews 
 Home &gt; Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Restaurant United Kingdom Restaurants &gt; 
 Product Overview Compare Prices Product Information Reviews Media Gallery 
 
 About us  - Jobs  - Press  - Ciao Quality Seal  - Advertise with Us  - Become a Partner 
 
 Ciao Deutschland  - Ciao France  - Ciao Italia  - Ciao Nederland  - Ciao Sverige  - Ciao España 
 
 Site Index  - Ciao Charts  - Data Protection  - Most searched Products 
 © 2012 Shopping Guide GmbH travel.ciao.co.uk
	</body>
</document>
