<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003552" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090920204157AAEqX0X" time="2012-07-12-19:42" support="2" score="0.004302477569126516" bingtitle="Tips to be able to afford being a stay at home mum? - Yahoo!7 Answers" webtitle="Tips to be able to afford being a stay at home mum? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="113"/>
	<description>... Christmas gift a breadmaker is awesome... throw ... toys from recylable plastic bottles or boxes or ... food from the dollar menu at your local fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Pregnancy&amp;Parenting &gt; Other - Pregnancy&amp;Parenting &gt; Resolved Question 
 bettiebe... Member since: 22 June 2007 Total points: 1,555 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Tips to be able to afford being a stay at home mum?
 Any good tips on how to afford being able to stay at home full time to raise my kids when my 2nd baby comes along? For my first baby I went back to work part time, but I&apos;m looking for any good ways of cutting costs in our lifestyle so that I can be a full time mum for both of my kids. We don&apos;t have a particularly extravagent lifestyle, but I&apos;m just on the lookout for any cost saving tips. We already have most baby stuff because we already have a child... 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Heather Member since: 30 August 2009 Total points: 1,659 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 -Make a budget (write down everything you spend for the next month) and compare it to what your husband made this month. If you are spending too decide what you can live without

-Learn to cook if you don&apos;t know how there are plenty of recipes online or even on the sides of cans at the grocery store. It is nearly always cheaper to cook your own meal than to eat out (and usually healthier too)

-Get into the habit of having sandwiches for lunch. They are cheap especially if you make your own bread. (If your parents or someone offers to get you guys a Christmas gift a breadmaker is awesome... throw the ingredients in and you have cheap healthy bread a few hours later)

-Turn you thermostat up or down a degree (depending on if it is summer/winter)

-Put your kids in the shower with you to bath (depending on their age) it saves a lot of water or bathe them together when they are old enough. When filling the bathtub only fill it up a couple inches.

-Turn down your water heater (prevents burns and also saves gas/electricity.

-INSULATE all around windows and pipes and even around your water heater especially if it is in your garage or a cold basement

-Drink more water... pop or lots of cups of juice everyday is not healthy and costs more than water. And drink it from the tap unless it is truly unhealthy

-Turn off lights as much as possible. Open drapes for lunch rather than turning on the light. Depending on the age of your kids they might even have fun with a candlelight dinner (and you will save on electricity)

-Determine if you really need the internet / cable package that you have

-Hold each other accountable for money you spend. Agree on an amount that you can spend up to. In our house if one of us is going to spend more than $25 on something (other than groceries) we wait and check with the other before buying said item. Sometimes just by waiting we will decide ourselves that we really don&apos;t need that item we wanted or we might be able to buy a cheaper version.

-Shop at garage sales, thrift stores, consignment sales etc.

-Make toys from recylable plastic bottles or boxes or whatever you have laying around the house rather than buying expensive toys (there are lots of internet sites and books on activities to do with kids that don&apos;t cost much)

-Learn how to do stuff yourself. For example, our deck needed stained. We got an estimate that it would cost $875. We decided to do it ourselves and although it has taken us weeks to finish it by just doing a few hours here and there it has only cost us about $100 compared to the estimate for $875. Also my husband bought a book and replaced our water heater himself rather than paying someone to do it. Change your own oil in your car (not hard to do if you find a book or go online).

-Have date night at the park with a picnic lunch or if you really want to go all out with food from the dollar menu at your local fast food restaurant. The kids will have fun, it is free, and at least you are out of the house.

-Breasfeed (only cost is a few nursing bras). No formula to buy.

-Make your own baby food. Nearly any food can be cooked for a little while then put in the blender and pureed. I found I could make organic baby food cheaper than the cheapest jarred food and I knew exactly what was in my food. For a great reference I used&quot;Super Baby Food&quot;by Ruth Yaron. You can find it at most bookstores or online.

-Good luck! It can be challenging at first to stay within your budget, but it is so worth it. I LOVE staying home with my son. 
Source(s):
 Stay at home mommy to a 15 month old. Husband makes a moderate income. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: thank you SO MUCH to you all - there are some really great ideas here which we will be using!! 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (3)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by TwoGirls... Member since: 03 January 2008 Total points: 2,335 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Double coupon days at the grocery store and shop consignment for clothes.
I made the move to full time mom shortly before conceiving #2. We only have our&quot;date night&quot;at home and let #1 stay at a grandparent&apos;s house close by, but even with 48k less a year, we&apos;re a lot happier. There&apos;s no feeling in the world like being there full time to see everything. I wouldn&apos;t trade it for anything. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by cutewhit... Member since: 04 August 2006 Total points: 2,256 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 What I&apos;ve done to help cut costs is only go grocery shopping twice a month and stock up on food every payday(which for my husband is the 1st and 15th). I usually spend about $150 for groceries every payday so around $300 at most a month. I have found a cheap place to shop that I have to drive about 20 miles, but I figure the savings really help. I only go to the local grocery stores if I absolutely have too because they are expensive. I mainly just get diapers from the local grocery store. What I&apos;ve found really helps is buying frozen vegetables because fresh ones are always expensive and that has helped save me quite a bit of money. Right now I have a family of 3 and I also have a 2nd child on the way so it will be a family of 4 in January. Another thing I have done is completely eliminate television from our lives because it costs so much. I instead use Netflix to watch movies online when my husband and I want to relax and watch a movie and they also have great kids shows to watch online. That saves us over 100 dollars a month. We are only paying around $15 for Netflix. We also chose a cheap cell phone plan and cheap phones. My husband needs his cell phone for work and we don&apos;t have a land line so for us cell phones are working best. Also if you have 2 cars, they aren&apos;t always necessary. It always depends on your situation, but sometimes being able to drop off and pick up your husband from work might help with gas costs and car maintenance costs. That&apos;s pretty much all I can think of right now. Hope I gave you a little bit of advice. 
Source(s):
 I live in one of the most expensive areas in the world and even though my husband makes a pretty good living we have to make sure we stay within our budget. It&apos;s tough so I have to make due with what we have. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Lee Member since: 22 September 2009 Total points: 914 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I am a single stay at home mum so money is very tight. Firstly you can keep the power bills down by using energy saving lightbulbs and turn everything of at its source. if you use a remote for example to turn off the tv it goes to standby and is technically still on. The onlyappliancee i have on around the clock is the fridge. we don&apos;t use the heater we put on extra clothes and cuddle up under blankets. My last power bill was $30 for 2 months. Buy extra food in the shopping and make meals to go in the freezer. This way if you are too tired to cook or just can&apos;t be bothered you have a ready made meal that just needs heating through. If you have time to wash them cloth nappies save alot of money,( this isn&apos;t an option for me, my 9 month old saturates a disposable in less than an hour). 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Why are little kids so cute? I REALLY Need someone to calm me down :&apos;( please? ? When is a good age for a girl to lose her virginity? What could I get for my mums birthday? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Stay at home Mums - what do you do to earn an income? Have any of you stay at home mum&apos;s done an online course? do you think we should have more stay at home mums or more… How hard is it realistically to be a stay at home mum? Benefits for Being a Stay At Home Mum if Partner is Self… 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 
 Adoption Baby Names Newborn&amp;Baby Other - Pregnancy&amp;Parenting Parenting Pregnancy Primary Schooler Teen&amp;Preteen Toddler&amp;Preschooler Trying to Conceive 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
