<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003897" url="http://www.43things.com/things/view/235/be-more-assertive" time="2012-07-12-20:03" support="10" score="0.022152685593671975" bingtitle="be more assertive - List your goals on 43 Things" webtitle="be more assertive">
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>I went to a fast food restaurant and stood in line to order my food. There was a man with ... stated that she already took his order. The man was polite but seemed to give ...</description>
	<body>
		Zeitgeist Login with
Facebook    Log in  or  Sign up 
 

 707 people want to do this. 5 people have this New Year&apos;s resolution. 
 be more assertive 
 
 
 
 
People doing this
 See everyone 
 

 
Recent activity
 Aradam added this goal 23 hours ago 
 
 
 KnapmanAR wrote big flaw 
 
One of my main flaws is I am not assertive whatsoever. I like other people to do things for me, or I like to wait for things to happen. I need to change this. I don’t think I am as bad as when I was in England, but there are still occasions where I avoid certain things to stay in my comfort zone. I need to push myself harder. 2 weeks ago 
 3 comments . Comment 
 KnapmanAR added this goal 2 weeks ago 
 2 cheers 
 EchoGecko added this goal 4 weeks ago 
 1 cheer 
 mpgal completed this goal 3 years ago 
 
 acertainflower completed this goal 4 years ago 
 
 
 itsasecret completed this goal 
 It took me 1 year It made me calmer 

 How I did it: Sometimes if you give yourself a chance to calm down it can be better than shouting at the wrong person for the wrong reason. Sometimes shouting does absolutely no good at all. It won&apos;t accomplish what you were hoping and the person still might not really understand. Think about the situation and what you should say or how you should handle . Hopefully the other person will be able to understand your point of view. It doesn&apos;t work all the time but it should more often than not. Read how I did it… 3 months ago 

 4 cheers . Comment itsasecret completed this goal 8 months ago 
 10 cheers 
 
 itsasecret wrote I know I&apos;m getting better about doing this 
 
I have to do it more without shouting or arguing. I haven’t been shouting as much as my mother but sometimes she doesn’t listen enough either. I hope i can move out soon. It will definitely improve my relationship with my parents. 3 months ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 Danniibee added this goal 3 months ago 
 
 
 itsasecret wrote the only way to get through to my father is to yell 
 
When i move i can hang up on him without yelling which will still be better 4 months ago 
 2 cheers . Comment 
 trivettk completed this goal 6 months ago 
 
 
 landslide wrote An ongoing process 
 
I feel that I have achieved this goal. I took an assertiveness class around five years ago, and feel though I am much more assertive and comfortable being so. I have also become less shy over the years. I realize now that I cannot always be nice. And I realize that not everyone in this world will respect my needs if I don’t speak up for myself. 4 months ago 
 Comment 
 landslide completed this goal 3 years ago 
 9 cheers 
 JCA51698 added this goal 4 months ago 
 
 
 itsasecret wrote I asked Jeff to stop bringing up something that was bothering 
 
He did and i didn’t even have to yell:) 4 months ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 ryan fo2l wrote stand up for self 
 
I set up this goal following comments about me being nice and helpful–a bit too much.
It dawned on me one day that I could be passive at times and let people get their way. It might be from my spirtual side of listening to Wayne Dyer CDs or reading books of that ilk. Now don’t get me wrong, this stuff is very importatnt to me, but I just needed to redress the balance somewhat.

I bought a book called how to be assertive in any situation and things started to make sense. It’s OK to say, I don’t understand or‘if I may finish, when you are interupted at work, or stand up for yourself if someone takes liberties. This is OK.

This is actually very imporant and worth pursuing. I have become stronger at work. I say what I want, how I feel.

Also, I have started playing football and this has made me more competitive.
This one stays open for a little while longer… 4 months ago 
 1 cheer . 1 comment . Comment 
 paulahops added this goal 4 months ago 
 1 cheer 
 
 itsasecret wrote Once I move 
 
I think i’ll have a better relationship with my parents. Not that we always fight, but probably more often than i should. I probably get mad at other sometimes and yell at them because their there. I don’t always do everything they ask right away but i guess i shouldn’t shout that i’m not going to do it. 4 months ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 itsasecret wrote I wish i had been more assertive in the past 
 
I still can’t figure out how to be assertive without overdoing it. 5 months ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 drjacoby79 added this goal 5 months ago 
 
 finduilas completed this goal 10 months ago 
 
 
 itsasecret wrote I might stand up more to my parents than i should 
 
but i don’t think i should have to do everything just because i still live with them 5 months ago 
 3 cheers . 2 comments . Comment 
 
 itsasecret wrote I have been standing up more myself 
 
I just have to figure out how to without shouting like a maniac… LOL 6 months ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 katherineh added this goal 6 months ago 
 
 chowchow completed this goal 6 years ago 
 2 cheers 
 Mr_Accountant added this goal 6 months ago 
 
 
 itsasecret wrote I haven&apos;t give into Baby Bastard 
 
even though he started calling again and I don’t plan on it. I don’t care if he thinks i’m being mean or something like that. He just won’t grow up and it’s not my fault and i don’t have to be there for him. He doesn’t know how to be a friend and he doesn’t deserve my friendship. 6 months ago 
 1 cheer . Comment 
 
 itsasecret wrote I am far better at this than 5 years ago 
 
I think this site has really helped me know i don’t have to put up with people’shit. 6 months ago 
 2 cheers . Comment 
 page51 added this goal 7 months ago 
 1 cheer 
 See more:     Entries   |   How I Did It Entries 
 
People who once wanted to do this are now doing these things:

 
 become more assertive - 614 fewer people 
 
 say&quot;no&quot;to people who ask too much of me - 538 fewer people 
 
 be more confident + 10792 more people 
 
 
People have suggested &quot;be more assertive&quot; is really the same as:

 
 say&quot;no&quot;to people who ask too much of me - 538 fewer people 
 
 not be afraid to speak up when i have an answer/idea/opinion - 674 fewer people 
 
 be more assertive at work - 699 fewer people 
 
 
 Report a very similar goal 
 
Report a very similar goal
The current goal: be more assertive 
Very similar goal: (or Cancel )
Meaning is slippery, but try to only add goals that have nearly identical meanings. For example, &quot;Be fluent in Italian&quot; and &quot;Speak fluent Italian&quot;.
 On average: This goal takes 7 years to complete 
Worth Doing

69 out of 69 people (100%) think this is worth doing.
 
 “ Here is the test to find whether your mission on earth is finished. If you&apos;re alive, it isn&apos;t. ” - Richard Bach, author 
 ( What is RSS? ) 
 First added to Alison Staudinger &apos;s list 
 
 I want to: 
The world wants to...
 clare90 wants to clean my room drink less soda Learn japanesse Keep a journal garden more make a collage complain less watch more black and white classic movies (pre-1950) dream lucidly Write a virus that will un-install Internet Explorer (your know who you are) and replace it with Firefox. get rejected floss my teeth Run a mile in 11 minutes have more confidence in myself WATCH THE WHOLE NARUTO SERIES Create a budget Claytons wants to get in shape make friendster layout use my own picture make video games Learn how to make music with Reason stop procrastinating learn to ride a motorcycle learn to rap have more patience become an actor knit enough pairs of socks so I can wear hand-knitted ones every day! become fluent in spanish 
 City Hall 
 FAQ Guidelines Contact Us Tools 
 iPhone App RSS API About Us 
 Our blog Press coverage Terms of Use Follow @43things Copyright©2004 - 2012 Robot Co-op 
 
 43 Things Login 
 Username: Password: Remember me   Forgot username or password? 
 or Join 43 Things
	</body>
</document>
