<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003842" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Phoenix/Sonic-DriveIn_1172" time="2012-07-12-19:59" support="1" score="0.00048505645232897884" bingtitle="Sonic Drive-In - Fast Food Restaurant Phoenix, AZ 85048" webtitle="Sonic Drive-In - Fast Food Restaurant  Phoenix, AZ 85048">
			<query id="000249" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>Sonic Drive-In is a Fast Food restaurant located at 4302 E Chandler ... Accepts Credit Card: Yes; Parking: N/A; Atmosphere: N/A ... with vanilla ice cream if you&apos;re brave! Best drink ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Sonic Drive-In
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(480) 704-9151

 
 AZ &gt; Phoenix &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Sonic Drive-In listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Sonic Drive-In to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Sonic Drive-In
 Sonic Drive-In is a Fast Food restaurant located at 4302 E Chandler Blvd in Phoenix, AZ 85048. Sonic Drive-In has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, American (Traditional) Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Sonic Drive-In
 
 
 
All Reviews for Sonic Drive-In


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Sonic Drive-In:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Tweets from Sonic Drive-In
 
 January 01, 1970   Reply 
 
Sonic Drive-In Tips
 Java chillers
 
Patricia W. Grape cream slush will change your life!
 
Charlie J. Try the Ocean Water: Sprite and blue coconut over ice! Get the float with vanilla ice cream if you&apos;re brave! Best drink ever!
 
Zyrion L. Strawberry Limeade in full FX!!!!
 
djSQEME Try the cranilla craze. It is the best drink at Sonic and underrated
 
Heather S. 
Sonic Drive-In News
 Sonic Higher Ahead of Earnings New York, January 3rd (TradersHuddle.com) - Shares of Sonic Corp. (NASDAQ:SONC) are trading higher by +1.78% ahead of its quarterly earnings release. Sonic, the franchisor and operator of chain of drive-in restaurants is expected to release its quarterly ... Sonic - Shares Seeking Direction New York, December 21st (TradersHuddle.com ... mainly signaling an indecision between buyers and sellers. Sonic Corp. (NASDAQ:SONC) franchises and operates a chain of drive-in restaurants. The Company currently has Company-owned and franchised restaurants ... Starbucks coming to Anderson ANDERSON — The site that once housed Anderson’s third Sonic Drive-in will next house a Starbucks coffee shop ... the company is now self-sufficient and has been listed on the New York Stock Exchange since 2006. Carolina Holdings operates ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing SONIC®, America’s Drive-In® Cruise to SonicDriveIn.com to read the SONIC® menu, use the store locator or find information about franchise opportunities. Then stop in for a SONIC® burger, a ... Sonic Drive-In - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Sonic Drive-In is an American drive-in fast-food restaurant chain based in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, complete with carhops who sometimes wear rollerskates. As of ... Store Locator - SONIC® Drive-In Use the SONIC® Drive-In store locator to find the closest SONIC® Drive-In location. Sonic Drive In - America&apos;s Drive In! Feist your eyes on this site using Flash, version 9 and up Where is the closest sonic restaurant to buffalo, new york? | ChaCha Where is the closest sonic restaurant to buffalo, new york? ChaCha Answer: The closest Sonic to Buffalo is at 517 Grandview Crossing ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 90° 
Fri
 
 88° - 104° 
Sat
 
 88° - 99° 
Sun
 
 88° - 106° 
 
Address
 
Sonic Drive-In

4302 E Chandler Blvd

Phoenix, AZ 
 
85048
 
Telephone
 (480) 704-9151 
Sonic Drive-In
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Sonic Drive-In Photos
 
 Fast Food American (Traditional) 
 
 Local Places
 
 Wendys 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Cousins Subs 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Yoshi&apos;s Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell/Long John Silvers 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Mcdonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Martin Gordon Auctions 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Arizona Citizens for the Arts 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Arizona Songwriters Association 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Art of Framing 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Artlink Incorporated 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Phoenix Art Museums Galleries 
See all Phoenix Shopping Centers 
See all Phoenix ATMs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Sonic Drive-In Coupons 

 Sonic Drive-In Phoenix 

 Sonic Drive-In Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Phoenix Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X Y | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
