<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003063" url="http://www.qsrmagazine.com/category/microsites/digital-signage-menuboards" time="2012-07-12-19:11" support="1" score="0.0028168455089240996" bingtitle="Digital Sign and Menu Board News for Restaurants - QSR magazine" webtitle="Digital Sign and Menu Board News for Restaurants - QSR magazine">
			<query id="001007" bing-rank="20"/>
	<description>Even as they try to figure out how to be transparent about calories, quick serves might soon need to open up to consumers about their carbon footprints.</description>
	<body>
		Jump to Navigation 
Digital Signage&amp;Menuboards
 July 12, 2012 
Digital Signage&amp;Menuboards
 sponsored by: Visual Impressions 
featured articles
 
 100 Ways to Improve Your Drive Thru 
Tips to better the efficiency and experience in your lane today.
 Could This Be the New Menu Label? 
Even as they try to figure out how to be transparent about calories, quick serves might soon need to open up to consumers about their carbon footprints.
 
 
industry resource
 
 How to Do Drive Thru 
Opening a location with a drive thru presents a new set of challenges. Architecture expert John Miologos helps you open your new window of opportunity.
 The Bistro Solution 
Marriott execs were tired of watching dining dollars walk out the front door, so they built their own fast casual.
 How to Upsell Drinks in the Drive Thru 
Coke’s senior marketing manager, James Latimore, shares secrets for capturing the 13 billion servings you’re missing each year in off-premise beverage sales.
 Global Into Local 
A quick-serve brand’s national marketing team is important, but the local-store marketing programs are essential to driving traffic to stores.
 The Midnight Mistake 
Late-night menus are all the rage, but don’t underestimate your night-time diners. They’re looking for value, too.
 
 
industry headlines
 Whataburger Unveils Menu Redesign, Under-550 Calorie Offerings 2012-07-11 
Last week, Whataburger hosted its own version of“Exteme Makeover: Menu Edition”when it unleashed a brand new menu redesign and item...
 YCD Multimedia Partners with Elo Touch on Digital Signage 2012-06-18 
YCD Multimedia, a global provider of digital media solutions to the retail business world, has teamed up with Elo Touch Solutions, a commercial...
 Togo’s Debuts California Club, New Menuboards 2012-06-05 
Raving fans of Togo’s have new reason to cheer this summer. The sandwich brand unveiled today its new California Club sandwich.

Now...
 Carvel Debuts Redesigned, “Classic Cool” Stores 2012-04-20 
Everything old is new again at Carvel Ice Cream , which has debuted its new“classic cool”look....
 Panasonic Offers New Stingray Envo POS Workstation 2012-03-21 
 

 Panasonic is adding new... 
 Subway&apos;s TV&amp;Radio Digital Signage Network Set to Expand 2012-03-06 
Real Digital Media, provider of the enterprise-class NEOCAST digital signage platform, and Independent Purchasing Cooperative Inc. (IPC), the...
 New Menuboards Give Cousins Subs Fast-Casual Look 2012-03-06 
There’s a fresh new way to order at every Cousins Subs store in the country. Wisconsin-based Cousins Subs rolled out nearly 170 new...
 VeriFone Extends Convenience Store Digital Media 2012-03-02 
VeriFone Systems, Inc., today announced the acquisition of LIFT Retail Marketing Technology, Inc., the provider of a digital marketing system...
 Noventri Launches Tool to Simplify Digital Menuboard Use 2012-02-21 
Noventri brings simplicity to the digital menuboard user with a newly announced service, QSR-Net. The service is directed toward quick-service...
 Noventri Unleashes New Digital Signage Software 2012-02-08 
 

 ... 
 
   1 of 11 ›› 
 
 
 
 Subscribe 
 
 Subscribe to QSR 

 Renew 

 Update Address 

 eLetters 

 Advertising 

 Contact 
       
Articles
 
Food&amp;Beverage

 Menu Innovations 

 Marc Halperin: Resident F&amp;B Expert 

 Food Safety 

 Health 

 Ingredients&amp;Dayparts 
 
Expansion

 QSR 50 

 Franchising 

 Growth 

 Fast Casual 

 George Green: Fast-Casual Expert 

 Emerging Concepts 
 
Technology

 Ordering 

 Social Media 

 Promotions 

 Sustainability 

 Denise Lee Yohn: QSR’s Marketing Guru 
 
Operations

 Executive Insights 

 Competition 

 In the Store 

 Consumer Trends 

 Charitable Giving 

 Outside Insights 

 Human Resources 

 Roy Bergold: Tales from McDonald’s 
 
 
Research
 
QSR 50
 
OneSource
 
Drive-Thru Study
 
Growth 40
 
 Smart Chain 

 Franchise Opportunities 

 Find a Supplier 

 Find a Job 

 Restaurant Management 
 
 
Events
 
 
 
 Dine America 

 NRA Show 

 Webinars 

 Webinar: HFCS Myths Addressed 
 
 News 
 See All 
 Togo’s Debuts Restaurant in Tracy, California 

 Pretzelmaker Unleashes Pretzel Dog, Facebook Giveaways 

 Maui Wowi Expands Colorado Operations 

 Teavana Breaks Ground on First Manhattan Location 

 Daphne’s Restructures Management Team 

 Lovin’ Spoons Hires Industry Vet for Franchise Development 

 Revitalized Arby&apos;s Inks Major Franchise Deal in Dallas 

 Schlotzsky’s Partners with Diabetes Research Foundation 

 MasterCard Dine Out Campaign Stands Up to Cancer 

 Domino&apos;s Brings Ordering App to Amazon&apos;s Kindle Fire 
 
 QSRTV 
 
 Community 
 
 
Search
 Search this site: Copyright©2012 Journalistic Inc. All Rights Reserved. QSR is a registered trademark of Journalistic, Inc. 
Footer Links
 
 Restaurant Management 
 Menu Development Emerging Restaurant Chains Financing for Restaurants 
 Hospitality Technology 
 Restaurant Marketing Food Safety Chain Restaurant Rankings 
 Restaurant Supplies 
 Quick Service and Fast Casual Restaurant Franchises Food Service Conference Advertising
	</body>
</document>
