<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003858" url="http://theehp.com/2012/02/09/food-safety-former-fast-food-restaurant-manager-guilty-of-hygiene-breaches/" time="2012-07-12-20:00" support="1" score="0.0007510227776379389" bingtitle="Food Safety: Former fast food restaurant manager guilty of hygiene ..." webtitle="Food Safety: Former fast food restaurant manager guilty of hygiene breaches">
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>The former owner and manager of a fast food restaurant in Southwark ... Food Safety: Hygiene offences at kebab shop ... your say, register for the site (its free) and leave ...</description>
	<body>
		About theEHP Links Google Search Cookies on theEHP 
 theEHP the Environmental health news&amp;content site 
 Home News Categories 
 General Environmental Protection Food Safety Health&amp;Safety Housing Public Health Regeneration Sustainability This Week at theEHP Podcasts Quick Looks 
 Jobs&amp;Training 
 Generic Environmental Protection Food Safety Health&amp;Safety Housing Licensing Private Sector Training 
 theEHP Store 
 Environmental Health Books Environmental Health Media Wolverhampton Uni Book List British Standards 
 Business Electrical Safety Fire Food Safety Health&amp;Safety Quality&amp;Sampling Risk 
 Charities eco STORE Products 
 Consultants Directory 
 Environmental Protection Food Safety Health&amp;Safety Housing 
 RPT Decisions 
 Demolition Orders EDMOs Emergency Prohibition Emergency Remedial Actions HIMO Licencing Improvement Notices Overcrowding Notices Prohibition Orders Rent Repayment Orders 
 Advertise Contact us 
 
 Food Safety: Former fast food restaurant manager guilty of hygiene breaches 
 theEHP | 9 February, 2012 | 23:30 | Comments (0) Tweet 
 The former owner and manager of a fast food restaurant in Southwark has pleaded guilty to a series of food safety offences after a cockroach was found in a takeaway Chinese meal ordered for a meeting of company directors. 

 
Related Posts

 Food Safety: Cafe owner fined for poor hygiene standards Environmental Protection: Food storage company fined for causing nuisance to neighbours Health&amp;Safety: HSE prosecutions in brief 02 July–06 July Opinion: Why councils should take civil action against rogue private landlords Food Safety: Pub landlord fined for hygiene offences 
 
 

Following a complaint against the Jasmine Garden and Red Planet Pizza takeaway of 33 Bartholomew Street, Southwark Council’s food safety team carried out an investigation–and an infestation of cockroaches was discovered at the premises.

The council’s food safety team also discovered:

 Routine cleaning was not up to standard A significant accumulation of dead and live cockroaches behind the freezer A cockroach nymph in a container of pineapple chunks A cockroach nymph in a container with mushrooms and baby sweet corn 

A range of food ingredients, in uncovered containers in the preparation area, while there was a significant ongoing active cockroach problem.

Food team officers closed the premises using hygiene emergency prohibition procedures in October last year. The premises were closed for four days, while it was cleaned, and cockroaches were treated by a pest control company.

At Tower Bridge Magistrates Court on Thursday (26 January) Mahmoud Elghamry pleaded guilty to six separate offences under food hygiene regulations.

The registered company, Red London Bridge Ltd, also pleaded guilty to the six same offences under the Food Safety Act. In total Mr Elghamry and the company were fined £750 and ordered to pay costs in the region of £4,350.

Councillor Richard Livingstone, cabinet member for community safety at Southwark Council, said:“We can’t stress enough how important food safety is in our borough. Prosecutions like this send out a clear message that we will not tolerate restaurants and food outlets breaking the law and putting the health of the public at risk.

“With the help of the public in coming forward and reporting these kind of breaches, we continue to remain vigilant to this kind of offence. I’m proud to be able to say that Southwark is on track to stay within the top quarter of inner London boroughs for food safety performance.”
.
 
 Tags: leg , Legal 

 Category : Food Safety 
 
 About theEHP : I qualified as an Environmental Health Practitioner (EHP) 1999. Between 1999 and 2003 I worked in Local Authority Private Sector Housing Departments as an Environmental Health Practitioner where I specialised in housing.

I started working as a Housing Consultant in 2001 and left Local Government in 2003.

I have a BSc Hons in Environmental Health and a PG Dip in Housing. I am currently studying a PG Dip in Surveying.

I am a member of the Chartered Institute of Environmental Health and a Student Member of the Royal Institute of Chartered Surveyors. View author profile .
 
If you enjoyed this article, subscribe to receive more just like it.

 Subscribe via RSS Feed 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
 Register for email updates 
 
 Username: 

 Password: 

 Remember me 

 
 
 Register Lost your password? 
 
 Subscribe 

 Facebook Twitter LinkedIn RSS Feed Podcast 
 
 Archives 
 Select Month July 2012 (14) June 2012 (61) May 2012 (52) April 2012 (44) March 2012 (62) February 2012 (49) January 2012 (42) December 2011 (40) November 2011 (58) October 2011 (50) September 2011 (56) August 2011 (53) July 2011 (51) June 2011 (56) May 2011 (71) April 2011 (78) March 2011 (9) February 2011 (10) January 2011 (15) 
 Recommended iPhone Apps 
 
 MileBug - Mileage Log&amp;Expense Tracker - Izatt International Quickoffice® Pro - Quickoffice, Inc. 
 
 School for Landlords 
 
Courses Available:

 How to draft section 21 notices How to increase rent the proper way 
 
 Your Law Store Products 

 Assured Shorthold Tenancies - your complete guide to section 21 How to win Deposit Disputes Tenancy Agreements Audiobook 
 Amazon.co.uk Widgets   

Check out theEHP Store where you will find Environmental Health Books &amp; Environmental Health Media 

 Subscribe to theEHP podcast on iTunes 
 Poll: Is Private Sector Housing a PR Disaster? 
 
What is your opinion on Private Sector Housing&apos;s (PSH) PR. Listen to this podcast and cast your vote.
 Take Our Poll 
 Recently Popular 

 PAS 2060:2010 Specification for the demonstration of carbon neutrality Housing: RPT ruling could cut heating costs BS 8580:2010 Water quality. Risk assessments for Legionella control. Code of practice Housing: Shelter - Rent deposit complaints up 80% Food Safety: Outbreak of Salmonella Newport Sustainability: London 2012 leads the race by adopting new global sustainability standard Public Health: HPA raise awareness on the symptoms of botulism (Updated 25-11-11) RPT Decision: Rent Repayment Order (MAN/OOBY/HMA/2011/0007) Food Safety: 90% of Campylobacter outbreaks at catering venues due to undercooked chicken liver pate BS ISO 26000:2010 Guidance on social responsibility 
 
 Tag Cloud 
 24dash.com Benefits BSI Communities&amp;Local Government Construction Manager DEFRA Department of Energy&amp;Climate Change Empty Properties Environment Agency Environmental Protection UK European Food Safety Authority Featured Food Poisoning Food Standards Agency Guidance Health&amp;Safety Executive Health Protection Agency HIMO HIMO Licensing House Building Housing Minister Housing Standards IOSH Landlord Law Blog Landlords Legal Local Housing Allowance National Landlords Association Noise Opinion Osborne Richardson Photovoltaic Solar Energy Private Tenants Renewable Energy Rents Research RPT Decisions Selective Licensing Shelter Smoking Social Housing Statutory Nuisance Training Courses Video Preview Waste Management 
 theEHP Twitter Feed 
 
 RPT Decision: Improvement Notice Appeal (CAM/33UG/HIN/2012/0003) http://t.co/PYPvZPwd 
 (about 19 hours ago) RPT Decision: Rent Repayment Order (BIR/00CN/HMA/2012/0003, BIR/00CN/HMA/2012/0006&amp;BIR/00CN/HMA/2012/0005) http://t.co/GM7CuFFX 
 (about 19 hours ago) Food Safety: Cafe owner fined for poor hygiene standards http://t.co/jv81rFEl 
 (about 1 day ago) Environmental Protection: Food storage company fined for causing nuisance to neighbours http://t.co/9Y47eaMt 
 (about 1 day ago) Just found another &apos;Bed-in-Shed&apos; in Oxford. Should I be shot for thinking &apos;that&apos;s a cool self-contained flat at the end of the garden&apos;? 
 (about 2 days ago) 
 Follow @the_EHP 
 Easy to Navigate 
 
News is just a Hover&amp;Click Away. Only interested in housing news, select ‘Housing’ from ‘News Categories’ and you will be presented with only housing related news.

The tag cloud (located just below the twitter feed) lists the most common tags on the site. Interested in successful prosecutions, click on the ‘Legal’ tag. The larger the tag, the more articles associated with that tag.
 
 Join theEHP Community 
 
Find an article interesting and want to have your say, register for the site (its free) and leave a comment.

Want to post an environmental health related article of your own, contact us and I’ll post it for you.

Work for a Local Authorities and want to promote a recent success, contact us to add your article to the new LA Success News Category.
 
 About theEHP 
 
theEHP.com, bringing you environmental health news from around the web. The site is updated throughout the day and delivers environmental health news in a easy to use format.

 theEHP trading as 
 
 
 Stay Connected 
 Use the links below to follow theEHP on Facebook&amp;Twitter where you will recieve updates on new posts. Also, connect with the editor on LinkedIn. 
 
 © theEHP 2012. All rights reserved. |
	</body>
</document>
