<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003528" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Milwaukee/Pick-N-Save-Mega-Food-Centers-Whitnall" time="2012-07-12-19:40" support="4" score="0.006121443208923618" bingtitle="Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall - Fast Food Restaurant ..." webtitle="Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall - Fast Food Restaurant  Milwaukee, WI 53235">
			<query id="000465" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="10"/>
	<description>Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 4698 S Whitnall Ave in Milwaukee, WI. Enjoy Fast Food menu in Milwaukee and coupons ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Pick N Save Mega Food
Centers Whitnall

 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(414) 769-8801

 http://www.picknsave.com/ 
 WI &gt; Milwaukee &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall
 Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall is a Fast Food restaurant located at 4698 S Whitnall Ave in Milwaukee, WI 53235. Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall
 
 
 
All Reviews for Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Best Deals and Discounts on the Best Local Restaurants – Save ... Saving money on dining out is easy with Restaurant.com gift certificates. Find restaurants in your area and get $25 restaurant gift certificates for only $10! Start ... Scardina Bakery&amp;Delicatessen - Fast Food Restaurant Milwaukee ... (760) 770-4466 · 72877 Dinah Shore Dr Ste 100 · &quot;Best buffalo wings I&apos;ve ever had Best pastrami I have ever had And great staff very friendly&quot; www.yelp.com/biz/new ... Company Profiles&amp;Company Information on Manta Manta provides free company profiles&amp;company information on U.S. and International companies, including market research reports, business news, and resources. Walmart.com: Save money. Live better. Online shopping for the largest selection of electronics, home furnishings, video games, baby gear and more. Shop online and save money to live better, at Walmart.com. Topic Galleries -- OrlandoSentinel.com Topic galleries provide easy access to stories and photos about people, places, organizations, events and subjects of interest to you. They bring together rich ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 85° 
Fri
 
 73° - 86° 
Sat
 
 73° - 86° 
Sun
 
 70° - 88° 
 
Address
 
Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall

4698 S Whitnall Ave

Milwaukee, WI 
 
53235
 
Telephone
 (414) 769-8801 
Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Capri Pizza Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hardee&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Port China Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Yick Sing Chinese Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Martinos Italian Beef 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Cousins Subs 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Kopps Frozen Custard 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Scardina Bakery&amp;Delicatessen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Checkers Drive-In Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Ann M MoryWydeven Ceramic Std 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Brooks Barrow Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Cultural Alliance 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Fusion 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Gallery H20 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Milwaukee Art Museums Galleries 
See all Milwaukee Bars and Pubs 
See all Milwaukee ATMs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall Coupons 

 Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall Milwaukee 

 Pick N Save Mega Food Centers Whitnall Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Milwaukee Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
