<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003841" url="http://www.yellowpages.com/sacramento-ca/mip/mcdonalds-11058435" time="2012-07-12-19:59" support="3" score="0.003119435897925381" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s Sacramento, CA, 95820 - YP.com" webtitle="McDonald&apos;s Sacramento, CA, 95820 - YP.com">
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000147" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>white meat grilled chicken breast filet so tender and juicy, we can&apos;t keep it a secret. served on a bakery-style bun with leafy green lettuce, a slice of tomato and ...</description>
	<body>
		Join
 
 Thanks! Click the link in the email sent to activate your account.
 
Check your email at Email Inbox to activate your account. No email? Check your spam/junk folder or Resend It» Resend It» 
 X 
 White Pages Mobile Apps Advertise with Us 
 
 Sign In Join Sign in with Facebook 

 Welcome, User 
 » My Profile » My Locations » My Reviews » My Photos » My Searches and Listings » My Deals 
 Sign Out 
   YP.com What are you looking for? near Where? Home&gt; Sacramento Yellow Pages &gt; Fast Food Restaurants in Sacramento, CA &gt;McDonald&apos;s 
 McDonald&apos;s 
 38.525076 -121.410028 1.0 stars 
 3 Ratings 1 Review 
 » 
 Do you love this place? 

Help others by recommending it!
 X Not Now 
 Thanks! 
 Now see what others are saying» 

 
 X 
 » Close 
 Quickly rate your faves! 

Just point at the stars and click. Simple.
 
stars

 1 stars 2 stars 3 stars 4 stars 5 stars 
 
Your Rating
 
 (916) 386-1779 

 8030 Fruitridge Rd, Sacramento , CA 95820 

Near Southeastern Sacramento

 View Menu Visit Website 
 
 Save Email Send to phone Facebook Twitter 
 
Videos&amp;Photos

 Add a Photo 
 


 Be the first to add a photo» 
 
Business Details

 Edit info for this business 
 Hours: Not available Categories: Hamburgers&amp;Hot Dogs, American Restaurants, Take Out Restaurants , Fast Food Restaurants, Chicken Restaurants Payment: AMEX, DISCOVER, MASTER CARD, VISA Services: 
Breakfast, Lunch And Dinner Menu Items
 Neighborhoods: Southeastern Sacramento 
Amenities

Credit/Debit Cards\nArchcards\nDrive-Thru\nMcCafe\nWi-Fi

 ...read more 
 
Extra Phones

 TollFree: (800) 244-6227 

In Business Since 1955
 
Reviews&amp;Recommendations

 Write a Review 
 1.0 stars 
3 Ratings
 
stars
 
Your Rating
 
0 recommendations
 
 
 


 

 See all recommendations» 
 
 
 1 stars 

 bubzi723 11/05/2008

Bad As drive thru n manager

drove into a McDonald drive-thru and place an order:

-hamburger happy meal for a boy with apple juice

-20 piece nugget

-double quarter pounder meal

when ask what kind of drink with the meal, i replied with root beer. (receipt showed pibb xtra)

went home notice now burger and fries, check receipt only showed crew rang up med soda. drove back to McDonald, they close the door on me (a bit before 8pm) and signal me to go drive-thru. i wanted to ask for a manager but of course no one going to care unless i drive into the drive-thru. on drive-thru window i saw the same person that was waving me to go use the drive-thru. explain to her what happen and she just told the drive-thru person to ring me up my missed order and didnt bother to apologize. i dont even know if she the manager since her tag was not worn and of course i wont know her name. told her i didnt want it no more cause i cant stand looking at them while waiting in the cold.

i always go to this McDonald for breakfast, lunch and dinner. once in a blue moon, mistake is common and its ok with me. but this experience was just too much for me to keep to myself. if the rating is start off with a blank box, i would click on that blank box to show how bad this experience is.

knowing how their services is and the food i been getting from them, i dont mind driving 10 more minute away from home to go to the next fast food restaurant (will not mention their name).

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 
 YP Mobile Page for McDonald&apos;s, Sacramento, CA
 » Map&amp;Directions Paid Advertisement 
About

 About YP.com Contact Us Advertise with Us Careers Legal | Terms of Service and Use Privacy Policy Small Business Advertising Advertising Choices 
 
Site Directory

 Home Find a Business Maps&amp;Directions Find a Person White Pages Mobile Apps Reverse Phone Lookup Site Map Mobile YP 
 
City Guides More Cities » 

 Atlanta Austin Baltimore Boston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver 

 Detroit Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Memphis 

 Miami Milwaukee New York Oklahoma City Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Saint Louis 
 
AT&amp;T Family

 AT&amp;T AT&amp;T Wireless AnyWho Ingenio Yellow Pages Keen 
 
 Find Us on Facebook 

©2012 YP Intellectual Property LLC. All rights reserved.
YP, the YP logo and all other YP marks contained herein are trademarks of YP Intellectual Property LLC and/or YP affiliated companies.
AT&amp;T, the AT&amp;T Logo and all AT&amp;T related marks are trademarks of AT&amp;T Inc. or AT&amp;T affiliated companies.
All other marks contained herein are the property of their respective owners.
 Submit
	</body>
</document>
