<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003896" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/30/1446866/restaurant/Tampa-Bay/Five-Guys-Burgers-and-Fries-Largo" time="2012-07-12-20:03" support="2" score="0.00086291701666776" bingtitle="Five Guys Burgers and Fries - Largo | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Five Guys Burgers and Fries - Largo | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000510" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>The place is very open, and clean, aside from ... The fries are served piping hot in a paper tray ... only problem is that its a bit pricy for a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Tampa Bay » Greater Tampa Bay » Largo » Five Guys Burgers and... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Atlanta Charleston Jacksonville Los Angeles Miami New York Orlando More... 
 
Five Guys Burgers and Fries

 View all 14 Five Guys Famous Burgers and Fries locations 
 
(727) 595-4400
 Largo 13680 Walsingham Rd 
 Largo , FL 33774 
 fiveguys.com/home.aspx 
 See all 7 reviews Cuisine Burgers , Fast Food , Hot Dogs/Sausages Feature Kid Friendly Menu $ Under $10 per entree View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late 
   57 people have voted 91 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Golden Bear 87% $ Largo - American, Sandwiches/Subs, Breakfast/Brunch 12540 Starkey Rd 
 
 Olive Garden 79% $$ Largo - Italian, Soups 10500 Ulmerton Rd 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 September 1, 2011 Likes it Great burgers and fries by gulfbreeze ( 37 reviews ) Like every Five Guys I&apos;ve been in, it&apos;s the place to go for moist/thick burger with your choice of about a dozen toppings. Everything is made to order, including the fries, which you can get unsalted/salted/seasoned salt. The standard burger is two patties, so get the small hamburger stacked with your favorite toppings, you&apos;ll still be stuffed. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 26, 2009 Likes it Mixed bag of french fries... by Simon ( 193 reviews ) The place is very open, and clean, aside from the peanut shells that have spilled onto the floor. Yep, they give you all the peanuts you can eat while you wait. They have dogs and burgers, and all the toppings they have are free. The burgers aren&apos;t bad at all, but are pricey considering the fast food concept. In all honesty, I get a distinctive taste of Wendy&apos;s flavor when I eat there. So for the burger, I can get the same taste elsewhere. The fries are served piping hot in a paper tray inside a brown paper bag. The method is to rip the bag open on the table and spread em out so you can hit them with ketchup, salt, vinegar, whatever. Definitely go here for the fries, but the burgers here are just burgers, with a friendly heaping of toppings. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful July 21, 2009 Likes it pretty good by marystpete ( 18 reviews ) Not a bad place, not very crowded unsure how they are doing but the burgers and fires are good. March 16, 2010 Likes it Great burgers! by Rebecca ( 8 reviews ) Five Guys Burgers and Fries is a great restaurant to go to. They have by far the best burgers I have tasted. The only problem is that its a bit pricy for a fast food restaurant but the burgers are definatly worth it. Their fries are not the best though they are pretty good. They have a choice between cajun and regular which is great. While waiting for food you have the option to eat the peanuts they have out. If you have any peanut allergies then this is not the restaurant for you because they do cook in peanut oil. Overall this is a great restaurant. July 27, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Not good for the price by Jaws ( 10 reviews ) Maybe as good as Checkers but 5 times more money. Cost me $16 for 2 plain burgers 1 fry and 2 drinks. For the price I expected a Kaiser roll and a big juicy burger. I could of got the same at checkers or really anywhere else for alot less. It wasn&apos;t bad, it just didn&apos;t match the reviews. Only burgers, fries and dogs on the menu. I would of rather went to Philly&apos;s for a cheesesteak but it was too far away. August 13, 2009 Likes it Mobile review by Christine DiEnna ( 5 reviews ) Overpriced. Decent quality. Simple menu. Why are they still in business? February 24, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Sue ( 4 reviews ) Five guys has great food but is a little overpriced. I you want to get good food and don&apos;t care how much it costs, go here. It is delicious. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos
 Be the first to contribute a photo for this restaurant. View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Pizza Hut $ Largo - Pizza Cafe Roma Largo - Italian New China City $$ Largo - Chinese, Asian, Sushi Beef O Bradys $ Largo Havana Harry&apos;s Market $ Largo - Cuban, Sandwiches/Subs, Barbecue 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 5 guys largo five guys largo 5 guys in largo fl 5guys largo fl five guys burgers and fries 13680 walsingham road largo fl 33774 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
