<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003491" url="http://tribune-democrat.com/local/x1644183811/Capital-murder-case-again-delayed/print" time="2012-07-12-19:38" support="1" score="0.0003043639444679873" bingtitle="Capital murder case again delayed » The Tribune Democrat ..." webtitle="Capital murder case again delayedThe Tribune Democrat, Johnstown, PA">
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>Originally, jury selection for Gerholt was set for Nov ... down as she took a break outside the busy fast-food restaurant. ... process likely will increase the time to seat a ...</description>
	<body>
		The Tribune Democrat, Johnstown, PA
 October 5, 2010 
Capital murder case again delayed

 Kathy Mellott 
 kmellott@tribdem.com 

Bedford—The capital murder trial for a man accused of gunning down his wife in a McDonald’s parking lot has once again been delayed.

John Gerholt, 39, of Mount Union will now go to trial in early December, his court-appointed defense attorney, Thomas Dickey of Altoona, said Tuesday.

Originally, jury selection for Gerholt was set for Nov. 2 with the trial to begin as soon as a panel was seated.

“We’re pretty much ready to go on both sides. The judge wanted to make sure everything is in place,”Dickey said.“This is serious stuff.”

Gerholt is accused in the Nov. 9, 2008, murder of his estranged wife, Karen Gerholt of Hopewell.

Karen Gerholt, 24, was employed at McDonald’s on Route 30 in Snake Spring Township when she was gunned down as she took a break outside the busy fast-food restaurant.

Bedford County District Attorney William Higgins said he has been ready to go to trial for several months.

Higgins announced early in the case that the murder had sufficient aggravating circumstances and he will seek the death penalty if a jury finds Gerholt guilty of first-degree murder.

As a result, a number of experts have been court-approved for use in Gerholt’s defense, information Higgins said he has yet to see.

“We’re waiting for expert reports from him,”Higgins said Tuesday of Dickey.

A field of potential jurors will be summoned to the courthouse on Nov. 30 to fill out questionnaires with the selection process set to begin Dec. 1. Higgins said.

The jury will have to be“death-qualified,”meaning they must be able to impose the death penalty if they feel the prosecution has proven its case, he said.

The death-qualified process likely will increase the time to seat a jury, he said.

Little information was available Tuesday in a second Bedford County murder case scheduled for a status conference in front of Judge Thomas Ling.

Public defender Anthony Zanoni had no comment on the case involving first-degree murder charges faced by Terri Lynn Showalter.

Showalter, 46, of Clearville, is charged in the Dec. 27 stabbing death of her husband, Gary Showalter, 52.

She has been in the Bedford County Jail since Dec. 28, and her case likely will not come up again until later this year.

Stab wounds on the defendant indicated she may have been attempting to defend herself. Alcohol was present at the couple’s home where the stabbing took place, and Higgins said alcohol likely played a role in Gary Showalter’s death.

The defendant’s calls to 911 suggested she may have been intoxicated, authorities said.
	</body>
</document>
