<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003485" url="http://www.innonthepark.net/" time="2012-07-12-19:38" support="4" score="0.004334217579162765" bingtitle="Madison Wisconsin Hotel" webtitle="Madison Wisconsin Hotel">
			<query id="000716" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000705" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>Experience casual family dining, and American-style cuisine at Jerome&apos;s Restaurant for ... The Top of the Park - Madison&apos;s extraordinary skyline banquet space - provides ...</description>
	<body>
		^ Back to Top 
 Mobile Site | E-calendar | E-Map | Photo Gallery | Email Offers | Guest Reviews 
 
 Home About Us Location Accommodations Services things to do Meetings Weddings dining contact us 
 BEST WESTERN PLUS Inn on the Park Madison, WI Reservations BEST WESTERN PLUS Inn On The Park Hotel Reservation news, events&amp;
    Special offers Packages 
 Romantic Getaway Package State Street Shopping Package Farmer&apos;s Market Package 
 Local favorites 
 University of Wisconsin-Madison Art Fair On The Square 
 TOP 5
 Reasons To Stay 
 Madison&apos;s Only Capitol Square Hotel Free WiFi Internet AAA 3 Diamond Award-winning hotel Complimentary valet parking 20,000 sq. ft. of meeting, banquet
, and reception space 
 Madison&apos;s Only 
          Capitol Square Hotel 


Best Western Plus Inn on the Park, Madison, Wisconsin Hotel


 Madison&apos;s Capitol Square Hotel - 
An urban landmark on the Capitol Square in Madison, the hotel is located directly across from the magnificent State Capitol building. The Capitol Square is home to such popular seasonal attractions as the Dane County Farmers&apos; Market, Art Fair on the Square and Concerts on the Square. Only blocks from the University of Wisconsin-Madison campus, Frank Lloyd Wright inspired Monona Terrace Convention Center, Overture Center for Performing Arts, and the Kohl Center, the Inn on the Park is your best way to experience the heart of Madison.  Comfortable lodging and a convenient location await you at our moderately-priced Madison, Wisconsin hotel  
 Downtown Madison Hotel - 
Enjoy an array of modern hotel features while staying in the heart of Madison - complimentary high-speed Internet in guestrooms and throughout the hotel, complimentary newspaper delivery, modern fitness room, and indoor swimming pool. Complimentary valet parking and shuttle service to and from the Dane County Regional Airport and the UW campus add to a relaxing stay! 
 Madison Dining - 
Experience casual family dining, and American-style cuisine at Jerome&apos;s Restaurant for breakfast, lunch, dinner, and dessert. Relax in our full bar where you can enjoy local, hand-crafted brews and mouth-watering appetizers. Feel like going out? Guests enjoy an array of dining options just moments away. 
 Madison Hotel Amenities and Shuttle - 
Relax and unwind in our well-appointed guestrooms and suites, featuring comfortable furnishings and stylish décor. Enjoy contemporary amenities, including complimentary high-speed Internet, voicemail, 42&quot; inch flat screen TVs, coffee maker, iron, ironing board and hair dryer. Many rooms and suites feature views of the magnificent State Capitol building and Madison&apos;s beautiful lakes. 
 Madison Events and Meeting Services - 
Delivering superior meeting and event services for groups of all sizes, the Inn on the Park features 15 well-designed meeting rooms. The elegant Hall of Wisconsin Ballroom can hold events of up to 600 people. The Top of the Park - Madison&apos;s extraordinary skyline banquet space - provides views of the Capitol Building, Lake Mendota and Lake Monona. 
 Madison Things to Do - 
As a vital part of Madison&apos;s vibrant downtown community, the Inn on the Park Hotel is surrounded by exciting downtown events, superb shopping and dining, and Madison attractions that are sure to make your stay unforgettable. BEST WESTERN PLUS Inn On The Park Hotel - Madison, Wisconsin (WI) Located at 22 S Carroll Street , Madison , Wisconsin 53703-3309 Phone: 608-285-8000 Fax: 608-257-5995 
Email: reservations@innonthepark.net 
 http://www.innonthepark.net/ Madison Hotel Specials&amp;Packages  |  Wisconsin Hotel Meetings  |  Madison, Wisconsin Our Neighborhood  |  Madison, Wisconsin Hotel Site Map   |   Bestwestern.com The World&apos;s Largest Hotel Chain®. Each Best Western®branded hotel is independently owned and operated.©2010 - 2012 Best Western International, Inc. All rights reserved. Website design, hosting&amp;hotel internet marketing by Milestone Internet Marketing, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
