<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003210" url="http://www.fitsugar.com/Fast-Food-Breakdown-French-Fries-768546" time="2012-07-12-19:20" support="1" score="0.00318403322089392" bingtitle="Fast Food Breakdown: French Fries - Fitness, Health &amp; Well-Being ..." webtitle="Fast Food Breakdown: French Fries">
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>Check out how a large-size order of fries compares at these ... If these numbers don&apos;t make you steer clear of fast-food french fries, maybe this video about McDonald&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		Don&apos;t Miss Our First Ever POPSUGAR Must Have Bag! Only 798 left . Join now to receive July&apos;s Summer must-have bag! 
 Front Page Entertainment 
 Celebrity Entertainment Sex&amp;Culture Miranda Kerr Keeps Cute Flynn Close and Showcases Two Sweet, Summery Looks 
 Style 
 Fashion Beauty CelebStyle Fashionologie ShopStyle STYL.MX 4 Easy Steps to This Gorgeous Cascading Braid 
 Living 
 Health Home Mom&amp;Kids Food Tech Money Pets Circle of Moms A Burger by Any Other Name: Touring McDonald&apos;s International Menu Options 
 PopSugar TV 
 Celebrity 01:48 Video: Would Channing Star in Fifty Shades? Yes! Latest on PopSugarTV PopSugar Rush I&apos;m a Huge Fan Specials The Buzz Celebrity Interviews Fashion 01:27 Nicole Richie Talks Summer Essentials — and Latest on FabSugarTV Fashion Week FabSugar Lookbook Currently Trending Fab How To Fab Flash Beauty 02:04 Karlie Kloss Reveals Her Supermodel Inspiration Latest on BellaSugarTV Bella Beauty Book Bella Secret Weapon Bella How To Bella Beauty Review Bella Beauty Beat Food 00:52 Make Tuna Tartare at Home With This Recipe From a Latest on YumSugarTV Get the Dish Yum How To Fitness 02:22 Jackie Warner&apos;s Prescription For a Killer Beach Latest on FitSugarTV Get the Bod Class FitSugar Fit How To Healthy Recipes Branded Content Meet Our Editors and Tell Us How You Stand Out! Latest Branded Content Starbucks Levi&apos;s New Balance Frye 
 Must Have 
 
 Shop 
 
 Sign In 
 Healthy happy you. 
 Fitness 
 Cardio Workouts Running Strength Training Yoga Beginner Fitness Tips Fitness Gear Workout Clothes 
 Healthy Living 
 Healthy Recipes Healthy Snacks Vegan Vegetarian Dairy-free Gluten-free Healthy Eating Tips Health News Healthy Recipe Group Sleep 
 Weight Loss 
 Calorie Breakdown Calories Diet Tips 
 Celebrity Fitness 
 Celebrity Trainers Celebrity Weight Loss 
 Fitness Video 
 Latest Popular Get the Bod Class FitSugar Fit How To Healthy Recipes 
 Summer 
 Top Excuses Women Skip the Sunscreen — Do You? 8 Berry Desserts Without the Guilt 7 Fantastic Yoga Festivals For 2012 Make the Most of Summer Days: Wake Up and Work Out Yoga Sequence to Build Your Best Bikini Body 
 More 
 Community Healthy Recipe Group Yoga Stretch and Tell Group Get Fit for 2012 Beginner Fitness Tips Calorie Breakdown Cardio Workouts FitSugarTV Healthy Recipes Healthy Snacks New Year Strength Training Sugar Community Vegan Vegetarian Women&apos;s Health Yoga 
 
 
Fast Food Breakdown: French Fries
 
 Updated Mar 27 2008 - 9:12am · Posted Nov 8 2007 - 11:45am by FitSugar · 51 comments 
 McDonald&apos;s · Burger King · break down · Fast Food · Breakdown · french fries · fried foods 
What is it about french fries that makes us crave them so? Is it the saltiness? The crispy outside and soft, warm inside? Is it that they make ketchup taste so good?

 

Well whatever the reason, people love them and fast-food joints know that. Unfortunately deep-fried foods aren&apos;t exactly healthy for us, which we know, but maybe seeing some actual numbers will help prevent us from ordering the super-size fries at Mickey D&apos;s next time.

Want to see the nutritional info? Then read more

Check out how a large-size order of fries compares at these popular fast-food chains.



 

 Place Calories Trans Fat (g) Sodium (mg) McDonald&apos;s 570 8 330 Burger King 500 6 820 Wendy&apos;s 540 1 550 Arby&apos;s Homestyle 566 1 1,029 Arby&apos;s Curly 631 1 1,476 Hardee&apos;s Regular 610 unknown 370 Hardee&apos;s Crispy Curls 480 unknown 1,190 A&amp;W Regular 430 5.5 640 A&amp;W Chili Cheese 400 4 990 In-N-Out Burger 400 0 245 Jack in the Box Natural Cut 640 10 1180 Jack in the Box Seasoned Curly 550 10 1,200 White Castle 700 11 560 Sonic Regular 280 0 135 Sonic Chili Cheese 450 .5 610 Dairy Queen 730 5 1,530 Carl&apos;s Jr. 620 unknown 380 Popeyes 310 1 660 KFC Potato Wedges 260 0 740 

 

Whoa, hang on a sec. Did I read those numbers from Dairy Queen correctly? 730 calories and 1,530mg of sodium? Yikes. I&apos;ve never tried their french fries but they better be the best-tasting potatoes in the world. White Castle&apos;s fries aren&apos;t too far behind with 700 calories and a whopping 11g of trans fat. The worst thing is that people eat these on the side . If french fries contain this many calories, I don&apos;t even want to think about what the total number of calories would be if you ate them along with a burger.

If these numbers don&apos;t make you steer clear of fast-food french fries, maybe this video about McDonald&apos;s preservatives will seal the deal. It&apos;s disgustingly shocking. It makes you realize that it&apos;s not only the trans fat, calories, and sodium that are unhealthy, but you have no idea what kind of crap and chemicals these fast-food chains are putting into their food, and how it&apos;ll negatively affect your body.

 Source 
 Link Love 
 A foolproof berry cobbler full of nutritional goodness — Eating Bird Food An arm workout to have you looking fab in the season&apos;s cutest tank tops — Shape From avocado to zucchini, healthy recipes for your farmers market bounty — Prevention Outdoor running has never been so cool: nine hairstyles to beat the heat — Health Five hotel-approved exercises for your next vacay — Fab Fit Fun Enough excuses! How to motivate yourself to get up and move — Real Simple Even your circuit workout can be kicked up a notch — here&apos;s how — HuffPost Healthy Living 
 Join The Conversation: Sign Up / Log In powered by Please sign in to comment. 
 Breakdown 
 Breakdown of Eggnog Alternatives Calories in Summery Smoothies See More 
 Burger King 
 8 Healthy Fast Food Options From Bad to Worse: The Unhealthiest Fast Food Items See More Featured Partners 
 

 Adam Levine and Model Behati Prinsloo Step Out Together in New York » Marion Cunningham, Author of Learning to Cook, Dies » Evan Rachel Wood Gets Her Nose Pierced - Watch If You Dare » Noah Lamaide Saves Grandma&apos;s Home from Foreclosure » 
 More News at PEOPLE.com 
 

 How To Lower The Risks Of Diagnostic Imaging » Study Finds Surprising Strategy To Reduce Bone Loss In Post 50 Women » What Do The Obamas Eat? » How To Cope With Hypochondria » 
 More News at HuffingtonPost.com 
 

 Which Food Has More Sodium? » 6 Allergen-Free Snacks for Kids » 4 Balancing Exercises for a More Muscular Middle » How to Be More Creative » 
 More News at Real Simple You might also like Sugar Shout Out: Getaways Inspired by Fifty Shades of Grey Because You Do More Than Bronze: Sporty and Stylish Swimsuits 15 Vegan Lunches You Can Take to Work Yummy Gluten-Free Cereals (That Don&apos;t Taste Gluten-Free!) Take Charge! 5 Things You Can Do to Reduce Cellulite Sponsored Links ShopStyle Headlines Top Brands 
  Balenciaga La Blanca by Rod Beattie Ella Moss Puma Irene Neuwirth Bluefly Room&amp;Board ForwardForward.com Jay Godfrey Alexander McQueen  Temperley London Jimmy Choo 
 Top Searches 
 silver necklace burberry scarf pump striped missoni dress satin dress marc by marc jacobs handbags lip gloss wraps sweat pants gold dress charm bracelet 
 Check out ShopStyle Deals : Kmart coupon codes , ... 
 Fitness 1 Jackie Warner&apos;s Prescription For a Killer Beach Body! summer 2 Top Excuses Women Skip the Sunscreen — Do You? Editor&apos;s Pick 3 Essential Tips For Your First Open-Water Race Vegan 4 20 Vegan Barbecue Sides That Will Have Guests Wanting More Running 5 Learn the Power of the Negative Split For Your Next Marathon! healthy living 6 5 Healthy Chips That Will Satisfy Even the Crispiest Connoisseur FitSugarTV 7 Get R.I.P.P.E.D. in Just 10 Minutes With This Total Body Workout! healthy living 8 7 Healthy Waffles to Jump-Start Your Morning FitSugarTV 9 What 100 Calories Really Looks Like: Nuts summer 10 7 Fantastic Yoga Festivals For 2012 FitSugarTV 11 Learn the Butt-Shaping Moves Gwyneth Paltrow Swears By! Running 12 Hit the Road: 6 Running Apps For Newbies summer 13 Make the Most of Summer Days: Wake Up and Work Out Weight Loss 14 6 Habits For Successful Weight Loss beginner fitness tips 15 5 Ways to Ease Sore Muscles healthy eating tips 16 4 Everyday Food Strategies to Burn More Fat All Day healthy recipes 17 10 Homemade Dressings For Healthier Salads healthy living 18 A Morning Meditation Can Change Your Whole Day healthy recipes 19 11 Bikini-Friendly Sweet Smoothies Fitness 20 Because You Do More Than Bronze: Sporty and Stylish Swimsuits FitSugarTV 21 Work Out Like the Stars: 7 Exclusive Celebrity Trainer Workouts healthy living 22 25 Things You Should Know About Cellulite celebrity fitness 23 Get Blake Lively&apos;s Sexy Legs With This Move The Amazing Spider-Man 24 Watch The Amazing Spider-Man Premiere LIVE on POPSUGAR! 
 Top Stories 
More Sugar 
 
 

 Shore Food Recipes The Best Instagram Grilling Pictures Summer Corn Recipes Controversial Cooking Ingredients 
 
 

 Marburger Farm Antique Show Pictures Design Star With Sabrina Soto Tips London Homes For Rent Eco Homes and Green Architecture Pictures 
 
 

 Revercel Papaya Cleanser Review The Best Hairstyles From São Paulo Fashion Week Zooey Deschanel Yellow Striped Nail Art How to Wear Colored Hair Extensions 
 
 

 Pictures of Wild Animals For Wild About Wildlife Month Kate Middleton and Lupo at UK Polo Match Pictures Dogs Hate Fireworks How to Prepare Pets For Air Travel 
 
Sites We Love 
 
 

 Stretch It Out! » Start Smart this Year » Meet A Walking Scientist » The Walking Fit Diet Meal Plan » 
 
 

 Women in Sports: Congrats to ESPY Winners! » 5 Fun Summer Workouts (Plan Your Next Vacay!) » Fitness Gear to Help You Beat the Summer Heat » 3 Moves to Funny Girl Tina Fey&apos;s Sexy, Sculpted Arms » 
 
 

 How To Lower The Risks Of Diagnostic Imaging » Study Finds Surprising Strategy To Reduce Bone Loss In Post 50 Women » What Do The Obamas Eat? » How To Cope With Hypochondria » 
 
 

 Be the Athlete You Want to Be! » 10 Hottest Stars of Summer: Emma Stone » Killer Kickboxing Workout » Small Bites, Big Weight Loss » 
 ©2012 Sugar Inc. · Insanely Addictive™· PopSugar Home&amp;Family About · Advertising · Site Map · Contact · Terms · Privacy · Mobile Site
	</body>
</document>
