<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003518" url="http://www.parentdish.com/2009/08/05/no-baby-shoes-no-restaurant-service/" time="2012-07-12-19:40" support="24" score="0.037627407744558666" bingtitle="No Baby Shoes, No Restaurant Service - ParentDish" webtitle="No Baby Shoes, No Restaurant Service - ParentDish">
			<query id="000085" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000781" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001338" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000522" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000962" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000459" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000931" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000773" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000148" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000553" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000899" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001496" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000116" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000053" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000242" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000093" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000072" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001056" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001181" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000993" bing-rank="113"/>
	<description>New In Pop Culture; Opinions; Weird But True; Celebs ... school student somewhere did a project in a fast food restaurant ... you have touched nasty money of some kind your cup and ...</description>
	<body>
		Click here to visit the new home of ParentDish! 
Hot on HuffPost Parents:

 Sarah Cawood: What if Breast Isn&apos;t Best? Jenny Isenman: Camp Phone Calls Could End A Marriage 
   
 AOL MAIL 
 ParentDish   
 Main Your Pregnancy 
 
 Baby Names Breast-Feeding Delivery Expert Advice Gear Guides Health Infertility Nutrition Research Reveals Week by Week 
 
 Your Kids 
 
 Babies Activities Child Care Development Expert Advice Health&amp;Safety Feeding Sleeping Gear Guides Research Reveals 
 
 Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers Activities Behavior Day Care&amp;Education Development Expert Advice Gear Guides Health&amp;Safety Nutrition Potty Training Research Reveals 
 
 Big Kids Activities Behavior Development Education Expert Advice Gear Guides Health&amp;Safety Nutrition Research Reveals 
 
 Tweens Activities Behavior Development Education Emotional Growth Expert Advice Gear Guides Health&amp;Safety Nutrition Research Reveals Tween Culture 
 
 Teens Activities Behavior Development Education Emotional Growth Expert Advice Gear Guides Health&amp;Safety Nutrition Research Reveals Teen Culture 
 
 Your Life 
 
 Just for You Beauty&amp;Style Diet&amp;Fitness Expert Advice Going Green Relationships Sex Work Life 
 
 Family Time Activities Birthdays Expert Advice Healthy Families Challenge Holidays Kids&apos; Games Mealtime Places To Go Riddles Summer Fun 
 
 Health Breast-Feeding Development Expert Advice Nutrition Medical Conditions 
 Pregnancy Sleep Special Needs 
 
 Home Base Adoption Amazing Kids Amazing Parents Back to School Empty Nest Divorce&amp;Custody Expert Advice Gay Parenting Relatives Religion&amp;Spirituality Siblings Single Parenting Try This Twins, Triplets, etc. 
 
 News 
 
 Alerts&amp;Recalls Featured Columns Funny Stuff In The News New In Pop Culture Opinions Weird But True 
 
 Celebs 
 Bump Watch Celeb Kids Celeb Parents News&amp;Interviews 
 Gear 
 
 Apps Baby Essentials Books for Kids Books for Parents Daily Dish Pick Decor Fashion 
 
 Gadgets Giveaways Movies Music Toys TV Video Games 
 
 Videos 
 
 Healthy Families Challenge AdviceMama P&apos;Dishes with Deb Funny Stuff Partner Videos 
 
 Your Voice 
 
 Ask Answer Advice Mama 
 
 Talk To Us! 
   
No Baby Shoes, No Restaurant Service
 
by Tom Henderson (Subscribe to Tom Henderson&apos;s posts) 
Aug 5th 2009 5:31PM

 355 Comments 
 
 Filed under: Toddlers Preschoolers , Health&amp;Safety: Babies , Development/Milestones: Babies , In The News , Weird But True , Day Care&amp;Education , Feeding&amp;Sleeping , Baby-sitting , Research Reveals: Babies , Nutrition: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Expert Advice: Babies , Health&amp;Safety: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Development: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Behavior: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Activities: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Gear Guides: Babies , Gear Guides: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Research Reveals: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers , Expert Advice: Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers 
 
 
 No shoes, no shirt, no service. That means you, baby. 

A six-month-old infant was told that she and her little piggies had to stay home. At least, they couldn&apos;t show themselves at Burger King in Sunset Hills, Mo.

The child, her mother and grandmother were told to leave because the manager said the little girl&apos;s bare tootsies posed a &quot;health hazard,&quot; according to a report by Fox News in St. Louis.

Mother Jennifer Frederich said she told the restaurant manager that little Kaylin&apos;s feet are clean, since she&apos;s too young to walk or do anything that could get them dirty. The whole thing was mystifying, she said.

What brought the family to the fast-food joint was an outing of about two dozen members of their church youth group, who were heading to Rock the River, a Christian concert, under St. Louis&apos; Gateway Arch, when they stopped off.

Frederich said she tried to put socks on Kaylin to placate the manager, but he still threatened to call the police. Everyone ate quickly and left, she said.

&quot;I think they [Burger King staffers] need to understand it&apos;s a baby,&quot; she said. &quot;They&apos;re not going to be walking around in their dirty, nasty feet.&quot;

No one at the local Burger King nor the corporate headquarters would comment on the incident. Frederich said that even if wanted to comply she couldn&apos;t since she hasn&apos;t purchased any shoes for her infant daughter yet.

 So, what is the right age to put shoes on a child? 



 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Tags: burger king , no baby shoes at restaurant 
 Share 
Your&lt;span&gt;Voice&lt;/span&gt;
 
Ask Us Anything About Parenting
 Type your question here... Get Answers 
Recently Asked

 This is not a question. But their NO!!!!! such thing of a perfect parent like every thing in all our life is a learning experience.One thing we all pa... Have time for a girlfriend? Say he has a newborn things didnt work out w/the childs mother but he is there for the child 100% does he have time for so... Beating children 
 More Related Questions 
The Talkies: Related Videos 
 
 Choosing the Right Baby Shoes Dr. Jennifer Trachtenberg talks about how important it is to choose the right baby shoes. What You Should Know About Baby Shoes Does it feel like you&apos;re in Vegas when baby needs a new pair of shoes? You roll the dice and hope they fit. And the stakes are high. Watch this episode and tilt the odds of a perfect fit in your favor. Daddy Brad and Daddy Clay host. How to Buy Your Baby&apos;s First Shoes Time for your tot to put her best foot forward. Follow our trusty step-by-step guide to finding the perfect-fitting shoes. Considering Shoes for Children Does it feel like you&apos;re in Vegas when baby needs a new pair of shoes? You roll the dice and hope they fit. And the stakes are high. Watch this episode and tilt the odds of a perfect fit in your favor. 
 
 Reader Comments (Page 1 of 18) 
 Add Your Comments 
 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:22AM 
 Brandi said... 
Your son is 7 months and you make sure he has shoes, I sure hope they are flexible shoes, otherwise you are harming his little feet. My uncle was a podiatrist and was very adament that children do NOT wear hard sole shoes until they are developed otherwise those are the children you see in leg braces and the like because the dumba** parents decided to put crap on their undeveloped feet. And a rusty nail? You say you are a mother? What mother wished that on a child? I feel sorry for your children..


 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:27AM 
 Tracey said... 
Tiana that is a terrible thing to say ...&quot;I hope those kids that come barefooted gets a rusty nail in their foot.&quot; WOW what if that happened to your child? God forbid! Please think before you speak...there is life and death in the tongue!!!


 
 8-07-2009 @ 11:46AM 
 DANNY REY JR said... 
That was the most idiotic thing to say, and you call yourself a parent. I wish no harm on anybody especially children. Unfortunetly we have poverty in this country, and some people can&apos;t afford shoes. To wish harm on children is just wrong and I feel sorry for your kids to have a disgusting person for a so called mother!


 
 8-05-2009 @ 8:45PM 
 Inadequate Wife said... 
Wow. I keep going back and forth on this one. First, I thought Burger King was being a bit ridiculous, after all, it&apos;s just a baby who doesn&apos;t walk.

Then I watched the video where the baby is half standing on the carpet being bounced up and down on her bare feet by an adult, and I can now see Burger King&apos;s point. Even though this is a baby who doesn&apos;t really walk, her bare feet are on the ground no differently than a toddler, teenager, or adult - all of whom are expected to abide by the &quot;no shirt, no shoes, no service&quot; rule.

So at what age should Burger King draw the line? I can understand their perspective of making the policy cover people of all ages.

However, I would think that socks should be more than sufficient as they would most certainly cover the baby&apos;s feet, even better than the flip flops that are otherwise acceptable footwear which clearly expose a lot more skin than a pair of baby socks.

Of course, Burger King doesn&apos;t make people wash their hands first, and everyone is touching the counter, trays, ketchup dispenser, napkin holder, etc... with who knows what grub on their hands. The baby&apos;s feet probably were a lot cleaner than most customers!

Assuming the grandmother didn&apos;t stand the baby on the counter, I don&apos;t see why they felt sending away 20 customers was justified.

 Reply 
 
 8-05-2009 @ 9:44PM 
 Nikki said... 
The reason for no shoes no service in a restaurant isnt because someones feet might be dirty. Your shoes are going to be a lot dirtier than your feet ever will. You wash your feet for goodness sakes. The shoe rule is for the safety of the customer. You dont know what someone could step on and in turn sue the restaurant because they cut their foot on something. If the manager at Burger King were concerned about the real reason for the rule he could have demanded that the child not stand on the floor. I think he might have been having a really bad day and took the rule too seriously and literally. Whats next? At what age does the rule apply? Are we going to demand a newborn wear shoes? I think if the baby is going to be walking around the restaurant they should be wearing shoes. Its that simple.


 
 8-05-2009 @ 10:18PM 
 Heidi said... 
Simple. No one who is paid minimum wage is really paid to think. Rules are rules and these peons aren&apos;t allowed to apply common sense to rules. Sending away 20 customers as a result doesn&apos;t really fit into the equation of following the rules. BTW, I&apos;d rather deal with the &quot;dirt&quot; from baby feet than the e-coli&amp;other bacteria in the ice they put in your soft drinks. Did you know that a high school student somewhere did a project in a fast food restaurant that proved there was more bacteria in the self-service ice dispenser than there was in the toilet? NO ICE PLEASE -- I&apos;LL TAKE THE BABY FEET!!


 
 8-06-2009 @ 10:43AM 
 Gail Lee said... 
The baby was being held and then in a high chair. The baby was not on the ground or the counter. I was there with our church group. There was another toddler who was on the ground walking and those people went and got shoes. There was also a baby who was 4 weeks old in a blanket being held that the management commented on. The news cast did show bouncing but that was in their own home. That wasn&apos;t in the fast food place.


 
 8-06-2009 @ 3:23AM 
 damoki said... 
Inadequate Wife,

I too watched the video, you know what I saw... an infant in its home, not at BK. Besides, It is not a matter of dirt, because if it was, many if not most of the people entering any fast food place would be be required to wash their hands before they touched the counter. I&apos;m not sure what they would do about those germ laden bills used to pay with. Irradiation?

DaMoKi


 
 8-09-2009 @ 8:07AM 
 Dan said... 
Because burger king just plainly sucks. Cold food, poor service, nasty counter personal, all around disgusting.


 
 8-07-2009 @ 8:31AM 
 George said... 
It&apos;s not because the baby posed a health hazard to others but like everything else these days it&apos;s about liability. The manager clearly was not able to articulate that so the manager should be fired or certainly retrained. The fact is that anyone walking around in bare feet could step on something on the floor and be injured. Being the litigious nation we are you know that someone would sue the restaurant even if they were the ones that broke a glass and cut their foot. It&apos;s all about liability...........


 
 8-07-2009 @ 9:01AM 
 Cindy said... 
The baby was bouncing up and down on the carpet in her own home....BK is so stupid


 
 8-07-2009 @ 4:42PM 
 Steve Kamradt said... 
Right---
And another thing to consider---at least in the area I live in----Burger King employess are not required to use barrier protection-----so they are making your sandwiches with their bare hands. Now how sanitary is that? I have personally seen an employess wipe his bare hands on his pants, then start making the next snadwich. And people are eating that sandwich. Now, how many people are licking the floor where the baby&apos;s feet touched?


 
 8-07-2009 @ 12:13PM 
 Jeff said... 
This was just nonsense. At all BK&apos;s, McD&apos;s and other fast food establishments that have a indoor play area there are signs posted that children take off their shoes before playing on the equipment and they even have racks to hold the shoes for the kids. Sounds to me like maybe the manager may have recently been slammed by a audit or an inspection and was taking it out on the group that was there.


 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:16AM 
 jax72782 said... 
My big question is this how many of you are eating your food off any part of the floor let alone haveing it mad off the floor? Did any of you was your hands before entering the store? Be for you have even sat down you have touched nasty money of some kind your cup and at least the tray your food is comeing on. Now are you trying to tell me that your hands are any cleaner that a 6 month olds feet? Just think about it.


 
 8-07-2009 @ 9:36AM 
 Kath said... 
You are obviously as brain dead as the lunkheaded manager of that Burger King. Where does common sense come in to play?


 
 8-07-2009 @ 9:55AM 
 sandie said... 
That is so stupid! They think nothing about serving filthy people. I have been in places where the person in line was so nasty and smelly I could never eat near them. No shoes is for those babies who do not walk. When they are old enough to walk then they ought to wear shoes.


 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:23AM 
 somethings can last forever said... 
I agree with Inadequate Wife the woman was saying she is just a baby and doesn&apos;t even walk yet someone on the video was leading her as if she were walking in bare feet. I change my vote to yes she should have been kicked out. Although who&apos;s to say someone wearing shoes is any safer to have in your restaurant what if someone stepped in dog poo or something how is that any cleaner then a baby with no shoes? I think everyone should just sanitize themselves as soon as they walk in the door to a fast food restaurant or any where else they have food.


 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:22AM 
 Bree said... 
If they are that concerned about it then they should take out the play areas in those restaurants. Simply because the rule in the play area is that you MUST REMOVE your shoes before climbing on tghe play gym. I have a 1 yr old who is constantly taking her shoes off in all restaurants, not just burger king and I have never heard a complaint from anyone, diner or employee. But then I don&apos;t let my child run loose in places of business any how.


 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:17AM 
 frank said... 
The no shirt/no shoe/ no service rules isn&apos;t about health, hygiene or liability. It&apos;s about keeping &quot;dirty hippies&quot; and indigents out of established by &quot;respectable&quot; clientele. If I was in that position, I would have stopped eating, found a complaint with the food, demanded a refund and gone for something to eat right next door, (but that&apos;s just me).


 
 8-07-2009 @ 10:30AM 
 dimalone570 said... 
It is common for 6 month old babies to be toted around without socks or shoes, and unheard of that service be refused for such a reason.....therefore, BK and restaurants who would choose to enforce such a rule should POST it CLEARLY that babies (and at what age) are/aren&apos;t subject to the rule.

I personally think babies should be exempt to the rule, however I wouldn&apos;t be upset if BK (or other restaurants) should dedcide otherwise. But they need to MAKE and publicize a decision. SHAME on BK corporate for not making a comment or taking a stand for or against the issue. I find the fact that they&apos;ve refused to comment OUTRAGEOUS and cowardly!


 1 2 3 4 5 Next 20 Comments Advertisement 
 Follow Us 
 Newsletter Facebook Twitter Flickr RSS 
Sign up for our e-mail newsletter so you’ll always know what’s happening on ParentDish .
 

 
 The Talkies 
 
 Ask AdviceMama 
 How can I get my teenage son to open up? AdviceMama Says: Start by teaching him that it is safe to do so. Read more 
More Recent Questions:

 Can I help my son come to terms with the new baby? What can I do with my 5 kids on the weekend? Can I help my daughter deal with her boys? 
 
 Dish &amp;Dirt 
 
 When Children Die First: A Meditation on the Unthinkable 
 Read More 
 Opinion: Where Do You Draw the Curtain in the Man Cave? 
 Read More 
 The Gay Genealogist: Creating a Modern Family Tree 
 Read More 
 My 14 Year Old is Awful to Her Younger Sister! 
 Read More 
 Speakers OfTheHouse 

 AdviceMama 
 Dish Picks The Family Gaytriarchs First-Parent Singular Free-Range Lenore How Bad? If Mama Ain&apos;t Happy KidPop Naked Data P&apos;Dish on Books P&apos;Dishes With Debbie SmackDowns The Condom Broke The Dish on Deals The Name Babes View From the Homefront 
 Also on AOL 
 Sites WeLove 
 
 A Question for Relationship Expert Dr. Gonzaga Tips For Speaking Up For Yourself, from Anita Hill Silence Is Key, from Ann Shoket 
 
 Rosalind Sedacca: The Two Types Of Post-Divorce... PHOTOS: Katie Holmes, Suri Cruise At The Zoo Yvette Survived Being Set On Fire By Her Husband 
 
 Sienna Miller Gives Birth To First Child (Report) Tom Hardy: Life’s Not Easy As A ‘Skype... Matthew&amp;Camila McConaughey Expecting Third... 
 
 CPSC Warns of Baby Monitor Cord Dangers Quiz of Sex Terms &apos;Pregnant in Heels&apos; Star Rosie Pope on Labor 
 
 Solve Your Daughter-in-Law Dilemma It&apos;s Our First Book! 3 Light Comfort Foods from Ellie Krieger 
 
 10 Tips to Cope With Psoriasis Sleep Better with Fibromyalgia How Cigarettes Cause COPD 
 
 We Paid Cash: A New Bathroom Sign up for the free 10-day budgeting course from... $40 voucher to GlutenFreely.com for just $20 
 
 Woman Keeps Dead Boyfriend&apos;s Corpse for 2 Years... Teacher and Suspected Child Molester Tries to... It&apos;s Official: Joe Paterno and Penn State Did... 
 
 Sports drinks for kids, hold the artificial... Turning baby clothes into a quilt. Or better,... Ice Cream Sundaes - 5 sensational recipes for... 
 
 Get Super Sexy Summer Legs Like Maria Menounos:... ‘Breaking Dawn’ Panel At Comic-Con 2012 —... Rihanna Interview: ‘I Was Really, Really,... 
 
 Pardon My Parenting: Episode 5 Pardon My Parenting: Episode 4 Pardon My Parenting: Episode 3 
 ParentDish Got a story idea? Submit it here! 
 Columns 

 Ask AdviceMama First-Parent Singular If Mama Ain&apos;t Happy P&apos;Dish on Books The Condom Broke The Dish on Deals The Family Gaytriarchs The Name Babes View From The Homefront 
 
 Expert Advice 
 Pregnancy Name Experts Babies Toddlers&amp;Preschoolers
 Big Kids Tweens Teens 
 
 Healthy Families Challenge 
 The Drevitch Family
 The Hatch-Paluck Family
 The Jackson Family
 The Quintana Family
 
 News 
 
 Celeb News And Interviews Funny Stuff
 Opinions The Latest Weird But True 
 
 In the Family 
 AOL Kids Healthy Living Gisele And the Green Team Heidi Klum on AOL KitchenDaily Paw Nation Secret Millionaires Club StyleList 
 
     
 Site Map | Staff | Terms of Service | Privacy Policy | Trademarks | Advertise With Us | About Our Ads | AOL Downloads | Contact Us | 

©Copyright 2012 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Aol Family
	</body>
</document>
