<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003634" url="http://bellaciao.org/en/article.php3?id_article=4175&quot;" time="2012-07-12-19:48" support="1" score="0.0008139959627007613" bingtitle="BELLACIAO - Too many voting &apos;irregularities&apos; to be coincidence ..." webtitle="BELLACIAO - Too many voting &apos;irregularities&apos; to be coincidence -   Ben Frank">
			<query id="000804" bing-rank="193"/>
	<description>The amazing ’coincidence’ that exit polls were ... did nixon and reagan only get 2% in some places? ... Every time we visit a fast food restaurant, we are supporting our ...</description>
	<body>
		Le site Bellaciao: coloré, multiple, ou le meilleur cotoie fort heureusement le pire, mélangé, bizarre, picabien et dadaîste, explorant toutes sortes de registres et de régimes rhétoriques, drole et polémiqueur, surréaliste: rencontre d&apos;un parapluie et d&apos;une machineàcoudre sur une table de dissection, têtes de Lénine sur le clavier d&apos;un piano Steinway ou Bosendorfer... 
 
 Mobile version 
 149308001 IP
169566685 pages
(since 02/10/2002)

 161 connects 
 
   Donation   Newsletters   Last comments 
 Actions 
 Demos-Actions Meeting-Debates Occupations Strikes 
 Art and Culture 
 Art and Culture Books-Literature Cinema-Video Comic strips-Drawings Exposure-Museums Music Theatre-Dance 
 Authors 
 Ben Frank Brian McAfee Chris Floyd Cindy Sheehan Daniel Patrick Welch Daveparts David R. Hoffman Gideon Polya Greg Moses Helen Thomas Jason Leopold Jason Miller Justin Raimondo Leuren Moret Manuel Valenzuela Mary MacElveen Michael Moore Michael P. Wright Mike Schiller Monica Benderman Naomi Klein Peter Fredson Richard Rapaport Robert Fisk Robert Thompson Robin Baneth Robin Cook Sam Hamod Sheila Sample Sidney Blumenthal Stephen Soldz Stewart Nusbaumer Tania Branigan Tariq Ali Ted Glick Ted Rall Thom Hartmann Timothy Bancroft Hinchey Tom Allard Trinity Uri Avnery Vicki Allen Ward Reilly Wayne Besen Wayne Madsen William Fisher William Rivers Pitt Yamin Zakaria 
 Bellaciao 
 A la Une Bellaciao France Bellaciao GB Edito 
 Environment 
 Agriculture - Fishery - Animals Energy Environment GMO Nuclear Twinning Water 
 Health-Social 
 Food Health Healthcare Hospital Humanitary Poverty-Precariousness Retirements - Pensions Social Solidarity 
 International 
 Africa Attack-Terrorism Australia Canada-Qubec Europe France GATS-Bolkestein International Italy Russia South/Latin America Trade-Exchange Rates UK USA Wars and conflicts 
 Knowledge 
 History School-University Sciences 
 Media 
 Digital-Technology Internet Media-Network Newspapers-mags Photo Radio Television 
 Politics 
 Administration Democracy Economy-budget Elections-Elected European Constitution referendum European Left Extreme right FR - Presidential 2007 G7 - G8... Governments Italian 2006 elections Movement Parties Referendum Religions-Beliefs Social Forum Trade unions US election 2008 US election 2012 
 Right 
 Expelled Extraditions Justice Police - Repression Prison Refugees Secret Services 
 Society 
 Catastrophes Conso-Adv Discriminations-Minorit. Logement Public services Sports The &quot;without&quot; - Migrants Transports Un/Employment Women - Feminism 
 
 Senal en Vivo 
 VIDEO 
 RADIO FRIENDS SITES 
with Bellaciao Bellaciao hosted by
 To rebel is right, to disobey is a duty, to act is necessary ! 
  |  Home  |  About us  |  Donation  |  Links  |  Contact  |  Search 
 PUBLISH HERE 
 Too many voting’irregularities’to be coincidence 
by : Ben Frank 
Friday November 5, 2004 - 12:55 &gt; Elections-Elected &gt; USA 153 comments 
Right now there is no hard proof, but the circumstantial evidence is a
mile high. Looking at all of these’irregularities’it’s hard to
imagine how one could conclude that this election was clean.

1. There were complaints in several states about the touchscreen voting machines not working properly.


Roberta Harvey, 57, of Clearwater, Fla., said
she had tried at least a half dozen times to select Kerry-Edwards when
she voted Tuesday at Northwood Presbyterian Church.

After 10 minutes trying to change her selection,
the Pinellas County resident said she called a poll worker and got a
wet-wipe napkin to clean the touch screen as well as a pencil so she
could use its eraser-end instead of her finger. Harvey said it took
about 10 attempts to select Kerry before and a summary screen confirmed
her intended selection.

 
The e-voting spokesman called this a glitch, the
touchscreen needed to be’recalibrated’- of course that’s what the
review screen is for. I wonder how many voters use these brand new
touchscreen voting machines and just assume that when they touch Kerry
that’s what the computer registers. Of course a certain
percentage of voters won’t bother to closely check the review screen,
thus allowing the computer’glitch’to vote for them?

2. Stryguy on the DemocraticUnderground.com found a huge anomaly in Franklin County Ohio. One polling location
registered a Bush victory 4258-260. Wow- impressive Bush support
eh? Funny how the vote (in this precinct) on all the other races was like 350-250.
It seems like 4,000 Bush lovers came to the polls to vote for Bush and
nothing else.

In case the DU thread is down- here is the pdf file of elections results from Franklin County.


Check page 23 Gahanna 1B for the unbelievable Bush victory, page 285
prop 1 is the Gay Marriage Ban- which you’d think at least some of the
4,258 rabid Bush voters would have also supported, but amazingly all 4,000 of them forgot.


3. Ohio Secretary of State Ken Blackwell is this year’s Katherine
Harris. Co-chair of the Bush campaign in Ohio, his blatant
partisanship
had many calling for his resignation. He bought e-voting machines for
Ohio even after Diebold CEO wrote, &quot;I am committed to helping Ohio
deliver its electoral votes to the president next year.&quot; Several
experts testify on the vote suppression in Ohio here .

 &quot;A poll worker told me this morning that there were no tapes of the results posted on some machines;
on other machines the posted count was zero&quot; 
4. The amazing’coincidence’that exit polls were accurate in non-swing states, but were way off in key states like Ohio and Florida . I can understand that exit polls may be flawed, but how odd that
they’re only flawed in swing states that Bush needed to win... and of
course the final results are always skewed towards Bush.. which is
exactly what would happen if Bush were losing, then a repub vote thief dialed in to the central tabulators and activated a script that would fix the count. How easy it is to
steal an election with modern technology.... no need to haul ballot
boxes to the lake- all you need is the secret phone number and the
election could be fixed from a home computer. (Election officials’unknowingly’gave out the secret phone # in a stack of requested
papers)

5. Earl at the DU forum took some http://www.democraticunderground.com/discuss/duboard.php... screen shots of CNN’s exit polls and caught them altering their exit polls to match
the reported vote. Funny how this’mistake’by CNN fits in so nicely
with #4.
 
Graphs split off of this single (too large for bellaciao) image 

Isn’t it strange that all of these’anomalies’in the exit polls and
touchscreen machines always seem to favor Bush? There were many
similar reports after the 2002 congressional elections, when the
Republicans took control of Congress (which the evil cabal needed to
prevent a real 911 investigation and to start the war free of
consequences).

So if you were a detective and this was the circumstantial evidence...
would you conclude that absolutely, positively beyond doubt there was
no fraud in this election? Of course not, there’s definitely some funny
business going on here.... so why did Mr.’Help is on the way’Kerry
give up so quickly?

 Greg Palast notes that Kerry was down by 136,000 votes with 247,000 ballots still
uncounted. Consider that most of these provisional ballots and
undervotes are from minority precincts where Republicans sent their’vote challengers’. Supposedly they were trying to prevent
unregistered voters from voting, but they actually just caused huge
delays in poor neighborhoods. People were waiting in line for 5-6
hours, in pouring rain just to vote... I wonder how many left after two
or three hours.

I recall Kerry frequently saying that this was the most important
election of our lifetime. What happened to make him change his
mind and just give up like that? We _know_ Bush is a liar, and now we’re supposed to just trust Diebold and the Republican henchman Blackwell were honest? No, they
haven’t earned any trust.

Why didn’t Kerry put up a fight? That in my mind is the most damning
evidence proving this was staged election. Why wasn’t Kerry
concerned about the Diebold CEO’committed to delivering’votes to
Bush? Why wasn’t he demanding a fair and transparent election
process all year long? Why wasn’t he concerned with the private corporations controlling our voting process ? Millions of regular Americans knew of the potential for fraud, computer
security experts have testified that this system is so open to fraud
it’s insane that anyone would even suggest it’s secure, but Kerry and
the Democrats never considered demanding a paper trail? What are they,
stupid? Or corrupt?

Wouldn’t it be nice to get beyond this circumstantial evidence and into
some hard proof that this election was rigged? That what Bev
Harris is doing at blackboxvoting.org 
  she’s filed Freedom of Information Act requests for vote records in
over 3,000 counties with more to follow. If you care about our
Democracy, the future of our children, and that of children in Iraq and
other countries about to be invaded, please go to blackboxvoting.org and get informed, do what you can to pass this info on. We cannot
accept another stolen election- either we rise up now or America as we
knew it is dead- replaced by 21st century fascism and the most idiotic
puppet dictator the world has ever seen. Is that what you want to leave
to your children?

Nov 4, 2004 Dubya: &quot;I’ve earned some political capital... and I intend to use it.&quot;
Lord help us
 


 Leave a comment 
 
 Print this article 


 
 Commentaires de l&apos;article
	</body>
</document>
