<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003412" url="http://www.chron.com/life/article/Heloise-Flying-food-might-get-checked-2116011.php" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="1" score="0.000763254214710921" bingtitle="Heloise: Flying food might get checked - Houston Chronicle" webtitle="Heloise: Flying food might get checked - Houston Chronicle">
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>Turn the cup upside down and cut two small x&apos;s (1/2-inch long - think of a lid from a fast-food restaurant) with a ... to the Houston Chronicle and receive access ...</description>
	<body>
		( skip this header )
 
 Register Sign In 


 
 Classifieds | Houston Weather | Houston Traffic | Mobile | E-edition 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012
 
 chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs La Voz 

 Jobs Homes Autos Shopping 

 Index▼ 
 Close [X] Quick links to other pages on this site | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Houston&apos;s best Tex-Mex is ... $31 million car wreck Tropical weather Cornyn vs. Holder Photo &apos;mistake&apos; that worked Starbucks at funeral home 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Hurricanes Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths 
 
 Texans Astros Rockets Dynamo Colleges UH Rice A&amp;M; UT High school Golf Outdoors MMA, Hockey&amp;more Tickets 
 
 FuelFix Chron 100 Markets Houston stocks World markets Currency Top workplaces Small biz Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater Celebrity Buzz Comics&amp;Games 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Delish Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Hill Country travel Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker Ski Colorado 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 Home price survey New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 
 «Back to Article 
 


Heloise: Flying food might get checked

 

Published 04:45 p.m., Thursday, August 18, 2011
 Tweet 
 Comments ( 0 ) Larger | Smaller Printable Version 

 Email This 
 Georgia (default) 

 Verdana 

 Times New Roman 

 Arial 
 Font 
 Page 1 of 1 
Dear Readers:

Traveling on an airplane with food or gifts can be a challenge for travelers and security screeners! The general rule, according to the Transportation Security Administration , or TSA ( www.TSA.gov), is that liquids, aerosol cans and gel items over 3.4 ounces should be put in your checked bag.

Carrying gifts on the plane? Don&apos;t wrap them! They may have to be unwrapped to really be checked. You don&apos;t want TSA workers to unwrap the gift!

When in doubt, you can check with the airline or TSA.

 - HELOISE
 
P.S.: I carry an empty water bottle in my bag and fill it once I&apos;m through security.
 
Dear Heloise:

While traveling throughout Texas this summer, I thought of this handy way to make a toothbrush holder at a hotel that only had paper cups. Turn the cup upside down and cut two small x&apos;s (1/2-inch long - think of a lid from a fast-food restaurant) with a pocketknife on the bottom about 1 inch apart. You can then insert your toothbrush.

 SHERRI S. , Ozark, Ark. 
 
 Heloise@Heloise.com 

HELOISE

P.O. Box 795000

San Antonio, TX 78279-5000

KING FEATURES SYNDICATE
 Printable Version Email This Tweet Subscribe to the Houston Chronicle and receive access to the Chronicle for iPad App Heloise: Flying food might get checked Traveling on an airplane with food or gifts can be a challenge for travelers and security screeners!

The general rule, according to the Transportation Security Administration, or TSA (www.TSA.gov), is that liquids, aerosol cans and gel items over 3.4 ounces should be put in your checked bag.... 
 More Houston Life 
 
 
 Comics&amp;Games 
 
 Delish (Recipes) 
 
 Flavor 
 
 Houston Grows 
 
 Gloss 
 
 Health News 
 
 Horoscopes 
 
 Weddings&amp;Celebrations 
 
 
Life blogs
 
 
 BabySteps 
 


 Botched song lyrics and other philosophies 

08:02 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Believe It or Not 
 


 Episcopal Church passes same-sex blessings,... 

07:33 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Bookish 
 


 Great fiction. Defined. 

7/11/12 at 10:49 a.m. | Comments 

 
 Design Houston 
 


 Ligne Roset showroom opens at West Ave 

7/11/12 at 10:35 a.m. | Comments 

 
 Leon Hale 
 


 What do you think of this? 

11:15 a.m. | Comments 

 
 MeMo 
 


 In which the kitten story has an end. And a... 

7/11/12 at 01:39 p.m. | Comments 

 
 The Middle Lane 
 


 Joe Biden takes a stroll down the Middle Lane 

10:45 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Mom Houston 
 


 Taking parenting too seriously can be bad for... 

7/9/12 at 03:49 p.m. | Comments 

 
 Shop Girl 
 


 Mullet style: Would you wear a dress inspired... 

7/9/12 at 07:14 a.m. | Comments 

 
 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation Business Sports Entertainment Life Blogs Weather Traffic 
 
Topics

 29-95 Small Business PetsHouston MomHouston HoustonBelief Gardening Work&amp;Career Advice Recipes from Delish 
 
Neighborhoods

 Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad Contests 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery Mobile RSS Feeds Chronicle in Education e-Edition Breaking News Alerts La Voz (Spanish) 
 
Services

 Contact us Business directory Legal notices Send us tips About the company Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad Ad Choices 
 
 A quadrantONE partner 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
	</body>
</document>
