<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003480" url="http://elizabites.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:37" support="3" score="0.011790692833712283" bingtitle="ELIZABITES | A fascination with Chicago food, restaurants, signs ..." webtitle="ELIZABITES | A fascination with Chicago food, restaurants, signs and more">
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>... handwriting I’d see on old, yellowed ledgers, and the style of the restaurant name ... 12 plates,12 wine glasses, 24 forks, 12 knives, 12 napkins, 4 votives. Urban Union ...</description>
	<body>
		ELIZABITES 
 Skip to content 
 Home About Contact 
 ← Older posts June 21, 2012 
 Antique Taco 
 
 
Mason jars, cloth napkins, vintage drums, even the font of the menu on the wall and other rustic touches set the scene
 
Even after 6 days on a serious taco binge in Mexico over Memorial Day weekend, I was dying to get to Antique Taco in Wicker Park. I had heard good things, but was honestly expecting a Big Star off-shoot, but discovered a gem of a taco cafe that was more quaint, rustic and seasonal than taqueria roadhouse. Don’t get me wrong, I loooove me some Big Star when I’m in the mood for some cerveza with my pork belly and summer crowds. But Antique Taco offered a different, and equally as delicious experience. Let start with the tacos. One look at the menu and my eyes darted to“garlicky kale,”“pickled escabeche”and“cilantro cream”in the market mushroom, so I knew I had to have it. These ingredients along with local mushrooms were stuffed inside a fresh, soft tortilla, each bite delivering all of my favorite flavors and bursts of lush green and pink. A fresh lemon wedge for the squeezing just added to the beauty of these generously sized dish.
 
Market mushroom taco
 
Garlic-soaked or not, I could eat kale everyday, but I need something crispy to balance it out. Our other taco was the crispy fish with smoked cabbage, scallions and sriracha tarter sauce. Light tempura battered whitefish was the perfect canvas for the smoky cabbage and spicy tartar sauce, again all wrapped up in a fresh flour tortilla.
 
Crispy fish taco
 
Coming off my Mexico trip, I had to do the tacos, but you won’t miss the tortillas if you get the taco salad served in a cardboard blueberry carton. With a crunchy and colorful array of kale, spicy peanuts, queso fresco, cranberries, corn chips, sesame, pomegranate vinaigrette, it’s almost too pretty to eat.
 
Antique taco salad
 
Pork carnitas, a toasted tortilla soup, chili cheese curds and habanero popcorn on the menu mean multiple visits are in order to basically try, well everything, and I didn’t even get to the horchata milkshake or are you kidding me Mexican chocolate and marshmallow pop tart, but the perfect summer quencher (and something we sipped all over Mexico) are the agua frescas made with seasonal pureed fruit, simple syrup and lemon juice…available with or without vodka. OK, I’ll stop, just go.
 Antique Taco , 1360 N. Milwaukee Ave.
 
Watermelon agua fresca
 
 
 Leave a Comment 

Filed under great for date , I like to eats , new restaurants , quick lunch 


 May 21, 2012 
 Vosges bar love 
 
I have always majorly hearted Vosges chocolate , and love when I happen upon the purple and white haven of confectionary genius in various airports and cities around the country. As if the chocolate wasn’t good enough, they go ahead and add things like bacon, chipotle chilies and organic pumpkin seeds to their bars, truffles and hot chocolate mixes that are almost too pretty to eat. But my favorite combo thus far was recently spotted at Goddess and Grocer; Rogue Ale and Chocolate Stout Beer with alderwood smoked salt, burnt sugar caramel and dark chocolate. Holy Ch-rist, it might be all of my favorite flavors wrapped up in dark chocolate bar..a campfire s’mores on steroids. The neighboring blood orange caramel didn’t look too shabby either..but nothing is more intoxicating that smokey-chocolately-salty dark chocolate. I was rushing out when I spotted it and didn’t have a chance to pick one up, but like a perfectly fitting dress or pair of shoes that haunts me after one look, I keep thinking about it and know I must have it. Watch for a full review…
 
Easily inhalable
 
 
 1 Comment 

Filed under Foodie gift alert , random spottings 


 May 10, 2012 
 Beijing Duck at Sun Wah BBQ 
 
After a short hiatus, I’m back at the blog and bringing you juicy, glistening perfectly roasted duck from Sun Wah. You’re welcome. Sure this delicacy has been written about a million times, but I FINALLY got to the famous Uptown Chinese restaurant just a few weeks ago with two of my favorite fellow diners. Each of our excursions get bloatier than the next, and this one was Bloat 5.0. I usually head to Chinatown for Chinese food or make the occasional run to Friendship in Logan Square, but I knew this experience would top them all. I have a serious weakness for duck on any menu, and especially the glistening Peking ducks hanging in the window of Chinatown restaurants, so I knew we had to get our pre-order on and make sure a full duck with accompanying pickled daikon radish, hoisin sauce and steamed bao were ready for us when we arrived. It didn’t take long for our master carver to begin cutting up the carcass tableside and set up the appropriate accoutrements. The result was juicy, flavorful duck with a perfectly crisped skin I could’ve noshed on all night, sweet hoisin and crunchy, cool radish and pickled daikon all stuffed into steamed bao that were quite reminiscent of the Momofuku Noodle Bar buns I know and love. Sun Wah, 5039 N. Broadway
 
The duck arrives
 
 
The carving begins
 
 
Before the bao
 
 
Just add hoisin, pickled daikon and garnishes
 
 
 1 Comment 

Filed under great for date , I like to eats 


 April 20, 2012 
 On the table: Nacional 27 
 
 Menu, cigar box tops. Nacional 27, 325 W. Huron.
 
 Leave a Comment 

Filed under great for date , on the table 


 April 4, 2012 
 Schiller’s Liquor Bar menu, NYC 
 
Some chilly temps and torrential downpours didn’t stop me from savoring every minute in NYC this weekend. It was a rare moment when I was there for pure bachelorette party fun rather than work. I finally got to see Apotheke (and sipped an edamame-purée concoction), was captivated by War Horse on Broadway and the Cindy Sherman exhibit at the MOMA. We ate, of course, and I’ll be posting about our bites all week. One brunch in particular stood out, but not so much because of the food. Perhaps my Norwegian Hollandaise at Schiller’s Liquor Bar was just a miss, but I loved everything else about this place, from the room to the Stumptown coffee, and especially the menu. The font reminded me of my grandfather’s handwriting I’d see on old, yellowed ledgers, and the style of the restaurant name was straight up Milwaukee circa 1950 beer bar/bowling alley…and they have an escarole and artichoke salad on the damn brunch menu! I mean….
 
I was happy with my Stumptown, and didn’t indulge in wine, but I loved the layout of the wine list…Cheap…Decent…or Good, by the glass, carafe or half carafe…simple and to the point. Schiller’s Liquor Bar, 131 Rivington, East Village, NYC
 
 
 Leave a Comment 

Filed under eliz-a-trip , random foto , random spottings 


 March 23, 2012 
 A guest blogger gets all sappy… 
 
Actually, my friend, fellow foodie, Restaurant Intelligence Agency creative mastermind, dedicated dining partner and all around nifty young fellow Matt Kirouac didn’t actually get sappy for his guest blog post at all, but he did report on a sticky situation— his very fun and very important job as judge at the National Maple Syrup festival in Indiana a couple weeks ago. From the twisting paths of tapped maple trees to maple Italian cream cake and maple tea..it was a true maplepalooza.
 
Tapping into the sugar trails
 
Memorable Moments From My Weekend at the National Maple Syrup Festival

I recently attended the National Maple Syrup Festival in Medora, Indiana, where I was asked to be a judge at the King Arthur Sweet Victory Challenge. Criticizing maple dishes is what I do best, after all.

Chatting with Tim Burton, head honcho at Burton’s Maplewood Farm, was the highlight of the weekend. He exudes energy and generosity, not to mention his killer maple tea, made with maple sap. The tea bar has been raised.

The Sweet Victory Challenge (aka the American Idol of maple syrup, per me) was fun, if a bit disappointing that two entrants’recipes failed before we could taste. My favorite was the five-spice pudding with maple glaze. It didn’t win.

The winner was a maple Italian cream cake. Not so good was the maple “upside-down” cake, which was not upside-down in any way. And it was inexplicably flavored with Greek yogurt. No.

Exploring the“sugar trails”in the woods on the farm was incredible. Sounds like real-life Candyland, but actually they were just paths winding around tapped maple trees. Along the way, folks clad in colonial garb demonstrated antiquated maple-ing. We tasted maple sugar made the old-fashioned way and it was sublime.
— Matt Kirouac
 
An example of said antiquated maple-ing
 
Maple Italian cream cake...holy yum
 
 Leave a Comment 

Filed under guest blogger 


 March 20, 2012 
 On the table: Balena 
 
 4 plates, 4 napkins, 4 forks, 4 knives,4 water glasses, one votive. Balena, 1633 N. Halsted.
 
 Leave a Comment 

Filed under great for date , new restaurants , on the table , Take the &apos;rents 


 ← Older posts 
 
Eliz-a-bite of the week
 Asparagus, lemon curd and pecan tartine, Floriole Bakery, Chicago 
Blogroll

 Broccoli and Prosecco ckramer316 d. graham kostic [lives] Fig Catering Lawyer 4 Musicians Liz Grossman ManUpChicago Passport Delicious Same Conversation Toki Collection Unnecessary Quotation marks 
 
Categories
 Select Category ..and more 5 reasons why I love… Best bite boozeworthy cheap, tasty brunch chef’s tales eliz-a-trip fail-safe sushi family foods Foodie gift alert great for date guest blogger hot dog hunt I like to eats It’s on a truck mystery spot new restaurants not known for on the table quick lunch random foto random spottings recipes red velvet cupcake report Take the‘rents the MKE report thick Uncategorized video Q&amp;A 
 Tasty tweets 

 Hey @ nephotography and @ mayahenderson , awesome new class alert...Deep Extreme @ Equinox ! 3 weeks ago 
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 
Recent Comments

 zoe on Vosges bar love Peter - The Roaming… on Beijing Duck at Sun Wah B… Beijing Duck at Sun… on More Momofuku 
 
Blog Stats

 85,560 hits 
 
   Subscribe in a reader 
 Search for: ©Elizabites 2008-2012. All rights reserved. 
 ELIZABITES Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Pilcrow . ELIZABITES ·A fascination with Chicago food, restaurants, signs and more Blog at WordPress.com .·Theme: Pilcrow by Automattic . Follow 
 Follow“ELIZABITES” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel
	</body>
</document>
