<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003991" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/newbreak-coffee-and-cafe-san-diego-3" time="2012-07-12-20:12" support="8" score="0.036968748099654475" bingtitle="Newbreak Coffee &amp; Cafe - Point Loma - San Diego, CA" webtitle="Newbreak Coffee&amp;Cafe - Point Loma - San Diego, CA">
			<query id="000821" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000833" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000815" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000820" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000838" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000837" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000842" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000824" bing-rank="25"/>
	<description>The breakfast menu board looked like it was the main one! ... Service is great, they seem to remember my order from ... So this place is no where near 5 stars. It&apos;s really a 3 ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Newbreak Coffee&amp;Cafe
 108 reviews Rating Details 
 Categories: Food Coffee&amp;Tea Restaurants Breakfast&amp;Brunch Coffee&amp;Tea , Breakfast&amp;Brunch   [Edit] 
 1959 Abbott St 
(between Santa Monica Ave&amp;Newport Ave)
 San Diego , CA 92107 
Neighborhoods: Point Loma, Ocean Beach
 (619) 226-4471 http://www.newbreakcafe.com/ 
 
 Add Photos Hours: 
Mon-Fri 6 am - 6 pm

Sat-Sun 6:30 am - 6 pm
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Street
 Attire: Casual
 Price Range: $ 
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: Free
 Good For: Breakfast
 Alcohol: No
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Hipster, Casual
 Has TV: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 First to Review Kinsee M. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review Yelp Ad Babycakes 945 reviews 
 Matthew B. said: &quot;RED VELVET!  Nom Nom.  Sunday Church, Fun times.&quot;   read more» 
 
 Reviews (108) About This Business 

 
 
108 reviews for Newbreak Coffee&amp;Cafe
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;Also free Wi Fi so if you have some work to do it is great.&quot; In 6 reviews &quot;Rare flavored cream cheese spreads (honey nut raisin mmhmm...&quot; In 8 reviews &quot;Super laid back and casual-just like OB.&quot; In 5 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
108 reviews in English

 
Review from Brian F. 
 
 16 friends 13 reviews 

 Brian F. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/1/2012 
ah newbreak.. I love this place.. Many a hungover morning was spent here, as well as hours upon hours of studying.  I am one of those types that likes/needs to separate environments of work and fun.  I can go here, and sip on coffee or one of their delicious teas, while I people watch or simply encourage ocean views, all while being damn productive.  Need a quick study break, go roam across the street to the beach and soak in the sun.

The food is also quite good here.  My goto&apos;s are the sunrise sandwich, and their breakfast burrito, which is freaking great!  Finding a table to get work done, never seems to be an issue, and the barista&apos;s are always accommodating and friendly.

My only gripe about this place, is that it closes at 6pm.  Would love if they were open to midnight, as this would be certainly be my spot to frequent after hours..
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Helen D. 
 
 23 friends 109 reviews 

 Helen D. 
 
Brooklyn, NY
 3/7/2012 
Food was very fresh.

What I didn&apos;t like was that we had to stand in line to order our food, it was slow moving. But I guess meanwhile, the other person can secure a table (they have some tables by the sidewalk and a big dining area) and it gives you time to look at their menu up and down, up and down...

I got a half-faced lox bagel, which was made beautifully. The lox was perfectly portioned and the onions, tomatoes, cream cheese....it was so fresh. My bf got the veggie omelet which was as good as an omelet can be. Whatever. And a green iced tea. Thumbs up for the view outside, though occasionally obstructed by cars parallel parking...

&quot;There goes our view,&quot; I kept saying.

Great place, good quality food, simple, good prices. Our brunch cost us around 17 bucks. Good stuff.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ann H. 
 
 55 friends 33 reviews 

 Ann H. 
 
San Diego, CA
 1/21/2012 5 Check-ins Here 
This is a great coffe shop.  Really &quot;authentic&quot; coffe-shop feel.
Great coffee and great food.
There is a huge wall of TEA.  I don&apos;t drink that much tea, but it seems very impressive.  GIving advice on which tea soothes ailments and such.
Awesome location!
 
 Listed in: On the Beach 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from patty p. 
 
 11 friends 76 reviews 

 patty p. 
 
Lemon Grove, CA
 6/24/2012 
went for breakfast this morning, after a nice long walk by the beach.  We were looking for a place with healthy options.  I once walked by this place and peeked in on what people were eating, it looked like a great place to eat.  I&apos;m giving it three stars because I wasn&apos;t amazed by the food they make.  I ordered the sunrise breakfast sandwich and expected something more appealing to the eye, maybe more veggies in it.  I could have made a better sandwich at home.  Okay, I admit the price was good for a place like this, specially a place right across from the beach, and with beautiful views of the beach.  The sunrise sandwich was maybe around 5 - 6 dollars.  not a bad deal, but I rather pay a bit more and get an amazingly delicious morning sandwich.  a little more effort on their sandwiches would be a huge improvement :)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Bree F. 
 
 6 friends 97 reviews 

 Bree F. 
 
San Diego, CA
 6/23/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Great coffee and I love their dog friendly patio. They always have a nice lil selection of breakfast pastries and they also make sandwiches in house. The only bad thing is they really need to update their website as it is done in flash that is not mobile friendly :( I wanted to look up their menu but was unable to.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alyssa D. 
 
 3 friends 46 reviews 

 Alyssa D. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/10/2012 
Hit and miss... I&apos;m not a fan of the lunch items and some of the employees are rude.  I still love studying here because their Vietnamese coffee is really good and I like their pistachio baklava. Their internet doesn&apos;t have a time limit like some coffee shops and it&apos;s nice to feel the ocean breeze while you&apos;re stuck inside doing homework or a paper.

Summary: Don&apos;t come here for lunch and expect hit and miss service, but coffee drinks are really yummy and it&apos;s a good place to study.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Grace G. 
 
 0 friends 4 reviews 

 Grace G. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/6/2012 
Really great atmosphere and food. But they NEVER get my order right. My boyfriend has food allergies so we can&apos;t just eat around it. While we were there one morning, we saw this happen to 2 other guest. One time we sent it back and they brought us something we didn&apos;t even order! It was tasty, but not the meal you are looking forward to. I still love going. Its a great place to study and their tea selection is huge, just make sure you reiterate what you would like to eat :)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Hannah P. 
 
 16 friends 59 reviews 

 Hannah P. 
 
San Diego, CA
 4/16/2012 
I love this little coffee joint. Great quality coffee, the smoothies are delicious, and the muffins are really yummy. It&apos;s very warm and inviting inside, which is nice.. If you like tea, youll love this place because there&apos;s a huge wall filled with different loose tea jar. The location can&apos;t be beat, either.. It&apos;s pretty much oceanfront.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from William B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 99 friends 747 reviews 

 William B. 
 
San Diego, CA
 3/18/2012 
Living in California years ago, right after I studied for and passed the bar examination, I craved a place to hang out kind of like this-- cozy, spacious, good internet and tolerant of studiers, looking out on the ocean.  Newbreak has all of that with simple, tasty, California-style sandwiches, plausible cappucino, good hours, and a very cheerful and friendly staff.  I don&apos;t even live in O.B. and I&apos;m willing to drive six miles to spend the afternoon working here.  If I lived in O.B., I&apos;d probably be here multiple times a week.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Cynthia C. 
 
 12 friends 5 reviews 

 Cynthia C. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 3/1/2012 
The best Chai ever. The have super tasty sandwiches which are also healthy. It has some great people watching and I love how close it is to the beach. I can&apos;t wait to go back.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Melissa V. 
 
 15 friends 4 reviews 

 Melissa V. 
 
La Mesa, San Diego, CA
 4/8/2012 
Love this little coffee shop in OB.  I go out of my way to stop in and get my coffee here.  I love how they offer coffee in a big mug.. It makes it more homelike.  Also the workers are super friendly and always willing to tell me some must see places in Cali.  They also have an outdoor seating area which is great for meeting people or just the standard people watching, coffee break, to spend the afternoon.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Angela M. 
 
 5 friends 12 reviews 

 Angela M. 
 
San Diego, CA
 2/22/2012 
My favorite coffee shop in OB.  Great coffee, good food&amp;service. A great place to study or get some work done. Free Wifi is really fast.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Wes Y. 
 
 0 friends 7 reviews 

 Wes Y. 
 
San Diego, CA
 10/18/2011 
I get coffee here all the time. They are super nice and have good food.
The Super Bowl is my fave!
 
 Listed in: Top Restaurants 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nick T. 
 
 497 friends 1453 reviews 

 Nick T. 
 
San Diego, CA
 2/7/2011 1 Check-in Here 
I had a http://restaurant.com coupon for Daybreak Cafe, not Newbreak Cafe ! Obviously I felt like an idiot when I was about to pay at the counter and the cashier just gave me a funny look when I handed her the coupon.haha oh well.

She asked if we still wanted to eat here, considering we already spent a few minutes checking out the menu and having already placed our order. It had not been sent to the kitchen yet though.

I didnt want to appear cheap so we said eff it, lets just stay. The cashier said that it happens all of the time. People getting the two cafes mixed up. So we picked a table and chatted for a bit. It only took less than 10 minutes for our food to arrive.

My Vietnamese coffee was sweet but wasnt very strong. My California omelette was alright but the hash browns and toast werent very good and there was no butter or jam provided.

Its in a great location and Ive walked by this place maybe a couple hundreds of times but never made it in here. I&apos;d come back though. Its in OB and this is my beach community of choice.

By the way, theres a dude that works here that looks just like my friend Mason ( former yelper ), except he looked a bit younger and wasnt tatted up. It was like how Mason was a few years ago. Comedy. I should have sneaked in a photo.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jen S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 88 friends 557 reviews 

 Jen S. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/15/2011 
What a letdown. I stopped for a latte. Their &quot;large&quot; is the size of a medium and in some cases a small when compared to Lestats or Filter. Also, the latte was about the same price as one at Starbucks, and it tasted burned.

The indoor seating is uncomfortable and the layout is busy and hectic.

The tables were dirty.

Boo!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Luke E. 
 
 8 friends 2 reviews 

 Luke E. 
 
San Diego, CA
 11/13/2010 
I&apos;ve lived a stones throw from Newbreak for the past three years.  During this time I&apos;ve spent lots of time at Newbreak studying, meeting others for coffee, or just relaxing and watching the ocean.  The coffee is great, the food is good and the ambiance is nice and cozy.  Overall I would love to give this joint a 4 star rating, however in the the past 3 years I have noticed a backsliding trend in the level of customer service.

When i first moved into my apt. Newbreak was a haven to me on hungover days I would stumble down the alley to be greeted by a smiley yet laid back barista.  The baristas of old enjoyed their jobs, happily took customer orders, banged out lattes and mochas, then delivered drinks to their owners with a smile and a thank you. The way it ought to be done.  It was great I would always happily throw a $1 tip on my $2 black coffee togo and return back down the alley from which I had come -the system was in unison.

This type of service is wahat caused my continual patronage...until recently.

The system is breaking down.   I have noticed many of the employees change over and they are being relaced with lower quality baristas.  I understand that there is a learning curve in training new employees, but it is impossible to train someone to care or to be positive and hardworking, this is why hiring is so important.  I feel the company has made a few mistakes with the type of people they have hired.

Recently on one such hungover day I made the journey down the alley in search  a cup of joe.  Upon entering newbreak I approached the counter - the new guy who was working was talking to the cook in the corner.  The two employees both saw me, but neither acknowledged me and  finally after a couple of minutes of conversating the barista came over to help me (WTF did he think I was just going to go away?).  So I paid for my coffe and left a 50% tip as usual and sat and waited for a new pot of vanilla nut to brew.  After a few minutes I hear &apos;Vanilla Nut togo&apos; and the barista sets the coffee on the counter and walks back to his conversation with the cook.  No thanks for your business? Really?  I just gave you a nice tip to pour liquid in a cup and you don&apos;t appreciate my business?

However foolish of me, I have returned on a few occasions since then and had the similar results.  The same individual mentioned above generally has been a downer. Once he actually greeted me with a mouth full of food.  Not only is this disgusting and rude, it also would be considered a critical violation if a health inspector would have observed that type of behavior.  On another occasion I intentionally made sure he saw me drop a tip in his tip jar and thanked him when he handed me the coffee this time, to which he replied &apos;yup&apos;-still no thank you.  Just a bad attitude I guess, I don&apos;t understand people in OB are usually friendly.

Fianally the system has broken. Today I went in for the usual and it was not the employee mentioned above, but another new employee.  All the other variables were still the same and so too was the result. The employee had the same crappy attitude which I now have come to expect from Newbrak baristas. I paid, tipped and waited for my drink.  When it came I said thank you, to which this new staff person replied &apos;yup&apos;.  No thank you, no appreciation of my business.  It is clear that something unfortunate has happened in the company&apos;s service phiolosophy.  The bad attitude of one individual has spread over throughout the rest of the staff.   What is really worse is that Newbreak has potential to be a great spot.

I may be just one customer, but I was loyal to Newbreak, and now I go am going to have to go out of my way to avoid the place.  Sad that the only thing that changed about Newbreak was the customer service, however at least for me it is enough to make me stumble the extra couple blocks to Java Jungle on those all too common hung over mornings.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (8) Funny (2) Cool (3) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Drew M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 234 friends 213 reviews 

 Drew M. 
 
Costa Mesa, CA
 3/17/2011 1 Check-in Here 
We only stopped in here to get coffee before we walked around on the beach, but let me just say, APPLE MUFFIN.  That&apos;s all I want to review here.  It was fresh, it was like eating a unicorn jumping across a double rainbow while it was raining golden drops of apple rain.  NOM NOM NOM I wanted another one but I had to go eat brunch and although I implored my friend to leave me while I hid under the table and committed apple adultery, I was drug away after just one.

Everything else was superfluous, time stopped, and the universe bended to my apple will.  Ok, it wasn&apos;t that good, but it was definitely amazing, and there are apples baked into the muffin, and there is sugar on top and... oh noes, there I go again.  Just try it.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Amy Y. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 48 friends 57 reviews 

 Amy Y. 
 
San Diego, CA
 3/13/2011 
I would have given this place all the stars if it weren&apos;t for the fact that they only served breakfast during breakfast time. I know I know, to be expected, but they should have a time written on the board saying what time they serve it till.  The breakfast menu board looked like it was the main one!

Anyways, I came here to actually do some work and there were plenty of outlets compared to other places.  A great atmosphere that allows a lot of sunlight and you can even see the ocean in the far distance!  Parking is a LITTLE hectic since it&apos;s kind of on the main strip right next to the beach, but doable I would say.

Service was really good, I got the secret garden, wasn&apos;t what I was expecting honestly but still pretty tasty.  Just overall a really cool and chill environment.  I would recommend it for those that wanna just hang out as well as those that want to catch up on a little reading or work. :)  They also have free wifi so that&apos;s also a plus!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Franklin M. 
 
 5 friends 198 reviews 

 Franklin M. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 12/25/2011 1 photo 
Just filled up at Hodad&apos;s and needed my small mocha to make the drive back to Los Angeles. I was going to go to Starbuck&apos;s and ran into this place on my way back to my car. I am a coffee snob so I wasn&apos;t so sure if they would make a good mocha but took the chance anyways. The earth girl behind the counter took my order for a &apos;short&apos; double mocha. She knows what she is doing because she made it right. This is a nice place to chill right across from the beach, so if you have time and don&apos;t want the Starbucks crowd then this is the place to be.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tanya D. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 111 friends 262 reviews 

 Tanya D. 
 
Laguna Beach, CA
 10/31/2011 
We had a family gathering in OB and stopped by here at about 10:30 on a Sunday - much less packed than Shades and Nick&apos;s, this cafe was more capable of fitting our party of 12 (yikes!). The view alone is worthy of almost full stars - it&apos;s right across the street from the beach, and from the open-window-facing tables you can see the pier (definitely my favorite in the San Diego area).

Although there was a bit of space in the dining room, the line was pretty long, which is a testament to an establishment&apos;s kitchen if you ask me. A mixed Ocean Beach type crowd was waiting to be served their bagels, burritos and morning brew. So we got in line, ordered, and seeing as the line&apos;s length never waned, we received our food in due time. Our table included orders of bagels, breakfast sandwiches and burritos, the Nova and my order - the Veggie Burrito. Not your usual veggie burrito, this is more of a breakfast style. Eggs with a ton of veggies (mushrooms, onion, spinach, etc) and I had them hold the cheese and potatoes. I can&apos;t speak for the bagels, but my burrito was delicious. My cousin and I both had two types of breakfast burritos and they were less expensive that some of Newbreak&apos;s bagel options, which might be why their size isn&apos;t too hefty. But that&apos;s great with me: a breakfast burrito that isn&apos;t too huge or greasy at all, thank you sir may I have another?

But all in all it was a cafe so the service was a bit slapdash, not exactly suited for our party of 12, which isn&apos;t their fault. I envision my next visit  to this cafe as a bagel, cup of coffee and an ocean view - really indulging in what seems to be the highlights of this place.
 
 Listed in: Breakfast or Breakslowly 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Danny W. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 4346 friends 898 reviews 

 Danny W. 
 
Chicago, IL
 8/28/2009 6 Check-ins Here 
The location of this place is so sick for a coffee shop. How can you not heart a place that you can sit on  the patio with your laptop and a cup of Joe or a smoothie and be half staring at the Pacific and half looking at the Youtube video &quot;David After Dentist&quot;.

The food is pretty solid as well! I&apos;ve had a few different sandwiches and wraps and all have been freshly made and yummy! The service is a bit spacey but is to be expected in OB aka Stonersville, CA.

If you are suffering from the crappiness that is unemployment come out to this coffeeshop and do some web browsing here for a new gig. Even if you don&apos;t find anything at least your office is overlooking the beach unlike your employed friends who are wasting away in cubiclesville.
 
 Listed in: Getting Buzzed 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (7) Funny (7) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Shelli S. 
 
 279 friends 286 reviews 

 Shelli S. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/28/2009 1 Check-in Here 
This is the location that looks straight at the ocean and the really big lifeguard station, not the little booths, the biggie mother ship.

Now that I&apos;m one of the many looking for a job (QA software and website testing-shameless plug-ha!) this is a great spot to get some people time if I need to see some faces because I&apos;m going cross eyed applying for jobs online.

Bonus points: They take bank cards! (Any biz that doesn&apos;t take cash in this town drives me NUTZ)

I like this place because they have breakfast for $2.78 fresh baked bagel, cream cheese and a large coffee. Lots of choices of bagels, lots of choices of those sweet kind of coffee cake things. I&apos;m not a huge fan of that kind of sweet stuff. I go for more savory dishes and foods when it comes to coffee shop menus.

One of my faves here though is The Hamlet, it&apos;s an open faced bagel toasted with swiss cheese then it&apos;s layered with ham and under this a layer of cream cheese. Of course with my lactose issues I try so hard to avoid it, but I break down inevitably all the time.

I like their soy mocha with ice and they make a mean, mean Vietnamese, one of the best around. The Obecian smoothie is tasty, and a lot of my friends like the sunrise or greek sunrise egg sandwich. I bring every out of towner here and they eat it up, the view and all the goodies.

In my opinion to compete with chain coffee shops, I think you need to provide variety that chains don&apos;t offer. And this place does that well. Also there is a patio and spot to bring a dog if you want to sit outside with your dog on a leash.

There&apos;s one thing me and my pal agree on, the views where the customers sit are often blocked by wooden cross beams along the windows. It would be most excellent to get some small time contractor to fix this window issue and it would make it a 5 star for the views.

Service is great, they seem to remember my order from only being here a few times as of late. Perhaps they know my yelper MOJO (hahahahah I am so NOT stuck up about my YELP-i-rific status ;)

(I&apos;m really kidding about the last part, the part being that I have any kind of status that is . . .)
 
 Listed in: Veggie Mite Sandwhich! (or… , One bean, 2bean we all scream… 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (4) Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ben Y. 
 
 43 friends 71 reviews 

 Ben Y. 
 
San Diego, CA
 11/30/2008 
I lived in OB for a while, and Newbreak (mostly because of convenience) became a place I would go on an all too regular basis. It&apos;s really not that great. It&apos;s not that bad either, pretty cool actually, but really not that great. The location is fantastic, it&apos;s very large, free wifi, OK coffee, but what really kills it is the food. It&apos;s sort of pricey, which is understandable for the location (their rent must be INTENSE) - but most importantly, it&apos;s just not that great.

If I still lived in OB, I&apos;m sure I would still come back regularly. But I don&apos;t, so I won&apos;t!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (2) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ryan J. 
 
 45 friends 86 reviews 

 Ryan J. 
 
Long Beach, CA
 Updated - 3/22/2009 
I walk in Newbreak on this cool, drizzly, morning. I order my overpriced bagel and my latte. I find a seat, and get ready for some serious productivity. You see, I am a law student, in addition to two midterms, I have to prepare for a closing argument and complete drafting a revocable trust all by Thursday. Needless to say, my past week has been busy, and my next five days are going to be hellish.

So on this morning, I opt to go to Newbreak for a change scenery and because I don&apos;t feel like making breakfast and coffee at my house. I boot up, and much to my chagrin, no internet. I see a print out that notifies customers:

&quot;Effective March 14, there will be no wireless internet access or studying permitted between 8 a.m. and 1 p.m. on the weekends due to our seating problem. Thank you for your cooperation.&quot;

Cooperation? Huh!!! How&apos;s this for cooperation?

Newbreak, I will not patronize your establishment on the weekends nor, for that matter, on the weekdays until this policy is rescinded. Please, let me explain.

On any given weekday, over 70% of your patrons are on the internet or studying. In business terms, this means they are keeping your doors open. By denying access to the internet and forbidding studying, you are essentially saying: &quot;Hey regulars, go f*ck yourself, it&apos;s the weekend, and it&apos;s time to come up, son. It&apos;s all about the Benjamin&apos;s. We have to make space for all or our customers that come by once or twice a month.&quot;

Moreover, it&apos;s ok to read the Union Tribune, a novel, or the Reader, but bust out a text book and you gots to go. This is ridiculous.

Here is a list of the changes that have taken place at Newbreak in the past year:

Raised prices on drinks and food.
Began charging for refills on coffee.
Limited seating in booths to two people during 8-1.
Denying internet access during 8-1 on the weekends.
Forbidding studying between 8-1 on the weekends.
Dollar cover to enter.
$5 seat rental per hour.

Ok, so maybe the last two haven&apos;t happened yet, but I wouldn&apos;t be surprised. After I get through this week of hell, the owner is getting a letter, and until the policy is rescinded, I am off hunting for another coffee shop with free Wi-Fi during ALL hours of operation. Anyone got suggestions?
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (3) Cool (3) 
 
1 Previous Review: Show all» 

 2/25/2009 
I am not a coffee shop person. When I walk into a dive bar, it is getting the benefit of the doubt.… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Erin G. 
 
 6 friends 9 reviews 

 Erin G. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 5/25/2011 
Tasty organic blend coffee.
The bran muffin was fresh and tasy and didn&apos;t make my stomach hurt like most processed flour muffins do.
I also am a huge fan of their housemade musli.
Free sides of steamed soymilk at my requested was very much appreciated.
I have never tried anything from the kitchen.

I first tried Newbreak in 2010 and had to come back this year during a stay at the Ocean Beach Hotel. I love the short walk to this friendly, affordable, fresh cafe.  Newbreak is also right across from the beach.

Sipping organic coffee and smelling the ocean breeze = heavenly.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Robin L. 
 
 184 friends 223 reviews 

 Robin L. 
 
San Diego, CA
 11/30/2008 
Great location.  Semi-great food.  Less-than-semi-great service.  Kinda crappy prices.

I used to walk to Newbreak on a fairly regular basis to get a coffee and bagel sandwich.  Great hangover food.  If you go at lunch, the OB KenOB is fantastic.  For the prices, though, not that impressive.  It&apos;ll cost you $8+ for a bagel sandwich and a small latte.  I suppose it makes sense since they have to afford their rent.

The people working there rarely seem like they&apos;re enjoying their job, but we&apos;ve met a few cool ones before.  They take your order and give you the food, so I guess I have nothing to complain about.   I guess places like Starbucks and In-and-Out have spoiled us when it comes to cracked-out smiles waiting for you as you walk up to the counter.  Too bad they don&apos;t serve bagel sandwiches.
 
 Listed in: My (old) Neighborhood 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Chris H. 
 
 7 friends 10 reviews 

 Chris H. 
 
Manhattan Beach, CA
 9/6/2007 
Best coffee in OB and best service you could ever ask for! Renda the lady who runs it is the nicest person around. Best bet it to go for the bagel and coffee special which is only 3 bucks (toasted bagel, cream cheese, and a large coffee)...

Also free Wi Fi so if you have some work to do it is great!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Norman R. 
 
 259 friends 151 reviews 

 Norman R. 
 
Chula Vista, CA
 10/8/2008 4 photos 
Newbreak has an awesome view of OB. Pretty much ocean front property here. Cute little cafe with cute decor. The caffe mocha I had was a little bit strong, but it was fantastic compared to the sorry ass ham and cheese panini I ordered. I literally had to force myself to eat it. No bueno! A bird flew in through the big open patio and hopped around and flew everywhere while I sat and studied. I don&apos;t know how I feel about that.

The free WIFI is absolutely the best thing about this place. I think it&apos;s literally the only WIFI hotspot in the area. It closes early. So this place is no where near 5 stars. It&apos;s really a 3.5 for me. But i rounded off to the nearest star because of the WIFI and location.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Matt P. 
 
 50 friends 75 reviews 

 Matt P. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/12/2008 
Really nice strong coffee. pretty chill environment. Foam was a little weak. Looked like they had some awesome stuff on the menu, I&apos;ll try it next time and update this. For now just a coffee review. Question - &quot;Why did he only give it 3 stars, what a prick&quot;. Answer - No raw/ brown sugar. Sometimes I don&apos;t even put sugar in my coffee, if I do I use half a packet, it&apos;s not that big a deal - except when I WANT a little sugar, and when I do I don&apos;t want white sugar, it&apos;s nasty and highly processed and cheap and if I&apos;m paying a premium for my coffee I&apos;d like to be able to get some premium sugar too! That&apos;s all.

This place might go up in my estimation if I try the food and it&apos;s amazing or something.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jerry F. 
 
 130 friends 134 reviews 

 Jerry F. 
 
Arlington, VA
 7/10/2009 
I went here for lunch with a couple of coworkers.  I&apos;d never been here before, but this place is right next to the beach, with a wide variety of traffic coming through.  There&apos;s working professionals here enjoying coffee/tea and browsing the net, as well as people just enjoying a day at the beach.

This place has a wide selection of sandwiches and wraps.  But the thing I liked best was their wall of tea!  They have so many choices here.  I&apos;ll definitely head back here some time, and enjoy some tea while getting some work done.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tamara C. 
 
 39 friends 94 reviews 

 Tamara C. 
 
San Diego, CA
 12/13/2010 2 Check-ins Here 
Good atmosphere usually pretty crowded though. Great lemon poppy seed muffins.  No free wifi and limited plugs for computers.  Good tea selection and coffee is far above average.

- Tamara Cross Lawyer
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alexa F. 
 
 0 friends 6 reviews 

 Alexa F. 
 
San Diego, CA
 Updated - 3/26/2009 
Recently I tried to go back to Newbreak to meet a friend (they suggested it) and I got harassed by some homeless guy inside Newbreak. The workers thought it was funny and didn&apos;t help me out.

I ordered an everything bagel with cream cheese and a coffee since last time I didn&apos;t have much success with what I ordered.

About 10 minutes later I am still waiting for that bagel and coffee. So I go to ask and they forgot to bring it out. The girl hands me a cold cup of coffee and tells me that they just gave out the last everything bagel.

When I ordered, there were everything bagels but after they f&apos;d up my order there were none left. So I get stuck with a black bagel, at first I though hmm, chocolate that might be nice but no, pumpernickel!

I am Jewish and I know an thing or two about bagels this bagel was awful and my coffee was to cold and weak to overpower the taste of burnt pumpernickel.

Once it was time to go,  I went to my car across the street and I got attacked by teenage zombie homeless drug people, who all wanted my change. They saw the University of San Diego sticker on my car and kept saying &quot;USD money for me&quot;

The whole experience was a nightmare, I wouldn&apos;t go back.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
2 Previous Reviews: Show all» 

 2/23/2009 
They have another Yelp posting with a bunch of bad reviews, so I thought I would post on this one… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Diane C. 
 
 16 friends 22 reviews 

 Diane C. 
 
San Diego, CA
 1/12/2011 
It&apos;s hit or miss with this place but the blueberry black tea is a consistent winner. I wouldn&apos;t recommend breakfast here when you can get a delicious breakfast sandwich at the Olive Tree and have a way better customer service experience. Plus, I think the coffee at the Olive Tree is way better than the Peerless stuff at Newbreak.

The Birchirmuesli is very yummy if you happened to get it before it goes bad. I don;t think the baristas have any way to track when they make the muesli cuz the last couple time I&apos;ve ordered it it tasted old.  The Abbott location is great, more spacious.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brittany Z. 
 
 7 friends 8 reviews 

 Brittany Z. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 11/22/2008 
My new study place. Free Wi Fi. Good for people watching. Pretty good, home made chicken soup.

My only complaint so far is being taunted by the crashing waves across the street. I would rather be on the beach, but my lap top hates the sand.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Terrence M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 59 friends 118 reviews 

 Terrence M. 
 
San Diego, CA
 9/16/2009 
Great beach-view coffee shop in OB. Free wifi, decent food, and chill local crowd.

Overheard during my most recent visit:

Plump, old lady: &quot;I like to talk about sex.&quot;

Friendly older local guy with British accent: &quot;I&apos;m all ears.&quot;

Homeless guy without British accent: &quot;I&apos;m all tears.&quot;

Now, you won&apos;t hear THAT at Starbux!

Newbreak is a friendly, locals place and the perfect environment to study in or grab a bite with friends within earshot of the Pacific pounding away at the shore nearby.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (3) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Teej T. 
 
 668 friends 660 reviews 

 Teej T. 
 
Urbana, IL
 4/26/2008 
This is reason number 8,006 why it will be hard to move to Illinois this fall.  Newbreak is a cute, cozy coffee shop in OB that looks directly out over the ocean.  There is nothing better than to sit and just enjoy a tasty iced mocha while sitting out with a friend and watching the waves roll in.  Life just gets better after one of those sitting and thinking moments.

The coffee shop itself isn&apos;t extraordinarily remarkable, it&apos;s a little close and a little small, but it&apos;s got a nice little charm to it, and there&apos;s free wifi.  And oh my God there&apos;s the ocean right outside!

Seriously, I got so upset yesterday as I REALIZED THAT IN SIX MONTHS i WILL BE 2,000 MILES FROM THE PACIFIC OCEAN.  Yikes.
 
 Listed in: Caffeine Rush 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Anthony P. 
 
 23 friends 52 reviews 

 Anthony P. 
 
San Diego, CA
 7/23/2007 
The coffee is mediocre. The breakfast burritos so-so. The bagels, well, bagels.

Not much to say, strangely enough. Beach. Sitting in chairs.

In short: stop-gap. But there is wi-fi.
 
 Listed in: Ocean Beach-Around 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michelle M. 
 
 2 friends 49 reviews 

 Michelle M. 
 
San Diego, CA
 12/1/2010 
I have been here before&amp;had good experiences - but not great, so they were easily eclipsed by the latest, all-around rotten experience. I&apos;m in complete agreement with the other reviewers who say the customer service has gone WAY downhill.

We like to stop while walking our dogs, so outside seating is a must. They get no bonus points for that since their outside seating is a few tables set out on the sidewalk. That would be fine except those tables are usually dirty.  The smoothies are good but not great,&amp;the options are limited - my favorite place makes much better smoothies&amp;has a MUCH larger menu.
You also have to ask for the WiFi password every time,&amp;when we asked the employees stood there talking to each other for a few minutes while we waited for them to acknowledge us.

We ordered 2 sandwiches, nothing hard... first they came out with one sandwich already made on a different bread than we ordered; the girl apologized for being out of the one we wanted, but the sandwich being already made makes it more inconvenient to change the order... They also forgot to put avocado on the sandwiches; they apologized&amp;corrected it (slopping a couple of pieces onto each one), but it still wasn&apos;t finished. It turns out they also used pepper turkey on both sandwiches, not the regular turkey they were supposed to come with...without asking us about the substitution or offering any options. When we asked about it they said they were out if the regular turkey, which they didn&apos;t bother to tell us when we ordered or before they made the sandwiches, OR even when they brought them out.  I ate mine (I was too hungry to care that much), my husband got a refund for his.

The final straw that ruined my lunch was the guy working on the outside (where I was attempting to eat); dragging his ladder back&amp;forth along the sidewalk scaring my dogs, who I was trying to hold onto while eating my sandwich&amp;balancing my laptop; banging on something on the overhang causing flakes of paint/wood/whatever it was to fall all over the place just a few feet from my food. We finally left at that - my husband didn&apos;t get any lunch&amp;I ate about half of mine before I had to leave.

I don&apos;t know if this was an anomaly or an indication of what Newbreak is coming to...but I don&apos;t know when I&apos;ll be willing to give them a chance to redeem themselves after this. I&apos;ll be going elsewhere for a while - I&apos;m not a Starbucks fan but at least I can be pretty sure I won&apos;t get paint chips rained into my coffee there,&amp;we&apos;re willing to walk farther to get lunch made correctly&amp;without the ignore-or-offend-the-customers-maybe-they&apos;ll-go-­away attitude.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Charlie L. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 79 friends 389 reviews 

 Charlie L. 
 
Seattle, WA
 2/23/2008 
Had a lovely breakfast in this great little down to earth cafe setting. Almost feels like you&apos;re in the diner of a small town... which I totally dig, hence the four star... despite the fact that the food was unmemorable (but I do recall it being pretty good).

Since it&apos;s across the street from my dentist, I would likely end up there again.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nicole P. 
 
 10 friends 24 reviews 

 Nicole P. 
 
San Diego, CA
 6/2/2008 
Great place to relax and enjoy coffee and a bagel.  They have a huge selection of teas that are wonderful.  It overlooks the ocean and is inviting and relaxing.  I could enjoy coming her on my lazy mornings.  Not too crowded and casual.

Highly recommend
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 1 to 40 of 108 ( 18 Filtered )

 |   
 Page: 1 2 3 
 Write a Review What&apos;s This? 
About This Business
 Provided by business 
Specialties
 
Besides our delicious specialty coffees we also serve a wide variety of smoothies. We serve breakfast and lunch and are known for healthy foods
like the Birchirmuesli, Super Bowl, and homemade homous.
 Flag as inappropriate View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
Deals Nearby
 More» 
 $10 for $20 Deal Waffle Spot San Diego, CA $9 for $15 Deal Rocking Tanuki San Diego, CA 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 Your Mama&apos;s Mug  27 reviews &quot;Thank you Judy for your kindness and generosity.&quot; Day Break  51 reviews &quot;And true to form, quite dog friendly.&quot; Jungle Java  63 reviews &quot;Great for people watching on Newport Ave.&quot; Dee&apos;s Newbreak Coffee and Cafe  5 reviews 
Neighborhood: Point Loma
 Lazy Hummingbird  41 reviews &quot;Danielle 1, 2, Darcy and Christian are all awesome.&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 On the Beach 
Restaurants, bars and activities on and really close to the beaches and bays of San Diego!
 Breakfast or Breakslowly 
I&apos;m not really the brunch and mimosas type of person, so my brand of breakfast is affordable, the most…
 One bean, 2bean we all scream for… 
If you want to define a city by it&apos;s culture, you need to look at the businesses that swirl within, local…
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Coffee Ocean View San Diego Daybreak Cafe San Diego Coffee Shop San Diego 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 San Diego Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
