<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003755" url="http://forums.mikeholt.com/showthread.php?t=127703" time="2012-07-12-19:55" support="3" score="0.0013914579057703947" bingtitle="Plan Rejection, Load Calculations - Mike Holt&apos;s Forum" webtitle="Plan Rejection, Load Calculations">
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000039" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="118"/>
	<description>... greater of connected -OR- using value from Table ... per 220.14(F) @ 125%; Gen. purpose receptacles @ 180VA ... This is a fast food restaurant. I don&apos;t disagree with my own ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Forum 
 Moderators FAQ Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 Who&apos;s Online Member List 
 
 What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum Active Forums Electrical Calculations / Engineering Plan Rejection, Load Calculations 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You must register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing posts,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the list below. Join Mike Holt on Facebook , Twitter and YouTube . 
 Closed Thread Page 1 of 2 1 2 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 1 to 10 of 19 
Thread: Plan Rejection, Load Calculations 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Email this Page… Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 07-20-10  10:59 AM #1 Npstewart 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Senior Member Join Date Feb 2010 Posts 522 
Plan Rejection, Load Calculations
 I received the following rejection on a project we did. It is a STANDARD rejection that was obviously copied and pasted. I used the same load calc I always use for commercial, (and never have issues with) which basically breaks everything down and takes the load at 100% except the lighting which I multiply at 125%. Heres the rejection:


 Please revise the Service Calculation to conform to the prescriptives in the NEC: General Lighting load as greater of connected -OR- using value from Table 220.12 NEC; Comply with NEC 600.5 for sign circuit requirements. Calculate per 220.14(F) @ 125%; Gen. purpose receptacles @ 180VA; Special purpose/ dedicated loads shall be itemized @ actual value; HVAC: greater of Heat -OR- A/C (loads per 440.34); All Motor Loads (Largest @ 125%); All continuous loads @ 125% (sign, lighting, etc.); Storage Type Water Heaters (120g or less) shall be considered (calculated/ protected as) a continuous load (125%) per 422.13. *Also, itemize the following continuous outlet loads: Illuminated Menu, Backlit signage, etc. to demonstrate inclusion. 


I know it looks like its long, but like I said its standard, I know this because he cites a electric storage water heater, but my water heater is a instant gas heater. My question is, it appears he wants me to multiply EVERYTHING almost by 125%, however the NEC only says to use 125%&quot;For the purpose of sizing BRANCH circuits&quot;. For instance, a water heater has to be taken at 125% if it is under 125 gallons, however the code states that it is only for SIZING branch circuits. So if you have a water heater that is 4500 watts, the breaker is required to be sized for 125% however, the load itself should be taken at 100%. If you read the rejection, it appears he wants me to artificially increase the load correct? Also, I usually DO increase my lighting in the load calc by multiplying my lighting load by 1.25, but this also is only supposed to be for sizing branch circuits.

Any opinions would be appreciated because I see this interpreted differently quite often, thanks. 07-20-10  12:13 PM #2 Npstewart 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Senior Member Join Date Feb 2010 Posts 522 Also, I think the reason why it is required to multiply by 125% (continuous load)is because 1.25 is the inverse of 80%. For continuous loads you shouldnt fill the breaker over 80%. 07-20-10  12:25 PM #3 nakulak 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Senior Member Join Date Aug 2007 Posts 2,754 imo the reason is because of the definition of continuous load. imo everything he noted is per NEC (but I am no expert) 07-20-10  12:46 PM #4 Npstewart 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Senior Member Join Date Feb 2010 Posts 522 Its in there, but hes missing an entire statement that says&quot;for the purpose of sizing branch circuits&quot;. 07-20-10  12:50 PM #5 nakulak 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Senior Member Join Date Aug 2007 Posts 2,754 how about posting the load calculation and somebody can pick it apart or agree ? 07-20-10  12:53 PM #6 steve66 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Senior Member Join Date Jun 2003 Posts 5,116 Well, I do think motor feeders need the extra 25% of the largest motor calculated in. And I&apos;m not really seeing where he is asking for everything to be taken at 125%.

I would suggest seeing if you can call the person who wrote the comment. They can probably be more specific over the phone about what they see that they don&apos;t think complies.

Steve 07-20-10  01:11 PM #7 Npstewart 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Senior Member Join Date Feb 2010 Posts 522 Im just going to post my revised load calculation where everything is broken down specifally. My point is that the 125% shouldn&apos;t be carried to the service calculation, it should stop at the branch circuit level. I think this revised one will work, and I do have a call/email into him. Attached Images 
 load calc.pdf‎ (35.6 KB, 122 views) 
 07-20-10  01:37 PM #8 nakulak 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Senior Member Join Date Aug 2007 Posts 2,754 Originally Posted by Npstewart Its in there, but hes missing an entire statement that says&quot;for the purpose of sizing branch circuits&quot;. I looked at the calculation. which items are you disagreeing with ? the allowable demand factors are spelled out in part III and IV, and I don&apos;t see permitted reductions for lighting, hvac to less than 125% ? (what type of occupancy is this ?) 07-20-10  01:52 PM #9 Npstewart 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Senior Member Join Date Feb 2010 Posts 522 This is a fast food restaurant. I don&apos;t disagree with my own load calculation, I disagree with the reviewers comment (see original post) that certain items in the load calculation have to be multiplied by 1.25.

In my opinion you should only have to multiply something by 1.25 to size the branch circuit, hence the NEC saying&quot;for the purpose of sizing branch circuits&quot;that is just saying not to load a breaker more then 80% of its value for certain items such as a water heater or lighting. He is asking me to multiply certain items in the load calc by 1.25. Last edited by Npstewart; 07-20-10 at 02:00 PM . 07-20-10  06:10 PM #10 OTT2 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Member Join Date Mar 2010 Location Orygun Posts 96 Originally Posted by Npstewart This is a fast food restaurant. I don&apos;t disagree with my own load calculation, I disagree with the reviewers comment (see original post) that certain items in the load calculation have to be multiplied by 1.25.

In my opinion you should only have to multiply something by 1.25 to size the branch circuit, hence the NEC saying&quot;for the purpose of sizing branch circuits&quot;that is just saying not to load a breaker more then 80% of its value for certain items such as a water heater or lighting. He is asking me to multiply certain items in the load calc by 1.25. 230.42 (A) requires that you take the continuous loads at 125% unless the equipment is listed for operation at 100% of its rating!

The examples in Annex D seem to support this as well.

Your right about the standard rejection format, that&apos;s a fairly normal comment for a plan review. 
 Closed Thread Page 1 of 2 1 2 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Quick Navigation Electrical Calculations / Engineering Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums Active Forums 
 Business Management / Estimating Continuing Education (CEU) Electrical Calculations / Engineering Electrical Instructors Exam Preparation Grounding versus Bonding Hazardous (Classified) Locations Lighting Low Voltage and Limited Energy NEC Photovoltaic Forum Power Quality&amp;Surge Protection Proposals/Comments for the next NEC cycle Safety UL Issues 
 Resources 
 Mike Holt Newsletters Mike Holt YouTube Videos Mike Holt on Facebook 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 Facebook Twitter Google StumbleUpon Digg del.icio.us 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts 
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 
 Mike Holt Enterprises Home Page Top 
 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 12:55 PM .
	</body>
</document>
