<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003494" url="http://reviews.opentable.com/0938/78469/reviews.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:38" support="2" score="0.00366831098748471" bingtitle="J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Reviews - Rated by OpenTable Diners" webtitle="JG Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Reviews - Rated by OpenTable Diners">
			<query id="001006" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>Simply grilled preparations accompanied by bold condiments anchor the J&amp;G Grill dining ... so loud my wife and I could not talk at the table. We were also shoved at a table ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Reservations - Free•Instant•Confirmed Home Mobile Help Learn More Print this page Restaurant Reviews Restaurant reviews by area Alabama Anchorage Arkansas Atlanta / Georgia Atlantic City Austin Baltimore / Maryland Boston / New England Calgary / Alberta California Central Coast Caribbean Charlotte Chicago / Illinois Cincinnati / Dayton Cleveland / Akron / Canton Coastal North Carolina Columbus Corpus Christi / McAllen Dallas - Fort Worth Denver / Colorado Detroit / Eastern Michigan East Tennessee Edmonton / Alberta El Paso / Southwest Texas Grand Rapids / Western Michigan Greensboro / Winston Salem / Highpoint Hawaii Houston Idaho Indiana Iowa Jackson Hole Jacksonville / Northeast Florida Kansas City Kentucky Key West / Florida Keys Lake of the Ozarks Las Vegas Los Angeles / Orange County Manitoba / Saskatchewan Memphis Miami / Southeast Florida Ft. Lauderdale - Broward County (7,720) Hollywood (750) Miami - Dade County (14,248) Aventura (260) Bal Harbour (434) American (166) Asian (4) Contemporary American (66) French (45) Italian (17) Seafood (8) Steakhouse (128) Brickell (168) Coconut Grove (444) Coral Gables (2,139) Design District (46) Doral (118) Downtown (143) Hallandale (168) Kendall (12) Key Biscayne (36) Miami (4,174) Miami Beach / South Beach (5,380) Miami Lakes (84) Miramar (87) North Bay Village (10) North Miami (96) Pembroke Pines (1) Pinecrest (50) South Miami (142) Sunny Isles Beach (21) Surfside (37) Weston (198) Palm Beach County (13,702) Minneapolis - St. Paul Mississippi Montana Montreal / Quebec Nashville Nebraska New Mexico New Orleans / Louisiana New York / Tri-State Area North Dakota Northern Michigan / Upper Peninsula Northwest Florida Nova Scotia / New Brunswick Oklahoma Orlando / Central Florida East Palm Springs / Palm Desert Cities Philadelphia / New Jersey Suburbs Phoenix / Arizona Pinehurst Pittsburgh Portland / Oregon Raleigh / Durham / Chapel Hill Sacramento / Central Valley San Antonio San Diego San Francisco Bay Area Seattle / Eastern Washington South Carolina South Dakota Southwest Florida Southwest Indiana / Tri-State Area Springfield / Branson St. Louis Tahoe / Reno Area Tampa / Central Florida West Texas Panhandle Toledo Toronto / Ontario Utah Vancouver / British Columbia Virginia Washington, D.C. Area West Virginia Western North Carolina Wisconsin Find Restaurants in Your Area Select a Location 
 Alabama Amsterdam Anchorage Arkansas Atlanta / Georgia Atlantic City Austin Baltimore / Maryland Beirut Boston / New England Calgary / Alberta California Central Coast Caribbean Charlotte Chicago / Illinois Chihuahua Cincinnati / Dayton Cleveland / Akron / Canton Coastal North Carolina Columbus Corpus Christi / McAllen Dallas - Fort Worth Denver / Colorado Detroit / Eastern Michigan East Tennessee Edmonton / Alberta El Paso / Southwest Texas Grand Rapids / Western Michigan Greensboro / Winston Salem / Highpoint Hawaii Houston Idaho Indiana Iowa Jackson Hole Jacksonville / Northeast Florida Kansas City Kentucky Key West / Florida Keys Lake of the Ozarks Las Vegas Los Angeles / Orange County Malaysia Manitoba / Saskatchewan Memphis Miami / Southeast Florida Minneapolis - St. Paul Mississippi Montana Montreal / Quebec Nashville Nebraska New Mexico New Orleans / Louisiana New York / Tri-State Area North Dakota Northern Michigan / Upper Peninsula Northwest Florida Nova Scotia / New Brunswick Oklahoma Orlando / Central Florida East Palm Springs / Palm Desert Cities Philadelphia / New Jersey Suburbs Phoenix / Arizona Pinehurst Pittsburgh Portland / Oregon Raleigh / Durham / Chapel Hill Sacramento / Central Valley San Antonio San Diego San Francisco Bay Area Seattle / Eastern Washington South Carolina South Dakota Southwest Florida Southwest Indiana / Tri-State Area Springfield / Branson St. Louis Tahoe / Reno Area Tampa / Central Florida West Texas Panhandle Toledo Toronto / Ontario Utah Vancouver / British Columbia Villa de Muerte Virginia Washington, D.C. Area West Virginia Western North Carolina Wisconsin 
 Reserve now: Reserve Now on OpenTable.com J&amp;amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Reservations Restaurant Reviews List &gt; Miami / Southeast Florida Restaurant Reviews &gt; Miami - Dade County Restaurant Reviews &gt; Bal Harbour Restaurant Reviews &gt; American Restaurant Reviews 
 J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Reviews List 
 
 J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour 
 9703 Collins Avenue
Bal Harbour, FL 33154

A comfortable yet elegant hideaway – signature Jean-Georges sophistication realized far from home.
J&amp;G;Grill combines a curated selection of Jean-Georges&quot; greatest appetizers, side dishes and accompaniments from his portfolio of domestic and international restaurants around the world with the highest quality meats and freshest seafood available in the market. Simply grilled preparations accompanied by bold condiments anchor the J&amp;G;Grill dining experience at the St. Regis Bal Harbour Resort. J&amp;G;Grill offers an extensive wine selection, handcrafted specialty cocktails and house-made sodas.

 Dining Style: Casual Elegant
 Price: $50 and over
 Parking: Valet
 Cross Street: 
 See more J&amp;G;Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour details 166 Current Reviews Summary of Diner Ratings&amp;Reviews Overall (Outstanding) 4.3 / 5 (166 Reviews) Rating Breakdown 166 reviews 5 stars (84) 4 stars (59) 3 stars (14) 2 stars (7) 1 star (2) Food (Outstanding) 4.3 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 4.3 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 4.4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate Read all 166 reviews Write a review Filter Reviews By: Diners classify this restaurant as: 
 special occasion (99) fit for foodies (97) scenic view (95) 

 romantic (74) notable wine list (69) hot spot (35) 
 see more Sort By Featured Reviews Newest Oldest Highest Rating Lowest Rating Longest Shortest J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Reviews List Review 1 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 what a fabulous property w 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/05/2012 2007 Dined on 07/05/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; what a fabulous property w amazing views, incredible decor and good food! &quot; Dined on 07/05/2012 2007 Special Features: late-night find , neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 2 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Don&apos;t wait for a special occasion! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/06/2012 2011 Dined on 07/06/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; We decided to celebrate our anniversary at J&amp;G after hearing so many great things about it. We felt welcome right from the start. Our Server Bora provided the finest service I have experienced in years; engaging, informative, and unobtrusive. We both took his recommendation for the tasting menu which was fantastic! Their Sommelier Luis is equally passionate and knowledgeable. They made our anniversary very special... We will find an excuse to visit again soon! &quot; Dined on 07/06/2012 2011 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 3 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Pea soup was outstanding. 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/03/2012 2006 Dined on 07/03/2012 2006 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Pea soup was outstanding. Fish slightly overlooked and over seasoned. Nice setting. Service was extremely professional and attentive. More for the grand experience than the food. Good wine by the glass choices and cocktails were made well. &quot; Dined on 07/03/2012 2006 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 4 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Excellent Bal Harbour restaurant 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/02/2012 2006 Dined on 07/02/2012 2006 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Great and interesting food. Service was impeccable. Overall, a wonderful dining experience. &quot; Dined on 07/02/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 5 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 JG is NOT to be missed ! 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/29/2012 2009 Dined on 06/29/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Jean George never disappoints. Awesome dinner! Fantastic service and highly recommend the tastings menu with wine pairing. Sommelier was knowledgeable and interesting. &quot; Dined on 06/29/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 6 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 My wife&apos;s snapper dish was 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/24/2012 2006 Dined on 06/24/2012 2006 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; My wife&apos;s snapper dish was excellent. The Mahi I ordered was seriously overcooked. I sent it back and asked for it to be prepared again. This time it was very good.
I would expect a bottle of wine purchased with dinner to be poured by the wait staff. The manager took our wine order, brought the wine and poured the first glass for each of us. I then had to pour the rest of the wine over the course of our dinner. That is totally unacceptable, in any restaurant, regardless of the price of the bottle. Apparently nobody bothered to tell the sommelier that we had ordered wine. A subsequent lengthy discuussion with the sommelier ensued - much to our satisfaction. An error was made and a sincere apolgy has been accepted. &quot; Dined on 06/24/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 7 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Not what I expected. Jean-George 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2008 Dined on 06/23/2012 2008 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Not what I expected. Jean-George is supposed to be one of the best chef&apos;s in the world. This was not a bad meal, but it was far from a great meal. The lobster was heavy; the short ribs were well cooked but had no flavor. Hopefully, the local chef will learn to live up to J-G&apos;s name and the St. Regis&apos;s view of the Atlantic. &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2008 Special Features: scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 8 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Excellent dinner with wine 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/23/2012 2006 Dined on 06/23/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Excellent dinner with wine pairing. Very expensive but incredible! &quot; Dined on 06/23/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 9 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The direct ocean views will 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/21/2012 2010 Dined on 06/21/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; The direct ocean views will entice you to dine early. The ambiance was lovely and the decor is tasteful. We ordered the Chefs Tasting Menu and found it to be an exceptional value. Most tasting menus feature scaled-down portions, but that was not the case at JG Grill. The hearts of palm salad featured delightful locally grown tomatoes. The true gem on the menu is the pureed pea soup with parmesan foam. This was one of the best dishes and no visit to JG Grill would be complete without it. We also enjoyed the peekytoe crabcake, Mahi Mahi with fermented black beans and the molten chocolate cake. The other dishes were all quite good and met or exceeded my expectations. The service deserves an A+! We look forward to returning to JG Gri &quot; Dined on 06/21/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , great for brunch , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 10 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 waiter looked afterus very 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/19/2012 2010 Dined on 06/19/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; waiter looked afterus very well &quot; Dined on 06/19/2012 2010 Special Features: scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 11 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Having been to Jean George 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2005 Dined on 06/16/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Having been to Jean George in NYC we were excited to try this local spot - we could not have been happier and totally pleased. From service to food to decor this is a wonderful restaurant all around. &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , romantic , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 12 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Food, service and view were 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2012 Dined on 06/15/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 &quot; Food, service and view were excellent. Ever since Emerald&apos;s closed last summer the only real fine dining I could find has been Blue Moon in Ft. Laud. Now I have a new favorite spot...J&amp;G Grill. Thank you. Jorge &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2012 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 13 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 As usual this top-chef restaurant 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2007 Dined on 06/15/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; As usual this top-chef restaurant does an outstanding job with food. &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 14 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Sophisticated! 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2009 Dined on 06/15/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Service that makes us want to come back! The lounge area is gorgeous with live music and such accommodating bartenders. Feels good to be there. Food and service in the dining room is excellent. A very sophisticated setting and a great experience. &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2009 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 15 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Much quieter than previous 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/11/2012 2011 Dined on 06/11/2012 2011 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Much quieter than previous occasions. Could it have something to do with the fact that we asked twice to order some sides before our main course arrived and twice no one took our order. Or the fact that despite saying we would have wine with out meal no one came to take our wine order despite having the wine list open on our table? By now they should have ironed out their bugs. At these prices, and $16 for a very small cocktail, they need to up their game. There is a lot of choice in north Miami. &quot; Dined on 06/11/2012 2011 Special Features: scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 16 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 We always have a beautiful 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/10/2012 2009 Dined on 06/10/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; We always have a beautiful dining experience at J&amp;G. The room is beautiful and the view is spectacular. &quot; Dined on 06/10/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 17 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Excellent food, excellent 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/10/2012 2007 Dined on 06/10/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Excellent food, excellent service. &quot; Dined on 06/10/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 18 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 J&amp;G Grill is a beautiful gem 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/10/2012 2012 Dined on 06/10/2012 2012 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; J&amp;G Grill is a beautiful gem hidden in the huge new St Regis Hotel in Bal Harbour. All tables overlook the beach. The overall ambience gives a small restaurant feel with tables well-spaced so noise is at a minimum. Food is excellent but portions are on the small side and everything is a la carte. The sides are delicious, especially the mushrooms. And, dessert is over the top! &quot; Dined on 06/10/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 19 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 No more sangria. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/06/2012 2006 Dined on 06/06/2012 2006 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; We went on Valentines day and really enjoyed the place. My wife loved the sangria and said it was the best she ever had. I had the mojito and it was very good. We went back the other day, she was really looking forward to the sangria. When we sat down to order the we found out that the sangria was removed from the menu. That deflated the entire experience. On top of that my mojito had no flavor. I ordered a 2nd and that one had no flavor either. Not pleased with the bar to say the least. The food was consistent with our previous visit. &quot; Dined on 06/06/2012 2006 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 20 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Outstanding. Did the 5 course 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/30/2012 2006 Dined on 05/30/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Outstanding. Did the 5 course with wine pairings. Waiter and sommelier were amazing and very knowledgable
The pea soup was amazing, wanted to lick the bowl. LOL &quot; Dined on 05/30/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , great for outdoor dining , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 21 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Our experience was wonderful. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/02/2012 2007 Dined on 06/02/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Our experience was wonderful. The food was fantastic, the wine delicious and the service impeccable. &quot; Dined on 06/02/2012 2007 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 22 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 This has great ambiance and 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/02/2012 2007 Dined on 06/02/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; This has great ambiance and the food was spectacular. Presentation was dramatic and the service was superb. Best of all the pricing was very fair. &quot; Dined on 06/02/2012 2007 Special Features: romantic , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 23 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Very pretty restaurant. Food 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/02/2012 2008 Dined on 06/02/2012 2008 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Very pretty restaurant. Food was good but not great. Prices high. Service average. &quot; Dined on 06/02/2012 2008 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 24 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 This was our fourth visit 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/01/2012 2007 Dined on 06/01/2012 2007 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; This was our fourth visit to J&amp;G and I was not as impressed with my meal as usual. The grilled filet I ordered must have come from the tip of the filet because it was fatty and and had quite a bit of gristle. I had to cut around it quite a bit and ended up leaving a fairly big chunk on my plate. I have always ordered fish there and I think that that is definitely the way to go. &quot; Dined on 06/01/2012 2007 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , great for brunch , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , great for lunch , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 25 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Great service, and fantastic 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/01/2012 2012 Dined on 06/01/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Great service, and fantastic food! Will go again. &quot; Dined on 06/01/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 26 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Excellent Service&amp;Fit 4Foodies! 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/27/2012 2010 Dined on 05/27/2012 2010 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; We did the tasting menu and were very pleased. Steak was overcooked, but they immediately rectified it. Service was amazing. Older crowd in the early evening and younger crowd after 8PM. &quot; Dined on 05/27/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , late-night find , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 27 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Make sure you have the Truffle 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/26/2012 2009 Dined on 05/26/2012 2009 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Make sure you have the Truffle Pizza appetizer! &quot; Dined on 05/26/2012 2009 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , romantic , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 28 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Good food and service. Your 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/27/2012 2007 Dined on 05/27/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Good food and service. Your tab will be around $100 - $150 per person depending on the quality of the wine you like. We had Hamachi, excellent, tiny portion, FL Pink Shrimp, ok, a little fishy smell though, The Fettuccini Meyer Lemon was excellent as everyone says, however the pasta was not at all il dente (matters to us Italians). The Milk Fed Veal Chop with Pistaccio Pesto and Roasted Cauliflower was outstanding. The Soy Glazed Short Ribs were fair. Desserts all worked. Attractive presentations and service. Knowlegeable Sommelier on site. Wine bottles are about 3 times retail, glasses are about half of the retail bottle cost. Large wine list, and about 20 by the glass choices. All younger/recent vintage wines. Valet parking not free, $12 &quot; Dined on 05/27/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 29 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 We had a 7:00 pm reservation 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/26/2012 2008 Dined on 05/26/2012 2008 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; We had a 7:00 pm reservation on a Saturday evening so we got to the hotel early to look around and have a cocktail in the lounge. The live music was good, but it was still easy to hear the conversations of others across the room. Two cocktails including tip amounted to $42.00. I did not think it was worth the money. J&amp;G Grill, St. Regis Bal Harbour is an upscale restaurant. I had requested a window table for a special ocassion, but we were not seated by the window. There were several empty tables by the window and I asked if we could be seated there. The hostess said no because they were tables for four. However three of the tables were later occupied by parties of two. From the beginning I was unhappy with the result of my reques &quot; Dined on 05/26/2012 2008 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , special occasion , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 30 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 A Great Find 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/21/2012 2008 Dined on 05/21/2012 2008 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; This restaurant, located in the St. Regis Hotel, is excellent. Pricey, but you get what you pay for. Ocean view, nice atmosphere, great and innovative food flavors and options, and great service. We will be back. &quot; Dined on 05/21/2012 2008 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , good for groups , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 31 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Fair) 2 / 5 
 I found the tables a bit too 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/19/2012 2012 Dined on 05/19/2012 2012 Food (Fair) 2 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Fair) 2 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; I found the tables a bit too close to each other. The palm salad was too vinegary. The main course of fish arrived barely warm and was bland. However, the service was excellent and the view lovely. &quot; Dined on 05/19/2012 2012 Special Features: scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 32 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Recommended 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/20/2012 2012 Dined on 05/20/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Very good restaurant, service was great and we were very pleased &quot; Dined on 05/20/2012 2012 Special Features: great for brunch , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 33 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 We were there for brunch. 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/20/2012 2004 Dined on 05/20/2012 2004 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; We were there for brunch. The menu included breakfast items as well and lunch. We had, eggs and French toast, both were very good. Not too pricey, but sitting by the window overlooking the pool and ocean, was just lovely. This was the second time we came to J&amp;G Grill and I think it will become a regular stop for us. The entire experience was excellent! &quot; Dined on 05/20/2012 2004 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 34 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Fair) 2 / 5 
 Not impressed... 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/19/2012 2010 Dined on 05/19/2012 2010 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Fair) 2 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Four of us found the food good to very good but for the price extremely small portions. The service was wonderful. The restaurant itself is too modern to be considered romantic, all glass and steel. The most ridiculous part we found in the decor, and call us small minded if you like, was that the tables were set up with PLACE MATS! Seriously? Dinner at a very expensive restaurant and place mats? The feel was that of having dinner at what would have been the breakfast place at a five star resort. Figure dinner per person will run about $110 for what would entail one glass of wine, appetizer, entre and dessert. Ocean view but too many cabanas dotting the beach and pool area to give it a romantic feel or scenic view. &quot; Dined on 05/19/2012 2010 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 35 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 From the Valet service to 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/17/2012 2012 Dined on 05/17/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; From the Valet service to the receptionist, the service is high class. Add to this the knowledgable and friendly waiter, and you have a must visit restaurant again and again. The menu is inviting and tasty and the view is outstanding. It is a place I plan to visit often. &quot; Dined on 05/17/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , great for brunch , late-night find , neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , great for lunch , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 36 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The brunch menu is spectacular! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/13/2012 2009 Dined on 05/13/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; The brunch menu is spectacular! Huge fan of Jean Georges - and he did not disappoint. Eggs Benedict (any style) are amazing. The Peekytoe Crab Cake is Incredibly flavorful and my favorite item.
Desserts were as good as the appetizer and the entree. &quot; Dined on 05/13/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , great for brunch , kid-friendly , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 37 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 J&amp;G is one of the top restauarants 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/13/2012 2005 Dined on 05/13/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; J&amp;G is one of the top restauarants in South Florida Food ,service, ambiance and view. It has it all &quot; Dined on 05/13/2012 2005 Special Features: special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 38 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 It was my husbands birthday 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/10/2012 2007 Dined on 05/10/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; It was my husbands birthday and all the requests I made were fulfilled.It&apos;s nice for any occasion. We had a beautiful view of the pool and beach.The staff attentiveness was great!! &quot; Dined on 05/10/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , great for brunch , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 39 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 The chef&apos;s combination of 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/05/2012 2006 Dined on 05/05/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; The chef&apos;s combination of exotic flavors is sublime. Each bite is a symphony of flavors. &quot; Dined on 05/05/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 40 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 It&apos;s a 5 Star hotel with a 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/05/2012 2004 Dined on 05/05/2012 2004 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; It&apos;s a 5 Star hotel with a 5 Star restaurant. Last Friday was our visit visit to J&amp;G Grill. It won&apos;t be our last. Everything was just perfect - service and food were just wonderful! We could not have asked for a nicer evening. &quot; Dined on 05/05/2012 2004 Special Features: neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion , scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 41 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Brunch at J&amp;G Grill/St. Regis 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/29/2012 2008 Dined on 04/29/2012 2008 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Brunch at J&amp;G Grill/St. Regis Bal Harbour was excellent. From the surroundings to the service to the food everything was wonderful. We particularly liked the bloody marys and the wine suggestion our server Armando made was spot on. It was definitely a bright spot on what was a VERY rainy Sunday. We&apos;ll definitely be back on our next trip. &quot; Dined on 04/29/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , great for brunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 42 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Service&amp;Food are outstanding 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/25/2012 2010 Dined on 04/25/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; I really like this place, great food, great service&amp;a beautiful view overlooking the atlantic ocean. &quot; Dined on 04/25/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , special occasion , scenic view , great for lunch Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 43 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Welcome Jean George!! 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/20/2012 2006 Dined on 04/20/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; One of the best meals I have had in Miami - and I have lived here for 12 years and eat at all of the&quot;foodie&quot;restaurants. The food, similar to that of Market in Boston, is fresh and exquisite in unique and delious flavors. The service excellent and of course the hotel was fabulous. I almost felt that I was visiting an old friend...I watched the demolition of the Sheraton and put up with the traffic for what? 5 years? Anyway, I read some bad reviews and had a very different experience. I plan to return for lunch where I can get 2 courses for around $20, plus tip, tax, villiage tax? and wine. BTW, the prices of the wines by the glass were quite, quite high, however, the prices of the bottles reasonable. &quot; Dined on 04/20/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 44 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Food A+++ // Service C- 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/17/2012 2006 Dined on 04/17/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; So, the elusive J&amp;G grill. Too many service hiccups for a Jean Georges restaurant in a Starwood property.Drinks, food, wine list all great! I&apos;ve thoroughly enjoyed most of the dishes since they opened and feel the love and passion. Service hiccups cause me to leave frustrated. Charged for wrong water, drinks incorrect and never brought to table, food inaccurately described, and the icing on the cake is a new server took over at the end of the meal without a salutation. Still new: working out kinks. Go see Katie at the hotel bar. Great drinks and no hiccups there &quot; Dined on 04/17/2012 2006 Special Features: vibrant bar scene , fit for foodies , good for groups , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion , scenic view , great for lunch , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 45 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 The service from the kitchen 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/14/2012 2011 Dined on 04/14/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; The service from the kitchen was too fast . The entrées were served when we had barely finished the appetizers. Otherwise, everything was extremely good. Our server was extremely competent and polite. &quot; Dined on 04/14/2012 2011 Special Features: fit for foodies Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 46 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Fair) 2 / 5 
 For a restaurant that is supposed 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/13/2012 2009 Dined on 04/13/2012 2009 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Fair) 2 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; For a restaurant that is supposed to be top of the line and expensive, the service was poor (waiters were not professional). On top of that a 18 per cent gratuity was added to the bill even though we were a party of four Also, when we ordered grouper for our entree the waiter came back minutes later telling us they were out of itOverall, the food was pretty good but the menu is very limited. Disappointed in this restaurant . I am not sure if I&apos;ll ever go back. &quot; Dined on 04/13/2012 2009 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 47 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 While the food and service 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/14/2012 2005 Dined on 04/14/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Poor) 1 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; While the food and service were great, the noise from the&quot;background&quot;music was so loud my wife and I could not talk at the table. We were also shoved at a table back by the wait staff station. Don&apos;t expect a fine dinning atmosphere here. No table cloths, just place mats and people in shorts and sneakers. &quot; Dined on 04/14/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 48 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Not to be repeated 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/13/2012 2008 Dined on 04/13/2012 2008 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Fair) 2 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Honestly, I wouldn&apos;t return. This is one of those places where it is all about the fame the chef has, but other than that, I am not impressed. The food is good, but not outstanding, much less at the price. They charged us double for our appetizers, and then the maitre D&apos; told us our desserts had been ordered. We assumed that they would be complementary, because they didn&apos;t even asked us what we wanted. To our surprise, they were in our bill. It was a very tasty chocolate sundae with popcorn and a cheesecake(not impressive at all). &quot; Dined on 04/13/2012 2008 Special Features: notable wine list , scenic view , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 49 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Fair) 2 / 5 
 Lunch menu has been whittled 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/12/2012 2004 Dined on 04/12/2012 2004 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Lunch menu has been whittled down from opening menu with fewer choices. Salmon salad lacked adequate dressing. Service lacked efficiency&amp;zip. Didn&apos;t feel like a Jean Georges venue. &quot; Dined on 04/12/2012 2004 Special Features: scenic view Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 50 for J&amp;G Grill - St. Regis Bal Harbour Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Less than what expected. Food 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/06/2012 2012 Dined on 04/06/2012 2012 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Less than what expected. Food is good but at the end it&apos;s just one more grill &quot; Dined on 04/06/2012 2012 Special Features: notable wine list , romantic Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. 1 2 next &gt;&gt;
	</body>
</document>
