<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003230" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Michigan-City/Albanos-Villa-Restaurant" time="2012-07-12-19:21" support="1" score="0.007441319716456351" bingtitle="Albanos Villa Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant Michigan City, IN" webtitle="Albanos Villa Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant  Michigan City, IN">
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>Albanos Villa Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located ... But keep in mind that this is Havana, not New York ... atmosphere of a private villa where the homely reception ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Albanos Villa Restaurant
 
Average User Rating
 
9
 
Amazing

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(219) 872-0571

 
 IN &gt; Michigan City &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Albanos Villa Restaurant listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Albanos Villa Restaurant to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Albanos Villa Restaurant
 Albanos Villa Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1612 Franklin St in Michigan City, IN . Albanos Villa Restaurant has been described as an Amazing Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 9 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Take Out, Pizza Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Albanos Villa Restaurant
 
 
 
All Reviews for Albanos Villa Restaurant

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
9
 
Decor
 
9
 
Service
 
9
 
As my friend put it who is originally from California. There is NO place in the country that has better taco pizza.
 
Overall Rating
 
9
 
&quot;Amazing&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Albanos Villa Restaurant:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
Albanos Villa Restaurant News
 Kuleto&apos;s and Villa Florence Celebrate 25 Years SAN FRANCISCO, CA — JRK Hotel Group is proud to celebrate the 25th anniversary of Kuleto&apos;s restaurant at their San Francisco ... the Roger Williams New York, the Villa Florence San Francisco, and the largest Holiday Inn Express in the nation ... Haute Living Announces Launch of Restaurant Madness—an Interactive, Voter-driven Competition to Choose the Best Restaurants in Miami The five-week tournament will begin Mar. 22 with a list of the 32 best restaurants in New York, Miami, Los Angeles ... Il Mulino, Meat Market, The Villa Mayfair, Carpaccio, Villa Azur, Michy’s, Bianca, Zuma, Macaluso’s, Prime Italian, 1500 Degrees ... Private Restaurants Try to Expand Cuba’s Menu Decades of Communist rule have produced a host of state-run restaurants where, all too often ... But keep in mind that this is Havana, not New York: the paladar scene is limited and relies on a client base of expats, tourists and the few ... Villa Ducale, Taormina, Sicily: Where to stay The owners have recreated the atmosphere of a private villa where the homely reception area resembles ... and a large choice of restaurants and cafés. Enjoy a Plentiful Easter Buffet With Fine Dining in Tampa Located within the Renaissance Tampa International Plaza Hotel, Pelagia Trattoria is one of the finest Italian restaurants in Tampa and uses ... Guests can also choose from Pelagia-style Panini, New York strip, grilled salmon with caper dill ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing NINJA NEW YORK Restaurant, Finest Japanese Cuisine Ninja New York, ninjanewyork, High-end Japanese Cuisine, Ninja Style Restaurant, TriBeCa, New York City Christopher&apos;s Restaurant and Country Lodge - Oneonta, New York Christophers Lodging and Restaurant, Oneonta, NY - Classic Adirondack style lodging and cuisine. La Villa Pizzeria&amp;Restaurant - Howard Beach - New York Magazine ... From a fleet of ovens comes a dizzying array of golden-crusted pizzas and focaccia at this friendly family restaurant. See the review of this Italian restaurant at 82 ... Sevilla - Spanish Restaurant Greenwich Village New York, NY 10003 Sevilla a Spanish restaurant with a location at 62 Charles St in New York, NY. Enjoy Spanish menu in New York and coupons of Sevilla and directions to Sevilla. Villa Pacri - Meatpacking District - New York Magazine Restaurant ... Five French partners and two Italian chefs all housed together in one meatpacking-district space. See the review of this French restaurant at 55 Gansevoort St. in ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 89° 
Fri
 
 72° - 90° 
Sat
 
 73° - 90° 
Sun
 
 72° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Albanos Villa Restaurant

1612 Franklin St

Michigan City, IN 
 

 
Telephone
 (219) 872-0571 
Albanos Villa Restaurant
 
 Rating :  9 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Albanos Villa Restaurant Photos
 
 Fast Food Take Out Pizza 
 
 Local Places
 
 M&amp;M Restaurant Open 7 Days A Week 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Peking Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Carlsons Drive in 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Albanos Villa Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Buffalo Wild Wings 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Rallys Hamburgers 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pumps on 12 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Oriental Pearl 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Michigan City Historical Society 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Lubeznik Ctr for the Arts 
Cuisine: Art School Great Lakes Museum of Military 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries John G Blank Center for the Arts 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Prince Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Michigan City Art Museums Galleries 
See all Michigan City Art School 
See all Michigan City ATMs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Albanos Villa Restaurant Coupons 

 Albanos Villa Restaurant Michigan City 

 Albanos Villa Restaurant Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Michigan City Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | W | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
