<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003704" url="http://www.wzzm13.com/news/article/177979/2/More-restaurants-accepting-food-stamps" time="2012-07-12-19:51" support="1" score="0.0017239559143536279" bingtitle="More restaurants accepting food stamps | wzzm13.com" webtitle="More restaurants accepting food stamps | wzzm13.com">
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>(USA TODAY) - The number of businesses approved to accept food stamps grew by a ... Now, restaurants, which typically have not participated in the program, are lobbying for ...</description>
	<body>
		Gas Prices Send it DealChicken Events 
 
 Home News 
 
 
 13 On Your Side Education Grand Rapids Metro Lakeshore Lottery Money Morning Show Super Saver The Job Hunt Try It Before You Buy It Made In Michigan Watercooler 
 
Latest Headlines
 
 Report: Penn St. officials concealed abuse 

&quot;The most powerful men at Penn State failed to take any steps for 14 years to ...
 
 Man charged for making dog and raccoon fight 

Investigators say David Pennell posted the video in May. It&apos;s still on his ...
 
 Car crashes onto boat in Spring Lake 

Authorities in Spring Lake says a woman drove her car off a dock and crashed ...
 
 
 Weather 
 
 
 13 Weatherball 7 Day Forecast Closings Forecast Lake Michigan Water Temps Forecast In Spanish iControl Radar Live Radar My Weather Satellite Radar Weather Station 
 
 
 Health 
 
 
 Allergy Report Beat the Odds Breast Cancer Resources Cold - Flu Season The Cutting Edge Get Fit Health Care Reform Healthy You Healthy Heart Just Ask Live Healthy One More - MI Blood 
 
Latest Headlines
 
 Opana abuse in USA overtakes OxyContin 

&quot;It&apos;s almost like a game of Whac-A-Mole. You get a handle on OxyContin; they ...
 
 Study reveals top reasons for soldier suicides 

&quot;This really is the first study that provides scientific data saying that the ...
 
 New heart screening can save infant lives 

Mercy Health in Muskegon has started a new program that screens every newborn ...
 
 
 Take 5 
 
 
 About Book Club Facebook - Take Five&amp;Co Giveaways Help! How Do I? Links Twitter - Take Five&amp;Co 
 
Latest Headlines
 
 Terra Trike 

See what the Terra Trike is all about.
 
 National Blueberry Month 

See how almonds and blueberries go together.
 
 National Baby Food Festival 

Learn about this year&apos;s National Baby Food Festival in Fremont.
 
 
 Sports 
 
 
 HighSchoolSports.net 13 On Your Sidelines Scholar Athlete Scholar Athlete Form Golf Hunting MLB Detroit Tigers Baseball NASCAR Spring Training NBA NCAA 
 
Latest Headlines
 
 Freeh findings point finger at Paterno and others 

It&apos;s not like it came as a tremendous shock to anyone who has followed the ...
 
 MHSAA welcomes Muskegon Hts. charter school 

High school student-athletes will still be able to compete for state ...
 
 Giants-led Senior Circuit blanks AL 

The National League, sparked by a trio of San Francisco Giants and exceptional ...
 
 
 Features 
 
 
 Community Calendar Contests E-Block Greenthumb Hot Kroc Summer Mobile Apps My Favorite Teacher Pets&amp;Animals The Search for Deanie Recipes What&apos;s On TV Green Living 
 
 
 Video 
 
 
 ABC Program Player Live Video Must See Video Photo Galleries MDOT travel cameras Send It! Take Five Video WZZM Promos Salutes WX Chaser Video 
 
 
 
 
 FEATURED: WZZM 50th Election High School Sports 
 Search 
More restaurants accepting food stamps

10:05 AM, Sep 6, 2011  |
	</body>
</document>
