<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003413" url="http://www.experienceproject.com/stories/Am-Unemployed/1238696" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="1" score="0.0010667168959375337" bingtitle="Unemployment Is Chipping Away My Sanity... : I Am Unemployed Story ..." webtitle="Unemployment Is Chipping Away My Sanity... : I Am Unemployed Story&amp;Experience">
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>... enough money to maybe put a roof over our heads, food in our tummies... but not to also pay for my student loans and credit card ... I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant</description>
	<body>
		Stories Confessions Questions People 
 Search Post 
 Experiences Stories Confessions Questions 
 Register Sign In Username: Password: Keep me logged in I forgot my password I forgot my username Not a member? Sign up now. 
 Full Site 
 
 Relationships Family&amp;Friends Health&amp;Wellness Culture Community 

 All Relationships Affairs Broken Hearts&amp;Betrayal Crushes&amp;Obsessions Divorce First Love Intimacy LGBT Long Distance Marriage Military Romance&amp;True Love Singledom Struggles 

 All Family&amp;Friends Family Struggles Fatherhood Loss in the Family Loss of a Child Loss of a Friend Loss of a Pet Loss to Suicide Motherhood Pets Single Parenthood 

 All Health&amp;Wellness Abuse Addiction Alcoholism Beliefs Bipolar Disorder Cancer Depression Empowerment Friendship Image&amp;Weight Loneliness PTSD Personality Disorder Phobias Rape Self Harm Self Improvement Suicide Unemployment Work 

 All Culture Books Fashion Fiction Food Hobbies Jokes&amp;Riddles Movies&amp;TV Music Poetry Politics Religion Sports Tattoos&amp;Piercings Travel Writings 

 All Community EP Quizzes WTK 
 
 Stories » Jobs and Personal Finance » Career and Work » I Am Unemployed 
 
 Unemployment Is Chipping Away My Sanity... 

By: singingpilgrim 

Written on October 22nd, 2010
 I am unemployed and I feel like vomiting from the stress. I&apos;m not unemployed with unemployment checks. I&apos;ve got no income at all. I&apos;m 24 and live with my parents.

I graduated from college, moved back in, and it took me three months to find a job that paid $9/hr for 30 hours a week, but I was happy to have it. Unfortunately, then the economy got worse and as one of the newer hires I was laid off after four months of solid work. I hadn&apos;t worked long enough to even be considered for unemployment, plus I was working an office position with a research company so I was being &apos;rehired&apos; for each new project they got and so even if I had worked there longer, I&apos;d not have qualified as I was only ever a temporary worker.

I wasn&apos;t worried though, because I had some money saved for about two months cushion (which I think was pretty good for only having worked four months) and I thought I&apos;d find a job. And I did... 11 months later.

Another temporary position, helping relaunch a website. Once it was launched, the job was over. I didn&apos;t have enough time to really get my feet back under me, bill wise, before it was over, but I got about one month&apos;s cushion.

That was five months ago.

Being a burden on my parents is the worst. My mom has fibromalygia and is unemployed. Hers isn&apos;t bad enough that she couldn&apos;t work at all, but she can only work part-time, no more than two days in a row, in a sit-down position. And in this economy, she can&apos;t afford to be picky and hasn&apos;t been able to find anything, though she did work for the Census briefly this year. But the Census, in our area, had a wonderful return rate-- great for them, but meant that she had two months less work than anticipated.

My father is a manager of a grocery store and works 50 hours weeks. And yes, people do have to eat and grocery stores are still in business-- but if you&apos;re on a decreased income the first place people cut their budget is food. So they aren&apos;t doing great these past few years and with inflation, we&apos;re majorly struggling.

For a while I was applying every single day... right now I&apos;m applying like every other day because a) I&apos;m discouraged b) there seems to be less and less jobs I&apos;m qualified for. How often I apply seems cyclical. Every time I apply for a job, the anxiety makes me want to vomit, so I can only take so much.

Apply as I may, I&apos;ve only heard back from four jobs at ALL, and only gotten one interview.One the guy emailed more detailed information than in his ad and it turned out I didn&apos;t actually qualify (he wanted me to be a notary). Another, a sales position, I got to the second round but never heard from them again. Another was too far a commute for only four hours a day, five days a week that after gas money it would have only been more of a burden. And the one I interviewed for was perfect and I totally thought I got it... only to be told someone else was hired. It happens.

A friend of mine gave me a lead and told me she&apos;s close friends with the regional manager of an employment company and she&apos;d take care of me. I really thought I&apos;d get a job. But it&apos;s been more than two weeks and she hasn&apos;t even tried to contact me back.

So now I&apos;m contemplating relocation because my aunt has offered to let me stay with her. I&apos;d have to sell pretty much everything I own to try to pay for the plane ticket, and I&apos;m not sure even then I wouldn&apos;t have to borrow money from friends or family (my parents don&apos;t have it). But it might be my only option...

I don&apos;t own a car, or even have a driver&apos;s license. It wasn&apos;t suspended, I just don&apos;t have the money for car insurance. If you have a permit you don&apos;t have to pay it. With my mom unemployed I have &apos;a reliable mode of transportation&apos; (and if I got a steady job, I&apos;d get my license), but I don&apos;t have a valid driver&apos;s license. I also live in a rural area, five miles from the nearest store. I am trapped at home every day. My mother is a homebody. She&apos;s practically a hermit. She doesn&apos;t like to leave the house more than once a week and I practically have to beg to get her to take me anywhere. She only does like once or twice a month. My father is just so exhausted when he gets home it&apos;s not an option. Except for Bible Study, which I have a ride to every week, I&apos;ve only left the house twice in the last month. I&apos;m losing my mind.

The most valuable thing I own is my laptop... which broke last week. After that, I don&apos;t think I own anything that costs more than a hundred dollars. I&apos;ve only bought one shirt since my last job ended. Most of my clothes have holes or stains and I can&apos;t afford to replace them. I only have two good &apos;work&apos; outfits left that I&apos;m trying not to touch, to save for interviews and such. I feel like a hobo.

I&apos;ve basically been unemployed, trapped in my parent&apos;s home for two years. I love them. I do. And I am grateful not to be homeless, I am. But I&apos;m an adult. And I&apos;m going crazy.

I am nauseous from being a burden on my parents. My mom is going crazy from financial stress too. Our payments keep being late. We&apos;re not sure we can pay the mortgage. And I know I&apos;m a huge part of the reason. And I feel so awful, but I don&apos;t now what else to do.

The thing about being unemployed is if you have a job that stresses you out and you complain, people sympathize or at least help you appreciate what you have (&apos;at least you have a job&apos;). But if you&apos;re unemployed, and you go to even your nearest and dearest
they just give you advice lots and lots of well meaning but usually useless advice that makes you feel like you&apos;re never doing enough and you&apos;re worthless. They tell you to apply for jobs online. Well, I do. They tell you to call people back and are shocked when they learn that most places don&apos;t offer you a phone number, just a fax or email. Or tell you to go back to school. When you can&apos;t afford a candy bar, let alone a Master&apos;s degree.

I have Plantar fasciitis and I can&apos;t stand for more than 45 minutes. I can sit or walk all day long, I just can&apos;t stand. So when I tell people that, they assume I&apos;m lazy and just don&apos;t want a job that makes me stand. But I honestly can&apos;t do it. I did it in high school-- that&apos;s when I developed plantar fasciitis, working as a cashier. But when I tell someone that they think I&apos;m saying &apos;I am too high and mighty for that&apos;. They don&apos;t seem to realize that I apply for other kinds of lower paying jobs-- like retail that&apos;s not cashier, or a waitressing-- where I can walk around. But they just never ever call me back. I think it&apos;s because I do have a college degree and the employers would rather hire someone who doesn&apos;t because they&apos;re less likely to leave the job for something better.

I don&apos;t want to whine or complain. I want to be joyful. I try to do more housework. But often, this causes conflict between me and Mom, because she wants things done HER way or not at all. And I just don&apos;t think like her. I do some chores, but there&apos;s no sense of accomplishment.

It&apos;s not laziness. Actually, I enjoy getting something accomplished. Those two times this month I got out when I wasn&apos;t going to Bible Study? I went to my friend&apos;s house and cleaned and cooked and baked. She&apos;s pregnant and is having trouble doing things herself. I felt useful and productive and wonderful. It was great. I rarely get that at home.

I do art. And that&apos;s great. I feel like I&apos;m doing something... but it costs money to get supplies. I&apos;ve tried to sell it. I rented a table for $30 at an art sale the artist&apos;s community was doing. I sold two pieces... for less than $30 total. It felt great that someone bought those pieces... but when the next sale rolled around I didn&apos;t have the money to try again.

I&apos;ve not had a dollar of my own money for months. I don&apos;t go anywhere. I eat only at home. I try to network. I&apos;ve seen people, facebook friends, get leads when they say &apos;I need a job&apos;. So I&apos;ve tried that four times, spread out over time. I only got one reply, and the person told me they&apos;d heard about a job... in a city I don&apos;t live in. I said thanks but that&apos;s too far and she told me to ask for a signing bonus.

In this economy? And I&apos;d need money for not just a move, but a car, an apartment deposit... I need a job to afford to leave my parent&apos;s home. Except for going to San Diego. There I might have a chance... but how much worse would the situation be if I was living 3000 miles from my friends and family and still couldn&apos;t find a job? I might have to do it, but I can&apos;t make the decision lightly...

I have a wonderful boyfriend. In India. And he&apos;s the best thing going on in my life, aside from God. But there&apos;s also anxiety there because for one, he&apos;s leading a very different life from me. He&apos;s employed, living in a city of a million people. If he wanted to, friends want him to go out with them every night.

And I want to marry him. And he wants to marry me. Not today, but probably in a year. But in order for him to come over on a fiance visa, I need to have a job (and have tax records to prove it, so need it for at least a year) that can support not only me, but him as well. If I don&apos;t find a GOOD paying job soon (like by the end of January, probably) this just isn&apos;t going to happen. If we want to marry in a year, I&apos;ll have to move to India. And unfortunately, I have to live over there without legally able to work for at least a year if I do that. Here, he&apos;d be able to work in about three months of paperwork, possibly sooner. But there, it&apos;d be a minimum of a least a year. And the thing is, he makes just enough money to maybe put a roof over our heads, food in our tummies... but not to also pay for my student loans and credit card debt (from buying books and other living supplies during college-- I&apos;ve not bought anything on credit since before I graduated). If I worked a full time job there, it&apos;d cover it.. just.

I&apos;m sorry to write something so long winded. But I just felt like I was going to explode tonight. And I typed &apos;I am unemployed&apos; into google and found this sight.

I am loading up things to give away today. Nothing big. Books of poetry I never read. Old textbooks that are too outdated to sell to current students, and I never look at. A pair of ridiculously high stilettos I&apos;ve only worn a couple times. I am trying to cleanse my life now. It&apos;ll make it easier to move if I go to San Diego, for one... And if not, then at least that&apos;s one less thing sitting around the house all day. Maybe I can live vicariously through it. By: singingpilgrim Age: 22-25 , 
 
 Vote up! 1 
 | Favorite | Flag | Subscribe 
 
Please Respond to Story with authenticity, support, and respect 
 Sort By: recent oldest mvotes 
 I feel your pain.. and I am older than you and in a not so hot situation. I am 28 (an Australian women) and have just &quot;gasp&quot; LEFT my job (without being fired or made redundant) because my health broke down so badly (for the second time) that I couldn&apos;t work anymore (severe multiple infections, open sores, my face swelled up, I was having circulatory and breathing issues- and concurrently was suicidal.. you can imagine why) basically a total immune system shutdown (the same thing had happened only half a year before, but the first time I recovered slightly and went back for more because how else am I to pay the mortgage) this time I can&apos;t go back for more. I can tell you, for those left in the jobs when people are not being hired, or replaced, and being fired or made redundant- for the suckers left in the actual jobs- we are doing the work of many many people (between 3-12) for example our workplace is supposed to have 12 ppl, many days there will be 3, 4 or 5 of us for weeks and weeks and they promise they will hire (and don&apos;t) AND then KICK our butts, strangle us psychologically because their profits and stats are dropping (NO **** YOU DIDN&quot;T HIRE ENOUGH PPL TO DO THIS ****- AND EVERYONE WHO WORKS FOR YOU IS SICK AND BURNT OUT), burning out and having our health destroyed.. it&apos;s two months later and I still have a chronic respiratory infection, but the sores, the swelling and the circulatory stuff have all settled down. Now I just have mind numbing depression coupled with weight gain due to depression. I am 28 years old and happily married. We have been struggling for a full 10 years as it is- as students (my hubby did a PhD and I did two degrees) and were hoping this would be a time of prosperity for us..and a home (finally after 10 years of sharehouses and 10 different rentals) and children (we can&apos;t afford) instead my health and my general spirit are completely broken- at this point I am so screwed up that I would rather freeze/starve to death than work for somebody else again after almost dying (either through suicide or a transitory embolism during which I genuinely thought I was going to die, but came through it) so a company can make some extra bucks on the stock market. I have worked since I was 15 years old, went to university, and did all the &quot;right&quot; things.. and still here I am. I have at this point completely withdrawn socially, because I am too depressed to be around people anymore. Also we are living in a state that is fricking freezing cold- which doesn&apos;t help depression- I would love to get the hell out of here except we moved here for my husband&apos;s job which is the only thing keeping this boat afloat at all at the moment. So unemployed, stuck in a freezing miserable geographic locale, socially isolated and gaining weight due to severe depression FUN TIMES mjcam3 3 days
 ago 1 reply 

 I&apos;m 24, can&apos;t find a job in this economy, and live in my dad&apos;s dining room. I have a car, but it&apos;s 28 years old, and it has a few problems, so I&apos;m afraid to really drive it, and only use it when I really need it. The battery is dead, the tires are old, cracked, and balding, it burns oil, etc. I&apos;m also hopelessly single, and can&apos;t seem to find a girlfriend either. I have about 6 different profiles on free dating sites, but I just get ignored and rejected. I used to go out more to try and meet people, but it seems to be a hopeless cause. I&apos;m intelligent, creative, interesting, fun, good at conversation, (my friends and family agree) but girls don&apos;t want to hang out with me or date me. I&apos;m lonely and depressed everyday. I stay up all night and sleep all day. I&apos;ve lost self-control and motivation. I overeat and get fat, then starve myself to lose weight again. I stopped going out, because I have nobody to hang out with, and I get even more depressed, wandering around alone, and seeing happy couples holding hands and kissing everywhere, except me. I tried getting a job for over two years, and even though I can build and fix computers, I didn&apos;t even get called back by McDonald&apos;s. Stupid people who don&apos;t know that we&apos;re in a ******* recession, try telling me I&apos;m not trying hard enough. I hate that. I have a list of places I applied at, that&apos;s about 4 pages long. I just can&apos;t seem to get ahead in life, no matter what I do. My fear is that I&apos;m going to be 25... 26... 30... 35... 45... and still be single and living in my dad&apos;s dining room... still having to wait until 3am to jerk off to pictures of girls who don&apos;t want anything to do with me. Sometimes I get really depressed and lash out at innocent people, then feel bad about it later. I can do a pretty good job of getting my mood back up, but I&apos;m still lonely and frustrated with life. EnergyShift a while
 ago 1 reply 

 Let me tell you, you are not alone. I am 30, have 2 master degrees and have been unemployed for 15 months now. I live with my parents and I do not get any unemployment benefits, on top of that I am struggling to pay my loans from grad school with my job as a waitress.

I apply for jobs every day. I do not know what is going on. It seems there are jobs that I am qualified for, but no one calls me back. I did also apply for numerous government jobs and part time jobs, nothing. There are times that I want to give up, but hope never dies. I keep trying. What else can i do...?????? I am stressed, desperate, and sad, but I keep applying, because I know, that is the only way I will get a job. These are challenging times for me, and I know I am doing my best.

I am prepared to give tests to prove my qualifications, i am willing to work 14 hours every day seven days a week just to have a job and feel normal. The true and sad part of this story is that I am no longer looking for &quot;The Job&quot;, but I am looking for “a job”

I wish all of you that are in my shoes, Good Luck and never give up, not even for a moment!!!!!. lolak39 a while
 ago 2 reply 

 Is your boyfriend from Kerala? How did you meet him? Your story is beautiful and honest and I think if you keep trying you will succeed. But, I think you should be aware that your boyfriend might be an additional burden on you. I had one. It&apos;s true, they have much better lives and friends. But be careful. Take care of yourself first! seekerforlife a while
 ago 2 reply 

 This is the way it is now. Good on ya for batteling on but get used to unemployment. An EP User a while
 ago 2 reply 

 
 
 I Am Unemployed 

 Me Too 
 
 242 Stories About this Experience Unemployed, Lonely And Scared To Death! 2,130 Views Getting A Bit Frustrated.... 1,122 Views Unemployed But $25 Changed My Situation 632 Views Scared 451 Views (5 of 242 Stories) See All 
 
Baseball season is here! What&apos;s your favorite ballpark memory?
 I have a many of great ballpark memories. Taking my son to his very 1st MLB gam... [ more ] Going to Fenway with my Dad in 1967 It was great. Red Sox fan forever.... [ more ] In 1984, the Tigers had their greatest season ever, and I believe were the first... [ more ] 

 Answer Question 
 Related Groups 

 See All 

 
 I &apos;m Not Sure What Day It Is Anymore 
 Members: 42 Stories: 3 
 I Want to Play More and Work Less. 
 Members: 176 Stories: 7 
 I Work In Mental Health 
 Members: 21 Stories: 8 
 I Definitely Chose the Wrong Career 
 Members: 25 Stories: 9 
 Search over 13 million life experiences and stories From the experience archive: I Love Badass Women , It Soothes My Mind All Stories Groups Answers Blogs Confessions 
 Full Site 
 Share 
This is your place to share the experiences that matter most to you.
 
 Experience&amp;Support Groups 
 Stories / People 
 Confessions / Challenges 
 Answers / Blogs 
 Dream Interpretations 
 Invite Friends 
 Explore 
From pets to cancer support, EP has something for everyone.
 
 Life / Education / Entertainment 
 Food + Drink / Friends + Family 
 Health / Recreation / Careers + Money 
 Pets / Current Events 
 Relationships + Romance / Religion 

 Search or Browse Stories 
 Play 
Relax and have some fun—check out these fun features:
 
 Causes / Petitions 
 Trending Topics 
 Free Online Games 
 Name Meanings / Song Meanings 
 Greeting Cards / Dictionary 
 Topics / BroadCause 
 About 
Experience Project is the largest living collection of shared experiences.
 
 Help + FAQs / Suggestions 
 About Us / Our Blog 
 Advertise / Contact 
 Press / Company Info 
 
 Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Sitemap 

Site contents©Experience Project, Inc. 2004 - 2012. All Rights Reserved. Unauthorized reproduction is strictly forbidden.
	</body>
</document>
