<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003778" url="http://www.post-gazette.com/neigh_washington/20010701wacover2.asp" time="2012-07-12-19:56" support="1" score="0.00027726018369611023" bingtitle="The frank facts - Post-Gazette.com" webtitle="The frank facts">
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>... hours, passers-by can watch the cook slather condiments ... added a nook, about 12 feet by 14 feet, to seat ... I think if a fast-food restaurant were to open next door, people ...</description>
	<body>
		The frank facts 
 A review of hot dog history and the shops that relish in winning wiener legacies 
Sunday, July 01, 2001
By Deborah Shankovich 






Life holds many mysteries: The Bermuda Triangle. The building of the Egyptian pyramids. The difficulty men and women have communicating.
And ranking high on this list is this well-grilled question: What is behind America&apos;s love affair with the hot dog? After all, who knows what&apos;s really in a hot dog that packs 150 calories and jumps to 328 calories, 18 grams of fat and 1,050 milligrams of sodium with a bun, chili, onions, relish and mustard?
Americans apparently don&apos;t care what&apos;s in them. In 2000, Americans ate 20 billion hot dogs that, if placed end to end, would encircle the Earth at the equator 63 times.
And the nation is poised to eat 150 million hot dogs during the Fourth of July weekend, according to the National Hot Dog and Sausage Council, based in Washington, D.C. In fact, the council estimates Americans will consume more than 2 billion hot dogs this month, which has been proclaimed National Hot Dog Month.
Many events are planned in celebration of the venerable treat. A hot dog lunch will be served July 4 on Capitol Hill, and a hot dog festival is scheduled in the appropriate location of Frankfort, Ind. Contests also are under way to determine the top 10 hot-dog-consuming cities. Information is available through the council&apos;s Web site at http://www.hot-dog.org .
With that in mind, the council set out to learn something frank about the &quot;furter.&quot;
One theory is that the hot dog got its name from a cartoonist who drew a picture of barking dachshunds between buns and labeled them &quot;hot dogs&quot; because he couldn&apos;t spell dachshund. However, investigators from institutions as esteemed as the Smithsonian were unable to find the cartoon.
Another theory is that buns were popularized when a vendor, who couldn&apos;t collect all the white gloves he lent to customers to hold the steaming sausages, implored a local baker to design a roll to hold his hot &quot;dachshund&quot; dogs.
Hot dog historian and Roosevelt University Professor Emeritus Bruce Kraig said while these situations may have happened, the hot dog actually was brought to America by German immigrants.
Whether they were called wieners, hot dogs, sausages, dogs on a stick, brats or frankfurters, Americans relished them, and by the 1920s, they became the food of choice at ball games, fairs, horse races and circuses.
Perhaps Rick Sebak summed up America&apos;s feeling towards this culinary delight: &quot;They just plain taste good!&quot;
Sebak, who wrote and produced the WQED special &quot;A Hot Dog&quot; said he traveled through many states tasting hot dogs to make the show.
&quot;I think one of the reasons we are so intrigued by hot dog shops has to do with the fact they are still individually owned, and they are able to retain their own distinct personalities,&quot; he said. &quot;At a time when everything is getting more alike, something about that individuality appeals deep in our soul.&quot;
Many places still offer natural casing wieners. &quot;I&apos;ve tasted a lot of hot dogs, and those are my personal favorite,&quot; Sebak said.
Washington County has distinct hot dog havens -- Shorty&apos;s Lunch on West Chestnut Street in Washington and the Washington Mall in South Strabane, and Bert&apos;s Hot Dog Shop on Route 18 in the village of Slovan in Smith.
But before visiting those classic hot dog diners, it might help first to understand the hot dog itself.
The best place to learn is Green Valley Packing Inc.
On Route 221 in Buffalo, Green Valley Packing makes Albert&apos;s Franks and produces hot dogs for Bert&apos;s and Shorty&apos;s. Company President George P. Weiss said Albert&apos;s Franks, named for his grandfather -- Albert, not Frank -- who started the business in the 1920s, are made from a quality blend of beef, pork and spices. What they don&apos;t include is extenders -- soy protein, corn syrup solids or milk powder many competitors use. He recommends customers check labels.
&quot;We use wholesome quality meat -- the same meat used in ground meats,&quot; he said. To counter misperceptions about ingredients, Weiss said steak isn&apos;t used because of cost but also because steak and prime cuts have too much fat.
&quot;The government set the maximum at 30 percent fat, but we run 24 percent fat,&quot; he said. &quot;You season for taste, and in different areas, the seasoning is different. We make a mild hot dog. We don&apos;t like to cover up the flavor of the meat with spices.&quot;
The packing house employs 65 and is the only hot dog maker in Washington County. It also produces sausages, kielbasas and other meat products.
&quot;We strictly make quality,&quot; he said. &quot;We are not a &apos;me-too&apos; hot dog.&quot;
For proof, consider Shorty&apos;s. Customers at the original Shorty&apos;s Lunch in Washington that uses a special recipe of Albert&apos;s Franks claim a Shorty&apos;s hot dog is a treat for the palate and the psyche.
&quot;This place is definitely good for the soul,&quot; said Jess Sumney, a Washington resident who&apos;s been a Shorty&apos;s customer since 1952. &quot;It&apos;s cozy and inviting, and like the television show &apos;Cheers,&apos; everybody knows your name.
&quot;Back when I was in Vietnam, most everybody couldn&apos;t wait to get home and have a cold glass of milk,&quot; he said. &quot;I couldn&apos;t wait to eat a Shorty&apos;s hot dog.&quot;
Sumney&apos;s wife, Vicky, said going to Shorty&apos;s is in her genes: &quot;My granddad and my dad ate here. They brought me, and now I bring my kids. It&apos;s like a tradition with us,&quot; she said.
Upon entering Shorty&apos;s, one gets the feeling of stepping back in time. A red and white neon sign proclaims Shorty&apos;s has been a treat for more than 50 years. The brown linoleum floor is the original one installed in the 1930s, and the steel grill placed in the large front window is the one that stood there when the doors first opened.
During busy lunch hours, passers-by can watch the cook slather condiments on as many as 10 hot dogs lined neatly up his arm. The dining and counter areas are made of dark, old-fashioned wood and stainless steel. The eight high-backed booths, featuring large oval vanity mirrors, are another reflection to bygone days. The waitress brings the order on heavy green and white plates, reminiscent of grandma&apos;s era.
Shorty&apos;s owner, George Alexis, grandson of the original Shorty -- 5-foot, 4-inch Pete Alexis -- said little has changed in the restaurant since it opened.
&quot;The customers want it that way,&quot; he said.
He recently installed air conditioning for customer comfort; the top of the old grill was replaced years ago; and prices have gone up, but not by much. The most expensive item on the menu is $3.25. Customers agreed these were necessary updates but have asked Alexis not to remodel.
&quot;In this day and age with all the new modern restaurants, fast-food places, video games and piped-in music wherever you go, it&apos;s so nice to come into a place like this and unwind,&quot; Sumney said. &quot;I&apos;m of the opinion that if it ain&apos;t broke, don&apos;t fix it.&quot;
The hot dogs are so good that many said they have tried unsuccessfully to cook up the same results at home. &quot;These can&apos;t be duplicated. I know, I&apos;ve tried,&quot; Sumney said. &quot;I&apos;ve even bought their own sauce, but it&apos;s not the same.&quot;
Over the years, Shorty&apos;s has become a Washington landmark. It has been featured in books, magazines and newspapers and on television. Alexis said his sauce has been sold to people from every state, Saudi Arabia, Germany, England, France, Vietnam and Canada. Shorty&apos;s also sells ball caps and T-shirts. T
he staff says they serve everybody from the unemployed to judges, and they estimate about 800 customers pass through their doors every day.
Elizabeth Reis, who used to own an antique and craft shop next to Shorty&apos;s, said she chose the location for that reason.
&quot;Our advertising campaign used to include Shorty&apos;s. It said, &apos;Stop in and browse. We&apos;re located next to the busiest restaurant in town,&apos; &quot; she said.
But Shorty&apos;s isn&apos;t the only hot dog salon in the county.
Helen Bertolotti, or Bert as she is known, rests her tired legs on milk crates in the tiny oblong kitchen of Bert&apos;s Hot Dog Shop on Route 18 in Slovan. It was 5 p.m., and she&apos;d been cooking and taking orders since opening for coffee and doughnuts at 7 a.m.
&quot;Before we had a picnic table outside, customers used to line these crates up outside and use them as stools,&quot; the 66-year-old Bertolotti said in a voice gone hoarse from chain smoking and laughter. &quot;It must have been a sight, because people were always stopping by to investigate.&quot;
Bert&apos;s opened in 1948, and Bertolotti has been operating the shop with help from family members since her husband&apos;s death in 1981.
&quot;My husbands stepfather, Mario Funari, was partially paralyzed and couldn&apos;t find a job anywhere,&quot; Bertolotti said, &quot;His mother, Ida, suggested he try the local gas station. He got hired immediately.&quot;
But Bert said Funari got tired of eating cold sandwiches for lunch, so his mother packed him a hot plate to cook hot dogs and hamburgers. Soon, other service-station employees wanted Funari to cook for them, and the smell of food drew gas station customers.
&quot;My father-in-law couldn&apos;t keep up with the demand for hot food, so he quit the gas station and put up a temporary shed, you know, the kind you see at construction sites, and he cooked in it. It was never supposed to be permanent, but here it is, still standing 53 years later,&quot; Bertolotti said.
The featured food at Bert&apos;s is the foot-long hot dog complete with a secret sauce passed down from Mario Funari&apos;s original recipe. At customers&apos; requests, Bertolotti has increased the menu to include salads, chili, chicken, shrimp and ham barbecue. She also has added a nook, about 12 feet by 14 feet, to seat customers.
&quot;I couldn&apos;t use milk crates forever,&quot; she said.
Like the customers at Shorty&apos;s, patrons at Bert&apos;s resist change. Bertolotti said occasionally someone will tell her she should expand. &quot;I tell them that if I get any more customers, I&apos;d have to give them an apron and have them cook their own food.&quot;
A lot of people have speculated on the success of the little hot dog shop, but perhaps Andy Wrubleski of Washington sums it up best.
&quot;I&apos;ve been coming here in the summer months for five years, and it&apos;s like no place I&apos;ve ever eaten before,&quot; he said. &quot;Bert is friendly. She remembers people. She seems to have her finger on the pulse of this community. I think if a fast-food restaurant were to open next door, people would still come to Bert&apos;s.&quot;
&quot;It&apos;s hard to believe that this much business started with one hot plate,&quot; Bertolotti said. &quot;Who knew?&quot;
 Deborah Shankovich is a free-lance writer. Staff writer David Templeton contributed to this report. 



 
 Take me to... PG News ---- Nation&amp;World ---- Local News ---- Obituaries ---- Neighborhoods ---- Business&amp;Technology ---- Sports ---- Health&amp;Science ---- Arts&amp;Entertainment ---- Lifestyle ---- Opinion Special Reports Photo Journal AP Wire Sports ---- Steelers ---- Pirates ---- Penguins ---- University of Pittsburgh ---- Penn State University ---- Collegiate Sports ---- High School Sports ---- Golf Classifieds ---- Announcements ---- Business Opportunities ---- Business Services ---- Cars ---- Celebrations ---- Consumer Rates ---- Farm&amp;Lawn ---- Great Outdoors ---- Hobbies ---- Jobs ---- Legal Notices ---- Legal Services ---- Merchandise ---- Mortgage Rates ---- Classified Obituaries ---- Personals ---- Pets ---- Real Estate Rentals -------- Pittsburgh Apartments ---- Real Estate Sales ---- Commercial Real Estate ---- Travel Getaways ---- Place an Ad Weather PG Store PG Delivery About the Post-Gazette Contact Us Search Site Map Help Corrections/Clarifications Copyright and Terms of Use 
 Terms of Use    Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
