<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003375" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090101182802AAR94XB" time="2012-07-12-19:31" support="1" score="0.0017697603192350644" bingtitle="What should I name my restaurant? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="What should I name my restaurant? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>It will be a casual place, order and pick up at counter... serving regular ... When was the last time you ate at a fast food restaurant? How many people think a ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Other - Dining Out &gt; Resolved Question 
 Hypnotic Hannah Member since: December 19, 2008 Total points: 1,178 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What should I name my restaurant?
 It will be a casual place, order and pick up at counter... serving regular soups and salads and all the entrees will change seasonally and weekly. In a small town, in a new development.

I&apos;m trying to think of something cute and clever... the kind of name that has you saying&quot;honey can you pick up _______ after work?&quot;But not too cute like&quot;Yummies&quot;which is one that I was tossing around! Got any ideas? Thank you! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 &quot;Mommy, Mommy, I want Krusty Krabs&quot;roflmao. 
 4 years ago 
 by Music Man Member since: March 02, 2006 Total points: 156,176 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 Creekwood Cafe 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Wow! I had a hard time choosing best answer because there were so many good ideas! I really liked seasons and I also liked the advice to go with a family name and not be too corney.. but this one is perfect because it totally goes with the town and it&apos;s really charming. Thank you so much! 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (11)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by annie Member since: December 02, 2007 Total points: 604 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Souper Square ( square because Soup Salad,,,Souper as in super and soup)

Salads, Soups and So much more....( alliteration)
or
Salads,Soups, and what more

Salad Stop

Soup Shack

One Stop DInner Shop

i hope you like them.....VOTE FOR BEST ANSWER..Please 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by tjb2676 Member since: July 05, 2006 Total points: 848 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 use either your mom or your Grandmother&apos;s middle name. in a small town where small town values may exist, they may respect and appreciate an actual name opposed to some corny catch phrase. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Reno Member since: August 12, 2007 Total points: 492 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The Krusty Krab.

lmao jplay


why don&apos;t you name it something that no knows about yourself, but at the same time something that is fun and unique 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Jordan B Member since: November 15, 2008 Total points: 178 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 u should name it after an important location or monument in ur city and put grand in front of it. Trust me it works 
Source(s):
 i r edjmacated 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by G*G* Member since: March 23, 2006 Total points: 13,146 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 &quot;Why Cook?&quot;I always thought that would be a cute name for a quick fast&amp;easy restaurant! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by lostintr... Member since: November 04, 2008 Total points: 1,377 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 &quot;what&apos;s for dinner?&quot;
&quot;hole in the wall restaurant&quot;
&quot;diamond in the grub&quot; 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Akmal Member since: November 20, 2008 Total points: 610 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The Old Times 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Dinkles Member since: May 10, 2008 Total points: 4,096 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No Soup For You 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Emily B Member since: December 25, 2008 Total points: 54 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I would call it&quot;time out&quot; 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by lizzi Member since: December 30, 2008 Total points: 46 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Seasons =]

haha
Krusty Krab. lol 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by mike c Member since: April 18, 2008 Total points: 2,800 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Hannahs House, hows that? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Dining Out 

 Why do I get food poisoning from fast food places? My boss serves up old out of date food , what to do ? What do you usually get at Panera? Where to buy good cheesecake thats NOT from Cheesecake Factory? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 What are some creative names for a 5 star Restaurant? what should i call my restaurant? What should I call my restaurant? I&apos;m preparing to open a restaurant, but I can&apos;t think… What are some memorable Restaurant names you have seen or… 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 sassygirl 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
