<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003141" url="http://fastfoodies.org/food-pornography/" time="2012-07-12-19:16" support="2" score="0.0021694723500405013" bingtitle="Food Pornography | Fast Foodies Fast Food Blog | A Fast Food Blog ..." webtitle="Food Pornography | Fast Foodies Fast Food Blog | A Fast Food Blog for Fast Foodies">
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="76"/>
	<description>You forgot to pay your cable bill this month and ... Related posts: Portrait of Charlie Sheen as a Fast Food Restaurant ... fil-a chicken nuggets chipotle combo creations condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Articles Comments 
 Fast Foodies Fast Food Blog | A Fast Food Blog for Fast Foodies 
 Home About This Is Why You’re Fat Contact Write for us! 
 
 Fast Foodies Fast Food Blog | A Fast Food Blog for Fast Foodies » Uncategorized » Food Pornography 
 
 Food Pornography 

March 19th, 2011 | 1 Comment 
 
It’s 3am on a Friday night. You’ve stumbled home from a long night of friends, drinks, and scrounging the bottom of your purse for change to bum cigarettes. With a Bushwick Pita Palace burrito in your hand and your third wind rising, going to bed is out of the question. Turning on the television (because apparently it’s 1992 and you only have dial-up), you settle in for a late night“personal massage”with the Spice Channel.

But blast! You forgot to pay your cable bill this month and all the Spice Channel is serving is scrambled titties without even a dash of hot sauce. Never fear! For a no-monthly fee, you can see all the close-angled, slathered baby backs you desire. Mute the volume on Everybody Loves Raymond (gotta preserve that boner), wait for the advertisements, and then…ohhhhh yeahhhhh.

That’s right: commercials for higher-end restaurant chains like Chili’s, Outback Steakhouse and TGI Friday’s—and even some bootleg franchises like Long John Silver’s and Arby’s—don’t just celebrate their product—they exploit it. They get all up in it. Work it, tenderloin steak. Work it. 

From my extensive one-handed research of food commercials on Youtube, I’ve determined there’s three main techniques to creating a successful food porn commercial. For amateurs to the industry, here’s some tips:

 The“Close-Angle”Shot 

Commercials like this should be prefaced by a disclaimer: Do not get this close to food without adult supervision, safety goggles, and an eyewash station in the vicinity. That burger being slowly, seductively crushed by a spatula is not surrounded by little beads of desire—that’s boiling grease, going into your eye.

 


But Daddy, you did say you liked it hot, mmmmmmm?

 


 The Caress 

That chicken breast? Not slick enough. That rack of ribs? Not wet enough. Bust out your grill brush, and get it wet, baby.

 


Ooo, Daddy. Can you do a wave pattern for me?

 


 The Cumshot/Flying Food
 

In seafood commercials (Red Lobster, Long John Silver’s), the cumshot arrives in the form of splashed butter/squeezed lemon. Yes? Yes. Yes. 

 


But so many other commercials reach climax by food tumbling from the heavens right onto your plate. Spices fly—sauce splatters—it gets nice and dirty. 

 


It’s kind of like a teenage boy’s fantasy of a naked woman falling from the sky right onto his manhood. This fantasy and the flying food commercial share the same oversight if converted to real life: the crippling pain that would ensue if said naked woman/food is aimed badly.

 


But the similarity between porn and food commercials goes beyond the videos. Sure, the men and women of porn look desirable on camera, but if you caught them on a day without makeup, under fluorescent lighting, the toll from years of disillusionment, meth, and sexual disease will prevent you from asking him or her out on a date. So too with the food of commercials, versus the food encountered in real life. 

Besides, I think we all know who we really want to see standing at the end of the aisle:

 

Related posts:

 Portrait of Charlie Sheen as a Fast Food Restaurant 
 
 
 
 Written by Mary 


 
 Visit Mary&apos;s Website 
 
Filed under: Uncategorized ·Tags: arby&apos;s , chili&apos;s , commercials , food porn , food pornography , outback steakhouse , red lobster 
 
One Response to&quot;Food Pornography&quot;
 
 Taste Test: Subway&apos;s Pulled Pork | Fast Foodies Fast Food Blog | A Fast Food Blog for Fast Foodies says: July 14, 2011 at 11:02 am 
[...] sandwich be prepared is like the low-rent version of a TGIFriday’s commercial—messy, oddly pornographic, and 100% [...]
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * (will not be published)

 Website 

 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 thefastfoodies 

 

 Notify me of follow-up comments by email. 

 Notify me of new posts by email. 
 
Follow Us!
 
Latest

 Why Taco Bell Tastes Better on Friday R.I.P. Pink Slime: Abhorrent Moment in History–2012 Stacey Irvine: A Fast Foodies Non-Hero Fast Food to Deliver, All Your Dreams to Come True Midwestern Import: Steak‘n Shake 
 
 
Categories

 Battle of the Brands Breaking News Combo Creations Courting the Food Court Fast Food Fast Food Mascot Bios Fast Food News Fast Food That Sucks Ass Fryday Paula Deen Restaurant Review Secular Holidays Slow Food for Fast Foodies Thirsty Thursday Tuesdays with Salad Uncategorized Vlog Was It Worth It 
 
Blogroll

 Al Dente Blog Brand Eating Brokelyn Burger Bedlam Dude Foods Eater Fancy Fast Food Fast Food Fever Fast Food Maven Fat Guy Food Blog Food Junk Foodette Reviews Foodista Goodburger Blog Grub Grade I Heart Brunch Kentucky Fried Bloggin&apos; Lies About My Friends Me So Hungry Not This American Life Phoood Slow Down&amp;Savor So Good Blog Street Carnage Tales of Two Shitties Tampa Bay Food Monster The Headless Society The Mandy/Ebert Project The Mighty Rib The White Cube This Is Why You&apos;re Fat Top Ten Dishes 
 
 
Recent Comments

 YourMama on Fast Food That Sucks Ass #3: Rice nateBleakHaus on R.I.P. Pink Slime: Abhorrent Moment in History–2012 Dawn on Tuesdays with Salad: Wendy’s Baja Salad Tymon on Taste Test: Taco Bell’s XXL Grilled Stuft Burrito ALLISON on R.I.P. Pink Slime: Abhorrent Moment in History–2012 
 
Tags
 america arby&apos;s bo*jangles brooklyn burger king chick-fil-a chicken nuggets chipotle combo creations condiments courting the food court delivery domino&apos;s dunkin donuts fast food fast food that sucks ass filet-o-fish france french french fries fryday jack-in-the-box jesse eisenberg kentucky fried chicken kfc love mcdonald&apos;s mcrib midwest milkshake new york new york city outback steakhouse pizza pumpkin salad sonic starbucks subway taco bell the south thirsty thursday vlog wendy&apos;s zaxby&apos;s 
Briana
	</body>
</document>
