<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003474" url="http://www.dimensionsguide.com/pepper-mill-sizes/" time="2012-07-12-19:37" support="1" score="0.0016720383041763512" bingtitle="Pepper Mill Sizes | Dimensions Guide" webtitle="Dimensions InfoPepper Mill Sizes">
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>The Unicorn Magnum Plus can store a cup of ... and there is no mess left at your kitchen counter. ... The Average Size for a Fast Food Restaurant can be anywhere from ...</description>
	<body>
		Because Size Matters
 

 
Pepper Mill Sizes
 
A pepper mill lets you extract the maximum flavor from fresh ground pepper. Unlike the pre-grounded type, a pepper mill allows you to grind the pepper just the way you want it.

Pepper Mill Dimensions: William Bounds Key Mill

The William Bounds Key Mill measures 2.8 x 2 x 3.5 inches. The device has a stainless steel mechanism that it uses for mincing and grinding. The grinder can be adjusted from coarse, medium to fine.

The control is at the top ring. The control ensures the grinding is refined and precise. The mechanism is set up in such a way the pepper flavor comes out.

The unit has an acrylic makeup and lets you see the contents. This will let you know if it is time for a refill. The compact size ensures it does not take up a lot of space in the kitchen.

Pepper Mill Dimensions: Unicorn Magnum Plus

The Unicorn Magnum Plus is 8 inches high and comes in a black color. The grind can be modified to suit your taste. It has a secure but comfortable grip.

In addition, there is a nut located at the pepper mill’s base. This is independent of the mill’s loading ring. This means you do not have to reset the unit after you refill it.

The Unicorn Magnum Plus can store a cup of peppercorns. There is a big hole on the side where you can pour in the contents. The grinding instrument comes with nickel plated heads. This ensures the cutting edges will not dull. The device is not run by battery so there is no need to buy one.

Pepper Mill Dimensions: Olde Thompson

The Olde Thompson pepper mill measures 5 x 3 x 8 inches. The pepper mill is made of stainless steel. The grinding instrument is made of carbon steel. It may be adjusted from coarse, medium to fine. The pepper mill is sold along with a salt shaker.

The grinding mechanism ensures the pepper comes out in small chunks. There is no need to worry about large chunks of pepper being generated. Both the pepper mill and salt shaker are solidly built. They are also stylishly made so they can be put on display as well.

Pepper Mill Dimensions: OXO Good Grips

The OXO Good Grips pepper grinder measures 2.2 x 2.2 x 5.5 inches. The body is acrylic. There are also stainless steel accents around it. The grinder does not corrode. The grinder does not soak in odors or flavors.

The grinding mechanism is placed at the top. This ensures the grinding process is clean and there is no mess left at your kitchen counter. The grinder comes with adjustable settings for getting the pepper with just the right texture. The grinder also has nonslip grip so it can be used continuously. The capacity is 4-3/4 ounces.

Along with the pepper mill dimensions, the capacity of the unit should be looked into. If you use a lot of pepper, the efficiency and durability of the grinder will be critical.
 
 Tags: cooking Kitchen Tools 
 Food and Drinks No comments 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

 

 
 
No related posts.
 
 Search for: 
Categories

 Business Cars and Vehicle Clothes and Fashion Computers and Internet DIY and Construction Entertainment and Sport Food and Drinks Health and Beauty Home and Furniture Nature Pets and Animals Places and Events Recreation Reference Seasonal Sports Tools Travel What is Hot 
 
Recent Posts

 Bike Sizes Cyclocross Bed Sizes for RVs Belvedere Vodka Bottle Sizes Beer Keg Sizes Canada Truck Bed Dimensions of a Chevy Avalanche 
 
Recent Comments

 mike on 20ft Container Size William F. L. Burgess on What are the Sizes of Barbells? aangela on Size of a Beakers Edwin Sharp on Interior Door Sizes . on Smallest House 
 
 



 

 Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
