<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003120" url="http://www.job-applications.com/circle-k-application/" time="2012-07-12-19:14" support="1" score="0.0015193081799763585" bingtitle="Download / Print Circle K Employment Application Form Online" webtitle="Download / Print Circle K Employment Application Form Online">
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="138"/>
	<description>Customers can find anything from food and drinks to magazines, sunglasses ... I really need a job so I’m trying to do anything I can in order to get a job as a cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		The #1 Independent Online Job Application Resource Website 
 
 
 
 
 Home » Gas Station Jobs »Circle K

Circle K Application
 
 
 
Circle K Application Online–Job Employment Form 

 
 
 
 
 Apply for Jobs at Circle K Online 

 Application for Circle K: Circle K does not provide a printable job application. If you want to get a job at Circle K, you must apply for employment on the website by following the link above. Full-time or part-time positions may vary depending on the location.

 Interview Tips: Go to the Circle K job interview questions&amp;tips page.

 Available Positions at Circle K: Customer Service Representative, Gas Station Attendant, Customer Service Representative Leader, Inventory Associate, Assistant Manager, Manager, Marketing Manager, Finance Manager, Financial Analyst, Inventory Auditor, Refrigeration Technician, Maintenance Technician, Franchise Development Manager

 Minimum Age to Work at Circle K : 18 years old (How old do you have to be to work at Circle K?)

 Circle K Hours of Operation: Open 24 hours a day, 7 days a week

 More Information: Circle K Job Info 
 Related Jobs :

 7-Eleven 
 
76 Gas Station 
 
ARCO 
 
BP 
 
Chevron 
 
Citgo 
 
Clark 
 
Conoco 
 
Marathon 
 
Mobil 
 
Murphy USA 
 
Pilot Flying J 
 
Quik Trip 
 
RaceTrac 
 
Sheetz 
 
Shell 
 
TravelCenters Of America 
 
Texaco 
 
Valero 
 
Wawa 
If finding employment has you running in circles, try the Circle K application. Find a job that fits into your schedule by applying online today.

Circle K is a chain of convenience stores known for their distinct logo of a red “k” inside a white circle. Primarily operated as convenience store locations, some sell gasoline in addition to a wide range of name- and off-brand products. Customers can find anything from food and drinks to magazines, sunglasses, lottery tickets, and more.

Circle K was founded in 1951 in El Paso, Texas. What started out as three simple locations in the Lone Star State has now grown to become the single largest convenience store chain in the United States, second only to 7-11 in number of overall locations. In addition to their U.S. stores, Circle K also has a global presence, with stores in countries like Mexico, Hong Kong, and Taiwan. Circle K is a wholly-owned subsidiary of the Canadian-based Couche-Tard Corporation that operates over 6,000 convenience store locations and is the largest of its kind. Couche-Tard, which is French for “night owl,” also own and operate under the Dairy Mart, Daisy Mart, and Winks brand names.

With locations all over the United States and throughout the rest of the world, employment opportunities with Circle K are relatively easy to come by. Circle K consistently hires workers and associates for a number of different job titles. Work as an entry-level employee in customer service or in a career as a store manager. To apply for work with Circle K simply pick up an application for employment or continue reading to find out more about careers and opportunities for work with this industry leader.

Entry-level jobs available at Circle K exist as customer service representatives. Primary jobs duties for this position involve a great deal of customer service. Responsibilities may include greeting the customer, ringing up purchases, answering questions about products and services, and making sure the store is clean and orderly. Customer service workers should be friendly and motivated. No real experience is necessary for these position, however, the employer may favor those with a related work history.

Careers also exist within the company. Circle K is always looking for entry-level employees that want to take their career to the next level. Career opportunities are available as managers and include both supervisory and administrative duties. Specific responsibilities include setting schedules, hiring and training new employees, answer the phones, and communicating with the corporate office. This is a perfect way to build a resume and receive great pay while doing it. All applicants for these positions must be at least 18 years old. Some locations may require candidates have at least a high school diploma or equivalent. Fill out an application for more details.

In addition to great pay, all eligible employees have the ability to qualify for benefits packages that include a 401(k) retirement savings plan, medical and dental insurance plans, paid vacation and holidays, and more. Bring your employment search full circle with the Circle K job application. Apply today!
 8 comments: 
 Janardan Krishna Kadariya: 





Respected Sir,

Sir, I am Janardan form Gunjanagar-5, Chitwan, Nepal I looking for Computer Operator job of Macau Country. I had completed Computer Hardware&amp;Networking Training in Nepal. Sir I hoped………………………….this job .

Urs Best Regards
Janaradan


 
 Kiley Swanson: 





Would I be able to fill out an application for Circle K online and then fill out a printable one to bring into my local store? I really need a job so I’m trying to do anything I can in order to get a job as a cashier here.


 
 Natalie Woodson: 





I would like to fill out an application for cashier at Circle K, but I would also like to know more about the customer service representative and what is required for this job.


 
 Kiara Carpenter: 





I love going to Circle everyone knows me and is very friendly. I wouldn’t mind at all working there. In fact I am going to fill out an application right now. I hope I get an interview. I would really like to be a cashier to meet new people everyday.


 
 Aubrey Eliott: 





I am going to fill out the online application form for Circle K. I think it would be a great benefit for me and my career. Speaking of benefits, does anyone know if Circle K offers their employees a benefits package that includes health insurance?


 
 ANASTASIA DAVIS: 





MY NAME IS ANASTASIA. ME AND MY HUSBAND FREQUENT YOUR STORE ON PINELOG ROAD AT LEAST 10 TIMES THROUGHOUT THE WEEK AND I WOULD LIKE THE OPPORTUNITY TO WORK THERE AS ASTORE CLERK. PLEASE REVIEW MY APPLICATION AND CONTACT ME FOR A JOB INTERVIEW.


 
 melissaint moinius: 





my name is melissaint. i am interested to work for circle k.


 
 Brittney Citizen: 





my name is brittney and i have 3 years experience in gas station work and i really would like the opportunity to be a team member with the circle k family….


 
 
 Most Popular Jobs Retail Store Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Career Research Employee Benefits 
 En Espanol 
 Interview Tips 
 Interview Questions 
 Job Descriptions 
 Job Finding Tips 
 Salary Info 
 Job Newsletter We&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name: Email: Zip Code: Select Category: Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery 

 Sign Up Job Categories Airline Jobs 
 Amusement Park Jobs 
 Armed Forces Jobs 
 Automotive Store Jobs 
 Banking Jobs 
 Book Store Jobs 
 Casino Jobs 
 Childcare Daycare Jobs 
 Coffee Shop Jobs 
 Computer Store Jobs 
 Cruise Ship Jobs 
 Delivery Driver Jobs 
 Department Store Jobs 
 Fashion Jobs 
 Fast Food Jobs 
 Fitness Health Jobs 
 Furniture Store Jobs 
 Gas Station Jobs 
 Grocery Store Jobs 
 Hardware Store Jobs 
 Healthcare Jobs 
 Home Decor Jobs 
 Hospital Jobs 
 Hotel Jobs 
 Ice Cream Shop Jobs 
 Insurance Jobs 
 Mechanic Jobs 
 Movie Theater Jobs 
 Office Supply Jobs 
 Pet Store Jobs 
 Pharmacy Tech Jobs 
 Pharmacist Jobs 
 Pizza Delivery Jobs 
 Rental Truck Jobs 
 Rental Car Jobs 
 Restaurant Jobs 
 Retail Management Jobs 
 Retail Store Jobs 
 Shoe Store Jobs 
 Smoothie Maker Jobs 
 Specialty Foods Jobs 
 Sporting Goods Jobs 
 Telecommunications Jobs 
 Temp Agency Jobs 
 Tools Jobs 
 Tutoring Jobs 

 All Job Categories 
 
   

 
 Sign up - we&apos;ll email jobs to you. Name:
 Email:
 Zip:
 Select Category:
 Retail Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Housekeeping Pharmacy Delivery Driver Footwear Healthcare Automotive Cruise Ship Grocery Store Casino Airline Pizza Delivery Sign Up 
 
 disclaimer 

 privacy policy 

 terms of use 
 
 
Copyright © 2011, 2012 Job-Applications.com
	</body>
</document>
