<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003660" url="http://www.letsrideuta.com/tag/utah-county/" time="2012-07-12-19:49" support="1" score="0.0024020796122030765" bingtitle="Utah County • Let&apos;s Ride UTA" webtitle="Utah CountyLets Ride UTA">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>... Trains of Thought Tagged with bus, Change Day, Davis County, Salt Lake ... to open the FrontRunner South commuter rail line ... trip that leaves Weber State University near 5:10 ...</description>
	<body>
		UTAH TRANSIT AUTHORITY July 12, 2012 TRAINS OF THOUGHT MOM ABOARD URBAN TICKET ﻿ 
 
 
Tag Utah County 
 
 April Change Day Information 
 Filed in Featured , Trains of Thought Tagged with bus , Change Day , Davis County , Salt Lake County , Utah County , Weber Councy April 11th, 2012 @ 1:00 am 
Our April Change Day is quickly approaching and though we anticipate only a few minor changes to the system this spring, we encourage bus riders all along the Wasatch Front to double check their route information.

Most of the changes being made are to improve system reliability, ensure trip efficiency or to adjust seasonal routing.

 The changes will go into affect on Sunday, April 15. 

 

 

For more information about the changes, please see our April 2012 Change Day flier.

 
 
 UTA Invites the Public to Participate in 2012 Scoping Process 
 Filed in Featured , Trains of Thought Tagged with FrontRunner South , Public Hearing , Scoping , Utah County April 9th, 2012 @ 1:45 pm 
UTA is preparing to open the FrontRunner South commuter rail line that will offer high-capacity mass transit service between Provo and Salt Lake. When the line opens in December 2012, it will increase transit service to Salt Lake and Utah Counties and necessitate some changes to some existing bus routes.

Prior to creating any service proposals, UTA would like to gather public input on the transit system and how resources should be allocated.  Riders are invited to complete an online survey, attend a scoping meeting and provide comment. Public feedback will guide UTA on how to allocate limited resources and provide the best mix of bus and rail service.

Please click here to take the online survey .

If you would like to speak with UTA representatives in person, attend a public scoping meeting.

 Saratoga Springs/Eagle Mountain
 Saratoga Springs City Offices
Wednesday, April 11, 2012
6:30 – 8 p.m.
1307 North Commerce Drive, Saratoga Springs

 American Fork
 American Fork Senior Center
Thursday, April 12, 2012
6:30 – 8 p.m.
54 East Main Street, American Fork

 Spanish Fork
 Spanish Fork City Hall
Wednesday, April 18, 2012
6:30 – 8 p.m.
40 South Main Street, Spanish Fork

 Orem
 Orem City Offices
Thursday, April 19, 2012
6:30 – 8 p.m.
56 North State Street, Orem

 Provo
 Utah County Administration Building
Wednesday, April 25, 2012
6:30–8 p.m.
100 East Center Street, Provo

To assure full participation at the open house, accommodations for effective communication, such as sign language interpreters or printed materials in alternate formats, or a language interpreter for non-English speaking participants must be requested at least five (5) working days prior to the date of the scheduled event. Requests for ADA accommodations should be directed to UTA ADA Compliance Officer at 801-287-3536 or for deaf/hearing impaired person, dial 711 to make a relay call. To request a language interpreter, please contact Title VI Compliance Officer at (801) 287-8871.

 
 
 Malawi’s Pizza 
 Filed in Featured , Urban Ticket Tagged with bus , Malawi Pizza , Orem , Provo , The Shops at Riverwoods , Urban Ticket , Utah County February 17th, 2012 @ 1:37 am 
Bus route 832 is a long winding route. If you rode from end to end, you would stop by no less than three shopping malls and dozens restaurants. One of the best? Malawi’s Pizza , located at The Shops at Riverwoods.

 

This unique casual dining establishment is more than just a restaurant though. It’s a cause . For every meal purchased at Malawi’s, a meal is provided to a child in the African nation of Malawi.

The menu features a wide variety of pizzas, as well as pasta, salad and dessert. The generous plates average between $8-10 per person.

The Capri Pizza was a hit.

 

As well as the Chicken Pesto Pasta.

 

Head on over to Malawi Pizza and let us know what you think!

*If you know of a locally owned shop or restaurant on a UTA bus or rail line that you think we should review, let us know!

 
 
 FrontRunner South Project Update 
 Filed in Trains of Thought Tagged with Commuter Rail , Construction , FrontLines 2015 , FrontRunner , Salt Lake County , Utah County November 2nd, 2011 @ 5:00 am 
The FrontRunner South commuter rail project continues to move forward and construction of the 45-mile line to Provo is more than 85 percent complete.

Construction in Utah County is essentially complete from Provo to Lehi.

 Provo Intermodal Center construction is underway and Orem Intermodal Center construction is scheduled to begin in early 2012. Construction crews are putting the finishing touches on the American Fork and Lehi park and ride lots that have been partially open to the public for more than a year. 

Construction in the Jordan Narrows is winding down after three years of challenging construction work that included canal relocation, bridge construction and relocating Union Pacific’s railroad track to make room for FrontRunner.

Most of the remaining project construction is in Salt Lake County.

 Construction crews are nearly finished with several bridges that will allow FrontRunner to travel over major east-west running roadways in Salt Lake County. Construction on the South Jordan and Murray stations is currently underway. FrontRunner track will be installed throughout Salt Lake County by the end of 2011. 

Substantial completion of construction is anticipated in late 2012. After construction is complete, the line will be tested for signal integration and safety. It is anticipated that the line will open for operation in early 2013.

The following presentation was made to area stakeholders and elected officials October 27, 2011.
 


 
 
 UTA to Debut Public Art in Utah County 
 Filed in Mom Aboard Tagged with Art , Art in Transit , Bus Mural , Lehi , Orem , Timpanogos , Utah County October 11th, 2011 @ 6:37 pm 
Transit riders coming and going from the FrontRunner park-and-ride lot near Thanksgiving Point in Lehi and the bus shelter in front of Orem’s City Hall will be treated to a nice pop of color thanks to some local artists.

 The mural in Lehi entitled“Connections,”was developed by students at the Lehi Arts Center under the direction of teacher Linnie Brown. The students involved in the project–Arissa B., Kylie B., Danielle G., Acacia G., Colin J., JJ M., Cole N., Skyler P., Savannah S., Abigail W.–range in age from seven to 11 years old.

Images depicted in the artwork include the IM Flash building, Thanksgiving Point, Lehi Roller Mills, Lehi Legacy Center, along with other community attractions and a variety of houses.

The second mural is located on State Street in Orem in front fo City Hall.

 The piece was created by local stained glass artist Jeanne Gromm. Jeanne enjoys finding the hidden beauty and has created a piece to guide viewers to some of Utah County’s most treasured spots.

The addition of these two pieces bring the total number of murals located in bus shelters to 11. Each year, UTA works to involve youth groups, local artists, seniors and community groups in the design and execution of bus shelter mural projects. For more information on participating, please visit UTA’s Art in Transit information page .

UTA will hold an unveiling ceremony to debut the two pieces on Monday, October 17 at 3:30 p.m. The event will be held at the Lehi park and ride, located at 3101 North Ashton Blvd.

 
 
 All Utah County Now a Part of Transit District 
 Filed in Trains of Thought Tagged with Utah County June 16th, 2011 @ 9:40 am 
The Utah Transit Authority Board of Trustees unanimously approved a measure that will bring all of Utah County into the agency’s service district Wednesday, during a special board meeting.

The annexation followed a move by the Utah County Commission on June 7, to increase sales taxes in some areas of the county. Now the whole county will pay into the county’s transit district fund.

Previous to the vote, cities in Utah County had to approve the sales tax increase and request for annexation individually.

Moving forward, UTA will collect just over half a percent on each cent collected in sales tax throughout the county. Prior to the vote, the full tax was only paid by cities that had joined the transit district. Areas without transit service were paying a quarter of a cent to help fund the construction of FrontRunner Commuter Rail.

Orem and Provo were first to join the transit district in 1985. Four years later, American Fork, Lehi, Lindon and Pleasant Grove joined.

Springville, Alpine, Cedar Hills, Highland, Mapleton, Payson, Salem and Spanish Fork all voted to join the transit district during the ‘90’s. In 2008, Eagle Mountain and Saratoga Springs joined the service district, followed by Santaquin in 2010 .

This change will allow for UTA to provide for future service in some of the county’s smaller towns (Cedar Fort, Elk ridge, Fairfield, Genoa, Goshen, Vineyard and Woodland Hills) should there be a demand.

 
 
 Public hearings scheduled for April 2011 proposed service changes 
 Filed in Trains of Thought Tagged with bus , Change Day , Ogden , Public Hearing , Trains of Thought , UTA , Utah County , Utah Transit Authority January 11th, 2011 @ 6:31 pm 
UTA is proposing several service changes to bus service in Box Elder, Davis, Weber and Utah counties.

The changes proposed are based on current ridership, efficiencies and 2011 budget projections. Although a number of the changes represent a small reduction in service, net ridership is expected to increase in the coming year.

Following is an outline of proposed changes:

 Route 685–Brigham City/Ogden Express– Discontinue service. Route 685 has one weekday southbound trip that leaves Brigham City about 7 a.m. and one weekday northbound trip that leaves Weber State University near 5:10 p.m. The underutilized route services Brigham City, downtown Ogden, Weber State University and the Flying J office in Ogden.

Routes 626 and 627 –West Roy/Weber State University Davis Campus/Davis Applied Technology Center–discontinue Saturday service. Routes 626 and 627 run hourly on Saturdays from approximately 7:20 a.m. to 5:45 p.m. These routes connect 5600 South and 3500 West in Roy to the WSU Davis campus in Layton and the DATC in Kaysville. The changes will impact less than seven percent of riders on each of the routes.

Route 667–Lagoon Shuttle–Discontinue Sunday service. The Lagoon Shuttle runs every 30 minutes on Sunday from approximately 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. April through October. The route connects Lagoon to the Farmington FrontRunner Station. This is an under utilized route and the change will affect approximately one percent of current shuttle riders.

 Route 455–University of Utah/Davis County/Weber State University –Discontinue Saturday service. Route 455 Saturday service runs hourly from approximately 8:45 a.m. to 5:45 p.m. The route connects downtown Ogden and Weber State University Campus with downtown Salt Lake City and the University of Utah. The changes will affect less than two percent of route 455 riders.

 Route 613–Weber Industrial Park - Discontinue Saturday service. Route 613 Saturday service runs hourly from approximately 8:30 to 6 p.m. The route connects the Ogden Transit Center/FrontRunner Station to the Weber Industrial Park. The changes will impact less than four percent of route 613 ridership.

 Route 816–Sandy Civic TRAX to Provo East Bay - Discontinue Saturday night service due to low ridership. Route 816 connects the southern most TRAX stop with Utah County, continuing south to Provo’s East Bay.

 Route 850–Utah County State Street –Cancel 15 of the 43 trips with the lowest ridership.

The proposed changes would impact less than one half a percent of UTA riders.

Public hearings are being held in each county to provide interested parties the opportunity to comment on the proposed changes. Meeting dates, times and locations are available on the UTA website. 

Following the public hearings UTA will review the comments collected, make any necessary adjustments and finalize the schedule. Changes will be implemented in the system in April 2011.

For more information on Box Elder, Davis and Weber County changes, please contact  Kent Jorgenson at kjorgenson@rideuta.com or (801) 510-1484 prior to January 18.

For more information on changes in Utah County, please contact Ken Anson at kanson@rideuta.com or (801) 227-8957 prior to January 27.

 
 
 Santaquin joins UTA transit district 
 Filed in Trains of Thought Tagged with bus , Santaquin City , Utah County November 18th, 2010 @ 10:00 am 
On Thursday, Nov. 18, the UTA board of trustees unanimously approved Santaquin’s bid to join the transit district.  The resolution follows the November general election when a majority of Santaquin voters approved a local sales tax increase that will help fund the city’s annexation.

Santaquin is one of the few remaining Utah County communities not part of UTA’s service area to opt in.  Unlike Salt Lake, Davis and Weber Counties, which joined as a whole, Utah County cities have joined periodically over the last three decades.

Provo and Orem were the first cities in Utah County to join UTA in 1985.  American Fork, Lehi, Lindon, and Pleasant Grove joined the district in 1989, followed by Springville in 1990. Alpine, Cedar Hills and Highland joined in 1992, and Mapleton, Payson, Salem, and Spanish Fork entered in 1995.  The most recent communities to opt into UTA were Eagle Mountain and Saratoga Springs in 2008.

Following the Santaquin addition, the only communities not part of the transit district include Cedar Fort, Elk Ridge, Fairfield, Genoa, Goshen, Vineyard, Woodland Hills, and unincorporated portions of Utah County.

Bus service to Santaquin is not expected to begin until late 2011 to give time for tax revenues to accrue and for service plans to be developed.  The following steps also still need to take place:

 UTA and Santaquin City will notify the Utah Lieutenant Governor and the state tax commission UTA and the city will cooperatively agree on a service plan based on projected revenues 

Initial service may include either an extension of local service from Payson or an extension of express service from Payson or some combination.

 
 ﻿
 
TubePress
 Title UTA Ticket Kiosk Runtime 1:42 Description How to use UTA&apos;s FrontRunner ticket kiosk to pay f... Title UTA&apos;s Front Runner Commuter Train Ogden to Salt Lake Runtime 5:03 Description Here&apos;s what it looks like to take UTA&apos;s FrontRunne... Title UTA&apos;s Front Runner commuter Train Salt Lake to Ogden Runtime 5:00 Description Here&apos;s what it looks like to take UTA&apos;s FrontRunne... Title Future Airport TRAX Line Welcome Center Runtime 1:23 Description The future UTA Welcome Center and TRAX station tha... 
 Twitter: rideUTA 

 @northmccormick We&apos;re working on some track out by the freight interlocking. Until the work is complete, it is considered a slow zone. 10:43:27 PM July 10, 2012 from HootSuite in reply to NorthMcCormick Reply Retweet Favorite @cb1572 That hasn&apos;t yet been determined. 09:54:19 PM July 10, 2012 from HootSuite in reply to cb1572 Reply Retweet Favorite @lkirk 17 minutes 09:44:08 PM July 10, 2012 from Twitter for BlackBerry® in reply to lkirk Reply Retweet Favorite 
 @rideUTA 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 
 
 
Copyright© Let&apos;s Ride UTA 
 Utah Transit Authority
	</body>
</document>
