<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003980" url="http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/long-john-silvers-c6814.html" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="16" score="0.029437386622029833" bingtitle="Long John Silvers Complaints, Reviews - Horrible service and food" webtitle="Long John Silvers Complaints, Reviews - Horrible service and food">
			<query id="001179" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000177" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000551" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000739" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000866" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001494" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000929" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000897" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000677" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000426" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001149" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000114" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001022" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>I order the chicken and more with NO SLAW and ... Long John Silver’s may merely be a fast-food restaurant and ... Then when I ask if I could receive my receipt back ...</description>
	<body>
		The most trusted and popular consumer complaints website 
 
 Everything 
 Everything Complaints Articles News&amp;Stories Recalls Videos Groups Questions 
 Home News&amp;Stories Tips&amp;Tricks Questions Videos Photos Recalls Groups Submit Complaint Connect With: Login Register 
 
 
 
Recently Discussed Complaints
 1. (0 mins ago) 
 KIMBERLY GLASNAPP 
ANIMAL RESCUE FRAUD 2. (2 mins ago) 
 Orgreenic 
Scam 3. (2 mins ago) 
 William Scott and Associates 
Fraud 4. (5 mins ago) 
 Lux E cig/aka Bright Burn 
scam/fraud 5. (7 mins ago) 
 Sears Service and repair 
HORRIBLE SERVICE 


Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks
 
 
 
    5 Ways to Save Energy in Your Home 
 
 
 
    Choosing the Water Bottle that&apos;s Right for You 
 
 
 
    Grocery Shopping Tips 
 

 
Latest News&amp;Stories
 
    French Total wins gas drilling tender 
 
    Deceptive Marketing For Prepaid Calling Cards Targeting Immigrants 
 
    Who&apos;s Paying For What? Washington Takes Aim at Secret Political Money 
 


Latest Questions
 sueing cr england not getting my welfare check from govement Neotel SA NO RESPONSE MY MISSING MOBILE PHONE E-MAIL my order 

 
 
 
Long John Silvers Complaints&amp;Reviews - Horrible service and food
 Review all Long John Silvers complaints 
Long John Silvers
 
 Posted: 2007-03-17 by Darlene Ziolko   [send email] 
 
 
 Horrible service and food 
 Complaint Rating: Tweet My husband and I went to Long John Silvers in Countryside IL... I order the chicken and more with NO SLAW and extra hush puppies my husband ordered the shrimp with a side of the lobster bites. When the woman brought over our lunch she looks at me and says oh I put slaw on your plate but that is ok... I told her NO it is not ok and that I wanted my dinner changed as the slaw was on my fries and chicken and I order extra hush puppies... she had a horrible attitude and came back in about 1 minute and said heres your hushpuppies... extremely rude... my husband lobster bites were old and were nasty. We will not ever go there again. Service was horrible and employee was nasty... you have lost us as customers... I do not believe you really care though Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants Share with others:          
 Was the above complaint useful to you?
	</body>
</document>
