<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003628" url="http://www.thebaynet.com/index.cfm" time="2012-07-12-19:48" support="5" score="0.0043929049142719025" bingtitle="Breaking News,Classifieds,Events and Photos for St. Mary&apos;s ..." webtitle="Breaking News,Classifieds,Events and Photos for St. Mary&apos;s, Calvert Counties or Southern Maryland | TheBayNet.com">
			<query id="001429" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000704" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="110"/>
	<description>Sheriff&apos;s Office Retirement Board of Trustees Meeting Time Change ; Warrants Served By ... Beach, Dunkirk, Huntingtown, Lusby, North Beach, Prince Frederick (Calvert County ...</description>
	<body>
		[Please enable iFrames in your browser to use this feature.] 
 
 
Calvert, St. Mary&apos;s and Charles County
 Local Police/Fire/EMS Scanner Feeds    SOMD Politics    Games    Contests    Letters    RSS 
 News Business Classifieds Jobs Calendar Real Estate Auto Announcements Advertise 
 Log In / Register / Forgot Password? 
 HealthNet Public Works&amp;Energy Home Improvement Pet of the Week Coupons Forums Fun Contact Us News Tips 
 Dust off your tools and tune your Green Thumb - Check out TheBayNet.com Home and Garden Special Section! 
 
 
 Protesters Demand Bridgett Be Reinstated; County Working Out Agreement 

 7/12/2012 
Protesters gathered at the Charles County Commissioners&apos; Meeting on Tuesday to demand the reinstatement of County Administrator Dr. Rebecca Bridgett. Despite their efforts, the county confirmed Wednesday that Bridgett no longer works for the county.
 
 Reader&apos;s Letter: Race for Calvert County Board of Education Vastly Important 
 7/12/2012 Most Calvert County voters going to the polls in November will be reasonably informed when voting for President, U.S. Senator and their U.S. Representative. It would be difficult by then not to know about Romney/Obama, Bongino/Cardin and O&apos;Donnell/Hoyer. 
 
 
 
[Please enable iFrames in your browser to use this feature.] 
 
 
 
 
 
[Please enable iFrames in your browser to use this feature.] 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 SoMD In Pics 
 Click Images Below To View News Slideshows 

 
 
 hide box Get Breaking News in your E-Mail! 
 First Name: Last Name: E-Mail: Security Code: 
 
 
 Previous Spotlights 
 view all past spotlights 
 ManCave Organizes Wounded Warrior Fundraiser 
 An update on the efforts to raise funds for the Wounded Warrior Project in Southern Maryland includes news that a fundraiser is planned for Sunday, July 15. 
 VA Deploys New Processing Model for Compensation Claims 
 The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) announced today it is deploying a new model for processing compensation benefits claims at 16 VA regional offices. The new model is part of a comprehensive transformation plan designed to yield an estimated 150,000 to 200,000 additional compensation claim 
 Subjects Wanted For Questioning In Connection to a Theft 
 The St. Mary&apos;s County Sheriff&apos;s Office is attempting to identify the subjects who are wanted for questioning in connection to a theft which occurred July 4, 2012 at the Food Lion on Mt. Wolfe Road in Charlotte Hall, Maryland. 
 Detectives Arrest Suspect in Shooting on Derryfield Court 
 On July 11, Charles County Sheriff&apos;s detectives assigned to the Criminal Investigations Division arrested Earl Tryee Porter, 17, of Waldorf, in connection with a shooting that occurred at a party on July 7 in the 4900 block of Derryfield Court in Waldorf. 
 Attorney General Confirms Tracey v. Solesky Decision Regarding Dogs Is Not Yet in Effect 
 In a turn of events welcomed by The Humane Society of the United States, the Maryland Office of the Attorney General issued an opinion stating that the controversial Maryland Court of Appeals decision holding that all pit bull and pit bull type dogs are &quot;inherently dangerous&quot; is not yet in effect. 
 Marriage Petition Certified for November 2012 Election 
 Yesterday the Maryland State Elections Administrator informed the Maryland Marriage Alliance that the organization&apos;s efforts to put a marriage referendum on the November 2012 ballot succeeded. In the letter to Derek McCoy, Chairman of the Maryland Marriage Alliance, Administrator Linda H. 
 Car Torched Near Theater 
 The Office of the Maryland State Fire Marshal reported a late night motor vehicle fire in Waldorf July 10 was deliberately set. According to a report filed by Dfm. Dexter Hodges, the fire caused $2,500 in damage to a 1999 Buick Regal. 
 Relay for Life Combatants Press Charges 
 Calvert County&apos;s recent Relay for Life event was marred by an ugly incident that is tentatively scheduled to be the subject of hearings before a judge, according to documents on file in District Court. 
 McCoy Named Top Employee for July 
 Calvert County Government officials saluted Melissa McCoy, a grants analyst for the Department of Finance and Budget, as its Employee for the Month of July. 
 Board Delays Decision on Solomons Road 
 The Calvert County Commissioners voted unanimously Tuesday, July 10 to leave the record open for 30 days on a proposal to close a portion of a Solomons road in order to move forward with a contract renegotiation process. 
 Home Improvement 
 all HI Articles 
 Boothe&apos;s Heating and Air Conditioning Earns Top Scores From Buyers 
 On Friday, March 2, 2012 Northeastern Supply hosted their 2nd Annual American Standard Dealer Meeting at the Hyatt Regency in... Sponsored By: 
 Boothe&apos;s Heating and Air Conditioning Earns Top Scores From Buyers New Home Growth Slow, Niche Local Home Improvement Contractors Booming Motorists and Farmers Can Share the Road Safely Immediate Help for Roof or Siding Damage to Houses 
 
 Public Works&amp;Energy 
 all Energy Articles 
 SMECO Restores Service to Calvert and St. Mary&apos;s 
 SMECO restored electric service to all of its customers in Calvert and St. Mary&apos;s counties who were affected by Friday... Sponsored By: 
 Charles Water Restrictions Lifted Charlotte Hall Sewer Expansion Pulled from MetCom Plan Update on New Septic Bill Grandfathjering New Septic Bill Sets Grandfathering Deadline 
 
 Healthnet 
 all Healthnet Articles 
 Health Exchange appoints advisory committee leadership Local employee benefits advisor and business owner Jon Frank has been appointed to co?chair a statewide advisory committee addressing the next steps to opening the Maryland Health Benefits Exchange in January 2014. Frozen Desert Bars Recalled Calvert Hospice Recognized as a We Honor Veterans Partner Dr. Jay Lipoff: The Temporal Mandibular Joint (TMJ) Hornick Named CMH Nurse of the Year 
 
 TheBayNet Exclusives
 view all Articles 
 St. Peter&apos;s Church Blesses Classic Cars (0) Annual River Concert Series. (0) Comic Lovers and Science Fiction Fans Converge on Waldorf (0) Timmy Hill Finishes Ninth in Daytona Thriller (0) Solomons Fireworks: Behind the Scenes (1) Fireworks Light Sky Over Both Sides of Patuxent (0) Charles County Celebrates America&apos;s Independence (2) Two Honored For Saving Man&apos;s Life on Base (0) Young Eagle Rally at St. Mary&apos;s Airport (0) Nick on Politics: Shame on the Republican Congress (13) 
 
 Southern Maryland Press Releases
 view all Articles 
 River Concert Delights the Audience with &quot;That Independent Feeling&quot; (0) Severe Thunderstorm Watch Alert (0) Excessive Heat Warning in Effect for Today (0) Recalls Various Frozen, Ready-To-Eat Meat and Poultry Products (0) Raley Sentenced To 18 Months in Jail (6) Accokeek Foundation Garners Federal Grant (0) Calvert Cooling Centers Remain Open This Weekend (0) Charles Planning Commission Agendas Now Online (0) Schedule Released For 4th of July Celebrate Charles (0) Coast Guard Urges Holiday Safety (0) 
 
 Southern Maryland Regional News
 view all Articles 
 Missing Hughesville Teen Found (4) Severe Storms Slam Southern Maryland (0) Excessive Heat Warning for Charles; Heat Advisory for Calvert, St. Mary&apos;s (0) Maryland Announces Free Fishing Days (0) Cankerworms Defoliate Trees in Southern Maryland (0) Local Girl Chosen as Cherry Blossom Festival Jr. Princess (0) Commissioners Okay Mapping Error Correction (0) MISSING DOG: Daisy from Town Creek (0) Wii Tournaments at Calvert Library (1) UPDATE:Snapped Cable Prevents Outgoing Calls in Charles County (1) 
 
 Southern Maryland Video News
 view all Articles 
 Spalding Consulting, Inc. Unveils New Logo (0) Despite Some Rain Delays, Bowles Farm Had a Great Race Weekend (2) Tiki King Delights the Masses at Blessing (7) Caught in the Net Twice in Three Days (18) Welcome to TheBAYNET.com&apos;s Amazing Halloween Spooktacular! (0) 
 
 Obituaries - Sponsored by Mattingley-Gardiner Funeral Home 
 view all Obituaries 
 Mary Evelyn Bailey, 94 7/11/12 John Alton &quot;Skip&quot; Burgess, 80 7/09/12 Robert &quot;Rob&quot; Wilkinson, 55 7/09/12 Michael S. Eberhardt, 42 7/09/12 Bernard &quot;Buddy&quot; Cleo Ellis, 72 7/08/12 Sharon Mae Ptaszynski, 56 7/08/12 Mary Nell Svites, 70 7/08/12 Charley John Page, 85 7/07/12 
 
 The Bay Net Contests 
 see all Contests 
 No Contests Currently Available 
 
 The Bay Net Reader&apos;s Poll 
 see all Reader&apos;s Polls Your browser is not configured to view this feature. Please enable Iframes in your browser so that you can use this feature. Click here to view more pets! 
 Charlie Type: Dog Location: Leonardtown, MD Meet Charlie, a sweet, lovable boy who happens to be deaf. But don&apos;t let that scare you away. [ more ] 
 
 
 
[Please enable iFrames in your browser to use this feature.] 
 
 Latest News Most Read 
 Barrack T Leonardtown DUI and Crime Report [0] Commissioner Collins to Hold Town Hall Meeting July 23 [0] Two Burglarys in Waldorf [0] Sail for Youth 2012 [0] Charged With First&amp;Second Degree Assault [0] Commissioners Working Toward Agreement with County Administrator [0] County Leaders to Discuss the Importance of Intergovernmental Collaboration at MACo [0] Charles County Students Continue Improvement On State Tests [0] 

 Two Long-Time SMCM Employees Fired [15] Nick on Politics: Shame on the Republican Congress [13] Two Arrested on Drug Charges [12] No More Nights at The Roost [9] Marriage Petition Certified for November 2012 Election [9] Two Charged With 6 Counts of Burglary [8] Raley Sentenced To 18 Months in Jail [6] UPDATE:Seven-Year-Old Girl Killed in Bryans Road Accident [6] Fatal Motor Vehicle Collision on 235 [6] Detectives Arrest Suspect in Shooting on Derryfield Court [6] One Person Injured in Park Hall Accident [5] Two New Elementary Schools on Fast Track in Plan [5] Sewage Truck on Fire on South Bound Route 235 [4] Missing Hughesville Teen Found [4] O&apos;Donnell: Time to Repeal Obamacare [4] Local Man Receives Belated Honors For His Father [3] O&apos;Donnell vs. Hoyer: May Jobs Report [3] U.S. Constitution—Literal or Not? [3] Unattended Child in Car Leads to Charges [3] Attorney General Confirms Tracey v. Solesky Decision Regarding Dogs Is Not Yet in Effect [3] 
 
Southern MD Announcements
 see all 
 Mary Evelyn Bailey, 94 
• Obituaries 

 Local Teen Crowned Miss MD Teen 2012 
• Agendas 

 Temperance Alexa Hance 
• Births 

 Summer Festival at Auto Drive 
• Agendas 
 
 
 

 
July Events
 see all events VACATION BIBLE SCHOOL! 
Monday, July 30 | 9:00 AM | So. Cal. Baptist Church 12140 HG Trueman Rd., Lusby, MD 


 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 
 7/12 - Nature Time Camp at Greenwell 
 7/12 - Read. Learn. Grow. 
 7/12 - Introduction to PowerPoint for Kids 
 7/12 - Dream Big 
 7/12 - CofCommerce Biz After Hours: Lincoln Exhibit Kickoff. 
 7/12 - Dream Big 
 
 Forums 

 Annual Maryland Driver Survey 
 Last Reply: 10:04 AM, Total Replies: 2 Question for Obamaians 
 Last Reply: 1:38 PM 7/11/2012, Total Replies: 219 Electrian in Charlotte Hall area 
 Last Reply: 6:24 PM 7/7/2012, Total Replies: 2 Act by June 29th to be part of Maryland history 
 Last Reply: 4:34 PM 6/29/2012, Total Replies: 0 Annoying motorcycles... 
 Last Reply: 11:06 AM 6/25/2012, Total Replies: 8 act by May 29th to be a part of Maryland history 
 Last Reply: 4:31 PM 5/30/2012, Total Replies: 1 The Prices are OUTRAGEOUS right now... 
 Last Reply: 10:15 AM 5/30/2012, Total Replies: 1 Metrocast Cable 
 Last Reply: 11:26 AM 5/25/2012, Total Replies: 7 [ view all ] 

 Classifieds 

 Massage Table NEVER USED - Furniture and Appliances Music CD&apos;s ~350 Many Genres - Collectibles 4 Drawer File Cabinet - Furniture and Appliances Kenmore - Clothes - Washer&amp;Dryer - Electric - Furniture and Appliances Rabbitry Close-Out! - Pets and Animals GREENWOOD COMMERCIAL&amp;RESIDENTIAL;CLEANING - Services Gunmetal Rims - Rims and Tires Asphalt Sealcoating Free Estimates - Home and Garden DeFilippo Tile&amp;Marble, Inc. - Services Car top carrier - Vehicle Related Items [ view all ] 

 Local Businesses 

 Ferrante&amp;Dill, LLC Prestige Home Inspection Services Inc. Homes for Sale in MD Performance Auto Finishes Quantum Sail Design Group Southern Maryland Cycles Lightfoot Massage Southern Maryland Contracting Roofing and Siding TBGD Forever Uplighting (Weddings) [ view all ] 

 Employment 

 Security Officer/EMT Internet Representative Caregiver/Med Tech Freelance Medical Interpreter Patient Client Driver Children&apos;s Dental Practice Dental Sterilization Technician Hygiene Assistant Registered Dental Hygienist Nanny/Babysitters [ view all ] 

 Real Estate 

 PRICE REDUCTION!!! Log Cabin on 28 Acres - $545,000.00 Waterfront Cape Cod for Sale - $364,419.00 24330 BUDDS CREEK RD, CLEMENTS, MD 20624 - $272,999.00 3 Bedroom, 2 Bath - $198,250.00 Land For Sale in Scotland, MD - $ 79,900.00 The Value is in the Land!!! - $399,900.00 Own a Piece of History - $265,000.00 Excellent Great 3bed, 2bath Home in Essex South - $185,000.00 Cottage At The Beach - $174,900.00 Quiet Country setting 4 Bedrooms 2 Bath - $ 1,500.00 [ view all ] 
 
 
[Please enable iFrames in your browser to use this feature.] 
 TheBayNet.com Home   |   Copyright   |   Privacy   |   Contact Us 
 ©2005-2012 TheBayNet, Inc. 
Thanking you for visiting TheBayNet.com, Southern Maryland&apos;s Top News Source. We serve news, classifieds, job listings, real estate listings including waterfront property and more for  Chesapeake Beach, Dunkirk, Huntingtown, Lusby, North Beach, Prince Frederick (Calvert County seat), Port Republic, St. Leonard, Solomons Island, Scotland, Leonardtown (St. Mary&apos;s County seat), California Charlotte Hall, Golden Beach, Lexington Park, Abell, Beachville-St. Inigoes, Bushwood, Callaway, Chaptico-Maddox, Clements, Coltons Point, Compton, Dameron, Drayden, Great Mills, Helen, Hollywood, Loveville, Mechanicsville, Morganza, Park Hall, Piney Point, Ridge, St. Inigoes, St. Mary&apos;s City, Scotland, Tall Timbers, Valley Lee, and of course the NAS-PAX (a town unto itself).
	</body>
</document>
