<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003007" url="http://lynnnchicago.com/?p=1535" time="2012-07-12-19:06" support="1" score="0.0007026349515169438" bingtitle="IHJZ Real Housewives News / Project Runway / Alex &amp; Simon on GMA ..." webtitle="IHJZ  Real Housewives News / Project Runway / AlexSimon on GMA | LynnNChicago">
			<query id="000084" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>... outfit looks like it belongs in a fast food restaurant. ... ve kept the “wrong” collars and have receipts ... Adgirl.. the good Dr is not allowed to dispense ...</description>
	<body>
		LynnNChicago The Real Housewives Expert Skip to content 
 Home LynnNChicago Fun Recipes and Life Saving Ideas! LynnNChicago Archives LynnNChicago Book Club–1st Selection Guts: The Endless Follies and Tiny Triumphs of a Giant Disaster by Kristen Johnston LynnNChicago FINAL Jill Zarin Blog LynnNChicago RECIPE BOARDS LynnNChicago Reference Library LynnNChicago Taylor Amstrong–Investigated–Some Real Answers LynnNChicago Year End Survey–The Results LynnNChicago Book Club–Skinnydipping By Bethenny Frankel LynnNChicago Hope, Prayer and Advice Page Photo Credits Real Housewives of New Jersey Giudice Legal Documents Taylor Armstrong / Shanna Ford / Insert Name Here Year End Survey 
 ← IHJZ Housewives News / Bethenny’s E! True Hollywood Story / Top Chef Just Desserts IHJZ Real Housewives News / Real Housewives of Beverly Hills–The Blogs → 
IHJZ Real Housewives News / Project Runway / Alex&amp;Simon on GMA
 Posted on September 23, 2011 by LynnNChicago 
 IHJZ Real Housewives of New York 

Here is a recent post for Rumor Fix:

 http://rumorfix.com/2011/09/three-new-real-housewives-for-new-york/ 

There are three new housewives, unconfirmed by Bravo but then they never really announce cast members until just before the season begins to air, we typically hear everything from the Housewives on Twitter or Facebook.

One of the new housewives has become my new favorite already.

Heather Thomson already has several points in her favor before she utters her first word on screen.  She is a true fashionista and has her own line of…wait for it….Shapewear!  I love her already!  This has got to be making Jill’s blood pressure rise by the minute.  (I’m sure she’s enjoying her European vacation!)  But there is more!  A very close friend of mine has a  connection to Heather, my friend’s sister-in-law was Heather’s roommate in College!  So what do we already know about Heather?  Here’s what I learned:

Heather was a fashionista even back in college, one of those people who look great no matter what they’re wearing.  Heather could throw on a pair of jeans and a t-shirt and look like a million bucks!  (don’t you hate people like that?  lol)  Heather took a year off after high school before heading off to Becker College in Massachusetts .  She was a year older than most in her class and was able to drink a year before most in her class.  Heather was the ultimate party girl, she is described as,“lovely, fun and the star of whatever room she is in”.  Let’s see how she does as a Bravo Housewife!

Do you suppose that Bravo went and searched for someone with their own shapewear line just to get that last dig in at Zarin?  Let’s face it, they’re not a dime a dozen, there are a whole lot of fashion designers out there but someone who designs shapewear had to be tough to find.  All I can say is great casting- Bravo Bravo!!! 

I can just see Jill’s face when she found out that the new Housewife designs shapewear,“Is this a joke?”Jill would say,“Bawby, find out if this woman has more money than we do.  I can’t believe Bravo is doing this to me, the Shapewear is the only thing I have left and they replace me with this woman who has a shapewear line?  Can they do that Bawby?  Can we sue them?”

This has to be“Karma”in its most pure form!

I love this, Jilzy is twisting everything and blaming Ramona for getting her fired.  US Weekly posted this:

 Did Ramona Singer push Jill Zarin out of The Real Housewives of New York City? 

 Days after Bravo confirmed reports that Zarin, 47, would not be returning for a fifth season, a source told the new issue of Us Weekly (out now) that the pinot grigio-swilling Singer“wanted Jill out and her friends in.” 

 (Alex McCord, 37, Kelly Bensimon, 43, and Cindy Barshop, 47, were also axed from the hit reality series . ) 

 According to the source, Singer“came to Bravo with a few pals she thought would make good additions. Bravo decided to go with the new girls and not Jill, so Ramona basically ran her off the show.” 

 Singer insists she doesn’t wield that much power, telling Us:“We can recommend people to come to the show, but it’s not my decision.” 

 Though Zarin was part of the original cast, she probably won’t be missed by her former costars.“Jill caused a lot of problems,”another insider tells Us.“Her castmates were upset with her, since she’d tweet all these negative things. Karma’s a bitch.” 

The“insider”who is trying to blame Ramona is most likely Jill herself but as Ramona says, she can only recommend people, she doesn’t get to cast the show.  (or casted if you’re Kelly Bensimon)  I would bet at any time all of the Housewives have made recommendations to Bravo over the years and introduced friends or acquaintances to Andy at parties.  We all heard the rumor that Bravo was planning on replacing some of the housewives, what better opportunity to make some suggestions?  Of course a Housewife would prefer to work with friends than the unknown!

I can confirm that Ramona does not know Heather Thomson and that she was not one of Ramona’s recommendations.  The bottom line is that Jill was going to be fired regardless of whether or not Ramona introduced some of her friends to Bravo producers.  If they hadn’t found new cast members through Ramona, they’d have found them another way.

Jill appeared on the Joy Behar show yesterday, you can watch it here:

 http://joybehar.blogs.cnn.com/2011/09/22/jill-zarin-on-being-fired-from-real-housewives/ 

Joy wasted a lot of time talking about how Jill got fired, it was on the telephone, Joy thought it should be in person.  Joy thought that they should go to Jill’s house and fire her there.  How stupid!  Who does that?  Can you imagine how awkward that would have been, particularly for Jill,“You’re fired Jill”Jill would respond,“ahh ok, would you like some tea and latkas?”Joy is a moron!

Jill actually seemed shocked at Ramona’s comments and says that Ramona is beating a dog when it’s down and putting a nail in the coffin…..I suppose it was ok for Jill to spread rumors that Ramona is an alcoholic and that Mario is cheating on her.  Jill calls people“toxic”yet she’s surprised that Ramona used the word“cancerous”.   Joy’s quote was actually twisted (shocking!).  What Ramona said was that their relationship was cancerous and she didn’t even blame Jill for all of the issues.  The bottom line is that these two women do not like each other so why all the shock?  Because Jill was fired, suddenly Ramona should become fake and act like she’s sorry that Jill is leaving?

 Inside Information:  I’m told by a trusted source that this is truly the first time that a Housewife has actually been“Fired”.  Typically a contract will not be renewed or a release in a contract will be activated.  In this case the most recent contract signed by the ousted New York Housewives still had four months left and pay checks were still owed for those four months but this firing stopped any future payments.  Interesting, huh? 

________________________________________________________________

 Bethenny’s True Hollywood Story has created a lot of buzz and she’s getting a whole lot of attention from the show.  Naturally there are those few jealous haters but I know Bethenny’s not sweating the haters!  They can’t affect her life, her family or her bank account!  The best part is they’re still watching!  haha

I really enjoyed the show.  E! does a great job with their THS series.

Check out my RumorFix article:  Is A @ Bethenny Biopic On It’s Way? http://bit.ly/p3c1au 

________________________________________________________________

 Project Runway by BB 

Insert Rachel Zoe photo here…I mean…nevermind  (a joke for BB!)

 

 There are only 8 designers left. Heidi meets them on the runway and tells them only one thing. Image is Everything. Tim will meet them at a music studio to give them the details. Garnier has partnered with Rolling Stone to feature an up and coming band in the magazine. The band is called the Sheep Dogs. There will be two teams of 4. Team One is Oliver, Viktor, Kimberly and Josh. Laura, Bert, Anthony Ryan and Anya are on Team Two and they name themselves Team Harmony. Remember Anthony Ryan and Bert before when they were on the same team? Not pretty. Laura is also not very excited to be on Bert’s team again. The Sheep Dogs are a four member band and their music style is kind of classic rock, so they are big on denim and suede. One member mentions some type of caftan he likes to wear. Oliver is the only one who has no problem doing men’s clothing. Each team will create looks for the whole band and each designer will style one member of the band. Tim says the band doesn’t have to be cohesive, but they do have to look like they came from the same planet. Anya wants to design for Sam, Laura wants to design for Leot, Anthony Ryan wants Ryan, so that leaves lead singer Ewan for Bert. Oliver is going to design Ewan, Josh has Ryan, Viktor has Leot, and Kimberly will be designing for Sam. Each team gets together to plan. Josh thinks Bert has lived through the rock era, but can he remember the rock era? 

 They all go to mood to get their fabrics. Anya is really having trouble finding a fabric she wants. Oliver is also taking his time and getting stressed about time running out. Laura overspent and Bert lends her his extra money. She tells him she takes back anything she has ever said about him. He tells her to take back what she’s gonna say about him. I wonder how much Oliver’s accent is affected. Anya says Oliver needs to get over the fact that his band member is bigger than his manikin model. 

 Josh is looking at this like an individual competition rather than a team competition. Anya and Viktor talk about Oliver picking the same fabric he picks every time and how he didn’t get along with his client on the last challenge. The dual designers meet with their clients for the styling consultation. Oliver and Bert meet with Ewan; Laura and Viktor meet with Leot; Anya and Kimberly meet with Sam; and Anthony and Josh meet with Ryan. There are no big differences about how the clients are going to be styled. Kimberly is really freaking out about not being able to do men’s wear. Bert’s dye job didn’t turn out how he expected; it’s too purple but he kind of likes it. Tim comes in and tells Laura she needs to go darker on the jean. Leot tells Laura he doesn’t like to show a lot of chest hair so he wants her tank top to not be so low cut. Sam likes Anya’s design so far. Anthony Ryan shows Ryan two different ideas and Ryan picks the one Anthony Ryan likes so they seem to be on the same page. Bert is showing Tim and Ewan his design and Ewan says it seems like a lot of purple. Tim says it’s too feminine and Ewan says it reminds him of his mom. Burt may have to start from scratch and I heard him say earlier he didn’t buy a lot of fabric. Uh Oh. Moving on, Tim and Leot meet with Viktor and he tells him he wants to add come crispiness to Leot’s look. He shows them a cowboy look pleather jacket that Laura says she doesn’t like. Kimberly tells Tim she borrowed fabric from Anya for Sam’s design and Anya may be regretting her generosity. Ryan and Josh and Tim meet and talk about Josh designing for a gay band, but Ryan likes Josh’s design. Oliver meets with Ewan and he kind of laughs at the swans on Oliver’s shirt. Oliver says he doesn’t know if he’s going to be happy, but he will look good. Oliver is having trouble with time management again. He has Ewan’s measurements, but is having trouble figuring out the design without the manikin being the exact right size. Tim tells him designers have to do that all the time. I’m getting sick of Oliver talking about “plus size” people. Get over it, Oliver. Everyone is not a stick figure. Tim comes back with the band members for the fittings. The designers feel sorry for Ewan because he has Bert’s design. He definitely looks uncomfortable. Tim is showing Oliver what is wrong with his fit on Ewan. I really feel sorry for Ewan that he got Bert and Oliver as his designers. Oliver comes into the break room and Josh tells him he’s worried about him because his forte is menswear and he seems to be struggling. Oliver doesn’t seem that concerned. Anthony Ryan and Kimberly are stressing about running out of time and want some extra hours, but time is up for the day. Back at the apartment, Anya and Kimberly can’t figure out where the time went when they’ve had two days, and are noticing the challenges are getting harder and harder. Oliver says his design is not the worst compared to the others. 

 It’s runway day and the designers are hurrying to finish their creations for the band members. Kimberly is concerned about the precision of finishing her design. Tim tells them the band will be performing in their outfits instead of walking the runway. Team Harmony’s designs will be featured first. Anya still has a lot to do. Ewan is a little happier with Bert’s final design. Ewan is worried about Oliver being finished on time. He has been sitting on a stool in his underwear for about an hour waiting for him to finish. Oliver doesn’t see time management as an issue. Bert thinks Kimberly’s outfit looks like it belongs in a fast food restaurant. The band members go down for hair and makeup. They put Ewan’s hair in braids. It’s time to go to the runway and Anya thinks she and Kimberly are clearly in the bottom. We’ll see. The guest judge is American Idol’s Adam Lambert. The band performs in Team Harmony’s designs first. Ewan’s wearing Bert’s design; Leot is wearing Laura’s design; Sam is wearing Anya’s design and Ryan is wearing Anthony Ryan’s design. In my opinion, the band looks like old school seventies, which I kind of like. Anya hates her garment because the fit is not flattering. She wants to run out of the room. Laura likes her garment and thinks it’s flattering. Bert thinks Ewan looks spectacular and it looks very now and contemporary. Not sure if Ewan would have picked out that for himself. 

 The band is now performing in Team Untitled’s designs. What, they couldn’t even come up with a name? Ewan is wearing Oliver’s design; Leot is wearing Viktor’s design; Sam is wearing Kimberly’s design; and Ryan is wearing Josh’s design. Josh thinks Ryan’s look is really solid. Kimberly thinks Sam blends in with the band OK. She is just happy he’s dressed. Viktor thinks Leot’s jacket is stunning. Oliver is feeling generally good, but he sees some problems with proportion. Compared to some other people, he’s not worried. 

 I liked Team Harmony’s look the best, but this is going to be judged individually. This was hard to judge with the band members playing instead of walking the runway. If I had to pick some favorites, I would have to say Laura, Viktor, Josh and Anthony Ryan’s designs. I may not even been close to what the judges think, though. Sometimes they are hard to figure out. I’m sure they are going to say something about Ewan’s braids. Heidi is going to talk to Team Harmony first. Of the band’s combined look, Michael says there’s no swagger and Nina says it’s kind of an expected look. Laura explains her look first. Leot likes her colors. Heidi says it’s one of her favorite outfits. Adam says it’s one of his favorites as well. Michael is not a fan of the tye dye colors and it looks like he cut himself shaving. Nina doesn’t like it and thinks it looks like a lady’s jacket. Bert is next and Ewan says it’s outside of his comfort zone. All the judges seem to like the outfit. Heidi doesn’t like the pigtails and Nina loves them. Michael and Nina like Bert’s look. Nina thinks Anya’s look is too much like Pocahontas. Michael thinks he looks like Reggae Jesus. Anthony Ryan is next. Ryan kind of digs the sleeveless shirt. Michael says it looks polished. Nina thinks it looks like a woman’s blouse. Adam doesn’t think the look goes together. Well, I was right about some, but I am surprised they like Bert’s outfit. 

 Next is Team Untitled. Oliver is first. Ewan says it’s his style but he doesn’t like the color of the pants. Oliver defends his color. Heidi says it’s boring and they look like dad jeans. Nina says he doesn’t look the part of the lead singer of the band. Oliver didn’t have time to put a cuff on the shirt and rolled up the sleeves to hide it. Heidi was not fooled. Kimberly is next. Sam says he likes the pants but somewhere along the line the shirt got lost. Michael says he’s Peter Brady. Nina says it looks like old man pajamas. Adam says Scooby Doo Where Are You. Heidi says Forest Elf. Viktor is next. Michael and Heidi think the jacket is insane and it looks very expensive. Adam says the jacket has great movement. They like the sexy fit of the jeans. Nina says a lot of very impressive work. Josh is next and I think Adam is lusting after him. Ryan likes Josh’s look. Heidi likes it, but thinks it’s too many things. Adam thinks it’s a little too much, too. So does Nina. Michael likes it. Overall the judges like Josh’s design. 

 OK. Time for the judges’ deliberations. They didn’t like Oliver, Anya or Kimberly. Adam thinks Anya’s was the worst. Michael kind of takes up for Anya because of her inexperience in sewing, and thinks Oliver is the worst because menswear is supposed to be his specialty. They call Kimberly’s Salvation Army. They all three crashed and burned. Whoa, one of the favorites is going home and I don’t think it’s going to be Anya. I think it’s going to be Oliver. Kimberly pretty well admitted to the judges that she was just glad the guy was wearing pants and a top. I think they appreciated her candor. They talk about the favorites. Heidi doesn’t agree with Michael’s opinion of Viktor’s design. She says it wasn’t that “hot.” Michael likes Bert’s, but Adam didn’t like his pinstriped pants. I personally liked Laura’s the best. Bert is in. And the winner is . . . Viktor. It seems that Michael and Nina wear the pants in this group. Laura, Josh and Anthony Ryan are all in and they leave the runway. Anya is in and can leave the runway. It’s down to Kimberly and Oliver. I hope they don’t send Kimberly home because I think she’s a better designer than Oliver. Yay! Oliver is going home. Kimberly is very happy she is safe and she is very emotional about it. Oliver is not very emotional about leaving. 

Thanks BB, great job!  xo Lynn~

 Alex McCord and Simon VanKempen appeared today on Good Morning America.

Alex on Kelly “It’s hard to be on a reality show without being in touch with reality” 

 Simon on Jill“ Jill tried to get us off the show many times and she succeeded” 

Alex “Building a company is always better than fighting” 

It was touching to see Simon talking about his wife with such love and adoration even tearing up at one point.  This couple is going to be just fine!

Simon talked about Jill’s behavior and the words“Junior High”came up again, Jill being unpopular and even bullied as a young girl seems to have a lot of affect on Jill’s current behavior.  Simon isn’t the only one who feels this way as Ramona told me the exact same thing when I interviewed her a few weeks ago.  This could very well be the reason that Jill continues to claim that she was bullied on the show and on social media sites when she has never shown any proof of that.  The fact is that Jill is lashing out by bullying others.

Jill Zarin on Alex and Simon “I just feel pity for them using me for press yet again” 

Jill has the biggest ego I’ve ever seen, seriously get a grip Zarin!

________________________________________________________________

Over the past few months I’ve posted links and a few videos and yesterday the author/owner of those videos asked why I didn’t provide credit on the blog for her creations.  A reasonable question and as most of you know I typically always try to give credit for anything I use on the blog that is not mine and so I apologized and am apologizing again publically.  I am sorry for not giving credit when these were posted!

Here are her links / credits:  (hysterically funny, great stuff!)

 

 This is the blog page where I have the videos posted: 

 http://realhousewiveswatcher. blogspot.com/p/real- housewives-of-new-york.html 

 This is my youtube channel: 

 http://www.youtube.com/user/ velocity3d?feature=mhee 

 I am currently working on a‘Teresa’Compilation. 

I can’t wait to see what she does with Teresa! Thanks again for all of your hard work!  Follow her on Twitter:  @jjroland

Until Next Time…
 
 Share this: Facebook Email Print 
 
About LynnNChicago
I really am blogging from Chicago, the best city in the world! I love Bravo&apos;s Housewives from all City&apos;s and everyone will find this a great place to chat. View all posts by LynnNChicago → This entry was posted in Bethenny Ever After , Bravo , I Hate Jill Zarin , Project Runway , Rachel Zoe Project , Real Housewives , Real Housewives of Beverly Hills , Real Housewives of New Jersey , Real Housewives of New York , Uncategorized , Watch What Happens Live and tagged Adrienne Maloof , Alex McCord , Andy Cohen , Bethenny , Bethenny Frankel , Bravo , Camille Grammer , Caroline Manzo , Cat Ommanney , Cindy Barshop , Heidi Klum , I Hate Jill Zarin , Jill Zarin , Kathy Waikle , Kelly Bensimon , LynnNChicago , Michael Kors , Nina Garcia , Project Runway , Ramona Singer , RHONJ , Teresa Giudice , Tim Gunn . Bookmark the permalink . ← IHJZ Housewives News / Bethenny’s E! True Hollywood Story / Top Chef Just Desserts IHJZ Real Housewives News / Real Housewives of Beverly Hills–The Blogs → 
740 Responses to IHJZ Real Housewives News / Project Runway / Alex&amp;Simon on GMA 

 Powell says: September 23, 2011 at 8:29 am 
Was trying to catch Alex&amp;Simon but I had to get to the doctors. Tivod to watch later.
 Powell says: September 23, 2011 at 8:32 am 
Lynn thanks for the RumorFix about Cindy&amp;hitting me back on Twitter.
 
 LynnNChicago says: September 23, 2011 at 8:34 am 
No problem There are a lot of sites claiming that they were first to report Cindy getting fired but my rumor fix article was a month ago… 
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 8:37 am 
You should do a Rumor Fix of Silex and Romana congratulated Bethenny. This don’t sound right.
p.s. I hate JIll Zarin more than you.
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:32 am 
Good morning.

JILL ZARIN, YOU’RE FIRED.

 
 
 Powell says: September 23, 2011 at 8:49 am 
Every time you say that I just imagine The Donald saying it to her. You’re funny.
 
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 11:40 am 
I wish somebody could put a youtube clip together with Donald saying that and camera fads to Jill…
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 12:14 pm 
Yeah, with that look on her face that she got when Alex told her that Bethenny was done w/her. That“Oh, I think I have poop in my pants”look.
 
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 8:53 am 
Morning, Minkey!

How did the MRI go? I know you probably don’t have results yet, but I hope it went ok. Today’s the day for the brace fitting, right? Did insurance come through?

In the continuing saga of my son who wants to join the Marine Reserves but hurt his back, to date he has had 3 x-rays, 4 months of physical therapy, 2 MRIs, CAT scan with dye, and a bone scan, and they can’t find anything wrong with him. We have decided to take him to an acupuncturist/chiropractor next to see if he can“fix”him, even though this doctor is not on our insurance plan. Feel so bad for the kid. He had his whole future mapped out and now everything is up in the air.

Good luck with the brace fitting. I hope insurance comes through for you.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:26 am 
Hi Trudie. I feel so badly for your son. Our situation is so much more short term than what he’s going through. I can’t imagine what it’s like living in constant pain. Sending prayers that the acupuncturist/chirop will be of at least some help and doesn’t cost too large a fortune.

Don’t know anything regarding the MRI. Mr. Minkey drove the disc with the results over to the orthopedist yesterday in an attempt to expedite, but of course the doctor wasn’t even in. From the calls I’ve made, it doesn’t look like he’s in the office much. We’re not going to get a diagnosis until at least middle of next week, is my guess. (I freakin’hate that place.)
Fitting is today. Don’t know if it’s been approved, but I’d be totally shocked if it’s not. We have a good insurance plan.
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 10:20 am 
To both of you:
(((Trudie and Minkey))). We would gladly take the pain for our loved ones if we could.
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:49 am 
Trudie I think you may find success with the chiro.&amp;the accupuncture. My mom was in a bad car crash years ago, broke many bones&amp;her always bad back got much worse. She told me the only relief she got was from a chiro. It may take a long time, stick with it. Very careful stretching, like yoga might help too.

Wish both your son&amp;Minkey’s daughter the best!
 Furalis says: September 23, 2011 at 11:06 pm 
Very Important–Years of being misdiagnosed.

Be careful with the Chiro if it is a muscle disease. Is he getting twitching and tightness? Try getting him a light massage in the area and if they are tender afterwards it is the muscle. I have torticollis and went to a Chiro (prior to being diagnosed) and my neck went crazy shacking and twitching it was very bad and if continued could have done a lot of damage.
 
 happygal says: September 23, 2011 at 11:23 am 
Oh, how I love the sound of that greeting every morning! Karma is really what happens…and Lynn, You have GREAT Karma because you have always, IMO, presented the facts, your opinion and humor in a blog that just is the most interesting of the Housewife/Reality focus. Rumorfix articles only add to your growing popularity and isn’t it nice when things like that hapen…
So Good morning all and happyFriday.
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 8:35 am 
Sorry, don’t know if this posted on the other blog.
Re : BETHENNY
(sorry Lynn, I know you love Bethenny, I love you just not Bethenny, but will always hate Jill)
wow, this really makes me mad. Silex congratulate her many of times. even did a guest Appearance, u should know that Bethenny asked Silex to do an appearance. They congratulated her countless amount of times,even met for drinks and celebrated from what I hear. Ket’s not forget when they did appear on the show, u know the cry baby 40th episode one, all Bethenny did was bash Simon. I hate this woman as much as I hate Jill.
 
 sonjafan says: September 23, 2011 at 8:48 am 
I am a bit confused about this issue as well. Silex did congratulate Bethenny
and did appear on her program and I believe they twittered their congrats.
I am hoping this was an oversight on Bethennys part and she was swinging
against J, Luman, and KooKoo. I truly like Bethenny and love her success and drive and the mom she has become. Once again hope is was an oversight on her part, and she corrects it somehow.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 8:52 am 
I think maybe Bethenny was referring to a time before it became public, no one said anything to her, but she knew they knew about it.
 
 housewifeaddict says: September 23, 2011 at 8:56 am 
I distinctly remember Bethenny saying on WWHL that both Silex and Ramona congratulated her, while the others were cold.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:44 am 
Eventually.
 
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 9:06 am 
ITA–it was about getting congrats for her spin off. They knew but said nothing, except for JZ who said don’t film with Bethenny.
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 8:56 am 
I don’t like betheny at all. she isn’t being fair to her dad. it’s not true or fair the way she bashes him. I am hearing stories that her mom was psycho, and for a while her mom turned B away from her dad, you know them mature parents when they divorce how they use the child as bait. then, as B grew older naturally her dad had an established business, horse training, when she would go to see him&amp;ca she would complain she wanted to go party&amp;he didn’t let her. She admits to sneaking in night clubs as a teenager. but, one thing about him is he always paid child support so I don’t see how she grew up poor. her mom must of mis managed the money. he made good money. he gave, this was 25 years ago, so keep this in mind, but he gave her mom at least 2 grand a month.
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 8:58 am 
plus, she was always welcomed at her dad’s. she just never went, so for her to say she was homeless is bs as well. I’m sorry lynn, but Bethenny is telling half truths with her selective memory.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:41 am 
Only Bethenny herself can establish whether or not she felt welcome or just tolerated.
 Kat from Ohio says: September 23, 2011 at 2:09 pm 
sending child support does not make you a father. it makes you someone who obeys the law.

my guess is bethenny has a good reason to still be so mad and hurt. if not, what would be the point? she’s famous enough without speaking about him.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:37 am 
I did not take the things she said about her father as a bash from her point of view. I also did not take her explanation of why she stayed with her father when her mother left–that her mother said that he said he would only support her if she lived with him–as a statement that he never supported her after that. Her discussion of her mother not putting her plane incident, and him walking away from the situation, was more of a reflection of her mother using her against her father. He may not have been great father to her her, but the overall tone was not resentful, or vindictive.
 smompy says: September 23, 2011 at 4:50 pm 
So you have insider knowledge about exactly how much child support Bobby Frankel paid? That’s great. I’m sure you’d be willing to publish your source for this information , so that this whole issue can finally be cleared up. I’ve read several articles which reported Bobby Frankel’s total failure to pay alimony OR child support for many years, and I’m pretty sure Bethenny’s mother told this story, too. I didn’t know if that was actually true, of course, but now you can clear this up since you seem to possess personal knowledge about these things.

BTW, I don’t recall Bethenny claiming she grew up poor. I recall her saying that she grew up with no stability or security, financially or otherwise. I specifically recall her talking about how her mother hooked up with various men for financial support, and how, for a while, they’d live like kings, but then she’d come home from school one day and suddenly everything in the house had been taken or sold off, because the guy left and her mother was broke again. Etc.

But again, I’m sure you will clear all this up by exposing the actual information you’re privy to, rather than just making vague references to what, from a distance, sounds like a lot of rumors and/or assumptions. I for one can’t wait to see the proof!
 
 
 OneMoreInBoston says: September 23, 2011 at 10:21 am 
I absolutely adore Bethenny…but some things being reported are beginning to trouble me.

Silex *repeatedly* congratulated her. Silex went to her wedding, shown onscreen. So what happened between then and now?

Dunno. I still like B. a lot, but this just doesn’t seem right.
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:45 am 
Maybe she’s annoyed by how they congratulated her months after–not right away when she got the deal. After the fact they did congratulate her as we saw. But then Silex threw some barbs at her, as did Ramona when they talked about how the show would be“less toxic”and more successful without B. Lol we did see how that worked out for RHONY. These“work friendships”are always suspect. Look what happens when you leave a job. How many of your former co-workers are still your friends after you move on? My husband worked for 20 plus years at a huge corporation…he is in contact with very very few of his former co-workers. He had something like 100 people working for him, some of them he recruited, mentored&amp;made very successful over the years.
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 10:45 am 
I thought Alex and Ramona were at the birthday party that Jason threw for her when she had a panic attack and locked herself in the bathroom.
 
 Pghemtchick says: September 23, 2011 at 11:34 am 
They were.
 
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 11:43 am 
I really like B too, especially after her last season. But…there are incongruences in her story. I guess we all do that at some time or another. Did she really say she graduated from NYU?
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 11:51 am 
Silex went to her 40th b-day party also. Then b made a comment about him drinking or something and Simon tweeted her back,“not cool”or something. Can’t remember right off hand. It was a jarring comment though.
So RHONJ isn’t on this wknd I hear, and Patti is?
They are trying to shove Patti down our throats since NJ has nigh ratings and Patti don’t. OR unless they are making us wait a week til the finale? WT HELL bravo.
 
 If you had it like this says: September 23, 2011 at 1:08 pm 
I know. Something is fishy. I don’t think Bethenny is really friends with Ramona and Alex. I still contend that she doesn’t truly like Alex and Simon, thinks they’re weird, and thinks Ramona is crazy. Also, Ramona made a few digs at Bethenny about the show being better without her which I don’t think she liked. Seems like she talked about that on WWHL. Then because of the little Simon twitter scuffle, I don’t think she wanted to have any of them on her THS. That’s probably why she asked Sonja, who she knows the least. Sonja is always very complimentary to Bethenny so it makes sense that she would choose her. It was a safer bet.
 
 Wicked says: September 23, 2011 at 1:34 pm 
If I were Alex and Jill (when Bethanny was friends with her S1&amp;2) tried to get Alex and Simon fired (Jill s2) and leaked a story about Simon drinking to much (Jill S2) I would be apprehensive about Bethanny at first too.

I think Alex needed to learn that Jill did mean things without Bethanny. That would take time to go through all of the lies, denials, and gossip to find out the truth.

When Jill did attacked Bethanny on S3, I think Alex&amp;Ramona woke up and realized it was Jill doing all the attacking not Jill/Bethanny behind the scenes tag team.

Who know what lies Jill said to cover her butt or made it appear that others were involved (Bethanny) etc.

Bethanny (S2) confronted Jill on RHoNY about the tabloid article on Simon drinking. Alex probably didn’t know what to think about anything then–Whats real or Whats for the cameras until season 3&amp;4 with the Jill/Bethanny Fight.

IMHO
 
 icantstandthetoxicity says: September 23, 2011 at 1:27 pm 
Shortly after season 3 of RHONY premiered, Bethenny was on the Wendy Williams show. Wendy asked her if anyone from RHONY congratulated her on her spin-off and she said that Simon congratulated her. On THS, I could have sworn that I heard the narrator state that none of the LADIES from RHONY congratulated. Technically, Simon isn’t a member of the RHONY cast and he definitely isn’t a lady. LOL

I don’t understand how Bethenny stating that she was never congratulated by the ladies of RHONY has anything to do with Ramona, Alex and Simon attending her wedding or her birthday party. What does that have to do with anything? I am confused. The announcement of her spin-0ff show was months before her wedding and over a year before her 40th birthday party.
 
 Dani says: September 23, 2011 at 8:34 pm 
I agree with what you wrote. I think before it was announced to the viewer’s that the other housewives knew she was getting her own show and they didn’t say anything to her about it. It was like the elephant in the room and the ladies were jealous and Bethenny was hurt that they weren’t happy for her. She truly thought a few of them were her friends.
 
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 8:48 am 
I’m sure they all EVENTUALLY congratulated Bethenny. But not at first.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 1:09 pm 
None of us were there so how would we know. Its show business, truth on both sides gets mixed with fiction. From what I have seen in the work place, people say things to the boss that they normally would not say, to curry favor, so yes Ramona, Alex and Simon may have said critical things against Bethenny and vise-versa, but that is far from being a Jill Zarin. I think because of Bethenny’s past, she has a hard time getting close to many people. Show biz is perfect for her because she has a good excuse to keep people at arms length.
 
 Powell says: September 23, 2011 at 8:51 am 
I can’t remember who started this on Friday’s but is today“down memory lane friday”?
 
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 9:07 am 
Diva–flashback Friday!
 
 Powell says: September 23, 2011 at 10:01 am 
Yeah. Thks.
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 9:34 am 
Well, we did have the whole visit w/the Monkees and Sonny and Cher last night. So fun! Still grooving on that. 
 
 Cityside says: September 23, 2011 at 5:23 pm 
Perfect.

Is it Bridget who can make a pretty picture to go with Flashback Fridays?
 
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 8:52 am 
Okay, Question,
Didn’t Jill say she wanted her shape wear to be more affordable? Isn’t Lord&amp;Taylor higher end like Saks? I bought a shirt one time at Sak’s true story.
One time I was waiting tables at a high end restaurant. We would wear a nice white button down shirt. I was working a double shift and they hired a“wine guy”to serve wine. This idiot didn’t know his whole from his but and he opened a bottle of wine and some how managed to splash it all over me. I tried using bleach water etc. I lived further away so I naturally couldn’t work in my shirt. So, my boss said, sorry if you can’t get another shirt I have to take u off the floor. I had only a 1/2 hr, so I go out and the only store around was sak’s, cheapest white shirt, ! 195.00 yes, one hundred and ninety five dollars with a 1% city tax. And it was ur typical white shirt. Express was 90% less, and I liked their shirts better. To bad there was no express stores near by.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 8:55 am 
L&amp;T is more like Bloomies than Saks.
 
 Wicked says: September 23, 2011 at 1:37 pm 
It’s not Sears or JC Penneys that’s for sure. To her L&amp;T is cheap compared to the $5,000 underwear she buys.
 
 Wicked says: September 23, 2011 at 1:38 pm 
Pucci&amp;Verace underwear isn’t affordable to most people.

Jill’s underwear drawer is probably worth $50,000 alone.
 
 
 plainviewsue says: September 23, 2011 at 9:00 am 
Saxs and Bloomys are a fortune normally. Lord and Taylor isn’t quite up to them. I could never afford the first two, but I have bought clothes at Lord and Taylor.
 
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 11:44 am 
L&amp;T is like a classier, (sorry Alex), more mature version of Macy’s. No where near Saks in price.
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 11:52 am 
lol me neitgher, couldn’t afford that shirt but I had to buy it, funny part is I made only $120 that night. $195 for the shirt.
 
 housewifeaddict says: September 23, 2011 at 9:05 am 
Perhaps for someone like Jill that is“more affordable”. She’s not exactly in touch with reality.

I’ve got to say–karma has hit Jillzy very hard. Not only is she trying to launch a line of clothes that frankly can only be sold through name recognition–since there are so many similar products–which is hard enough and it looks like only one store agreed to carry her line (despite talk of Macy’s etc.), but now her main fan base (all 2 of them) may fall in love with a new housewife who is selling a similar product that presumably is already readily available. AND not only did she get fires–but she was fired in a very public and humiliating way. KARMA.
 
 Toront0 says: September 23, 2011 at 9:25 am 
And…Jill’s already made millions on the shapewear, according to her. How is that possible?
 
 icantstandthetoxicity says: September 23, 2011 at 9:31 am 
Jill is lying, she wants people to think that she is a savvy businesswoman, like Bethenny. The shapewear just launched and as of right now, it is only being sold in one store. Jill is a crackpot!
 
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 2:20 pm 
Jillzy stated in one interview that she was going down to Lord&amp;Taylor to unpack cartons of her newly arriving skwishers…..I doubt Coco Chanel ever did that! I want to see pictures of Jillzy unpacking cartons of her constrictor skivvies. Will they be DOA? I imagine, like her bedding, they will be heavily discounted (LIKE LUANN) and on clearance even before the Christmas shopping season.
 
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 2:28 pm 
I’m sure the next batch will be constrictor skwishers for pets. I would hate for the New York, Hamptons and Hollywood elite pets to miss out on wearing just the right outfit because they ate too many lamb chops and hadn’t had time to deposit the digested lamb onto the living room carpet. I can’t wait to see the tweets that Ginger starts posting about that!
 
 
 sony4ou says: September 23, 2011 at 9:36 am 
She was saying that before it hit stores..I do not see how it is possible. She really is a delusional fool. She still has not take“Star of RHONY”off of her twitter, it just irritates me.
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:51 am 
This is how it is possible:

1. She has to be talking in terms of gross, not net
2. She has to be including potential sales, ie the projections the company provided the bank in obtaining financing
3. Wishfull thinking.
 
 happygal says: September 23, 2011 at 11:33 am 
Wishful thinking for sure…I went online to check out the cr@p, and ewwwww- first it is ugly, second granny panties and the most insulting is the cost! If I want shapewear…and unfortunately, i sometimes need it…. I buy brands i trust, Flexies, or Bali, or any other longstanding company.
 Wicked says: September 23, 2011 at 1:41 pm 
It’s not on individual sale its on Bulk orders shipped to stores warehouses. Whether or not it sells at L&amp;T doesn’t matter, she is already paid to stock the store. It’s L&amp;T’s loss now.

Only 3 million people watch RHoNY, people probably won’t even know it’s Jill’s or who Jill is.
 
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:59 am 
When I was a kid, L&amp;T was considered very fashionable and pricey. Ladies used to get all dressed up, and during shopping would lunch on little finger sandwiches and chicken salad in their Birdcage restaurant. My grandmother used to put on her white gloves and take me to there when I was really young, and just I hated going to that Birdcage filled with all those proper women.
Times sure have changed, and L&amp;T has too.
 
 Pamela says: September 23, 2011 at 10:28 am 
With Jill there unloading all of her girdles I picture more of a Cuckoo’s nest than a Birdcage.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:42 am 
Got that right, Pamela. Lol.
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 3:54 pm 
Do you mean the one on City Line Ave. in Bala Cynwyd? My Mom and grandmother&amp;I used to go to the Birdcage, but no one got especially dressed up. I loved the Birdcage. I recall that they had several real birds in the cage when I was little—I think they were lovebirds or some small, colorful birds, not parrots, in this very large and tall bird cage at the front of the restaurant. Later they got rid of the birds and put fake birds in it, and it just wasn’t the same. I guess the birds were regarded as too much work and too expensive for the staff to care for. By the 1980′s Lord&amp;Taylor (at that location, anyway) was already kind of run down. In the early 90s I went to their store near Princeton, and got lots of great things. They were very competetive on price and had great quality clothes under their store label. But I haven’t been to an L&amp;T in years. There’s one in King of Prussia, but I think I’ve only been in there once.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 6:30 pm 
L&amp;T used to be Hayne’s. It’s on par with Macy’s. I shop at L&amp;T and they have GREAT sales. one of the best deals i got was a $90 Ralph Lauren blouse for $11.00. i would consider L&amp;T affordable.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 6:33 pm 
i’m not 100% sure but isn’t Bethenny’s shapewear available in Target?
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 11:10 pm 
Not that I am aware. I’ve been reading for some time that she hoped to have a“store within a store”in Target. Don’t know if it’s actually in the works or not.
 
 
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 8:55 am 
Why is NJ not on this Sunday? My TV Guide channel shows Patti’s MM. Bravo is getting too be Patti all the time, she’s even on for the hour-long WWHL. I guess I’ll be watching The Amazing Race and some Netflix.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:00 am 
Really? It makes no sense to me, either, why Bravo will reschedule a show to another night, or put something new in it’s place, before the series concludes.
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 9:00 am 
They are trying to shove Patti down our throats since NJ has nigh ratings and Patti don’t. OR unless they are making us wait a week til the finale?
 
 housewifeaddict says: September 23, 2011 at 9:08 am 
Do they not realize that we have a remote? Seriously–all they do by trying to shove skanker or those other unwatchable shows like the one in dallas down our throats is train us to go to other channels first to see what’s on.
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 9:10 am 
ITA–Bravo is trying to shove the skanker into a ratings spot!
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 9:38 am 
Well, note to Andy: I don’t like Lima beans and putting them on my plate every day is not going to make me develop a taste for them.
HWA, ITA–all of the other networks have their new seasons back on–we may become very familiar with NBC, CBS, ABC and Fox.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:58 am 
There is always Hulu
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 am 
“I don’t like Lima beans and putting them on my plate every day is not going to make me develop a taste for them.”

OK, that made me choke on my ice tea!
 Queen Butter Bean says: September 23, 2011 at 12:28 pm 
You don’t like Lima Beans?!?!?!?!?!?

:,-(
 Kansas Girl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:46 pm 
Empress, I’ll eat your limas for you. I love them! Schooch them around on your plate so Mom doesn’t know you didn’t eat any.
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 1:18 pm 
OBB and Kansas, never liked lima beans, but strangely enough I Love brussel sprouts. Mom would serve lima beans and we would sneak them to the dog.
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:12 pm 
Fresh (or dried) limas are yum–frozen limas are yuck.
 
 
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 9:58 am 
That approach will backfire for Stanker. The more they forcefeed, the more we gag. She is just too much. A little bit of her, we could maybe tolerate–too much is too much. They will soon hear loud protests to get her off the screen. Enough already.
 
 lizzielou says: September 23, 2011 at 10:10 am 
I’ve tried to watch MM on several occassions. I can’t. Skanker really bothers me.
 
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 am 
What is it about Patti and Andy?
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 3:57 pm 
I don’t know, but I won’t be watching“Pandy.”
 
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:20 am 
MM is barely getting over 1 million viewers on its Thursday night spot. Project Runway is getting about 3 times that. Bravo is being is crazy supporting MM. Didn’t they just extend her contract recently? Way to lose $ Bravo! And viewers lol.

 http://tvbythenumbers.zap2it.com/2011/09/16/thursday-cable-jersey-shore-slips-sunny-archer-premieres-beyond-scared-straight-la-ink-finales-more/103911/ 
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 10:23 am 
She lost me when I saw her demonstrate her“no sex before monogamy”spiel where she points out three orifices and says“no in, in or in”. She speaks to those people like she is giving a stranger-danger speech to toddlers.
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:35 am 
How Bravo thinks they are going to get more people to watch the Stankass is beyond me. I think Andy is in deep deep doo doo over at Bravo&amp;he is desperately trying to get another job. Did you see on the Nightline piece how he equates the HWs to“crack cocaine?”He is addicted to the toxic catfights&amp;he loves to stir the pot just to watch the claws come out.
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 11:19 am 
Yeah, I don’t find any of that cute or funny. And neither do her clients, apparently. They all look at her like she’s crude and she just makes everyone around her uncomfortable. W/all of the dough she must be making, do you think she could take advantage of a little etiquette training, maybe?
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 4:01 pm 
That was nothing compared to that creepy woman she employs who’s like 80 talking to guys in their 30s about sex and their genitals. If anything would kill one’s sex drive, it would be her. Watching her talk about sex gives me that grossed-out feeling I had when listening to matronly teachers lecture us about menstruating in 8th grade. I don’t like to be an ageist, but at some point it’s just effing creepy to be lectured about sex as an adult by someone who’s 40 years older than you.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 6:43 pm 
Dr. Ruth? she looked like 80 years old 30 years ago and she still look 80 years old. very odd. i worked with a man in the late’80s, a very attractive man i might add, who dated her daughter. LOL Dr. Ruth was such a natural at it though.
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 10:58 pm 
No, not Dr. Ruth, I’m talking about a woman who works with Patty and whom she’s had on her show to talk to men.
 
 
 
 lizzielou says: September 23, 2011 at 11:48 am 
I love Project Runway!
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 6:41 pm 
I love it too, but for some reason this season I haven’t starting rooting for anyone! No one really stands out to me.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 6:44 pm 
i like Anya.
 
 
 RabbleRouser says: September 23, 2011 at 4:06 pm 
I can’t believe almost 7 million people watch the Jersey Shore. I can’t wait for those D-bags and those flipping Kardashian’s to fall of the radar. It happened to Paris, it’s just a matter of time.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 1:28 pm 
It is a form of brain washing. If we watch the show enough, we will get use to Patti Stinker, and want to watch her everyday. The problem for Bravo is that we have remotes and we can and will change the channel. She is as bad if not worst then Jill because she is a fraud of the first order. Madam Stinker!
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:13 pm 
It doesn’t work, she gets worse and more distasteful the more exposure you have. Don’t they do focus groups? She’s horrible.
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 6:06 pm 
The operative phrase:“if we watch the show.”I stopped watching it a long time ago.
 
 Psol says: September 23, 2011 at 8:06 pm 
So did I. When she made the remark“any cow can get pregnant”I left her alone.
 
 
 
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:55 am 
Good morning everyone, it is chilly in the great state of TN.
I have a little story from the weekend. One of our sons came up and brought our 18 month-old grandbaby, he gets up early and brings her [in] to put in bed with her sparkle-grammy and granddaddy. Huuuuuuf….2 seconds later there’s like a GALLON of gatorade/vomick, but sparkle-grammy has it contained (between us). I fully expect grandaddy to leap from the bed with cosmic superhero speed to get a towel etc.
Time passes
……..(this is time passing)……………………………………………………………
maybe 10 seconds–felt like 30 min.
Granddaddy says,“Sparkle, did you SEE that?”
 
 OneMoreInBoston says: September 23, 2011 at 10:22 am 
LOL! ahhh…men.
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:32 am 
lol I wonder who cleaned up that mess? Anything connected to vomit etc. lands in my department. My female German shepherd has a very nervous stomach. Sooner or later she vomits…and my tough guy H.S. football player can’t stand to clean it up!
 
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 10:43 am 
Is that a man-story or what? yes, I cleaned up as grandaddy is a vomick-er too:)
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 11:27 am 
; )
 
 
 RabbleRouser says: September 23, 2011 at 4:17 pm 
LOL…
 
 plainviewsue says: September 23, 2011 at 9:01 am 
So sorry I missed GMA. Any chance the interview can be posted?????

I HATE JILL ZARIN!!
 
 plainviewsue says: September 23, 2011 at 9:01 am 
I meant the Alex/Simon interview. I saw Jillzilla.
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 9:20 am 
The Nightline clip is on Hulu:

 http://www.hulu.com/watch/281855/abc-nightline-fired-housewives-stars-break-silence-#s-p1-so-i1 

The GMA clip will probably be posted there later today.
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 9:32 am 
Simon&amp;Alex on GMA this morning…
 http://abcnews.go.com/GMA/video/real-housewives-ny-firing-fallout-continues-14589025?tab=9482931&amp;section=1206836&amp;playlist=2898870 
 
 plainviewsue says: September 23, 2011 at 11:25 am 
Thanx Blue Sky! Just watched it. I thought they came off great.
 Eastbayca says: September 23, 2011 at 1:49 pm 
I like Simon’s take on Jill…..”flawed woman extraordinaire”. This seems to be a perfect summation of Jill.
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 4:07 pm 
Good lord, I can’t stand these two. They’re so busy with their company (which of course they tried to use this little interview to shill), yet they were upset to be be let go? It’s because their company is anything but luxury items. Looking at the towels and lotion pumps, etc., it looked like a very average assortment of things you could find at Bed Bath&amp;Beyond. Extremely ordinary. I’ve actually seen more striking things at discount stores like Home Goods.

Does Simon really think neither he nor his bride are flawed?? He has been a royal pain in the ass since the inception of the show, and she’s just a complete weirdo. They have absolutely no taste and are 2 of the most deluded people I have ever seen on tv. I think the cast of Jersey Shore is more self-aware than they are.
 
 WasLurking says: September 24, 2011 at 8:10 pm 
Good lawd you are hateful about them. In all this time since the blog began………not ONCE have you given anyone else’s opinion a chance at all!
Can you just not see or refuse to see them as people with flaws?
You so confuse me…….. like a pit bull with attitude and no real reason why except you were‘leashed’that way.
(I have a Pit bull…..he’s the loveliest most heart filled critter in the world.)

blah….this is two blogs back so won’t be read..no biggy…just a vent!
 
 
 Eastbayca says: September 23, 2011 at 2:56 pm 
Hmmm Silex interview much better than Jill.
 
 
 Dubyaveeyou says: September 23, 2011 at 9:05 am 
Project Runways has always been a favorite but last season was a snore. I didn’t have much faith in PR’s ability to draw me in again, but this latest challenge was ingenious. However, I kept having flashbacks to the Jetsetter Challenge from Jeffrey/Laura/Kayne season. Jeffrey Sebelia’s rock star ensemble sticks in my mind as the ultimate in rock gear. Many of the offerings from last night seemed more like Kayne’s disco Elvis look-just so wrong in so many ways. Even my fav for the win, Anya, succumbed to dark forces of bad, bad design. Ultimately the right designer is eliminated. His design, fabric choices and personality were anemic. Go Anya;-0
 
 housewifeaddict says: September 23, 2011 at 9:11 am 
I was glad they gave Anya a pass on her mess. She’s got a lot of talent. I’ve got to say I didn’t really like any of the outfits last night. Shirts and pants don’t make my heart flutter. It’s sort of the first time I remember designers getting a pass because men’s wear is so difficult–but I was glad to see Oliver go.
 
 Pghemtchick says: September 23, 2011 at 11:56 am 
My problem with Anya is she wore Jillzilla tights last night. Granted she worked the look, but it made me think of JZ. Gag.
 
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:02 pm 
That’s so funny: EXACTLY what I thought the second I saw her.
 
 Cityside says: September 23, 2011 at 5:51 pm 
I agree. None of the outfits looked good. Horrible actually.
 
 Bella Bay Beach Girl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:51 am 
All of the outfits reminded me of a 70′s themed costume party where they were giving awards for best ensemble. None of them looked fashion forward or up to date.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:55 am 
Well, they didn’t have a lot to work with IMO. That band was definitely a throwback to the 70′s. I mean they said they liked denim and suede. You can only do so much with that. And so far, they are AUFFING the right people. I agree last year was a disaster, but this year is much better.
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 9:06 am 
I will say this–the new Housewife, Heather Thompson, is gorgeous.
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 9:10 am 
“Pinot Grigio-swilling”…talk about sour grapes. I have to say that I love that Ramona was able to just kick JZ right in the nuts. Couldn’t have happened to a more deserving person.
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 2:31 pm 
I agree. I found that comment very uncalled for. She may be swilling her Pinot but her products still far outsell JZ.
 WasLurking says: September 24, 2011 at 8:12 pm 
LOL…awesome!
Can’t wait for her wine to hit AZ……I’ll for damn sure try a bottle.
 
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 9:21 am 
Jill is not a businesswoman and all her projects will go the same route as the moldy book and no tell motel bed linens. She wanted tweeters/facebook numbers (not fans) to prove to buyers that her gaudy girdles would have people who would potentially buy her crappola. Now rumors of another tv show–lol wishful thinking!
Goodbye Jill! Hello new housewives!
 
 housewifeaddict says: September 23, 2011 at 9:24 am 
ITA. One prime example of her LACK of being a business woman is going on an extended cruise as her shapewear line hits the stores. This is her one shot at getting enough sales to promote it–but she doesn’t care–she books a cruise so that she can show Bravo she doesn’t need them (and boy did she show them hehe). It’s pretty clear that her merchandise was a hobby–not a career. For Bethenny it seems like the show as the hobby, and her businesses were the career.
 
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 9:37 am 
Bethenny and Ramona timed their product launches to take advantage of maxium marketing opportunities the RHNY were giving them. Jill daubled in a saturated market, didn’t have a line ready to launch when she said she would and still doesn’t have her act together! Now she is off on the cruise of a lifetime with the only people who are willing to blow smoke up her skirt–probably because then she will keep her toxic rants to a minimum.
 
 HD says: September 23, 2011 at 9:54 am 
I agree WindyCity and let’s be honest, how much more shapewear do we as women need? There are a million lines out there.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 10:25 am 
Even Spanx is a rip off. I have still have my Body Slimmers By Nancy Ganz (half slip) that I have had since the 1980′s.

I hate to buy new ones. After all these years, they are really comfortable, yet still smooth out the thigh in straight skirt.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 10:32 am 
Oops–9o’s.

And it has a lace bottom, but does NOT stick out below my skirts. So, nothing new, Jill Zarin.
 
 happygal says: September 23, 2011 at 11:38 am 
Gosh, I remember when those came out–revolutionary.. great line.
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 2:39 pm 
Is it reversible so you can get arrested for reversing it in a public restroom?
 
 
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 1:53 pm 
Ms. Zarin does not have on original thought in that weird head of hers.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:24 am 
She likes to lie and brag about the“millions”she’s made already, but she’s never been willing to actually put the work needed into anything enough for it to succeed. She’s lazy, and not terribly intelligent.
 MichellefromNY says: September 23, 2011 at 10:39 am 
housewife, you nailed it on the head. It’s the moment you launch you business that you have to be fully invested in it. You can’t just be like,“oh it launched! Let’s jet around the world and congratulate ourselves”Jill thinks she can slap her name on something and it will sell, as narcissists often believe. The problem is that business is stressful and especially when launching your own product–the work is far from glamorous. But that’s what zarin is doing–treating business in its idealized form aka“I get to choose fabrics and design plus make millions!”
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:58 am 
You know it! Remember Bethenny trying to sell her muffins in the grocery store? It was so sad. Nobody even tried one–and she had them nicely arranged on a platter, she looked cute, smiled so hard….just one person asked her“where are the ___ located?”It was so funny but sad. Then she was at Cosco, with Jason I think–was it a book signing? Nobody interested again. However she never gave up. Went on all her tours, countless times,&amp;gradually things started to turn around. The Skinny Girl margarita, book tours, etc. she worked her skinny ass to the bone. Jill going on a cruise is just so typical of her work ethic. Now when her skeevewear tanks, whose fault will it be?
 
 happygal says: September 23, 2011 at 11:41 am 
Exactly, B worked every opportunity, even when there was no turn out, she turned it into a learning experience of how to do it differently or better. That type of drive is really needed to launch something that has not outside backing. That type of drive will make things happen, but it is also the quality that can be difficult to balance. That is where I think, B is learning and finding her way.
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 2:04 pm 
It will be Alex and Ramona and Simon and Bravo and Andy and LuMan…and anyone else that Jill can blame in her passive aggressive way, on national TV.
 
 JaniceP says: September 23, 2011 at 1:42 pm 
I wonder if Bawby thinks her launch will fail and decided to take her on a trip. Haha!! I hate Jill Zarin.
 
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 3:39 pm 
I know Jillzy is partnered with someone on this venture. I wonder if the partner is paying for Bawby and Jillzy to take the cruise to get her out of the way during the constrictor launch?
 
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:08 pm 
“It’s pretty clear that her merchandise was a hobby – not a career. For Bethenny it seems like the show as the hobby, and her businesses were the career.”

as soon as i read this i thought BINGO! That’s it! that describes the difference between Jill and Bethenny’s respective endeavors perfectly.
 
 
 justanothermary says: September 23, 2011 at 9:57 am 
Good morning from chilly Minnesota!

We’ve been moving and it’s a bitch, but every time I get a few minutes to cop a squat and relax, there she is–STANKER- on my Bravo TV every day. Does Bravo just not get it? I know they recently signed some big contract with her. Are they trying to convince themselves that they didn’t screw up? I had my TV programmed to not show Bravo before we moved, but have a new satillite system where we moved and I don’t know how to do that here. I’m almost to the point were I’d rather see JZ than Stanker–well, maybe not.
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:27 am 
Good luck with your move Mary! Do you have lots of renovating to do?
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:49 am 
Hi Mary. Are you moving nearby or long distance? Up or Downsizing?

I’d watch almost anything before tuning in to the Stanker.
 
 justanothermary says: September 23, 2011 at 12:35 pm 
We bought a beautiful little“hobby farm”with about 8 acres of land, barn, pole shed and house. We are in Heaven. There’s work to do, but right now I’m just planning the big holiday dinners I’ll serve and we’ll leave the reno for Spring. I can’t remember when we’ve been this happy. Justanothervirgil hasn’t stopped smiling since the closing.
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 1:21 pm 
Oh, Mary, sound great. We have a little over 5 acres and despite all the work, it really is our slice of heaven.
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 2:33 pm 
Sounds absolutely idyllic! Kadooz for you!
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:15 pm 
How wonderful–congrats to you and JAV! 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 3:35 pm 
Oh that’s right! The hobby farm! What fun it’s going to be for you. Much happiness there, Mary!
 
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 11:04 am 
Hey Mary just had an idea. You could do a blog (or do a show on you tube) showing what it’s like to start fresh on your own little acreage/mini farm. I can imagine what the winter will be like. Howling wind, below zero temps, but warmth galore in your comfy new home with friends&amp;family. My brother says that the colder the weather the warmer the people, and that’s someone south of you saying that lol. I love the fact that you are living your dream. Go Mary!
 
 justanothermary says: September 23, 2011 at 12:35 pm 
A blog might be fun–I’ll have plenty of time on my hands when I’m snowed in!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:06 pm 
Oh (((JAM)))!
I’ve been wondering how you are. If you pass back by, please know I’ve been sending warm wishes for an easy move in your (as Empress sez)“slice of heaven.”

I am ver-y envious.
xo
V5
 
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 11:13 am 
What I had to do on my service to exclude channels (TLC, for one) was to set up a Favorites list, and check off just the channels I do want to see.
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 11:56 am 
I admit it, I could watch JZ over Stanky. She is just repulsive.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:11 pm 
i do watch jill over stanger. watch RHoNY but gave up MM a while ago.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:59 am 
Congratulations on your move! Hope it’s everything you’ve ever dreamed about.
 JaniceP says: September 23, 2011 at 1:44 pm 
ITA, they’re one in the same. Get off my tv Skanker!!
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 10:18 am 
In the Nightline interview, Jill said that she’s already made“millions”from her shapewear line. The interviewer seemed shocked and had her repeat this statement. Yes, millions, Jill confirmed. But since the shapewear hasn’t been on sale long enough to make millions, the money (if indeed it was paid—this might be a lie) can only be an advance payment on future sales, just like a book advance.

What this would mean, then, is that Jill has done the same thing to Lord and Taylor that she did to the publisher of her book. To get that deal, she convinced the publisher that her fan base was large enough to bring them a hefty profit—but as we know, sales tanked. Now L&amp;T is poised to lose some serious money as well.

To me, this is a type of fraud. Jill knew when she made both deals that she doesn’t have many fans, and she counted on the fact that publishers and store executives wouldn’t know the truth of her situation. She called herself a star and they fell for it, thinking only of name recognition. Shame on them for not doing their homework, but shame on Jill even more for duping them. I think her behavior is immoral.
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 10:24 am 
I think she’s lying–I highly doubt that L&amp;T paid her millions for her crapwear. Her philosophy is to fake it until you make it. Unfortunately for her, the internet blows that sh#t right up in her face.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:22 am 
JZ has NOT made Millions of Dollars…
She’s made MILLIONS of Rubber suits….!!!
When this venture tanks…..they will packed and shipped to mental institutions for additional padding in those
”special”rooms…..
Dedication for the JZ wing coming to your area SOON…..

Diva
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 11:48 am 
Ah, Reclamation at its best. Maybe JZ can do something good for others.
 
 JaniceP says: September 23, 2011 at 1:46 pm 
I just made a mil reading this blog…I wish!
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 10:24 am 
I can’t understand how L&amp;T would pay her–in advance yet–millions of $. More likely her deal is tied to sales results. Hahaha we all know how those sales results are going to tank like everything else she touches. Didn’t L&amp;T do research? If they just looked at her book&amp;her bedding line that should have told them something!
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:31 am 
If they had taken a look at how her girdlewear looked on Jill herself, they wouldn’t have fallen for it.
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 11:20 am 
The way it works in publishing, the advance is an advance payment based on future expected sales, but the author doesn’t have to pay back any of the advance money if sales aren’t as expected.

I have no idea if it works this way with other types of merchandise, but if so, and if Jill is right about the millions, then Lord&amp;Taylor’s head honchos are idiots.
 
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 12:06 pm 
She’s lying. L&amp;T is owned by the mall conglomerate NRDC, an industry with very tight margins right now.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 2:31 pm 
Thanks for providing this info! I didn’t know that L&amp;T was owned by a mall company—and if it’s anything like the company that owns the mall in my town, you’re right about the tight margins! (My mall is going broke.)
 
 
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 10:29 am 
That annoyed me too. I wanted to scream liar at the screen. I can see her Skweezies going the same way as her book. She will be shilling it during luncheons at over-55 gated communities. She has the attention span and thought process of a toddler.
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 10:49 am 
She is just‘counting her chickens’
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 11:22 am 
Maybe, but I watched the clip again, and she seems pretty confident when she says“millions.”So the more I think about it, the more I believe that the money was like a book advance, where the recipient doesn’t have to give any of it back if sales aren’t as expected.
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 12:07 pm 
Maybe–but, just because she says it confidently, doesn’t make it true. That’s one of JZ’s techniques:“Of course, Bravo wants me back”…
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 12:20 pm 
ITA, Sara–Jill says everything with this air of complete conviction.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 2:20 pm 
Because Jill is a lair?
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:17 pm 
Yes!
 
 
 JenFromCincy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:04 pm 
Plus, look at how tight she gets around the mouth when Andrea asks her the second time. She’s all but holding back a snarl. It comes off like she’s getting caught in a lie and she knows it and she’s pissed as heck that Canning pressed it.
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 1:22 pm 
It’s a“tell”, like watching a poker player.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 2:22 pm 
Then for Jill, moving her mouth and making sound is also a tell!
 
 JenFromCincy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:29 pm 
Hahahahahaha! Perfect.
 
 
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 2:35 pm 
Yes, she did sound just as confident when she said that Bravo wanted her—but back then, didn’t she truly believe they wanted her? She seems to think those millions really are in her pocket. So maybe instead of being a master of deception she’s a master of delusion. She convinces herself that her expectations are truths, and then tries to convince others of this as well.
 
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:07 pm 
“I have changed”and“I am a nice person”were said with the same complete conviction. Believing your own lies…clear sign of delusion 

Won’t be long til she’s offering squeezies free for people’s fundraisers, just like her book….
 
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 12:45 pm 
I also read somewhere that Jill said the 2012 sales were projected to be $50 million. That was before any 2011 sales as I remember I commented that she should sell one before she projected into the future.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:08 pm 
uhh…right. If she sells 2.5 million units at, say, 20.00 each…she’ll have 50 million in sales. Good God. Someone save this woman from herself!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 12:56 pm 
She hasn’t made millions.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:16 pm 
i think she meant she’s spent millions on the Shapewear. that seems more plausible anyway. it has to have cost her quite a bit of money to launch this product and considering it’s not even in stores yet, how did she make all of that money back AND get millions in profits on top of it. she’s a bold faced liar just like Taylor.
 
 
 
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 10:19 am 
(republished from end of yesterday’s blog)

 http://realitytea.realitytea.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/new-uploads/2011/09/teresa-joe-giudice-wedding.jpg 

I just love this photo from InTouchWeekly with Tre and Magilla Gorilla at their fake second wedding. The caption reads, “Doting Husband,” but Joe’s expression screams otherwise. I can just imagine what Juicy Joe was saying:

“Hey Tre, how long do I gotta hold up this piece of crap? The f***in’ sun’s in my eyes, Tre. No more pictures! No more pictures! You’re such a pain in the ass, Tre.”

And he looks equally thrilled here. http://realitytea.realitytea.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/new-uploads/2011/09/teresa-joe-wedding.jpg 

“Tre, sit down already. I don’t care about the f***in’ cake. I gotta go to da bathroom.”

Do you think Teresa even noticed? I think she was focused on the new free wedding rings that she got. That is, when she wasn’t shouting, “MILANIA! ARE YOU SERIOUS?”
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 10:34 am 
The first pic credits Kleinfeld’s from“Say Yes to the Dress”for her gown and veil. Do I see an episode with Tre picking out dresses at Kleinfeld’s?
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 11:25 am 
Yes and kvetching about: a) How she’s not getting enough support from Kathy and Melissa or b) Kathy and Melissa are only faking their support for her for the cameras. Teresa’s pony show is becoming a big bore.
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 4:17 pm 
Who waded up the hotel curtains and made Tre carry them down that gravel path?
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:25 am 
TLM…..thanks for the giggle on those pics…
First one looks like he sees his reflection in the fork..Hey is that a booger in my nose ??
Second one…he looks like a FAT garden gnome in a tux……

These people are so shameless….. UGH

Diva

back to making phone calls…Double UGH
 
 justanothermary says: September 23, 2011 at 12:41 pm 
Hey–I LIKE garden gnomes!
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 4:13 pm 
It scares me a little that I can predict what Joe Giudice will say in any given situation now. LOL.
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 6:57 pm 
I like garden gnomes too, until now! Too funny!
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:20 pm 
if these are the ones the printed, can you imagine the ones they didn’t choose?
 
 Dani says: September 23, 2011 at 10:27 am 
Can’t wait to see the new season of HWNY.
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 10:45 am 
Did anyone notice on those interviews the captions…
Alex and Simon…stars of NY HWS
MZ Zarin..cast member…..LOL
She’s a member all right…One of BWABBYS…..guess which one ??

HAPPY FLASHBACK FRIDAY..
BBL..got lots to do this Friday…UGH….
 Wall St Lady says: September 23, 2011 at 10:45 am 
Please Join while you still Can !
Join the
INTERNATIONAL Organization
To STOP Bullying Jill Zarin’s Girdles !

ILL Zarin is doing a press conference on the Hull of the WORLD BOAT today
announcing a
World Wide plea to
STOP
Girdle Bullying !

ILL claims
New HW Heather Thompson’s
National Yummie line
and
Bethanny’s wildly successful sexy
Shape lines
Are

Bullying

ILL’s
very young,
innocent,
inexperienced
Unsuccessful
Squeeze Coutre.

ILL Begs&amp;DEMANDs your support !

Show that support by buying her personal and private News Letter.
She will share graphic details of how Squeeze has been kicked like a dog when Squeeze is down and in risk of being canceled nationwide by L&amp;T

Bullying of Squeeze girdles is
inauthenic
creepy
Not approved by Lisa Lawyer(watch out)
Not blessed by Gloria
Not a Jewish secret
High school behavior
Un American
Instigated by the IHJZ blog

Please feel free to add other reasons
WHY
Bullying Squeeze girdles should
STOP

**Join quickly as there are so many people who want Jill’s secret letter
TEAM Jill may have to limit you to one membership per city block.
Not to worry neighbor clubs are being started; meet at the largest block dumpster tonight at 12am. (First one there will be the block President and will be invited to clean out Jill’s failed store at Zarin Fabrics in the Bowery).
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 1:01 pm 
Very funny! Lol.
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:19 pm 
Awesome! 
 Rebecca says: September 23, 2011 at 4:14 pm 
You’d better hurry up if you want to bully the Squease(y) line–they’re already on sale at L&amp;T online! I’m guessing clearance rates by Halloween.
 nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 4:17 pm 
WSL So good to hear from you. Have missed reading your posts.
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:09 pm 
You’ve written a perfect script for her.
 
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 10:51 am 
Dame, I forgot to ask how is the meth cooking going, and are you wearing Tre’s super-fashion forward earrings?
 MichellefromNY says: September 23, 2011 at 11:07 am 
Just checked the lord and taylor website. Only has eight of her“hundreds of products”which tells me that they are testing out the popularity of her line before moving forward.

Also, her“shapewear briefs”look like granny underwear. The“lace”she’s so proud of is done very distastefully. Overall, her product is so unappealing. I’d buy wolford tights over the tights she has there any day. They don’t look sexy, they look like a 50 year old woman who is trying too hard to be sexy.

I can tell you, as a 23 year old, I would never buy her products simply because I’d feel dowdy wearing them. I’d prefer hanky panky or yummy tummy for shapewear because they make an effort to make their packaging and products appealing to younger buyers.
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:08 am 
@RealMinkey are you still here?
I’ve been furious (by proxy) at your catnapper !!
When you do figure out who they are you can sue them in small claims court for the vet bills. Just getting served will freak them out.
If you’ve kept the“wrong”collars and have receipts from the replacements you purchased that’s great. At any rate write down (as best you can recall) the dates of the events and how long you’ve had Theresa etc..
I’d claim those people made her sick, or theft (pets are“property). Just throw everything against the wall.

I knw it’s not very nice but those neighbors who are stealing your pet sound awful.
 
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 11:17 am 
Cats are notorious cheats when food is involved. There’s a children’s book about a cat getting every family on the block to think he’s their cat. But I’m surprised that anyone would assume that a cat didn’t already have one home in the area, even if the cat was giving an Oscar worthy performance of never having been fed before in it’s life.

Your catnappers must not be real cat people or they’d know what a stray really looks like–very different from a cat living with a loving family!

Hope purple collar arrives soon
 
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 11:17 am 
“its”
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 11:21 am 
I’ve been thinking about your cat too Minkey. Can you put a tracking device or a minicam on the collar so that you can figure out where your cat is going? Or get the kids to talk to the neighbors. In my experience, the kids know everything that’s going on.

That story about the cat that ended up in NYC but was really from Colorado was amusing. So they got their cat back because the cat had the microchip….what a story.
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 12:08 pm 
You can buy mini cat cam’s. I have one. Pretty Funny pics. Under cars they go, (scary to think though) Neighbors YARDS, (oy, sorry neighbors) I bought mine for $30 it’s called“pets Eye View” http://bit.ly/nkDNCS I did a google search in Mozilla, sometimes the search URL’s only work on the page you do them on, so I shortened the link.
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 12:57 pm 
We were at the AT&amp;T store this weekend and I saw a GPS that you can put on your pet’s collar. I don’t remember how much it cost, though.
 
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:11 pm 
I know! And teh kitteh is so ungrateful.
Hmph. Well, perhaps they shouldn’t have named her‘Teresa.’
*shrugs shoulder delicately*
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:23 am 
Jill’s claim she’s made millions already…
If L&amp;T and other retailers ordered a total of 100,000 pieces at $18.00 wholesale, Skweez would have $1,800,000.
I’m just making up the wholesale price&amp;and the qty of the orders. She has a number of skus in various sizes so it’s not totally kooky.

That is not a $1.8m check to Jill, that is to Skweez to purchase wholesale for the manufacturered product.

How many reatail store fronts are carrying her line? L&amp;T NY, L&amp;T online, someplace in Atlanta and I’ll bet stores the Yenta belt in Florida.

It’s possible she can claim millions but she’s not depositings million dollar checks into her account.

I say good on her if she can make this work. If Jill can control the tummy flab of Gloria’s bunko club friends, then more power to her.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 11:33 am 
In the interview, it sounded like she was talking about she herself getting the money, not her company getting the money in exchange for product.

So what if Lord&amp;Taylor gave her the money to cover her duties as spokesperson for the line, just like Bethenny with Skinnygirl? If that’s the case, then there would have to be ways, spelled out in the contract, for them to recoup some money if she doesn’t perform as expected. (And we know she won’t!)
 
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 11:50 am 
Nothing Jill has done adds up to“millions”of dollars! It would be more interesting to see how much of Bawby’s millions she has spent on these“projects”.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:26 pm 
I think she has her debits and credits mixed up again.

She owes millions of dollars for Skweez.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 1:16 pm 
That is the way Jill talks. Everything remotely connected to her is‘her’,‘mine’,‘I’…

HWNY is‘her’show. Zarin Fabrics, a company started by her husband’s father and which her husband’s children manage, is‘her’store, as in“Welcome to my store”.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 4:42 pm 
Jill even refers to Bawby’s kids’children as“her”grandchildren. As if Bawby’s ex-wife, the mother of his children, the actual grandmother, doesn’t exist.
 
 RabbleRouser says: September 23, 2011 at 4:31 pm 
If Jill actually made money then why isn’t being discussed in various financial and business journals like when Bethenny made her cash grab.

Sure, Jill you made millions just like you have a yellow Ferrari that for some reason, you only drove on ONE weekend in the Hamptons.
 
 Wicked says: September 23, 2011 at 2:04 pm 
Jill paid herself a million dollar pay check. The company doesn’t have to post a profit for her to collect a salary.
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:28 pm 
it also cost her a pretty penny to get the line up and running. so subtract that amount from whatever she did sell. it most DEFINITELY is not millions. i’d bet anything on it.
 
 BlueSky_Forever says: September 23, 2011 at 11:24 am 
OMG it’s raining cats&amp;dogs here in central NJ! Be careful out there today with the rain/flooding. The boys are going to have a heck of a football game tonight if this doesn’t stop.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 1:19 pm 
Lucky. Our 30%‘chance’passes us by. Again.
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:30 pm 
i bet there’ll be flooding again. i feel really bad for those in the flood prone areas. although the government has offered to buy many of them out and some have decided to stay. we’re not talking about happening once every 10 or 20 years, this is happening year after year and this year multiple times. i’d take the money and run.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 11:26 am 
In searching the Internet for articles that might back up Jill’s claim of getting millions for her shapewear line, I found an article on Jill’s business. It doesn’t have the information I’m looking for, but it’s an interesting read anyway:

 http://www.businessnewsdaily.com/skweez-couture-shapewear-1791/ 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:40 am 
Thanks that was a fun read. A fluff piece. The author didn’t challenge anything. He calls her co-owner of Zarin Fabrics.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 1:21 pm 
I don’t believe she is co-owner of Zarin Fabrics anymore than Bobby’s Ex was a co-owner.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 2:40 pm 
I guess she sees herself as co-owner because of community property. (Or isn’t NY a community property state?) But if she ever had a real hand in that business, she’d run the company into the ground.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 3:29 pm 
No. NY is a separate property state. Even in a community property state, an inheritance is separate property. Zarin Fabric came from Bobby’s father.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 4:06 pm 
Oh, thanks! I thought NY was like California. But with Jill, it’s probably the case that no matter where she lives her motto is,“What’s mine is mine and what’s yours is mine too!”
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:32 pm 
as Bessi said, even in CA an inheritance isn’t considered community property.
 
 
 
 
 
 Lillybee says: September 23, 2011 at 12:04 pm 
I loved that at the bottom of that article there was an ad for spanx.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 1:22 pm 
LOL!
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 1:31 pm 
Oh, my god–the fibs and exaggerations just jump out an slap you right in the face!

Thanks, Sam, for the effort. It is amusing.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 2:42 pm 
You’re welcome! I got a kick out of it too. Jill really is, as my mother used to say, a piece of work.
 
 Wall St Lady says: September 23, 2011 at 2:10 pm 
This is the 3rd different version of a Bio iLL has presented. In Corporate America , particularly a public company or any Wall St offering document, A lie on a document is grounds for IMMEDIATE Dismissal. It is called FRAUD. The SEC would revoke a license and Goldman Sacks could ask for stock options back. It’s a good thing iLL can’t be fired from the internet ! OneMo Bo did some research that I will dig up to show you the 3 different past job descriptions. I am starting to think iLL thinks we are as stupid as Taylor does !
 Eastbayca says: September 23, 2011 at 3:18 pm 
Excellent fluff piece…..
Per the article (JZ) you have to promote the brand yet she takes a cruise during the launching of her skweezy things. I don’t think she is committed to having a successful business, its a very‘i don’t care attitude’. If she doesn’t care why should the consumer give a damn?
 
 ValleyVal says: September 23, 2011 at 11:44 am 
What the hell is wrong with Bravo? What is it? The PATTI STANGER NETWORK !!!
 
 LavaLady says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 am 
Just heard they’re airing a special episode Sun. night at 10. Isn’t that the NJHW’s time slot?
 
 ValleyVal says: September 23, 2011 at 12:15 pm 
It looks like they are airing Patti Stanker 24/7 to be honest!
I think they are trying to extend viewership for RHONJ for as long as they can. It has been a very successful season for them.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 2:34 pm 
Patti must know something really bad about Andy. Now I feel kind of sorry for him. Not!
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 2:47 pm 
Maybe Patti will admit she is a fraud and resign on the special episode. Let’s hope. She is Mr. Cohen first guest on the new season of WWHL, right after her show on Sunday. Its an hour long show so maybe he will apologize and explain why he holds this horrible women in such high regard. By his choices, he keeps letting us know, what a stand up guy, he really isn’t. Go Andy! I mean really, go away Andy, before you completely destroy the Bravo channel.
 
 ValleyVal says: September 23, 2011 at 4:46 pm 
I heard that before. It’s either that ( she has dirt on Andy ) or the higher ups at Bravo have special privileges at her club…
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:37 pm 
and he wants us to think he listens to the fans…yeah right. he should does pick and choose. i think HE wanted JZ, KKB and Alex gone and is taking advantage of that by acting like he fired them because WE wanted them gone.
 
 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 am 
Here’s what i read…

ME ME ME ME ME ME ME..
i am my own self promoter…..
So let’s go on a CRUISE the week of my launch…..
So what..did she pack them all up and is planning on throwing at people at every port o call…..Or maybe she’s making a deal for fashionable floatation devices……
No more Mae West vests folks…
We now have Zarin Zappers…..

AHOY MATEYS….. All hands on deck…

Diva
 
 WindyCityWondering says: September 23, 2011 at 11:57 am 
Wait a sec–didn’t she tweet she wants her adoring fans to meet her at L&amp;T to unload and unpack boxes of the gaudy girdles next month? So all this time that should be spent checking shipping/inventory/media announcement/website, etc is being spent on a cruise of a lifetime? What a dedicated and saavy businesswoman!! Harvard Business School should do a case study on JZ–the perennial, entrepreneurtal failure.
 
 Jezzibel says: September 23, 2011 at 12:30 pm 
except she doesn’t have adoring fans, she has a bunch of paid for dummy twitter accounts.
If she really had adoring fans:
Her book would be in its 2nd or 3rd printing(but its not, it sits molding in the warehouse out Zarin Fabrics).
Her bedding line(which she didn’t really seem to do a great deal of publicity or marketing for) was in the clearance sections in what under 6mths and most Bed Bath and Beyond didn’t carry it.
I think the shapewear is going to be a bust as well
She can claim she’s got tons of fans the support her, but they sure as hell aren’t doing it monatarily
 
 LavaLady says: September 23, 2011 at 12:43 pm 
I went to Lord and Taylor online to see her shapewear. Looks like she has 4 items available for purhase, 2 of which are on sale. No other shapewear is on sale, except for one item of Spanx.
 
 MichellefromNY says: September 23, 2011 at 1:11 pm 
I saw that too. It just came out and already it’s on sale? That’s not smart business. Maybe Lord and Taylor know it’s going to fail and are trying to get rid of as many as they can by putting it on sale.
 
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 4:43 pm 
Someone at Lord&amp;Taylor must have spoken with somebody at Bed Bath&amp;Beyond…..
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 4:02 pm 
Great sales–One item is regularly $41 and is now on sale for $40!
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:40 pm 
even if she did have adoring fans, you need a good product to sell it. her book, linens and more than likely her squeezwear would still fail.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 1:46 pm 
I don’t think that was next month. I think hat was this week, before she left.
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 12:01 pm 
Oh hush Diva, it’s about me Koo Koo Kelly. I need to like get some sea shells from out side and decide how to make a your tube video on them.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 12:13 pm 
WOW….Hush ?? I aint been told to HUSH in like…NEVER..
Well butter my buns and call me a bisquit…
It’s FLASHBACK FRIDAY…..

HUSH NOW…. CRANK IT UP………

 http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;sqi=2&amp;ved=0CCYQtwIwAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DeLzqQupzzmA&amp;ei=w718TqnCNc6htwf04elX&amp;usg=AFQjCNGJmGIXGterUpXujwjN35WfROlsww 
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 12:18 pm 
Oh yeah! Dancing in the office….:)
 wow says: September 23, 2011 at 4:41 pm 
Lol you silly.
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:12 pm 
Floatation devices…. ROTFL. (the visuals!)

Too bad she couldn’t get the ship to change it’s name to“Skweez Queen”.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:46 am 
Who watched Taylor on Dr Phil??? Wowzaa.
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 12:03 pm 
Yes, made me mad. The second cry, where her face was bunched up had,“No Tears.”!
Were you talking to me Adagirl? When you say Wowzaaa?
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:18 pm 
Love your name!!

Her scrunched up rubber face was really odd. In repose she looked great (compared to this season on tv).

I believed 50% of what she said. Certainly not anything about her ignorance of their business matters and why she changed her name etc.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 2:11 pm 
*Definately* not that she didn’t know nuttin. She has already said she and her husband were business partners, her marriage was 80% business, they shared an office, she knows whether or not she performed consulting services for any particular person for which she receives a check, and nobody changes their last name to match their favorite skirt.

And I have this to say about those other HW’s–Kyle in particular:

They read all the press on Camille and her past last year, so it is inconceivable they have not read it on Taylor. In addition, they had knew that Taylor was telling everyone who would listen that a Maloof was her daughter’s godmother and that it was a lie. Something is wrong with them, if they allow someone like that too close.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 2:12 pm 
knew or had to know
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:41 pm 
she was scrunching up her face to try and get tears to fall. still didn’t work. she’s such so inauthentic.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:42 pm 
TRULY inauthentic, not Kelly’s inauthentic
 
 
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 12:10 pm 
Me. She says that she doesn’t want Russell’s children to think badly about their father and then plasters her black eye photos all over the place and tells her many tales of woe.
She sure didn’t want to talk about the finances.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:19 pm 
How many versions of who paid for that damn birthday party have we heard??
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 12:26 pm 
I know Dr. Phil wanted to be the first interview but it almost appeared as if he were afraid to ask her anything even remotely controversial. It was as if he realized that she was still in victim mode and he didn’t want to look like a bad guy. He called out Cindy Anthony about her murderous daughter but handled Taylor with kid gloves.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:53 pm 
I agree. He was non-commital. I suspected he thinks that yes she was physically abused but she also suffers from serious mental health issues.
I guess there isn’t any upside to pounding down someone who is both a victim and a liar.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:10 pm 
Adgirl,
Re: the $60K birthday party. SO now she is saying that the party was“compted.”
The why didn’t she say that ON CAMERA?
Her whole life is a farce. She is so desperate to be something that she’s not.
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 1:25 pm 
Did she say her sister was with her when Russell’s body was found? If so, I think that’s the first time I’ve heard anything about her OK family during this whole thing.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 1:47 pm 
Assistant. Her assistant was with her. Who knew they could afford an assistant to drive around with her.
Her family apparently was left behind many names ago.
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 7:16 pm 
Oops, thank you–another Emily Littella moment for me.
 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 2:53 pm 
Adgirl.. the good Dr is not allowed to dispense”psycho med advice”.. His license is now retired…His show is for
”ENTERTAINMENT”purposes only.
He has to thread lightly or face a hearing for PRACTICING w/o a license…
I believe and it’s jmho…he does more harm than good to most who appear on his show…
Wonder if he’s having flashbacks of how crappy he treated his FIRST WIFE….

Diva
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 3:01 pm 
Two frauds in the same room sharing camera space. How could that happen on an American TV set. I am shocked!!! Taylor and Dr. Ill deserve each other.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 3:11 pm 
His next leap will to BRAVO..the psyso dr. for all their STARS….He will have to certify that YES..they are crazy and ready to be shown on TV for“entertainment”purposes…of course……WAHHHHH

Diva
 
 
 Kris says: September 23, 2011 at 1:40 pm 
yeah, but Cindy’s had 3 years and a trial to come to her senses and she continues to be a delusional idiot. Taylor technically is still grieving, Idk what stage comes first (denial?), but I give her a teeny tiny pass on not getting tko’d with questions. hopefully she will still be held accountable.
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 2:20 pm 
Dr. Phil was stupid enough to agree to Taylor’s terms–the terms that Barbara Walters would not. He was precluded from asking anything other that what he did. But I guess that is why Dr. Phil is Dr Phil. (I don’t think we even get him here anymore)
 
 Toront0 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:32 pm 
Do people get paid for being on Dr. Phil?
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:46 pm 
sometimes
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:47 pm 
that’s my guess anyway. i know he said the Anthony’s refused money so…
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Wow says: September 23, 2011 at 11:59 am 
Lynn,
Since the Bravo God’s granted y(our) wish and fired Jill, will this blog be still called“I Hate Jill Zarin”or the title I shall say? My only concern is it will get her publicity if you keep it the same. It keep her current if that makes sense. They say all publicity is good publicity.
I have some suggestions if you decide to change it.
Patti Stanger
LuAnn
Teresa
Joe Guidice
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:52 pm 
i know what you’re saying and i’m torn about how i feel on this. in a way, i think it would sting Jill to change the name. but i don’t think it should be changed to another I Hate _______ blog because then that diminishes it ever being about hating jill zarin. and let’s face it, no one should or could take jill’s place in that regard. my opinion only of course.
 
 Lulu says: September 23, 2011 at 12:13 pm 
My take on the reasoning behind RHONY firings

Alex and Simon—They promoted LGBT rights
Jill–A liability who threatened bravo with lawsuits i.e blogs and who knows what else!
Kelly–Appeared to be on drugs!!! Though I think it’s just her personality
Cindy–A Dud and can be perceived as a neglectful mother ( though I don’t think so)

I wonder if Bravo’s sponsors threatened to yank their ads of any of them returned?
 
 Lulu says: September 23, 2011 at 12:15 pm 
Forgot to add no idea why but certain networks don’t like LGBT rights promoted??? Stupid right!
 MaryE says: September 23, 2011 at 12:21 pm 
I disagree about Silex. I think promoting LGBT rights would help them on Bravo. Really, why would Andy have an issue with this. Now maybe it has something to do w/ Simon calling someone a C___? I know a lot don’t agree w/ me, butt I like Alex, liked Simon though S1, but he has become a fame whore.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 3:23 pm 
People in the UK use the C word much more then we do here. They seem to like the word. Not my favorite word, but it will not change how I feel about Simon or Alex. I think it was said to shock the un-shockable LuMan.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 9:05 pm 
I have heard the word used in casual conversation twice while in London, now that you mention it. No one seemed offended by it but a coworker from Sweden and myself. They didn’t stumble over it or seem hesitant to say it at all.
 
 
 Jezzibel says: September 23, 2011 at 12:22 pm 
The really scary thing is: out of all the castmates fired from RHNYC Kelly is the one taking the high road with dignity. She finally issued a statement on her website and its short, rather nice. I dislike Kelly but I will give her(or whoever is managing her) credit of FINALLY being a real classy person(it might only last for a day or two, but credit where its due).
 
 ValleyVal says: September 23, 2011 at 12:43 pm 
She probably doesn’t even know that a statement was issued. Her PR people handle her. How do we know that?…words like; Like uh, it’s weird, duh, and there are no typos…it was short but, SHE DID NOT WRITE IT.
 
 Jezzibel says: September 23, 2011 at 12:51 pm 
but credit to her PR people for keeping her on a short leash and muzzled so the crazy doesn’t come out. They are going above and beyond by making her seem(which she’s not if left to her own devices) to be rational about being fired in comparison to the way Jill is handling it.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 3:51 pm 
There is no there, there. Kelly is barely a person, to begin with. Her handlers are handling her. That is what they get paid to do. Kelly is a nasty piece of work. I am sorry that Kelly is crazy but because of Bravo she is going to keep popping up, talking crazy %$#* which is really annoying. She does not get a free pass for the way she treated Alex or Bethenny, ever. Kelly has been handed a great deal in her life, including the Housewife show, which she treated like a camping exercise, from day on. I think she destroys almost everything she touches because she is dangerous and very disturbed. Classy is not a word I would ever use to describe a snake. Even a sick one.
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 7:17 pm 
Her crazy will always come out. She posted twitpics of a business meeting in her bathroom.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 7:56 pm 
kelly will NEVER know how to act with dignity. like everyone else said, it’s not her statement(s). i think it’s only a matter of time until she extinguishes any dignity displayed on her behalf.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 1:13 pm 
Sonja also promoted LGBT rights. So does Andy. Bravo was the network of Queer Eye for the Straight Guy, winner of GLAAD awards. Bravo knows gays are among its core audience for many of their shows, including the RH franchise. That’s not the reason Silex were let go, IMO.

Rumors months ago that Bravo wanted to upscale RHONY with new cast, given the success of BH, appear to be correct if the new cast list is accurate. The old story lines and fights which continued through this last season were old. It may be that the Jill vs Alex story line, bought Alex this last season on the show, but the relentless fighting turned people off as the reunion ratings showed. Silex were always a bit of an odd fit in the show and if Bravo wanted to take it in a new more socially upscale direction, they would be even more so. IIRC Alex or Simon referred to being“collateral damage”and that may indeed be the case.
 
 Lulu says: September 23, 2011 at 1:58 pm 
Sonja’s a Morgan and what commericals are repeated every 5 seconds. Chase…I just think the sponsors not bravo were not exactly thrilled about the LGBT rights speech/walk. Though as stupid as it sounds. The sponsors are pro everything as long as its done in a PC type of way.

I do agree about“upscaling”the NY brand. The end (hopefully) to the bickering and fighting.
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 4:25 pm 
How long have you been watching Bravo?? The network is the poor man’s Logo. Starting with Workout, Project Runway, and Flipping Out, and , Bravo has had a VERY strong and uncloseted gay theme to its programming. Their programming head is an out gay man who has his own show, where he has often had other out gay celebrities on as guests. All of the Housewives shows have had out gay men as part of the show. No other network has been more gay-positive.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 5:05 pm 
Exactly. The idea that Bravo fired the“straight”couple for supporting gay rights is contraindicated by its programming history,“stars,”&amp;network execs. Advertisers who have been with the network and show for years also are quite familiar with the net’s demographics. Bottom line, for both the network and advertisers: it’s all about the cash.

Any advertiser that leery of Bravo’s gay-friendly/supportive programming content would already be limiting itself to sponsoring reruns of“Little House on the Prairie.”
 
 
 
 Wicked says: September 23, 2011 at 2:08 pm 
Could it be possible that Bravo truly only wants very wealthy people on NY and only Manhattanittes and not upper middle class like Alex but BIG $$$ and it wasn’t personal.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 4:10 pm 
Yes. This is the first rumor that was floated and seems to be the thing that materialized–whatever other reasons that was included.
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 4:31 pm 
It was not personal just treason on Bravo and Andy’s part. Corporations have no loyalty to the viewers or Alex would still be on the show, maybe without Simon so much. She is still popular. Its not great business to get rid of popular characters unless they make demands that are unreasonable. Bad karma. Andy is a rich man’s groupie. Always counting other peoples money like a 6 year old, with no shame. No big surprise then that he would want to revamp NY Housewives so that he could lord over another batch of rich women , and yes, then count their money.
 
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 12:16 pm 
Hey AdGirl, Don’t get me started on Taylor. What she’s doing by giving all these interviews and trashing her late-soon-to-be-ex-husband will prove absolutely torturous to Kennedy. This stuff will be on the internet forever. Whether abused or not, Taylor is a Psycho who is inflicting emotional cruelty to her daughter. She should just shut up!!
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:24 pm 
Wha? Shut up? NO WAY! This is her Academy Award acceptance speech!

What luck–just as all of their dirt is surfacing she gets to grieve for him
publicly, make money and dump all of the blame on him. Beaooootiful!

I wonder what he would make of her doing the thing he thought Bravo was going to do?
Crucify him publicly.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:16 pm 
Adgirl,
I wonder how her relationship with Kyle is doing?
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 2:40 pm 
Kyle is an idiot is she does not keep Taylor at arms length.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 2:40 pm 
is an idiot if
 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 1:34 pm 
Adgirl…She’s talking cause she’s PISSED that bravo cut out all the scenes with Russell…Now she doesnt have the street cred anymore…so she’ll wing it…TILL some lawyer some where asks for the VIDEO….
I say LET HER TALK….she’s just dumb enough to start leaving the bread crumb trail to the pot o gold at the end of the rainbow….The FEDS will be waiting…..So much for wanting to
”protect”her daughter……

She’s in CMA mode…..Kennedy is an afterthought…..much after…
and as always

JMHO

Diva
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 2:23 pm 
LOL. Taylor has PhD in CMA.

You’re right. Let her big face flappers keep on going.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:04 pm 
She’s an idiot for talking in re: to her financial lawsuits. She is getting caught in many lies already. I hope she uses all the money she’s made to hire a GREAT attorney because she is going to need one.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:07 pm 
i think she’s setting up a“Russell made me do it or else”scenario.
 
 
 
 
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 12:36 pm 
My grandfather died EXACTLY the way Russell died. I never me him, he died young, but I tear up just at the thought of it. When I see Kennedy, I can’t help but think of my elderly Mom, who was raise on lies, and never knew his family until it was too late.
Respect the tragedy of a lost life, a fatherless child.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 12:50 pm 
I am so sorry! We had a horrible suicide in our family 2 years ago. Things are never the same.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:25 pm 
I’m sorry.
 
 
 lizzielou says: September 23, 2011 at 3:52 pm 
I had a boyfreind that committed suicide about 4 yrs ago. Big hugs to everyone out there that has lost someone that way.
 RabbleRouser says: September 23, 2011 at 4:45 pm 
I’m so sorry.
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:08 pm 
((()))
 
 Zarout! says: September 23, 2011 at 12:52 pm 
A good friend of mine was childhood friends with Heather Thompson. She describes her as the“fakest”person she’s ever known…a real piece of work. It should be interesting to see how she fits in with the franchise.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 1:05 pm 
Sounds like a Bravo dream, then.
 
 Empress of FOD Farm says: September 23, 2011 at 1:27 pm 
Yep, but I still want to see some of these newbies with Lulu. Should be a casino. Go ahead, Lulu, call them darling just once…
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 4:05 pm 
And please, by all means,‘correct’the newbies manners and diction, Lulu“Ms Alls I know”….
 
 FLG (Mr. Tigre&apos;s Butler) says: September 23, 2011 at 4:58 pm 
LuAnn, please keep wearing“jewelry”that I can comment on!
 
 
 
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 12:52 pm 
Sorry for your loss ADGirl, But that is why it angers me for Taylor to exploit the situation. She must be heartless.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 12:59 pm 
In honor of Michael Kors’reference to Peter Brady last night on Project Runway and since it’s FLASHBACK FRIDAY . . .

 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 1:16 pm 
MARSHA MARSHA MARSHA….
OOHH my NOSE…….

Thanks BB
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 1:30 pm 
Pork chops and applesauce.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:46 pm 
?????
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 1:56 pm 
In one of the episodes Peter asks his Mom and Alice what’s for supper in a Humphrey Bogart voice. They tell him Pork Chops and Applesauce. You can search for yuotube by typing brady bunch porks chops and applesauce.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:03 pm 
Thanks. I didn’t have a lot of time to watch TV growing up so I’m a little clueless.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:22 pm 
Nope. You’re lucky. At least you didn’t stare at the TV, and then back at your family, and think:‘what’s wrong here?’
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 2:26 pm 
Seriously. I lived like that too.
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:55 pm 
V5,
I didn’t need a TV to ask that question. I used to do my homework at NHL games in a smelly locker room.
 
 RabbleRouser says: September 23, 2011 at 5:12 pm 
Did you ever get to meet Bobby Orr, Bobby Hull, or Eddie Shack?

I grew up listen to my dad talk about the great ones….(way before Gretzky)
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 5:59 pm 
RR….how the heck are you ? long time no see…..wink
diva
 
 
 
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 2:42 pm 
We say that every time we have pork chops for dinner. My kids have no idea where it came from, but they say it all the same!
 
 
 
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:30 pm 
Heh heh heh heh….this just makes me so giddy. You know, I remember the awesome Friday night line up–Brady Bunch and Partridge Family. Mmmm….Keith Partridge–wasn’t he just yummy???? 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 4:43 pm 
Sara…I have 2 videos for you..
One for the Happier Days….
 http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=1&amp;sqi=2&amp;ved=0CBoQtwIwAA&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DxZrn0UNAA00&amp;ei=Yvl8TtrjMI2Wtwe54JFo&amp;usg=AFQjCNGXFnYDTjGzPPLABRnSJBjm6As4Vg 

Diva
The second one….when he got busted here in st lucie for DUI..scroll to the bottom and watch the whole FHP dash cam…
 http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;source=web&amp;cd=7&amp;ved=0CGQQFjAG&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.wtsp.com%2Fnews%2Flocal%2Fstory.aspx%3Fstoryid%3D159681&amp;ei=_vV8TvmUOYaztwekn_Bv&amp;usg=AFQjCNHDb04j6IXpZTd-XWQpfIkT59OZOg 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:10 pm 
is was on a TruTV show video getting arrested for DUI. it was sad.
 
 
 Pantry Viewer says: September 23, 2011 at 1:03 pm 
Thanks for the video compilation (can’t figure out the name of who did these?) of Krazy Kelly’s OBSESSION with Bethanny. Funny stuff, but scary and so maddening when I was watching it all go down! Loved the hobag video!
 icantstandthetoxicity says: September 23, 2011 at 1:18 pm 
A Hypocritical Jill Zarin Calls‘Real Housewives’Toxic
****************************************************************************

Jill Zarin is on the screen again. Just when you thought you wouldn’t see her after she was fired from the Bravo show, The Real Housewives of New York, she’s back on Good Morning America to discuss her firing.

And Zarin contradicts all of her former statements she has made. First, she loves the show, loves the women, and enjoys all the exposure the show brings to her. Now that there is a firing slip in her mailbox, her tone is changing. On camera, Zarin shares that the show created a toxic environment for her and that it took her months to get back down.

Back down from her high horse? Jill Zarin ego surely shot through the skies when Bethenny Frankel left the show, leaving her in control to manipulate, bully, and harass other cast members. When Bravo had enough, she got fired. But Jill Zarin doesn’t want you to believe that.

Instead of admitting that she may have been the reason fans stopped watching the show in favor of other franchises, she wants you to know that she will be fine. Jill Zarin adds the irrelevant fact that she earns millions on other ventures. It sounds like she is getting back on her high horse.

 http://entertainment.gather.com/viewArticle.action?articleId=281474980372418 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:22 pm 
Maybe she should climb on Kelly’s horse that lives in her living room.
 
 icantstandthetoxicity says: September 23, 2011 at 1:30 pm 
LOL!
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:19 pm 
in“the”living room“of her brain.”

#fixeditforyou
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:44 pm 
V5,
No need to correct. Kookoo DOES have a plastic horse in her living room.
 
 KerryOkie says: September 23, 2011 at 3:51 pm 
And she doesn’t have a brain.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:13 pm 
LOL
 
 
 
 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 1:52 pm 
OT. Sorry, Lynn. Had to disagree with you on the Rumorfix article about the Bethenny Biopic. I love Bethenny, but I already know everything I want to know about her past life. Don’t need to see it acted out by Lea Michelle or anyone else. Bethenny needs to reel it in (no pun intended referencing her near death experience on the high seas) a little on the exposure thing. JMHO.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:55 pm 
I couldn’t agree more! She’s almost acting like Jill right now.
More isn’t always good.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 1:58 pm 
It must be some type of chemical brain reaction to a little fame. It makes you a fame ho. Even our Bethenny isn’t immune to it. Lol.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:11 pm 
I worry about Bethenny because she will always seek something more in life and it has nothing to do with money. I don’t think Bethenny enjoys free time.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 2:05 pm 
If A LOT is good, then MORE must be better, right?

Not always.
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:17 pm 
but i couldn’t care less about Jill. Bethenny is a different story. i think she should take all she wants that comes her way. i’d love to see her do that talk show especially. i just can’t even put her in the same category as Jill in any respect.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 1:58 pm 
BB,
Did you get both of your dogs together?
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:02 pm 
Nope. My youngest daughter got both of them for me. She got Cody from the Glade Springs area of Virginia from a family with little kids who didn’t know how to treat a dog and their mom didn’t think they were ready for a dog. Plus she worked and didn’t have that much time for him. That was about four years ago. She got Tanner last March from a high kill shelter in Wise County VA. He had about one day left. He was an owner surrender. Tanner’s only 1 yr old. Best thing that ever happened to both of these lucky little tykes.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:06 pm 
Do you know why Tanner’s owner gave him up?
Did they get along from the gate?
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:12 pm 
I have no idea, but I can guess. Tanner is a handful. He’s very hyper. He needs a lot of exercise to tire him out or he will drive you crazy. He has calmed down a lot since I’ve gotten him, but he’s still a work in progress. Give him another year and he will be a calm, submissive dog as Cesar likes to say. And he had some potty training issues right wnen I first got him, but he hasn’t had an accident in a long, long time. He just follows Cody’s lead in that respect. Cody NEVER has an accident.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 2:47 pm 
I wish I could make that same“he’s never had an accident”about my 5-month-old puppy Boris. Housebreaking has been a challenge for this little guy. (The past two days have been accident-free, though, so there’s hope.)
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:52 pm 
We had to replace our entire carpet because of our pug Emily. She was so hard to house train. I heard that a lot of pugs have the same history.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:29 pm 
What kind of dog is Boris? Some breeds are harder to train than others.
 
 Sam says: September 23, 2011 at 5:54 pm 
Boris is a Boston terrier. My two girls are Boston terriers too, and they were really easy to train, so I’m thinking this must be a boy thing. (I’ve never had a boy Boston before.)
 
 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:15 pm 
Oh and they got along from the get go. Cody has to put Tanner in his place sometimes though.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 2:11 pm 
What little cuties your dogs are!!
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:13 pm 
Thanks!
 
 
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 2:05 pm 
The Salahi’s another pair of jokers! The Armstrongs lite.

Tareq is also conducting a Victim-thon. He was shocked! shocked! that Micheale found a hole in her cage to sneak out of. He hadn’t realized that she finally was skinny enough to slip down the bathtub drain to freedom.

And Micheale, well it only took her 9 years to figure out Tareq was disgusting. In the meantime she amused herself by impersonating a Redskins cheerleader and stiffing hairdressers and wait staff around the DC area.

And Neal Shon, does he have a thing for middle aged skeletons? I do love that he email his a photo of his shlong to Tareq. Klassy.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:08 pm 
Are you kidding me. Didn’t Tamera’s son do that? Gross!
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:17 pm 
I dunno. Better a middle age skeleton than a fifteen-year-old…seriously. Also, I think it’s funny he emailed a photo of his shlong. I can’t excuse Michael(e) -however she spells her name–at all, but I am rather enjoying this middle-aged rock-n-roll show. More power to her, IMHO. At least she can get room service and backstage food and, you know: eat, and stuff.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:21 pm 
I also kinda suspect this is a show to sell more tickets on Schon’s part.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:21 pm 
I think it’s all pretty amusing myself. No“victim”in this scenario that I can see, except maybe the doberman.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:23 pm 
poor doggie *sob!*
I’m serious.
 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:18 pm 
Neal“Anthony Wiener”Schon. lol.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 2:20 pm 
LOL!
 
 BarbinGa says: September 23, 2011 at 3:06 pm 
Just tossing in 2 cents here…Although I don’t care for the Salahi’s (ok, I really do…no bigger drama or balls than them!), I seriously feel my sympathy for Tareq than I do Taylor Armstrong. I’m probably going to hell, but it’s the gawds honest truth.

I guess they both literally lost their partners in crime, I’m thinking Taylor should hook up with him!
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:44 pm 
HA! they would make an ideal pairing! i have to say i have no sympathy for either.
 
 
 
 
 BarbinGa says: September 23, 2011 at 2:16 pm 
Just popping in to say when I read about your connection to the Shapewear lady and that Ramona didn’t present her to Bravo…Jill is going to believe Bravo is in cahoots with you! I hope that makes your day Kinda makes mine.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 2:23 pm 
I KNEW it was all Lynn’s fault! Lol.
 
 BarbinGa says: September 23, 2011 at 3:03 pm 
Poor Shrill, the haters prevail! I smell a lawsuit, Baawwwwwby, get the lawya on the phone!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:08 pm 
What’s going to happen when Bawby’s money runs out?
I’m sure his family are shaking their heads.
 
 BarbinGa says: September 23, 2011 at 3:12 pm 
Between raising money for the family trust and her projected millions from her products, I’m sure they’ll be just fine!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:15 pm 
I don’t believe for a second that Jill has made any money from her“girdles”.
Everything she touches blows up in her face. How could Lords&amp;Taylor not do their homework? I’m not buying it.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 3:17 pm 
Nancy..the $$ wont run out..It’s in the
FAMBILY TRUST….I dont think BWABBY even has the KEYS any longer…..hahahahahaha…
He’s been put on an allowance..This pilgrimage they are on…the HIGH SEAS TERROR TOUR..is their last HURRAH…
UP NEXT.. selling of the CONDO in NY…. watch and see what happens…..
WINK

Diva

Can you smell my double chocolate with REAL chocolate chips cupcakes baking ???
YUM….and because it’s FF….we have to consume FISH…stuffed tilapia with lots of butter garlic and lemon…stuffing is artichoke and spinach dip……DELISH…with side order of angel hair pasta…and HM garlic bread….
Dinner at 9….you dont have to dress..come as you are in our house…..

Diva
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:49 pm 
Can I bring Emily? I promise I won’t let her drink out of your crystal glasses.
George isn’t house broken yet so I’ll leave him at home with the cats.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:50 pm 
May I
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 3:59 pm 
You can bring George…Mr Ford will show him the correct areca palm to use…..
and yes please bring Emily..she can drink out of my vintage blue glass goblets….they are the perfect height for her…..
I’ll send the jet when the MAID returns from her spy mission for me….
diva
 
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:33 pm 
Your menu’s are marvelous. Sorry I can’t join you tonight. I made a birthday cake for my husband with lots of extra chocolate frosting (made from scratch), and no way am I going to leave three men alone in the house with it or I won’t get a bite!
 
 
 
 Sara says: September 23, 2011 at 3:32 pm 
Yeah, me too. Now, she and JZ can never be friends!!
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 2:38 pm 
I’ve always rooted for Bethenny but I am tired of her.
Her THS was a hit piece on her parents. I think she is just awful to her mother regardless of what happened between them.
I did not break out in tears because suddenly Bethenny was“homeless”when her mother’s marriage broke up because, you see, Bethenny was in COLLEGE and she didn’t know where to go to have her turkey and stuffing. Tragic.
So sad, Bethenny.

And what about the long line of perfectly wonderful men who loved her but she dumped after they made life changing commitments to her? Now years later she’s holding them up to public ridicule?“I just didn’t LOVE him. I loved his family. I loved the idea of him.”. What a way to demonstrate your respect!

Geez, stop being an instrusive self-center whiner. And get off my tv and internet until your next show airs.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 2:42 pm 
All I kept thinking when I watched her was
Bethenny’s DOC (drug of choice) was men!
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 3:04 pm 
I just don’t think it is awful to tell the truth. Did I need to know? Not really. But your life is your life and it does not make it a hit piece.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 3:20 pm 
I totally undestand that. (But..) I think it could have been handled more delicately. It’s also the lives of other people they are discussing.
If my old boyfriend became famous and THS did a profile on him spending 4 minutes discussing how I wasn’t a fulfilling partner to him–that would bug me.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 4:29 pm 
I understand that. But Bethenny, with respect to the men, said that she thought there was something wrong with her, not them (she has always said that every man she was with was a great guy). I just think that no one came off badly except the mom–and rightfully, THS put up witnesses to Bethenny’s account. And, Bethenny, too.
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 5:12 pm 
THS does not handle anything with class, anymore. They use to at least do stories about real stars of the big screen, TV and music. Now it’s basketball wives, porn stars, reality stars, criminals and their victims. I can not imagine what will be next.
 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:18 pm 
I don’t think it was a hit piece on her parents. It was what it was. Her childhood and high school friends seem to back her up. I don’t see anyone, other than her mother, disputing how her early life was. And I don’t see any of her exes saying anything against her either. I think some of them even helped her after the breakups. Am I getting a little over her? A little.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 4:35 pm 
THS needs to be the end of it. She really did have a life pre-hwny that could fill books–working in Hollywood alone. But a movie? I don’t do Lifetime movies.
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 4:40 pm 
I said this before, but I thought she took full responsibility as the one who was at fault for those relationships not working out. She said they were all great guys (except for Jason 1.0).

Re: her parents, I actually thought this show was MORE complimentary to her parents than in the past. I was surprised to see there were times in Bethenny’s teen years where she did see Bobby Frankel. There was a scene at the race track where she hugged him when they were sitting in the bleachers. She did say complimentary things about her mother. I can’t recall verbatim, but having seen RHONYC, BGM, BEA many times and having read POY, I just had the impression she was less one-sided in her characterization of her parents on THS. She did say her mother“did the best she could,”that“she was a kid with a kid.”But it sounds like there are other people who back up the claims of the craziness that went on, including Bethenny’s own mother, who acknowledged that there were screaming fights. She just thought it wasn’t a big deal the cops were called to the house many times“because no one went to jail.”I think that says a mouthful.
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 5:15 pm 
Imagine what Kelly’s children will be able to say about her in 10 years. It will not be pretty.
 
 Ms Jxn says: September 23, 2011 at 8:12 pm 
Sorry, but if you haven’t personally HAD THE REAL LIFE of VERBALLY/PHYSICALLY abusive parent(s), I think you have no valid opinion as to how or what you would do in later year’s to heal yourself. That you may one day try to have a healthy family,..not knowing how to do that from example. You only know what you will never do,..not what TO do,….So,..all you do is what your’s didn’t,…and that’s the best you can do.
 
 Ms Jxn says: September 23, 2011 at 8:15 pm 
Oh,..this was in re: to B NOT Traylor!!!
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:56 pm 
exactly. i don’t think there’s anything wrong in telling your truth when they are doing a story about your life. if people don’t want to be spoken about badly then they shouldn’t treat people badly. she takes responsibility for her failed relationships. she doesn’t speak about Jill because she didn’t have the responsibility for the relationship souring, jill did and she’d have to throw her under the bus in order to tell the truth.
 
 
 
 
 We Can Never Be Friends says: September 23, 2011 at 3:05 pm 
 http://rumorfix.com/2011/09/exclusive-camille-grammer-steps-out-with-her-new-man/ 

Whoa, read the comments underneath about him.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:13 pm 
He sounds like trouble to me.
 
 We Can Never Be Friends says: September 23, 2011 at 3:19 pm 
I dunno what’s true or not but his detractors and defenders sure came out quickly.
It’s just super ODD how none of Taylor’s family (or home town friends or acquaintences) have spoken about her or been anywhere near her on the show, off the show or now, when a person needs their family the most.
 
 KerryOkie says: September 23, 2011 at 4:08 pm 
On Dr. Phil,“Taylor”said she was embarrassed about growing up poor, so I think she’s ashamed of her family, or maybe that’s just a convenient excuse to keep them out of the spotlight. They probably know a lot about Shana she’d rather not have made public.
 
 zanne says: September 23, 2011 at 4:19 pm 
They may be ashamed of her parents, but I question them being too poor. The high school she attended is in a neighborhood of 98% (or more) being high end middle class. Very rich school district. Has a basketball court bigger than the Univ. of Tulsa. Football team always one of top 5 in state. New band uniforms every year. Every student has computers.
 
 zanne says: September 23, 2011 at 4:19 pm 
She may
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 4:52 pm 
I was just about to say: I don’t trust“Taylor’s”representation of‘poor’. In her mind, it could just mean not having millions.

And Taylor may well have left OK and never looked back, and the family are at least decent enough to let her live her life as she chose it–without them in it.
 
 RabbleRouser says: September 23, 2011 at 5:24 pm 
Taylor makes me want to vomit, she and her husband defrauded people out of their life savings, are millions of dollars in debt, living a LIE in trying to fit in with a BH life style but is ashamed she grew up poor.

It’s all about the $$ with that ho. I can’t stand her. I think she is more vile than Jill Zarin.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:55 pm 
ITA!
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 8:58 pm 
so do i.
 
 
 
 Called A Princess... says: September 23, 2011 at 5:31 pm 
You can be poor and go to a school with a lot of people who have money. It would just make Taylor want to be a part of the money crowd, all the more. Believe it or not, there are a lot of people who have become wealthy by ill gotten gains. It is not a new story. The Armstrong’s are not alone in crookville.
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:02 pm 
And didn’t they show a picture of her in a cheerleader outfit? Most after school activities cost money for uniforms, trips, etc. Never really had the opportunity to participate, as I always had an after school job.
 
 
 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:25 pm 
He needs to wash some of that product out of his hair. He’s her rebound man, I think. More power to her.
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 3:26 pm 
He’s a bankruptcy lawyer…hmm…from Texas…. wonder if his‘short’term training was first for taylor and her financial woes…oops..then he met Camille……
Why is it woman with $$ dont check these guys out BEFORE they interact and introduce their kids to them ????
Geez…stop thinkin with your crotch….

Diva
 
 We Can Never Be Friends says: September 23, 2011 at 3:42 pm 
 http://www.dailymail.co.uk/tvshowbiz/article-2041114/Real-Housewives-Beverly-Hills-star-Camille-finds-love-dumped-love-cheat-Kelsey-Grammer.html 

More photos‘n stuff.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:44 pm 
Wow! She has gor-geous legs! Camille is very pretty.

But what sort of seaweed is on top of that guy’s head, I wonder?
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 6:31 pm 
ITA! I believe she said she used to be a dancer. Was kind of hoping she had a chance to be on DWTS. I think she would be fantastic.
 
 shiny14 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:41 pm 
Notice that the owner of Angel Champagne was there–guess the dinner bottle of extravagence at Adrienne’s house was mainly product placement for a friend.
 
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 9:09 pm 
a few things about this article…i HATE it when people write or say“could OF”instead of“could HAVE”or“could’ve.”ok, i’m nitpicking. don’t Camille’s eyes look strange in that one picture? i guess she’s looking up, but it just looks eerie. at the end of the article Camille says Taylor has been spending time“with her family.”who? Kennedy? i wish there were some follow up questions there. man i’m glad i don’t have to sign or even say his name. is it really necessary to make a name THAT long? he’s okay looking i guess but don’t like his hair. too much product or something.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 3:27 pm 
This is so sad…I love Kim Delany when she was on All My Children (today is its last broadcast). She has a terrible drinking problem.
====
Actress Kim Delaney Disheveled, Disoriented at Dinner Honoring Robert Gates

 http://www.nbcphiladelphia.com/news/local/Whats-Wrong-With-Kim-Delaney-130402588.html 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:36 pm 
OMG
That was hard to watch. I hope she gets some help.
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 3:42 pm 
Adgirll I watched that this a.m. I believe she is having a BRAIN EVENT like that news reporter lady…. It can and does mimic a drunken stupid stupor…I am hoping she seeks medical help for what may be wrong..
I really enjoyed her on Army Wives….

Diva
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 4:02 pm 
I would believe that too…except for her DUI’s and rehab visits.
 
 Lillybee says: September 23, 2011 at 5:24 pm 
Didn’t CSI fire her for her drinking problems?
 
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 3:47 pm 
I saw that. Sooo sad.
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 4:49 pm 
I’m starting to wonder if the rest of the country thinks everyone in Philadelphia and New Jersey is an alcoholic. 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 5:05 pm 
TLM..not to worry…we have our fair share here in florida..well of course they are the people from jersey and philly….
hahahahahahaha……..

jk
Diva
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 11:07 pm 
It upsets me that no one seems to care to get Snooki into treatment for alcohol abuse. The stuff I saw on there the other day is to such a level that it isn’t funny. She is completely blacking out, falling down, embarrassing herself and the drinking to excess is practically every single night.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:42 pm 
Yes. Yes, we do…
;D

*teasing.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:49 pm 
I dunno. I can’t see any drunkenness, and I don’t know enough about modern pills to make a judgement. It does seem as though she couldn’t read the teleprompter–and I wonder if it was just a service of needing glasses?
 
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:21 pm 
Idk what the heck was up but I enjoy watching her on Army Wives.
 
 Austin says: September 23, 2011 at 8:59 pm 
That’s a shame. I really, really liked her on NYPD Blue. I still miss that show.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 3:31 pm 
Well, well, well…Teresa the cat just arrived back home- her REAL home- a little while ago. She escaped before I got up this morning. Must have slipped out the door when TeenMinkey left for school or Mr. Minkey went out to the back porch with his coffee. She’s now mad at me for keeping her under house arrest, and she’s copping an attitude. She just went into the laundry room and knocked down the folded clothing on top of the dryer. She’s being corrupted and brainwashed by those evil catnappers!

Checked into cat GPS…$200.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:42 pm 
Do you want to swap cats? When it was time to get my cats(aka my kids) inside last night Roxie was a no show. Once again I’m walking up and down the street calling and looking for her. I gave up around 3am. My husband woke me up to let me know that she was inside the whole time. She’s obviously ticked at me for something. I wish I knew why.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 3:44 pm 
nancy..cause you’re out walking her streets….you are invading her territory..
Time to have a chat with her….wink

Diva
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 4:19 pm 
I’ll have to take her in to rule out STD’s.
Her little a** is going to be inside at 6pm from now on.
She’s no fool. I take Emily out back every night around 6.
Both cats come around when they hear us to make sure Emily doesn’t run into any trees etc. She knows I’ll try to pick her up (to take her inside) so she does the 50 yard dash in 3.2 seconds so I can’t get her. It’s so hard to stay mad at her because she bats those beautiful little blue eyes at me and I go to mush. When I do get her inside earlier than she wishes she plays with my hair in the middle of the night. I can’t win!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:32 pm 
I know. What is up with these kittehs? Ungrateful vermin, I declare…
 nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 5:45 pm 
My cat does the same thing at night. She loves to play with my hair.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 5:57 pm 
Hi nancy!!!!!
How are you doing? I’ve missed you.
So you have a little monster too. I know Roxie is doing it on purpose but it’s impossible to get mad at her. When I’m on the couch she jumps up behind me and goes in for the kill aka my head!! Her beauty is going to get her in trouble one day.
 
 
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:23 pm 
I don’t wanna see little pussy on 12 and pregnant. Birth control kitties!
 
 CATNAPPER says: September 23, 2011 at 9:55 pm 
Now that sounds just like my cat! One night she slipped in the back door with a baby sparrow and played with it for about 45 minutes in the bedroom before I rescued said bird unharmed. Sneaky and then Sneaky some more they are.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:42 pm 
That Theresa needs a good grounding and all her catnip taken away for awhile! But just like all teenagers, she is going to make your life miserable the whole punishment time, so who’s really getting punished? Lol.
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 3:51 pm 
Argh, cats can be so tempermental! My cats always boycotted me for a week after I returned from a vacation.

$200? Maybe you can reward a local kid $20 if they can tell you who Theresa is sleeping around with. At least you’ll know where she’s shacking up.

Alternately, you might buy a fish tank or a Parakeet to keep her interested in spying on them in your home. I know my Madonna kitty would have her little mug pressed up against the fish tank all day long.
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:31 pm 
Oh noes!
200 is a LOT.
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 6:06 pm 
Especially after the last $350 vet bill!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:48 pm 
Ouch, Minks.
I’ll bet they’re feeding her something fancy, like: fresh salmon or something. Hmph. Teresa is ungrateful!
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 7:50 pm 
Woo Hoo! The custom super reflective purple ID collar (with purple bell!) came today in the mail! I can’t wait’til those‘nappers get a load of it! 
 
 
 
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 3:39 pm 
Well, after her name change and all that plastic surgery, perhaps Taylor’s family don’t recognize her.

Camille’s man: She really needs to be cautious, Vicki G’s new guy had similar allegations leveled at him.

Sad about Kim Delaney, loved that Jenny and Greg story line years ago. I wish it was just a bad teleprompter.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:44 pm 
Just by her appearance in the picture, I don’t think it was the teleprompter. Nancy, your professinal opinion, please.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:53 pm 
I’m still trying to figure that out. I don’t think it’s alcohol.
I’ll have to wait for Dr T to get home.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 6:09 pm 
It didn’t seem like she was only drunk. Drugged for sure, but not just drunk. She was very spaced out.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 9:13 pm 
i agree. i hate to say this but it reminds me of an Anna Nicole Smith interview i remember watching. i was never a fan of hers but what happened to her and her son was so sad.
 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:46 pm 
Too bad Dr. Drew has taken a hiatus from his Celebrity Rehab show. Taylor and Kim from BH, Dana from Army Wives, etc. I’m sure it wouldn’t take him long to fill up his rooms at the Pasadena Recovery Center. Who am I forgetting?
 
 lizzielou says: September 23, 2011 at 3:55 pm 
All Jersey Shore castmates
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:56 pm 
Simon, Marisol’s mother from DC Housewives, Juicy Joe from NJ, Lynn Curtin and her daughters from OC,&amp;Tamera.
 
 Lillybee says: September 23, 2011 at 5:27 pm 
Throw in the actress who plays Maxie on GH, too. She just got her second DUI and is going to rehab.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:33 pm 
Dr. Drew makes me sick. And I haven’t even watched his show. Ugh. I just–no.
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:25 pm 
Sadly, I would watch. Joe juicy?
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 3:51 pm 
He’s Greek…nice…always thought she secretly thought Mauricio was a hottie too. (Yes, I know, Mauricio has a mixed heritage)

Is he an attorney who wants to go Hollywood for the fame? We’ll have to watch what happens.

That being said, women like Camille, who have come out of the kind of life she claims to have been living with Kelsey for the past few years, are easy prey for men who seek out wealthy women. From Camille’s account, Kelsey paid little attention to her. How to win over Camille? Flower her with attention, shower her with things you can’t buy with money, give her the best sex she’s had in over a decade, and spoil her kids. Voila.

I hope he’s on the up and up, crazy about her, and it turns out well for her and the children. She’s been through a lot. Not as bad as some but certainly worse than others.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 3:59 pm 
Yes, I’m hoping she’s not going to get badly hurt in this relationship. If I remember correctly, Kelsey always gave Camille credit for straightening out his life. He had some serious issues going on in his Fraiser days. He’s always been a little flakey. She deserves being treated like a queen right now. Regardless of how she acted last season, I don’t think she’s that bad. When you’re that rich, you can get a little full of yourself and I think that’s what it was last season. Little did she know that she was in for the big Kaboom from Kelsey.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 4:04 pm 
I’m so glad she didn’t sign a pre-nup. 

BB,
Go to You Tube and watch this. It’s so funny
Pug toilet
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 4:14 pm 
Me too. She can thank Kelsey for that NOW.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 4:16 pm 
It’s cute.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 4:06 pm 
ITA! The public humiliation seems to have humbled her. She said it was Kelsey who wanted her to do the show. One day she’ll look back and thank him for that. I wish her the very best.

BB, still enjoying the new beach home? Cause if you’re getting tired of it and ready to let it go…. 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 7:27 pm 
Sorry, I just came back from going to dinner. Saw a double rainbow on my way back. Anyway, I think it’s going to be quite a while before I get tired of my new home, but you’ll be the first to know. Lol.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 9:35 pm 
Sigh…..ok.
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 6:10 pm 
His hair alone makes me nervous for her. Looks like a bunch of worms.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 6:29 pm 
RealMinkey, you’re hilarious! But it does make it seem as if he’s trying too hard with that hair. Or worse, he thinks it looks fab. Or he’s vain and high maintenance. I hope I’m wrong on all counts and he’s just having a bad hair day. Had a few of them myself. 
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:50 pm 
Not like that, TiaEP, not like that.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 7:29 pm 
LOL!!!
 
 
 
 
 
 BaaBee Loves Kitties says: September 23, 2011 at 3:54 pm 
Testing new avatar…:0
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 3:57 pm 
Hi BaaBee,
How are you?
 
 BaaBee Loves Kitties says: September 23, 2011 at 3:59 pm 
I am great honey~we just had homemade pulled pork sangwiches..lol
How are you Nancy?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 4:02 pm 
Oh don’t tell me stuff like that. Poor little pig.

I’m glad you are fine though. 
 
 BaaBee Loves Kitties says: September 23, 2011 at 4:10 pm 
Hubby said to tell you it was a tofu piggy..sorry honey.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 4:11 pm 
Ok you’re back in the will. 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:40 pm 
Phew. Glad it was a tofu piggy. That makes me feel better. Tell hubby thx.
 
 
 
 
 
 NYCer says: September 23, 2011 at 4:05 pm 
Jill learned nothing from Bethenny. What kind of entrepreneur goes on a Europeam cruise the week her product launches?
Seriously, she thinks planting gossip items in the press and getting a few minutes on Joy Behar is going to make her successful?

I can’t wait for her to fall flat on her face, again.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 4:12 pm 
Someone here has mentioned a few times that Jill is lazy, lacking a good work ethic, and therefore will never put in a good day’s work for any of her projects. She wants something, everything, for little-to-nothing. Again, story of her life, isn’t it?
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 5:08 pm 
That article Sam posted above certainly indicated that when she was working, Jill bounced from job to job.
 
 
 Viewer1234 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:01 pm 
OMG I HATE JILL ZARIN!!!!

 http://www.usmagazine.com/moviestvmusic/news/alex-mccord-jill-zarin-at-war-after-real-housewives-firing-2011239 
 
 ramonacoaster says: September 23, 2011 at 5:16 pm 
Since when has Jill taken the high road? Other housewives should take these firings as a warning. Don’t try to control anything (that’s what production is for), try to be flexible, don’t let your big ego get in the way of anything (unless it’s entertaining), and don’t be boring.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 5:29 pm 
Good advice.
 
 BessiB says: September 23, 2011 at 5:21 pm 
Simon should have kept his mouth shut. As true as that is, them’s fightin’words.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 5:32 pm 
He had to have know she would claw back. They know her well by now. Even out there sailing around the world on life-saving missions, you can still get a whiff of her stenching perfume.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 5:24 pm 
Jill…taking a high road….says stop the blame game…hilarious. I don’t know where she gets the balls sometimes…Then again, she has poor Bobby’s. He probably hasn’t seen them in years.

Jill, you’ve never been on a high anything (unless it was drugs back in your day). You’re the one that will crawl over hot coals to promote yourself and your crap. That’s almost our quote from the business (lol) article.

Blame game? May not be the reason they were fired, but you DID try to get them off the show. Don’t let Andy have to come clean about your attempts to get them off just as he did when he admitted you were not and have not been in touch with Bethenny. Or Ramona. You know she’ll rat your ass right out. You need to drop this right here because it will make you look worse in the end when the truth comes out.
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:37 pm 
Hi 1234!
How’s it going?

Thanks for posting.
I feel bad for Jill’s rep; clearly his first client ever…*or* Jill is such a moron that nothing will save her. Oh wait…
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 5:48 pm 
V5,
Why don’t you like Dr Drew?
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:52 pm 
He was wonderful on the radio. I’m sure he means well–but he’s up in everyone’s craw as“the expert”and sticking people on his show, for whom? Them? I doubt it. I just don’t like him. I think it’s easy for recovery people to get star struck and muscle their way into being“experts”and stars themselves. And don’t get me started on celebrity sobriety“friends”who are paid.

//end rant.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:07 pm 
V5,
He rubs me the wrong way too but he really is an expert meaning he did a fellowship after being board certified in Internal Medicine. My husband has the same initials after his name as Dr Drew does. Thank GOD he has no need to get in front of the camera. Dr Drew is no longer doing Celebrity Rehab as he said he was too busy. He seems to like being on TV more than practicing medicine which I find sad. Paying the“celebrity’s”to be on a show is disgusting to me.
What about the addicts that can’t afford rehab?
Aren’t they more deserving? Then he pays them another $250K to go through Sobriety House.
I just shake my head.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:13 pm 
Yep. Sad. I wonder when he got certified? It never occurred to me to question credentials when he was“The Love Dr.”in Los Angeles. Funny show.

Pasadena has its share of–okay…well, at least ONE center *other* than The Salvation Army (which has a very good program) to get sober in that is pretty much free. So…that’s a plus!

Say“hi”to your hubby. Yay!!
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 6:20 pm 
Nancy, you know I have a crush on Drew. When I found out they were paying the‘cast’for Celebrity Rehab/Sober House, he lost some points with me.

I know they did treat other patients at the clinic alongside these celebrities (on another ward), but I believe they were insured plus s few pro bonos.

I also think he prefers the TV jobs over solely treating. I guess he’s just over private practice now.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:22 pm 
Hi TiaEP.
 
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 6:23 pm 
Hiya!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:29 pm 
Which is sad because he took over his fathers practice. I don’t“hate”the guy I just think his talent could be better used behind the camera.
Have you watched his show on TV yet? I’m not impressed at all. It’s just one more talking head show to me. His“celebrity rehab”patients got paid $250K
and another $250K if they went to Sober House. Here’s the kicker, if they relapse they can do it all over again for another $500k.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:34 pm 
*vomit*
let’s hope the retreads don’t die trying for the 500K prize…
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:28 pm 
Explains Steven
 
 
 
 
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 6:36 pm 
JZ’s“rep”who feeds quotes for (and not for) attribution to media outlets is usually her PR/”Manager”/all-purpose flunky, Darren. Darryl was a“fan”who schmoozed up to Ms. You’re Hired If You Work Cheap and got hisself a job as Her High&amp;Mightiness’assistant. Then he quickly morphed into her“rep,”then OMG, her“manager.”Like she’s a rock star or something, lol.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:41 pm 
It’s hard being Darren. Because w/ the way (either) he handled Jill, or Jill wouldn’t listen to him…he’ll have a really, really hard time getting a job, let alone his own clients.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 7:41 pm 
Darryl doesn’t“handle”Jill. He’s her flunky, and willingly so, to do her bidding. He’s cheaper than any real PR firm that she’s too cheap to pay and would never listen to anyway.

Darren’s still there because he crawled so far up Jill’s ass that when she gets a colonoscopy its a 2 for 1 deal.

It’s not like he’s ever had a real job and what he’s doing now is not something any legit well regarded PR firm would be interested in.
 
 
 
 Eastbayca says: September 23, 2011 at 5:50 pm 
Why can’t Jillzy just own it? What Silex stated is true of Jillzy behavior towards them!
The woman-Jillzy is infuriating.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:53 pm 
She can’t own it, which is why…I hate Jill Zarin!
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 6:24 pm 
Amen Sister!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:26 pm 
word.
 
 
 
 KerryOkie says: September 23, 2011 at 8:15 pm 
I guess it’s just Jill’s world and the rest of us are merely players in it. So it’s okay for her to lay the blame for her own firing squarely on Ramona’s shoulders, but when Alex and Simon are forth coming about Jill’s venom toward them, that’s bad, bad, bad, because Jill is, you know, Jill, and the rest of us aren’t. What an effing hypocrite, just one more reason why I hate Jill Zarin.
 
 Ramonater says: September 23, 2011 at 5:32 pm 
I love this blog and it is such a joy to read the comments from all you friendly, smart and humourous posters. I get mad when I read comments on some of the other blogs where Lynn and all of us who read and post on here are slammed. Jealous, I think? Anyway–one thing I love is that you don’t have to only talk about the housewives–you all give great advice on many things, including pets. So, I have a question for you dog people out there. I have an absolutely wonderful White German Sheperd named Wally who is almost two years old. He is the smartest, most beautiful, loving and loyal dog you could ever hope for…when he’s at home with us. As soon as we take him outside he goes into shepherd guard-dog mode and seems to think anyone who comes near one of us is a threat. He barks and pulls at the leash and generally makes a spectable of himself. It’s embarassing, needless to say. I don’t think he would ever bite, but I hate that he’s not very social. We’ve tried different things such as bringing people over to the house, having friends spend time with him, etc., but we can’t seem to break him of it. He will settle down and accept people once he gets to know them, but strangers still send him into a frenzy. We recently had him altered and hope that will help, but do any of you have any great ideas to break him of this? Thank you for letting me ask! Oh, I also Hate Jill Zarin!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:39 pm 
Ohhhhh Wally! Poor little pup! I don’t know. I have kittehs.
Good luck, though… 
 
 Ramonater says: September 23, 2011 at 5:47 pm 
Thank you! At least with cats you don’t have the barking problems!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 5:51 pm 
Do you ever watch The Dog Whisperer? He’s the best for dog issues.
 
 Ramonater says: September 23, 2011 at 5:58 pm 
I have, and I’ve tried most of his ideas. I guess I just need to keep working on it!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:01 pm 
I know there are trainers in my town who use Cesar’s techniques. Perhaps in your town there are too.
 
 Ramonater says: September 23, 2011 at 6:08 pm 
That’s a good idea. I shall check that out.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:11 pm 
Maybe get one of his books? I swear by the man.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 6:12 pm 
I wish we had Cesar’s advice when our S.panky was young. I didn’t know about pack behavior, dog anxiety or territories. I just thought the damn dog was a pain in the rear.

Whenever we decide we are ready for a puppy I will watch a Cesar marathon.
 
 Jezzibel says: September 23, 2011 at 6:09 pm 
hmm my baby kitten owns my big dog, and there is not a day that goes by that he doesn’t remind her of that little fact
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 5:50 pm 
V5,
I have a question for you upthread.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 5:53 pm 
gotcha, babe.
 
 
 Jezzibel says: September 23, 2011 at 6:04 pm 
dog park to get him socialized around other dogs. Honestly if your outside and your talking to neighbor or a friend, both of you just ignore him, he’ll quiet down when he realizes the other person is not a threat and he’s being ignored. Daily walkies help too
 
 Ramonater says: September 23, 2011 at 6:30 pm 
Great advice–thanks Jezzibel.
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:08 pm 
I agree, Jezzibel. Ignore. I have terriers. Terriers tend to be super intelligent, but are pretty much the most stubborn life form on the face of the earth. I’ve found that with their bad behavior, the primary thing to do is ignore, otherwise our acknowledgment in their minds is a sign of positive reinforcement. If you do have to acknowledge what they’re doing, always use a calm low stern voice, with one word- NO, and give them“the look”, like you used to get as a kid. Dogs understand eye contact. Other than that, you might try some obedience classes.

Those darned doggies!
 
 Puppyluv says: September 23, 2011 at 9:54 pm 
Ramonater, (This may get long and boring for most of you so scroll on by) This is a common problem with guard breed dogs. I grew up with German Shepherds and your description of your dog is so true. They are wonderful dogs. They do, however, need to know who is boss. For right now, I would suggest when in the lunging, barking situation that you say:“No”or Ah”and immediately turn away from the target with a quick sideways jerk on the leash. Walk briskly in the opposite direction. When at home teach him to“speak”: you bark and when he barks say good boy&amp;give him a treat. Keep this up until he barks on command. Then teach him“hush”. When he is barking (for any reason) say“hush”. As soon as he stops barking, say good boy and give him a treat. Be over the top with praise of what a good boy he is.
Go back and forth between speak and hush until he understands. It won’t take long–Shepherds are very smart. Praise and treats are the key. Once he knows“hush”use it outside. Also, I assume at his age he knows“sit”. If he doesn’t sit immediately on command, work on that so that he does. Don’t praise or treat him for anything other than an immediate sit. When out walking him if he starts lunging and barking, stop, say SIT, HUSH. If he has learned his lessions at home he should obey. Remember to“good boy”him then–but quietly so as not to excite him. Also, only give any command once and say it like you mean it. Not loud, just firm.

Dogs want to be happy. We want to be happy. Our dogs are happy when we are happy and vise versa. Keep the training sessions short. Dogs loose interest quickly. ALWAYS be upbeat. ALWAYS end on a happy note.

Sorry. I didn’t mean to sound like the dog training instructor (but I do did) so did–it won’t let me correct. If you would like to talk dogs or dog training off the site, ask Lynn for my email. I have been training alpha dogs all my life and would love to be able to help.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 24, 2011 at 3:54 am 
Ooooo…so thoughtful.
I loved reading the post. And I don’t even have doggies.
I hope Ramon-H sees it.
 
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:08 pm 
Reeallly off-topic.
I hate Comcast and their crummy new xfinity that only works 96% of the time.

If you’re in their area and have a choice, don’t get it!
Argh!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:12 pm 
I answered you upthread.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:13 pm 
gotcha.
And I still hate Comcast TV…
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 6:13 pm 
V5….. call them and complain…hahahaha
I knock knock havent had a prob with the tv part…and I fixed the comp connection myself..
HEY..did you see any filming last night from the bridge ??

Diva
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:15 pm 
Hi there Little Miss D,
I didn’t think to look. I’ve seen some photos in the Post every morning, but no further action.

*I hate Comcast!* I do call and complain, and then they offer, like: free Showtime. Yuck. (pardon to Showtime fans…I would prefer a good working service.)
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 6:27 pm 
V5…I called .. TALK TO A DUDE..the chicks are BITCHES…. I complained about slow internet…did a speed test for them when I had them online..had them PING me…hahahaha
Get $15.00 a month off my bill now for the next year….
hahahahaha…..
Try it….
Diva
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:30 pm 
Diva,
Is your son out yet?
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:33 pm 
No kidding! Agh! I just told my friend the same thing–a female wanted her to pay 40.00 for a tech to come out and FIX a mistake another tech made. I said…“call back and get a guy on the phone…”Geez!

Haven’t thought about the 15.00 off, though. Hmn…
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:42 pm 
I’m going to tell on you two!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:46 pm 
tee hee.
 
 
 
 
 
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 6:29 pm 
Does anyone else think it’s odd that Camille’s new man looks like a slightly younger version of Mauricio Umansky???
 http://ow.ly/6DrTy 
 http://www.nationalledger.com/pop-culture-news/camille-grammers-boyfriend-p-263453.shtml 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:31 pm 
He gives me the ick factor.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:33 pm 
It’s the crunchy hair gel and the hairspray.
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:45 pm 
Double ick. I don’t see a lot of resemblance to Mauricio, who I think is handsome. I guess cause I do not think this dude is at all! Different strokes for different folks!
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 6:41 pm 
Most definitely.
 
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 11:04 pm 
Ok, I guess I’m outvoted. I just was wondering if this wasn’t kind of a dig to Kyle that Camille is seeing a guy similar to Mauricio but younger…
 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:40 pm 
Dr Conrad’s trial is going to be a zoo.
I’m sure glad I don’t have to worry about being
called for jury duty.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:45 pm 
No kidding. Really; this story has so many damn facets and sides that it’s impossible to narrow it down to ye olde“first do no harm”–unless they’re going to make an example out of him.
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 6:41 pm 
I wonder what Mauricio did to keep Camille’s real estate listings…Does she hold her liquor by the ears. Oops! That was snarky!
So Jill Has a rep; boy, I wouldn’t want that job. However, if I did I’d get her on“Wife Swap”asap. Pair her up with Howard Stern, or Adam Corolla. That woman needs to be with someone who will tell her to“shut it”, every minute, everyday…for the rest of her life.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:45 pm 
What a great idea. Jill on the Howard Stern Show.
Knowing Jill she would say“Of course”. He would
rip her apart. I’m sure Robin hates her as much as we do.
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 7:00 pm 
Oh goodness that’s funny. Jill would never agree. Bobby might like the other wife better.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 7:18 pm 
Are u kidding? Of course he’ll like the other woman better. Hell, I like her already because she’s NOT Jill. 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 7:38 pm 
Well,“she”could be Taylor or Micheale. Oh wait. They don’t have husbands anymore.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 7:39 pm 
We should let Darren know about that show. Wife Swap.
Jill will do anything to get back on TV. Oh to dream…
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 7:53 pm 
I could see both Camille and Mauricio being discreet enough to keep an encounter secret. Hmmmm……
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:14 pm 
Jill with Howard Stern? He’d humiliate her by telling her to lift up her shirt and show him her Squeeezies! LOL!
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:46 pm 
Jill with Gary Busey?
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 9:00 pm 
LOL!!!!!!!!!!
 CATNAPPER says: September 23, 2011 at 10:17 pm 
RM, You are killing me-spilt milk everywhere!
 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:48 pm 
Tareq Salahi is on TV right now. He actually said“We had a beautiful marriage”.
I loved to hear what the other DC Housewives think about all of his. Esp Linda.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:54 pm 
Right. Because his wife always went along with whatever he said. I did catch (off topic) on the TV show…before they went to the White House (and Desiree what’s-her-name lost her job!) Michaele was staring at him so intently, asking‘do we need anything else?’–she knew damn well they didn’t have an invite, and with the cameras, etc. they would be let right in. Disgusting.
But I’m still happy she’s in Journey-land with Schon. It’s too delicious. And I don’t even like that band…
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 6:57 pm 
I don’t think it will end well though.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 6:58 pm 
I know. It kinda makes me sad, actually.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:00 pm 
It doesn’t make me sad at all for any of them. There isn’t a sympathetic character out of the bunch to me. Just call me cold-hearted. Lol.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 9:12 pm 
Cold-hearted. 
 
 
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:13 pm 
I’m happy for Michaele. Hope it lasts..hope she starts getting real. Gonna be a little harder for Tareq to find another Stepford Wife considering he’s been exposed just about everywhere in the WORLD for being an opportunist who’s broke as a Joe.
 
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 6:59 pm 
I wonder if Jillzilla wasn’t always a bully. I can’t see her being bullied as a child and growing up to treat others that way, seems like she would have empathy. I think it’s more likely that she has always been a bully and always blamed others for not getting what she wants.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 7:26 pm 
Sounds like Jilz even as a child may well have been a scheming, nasty little shite, likely the resident rat who would trade info against others for her own advancement/benefit. She would play the victim, while behind the scenes she schemed and undermined those who had crossed her. As an adult, with Bawby’s millions to support her, she’s free to be the scheming, manipulative bully who public berates and harasses social subordinates&amp;plots revenge against those who crossed her. And yet still portrays herself as the poor hapless victim of others, crying big ass crocodile tears to Bawby. She really is rather vile. And now she’s just making herself ridiculous. Good…so more people will laugh at her transparent BS.
 
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 9:59 pm 
she says she’s bullied now and she’s the bully so that easily could have been the case when she was a child. would be a good reason why she didn’t have friends and wasn’t liked. she was exactly the same as she is now.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 7:28 pm 
Tough call. Interesting. Okay: I’ll take a gander. Her sister was always more successful; perhaps she was more of the black sheep. She marries Bawbee, gets on the show, and suddenly *poof* she’s a player, and everyone around her is telling her she’s wonderful.
Um.
That’s as far as I got.
I guess I mean to say…she wasn’t prepared for success in any way, and was probably surprised she got cast in the first place. So the bullying stems from self-righteousness, and listening to the wrong people, and thinking she’s“the”star.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:09 pm 
I agree with you all. And when she reads it, it will bring back memories. People who behave like that are often told by others, esp when they’re younger, that they’re a babckstabbing manipulative snake. Bet she’s been told that quite often, which is why she has no real friends. When the real her comes out, the new friends take their toys and go home (like Beth, Ramona, and long list of others not in the spotlight).

Would love to read an interview with one of Bobby’s employees or ex-employees about her. Have no doubt they can’t stand her. She probably had them sign a Confidentiality waiver. But if there’s any ex-employees who never signed the waiver…would love to hear from ya.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 8:20 pm 
I dunno. I think…hmn. I think she’s probably quite nice to the people working at Zarin. It’s rather a schlock-house, and a fairly casual atmosphere. (I went there looking for out-of-stock fabrics many years ago–it is a schlock house; no real good brands at all.)

I think the problem is when she feels slighted–or whatever–or someone is getting something she deserves that she starts hitting back…ie: Bethanny. (I still cannot spell her name right) or whomever.
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:26 pm 
I happen to be of the mind that Jill was a wall flower in her younger years, and sat back watching and envying the more pretty, popular mean girls. My theory is, since marrying Bawwby and becoming *a famous reality star*, she’s since emulated the teenage behavior of those she always wished to be.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 7:23 pm 
Zoey…no excuses for JZ…she’s just a bitter ungrateful coniving back stabbing two faced cheating selfish WITCH….
There’s no fixing that with all the super glue out there..she will die bitter….
hell she divorced her first husband because he didnt make enough money…she allows her own daughter to disrespect that union by having her take Zarin as her last name…WHO DOES THAT….
On her death bed that’s going to be an epic nuclear type FLASH of her life before she goes….

Diva
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 7:29 pm 
Poor Bobby. Can you imagine the whining he’s having to put up with right now?
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 7:35 pm 
V5…
BWABBY GETS WHAT HE BOUGHT…
I bet he’s having buyers remorse right about….. NOW..
It’s cocktail hour somewhere….SPLASH…
did you hear something….??
Nope

Diva
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 7:36 pm 
I’d take my chances with the sharks! I’m waiting to see Bawby jumping ship on CNN!
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 7:40 pm 
I’m telling you I think Bobby’s a masochist. If Jill behaves this way all the time, which is pretty much proven at this point, he must enjoy it or love her so much he’s delusional. If he didn’t like her shenanigans, he could have put a stop to it a long time ago.
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 7:41 pm 
He can’t hear her through the Jack Daniels.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 7:43 pm 
It’s hard to believe that he drinks a lot when she doesn’t
esp if she really did have a problem with it. Those kind of marriages usually don’t last.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 8:17 pm 
He prolly tunes her out with memories of his well-worn Playboy collection. (If indeed he does not have uh, any other extracurricular interests on the side.)
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 7:58 pm 
Hadn’t thought of that. He could drink to drown her out and not deal with her as a pain.
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:34 pm 
Can you imagine her on a cruise? I pity that poor Captain! She’s going to be demanding his table every night, so she can sit at his right hand, and tell him how to run his ship! If there’s a news report of a ship captain jumping overboard, we certainly know who it will be!
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 8:38 pm 
They could always just set Jill adrift in a little boat, like the Bounty crew did to Captain Bligh. If there are other passengers on board, it might just come to that: mass mutiny and off she goes….
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:54 pm 
Before setting her adrift, her mouth would have to be duct taped. No need to disturb the whales and other wild life.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:50 pm 
Think Madonna’s character on the movie‘Swept Away.’
 
 CATNAPPER says: September 23, 2011 at 10:36 pm 
My bet is that she has been the same as a young girl and as an adult. JZ seems to suffer from narcissism. Most people know how difficult it is to change oneself so it would follow that this giant jillybean has always been about herself. She simply has a bigger audience to show off to than as a child. Something seems putrid within herself and it shows. She and Patti seem to suffer from the same ailment.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 7:34 pm 
She cannot enjoy her life though so I’m a little surprised that she hasn’t changed or is willing enough to seek therapy. She really is one of the most insecure persons I’ve ever seen.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 7:49 pm 
If Bobby threatened to jump ship, I think we’d see a change, however contrived it might be. I was in New York around the time the picture of Bobby at the restaurant talking to 3 ladies came out. Think it was the New York Post. Someone was laughing about it at my table and everyone agreed that we hope he came to his senses and was looking for love in some other places. Trust me, his stock would soar if he dropped Jill. Imagine all the Bobby fans buying every piece of Zarin fabrc they could lay their hands on in the warehouse, just so happy that he got away from Jill and lived to tell it.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 7:45 pm 
OKAY FOLKS…JOKE TIME…..
Pensioner in a Sex Store…

A little

old lady, well into her eighties, slowly enters the front door of

a sex shop.

Obviously

very unstable on her feet, she wobbles the few feet across the

store to the counter.

Finally

arriving at the counter and grabbing it for support, stuttering

she asks the sales clerk,

“Dooo

youuuu have dilllldosss?”

The clerk, politely

trying not to burst out laughing, replies,“Yes we do have

dildos.
Actually we carry many

different models.”

The old woman then asks:

“Doooo youuuu carrryy aaa pppinkk onnee,

tttenn inchessss lllong aaandd aabboutt ttwoo

inchesss ththiickk…aaand rrunns by bbaatteries

?”

The clerk responds,“Yes we

do..”

“Ddddooo yyoooouuuu kknnnoooww hhhowww

tttooo ttturrrnnn

iittt
offfff?”
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:03 pm 
LOL!!!!!!! Thanks for that. I’m in a drought here.
 vilzvet says: September 23, 2011 at 8:12 pm 
I actually got that one! Funny!
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 8:16 pm 
cute.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 7:46 pm 
Has anyone been following the Amanda Knox trial in Italy?
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:01 pm 
Nancy, I hadn’t, but wanted to get your opinion (and others as well) about something OT. What do you think of Michael Lohan’s new career of working with addicts? and what Dr. Drew and the other worker told him their concerns were around it?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:30 pm 
Michael Lohan is addicted to drama. He has nothing to offer an addict/alcoholic right now and probably won’t for years!
He has major issues. IMHO he needs to be in a long term program not a“Spin Dry”rehab he just got out of.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:44 pm 
Thanks, I agree completely. One of them predicted 2 things for him and one has already come to pass: He was going to punch a woman (or some form of domestic violence) and he was going to knowingly or unknowingly cross a boundary working with another addict because he’s still in his disease himself. Like falling for one of the female clients or breaking a rule to‘help’one of the clients, IMO.
 
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:33 pm 
Thumbs down. Too soon. I don’t think he has it fully together enough.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 8:09 pm 
I am very interested. Did anything happen today?
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:10 pm 
I have, not in the last few days, but after the conviction I read a couple of books about the trial, one pro, one con. Can I say the Italian prosecutor is a nut-casino? Their laws are quite antiquated. What do you think?
 
 vilzvet says: September 23, 2011 at 8:15 pm 
My cousin got me into that trial. Then Rolling Stone recently did a great article about it. I believe the case is back from hiatus soon and hopefully she’ll be released for time served? If not I think she’ll have to do a couple more years even though I believe she is innocent. It was the other guy, for sure. Amanda and her boyfriend were just in the wrong place, wrong time.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:24 pm 
She got 26yrs for it but I also think she’s innocent.
Her appeal is going on right now. Hopefully she will win that and be home. She is a strange one though.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 9:00 pm 
I think she is innocent. Has anyone read the Monster of Florence? The american journalist was writing a book about a series of murders going back years in Italy was accused by the same prosecutor of committing those murders. Totally crazy.

He wrote an addendum about Amanda Knox. He believes she is innocent.
Extremely sloppy policework and corrupt system there.
 
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:24 pm 
read about him, not his book, they also included him in a Primetime?( one of those shows) expose. Even though they completely embarrassed the prosecution and the police’s collection of evidence they are asking to extend A’s sentence. They also have her parents up on some crazy casino charges for speaking out against the prosecutor.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:42 pm 
Isn’t Jill going to be in Italy soon? I bet she tweets the Judge and asks him to lunch.
 
 
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 7:49 pm 
Kim Delaney is claiming the teleprompter made her mess up her speech so badly she was pulled of the stage.
 http://philadelphia.cbslocal.com/2011/09/23/actress-kim-delaney-escorted-off-stage-at-liberty-medal-ceremony/ 
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 7:57 pm 
of course she is.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 8:04 pm 
She reminds me of a dialed-down Courtney Love. She looks a mess.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 8:15 pm 
I LOVE Courtney Love’s music. I have all her CD’s.
 
 Need a Hobby says: September 23, 2011 at 8:29 pm 
Uh, yeah, right. Not like she’s a trained stage and film actress who’s used to memorizing scripted segments. Or has any experience in ad libbing extemporaneously when someone or circumstances force departures from from a script or a play’s dialogue. She had only the teleprompter, with no idea what she was supposed to say, lost the ability to organize thoughts&amp;speak coherently, and she also coincidentally went for the chic touseled, seriously disoriented look on purpose.

I wasn’t aware she had such known problems. Just remember her from NYPD Blue&amp;noticed she was on Army Wives, which I don’t watch. Too bad. Very bad to have to be escorted off the stage. She would have been better off to plead some medical issue of some sort. An allergic reaction to medication, alien possession, whatever.
 IDon&apos;tBelieveInUnicorns says: September 23, 2011 at 10:12 pm 
it did look like she was having problems with the teleprompter however, i don’t there were problems with the teleprompter. she probably couldn’t read it because she couldn’t see straight. that was really sad to watch.
 
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:13 pm 
Where is Dame?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:22 pm 
Dame and Mazel and AZGirl?
 
 sparklemuffy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:07 pm 
and error?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:35 pm 
He was on vacation but…
 
 Cityside says: September 23, 2011 at 9:38 pm 
and Error404?
 
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 8:18 pm 
God dammit–just let the puppy out and he got skunked. Time for a bath….. %$^*(!
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 8:22 pm 
Ugh. Bad puppy! Bad skunk!
…I haven’t smelled that in years. I don’t envy you.
 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:32 pm 
I love that smell as it reminds me of Canada.
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 9:05 pm 
Nancy, he is in a crate on the way to your house!
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:34 pm 
That was funny!
 
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 9:02 pm 
My kitty Madonna sneers: Cats are smart enough to never get skunked! Ha.
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 10:43 pm 
Bathed puppy, sprayed puppy with anti-smell spray, and the house now smells like skunk. I have smelled the dog so much that he thinks I’m making moves on him. I think the smell in the house is my imagination, but have anti-smell candles going all over the place. Of course, this happened when I am the only one home….
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:18 pm 
Trudie, have you tried the hydrogen peroxide, baking soda and dish detergent bath? It works.

I know what you mean about the imagination smell thing, though. My husband goes KooKoo with that post skunk smelling. It’s obsessive, actually.
 
 Trudie says: September 24, 2011 at 7:08 am 
Minkey, that is exactly what I used. Worked like a charm. Problem was that I didn’t want to leave him outside with the skunk and I had to buy hydrogen peroxide. So, I fenced him in the kitchen while I was gone. Hence, the skunk smell in the house. But, the odor reducing candles did the trick and this morning, we are skunk smell free!
 
 
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:42 pm 
Oh man..sorry trudie
 
 MazelnIndy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:23 pm 
 http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V2NlKBySA9Y&amp;feature=player_e 
mbedded
More misheard lyrics!! My son is perfoming this in his choir tonight with the Indianapolis Symphony Orchestra and their new boy conductor. I’m hoping to feel well enough to attend tomorrow evening.

After reading all of the posts and hearing the latest news getting a handle on some of these people is like grabbing for fish in a barrel.
Did anyone read Jill’s tweet regarding going away with Bobby as a way to“rekindle”their relationship. Telling words right there.
What idiot leaves the country when their product hits market? SMH.

Silex are off the the show IMO because the 2nd most irritating HW to Andy would be Simon. Sorry you guys I really like you, but Simon your need for attention is annoying.

I love Carole Radziwill. I read her memoir ( which I highly recommend) about 2 years ago and developed a major girl crush on her. I really hope she doesn’t disappoint. She sounds like she came from a fairly humble background and did not let her marriage to the Family go to her head.

Love the doggie video BB. I miss having mine so much, but I love living vicariously with all of your pets.

Recovery going well here. Having a hard time fitting in all of my relaxation activities into one day.
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:35 pm 
Glad you’re feeling better.
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:36 pm 
There you are! 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:38 pm 
Mazel,
That was one of the funniest things I’ve ever seen. Can’t wait for George to get home. How are you feeling? Hopefully not in too much pain.
I wish I could go with you tomorrow night to hear your son. Are they going to tape it? Don’t do too much too soon. Glad to see you back and healthy. 
 
 MazelnIndy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:52 pm 
Nancy, I thought you would love it! I hope they tape it….have you heard about this conductor? Krzystof Urbanski? He just turned 28. He will be leading our symphony.

Sometimes medicine is amazing. I have not had any pain at all. I have even reduced my pain meds to 1/2 the dose and I even forget to take them. No bandages or stitches. One thing I’ll say about the mid-west is we have some of the best medical care available. When I read about some of you( Diva and Minkey) and your frustrations in other parts of the country I just shudder. Yesterday was the toughest….I just felt like I had the flu really bad and based on everyone’s reports maybe I too had it.
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 9:07 pm 
So glad you are feeling better.
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:15 pm 
Mazel,
Yes I’ve heard of him. Imagine being so young with that kind of musicality. Is he going to be their conductor from here on in? It would be great to play in his orchestra.
Every year I went to a music conservatory through USC and we would have young conductors conduct. You are bringing back great memories.
I’m glad you are doing so well post-op. It will be interesting to see if you are still feeling“old&amp;depressed”. ha ha
I don’t feel like I am getting bad care for my RSD at all.
The problem is is that their is no cure. I got my care at UCSF which is one of the best hospitals in America.
It makes me angry at times but that really doesn’t help anything.
 
 MazelnIndy says: September 23, 2011 at 10:08 pm 
Yes, he is here to stay as long as agreeable.

I really didn’t mean to imply that medical care is worse than here. Just recall when my husband had his first back episode (ruptured disc) his mother wanted him to come back to NY
for treatment. When I had my first opportunity to visit the hospital in NY I was appalled at the condition of the facility. BTW, it was not a charity hospital.
Also, having aging in-laws in the South Florida area is quite the experience.
I just have become more attuned to geographical/sociological medicine.

When I told my husband that you had RSD he just grimaced and said“poor baby”. So I do understand your predicament.

I also know that when you are connected to the medical profession you are privileged and I don’t take that for granted….I know that I am blessed.
 
 
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 8:55 pm 
I’ve read articles about her, and of course thought how unimaginable it must have been for her MIL to live through…all that history, and then lose her son and nephew so close together. I don’t think I’d survive it very well.
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 9:08 pm 
Carole’s book was amazing. My mother really identified with someone who could speak so plainly about caring for your seriously ill partner. Very tough.

I don’t think Carole was embraced by the edler generation of The Family at all.

Can’t wait til she tells LuAnn to stuff her phoney Countess BS. Carole was married to a prince. He didn’t care about his title at all.
 
 MazelnIndy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:55 pm 
No, I sensed that she got a rather grudging respect from the MIL, which is really the best we all can hope for:)
Caroline was the one with the real stick up her you know what.
But I understand she is that way overall.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:02 pm 
Mazel. I know you are not there anymore, but your link was so funny! My husband is in the shower and humming that tune right now. Glad you are feeling better but don’t do too much.
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 8:37 pm 
Kim Delaney seemed emotional on The View today, perhaps due to her poor performance at the ceremony, and not as much about reuniting with old cast mates.
She’s a professional actress; if she couldn’t read the prompter, couldn’t she have just said
“I’ll speak from my heart…”and then ad-lib her message? She was a mess.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:40 pm 
A hot mess!
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 pm 
Oh man I missed it because as soon as I saw a very special edition I hit delete. Fridays view is pre taped. Thinking on Wednesday they double up. Anyone got a delaney time line?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:42 pm 
My boyfriend is on CNN right now.
Morgan Freeman.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 23, 2011 at 8:53 pm 
My TV boyfriend was on earlier. Lawrence O’Donnell.
*blushes*
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:29 pm 
Wow Viewer, a Lawrence O’Donnell groupie! I never really thought about it, but I guess I kinda think he’s cute, too! LOL!
 Pamela says: September 24, 2011 at 7:10 am 
Wait a minute, he must be two timing because he’s my boyfriend, too! 
 
 This is an Emergency People! says: September 23, 2011 at 8:54 pm 
I like him too. But since he’s your boyfriend, I’ll just admire from afar.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 8:58 pm 
You’re a smart woman. 
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 8:56 pm 
I love me some Morgan Freeman too!
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 9:16 pm 
Uhm Nancy. Didn’t Morgan Freeman run off with his step granddaughter or something?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:23 pm 
Al Sharpton, Al Sharpton!!!
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:22 pm 
Oh look, something shiny over there!
 
 
 
 JumpTheShark says: September 23, 2011 at 8:48 pm 
I’m watching Bethenny THS…IMO The SGM fiasco happened because she’s a chef and businesswoman, but not a chemist/biologist. She didn’t understand about shelf-life.
“Natural”is great, but mold is also“natural”(moldy cookies, moldy beverage) there are plenty of“natural”things that I wouldn’t want to eat.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:11 pm 
I have lots of blue-green fuzzy natural things at the back of my refrigerator. We’re a very natural food kinda fambly. 
 
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:47 pm 
Yup. Hubby is trying to bark his way out so that is his job this weekend. No golf for his butt.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 9:13 pm 
Mad Cow disease and anthrax are natural too.

I have a pet peeve. I see it on the news and during interviews with the housewives.
Bethenny is not being sued about the contents of SGM. Beam World Wide is. And Whole Foods is not suing, it’s a class action lawsuit by private parties who claimed they were mislead by the labeling.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:18 pm 
Adgirl,
May I co-peeve with you?
Perhaps a class action peeve?
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 10:05 pm 
lol. you’re on!
 
 Fairy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:48 pm 
Let’s bring one against jz
 
 
 
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:21 pm 
OMG,
Guess who’s back on TV.“Taylor”!!!
It’s a rerun from a few days ago . (Dr Phil)
I bet Dr Phil is seeing right through her.
I was Kennedy’s age when my mother killed
herself. If I had to deal with what Taylor is doing
to Russell my life would have been a nightmare.
At least I can daydream about what would have been.
Taylor has taken that away from her. It’s sickening.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:22 pm 
could have been
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 9:31 pm 
Is anyone keeping track? Who has clocked in more hours on the talk shows…Jill or“Taylor”?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:37 pm 
That’s a good one? I had to change the channel as I was going to throw something at our new TV! There will be a day that
“Taylor”wakes up and thinks to herself…
“OMG what have I done?”
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 9:39 pm 
RM,
I e-mailed you. 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 10:07 pm 
Nancy you are so mentally healthy it’s hard for me to remember what a difficult childhood you had.
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:26 pm 
Good point Adgirl. Goes to show you, adversity can make some people stronger, yet others fall apart.
 
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 9:34 pm 
Minkey, how did the brace fitting go?
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:12 pm 
Excellent, Trudie. I met the brace guy in the physical therapy section of the same building that houses the orthopedist. He fitted her with the huge contraption, and sent her home with it on the spot! (Just another example of how the doctor’s office gave me mis-information about the timing of this.) BUT (big but)………
As much as I hate to even discuss it, the brace guy (who was so super nice) did tell me on the side, outside of Minklet’s ears, that he had seen the preliminary diagnosis in his paperwork, and from his decades of experience, he’s concerned about the type and location of her injury. If it is as bad as it looks like it could be to him, she would be too young for the surgery that might be needed, and she could be very limited in her physical activity until it can be corrected after she has stopped growing. He was being very cautious in telling me this, as he isn’t a doctor, but he was genuinely concerned. What also alerted me, was the doctor actually came in to the physical therapy room during the fitting (which is totally unusual, according to the brace guy and others there) and made a whole big fuss over little Minklet. The doc told me to call him on Monday to talk about the MRI. I didn’t feel good about any of this. I do feel good about the fact that unbeknownst to me, after some asking around, I’ve found out that Minklet’s doctor is a seriously well-known and highly accredited specialist in that field. I guess we got lucky in that regard.
 
 Trudie says: September 23, 2011 at 10:40 pm 
Oh Minkey, I hope that it isn’t as bad as the brace guys thinks. Hopefully with the brace she can at least get back into some of her regular activities. I realize that she can’t do the physical activities, but just getting out and about will help her mental health. Sending healing thoughts and prayers her way.
 
 
 Dame Rhetorica says: September 23, 2011 at 10:06 pm 
Hey sparkle! I’ve got the meth lab just about up&amp;running and the child laborers from El Salvador are busy with the earrings.

No really–been down with some pu-monia. Just a lingering cough&amp;tired now. So this is what I missed the last 5 days:

* Taylor checked into the Betty Ford Clinic.
* Klienfelds is selling Squezit.
* Dr. Phil counseled Simon in his depression from being let go from RHONY.
* Olivier was voted off the island.
* Rachel Zoe had a son named Joey.
* Theresa married Shon.
* Someone named Jill is missing.
Does that about cover it?
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 10:10 pm 
LOL!
There is a missing KooKoo bird.
 
 Dame Rhetorica says: September 23, 2011 at 10:21 pm 
Oh, I forgot about the bird! And wasn’t there a beaver missing too?
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 10:29 pm 
Dame…Mr ford put a sign out in the yard..My beaver who is now a wood chuckette has been safely returned to its oringinal location…
Thanks for your concern…
My meth shipment did not get delivered to day..am sending my brownie troop out to look for the truck..
is your GPS working yet ??

Covert ops….wink

Diva
 
 Dame Rhetorica says: September 23, 2011 at 10:32 pm 
LOL…cough…cough…ROTFL…gasp…gasp…:)
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:02 pm 
Diva, I think the beaver is now here eating out of Teresa’s dish.
When that shipment comes in, please remember to forward my regular allotment.

Thx.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:37 pm 
RM…Okee ma choke me….Look for the BROWN TRUCK….the cable guy will be driving it…..

Diva
Rocky in the back…on ICE
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:04 pm 
A nude beaver! Bejeweled.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:40 pm 
Adgirl….not bejeweled…VAJAZZLED…
how much wood could a woodchuck chuck if a woodchuck could chuck wood….
I dont know.. go ask the beaver…DAM !!!
 
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:21 pm 
Dame, what you said makes just as much sense as what really happened. So yes, that does cover it.

Get better soon!!
 
 Dame Rhetorica says: September 23, 2011 at 10:26 pm 
Hey Minkey! I’ve been trying to follow your saga with the Minkette. No results till next week? Gez. We had to wait for damette’s MRI to be transcribed from an out if office company!
(i usually call her dammit:)
 
 
 Kris says: September 23, 2011 at 10:16 pm 
I don’t know if this was mentioned before, but I don’t get Taylor and her whole schtick. If she’s only been married to Russell for 5 years, what has she been doing for the other 30 years of her life? She talks about how she was alone (in the hot tub) and she doesn’t want to go back to that, and she thought she had a good thing with Russell before his financials/their scamming, hit the skids, but as someone who was raised poor as well, I learned at an early age if I wanted something I’d have to make it happen for myself b/c i would never want to be in a position to have to rely on a man or anyone else. So wtf was she doing to not provide for herself without the help of a man. Like some here say it’s uber bizarre that none of her family has spoken out; it’s all‘friends of Taylor’say xyz. For all the companies she’s had/been involved with how come she has no kind of job to go to, and is‘completely broke’. She’s been separated from Russell for months, so how does his death all of a sudden throw her into such a tailspin? Even if she had to bury him, that can be done for like 10K, and they have the family trust and I’d assume some kind of help for the burial if he was buried in TX. Plus, the whole four name changes is beyond shady. No one goes through that much paperwork just b/c they like Tom Ford the designer. (rant over, lol)
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:31 pm 
I agree, I wonder where she was for all those years. She says she didn’t get with him, or maybe marry him, til she was 34. Surely she dated before that? I think she was a sales rep for a pharmaceutical company, no?

She told Dr Phil that there was no family trust, that she found out that that was a lie.
I also agree with the name change thing. Coooome ooon! Ridiculous lie there.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 10:41 pm 
Kris and Zoey…. The name change was done in Fl in late 2004..It was part of the pre planned shell /sham game that her and Russell conjoured up…..
It all started on Taylors ( Shana ) part back in Oklahoma…
More to come later…….. have more leg work to do…..

Diva
 Kris says: September 23, 2011 at 11:01 pm 
that’s interesting since the lawsuit said that Russell’s mom has 51% (IIRC) or some high stake in the Russell Family Trust so who to believe…Dr. Phil hates scammers/stealing/grifters so I’m surprised he even had her on the show. I get theirs some interest since it’s the first reality tv suicide, but still Idon’t think she’ll bring in that many ratings.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:13 pm 
I think it’s going to hurt him.
 
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:33 pm 
Kris you are too funny! I think we all are very skeptical. I mean“Ford”because she likes a designer? What–not Kors or Prada? Puulleeez.

Those missing years will be quite interesting I’m sure. I can’t wait to find out what Diva has up her sleeve about the name change.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:44 pm 
Adgirl..i found the file online in PBC…I need to go to the courthouse to look at the stuff they put online…..should be interesting..I’ll prob meet up with V5 and have lunch…wink
I may NOT post what I find but if anyone is interested they can send me an email to my HWS account only..
 hugsandpeace@hotmail.com 
Diva
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:46 pm 
OOOPPS,,stuff they DONT put online…..

Diva
 
 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 10:23 pm 
Okay..for all of you that are having trouble relaxing…..or are overly stressed…

Here….try this

It actually works!!! Just let yourself relax and feel the warmth!!!!

Just in case you are having a rough day, here is a stress management technique recommended in all the latest psychological journals. The funny thing is that it really does work and will make you smile.

1. Picture yourself lying on your belly on a warm rock that hangs out over a crystal clear stream.

2. Picture yourself with both your hands dangling in the cool running water.

3. Birds are sweetly singing in the cool mountain air.

4. No one knows your secret place.

5. You are in total seclusion from that hectic place called the world.

6. The soothing sound of a gentle water fall fills the air with a cascade of serenity.

7. The water is so crystal clear that you can easily make out the face of the person you are holding underwater.

There!! See? It really does work. You’re smiling already. Feel free to forward this if you know others who might benefit from this technique.

Hugs and Serenity
Diva“&gt;)
 
 Dame Rhetorica says: September 23, 2011 at 10:30 pm 
No trouble if this is repeated several times a day, right?
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 10:35 pm 
I would expect no more than at least 10……Thats why I keep my bath tub clean at all times…never know when you JUST might feel the NEED to DROWN someone…or two..or three

WINKS

Diva
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:34 pm 
Hahaha, omg! I was waiting for something to jump out and get me, or maybe I was naked and someone startled me. Whew, it was only holding someone underwater.

Mr Salami boo hooing on HLN, again.
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:36 pm 
Diabolique! (Bath tub reference to a French horror movie.)

Tareq is such boozo. Haha.
 
 TLM says: September 24, 2011 at 12:07 am 
The supposed Neal photo sent to him online is at http://shavedlongcock.blogspot.com/p/journey-guitarist-neal-schon-his-name.html . (Word of caution: explicit.)
 
 
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 10:43 pm 
FYI- Don’t eat cantaloupes from Rocky Ford co. from Jenson Farms, Colorado. So far the CDC says 55 people have been infected, with 8 deaths attributed to Listeriosis. There may or may not be a sticker on it to I.D. where it came from; ask the store. I just bought a cantaloupe a few days ago…really want to eat it but will wait to call the store tomorrow and find out where it came from.
Last few months it was ground turkey (may still be an on-going recall).

Scary to think how much we trust these people with our lives!

 http://www.cdc.gov/nczved/divisions/dfbmd/diseases/listeriosis/092111.html 
 
 Lillybee says: September 23, 2011 at 11:35 pm 
Michelle Bachman wants to repeal most food safety laws.
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:42 pm 
Wha??? Is her cheese sliding off her cracker? The FDA needs to be revamped and made stronger, imo.
 
 
 
Pingback: IHBF News: The Appauling Behavior Of Lynn Hudson Part 1 | ihatebethennyfrankel 
 Dame Rhetorica says: September 23, 2011 at 10:51 pm 
Everyone rock on! I’m gonna take another nap. Diva, you’re in charge if the beaver.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 10:58 pm 
Dame…I’ll let Bullwinkle know…ya know how clingy he is to that beaver of his……wink

FEEL BETTER…
Will post you a ROCKING TUNE IN THE MORNING…after church and java…

Diva
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:24 pm 
Diva,
Are you still up? I had to leave the computer to go cat hunting.
I got Mona in but of course Roxie was a no show until her“father”came home. Figures. In his eyes she’s a princess but she treats me quite differently. I wish I had a son. Raising 3“daughters”is a pain at times. At least all are in for the night.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:30 pm 
Nancy. I’m up. Are you seeing pingbacks on your computer. I’m see some pingbacks about IHBF and the appauling behavior of Lynn Hudson. I actually hit it and there is a background of B with her buttcheek hanging out, but nothing else. What is a pingback anyway? It’s kinda funny.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:31 pm 
BB,
What in Gods name are you talking about?
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:36 pm 
NEVER MIND!!!!! I just saw it.
 
 Nancy says: September 23, 2011 at 11:37 pm 
I’m surprised that that can happen.
It’s Lynn’s site. I haven’t read the entire thing yet.
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:39 pm 
What is a ping back??
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:41 pm 
No clue here.
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:44 pm 
From the WordPress glossary:

Pingback lets you notify the author of an article if you link to his article (article on a blog, of course). If the links you include in an article you write on a blog lead to a blog which is pingback-enabled, then the author of that blog gets a notification in the form of a pingback that you linked to his article.
 thedesigndiva says: September 24, 2011 at 12:14 am 
Adgirl.. a ping back is a type of sandal worn by Catholic girls….it makes running in the sand so much easier…
JZ girdles will now take the former name for the other type of shoe…the SLING BACK….hahahaha

Diva
 
 
 Lillybee says: September 23, 2011 at 11:37 pm 
I am seeing them too.
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:42 pm 
I’m saying thre is a We Hate Bethenny Frankel website out there. What took someone so long to start one is the question.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:46 pm 
Maybe it’s been around a long time, but no one has known about it because no one reads it.
 
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:40 pm 
When I clicked it on, it went to an I hate Bethenny site that was complaining about a dispute between Lynn and Stoopidhousewives. The whole thing looked ridiculous.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:44 pm 
The spelling is horrible from what I can see.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 pm 
Very.
 
 Zoey says: September 23, 2011 at 11:45 pm 
I actually read it, or tried to. It made little to no sense, but the bottom line is it was something petty, unfounded, blown out of proportion, and sounds jealousy based, aimed at Lynn. Waste of my time reading that crappola!
 
 Adgirl says: September 23, 2011 at 11:53 pm 
Why would a blogger spend time whining about other bloggers? Don’t they have anything real to write about?
I could not care less about childish BS. Unless it’s on my tv.

Let’s talk about Taylor some more.
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 23, 2011 at 11:58 pm 
OK. I can’t figure her out. I keep reading everyone’s opinion and still can’t decide whether to hate her or feel sorry for her. I’m leaning towards the hate thing though. Discuss
 
 RealMinkey says: September 24, 2011 at 12:00 am 
Hate thing.

There, that’s my discussion.

Good night, ladies.
 
 RealMinkey says: September 24, 2011 at 12:02 am 
I forgot to tell you all I love you.

OK, now I did.

Goodnight again. 
 thedesigndiva says: September 24, 2011 at 12:06 am 
Good night Chet//Good night David..good night Minkey…WE LOVE YOU ALSO….
I’m watching golden Girls and checking in here…. So girls WASSUUUPPPP
 
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:00 am 
Adgirl,
You crack me up. I feel like we are having a sleep over.“Let’s talk about Taylor some more”!
Ok, you start!
 
 Adgirl says: September 24, 2011 at 12:07 am 
OK you know what BUGGED me the very most about Taylor on Dr Phil??
The night Russell was found dead Kennedy had a playdate -sleepover!

WTFFFFFF?
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:09 am 
I’m not getting the point.
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:13 am 
OMG,
I get it.
Yes that is REALLY strange.
It’s like she has no emotional
connection with Kennedy.
To be honest I don’t think she has that to anyone.
 Fairy says: September 24, 2011 at 1:15 am 
I know. Hard to see how her home would not have been on lock down. I would have canceled the playmate. Milk, cookies, and oh yeah…can’t even finish that. Ack
 
 
 
 
 TLM says: September 24, 2011 at 12:04 am 
I couldn’t follow the rambling, myself. It’s funny that it’s called I hate Bethenny when it’s really about“I Hate Lynn.”I wonder if it was written with the help of Jelly Beans Beensomeone.
 
 
 
 
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 23, 2011 at 11:52 pm 
Boy you girls dont pay attention do you…wink…..Those ping backs happen here almost every day.. at least on my computer they do…
Mr ford has a full belly and went to bed hrs ago,,
Now it’s my time…
Glass of lemon water and choc cupcake…
Life is Good…. Rock On

Diva
 TLM says: September 23, 2011 at 11:59 pm 
I don’t know if this is the real deal, but supposedly this is the sexting pic Neal Schon sent Tareq. If this is really him, not sure how Michaele can walk! (WARNING: NSFW) http://shavedlongcock.blogspot.com/p/journey-guitarist-neal-schon-his-name.html 
 thedesigndiva says: September 24, 2011 at 12:03 am 
Did anyone watch the premier of dateline tonite ??

Diva
 
 Adgirl says: September 24, 2011 at 12:09 am 
on DVR. Was it good?
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:16 am 
I answered your post upthread.
 thedesigndiva says: September 24, 2011 at 12:17 am 
adgirl…OH YEA…I was screaming at the tv and went on a rant after I watched it..Poor Mr Ford…We’ll discuss after you watch it…
Now that woman is the C word…wait till you see it….

Diva
 
 
 TLM says: September 24, 2011 at 12:05 am 
N.S.F.W. photo supposedly sent to Tareq by Neal Schon. Hard for me to believe it’s authentic. http://shavedlongcock.blogspot.com/p/journey-guitarist-neal-schon-his-name.html 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 24, 2011 at 12:07 am 
Good Night Everyone!
 
 zanne says: September 24, 2011 at 12:15 am 
I want to come to the slumber party.
“Taylor”was a cheer leader at her high school. Just know what I know about that school (and having a grand daughter as a cheer leader at another school), the uniforms and jacket and special shoes and socks and hair stuff and etc. it cost some one about $3,000.00 for her to be the cheer leader. She wasn’t to poor in high school.
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:17 am 
I really think she is pathological.
 
 thedesigndiva says: September 24, 2011 at 12:25 am 
nancy…she is a full blown sociopath that takes speed and drinks and creates illusions.. I see her crashing soon.. I truly believe that she poses a danger to her daughter…Let’s hope the ASSistant keeps a better eye on her this time around….
Diva
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:29 am 
I agree. There is something very disturbing about her. I fine her very cold emotionally. My heart breaks for Kennedy.
 
 
 
 Zoey says: September 24, 2011 at 12:17 am 
Good night! May tomorrow be a peaceful, pain free, productive day for all of us!
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:19 am 
Goodnight Zoey.
 
 
 zanne says: September 24, 2011 at 12:25 am 
Well, I’ve had a cat get up in the chair and say it’s time for bed. (she doesn’t think she can sleep unless my feet are under her). And now the poodle has just come in and keeps going down the hall to the bed room——–so good night all.
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:26 am 
Sounds like my house. Goodnight.
 Adgirl says: September 24, 2011 at 12:33 am 
You ladies have a great night!!
 
 Nancy says: September 24, 2011 at 12:30 am 
I’m going to bed. Goodnight everyone.
 thedesigndiva says: September 24, 2011 at 12:31 am 
Off to walk the kids…then play some ZUMA..
Hasta lata winnebago…..

Hugs and Peace
Diva
 Fairy says: September 24, 2011 at 1:18 am 
Nite gals. Cya when I toss the hub out to play with his friends. After he cleans the house.
 Proud Mary says: September 24, 2011 at 2:44 am 
Hi all!

My internet is finally up and running again and I am so enjoying everyones comments…especially about evil kitties (can they still be a kitty at 16? I’m sure she is evil though) With a name like Beauford, she was bound for trouble. 

The last week at work Ive been seeing promos for Taylor with her face scrunched up and no tears talking/wailing about Russell beating her and Kennedy asking for a doorway to heaven on some ET show. I want to throw a walker at the TV but then I’d have some‘splaining to do! 

The other night was priceless though (mind you I work in a dementia unit and the residents watch anything from Judge Judy to Jersey Shoret to Slap Chop guy without a blink) Taylor was on crying sobbing and one resident asked What’s wrong with her?? Another said Sourpuss while a third said her lips are as wide as the day is long!! Lol. Most interaction that I’ve seen in awhile! Her face really woke them up! I love my second family! 
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 24, 2011 at 4:01 am 
Hi there. I’m scrolling for the Beauford post (I adore kitties) and can’t find it.
So…good morning to you, PM!
 Zoey says: September 24, 2011 at 7:39 pm 
That’s so funny PMary, at least looking at Taylor is good for something!
 
 Baroness Beachcomber says: September 24, 2011 at 4:58 am 
Since we’re a bunch of animal lovers. Thought y’all would enjoy this feel good story and slide show.

 http://today.msnbc.msn.com/id/44613691 
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 24, 2011 at 6:07 am 
Oh…BB! *sob*
Pitties are the best!
You have made my morning.
Oh the little puppypuppypuppy-pup.
 
 emt2 says: September 24, 2011 at 5:56 am 
from dr phil interview:

Taylor’s Reasons For Doing RHOBH–“I would say that my primary motivation for doing the show was because I was in a dangerous situation in my home life and I felt like there was protection offered to me by having cameras in my life because how’s anything going to happen if there’s a camera there to document everything.”

Really, Taylor? This is the dumbest thing i have ever heard.

Why Did Russell Do The Show?–Dr. Phil wondered why Russell, whom Taylor says physically abused her regularly, would agree to do a reality show. Taylor stated Russell simply felt he was untouchable: “There was a part of him that thought that he was impenetrable and that the world would fall in love with him.” When asked if she would do the show all over again knowing what she knows now, Taylor responded: “I don’t think the end result of what happened in the Tornado would have been any different with or without the camera present.”

Really, Taylor? Because Russell always seemed to LOVE being on camera and made a big effort to be charming so the world would fall in love with him. I think that she is really talking about herself in this instance.

She is really spinning tails. She is freaking out about being held solely responsible for the financial mess they both created. I think that she did the show to find another husband because Russell didn’t have any more money. I really believe that.

She is off. I pray for her little girl.
 
 Viewer 5 says: September 24, 2011 at 6:04 am 
Well–It’s been reported she got 600K for recent appearances, interviews, and–um…photos of her black eye. It’s not surprising that her handlers just got 60K (at least) in one week for setting all these up.

Three years from now, we’ll be reading how Taylor was a“victim”of her handlers…(when she doesn’t have any money left and the show is canceled.)
 
 LynnNChicago says: September 24, 2011 at 6:52 am 
 http://wp.me/p1Knfy-p0 

New Blog!
 
 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
Admin

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
Search
 Search for: 
Advertisement
 Your Ad Here 

 
 
 
Recent Posts

 LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom LynnNChicago Real Housewives of Orange County / Pregnant In Heels / Exclusive Interview with Sarah Winchester LynnNChicago Real Housewives of Orange County / Pregnant In Heels / Exclusive Interview with Sarah Winchester LynnNChicago Real Housewives of Orange County Reunion Part I–Let’s Chat LynnNChicago Real Housewives of New York / Push Girls 
 
Recent Comments

 I Need A Housewives&apos; Detox Program on LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom Catseye on LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom I Need A Housewives&apos; Detox Program on LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom Catseye on LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom Catseye on LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom 
 
 
 
 Lynn N Chicago 

 LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC / Teen Mom: lynnnchicago.com/?p=9811 UPDATED 2 hours ago LynnNChicago Million Dollar Listing / Around The World in 80 Plates / Fashion Roundup RHOOC : lynnnchicago.com/?p=9811 New Blog! 4 hours ago @ BWalshWriter It did! Thank you for Tweeting me, I couldn&apos;t find you on Twitter! Loved the book! Thanks again for sending #GoldCoastWives 13 hours ago @ Mikeb5763 put your seat belt on #BadBoy :) 16 hours ago @ LaurenBGlassman Thanks Lauren! xoxo Love to hear from you! Hope all is well :) 17 hours ago 
 
Blog Stats

 
 
 

 
 
Contact Blog Owner
 &quot;Friend&quot; me on Facebook: http://www.facebook.com/lynnnchicago
Follow me on Twitter @LynnNChicago
Email me at: LynnAHudson@gmail.com 
Links

 Inbox Full Suggest Ideas 
 
Julia’s Organic Things
 
Handmade Skin Care
 LynnNChicago on Twitter Counter 
 LynnNChicago Proudly powered by WordPress. Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
