<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003125" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/the-fresh-market-latham" time="2012-07-12-19:15" support="8" score="0.009849729782915128" bingtitle="The Fresh Market - Latham, NY" webtitle="The Fresh Market - Latham, NY">
			<query id="000991" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000929" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000803" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000272" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001463" bing-rank="6"/>
	<description>I was holding my receipt and shopping bag, obviously not ... we have a different interpretation of the word &quot;order ... I expected it to be with the baking goods, since that&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
The Fresh Market
 44 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Food Grocery Grocery   [Edit] 
 664 New Loudon Rd 
 Latham , NY 12110 
 (518) 786-5150 http://www.thefreshmarket.com 
 
 Add Photos Hours: 
Mon-Sat 9 am - 9 pm

Sun 9 am - 8 pm
 Price Range: $$$ 
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 First to Review Ian W. 
 Edit Business Info Work Here? Unlock This Business Page 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review Yelp Ad Honest Weight Food Co-op 43 reviews About This Business: 
The Honest Weight Food Co-op is full-service natural foods grocery store. Organic foods have become trendy of late, but we&apos;ve been selling them for over…   read more» 
 
44 reviews for The Fresh Market
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;I was most impressed by their produce selection.&quot; In 20 reviews &quot;...the beer selection has a make your own six pack section.&quot; In 4 reviews &quot;...say enough about the bakery and cheese selection as well.&quot; In 6 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
44 reviews in English

 
Review from Chris C. 
 
 2 friends 18 reviews 

 Chris C. 
 
Latham, NY
 7/1/2012 
There are a few things here you shouldn&apos;t miss:
the yeast raised donuts: Ask for a box to put them in
the coffee - good stuff
the natural rotiserrie wings are about the best I&apos;ve ever had anywhere

Yes, it&apos;s cramped and far too expensive to be a regular stop, but it&apos;ll stay in rotation until Trader Joes opens in August. Oh, and the wings.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from mel P. 
 
 2 friends 25 reviews 

 mel P. 
 
Ballston Lake, NY
 2/22/2012 1 Check-in Here 
But... But... I want to like this store!

Pros:
I was on a mission to find organic fruits and vegetables for baby food. They had plenty! Avocados, mangoes, pears, apples, blueberries, and so much more. I also like their chip selection. I&apos;m so sick of garbage chips with all kinds of crap in them. The meat and fish cases looked really yummy. I just didn&apos;t have the energy to fight the lines.

Cons:
This store is so claustrophobic. You&apos;re constantly bumping into everything. You can get a cart but there is no room to push them around! Well, maybe if you were the only person in the store but, you won&apos;t be. This definitely makes it difficult if you have a baby with you. The store is anything but baby friendly.

The worst part is the check out! They give you a square foot to put all your groceries on. So check out takes forever and the lines just build up. Also, the cart from the person before you (and the people before them and the people before them...) all accumulate at the end of the check out. I literally couldn&apos;t get through. This is something they should address immediately!

I will be holding my breath HOPING they build a whole foods or Trader Joe&apos;s in this area soon! Until then... I&apos;ll have to get a baby sitter to run out to Fresh Market.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (3) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from James F. 
 
 3 friends 15 reviews 

 James F. 
 
Albany, NY
 2/17/2012 1 photo 1 Check-in Here 
When you are born and raised in Albany, Price Chopper and Hannaford are the only two grocery stores that really come to mind. A few years ago when Fresh Market announced they were making an entrance into the capital district I couldn&apos;t believe it.

Having shopped at Trader Joes a few times out of state, I was hoping Fresh Market could bring some of the same qualities and selections. The store is quite small, compared to others, but contains almost everything most stores have.

One of the main reasons I shop at Fresh Market is for fresh beef. Fresh Market carries Hereford beef which is known for being leaner and more flavorful compared to most beef. The full service butcher counter carries it all from filet to chimichurri skirt steak to premade gourmet burgers and much more. Every time I have purchased beef here it has been amazing and tasty.

Fresh Market also has very good prepared foods. I have recently fallen in love with the curry chicken salad (thanks for the recommendation ;-)) and the baked potato salad is very good as well. They offer many other prepared foods such as fried and grilled chicken cutlets, meatballs, salads, and twice baked potatoes which I have heard are good.

Other unique features are that you can grind your own fresh peanut butter as well as create your own 6 packs of beer, which is nice.

Fresh Market can be a little more expensive than other places but if you are looking for quality items and don&apos;t mind the increase then this is the place to shop.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Matt W. 
 
 32 friends 201 reviews 

 Matt W. 
 
Niskayuna, NY
 2/15/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
I&apos;m a fairly hardcore veteran of Trader Joe&apos;s and Whole Foods, being a recent Californian transplant, and thus my experience of The Fresh Market is probably inevitably going to be in contrast to these two bookend stores with similar, but hardly identical, approaches to better food.

As a general type, The Fresh Market is indeed wedged between Whole Foods and TJ&apos;s. It&apos;s smaller than Whole Foods but bigger than most TJs. It&apos;s got regular grocery departments like Whole Foods but has a higher proportion of processed foods. There are smaller dry goods sections (such as personal care) than WF, this type of thing being virtually non-existent at TJs. I may be overgeneralizing here, but it did seem like a &quot;medium&quot; option to TJ&apos;s bargain- and processed-food and Whole Foods&apos; high-end-everything Whole Paycheck approach.

There are a couple of problems with The Fresh Market, which I strongly suspect are localized and &quot;break-in&quot; issues, so I&apos;ll deal with the complaints at the end of the review. First off the good stuff, which predominated my experience.

The produce is excellent. Good organic brands, not as big a variety as Whole Foods, but more than TJ&apos;s and more on the fresher side. Certainly the best winter produce I&apos;ve found in the region since coming here, which is going to bring me back. And the prices are (generally) cheaper than we typically had at Whole Foods -- this is a straight Apples to Apples comparison (literally, in some cases). The meat selection for red meat and poultry was decent, with good free range and natural alternatives and a reasonably wide selection at, again, better prices for some similar items than Whole Foods had but not quite in the bargain hunting level the non-organic TJ&apos;s items usually are.

I like the layout of the store. It&apos;s easy to see where things are, the aisles aren&apos;t endlessly confusing, the &quot;gourmet&quot; and prepared food areas are in circles you can easily get around, and in general the lighting and mojo are good, right down to the piped in classical music. I didn&apos;t buy any of the prepared foods but they looked appetizing and there looked like a good variety. The checkout lines are a little confusingly blocked by bumper ends, though, and there&apos;s not a lot of negotiating room at the end to get your stuff together. That said, it&apos;s an improvement on both the typical Whole Foods and TJ layouts.

Some nits, followed by criticisms. The &quot;gourmet cheese&quot; section is what I&apos;d call Safeway-quality - hardly anything really unique, and I couldn&apos;t find local cheeses (I looked hard, maybe I missed them, but they weren&apos;t highlighted). The &quot;bulk foods&quot; area is small and is really emphasizing things like trail mix and not grains, seeds, pastas, and so forth the way Whole Foods does. The seafood section was pretty discouraging - just as bad as the Hannaford-Price Chopper-Shop Rite universe. In general, items were in smaller sizes or with fewer brands than a bigger store could support; for instance I couldn&apos;t get organic milk in gallon sizes, and the only California olive oil was flavored.

Now I&apos;m going to beat you up a little, The Fresh Market. The staff were pretty clueless about food, across the store. The seafood guy didn&apos;t know what I was talking about when I asked about sustainable fish or mercury counts. The butchers were a little unclear about cuts and origins of the meats. The produce guy was nice but couldn&apos;t tell me how old some of the stuff was and made some errors on the origins of the food. In general they seemed badly undertrained for a higher-end food store. If you&apos;re going to use quality as your niche, you better support it with staff who know the food and can sell it for you.

Then there was the &quot;coffee problem&quot;. I stopped in the middle of the store to get some coffee, where the urns appeared to be self-serve. No cups in sight. Absolutely no staff to be found anywhere near the coffee area. So I got out my own travel mug, something I&apos;ve done 500 times at Whole Foods or Starbucks over the years, and poured myself a cup.

Then, when I went to check out, the clerk was aghast I&apos;d POURED MY OWN COFFEE INTO MY OWN MUG. She told me not to do that, and she had no idea how to charge me. I had to wait for a manager, who dithered a bit before having my coffee rung up as...fresh flowers? I was scolded NOT TO DO THAT AGAIN. So, I&apos;ve just saved them a few cents for their cup, and prevented another styrofoam bullet from entering the environment, in part because I couldn&apos;t find any )#)@ cups to begin with and nobody to help me, AND I GET A #$#)@_@ING talking to? I mean, I got 10 cents back when I brought my mug to Bux, here I get the stink eye? C&apos;mon folks you gotta do better than that.

And,  I got no bag refund for bringing my own bags. What&apos;s up with that?

So, that said, relative to the area this looks like the only option for a lot of things in the organic food line, and it&apos;s not terribly overpriced, so I&apos;ll be back. I just am not going to buy the coffee if I value my life.
 
 Listed in: Groceries: Searching for Mr.… 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (9) Funny (3) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Daiji K. 
 
 46 friends 41 reviews 

 Daiji K. 
 
Albany, NY
 12/27/2011 1 photo 
Let&apos;s talk some baseball.  I am no pitcher, but if Fresh Market was the opposing team, our team would pull off the perfect game.

Today was my first time trying the place out, and I was highly disappointed.  At first glance, the place looked welcoming and vibrant.  I was drawn to the salmon deal that said buy one get one free for 5.99.  I started to ask a question to the lady that came over about that deal.  &quot;How much would I need to get to get that deal....&quot; She cut me off with something along the lines of, I&apos;m helping this customer, you need to get a ticket.  I definitely didn&apos;t act as if I was cutting in line, but she definitely made me feel like it.  The answer probably would&apos;ve take two words: &quot;any amount.&quot;  Decided that I&apos;m not having salmon tonight.  Strike 1.

I then went over to try some coffee.  They had some samplings which was nice.  I was pretty satisfied with the pumpkin spice decaff, but not so much on the decaff.  I asked the lady if there was a caffeinated pumpkin spice and she snapped at me saying that all the samplings were out in front of me.  Strike 2

I went to the check out, thinking overall, my first impressions were really bad.  A $3.79, 4.99, 5.99 came out to be 17.49.  I was actually a little preoccupied with figuring out whether the cash register was wirelessly connected to the TV, so I took a look at my receipt as I was walking out.  Now I know tax exists, but I didn&apos;t think I needed to tip my cash register.  I wanted to talk to someone about my receipt because it didn&apos;t seem right, and I was charged for a 10.99 bulk item.  As I went back to a register, the lady incessantly said, &quot;I am closed after this customer, please find another register.&quot;  I was holding my receipt and shopping bag, obviously not looking like I was going to purchase anything.  But that didn&apos;t seem to matter to her.  No customer service there.  Foul ball.

So I finally got someone to help me.  He initially said, the 10.99 was a bulk item. Then he almost tried to convince me that the 10.99 was for the coffee, but I said, no that was 5.99.  I usually don&apos;t remember prices, so that might&apos;ve changed my mind.  And then he came to conclusion that she accidentally pressed the wrong button.  He gave me back the $11 in cash and said, &quot;we&apos;ll call it even.&quot;  No apologies.  He wasn&apos;t rude, but it&apos;s nice to hear a simple sorry.  I mean think about it, that was 3 products I bought.  Most people buy a lot more, which makes the mistakes harder to check.  Strike 3, game over.

The ninth inning was the highlight of the game.  Let me tell you, it was no easy feat, but I have decided, I am not coming back here by choice unless management makes trades for better players or maybe a Joe.  I&apos;ll leave on a high note.  In hindsight, I feel like I lowered my standards for buying stuff from them because I don&apos;t just buy a product; it&apos;s also about the service.  I&apos;m sure if they recruited Wegmans, their team would hit a home run.  That&apos;s probably never going to happen, so I guess I&apos;ll have to wait on 79 Wolf.  Please make that happen Colonie.  Thanks!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (11) Funny (7) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tatjana V. 
 
 18 friends 94 reviews 

 Tatjana V. 
 
Galway, NY
 1/8/2012 
Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh.

If I close my eyes, it&apos;s like shopping at places I&apos;m used to shopping: New Flower, Sunflower, Sprouts, Whole Foods. I&apos;ve only been to Trader Joe&apos;s once in the last 15 years, and I cried because it was so beautiful... so this store is not in that league...

HOWEVER, I feel like I need to come clean: I moved here from Austin, TX. I am spoiled and used to very high food prices. Being in the middle of the state, food has to travel very far.

Moving here astounded me in it&apos;s limited grocery options. With the mind-boggling number of people coming from the city and whining so loudly about the lack of, well shopping, it&apos;s unbelievable that no one is taking advantage of a huge market vacuum.  Well, the smart folks from NC have opened a grocery filling this void. Mind you, it&apos;s 40 minutes away, in an area of soul-sucking strip malls. I bought more here, for less than I paid at Hannaford&apos;s in Amsterdam. 90 dollars less, to be exact. That counts the amount of gas I used, mind you. So at first blush, it was even more savings.

No, they don&apos;t have everything. Not a single bottle of gluten free beer graces their shelves, nor do they have one single variety of gluten free pizza crust; however, they have many delicious varieties for you to try. They have Fenitmen&apos;s Tonic, Ginger Brew and English lemonade (for Pimms!). They have Hobnobs, and salty chocolate, tamale husks and white corn. They have pretty darn friendly service. I did notice some surly customers, so if you don&apos;t get the best service, you might want to whip out that mirror to double check you aren&apos;t, yourself, being a douche. It happens to us all.
Now, I wish their fish counter was bigger, and had more sustainable options. I wish their meat had an organic or at least local, biodynamic option.

Their cheese counter could be so much... without 40 pounds of cheddar clogging its pores, but heck, I got my goatsmilk butter and sometimes I just want a hunk of colby.

Right, well, like I said, it&apos;s not perfect, but it&apos;s one of the best options I&apos;ve got at an-almost reasonable distance.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Karly O. 
 
 15 friends 29 reviews 

 Karly O. 
 
Schenectady, NY
 9/12/2011 5 photos 
I&apos;m SO pleased to have The Fresh Market in our area. With no Trader Joes, or Whole Foods of any kind we have been lacking any &quot;fancy schmancy&quot; place to shop. This place fills the void.

They offer gourmet cheeses, fresh veggies, wonderful breads, amazing fresh meats, spices, sauce, oils, nuts, ooooooh.... and the COFFEE selection is a reason to go here all on it&apos;s own!

Now granted, I&apos;m not completely love struck. I do know that it&apos;s expensive, and the Organic selection is kinda small and expensiver (yes, expensiver is a word)...
But they offer LOTS to make up for the few short falls.
I love the Cage free Omega 3 eggs and Nitrate free bacon and deli meats.
They have coffee samples out to taste daily. While there last week I tried the Pumpkin Spice flavor and fell in love! And as I walked around the produce section sipping my miniature cup of hot coffee the smell of pumpkin candles in the air, and the soft elevator music playing around me truly had me high. I was blissful.... very blissful.

I went on my lunch hour to grab a few things. Stumbled across the Hot Soup section which had Turkey Chili amongst a few other options. I grabbed a small bowl. It was DEVINE! I added a sprinkle of salt, pepper, and Tabasco (just cause I like my stuffs spicy!). I was impressed with the meat chunks and cooked down onions and peppers in it. Very flavorful. I&apos;d definitely get it again if the opportunity arose.

The staff was incredibly nice. I interacted with 3 people that day: A guy at the butcher counter who was very friendly and took the time to walk me over to the Nitrate free bacon section out by the eggs. A lady at the cheese counter who explained to me the difference between some cheeses. And the cashier who after me telling him I was bummed they didn&apos;t have more organic fruits explained to to find them, where they usually are, and apologized for the inconvience.
They were all Aces!

If you&apos;re looking for better quality foods and have a little extra padding to your wallet this place is a God send!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Colleen M. 
 
 83 friends 292 reviews 

 Colleen M. 
 
Latham, NY
 Updated - 9/7/2011 1 Check-in Here 
4.5 stars I&apos;m not gonna lie: my favorite feature is the make your own six pack.  Sure Latham Price Chopper offers a similar selection for its make your own, but TFM is chilled beer and instantly ready for consumption.  I&apos;ve tried a bunch of beers that I otherwise never would have tried because I was able to buy 1 as part of an $8.99 make your own six pack.  right now (september) they have a lot of interesting oktoberfest variations.  kiss kiss kiss.  love you.

The meat is comparable in price to the meat sold in Price Chopper and comparable in quality to other conventional meat.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
2 Previous Reviews: Show all» 

 6/7/2011 
So yes it is safe to buy sushi in a grocery store. Its not as good as what you would get in a… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Heather S. 
 
 20 friends 58 reviews 

 Heather S. 
 
Gloversville, NY
 7/15/2011 
I stopped at the Fresh Market and I felt like I had found foodie heaven.  I was so excited that I had to post a facebook status about it.  I felt like a kid in a candy store. of course, it is not as exciting as places you might find in NYC or Boston but for the Latham area, this is fabulous!   It is like Trader Joe&apos;s and Wegmans had a smaller old world European style baby!

I sadly live about an hour away so I could not buy anything from the freezer or cold sections but I did stock up on Hint water which I love.  They not only have the full Hint selection which is impossible to find around here but they had better prices than even http://Amazon.com .  The other section I did the most shopping in was the bakery.  Mind you, I had just purchased some treats at Bella Napoli around the corner so I had NO need for more baked goods but I could not resist.  I had to have pretzel bread, some rolls, cookies and the chocolate hazelnut breakfast buns.

I think this is a place for me but know it is not for everyone.  I do not mind the layout and love the selection.  Some might prefer something different.

The staff seemed amazingly friendly.  I had a pleasant chat while I checked out and the cashier commented that I bought all her favorite things so I know I must have been picking up some of their best bakery items.

I am hoping we get another Fresh Market in the area, a little closer to my home, because I would love to shop there all the time. For now, it will be a special treat when I am shopping in the Albany/Latham area.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Katie V. 
 
 30 friends 81 reviews 

 Katie V. 
 
Valatie, NY
 7/8/2011 1 Check-in Here 
I was not particularly impressed with The Fresh Market. Having been to other upscale and specialty supermarkets, I found this one to be a little cramped and scatterbrained. It&apos;s not quite a supermarket -- if you&apos;re the thrifty sort, I would not recommend making it your home base super market -- but it&apos;s pretty good for prepared foods and specialty items now and again.

I did find the prepared items to be quite good and fresh, and was happy to see such a bounty of candy. It might be a place where I will stop if I don&apos;t feel like cooking, but I don&apos;t think I&apos;d shop there on a regular basis.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Amber F. 
 
 47 friends 35 reviews 

 Amber F. 
 
Troy, NY
 3/13/2011 
Now that my puppy love stage with The Fresh Market is over I feel that it&apos;s fair to review it.

We&apos;ll start with what sent me in to my blissful denial stage.

When you walk in, the smell of fresh flowers and the classical music immediately put you in a great mood.
It&apos;s a fantastic way to start off a shopping trip. (not so good for my wallet)
Everything is beautifully laid out and merchandised wonderfully.

You sometimes you forget you&apos;re in Latham.

(Although the zen like shopping trip are null and void when you go on a Saturday)

The merchandise-

The orange juice is super delicious but pretty pricey.   They used to have a sample area for it but that has since disappeared.

I heart the coffee and all of the coffee choices. My favorite is the chocolate cherry.   It&apos;s actually cheaper than the Green Mountain that I usually buy.
I also love that I can get a little sample of coffee to have while shopping.

Spices!  I love the little spice bags I can pick up for 1-3 bucks on average.   I can fill up my spice collection without breaking the bank.

Notable mentions-The ginormous olive bar, the fact that they carry hearts of palm (although none from Brazil)  and the set price for the you pick 6 beers.
The sun dried tomato and asaigo cheese bread.

Excuse me for a second.
ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhh mmmmmmmmmm

Okay, I&apos;m back.

Now onto the reality stage of the relationship.

Besides the already mentioned poor cheese selection, the bread selection is probably worse.

Since they don&apos;t seem to carry the Ezekiel bread I usually buy, I was going to treat myself to regular old wheat bread but after scouring the small bread section I couldn&apos;t find anything that wasn&apos;t filled with gross ingredients.
Also, I don&apos;t think they carry almond milk.

Now for the embarrassing part.
In a moment of starved weakness I purchased a spicy trio sushi platter.  It was pretty gross all around but what do you expect?  However, it gets worse.  As I was stuffing a piece in my mouth I looked over and and staring back at me was a piece of shrimp that was not de-turded.  (I&apos;m no seafood expert but I have seen Tommy Boy a number of times.)
Let me say, I didn&apos;t finish my mouthful.

That was hard for me to admit but I felt it was necessary to save someone else from making my mistake.

I still love The Fresh Market as a fun little excursion and a place to get coffee but not as my regular shopping place.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (9) Funny (7) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Otis M. 
 
 73 friends 291 reviews 

 Otis M. 
 
Saratoga Springs, NY
 2/20/2011 
Finally made it down to FM. Thanks to their policy of &quot;if it&apos;s in a bin with a scoop you can sample it&quot; I emerged about 15 pounds heavier. But also about $141 poorer (we stopped in to get salad for dinner) so I guess the joke is on me.

The comparisons to Trader Joe&apos;s are apt. Rather than a full line market it&apos;s a curated selection with a lot of variety packed into a not-huge space. The difference is that while TJ is mostly house brand items, FM is a broader selection of brands. I didn&apos;t find anything outrageously overpriced. And there were some really nice sale prices.

Whether you love or just like FM is going to depend on how much you agree with their selection process. I&apos;d give five stars for the produce and the bulk bins, but found the butcher, bakery and deli sections fairly thin. (And more attuned to folks who want a semi-prepared meal to finish at home than those who are going to cook from scratch.)

A special note to those from down south: they have both field peas (frozen) and Trappey&apos;s pepper sauce (chiles in vinegar, for dousing said peas).
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (8) Funny (1) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jeffrey B. 
 
 17 friends 15 reviews 

 Jeffrey B. 
 
Latham, NY
 8/7/2011 1 Check-in Here 
In general items are priced higher than other stores, but they also have items that other stores do not carry along with great baked goods and a fresh as expensive meat department.
My wife prefers the molten chocolate coffee at 10.99 a pound not cheap, but worth it.
I don&apos;t go here often even living less than a mile away, but when I do go I am never disappointed with what I purchased.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Stephanie S. 
 
 22 friends 52 reviews 

 Stephanie S. 
 
Albany, NY
 1/29/2011 
I&apos;m a fan of Fresh Market, but there a few things that bother me.  I think they could have more organic products and carry more local products.  I think they try to give out the organic vibe, but they fall short.  It is extremely clean and nicely laid out which is nice.  It gives out an upscale vibe both from the outside and when you walk in.

I really like their meats.  My personal favorite is the chimichuri hanger steaks.  Mmmm.  I could easily eat them once a week.  They also have good prepared foods.  I really like their rotisserie chicken salad and actually their rotisserie chickens.  They also have delicious curry chicken salad.  I was a little disappointed to see the same old crappy ingredients in some of their baked sweet goodies, but I think that&apos;s almost to be expected in those type of things.

I think if you stick to the prepared foods and meats you won&apos;t be disappointed.  Mostly everything I have gotten has been great.

The people who work here are definitely friendlier than the employees at your run of the mill supermarket as well.

Overall Fresh Market does a good job.  I do feel the prices are a little high, but the alternatives in this area are pretty awful except for the co-op.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Willie W. 
 
 30 friends 90 reviews 

 Willie W. 
 
Albany, NY
 10/13/2010 1 Check-in Here 
After hearing about The Fresh Market when asking the Yelp community about ancho chili powder, I decided to take a ride out to check it out. I have to first admit, I am not a supermarket person. I have not been inside a supermarket in nearly a year, and really have no guilt about that. My wife does all the food shopping and I just do the butcher when necessary.

That said, The Fresh Market is a very different experience. Before we even walked in we saw a display of reusable shopping bags for purchase, setting the tone for what we could expect to see inside.

The selection was pretty diverse, items were available that we do not always find every day. My wife noticed a premium on many of the items that are available in the stores she shops, although she did find a few slam dunk bargains (only one I recall at the moment was the Romaine lettuce).

The store is laid out kinda funny. Things I expected to see in one area were in completely different spaces. For example, we were looking for quinoa, it&apos;s a gluten free grain. We&apos;ve heard about it but never bought it, but I happened to see it available online before we were at the store. I expected it to be with the baking goods, since that&apos;s what I expected you&apos;d be using it for. I do not recall where we ended up finding it, but it was a while later.

The most remarkable thing, however, is the various smells. There are spots you can stand and turn your head and pick up completely different scents. Between the coffee barrels, the candy area, spices, it was a remarkable olfactory treat. I imagine this is how my dogs feel when they stick their nose out the car window and just absorb all the different smells around them. Most other stores seem almost sterile in comparison.

While I thought the place was great in many ways, there were a few things that really did not sit well with me. You walk into the produce area and they have all sorts of fresh things on display. Huge display of apples, caught my eye. It&apos;s fall, in NY, in a place that has &quot;fresh&quot; in their name... I was expecting good things. I was not expecting apples from New Zealand. Seriously. Why would anyone want apples from across the globe during the local apple season?

Second, the isles are really pretty tiny. I know I have an issue around lots of people, I can often feel trapped. I guess it&apos;s kinda like claustrophobia, but it&apos;s really to do with people. I can be in a small space alone without bothering me, but if I start to feel there&apos;s too many people between me and an exit I start to need to find a way out. Anyway, the place is cramped and designed in such a way that it really triggered my idiosyncrasies. While there were plenty of people there and really enough room for everyone, it seems that everyone ends up being forced into the same choke points over and over. There is no way to walk around the store and avoid that. Very uncomfortable for me.

In all, we enjoyed the place. We picked up some items we might not have tried in our local markets. The smells were amazing and almost worth the visit on it&apos;s own.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (7) Funny (6) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from John N. 
 
 1 friend 67 reviews 

 John N. 
 
Rensselaer, NY
 4/23/2011 
Small.
Dark.
Expensive.

Products looked nice but because it is so small, I couldn&apos;t move around with the cart (which is child size to begin with).
After waiting, literally waiting, to get through the produce department I put the cart back, took a basket and got a few items. Nothing bad but overpriced compared to what can easily and enjoyably be purchased elsewhere in the Capital District.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kristy E. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 508 friends 154 reviews 

 Kristy E. 
 
Troy, NY
 Updated - 8/30/2010 9 photos 61 Check-ins Here 
Removing one star... only one, because of a few things I&apos;m quite picky about.

I&apos;ve been here maybe 6/7 times now. Most of the things I have purchased from here have been delicious and indeed fresh, However, I brought home a pineapple last night, looked at the bottom and there&apos;s a moldy spot. I bought large bottles of sparkling Voss the first night I visited a week ago, that have still not come back in stock since then. My daughter purchased some blackberries and said they had a musty taste. And I purchased some ready to eat salmon last night, that was absolutely fishy and dried out. Maybe because people don&apos;t buy it enough to replenish it and it just sits there? Their ready to eat chicken is great.. love the whole chickens and breasts. My daughter likes their garlic sesame wings.. spicy. I treated my pups to some of their ribs last night and they had no complaints! :)

So basically a few things need tweaking and a bit more monitoring. Luckily they have amazing customer service and a fantastic return policy!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (9) Funny (5) Cool (10) 
 
1 Previous Review: Show all» 

 8/19/2010 
Just had my first shopping experience at The Fresh Market, earlier this evening. I think it will be… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Daniel B. 
 
 314 friends 459 reviews 

 Daniel B. 
 
Albany, NY
 10/2/2010 4 Check-ins Here 
I&apos;m now here about once a week.  The Fresh Market has made it into a regular rotation, even though it&apos;s out of the way.

It&apos;s not Whole Foods. It&apos;s certainly not Trader Joe&apos;s. It&apos;s not Wegman&apos;s.

I think it&apos;s best to approach this store on its own terms.  A lot of items are pricier than similar items one might find elsewhere.  Sometimes this is because they are overpriced.  But other times it is because The Fresh Market products are actually better.

- Roast chickens that weren&apos;t fed antibiotics (when they were alive).
- Prepackaged sliced cheese made without the use of rBST.
- Grade B maple syrup (which is surprisingly hard to find here).

They have tasty challah at the bakery (although they do come frozen for kosher reasons). The bakery even torches creme brulee to order.  Get the pre-stuffed cannoli at your peril.

Not everything is great, and the service especially at the bakery counter and the deli counter can be slow.  The cheese selection is a major personal disappointment.  But this is by far the nicest place to get groceries in the Capital Region.

And if you have kids, they can get a card for the cookie club. Every time we are there, the children get a free cookie from the bakery.  When it&apos;s time to get more milk, can you guess where the little one&apos;s want to go?
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (8) Funny (2) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Lai-Yee B. 
 
 98 friends 497 reviews 

 Lai-Yee B. 
 
Albany, NY
 4/27/2011 5 Check-ins Here 
I like Fresh Market in a novelty kind of way - the way I like Trader Joe&apos;s. James L pretty much nailed the description on the head.

There are lots of snacky items that I avoid, plus I&apos;m wary about their &quot;all natural&quot; titling of the butcher&apos;s section since they serve Smithfield pork products (totally NOT something I want to eat) but the impression is that it&apos;s meat of a higher quality.

But like any store, sift through all of the overpriced bunk, and you&apos;ll find a few gems. They usually have some kind of fresh veggies and fruit on sale, most of which are conventionally or organically raised. I also like their store brand yogurt. Pretty thick and creamy, even the low-fat stuff.

So if you just want to wander in, your best bets are fruits and veggies on sale. Otherwise, eh, it&apos;s a lot of the same stuff you can get in other supermarkets, but at higher prices.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Amanda M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 261 friends 311 reviews 

 Amanda M. 
 
Tannersville, NY
 8/8/2011 4 photos 1 Check-in Here 
I had fun looking at all the unique items. Make your own fresh peanut butter, candy bags, nuts, coffee blends, dried fruit. A lot of store-made granola. All the counters were open at 8p.m. which I thought was great. A great place to find organic items. However the prices are slightly higher than Price Chopper or Hannaford, but so worth it.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (5) Funny   Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Josie L. 
 
 1 friend 20 reviews 

 Josie L. 
 
Ballston Spa, NY
 10/19/2011 
I moved from a major Metropolitan area and I miss my Whole Foods and Trader Joe&apos;s. I notice that the Fresh Market almost stole the lettering font and color from Whole Food and the basic premious of the store...setup etc.

When things go on sale they are in the Whole Foods range.

Let me say that I do shop here for some things but other things are overpriced even for Whole Foods standards. I was very disappointed that there meats are so OVERPRICED. They aren&apos;t even antibiotic and hormone free minus the chicken which I do buy. I called to ask them questions about their meat and clearly they have NO CLUE what they sell.

They can improve I hope because I really want to love it there. THey have some really unique fun things there such as their bulk,coffee and candy section. But they have a way to go.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from stacie n. 
 
 2 friends 34 reviews 

 stacie n. 
 
New York, NY
 Updated - 11/23/2011 
Pre-ordered our Thanksgiving meal on Sunday.  Called early today to confirm our order.  My husband just went to pick it up, and they are &quot;out&quot; of gravy......How the hell does that happen?  And for such an essential part of a holiday meal?  Apparently we have a different interpretation of the word &quot;order&quot; than the Fresh Market does. For us, &quot;order&quot; means, &quot;set aside for our exclusive purchase,&quot; not, &quot;hey dude, if we happen to have it around, you can like, totally buy it.&quot; Not acceptable.  Mind blown.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (2) Cool   
 
2 Previous Reviews: Show all» 

 8/24/2011 
Downgrading.  I&apos;ve decided to take a Yelp hiatus for the remainder of our time in the Capital… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Megan E. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 48 friends 213 reviews 

 Megan E. 
 
Troy, NY
 10/3/2010 
I absolutely love this place. I literally just returned from my first ever trip there and I am just so excited to have to go back for something. I was overwhelmed with the quality of the fresh produce, and the amount of nuts, and mixed snacks that they had. I also appreciated that the beer selection has a make your own six pack section. It had everything that I needed and everything was easy to find which is so rare when I need to go shopping. While it is not really on the way to anything I&apos;ll defiantly come here more often than not. Especially when I need fresh produce and or want to try some new beers or snacks. There was also a large section of coffee beans that you could grind there and some coffees that you could sample. It was delicious coffee and the next time I need to fill up my coffee stash this will be the first place I go.

I thought that everything was reasonably price which may just mean because I thought I was going to be overwhelmed with expensive food when I went in here and I could still afford my cart. This is definitely what this area needed, living in troy the price chopper is pathetic, Hanaford is alright and I&apos;m not driving all the way to walmart so thats out. This is just what my life needed.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ian W. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 360 friends 2586 reviews 

 Ian W. 
 
Pelham, NH
 8/18/2010 
The Fresh Market in Latham is now open! ! My folks and I went to check out the Grand Opening. The place was mobbed due to the newness and being the first store in NYS. I&apos;ve also shopped at The Fresh Market at Hingham Shipyard, south of Boston, which is a very nice store.

The parking lot was full, so we had to park across the street. This market looks very nice. It&apos;s organized, bright and clean, not as big (sizewise) as the standard suburban supermarket chain (Hannaford&amp;Price Chopper), but similar size as a typical Trader Joe&apos;s (which has good prices) and similar concept to the slightly larger Whole Foods Market.

There are several departments/sections including good selection of fresh produce, freshly prepared foods (sandwiches, entrees, sushi), gourmet salads, meats, deli, cheeses, dairy, seafood, bakery, coffee, snacks, nuts, organic&amp;healthy groceries, flowers, frozen foods, and more. The products sold here tend to be on the pricey side. However, the bakery rocks! I picked up some Almond Croissants and Chocolate Croissants for only $1.29 each and muffins for only 60 cents (regular price $1.09), a great bargain compared to Au Bon Pain where I normally get my sweet treats at double the price. I tried out some free food samples throughout the store including some cheese and BBQ spare ribs cooked on the grill outside, which were dry rubbed, chewy, and salty tasting.

We will definitely be back to The Fresh Market in Latham since this is a fresh healthy alternative to the other markets in the area, which sell everything else including the inexpensive processed foods. I can also grab a tasty lunch too!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Boris S. 
 
 1 friend 39 reviews 

 Boris S. 
 
Minden, NV
 10/23/2011 
I came here to get some food to eat during my stay in Albany. The prices are a tad high but the quality, presentation, and orderliness make up for it. They have a wide selection of cheeses, gourmet candies, and good and fresh tasting fruit. Their supplement section is thin but their soap bar selection could make up for it. They don&apos;t sell small single serving sized cartons of milk but they have a very appetizing bakery. The staff is quick to take you through check out and they are also very polite. It&apos;s a step up from Trader Joes and probably on par with Whole Foods.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Danika A. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 59 friends 161 reviews 

 Danika A. 
 
Albany, NY
 8/20/2010 
YAAAAYYY!! I&apos;d leave the review at that, but I should probably get into more detail. I&apos;ve been whining about the lack of these types of markets in the upstate New York area. Finally, the day has come!

I should mention that I&apos;m a fairly average shopper. I frequent Hannaford, Price Chopper, BJ&apos;s, and once in a blue moon Walmart. My goal, like most people, is to find healthy food at a reasonable price. I also don&apos;t want to have to spend a lot of time doing so, which is why I enjoy Hannaford&apos;s organic section so much. The Fresh Market is Hannaford&apos;s organic section blown out and all grown up. It is a time saver for me, and a very pleasant experience.

I stopped in just before closing, so I can&apos;t comment on the parking situation. Seemed fine to me! Of course it was packed on opening day, what else would you expect? If you&apos;re really concerned about being 2 feet from the door, don&apos;t come on Saturdays or Sundays.

I love the layout of the store. The TFM website describes it as &quot;the atmosphere of an old world European market,&quot; and I would agree. I was most impressed by their produce selection. Okay, so maybe we&apos;re not talking BJ&apos;s prices on peaches, but the fact that I didn&apos;t have to spend 5 minutes digging through to find one edible looking fruit was very valuable to me.

I found it interesting that they offer a few common brands along side their natural/organic offerings. For example, there was all natural mayonnaise alongside Hellmann&apos;s. I think they&apos;re either doing that to test out what we prefer as a whole, or because they want to give their customers a comfortable amount of variety.

I had to run past the bakery as quick as I could, because everything looked too delicious.

I agree with another reviewer: they should really expand their selection of household items. I&apos;m sure with time they will.

This place will definitely be a permanent part of my grocery shopping mix.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Sandy C. 
 
 0 friends 17 reviews 

 Sandy C. 
 
Saratoga Springs, NY
 1/26/2012 
Looks and smells nice when you walk in, pretty classical music playing makes this seem like it&apos;s above and beyond other area supermarkets. Sorry, but 90% of the gourmet and natural brands they carry can be found in the standard area supermarkets for half the price. If you think this is the only place to buy organic stuff, please open your eyes next time you&apos;re in PC, Hannaford or even Walmart. Ocean State Joblot in Ballston Spa (not at all the same as Big Lots) is a fantastic place to buy gourmet and imported dry goods for next to nothing. I ended up buying a couple produce items and some spices just because I had made the effort to shop there. The sunflower seeds I bought in the bulk section were stale. My curiosity is satisfied and I will NOT be back. I can&apos;t believe this business model even works!  I&apos;m waiting patiently for TJ&apos;s to open in Albany.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nick P. 
 
 216 friends 252 reviews 

 Nick P. 
 
Saratoga Springs, NY
 8/18/2010 
Fresh market is quite a bit smaller than what PC or the &apos;ford. I suppose it&apos;s not too much bigger than Honest Weight. Lets call it market sans the super size. I don&apos;t think Honest Weight will be hurt by Fresh because the market for this kind of thing has  existed for a long time and Honest Weight just does not serve a very wide audience.

I work in Latham, and I understand how people might not want to go there. That&apos;s about to get worse as this market is on a bottleneck of route 9 Fresh is going to be really popular.

It&apos;s comfortable to negotiate. However, since there were crazy crowds of people dying to shop in a grocery store that is well laid out with organic and healthy foods that more spendy than regular foods.... the line was about 20 minutes. It was the first day and the clerk was still figuring things out. But the thing is, I&apos;m an American and screw lines!

Anyway, it&apos;s cool (see Ian and Amy who beat me to this).
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Amy W. 
 
 15 friends 30 reviews 

 Amy W. 
 
Maspeth, NY
 8/18/2010 
This place is awesome for the Capital District Area! It&apos;s a hybrid of Whole Foods and Trader Joe&apos;s! I&apos;d have to say that the parking lot is going to be way too small for the businesses that are going to be in there. Walgreens is expected to be in the empty parcel of land in the middle of the parking lot.

I hope the prices stay the same, otherwise the produce and prices were better the PC and Hanniford&apos;s.

I bought the baby back ribs today, delicious. Yet, it was a bit heavy handed with the salt. The crab cakes were yummy too!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ashleigh H. 
 
 6 friends 21 reviews 

 Ashleigh H. 
 
Albany, NY
 8/25/2010 
This was my little entry I sent to All Over Albany; it was just easier to copy and paste!

I come from the land of the all famous Wegmans. I&apos;m not ashamed to admit that my boyfriend and I used to go wander when we were bored. In our minds, and our experiences, NOTHING will compare to Wegmans. Since recently relocating here we&apos;ve been on a quest to find &quot;our&quot; grocery store. We decided to take the little drive up to Latham last night and check out the Fresh Market. We came to the consensus that it&apos;s our new grocery store.

While the lines were a little long and it was a little crowded (it was also after work/dinner hour) we didn&apos;t mind the amount of shoppers. The produce selection is great. The dairy selection was not too bad. (We took notice that their store brand milk is hormone free.)

The flowers were a welcoming sight as you walk in as well. They have a pretty decent selection of bulk stuff (tons of whole bean coffee with a pot made for your to try nearby). Their prepared foods section is pretty impressive along with their breads.

While their &quot;normal&quot; shelf food can be a little pricey, they do offer selections that you can only find elsewhere at the co-op but Fresh Market has it cheaper for the most part.

One of the neat things we found was their &quot;build a 6-pack&quot; in their beer cooler section. They have a wide variety of micro-brews that you can mix and match for only $8.49/6pk.

Of course for cheese and most bulk items we&apos;ll still visit the co-op and for some shelf food stuff we&apos;ll hit up Hannafords. (We&apos;re anti-Price Chopper as they are the reason there isn&apos;t a Wegmans here!) But for the majority of our shopping, especially produce, the Fresh Market is our now go-to place.

I think everyone should check it out! (But beware the bulk candy section near the registers... it can be pretty tempting while waiting in line for check out!)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from joey L. 
 
 0 friends 9 reviews 

 joey L. 
 
Albany, NY
 1/24/2012 
Place is a joke.  Overpriced trendy foods.  Rotisserie chicken same as Hannaford costs twice as much.  Produce?  What produce?? Aisles too small, but trendy shoppers like that.  Better off going to Wallmart&apos;s organic food dept.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michelle B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 50 friends 178 reviews 

 Michelle B. 
 
Albany, NY
 9/14/2010 5 Check-ins Here 
The Fresh Market is definitely a gem in this area.  Yes, I said &quot;gem&quot;.  I was eager to try it but waited a few weeks after it opened and went on a Monday evening.  It was still busy, but nowhere near packed, and we had to wait in line for... oh, roughly 3 minutes.

I was disappointed by it&apos;s small size, but I am still impressed overall.  So, two stars for uniqueness, three stars for superb quality, minus one star for TFM&apos;s petite size and limited selection -- in some areas, anyway.

The produce section was pretty extensive and everything was very fresh; far superior to any grocery stores I&apos;ve been to in this area.  If you enjoy sorting through bruised, overripe fruits and veggies, examining them extensively to pick out the best of the worst, TFM is not the place for you.

The butcher and deli also had a lot of unique and hard to find items.  And the bakery -- oooh, the bakery.  I had to rush past it quickly and try not to splash any drool on the display case.  Everything looked amazing.  I may need to come up with an excuse to throw a party so I can buy some of that sweet, beautiful goodness.

As a few other reviews mentioned, I was disappointed by the small size of the household section.  They carried only a few eco-friendly cleaning products (Method), so I guess I&apos;ll have to keep going to Target for their broad selection.  On the other hand, TFM is a true grocery store, so what can I expect?

I want to note that TFM definitely focuses on *fresh* -- the produce, meats, cheeses and baked goods are the stars of the show.  I don&apos;t think they have a single freezer in the building.  And although all the basics are minimally covered, I wasn&apos;t impressed with their selection of dry goods such as pastas, cereal, etc.

I also wonder if they might extend their hours eventually.  I&apos;ll admit I&apos;ve been spoiled by 24-hr grocery stores, but it&apos;d be so enjoyable to take my time perusing these absurdly narrow isles during off hours so that I wouldn&apos;t constantly have to move out of people&apos;s way.  Seriously, the aisles aren&apos;t wide enough for two carts to pass each other.  TFM&apos;s floor plan designers and shopping cart purchasers need to work on their communication.

In conclusion, I can&apos;t wait to go back !
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Terry T. 
 
 8 friends 9 reviews 

 Terry T. 
 
Troy, NY
 4/25/2011 
I love this place!  The produce section is awesome.  Everything is fresh and healthy.  They&apos;re baked goods are delicious and usually very fresh.  The cheese and dairy could use a little help (not much more than the supermarket.)  I&apos;m absolutely amazed at their pick 6 beer selection!  If you&apos;re a big fan of spices try the bagged selections.  Half the price of bottled and very flavorful. The only reason I would give it a 5 is the spastic pricing. Some items are cheaper than any upscale alternative food store.  Some are nearly double the price you find in the supermarket down the street!  All in all a necessary stop in my grocery shopping.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jonathan R. 
 
 16 friends 19 reviews 

 Jonathan R. 
 
Troy, NY
 10/14/2010 1 Check-in Here 
NYC/west coast fresh food marketplace in Latham!

and Yes if you go their expect to spend at least $50 and then expect to walk out with a bag and a half of groceries, but wow are dems groceries tastey and not filled with preservatives, chemicals, transfat, high furctose corn syrup and other fun corporate crack cocaine!

All kidding aside, The New York Strip was excellent, the Rotisserie chickens are probably the best value out of what I have come away with so far, produce section is great the fruits and vegetables actually taste like fruits and vegetables vs plastic, and lots of good nuts and candy! check it out it&apos;s at least worth a walkabout.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mike L. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 18 friends 249 reviews 

 Mike L. 
 
Cohoes, NY
 11/12/2011 1 photo 4 Check-ins Here 
When this place first opened I hated it. It was overcrowded, overpriced, and didn&apos;t carry everything I was looking for. But after the initial shock of a new market wore off I decided to give them another shot, and I&apos;m glad I did. One thing to keep in mind is this is more of a specialty store than a full on supermarket. They don&apos;t have the wide selection of products that Hannaford or Price Chopper has but what they do have are harder to find products. They have great fresh produce, fresh meats that are not prepackaged, a large selection of nuts, seeds, and granola. There are also a variety of prepared foods by the deli. I especially liked the raw stuffed chicken breasts. You just take them home and throw them in the oven and its like you went out to a restaurant for a fraction of the price and no effort on your part. The cupcakes are also fluffy and delicious. Cheesecake on the other hand was sub-par and rubbery.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jacqueline W. 
 
 2 friends 3 reviews 

 Jacqueline W. 
 
Schenectady, NY
 6/23/2011 
I do love shopping at this place.  The seafood and meat selection is wonderful and always fresh.  I can&apos;t say enough about the bakery and cheese selection as well.  Admittedly it&apos;s a little pricey but you pay for what you get.  Good shopping to all!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Chris P. 
 
 3 friends 33 reviews 

 Chris P. 
 
Albany, NY
 11/28/2010 1 photo 
My destination market for specialty items.  Great atmosphere, so many new foods to discover, fresh produce, fresh everything.  Can score some great fresh deals with the posted &quot;Manager Specials&quot;   Pretty pricey - but worth it.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Shauen P. 
 
 11 friends 95 reviews 

 Shauen P. 
 
Minneapolis, MN
 11/28/2010 2 Check-ins Here 
Their setup is like a smaller version of Whole Foods and the service is just as friendly.  We have discovered that the green peppers are not so fresh and will continue to get our produce from Honest Weight Co-op but it has surpassed Cardona&apos;s Meat Market due to the selection.  That said, their meat isn&apos;t nearly as delicious as Cardona&apos;s but the place has a lot of nondairy options, an olive bar, and a LOT of candy -a winning set of criteria for sure.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from James L. 
 
 132 friends 95 reviews 

 James L. 
 
Fremont, CA
 11/28/2010 
If whole foods got together with trader joes and had a baby bam they&apos;d name it Fresh market.  Love the sashimi grade tuna for 11 bucks a lb . Didn&apos;t see any two Buck chuck though
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Casey S. 
 
 2 friends 94 reviews 

 Casey S. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 9/1/2010 
5 staars because as it says, this is about as good as your going to get around here. Yes Cordonas is unbeatable but thats more itialian specialty, this is the closest thing we will probably ever see to a whole foods in this area. Down to the products, the crab dip is top notch, breads all nice and fresh, filet is actually good for supermarket standards. Cheese is a little pricey but well worth it if your a cheese head. Deserts are well priced and great. Fruits and flowers both very fresh. Somewhat of a suprise, the pre packaged sushi is actually pretty fresh. That&apos;s covers everything I have bought from here so far, will update Im sure.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 1 to 40 of 44 ( 8 Filtered )

 |   
 Page: 1 2 
 Write a Review View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
Deals Nearby
 
 $5 for $10 Deal The Daily Grind Troy, NY $15 for $30 Deal Tiny Tots Tea Room Clifton Park, NY 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 Honest Weight Food Co-op  43 reviews &quot;They have an amazing bulk section which is my favorite part...&quot; Green Grocer  5 reviews 
Clifton Park, NY
 Latham Meat Market  1 review 
Latham, NY
 Hannaford Supermarkets  6 reviews &quot;...prices here are generally cheaper here than other stores in...&quot; ShopRite  11 reviews 
Niskayuna, NY
 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 Groceries: Searching for Mr. Hooper 
Grocery alternatives in and about a reasonable radius of Niskayuna.
 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Latham Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
