<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003136" url="http://www.internationalpointofsale.com/cash_registers.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:16" support="8" score="0.012027826395105534" bingtitle="Cash Registers - POS Software and Hardware, Retail and Restaurant ..." webtitle="Cash Registers | International Point of Sale">
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001215" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>... assist people in their daily lives to keep ... Whether you have a small business, fast food restaurant or ... POS Software | Receipt Printer | Barcode ...</description>
	<body>
		My Account 
 
 Cart Check 
 Out 
 
 
 
 
 


 Live 
 Chat 


 
 
 
 
 
 
   Check out the full article 
 library 
 
 
   
 5.31.2006 
     
 
 POS Solution for 
 Restaurants 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   
 7.07.2005 
     
 
 Home Decor Store computerizes 
 with CRE 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   
 12.23.2004 
     
 
 Liquor Store Point of Sale 
 Solution 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   
 3.20.2005 
     
 
 The Best Convenience Store 
 POS 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   
 04.01.2004 
     
 
 Labels, Ribbons, and 
 Printheads 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   
 02.13.2004 
     
 
 Barcode Scanners 
 101 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   
 10.15.2004 
     
 
 Choosing a portable Point of 
 Sale System 
 Read more 
 articles ..... 
 
 
   10.07.2004     
 
 How much should you spend on 
 a POS system? Read 
 more articles ..... 1 
 
   
 
 International Point of Sale brings you the best in POS hardware and software, all at 
 an affordable price. Any type of retail store can 
 benefit from our wide selection of products designed to 
 make your business more profitable. We have dedicated 
 service professionals available day and night to take 
 care of your business needs.&quot; 
   
     
 
 
 
 
   
 Cash Registers 
 
 Since the 1940s, Casio&apos;s creed has always 
 been &quot;creativity and contribution.&quot; Their commitment is to 
 create original and functional products that 
 assist people in their daily lives to keep society moving 
 forward.

Casio has been giving years of 
 reliable service with ideal solutions for running your 
 own business. Whether you have a small business, fast 
 food restaurant or a fine dining establishment, the POS 
 solutions and extensive line of cash registers by Casio 
 will fit your needs and allow you to 
 succeed.


 If you are looking for a model, 
 and do not see it,
please give us a 
 call at 1(866)468-5767
 
 
 
 CE-6000
Cash Register 

The CE-6000 cash register is versatile, convenient, and upgradable.




 
 PCR-260B
Cash Register 

The PCR-260B electronic cash register will let your business run more efficiently.
 




 
 PCR-262
Cash Register 

The PCR-262 is a Personal Cash Register. 
 It has great business efficiency for small businesses.




 
 PCR-275
Cash Register 

The PCR-275 is a Personal Cash Register 
 that features ten Deparments and eight clerk totalizers.




 
 PCR-360
Cash Register 

The 
 PCR-360 electronic cash register has 40 Departments, 400 PLUs, and 10 clerk totalizers.




 
 PCR-T2000
Cash Register 

The PCR-T2000 can run your business more effectively with the new electronic cash registers.
 



 
 PCR-T265
Cash Register 

 Item has been Discontinued. 




 
 PCR-T275
Cash Register 

The PCR-T275 personal cash registers that can track 15 departments.




 
 PCR-T465
Cash Register 

The PCR-T465 is a performance register that features a thermal printer.




 
 TE-2200
Cash Register 

The Casio TE-2200 is a 
 register with a multi-line display. It is a 
 replacement for the
CE-6000 and a step up from the TE-2000.




 
 TE-2400
Cash Register 

The 
 Casio TE-2400 great for hospitality 
 environments. It is a replacement for the
TK-6500.




 
 TE-3000
Cash Register 

The TE-3000 offers a 5.2 inch tiltable color LCD screen&amp;30 department keys - more keys than most available registers.




 
 TE-4500
Cash Register 

The Casio TE-4500 comes with a multi line color tiltable LCD diplay that makes viewing easy from most angles.




 
 TE-7000S
Cash Register 

The TE-7000S includes a large multi-line color LCD, multi-purpose keys, and compact flash card interface.




 
 TE-8500F
Cash Register 

The Casio TE-8500F is 
 designed for hospitality. Includes features like floating guest check&amp;spilt check operation.
 
 TK-6500
Cash Register 

The TK-6500 offers outstanding quality and functionality with easy upgrading &amp;flat keyboard.
 
 
 
 Contact Us for the Best Deals Anywhere: 
 1-866-468-5767 
   
 
 Home | Articles | POS Software | POS Hardware | Complete Systems | About Us | Download 
 
 
 POS Software | Receipt Printer | Barcode 
Scanner | Pole Display | Inventory Management 
 Credit Card Swiper | Cash 
Drawer | Label Printing | Portable Terminal 
 Site Map 2 3 full 
 sales@internationalpointofsale.com 

 2008 International Point of Sale 1-866-468-5767 or 
201-928-0222
	</body>
</document>
