<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003365" url="http://southerncaliforniadiningservicesfun.com/?paged=4" time="2012-07-12-19:30" support="11" score="0.025926732075793456" bingtitle="Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Services Reviews ..." webtitle="Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Lifestyle Reviews - Reviews for Movies, Restaurants, Entertainment and Lifestyle In SoCal">
			<query id="000553" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001496" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000242" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000116" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001181" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000899" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000616" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>I waited 30 minutes for my order. For a fast food restaurant, 30 minutes ... you go see this movie you need to have your cup ... half chow mein and half rice, they only give ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement
 
 Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Lifestyle Reviews 
 Reviews for Movies, Restaurants, Entertainment and Lifestyle In SoCal RSS 
Register to Subscribe to this blog and receive notification by email for new posts.
 
 Username 

 Password 

 Remember Me 

 
 
 Register Recover password 
 
Bookmark
 
Meta

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
Blogroll

 A) Movie Reviews etc. B) Southern California Gardening c) LA Grub Street D) Street Gourmet LA E) WordPress Blog 
 RSS Aug 02 
 Americana at Brand 
 by Napoleon on  August 2nd, 2011 at  5:16 pm Posted In: Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine , Fun&amp;Entertainment , Shopping 
Americana at Brand is an outdoor shopping mall located at the downtown area of Glendale, California. Glendale is a city located on the foothills of the Verdugo mountains,  north of downtown Los Angeles. It is an outdoor shopping mall that resembles a city center with shops, parks and apartment dwellings.

 

 

Address: 889 Brand Blvd., Glendale, CA 91210

 

The mall has 75 retail shops including Barnes&amp;Noble, Apple Store, Sephora, Tiffany and other high-end shops. It also has a variety of dining options from ice cream stands on the sidewalk to Cheesecake Factory.

 

 

 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

The Americana at Brand includes hundreds of  condominiums and apartments on top of the shops. They are called The Residences and Excelsior.

 

At the center of the mall is a park with an animated fountain. The musical fountain performs every hour. At the center of the water fountain is a gold-leaf statue. The statue is a replica of“Spirit of American Youth”by Donald de Lue in France.

 

 

 

 
 

 

The mall also houses Pacific Theaters with so many screens; you need to spend a day at the mall to see all the movies.

 

While the mall is crowded with shoppers, shops and restaurants outside the mall are almost empty. Before the mall is constructed it stirred debate in Glendale for several years with business owners fearing Americana would hurt businesses for stores along Brand Boulevard.

Like most newer shopping malls, Americana at Brand is a destination. You need to plan ahead and spend at least a day at this mall and the neighboring Glendale Galleria. Parking is abundant at both malls. It is easy to find a spot to park your car.
 └Tags: Americana at Brand , Glendale California , Glendale Galleria , outdoor shopping mall , shopping mall 
 26 Comments Jul 31 
 In-N-Out Burgers 
 by Napoleon on  July 31st, 2011 at  8:47 pm Posted In: Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine 
In-N-Out Burgers is a chain of hamburger restaurant that originated in Baldwin Park, a suburb in Los Angeles county. It is a Southern California hamburger icon and institution.. In-N-Out restaurants are located throughout the western United States (Arizona, Nevada, Utah and Texas) but most are  primarily located in Southern California.

 

Their key to success is keeping it simple. Their concept is very simple, only 3 varieties of burgers: hamburger, cheeseburger and double-double which has double meat patty and double cheese. Fries and fountain drinks are available including 3 flavors of milkshakes: vanilla, strawberry and chocolate. That’s their menu.

 

 

The hamburgers come with slice of tomato, lettuce and sauce. Onions are optional, the customer is asked upon ordering and it can be raw onion or grilled. The burgers and milkshakes are great but the fries are no match to McDonalds. The burger patty is very flavorful and moist while the milkshakes are very thick.The lettuce and onion are crispy and look very fresh.

 

 

 

 While the menu is very simple, there are several ways of ordering your burger. It is not on their menu and they call it the“secret menu”.  The secret menu is as follows:

1) 2 x 4 which has 2 beef patties and four slices of cheese.  You can also order 3 x 3 which has 3 meat patties and 3 cheese slices, 4 x 2 which has 4 meat patties and 2 slices of cheese.

2) 2 x meat (or double meat), which has 2 meat patties and no cheese.

3) Animal style in which the meat patty is mustard-cooked with pickles, cheese, sauce, and grilled onions. All are diced up and grilled  and placed in between the bread.

4) Flying Dutchman which is composed of 2 meat patties and 2 slices of cheese and nothing else.

5) Grilled Cheese which is grilled cheese without the meat patty but still has the tomato, lettuce and onions.

6) Neopolitan Shake which is a combination of the 3 milkshakes, vanilla, strawberry and chocolate.

These are some of the“secret-menu”and are not listed on their menu.

In-N-Out is a privately held, family owned chain of restaurants. The family that owns it has a lot of history. One of the sons of the founder died in a plane crash and the other son died from an overdose of painkillers. There were also legal issues regarding corporate leadership.

Other than their fries, In-N-Out is number one burger chain to me.

 

 
 └Tags: buger chain , hamburger , in-n-out , restaurant 
 15 Comments Jul 25 
 Captain America: The First Avenger 
 by Napoleon on  July 25th, 2011 at  1:07 am Posted In: Movies 
Captain America: The First Avenger is a sci-fi comics movie starring Chris Evans as GI Joe Steve Rogers,  Tommy Lee Jones as army Colonel Philips and Stanley Tucci as Dr. Abraham Erskine a German defector.

The movie is about pumping up a 90-lb human in a lab into a muscled, steroid taking look hunk. Rogers, a 90 lb weakling and the son of decorated war heroes is desperate to do his part during World War II.  Unfortunately he is sickly and classified 4-F or unfit for duty. But what he lacks physically, he makes up with his persistence to serve and this brings him to the attention of a German defector scientist Dr. Abraham Erskine.  Dr Erskine is looking for a guinea pig to test his molecular-growth serum. Rogers volunteered to be the guinea pig and became a muscled, tall hunk–becoming the first in a new breed of super-soldier.

Transformed from a weakling and bullied lad from Brooklyn  into a tall  muscular hunk, he should be fit to fight in the front lines. Instead, Rogers with his Captain America image is assigned  the home-front in a make-believe tour to convince Americans to buy war bonds.  When the tour was taken overseas to entertain the troops, he was booed by the troops.

The real deal came when he is needed in a rescue mission deep behind enemy lines. In Europe, Johann Schmidt is leading a Nazi insurgency by collecting supernatural items to use them to fuel Hydra, a science division of Fuhrer. The supernatural items transformed this mad scientist into Red Skull literally.

Captain America and Red Skull eventually met and fought. The fighting scenes are so phony and not believable, but then this is a“comics movie”. There was no suspense in this movie. We know that Captain America is always going to get out of any trouble no matter what. Unlike other super heroes, Captain America has no vulnerability.

One good thing about Captain America: The First Avenger is its retro-futurist designs. But there’s nothing memorable on the performances. I had a few yawns throughout the movie but not as bad as the yawns I had in Brad Pitt’s Tree of Life .

If you like super hero movies. you may like it but this is not for me.
 └Tags: captain america , chris evans , comics , movies , stanley tucci , tommy lee jones 
 15 Comments Jul 19 
 Citadel Outlets 
 by Napoleon on  July 19th, 2011 at  6:41 pm Posted In: Shopping 
Citadel Outlet Stores is the only Outlet Shops located in Los Angeles area.

Address: 100 Citadel Drive, Los Angeles, CA  90040

 

 

You will find Citadel Outlet Mall sitting very visibly at interstate 5 in the City of Commerce. It is an impressive sight along the freeway. It is a few miles south of downtown Los Angeles.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

The exterior of the mall was built to look like the Babylonian palace of King Sargon II. The unusual Babylonian and Assyrian architecture was dreamed up by the previous owner; a tire manufacturing company. The complex was built in 1929.

 

 

 

 

 

 

While the architectural design of the facade and exterior is eye-catching,  the shopping area itself is very new and modern with hundreds of name brand shops offering discounted items.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

Shops include women’s apparel and accessories, men’s apparel and accessories, leather, housewares and furnishings, children’s apparel and toys, footwear, jewelry, beauty and health. For dining, most of the selections are typical mall fast food restaurants; Panda Express, Sbarro, Hotdog On A Stick, Starbucks, Subway and Ruby’s.

 

 

 

 

 

 

The Citadel Outlet Mall is one of the biggest in Southern California. If you plan to shop at Citadel, plan ahead and spend a day at the mall. Parking is abundant, rest rooms are super clean. Overall it is a very nice shopping mall for discount items. You will not be disappointed.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
 └Tags: citadel outlet stores , outlet stores , shopping 
 58 Comments Jul 14 
 Bad Teacher 
 by Napoleon on  July 14th, 2011 at  6:27 pm Posted In: Movies 
This is a raunchy, filthy and funny comedy starring Cameron Diaz as an acid-tongued middle school teacher and Justin Timberlake. She stars as Elizabeth, a middle school teacher trying to marry somebody rich. She is about boobs and a man. She decides that landing a rich husband is her only route to happiness and the only way to achieve this is with a breast enlargement. The main driving force of the plot is her quest to raise funds for a larger breast.

The movie starts as Elizabeth is finishing a school term of what she taught would be her last school term as a teacher; she is marrying a rich guy. The wedding didn’t go through; the fiance got wise to her gold digging motives. She went back to teaching where she met Scott (Justin Timberlake). She taught all she needed to marry a rich guy like Scott  is to have a boob job. The operation costs $10,000 and getting the money  became an obsession. She tried to raise money for the procedure like soaping up at the school’s fundraising car wash. The bulk of the movie revolves around her attempts to raise the money for the procedure.

Elizabeth and fellow teacher Lucy Amy became rivals for Scott’s attention which led to a lot of plotting and back-stabbing on both sides.

Elizabeth is not an underdog. She has a potty mouth and she is a bully. She has open contempt for her fellow teachers and her students.

The movie is funny because of the f-bombs that are coming from an unexpected source, in this case a teacher. It is funny but it will not make you roll on the aisles. This movie is classless and not worth the money. This is a not-very-good dark comedy. Although she is funny in There’s Something about Mary , Cameron Diaz is not that funny is this movie and I don’t think she is equipped to carry a movie like this. The movie has some good moments but they are too few and far between.

Overall, Bad Teacher is a bad movie. It is classless and it deserves a D. It has a very thin plot and also preposterous. It is a dark comedy but not as good as Bad Santa. 
 └Tags: cameron diaz , comedy , justin timberlake , movie 
 12 Comments Jul 07 
 Larry Crowne 
 by Napoleon on  July 7th, 2011 at  2:38 am Posted In: Movies 
Larry Crowne is an old-fashioned romantic comedy starring Julia Roberts and Tom Hanks. This is a movie about second chances. Tom Hanks stars as Larry Crowne, a laid off (fired, downsized, shown the door) employee from a big box store. The movie starts out with Larry Crowne  as a happy employee when he was called to meet with company management but left the meeting devastated when he was told he was let go. He loves his job; he won the employee of the month 9 times. But it didn’t matter that he was an employee of the month 9 times. He was terminated because he has no college degree. In his manager’s eyes, lack of college education spells“limited advancement potential”.Because of a divorce, he suffered financial set-back and loses his house.

When he is unable to find another job, he went back to school, a community college where Mercedes Tainot (Julia Roberts) teaches speech class. He got the idea of going back to school from his eccentric neighbor who won the lottery a few years back and now oversees a permanent yard sale. Larry signs up for the class called The Art of Casual Conversation taught by Mercedes Tainot. Mercedes is going through a break-up with her porn addicted“new media”husband. Just like in other romantic movies, Larry develops a crush on Mercedes.

This movie provides an escape from the harsh realities of the present economic situation. Losing your job, your house and when you cannot find a job similar to your last one, you may end up flipping burgers in order to make ends meet. But who would go and watch a depressing movie.

Besides the two main characters, the supporting cast also made the movie entertaining. The supporting cast is the classmates of Larry Crowne. Being a speech class, there are funny and delightful classroom speeches.

The movie is directed by Tom Hanks and co-written with Nia Vardalos who wrote and starred in My Big Fat Greek Wedding. 

This movie is one big happy movie but is not the best movie of Tom Hanks or Julia Roberts. It is a feel-good and predictable movie but it is worth watching.

 
 └Tags: julia roberts , nia vardalos , tom hanks 
 14 Comments Jul 04 
 Zankou Chicken 
 by Napoleon on  July 4th, 2011 at  11:43 pm Posted In: Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine 
Zankou Chicken is a family owned chain restaurant based in Southern California offering Middle Eastern food. They have several restaurants in the greater Los Angeles area; Glendale with 2 locations, Van Nuys, Anaheim, Pasadena, Burbank, West Los Angeles,  Toluca Lake and Montebello. This is a Zagat rated chain.

 

 

For this review I visited their Glendale location. From the decor you could tell they are a chain restaurant but still in its infancy. The decor is still not very corporate/commercial. Their furniture and decor are all mismatched. Ignoring the decor, their food is awesome. I ordered the whole chicken special which came with one rotisserie chicken with sides; a hunnus, pickled turnips, cabbage salad, pita bread and garlic sauce as a dip.

 

The chicken is very moist and flavorful. The skin is broiled to perfection and very crispy and the meat is very tender and moist. The chicken is comparable to the chicken I had at Juan Pollo but I like Zankou Chicken better as a whole because of their sides. The hummus and pickles turnips are perfect. The turnip is crispy and not very sour and the hummus is perfectly salty, sour and garlicky and not too tangy or tart. I can go without the cabbage salad and the garlic dip is overly sour.

Other items on their menu are shawerma plate (marinated and flame broiled beef), falafel plate, wraps (roasted chicken, shawerma, chicken tarna and falafel), kebab plates (shish kebab, chicken kebab, and lule kebab).  There are several salads, tabbouleh, tahini and garden salad. Hummus, mutabbal (grilled eggplant, tahini and olive oil) and basmati rice are the sides.

 

The service at the location I went for this review can be improved. I waited 30 minutes for my order. For a fast food restaurant, 30 minutes is a bit too long. I would understand if they are a sit-down restaurant. The staff are very friendly though.

The family that owns Zankou Chicken has a family tragic drama of epic proportions. In 2003, the owner shot and killed his sister, shot his mother and he then took his own life in a double-murder suicide. It is believed that the owner was in the late stages of colon and brain cancer which may have affected his mental faculties.
 └Tags: armenian food , dining , mediterranean food , rotisserrie chicken 
 20 Comments Jul 01 
 Tree of Life 
 by Napoleon on  July 1st, 2011 at  5:04 pm Posted In: Movies 
Tree Of Life stars Brad Pitt and Sean Penn, written and directed by Terrence Malick, a reclusive director who have directed only a few movies. Tree Of Life got the top price at this year’s Cannes Film Festival.

The movie starts with a quotation from the bible then Sean Penn in a glass office building. The next scenes are that of a light at the center of the screen then a flash of light. At first I don’t understand what this is until I figured this must be the creation of the universe when spurts of raging lava, clouds of natural gas, a dinosaur are the next scenes.  Before you go see this movie you need to have your cup of coffee. The guy sitting next to me was snoring half of the movie.

The movie is set in 1960′s Texas and it is about a husband and wife and their relationship with their 3 boys. Brad Pitt starred as the father and Sean Penn starred as the adult version of one of the boys. The father is a disciplinarian with erratic temper and has frustrations in business and converts this frustration into“tough-love”way of disciplining his boys. He tells the kids“It takes fierce will to go ahead in this world”and calls his wife naive. The mother on the other hand is a free spirit. The father leans hard on his oldest son Jack (older Jack is played by Sean Penn) and the drama started when one of the boys died. It was never explicitly told how he died. Jack grew-up empty of joy and blames his father for the long-ago death.

When Jack is growing up he has appetite for risk and transgression-BB guns, electricity. He has a rocky relationship with his father. The death of his brother shattered the family and brought to surface his resentments toward his father.

Malick has an unconventional way of telling a story in this movie. The movie is scant on story and there is practically no dialogue among the characters. It is very long, the story could have been told in half an hour. I don’t think a typical moviegoer would appreciate this movie. This is a movie for the artsy not for the general public.

 
 
 └Tags: brad pitt , movies , sean penn , tree of life movie 
 11 Comments Jul 01 
 The Green Lantern 
 by Napoleon on  July 1st, 2011 at  5:02 pm Posted In: Movies 
This is a sci-fi/action movie starring Ryan Reynolds as the lead character. It also stars Angela Bassett.This movie is about a cocky, irresponsible and womanizing pilot from Earth who must overcome his fears after he was chosen to become a member on an intergalactic peace keeping force called Green Lantern Corps.

Ryan Reynolds character is Hal Jordan, a cocky pilot from Earth. He is a risk pilot who is haunted by memories of his pilot father crashing and exploding when he was just a little boy. Being an orphan, he grew up with a girl whose father has an aviation company. The aviation company is looking to snag a government contract. The government approval team is headed by Senator Hammond who has a scientist son Hector. Hector became one of the villain in the movie.

Somewhere in the universe, an intergalactic peace keeping force called Green Lantern Corps is battling Parallax,: a growing threat which has harnessed the power of fear. Parallax uses fear to generate/obtain it’s force; Green Lantern Corps obtains it’s force from the absence of fear and doubt. One of the Green Lantern Corps, Abin Sur fought against the growing threat, got wounded and makes it to earth. Abin has a ring and the power of the ring must be transferred to an earth person who has no fear; the ring must choose this person who has no fear and chooses Hal Jordan.

The body of Abin was obtained by a government agency headed by Amanda Waller (Angela Bassett) and must be examined by Hector. Hector got infected during the examination by Parallax. he became disfigured and developed extraordinary telekinetic powers. Upon Hal’s  return to earth, he battled the disfigured Hector and Parallax who intends to gobble up earth people in order to become more powerful. To make the story short, Hal was successful and defeated Parallax and Hector; becomes a full pledge Green Lantern Corps and dated the leading lady, a daughter of the aviation company owner. The Green Lantern Corps has the green color as the motif while Parallax motif is yellow.

The film has great visual effects, has dazzling superhero, a beautiful leading lady. Green Lantern has imperfections but it is entertaining both for comic fans and non-comic fans.  It has lots of characters and subplots but and didn’t have enough time to dealt with these characters and subplots properly. Angela Bassett’s character is one of these characters. Maybe they will have enough time to deal with these subplots in the next installment which I am sure there will be.

Green Lantern is worth spending time and money.
 └Tags: angela bassett , green lantern movie , movies , ryan reynolds 
 14 Comments Jul 01 
 Astro Family Restaurant 
 by Napoleon on  July 1st, 2011 at  5:01 pm Posted In: Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine 
Astro Restaurant is a 24 hour,  family owned diner restaurant located in the Silverlake district of Los Angeles. This diner is good for late night and breakfast.  It is specially perfect for late night dining.

 

 

 

ADDRESS: 2300 Fletcher Drive, Los Angeles, CA  90039

FOOD: Astro is a typical American diner. For breakfast, they have extensive selections of omelette, other egg platters, waffles and pancakes. Food in their breakfast menu can be ordered anytime of the day.

For lunch and dinner, they have hamburgers, sandwiches and pasta. They also have special items in their menu for the health conscious.

For this review, I visited the restaurant at 2:00 AM on a Saturday night after going to the movies. I ordered the spaghetti with meat sauce which came with a cup of soup I had the spinach soup). The cup size of their soup is huge; it will be the equivalent of a bowl in other restaurants. My order of spaghetti is also sizable; it can feed at least 3 super models. The pasta is cooked aldente and it came with enough meat sauce. The sauce is savory and sweet. Much too sweet for a sauce. The sauce is not as savory as it should be. I added a lot of parmesan cheese to make it more appetizing. Overall, the food is average, not awesome but not bad either.

The food at Astro is typical American diner food. It is bland and you need a lot of salt, pepper and maybe even hot sauce.

For a diner, their price is a little bit on the high side.

The service is extraordinary. We were seated as soon immediately and the waiter is very attentive and nice. He got our orders perfectly and the food was delivered to out table in less than 20 minutes. The cashier is also very friendly.

 

 

The building design is gogie architecture. Gogie is a modern, futuristic architectural design for coffee shops bowling alleys which is popular in the 1950′s to 1960′s. Being a family diner with a gogie design, Astro has a very old and quaint vibe. The place is immaculately clean and their rest room as well. They also have outdoor seating.

Overall, Astro is okay for a diner. It is not awesome but not bad either.
 └Tags: coffee shop , diner , dining , restaurant 
 24 Comments 
 Page 4 of 7 «First « 2 3 4 5 6 » Last» 
 
Categories

 ADVERTISE WITH US Food, Dining&amp;Cuisine Fun&amp;Entertainment Home&amp;Garden Los Angeles County Movies Orange County Performing Arts Theater Riverside/San Bernardino County San Diego County Services Shopping Welcome to Southern California 
 
Recent Posts

 Zaky Mediterranean Grill Pantages Theatre Barleymash Taco Luv Ontario International Airport ArcLight Cinemas Armstrong Garden Centers Larkin’s King Taco Sicha Siam Thai Cuisine Mt. Fuji Garden Center Commerce Casino The Gumbo Pot Aria Restaurant El Morfi Grill, Parillada Argentina Off Vine India Sweets&amp;Spices Jiffy Lube Victoria Gardens Advertise With Us Geffen Playhouse Fleming’s Prime Steakhouse&amp;Winebar I Love Tufo&amp;BBQ LA Live Tropical Food Express Two Guys From Italy Restaurant Pierre Garden Restaurant El Pollo Loco Rancho Santa Ana Botanic Garden Rise of the Planet of the Apes Americana at Brand In-N-Out Burgers Captain America: The First Avenger Citadel Outlets Bad Teacher 
 
Kontera Ads
 
 Random Post 
 
Blogroll

 A) Movie Reviews etc. B) Southern California Gardening c) LA Grub Street D) Street Gourmet LA E) WordPress Blog 
 
Advertisement
 
 tidzzhirtz ALTERNATIVE UNISEX ATTIRE - tidzzhirtz clothing company introduces a variety of alternative attires for unisex semi-formal to sports wear to a line of trend setting one of a kind zhirtz and jacketz that will definitely give you an ace &quot;umph&quot; to your rugged sense. 
 
©2011-2012 Southern California Dining, Entertainment and Lifestyle Reviews | Powered by WordPress with Easel | Subscribe: RSS | Back to Top↑
	</body>
</document>
