<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003200" url="http://www.couponqueenoftexas.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:20" support="3" score="0.002623741128733265" bingtitle="couponqueenoftexas.com — Your Best Online Resource for Coupons ..." webtitle="couponqueenoftexas.com — Your Best Online Resource for Coupons and Freebies!">
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="205"/>
	<description>Fast Food/ Restaurant; Coupon Policies; Food/ Drinks; Expired Coupons; Sunday Coupon Preview ... $1.00 Off Snapple Tea or Juice Drink. $1.00 off Snapple Tea or Juice Drink …</description>
	<body>
		About 
 About Me 
 Contact 
 Contact Me 
 Advertise 
 Media Kit 
 Disclosure 
 Disclosure Policy Privacy Policy Giveaway Terms and Conditions 
 
 
 couponqueenoftexas.com 

Your Best Online Resource for Coupons and Freebies!
 
 Home Coupons 
 New Coupons Baby Beauty Bathroom Fast Food/ Restaurant Coupon Policies Food/ Drinks Expired Coupons Sunday Coupon Preview Coupon Database 
 Freebies 
 New Freebies Magazines Food Books DVD’s Movie Codes Gym Passes Ebooks Kindle Apps Trial Offers 
 Matchups 
 Store Matchups 
 HOT Deals 
 Hot Deals! 
 Giveaways 
 Giveaways Sweepstakes Giveaway Sites List 
 Blogger Resources 
 Blog Directory Blogger Sign Ups 
 
 
 Back To School $200 Cash Giveaway! 

$200 Cash Giveaway! Welcome to the $200 Cash Back to School Giveaway!! This Giveaway begins on 7/12 at 12:01am and ends on 8/2 at 11:59pm.… [Read More] 
 
 $350 Estee Lauder Shopping Spree Sweepstakes! 

Estee Lauder is having a $350 Shopping Spree Sweepstakes!! One GRAND PRIZE winner will receive a $350 shopping spree at EsteeLauder.com. Click Here to… [Read More] 
 
 FREE Diabetic Meter! 

Do you or someone you know have diabetes? If so, check out this hot deal going on right now! You can snag a FREE diabetic meter in the color of your… [Read More] 
 
 FREE Refresher Drinks at Starbucks! 7/13 

 On July 13th at 12pm to 3pm, Starbucks is offering everyone a FREE refresher drink!  I am a HUGE fan of Starbucks, so I was so excited when… [Read More] 
 
 FREE Travel Pillow at Sleep Number Stores! 

Right now, you can score a FREE travel pillow at Sleep number stores when you find your perfect sleep number setting!! You will need to &quot;Like&quot; Sleep… [Read More] 
 
 Walmart: $0.97 Right Guard Bar Soap! 

Woohoo!! Here is a hot deal on Right Guard soap! You can get this soap for under $1.00 at Walmart!!

Walmart Deal Week of 7/8-7/14

Buy: Right… [Read More] 
 
 $1.00 off One Digiorno Pizza Dipping Strips 

I love eating Digiorno pizzas, especially when I am wanting a quick meal! The pizza dipping strips are new and look so delicious!! Click on the link… [Read More] 
 
 My Adorable Athlete Sweepstakes! 

Teach your little athlete that big dreams start at an early age. Upload a photo of your loved one, possibly playing his or her favorite sport, and you… [Read More] 
 
 Back To School $200 Cash Giveaway! 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

$200 Cash Giveaway! Welcome to the $200 Cash Back to School Giveaway!! This Giveaway begins on 7/12 at 12:01am and ends on 8/2 at 11:59pm. One winner will receive $200 cash via paypal. This Giveaway is open WORLDWIDE to users 18 years of age or older. Please enter the Giveaway using the rafflecopter widget below. ;)
Prize: $200 CASH
a Rafflecopter giveaway


Disclaimer/Disclosure: This Giveaway is not sponsored or affiliated by Facebook, Rafflecopter, Coupon Queen of Texas or any… [Read More...] 
 
 $350 Estee Lauder Shopping Spree Sweepstakes! 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

Estee Lauder is having a $350 Shopping Spree Sweepstakes!! One GRAND PRIZE winner will receive a $350 shopping spree at EsteeLauder.com. Click Here to enter the Sweepstakes! You can see Estee Lauder&apos;s official rules here. Good Luck!!!! ;)  Disclosure… [Read More...] 
 
 FREE Diabetic Meter! 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

Do you or someone you know have diabetes? If so, check out this hot deal going on right now! You can snag a FREE diabetic meter in the color of your choice! You will also receive a FREE recipe book, FREE meal planner, and a FREE glucose tracker!! :)  … [Read More...] 
 
 FREE Refresher Drinks at Starbucks! 7/13 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

 On July 13th at 12pm to 3pm, Starbucks is offering everyone a FREE refresher drink!  I am a HUGE fan of Starbucks, so I was so excited when I came across this hot deal!!… [Read More...] 
 
 FREE Travel Pillow at Sleep Number Stores! 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

Right now, you can score a FREE travel pillow at Sleep number stores when you find your perfect sleep number setting!! You will need to &quot;Like&quot; Sleep Number on their facebook page to unlock the coupon download! ;)… [Read More...] 
 
 Walmart: $0.97 Right Guard Bar Soap! 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

Woohoo!! Here is a hot deal on Right Guard soap! You can get this soap for under $1.00 at Walmart!!

Walmart Deal Week of 7/8-7/14

Buy: Right Guard TD 5 Bar Soap – $1.97
Use: $1.00/1 Right Guard Bar Soap or Body Wash (Use Zip Code: 78410 OR 12345)
Total = Only $0.97!! ;) Thanks, I Heart The Mart!… [Read More...] 
 
 $1.00 off One Digiorno Pizza Dipping Strips 

 July 12, 2012 By Connie Leave a Comment 

I love eating Digiorno pizzas, especially when I am wanting a quick meal! The pizza dipping strips are new and look so delicious!! Click on the link below to print your coupon. ;)

$1.00 off One Digiorno Pizza Dipping Strips… [Read More...] 
 « Older Posts 
Stay Connected
 
 
Enter your email address:

 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
Sponsors
 
 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 
Hot Printable Coupons
 
 couponqueenoftexas.com 

 Back To School $200 Cash Giveaway! $350 Estee Lauder Shopping Spree Sweepstakes! FREE Diabetic Meter! FREE Refresher Drinks at Starbucks! 7/13 FREE Travel Pillow at Sleep Number Stores! 
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.couponqueenoftexas.com&quot; target=&quot;”_blank”&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i1217.photobucket.com/albums/dd384/cqot10/cq-button-ava.png&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
 
 Return to top of page 
 
Copyright©2012· Lifestyle Theme on Genesis Framework · WordPress · Log in 
 Copyright © 2012 Coupon Queen of Texas - Design by Just Married with Graphics - Genesis Framework by StudioPress - WordPress 
 Switch to our mobile site
	</body>
</document>
