<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003541" url="http://www.stopemployeetheft.net/tag/employee-theft-2" time="2012-07-12-19:41" support="1" score="0.0013787553765615503" bingtitle="Employee Theft | Stop Employee Theft" webtitle="Employee Theft | Stop Employee Theft">
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>... cameras or making random inventory counts they will ... With an agreement from a nearby fast-food restaurant we ... selected, the customer always headed to a cashier.</description>
	<body>
		Stop Employee Theft 



 
 
employee theft
 
 Run the reports 
 
Unlike the immediacy of watching your high shrink merchandise walking out with a shoplifter, employee theft investigations take time. You might be able to see them take some product, or conduct a fraudulent refund on live surveillance, but that is only the beginning.

 The true exposure or scope of employee theft investigations is generally revealed through detailed exception based and statistical reporting. I have had many conversations regarding the importance, or the usefulness of such reports.

 On one hand, reports should be the road map that leads you from point to point in an employee theft investigation . It might lead you to additional refunds or pass offs of merchandise. The reports may also show you if other employees or outside parties are involved in the employee theft.

 The flip side is that if you truly have a pulse on your store and your inventory, there should not be any surprises when you run your reports. If the employee theft targeted a specific item, there should not be any surprise that this item is on a high shrink list.

 Statistical reports like excessive refunds, or inventory losses should reiterate the findings of your employee theft investigation. They should tell you that there are certain areas of concern and employee theft is the likely culprit. Sudden spikes in the losses from certain product groups are good examples.

 While it very well could turn into an example of which came first the chicken or the egg, reports will ultimately enhance and solidify any employee theft investigation.

 For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

   Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted July 9th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 It’s not what you know; it’s what you can prove 
 
It can be very exciting to uncover a case of employee theft . For some, it can be so exciting that logic and common sense can be replaced by a case of tunnel vision.

 Let me give you an example…

 Back in the day, I had a cash register with a hundred dollar shortage. It was pretty uncommon to be short more than five dollars in a day. We didn’t even bother keeping an over/ short tracking log for less than five dollars just for that reason. So when I saw a hundred dollar shortage, my heart sank.

 My heart sank at such a huge loss, and then I took a breath and decided it must have just been an error and I could find it with a little research.

 So off I went to disprove this as an employee theft case . It didn’t take me long to realize how wrong I was. The first cash transaction showed a very clear case of employee theft, at least that’s what I thought.

 The employee rang up a low dollar transaction for a customer. He handed her a hundred dollar bill. She tendered the transaction, and handed him his change and very clearly, the hundred-dollar bill back.

 When I went to my manager to open up an employee theft investigation, I was shocked that she didn’t want to interview right away. The video was so clear and we had suffered a big loss.

 I needed to take a step back and realize that even though the employee had incurred a loss, it didn’t mean that she was intentionally stealing. That was the difference. If we couldn’t prove that intent, we had no case of employee theft.

 I watched her like a hawk for months. Not even a single penny short. Maybe she did give intend to give that hundred back, or maybe she just had a bad moment. Either way, we could never prove it was a case of employee theft.

 For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

  Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted July 2nd, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Employee Theft: The Silent Killer 
 
 The biggest killer of small businesses is employee theft. Most small business owners have little or no experience in the field of Loss Prevention thus never seeing first hand the ravages employee theft can wreak upon a business if left unchecked. There are many tools that can both deter and catch a thieving employee. A business owner’s main goal should be to deter internal theft. There are several ways to deter employees from stealing but nothing is guaranteed to work 100%. 

 If an employee has their mind set to steal then losses will occur, it then becomes a cat and mouse game to catch this employee. Once again most small business owners have never conducted a quality employee theft investigation . One of the best ways to either deter or catch a employee stealing is purchasing a quality CCTV system. Once again, you can but the best camera system in town but you have to set it up so as to be able maximize the deterrence value and to be able to catch the employee stealing either product or cash. 

 I have performed many LP consultations for small business owners who had unfortunately never gave a thought to internal theft believing that they had the best employees on the planet since they were mostly either family or friends. Many times the consultation started off with me conducting an employee theft investigation and catching their employees“red handed”stealing from their businesses. At that point we had to discuss what mistakes they had made in setting up their business and how we could change it to deter further internal theft. Numerous times it started with the purchase and set up of a good CCTV system. I always ensured the registers were adequately covered to catch any“till taps”or product pass off’s known as“sweet hearting”. The next area I would ensure was covered was the stockroom where shipping and receiving occurred, a lot of product can disappear out the back door or be concealed in the stockroom. I would also suggest the owners implement a bag/pocket check to be conducted and logged every time an employee left the premises for any reason. 

 These few changes in a small business owner’s mindset and strategy saved their businesses. Purchasing and implementing the right tools allowed them to deter theft and conduct quality employee theft investigations. Deterrence is the key however when losses occur having the capability to switch to investigation mode will benefit any business owner. 

   For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal theft contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia 

   Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigatio n . 

 
 Posted June 25th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Don’t let the “What Ifs” Slow You Down 
 
Any time I have ever worked on an employee theft investigation , there is always a series of“What Ifs”to go through. What if we had better controls in place? What if we hadn’t trusted them with the keys? What if we had noticed / paid attention to their personal problems? The list can go on and on.

 It would be easy to let all those little what ifs slow you down. I know my store managers have a harder time with them because they take cases of employee theft personally. I tend to look at it as an unfortunate reality of the retail industry.

 It is hard to get other managers and owners to become aware that statistically 2% of employees are stealing at any given point in time. Most managers, and especially small business owners have a hard time believing that an employee could be stealing from them.

 If you have put your heart and soul and often your personal finances on the line as a small business owner, you tend to imagine that all of your employees (that you personally hired) are doing the same.

 When I am called in for cases that revolve around high inventory costs, one of the last things an owner expects to hear is that I need to start an employee theft investigation.

 When they see the end results, they are in shock and start to second-guess themselves with what ifs. While there are ways to prevent employee theft, sometimes you just have to realize that they would have found a way to steal, and it is time to move on.

 For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal theft contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

   Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted June 18th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Employee Theft – Caught on Tape 
 
   A common focus for businesses is to find and stop shoplifters from stealing merchandise, but they aren’t the only people who you have to keep an eye on. An employee, who know the in and outs, patterns and schedules could be your biggest trouble.

    As a Loss Prevention Agent I’ve conducted internal theft investigations with great success. I have found greatest tool to stopping employee theft are not my eyes but the many eyes above. At anytime I can review tapes of high shrink and cash areas. This has assisted me from stopping internal theft at the cash registers. Most recently an employee would not ring up multiple items and pocket the cash. This was only caught by reviewing the camera tapes above their register.

    A technique my store uses to scare off any shoplifters is a monitor above the front entrance that lets everybody know you are being watched and recorded. This monitor shows the front entrance and main cashier where most merchandise is being handled.

    Another type of theft that is unfortunately common among workers is employee theft of one another. Most of the time it will happen in the break room, it will have low traffic thus leading some employees to believe this is a safe area for leaving their possessions on top of lockers or on tables. Prevention is the best solution, lock up all your possessions and don’t forget that new MP3 player in your jacket pocket.

 For more information on employee theft, employee theft investigation or internal contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

   Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted June 11th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Let’s Take A Look Inside That Bag 
 
My most recent case of employee theft came about as a policy violation. I had a floating manager go lend a hand in one of my stores a few weeks ago. The Store’s manager, I guess, had forgotten that she was going to be there. As soon as she walked in the door, the SM suddenly realized that she had forgot to have someone ring up a pack of gum that she had clearly chewed most of.

 While that didn’t seem like a huge red flag at the time, after my SM had left for the day, my visiting manger noticed that an employee was snacking up at the front registers. When asked, the employee said that they always do this and then whenever the SM has a chance, she comes by and rings them up.

 By now, my visiting manger was starting to suspect that the door for employee theft was wide open. They called me to let me know that some things were not adding up.

 The last clue came later on that night when they started taking the trash out. The store employees were putting everything into black, opaque trash bags instead of clear ones. Upon asking why they were being used, the employees said that it was what the SM used, so they did too.

 It was clear that an employee theft investigation needed to begin. We were right too. The SM and a few other employees were all stealing. While we never did figure out how much was actually taken out of the store in those trash bags, we do know that it won’t happen again.

 For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

   Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted June 4th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 An Eye Witness Account 
 
When I first started in Loss Prevention many years ago, not every store had a good CCTV camera system in place. One store in particular had the Frankenstein system. It was pieced together from so many different system that our new service vendor would not work on it because of how patched together it was.

 This store firmly believed that an eyewitness testimony was still far superior to anything else. No one can contest an eyewitness account because there isn’t any other evidence on the contrary.

 For some situations, they were absolutely right. That is until I brought my first employee theft investigation to a close.

 $54,000 admitted dollars later; my store was starting to realize what they had been missing, literally. Without a usable CCTV system, they were missing not only live instances of theft, but they had no way to review to see how far the scope of an employee theft investigation could take them.

 They had been relying on live shots of employee theft. They didn’t realize that if the employee theft investigation produces previous instances of theft, than you can potentially seek restitution. The only way to get that is to have a comprehensive CCTV system that not only allows you to see the live action, but also a recordable set up as well.

 I recommend a digital system. Bigger storage capacity, longer retention, clearer recordings and no one had to remember to change out a day’s VHS tape.

 For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal theft contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

   Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted May 28th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Are you the victim of employee theft by voids?? 
 
The longer I work in retail the more I believe the phrase,“There’s more than one way to skin a cat”, was directed at theft. There are two things to steal in retail. One is money and the other is merchandise. Even still there are dozens of ways to go about stealing both. This is perhaps why internal theft (also called employee theft) is the number one loss category every year. It is not easy to conduct an employee theft investigation, but it sure is necessary.

 I have had to conduct an employee theft investigation at numerous gas stations recently. One similarity between this internal theft is the clerks using voids to help them steal cash. Here is how the activity works:

 Customer comes to pay for merchandise like food or drinks and pulls out cash.

 The clerk scans the merchandise so that the customer and the cameras show normal ringing activity. The clerk then voids the sale. The clerk then conducts a“No Sale”function to open the drawer, takes the customers money and gives them change (they do have to do the math in their head). The clerk now has unaccounted for funds that he/she is free to take. 

 By voiding the sale the money taken in from the customer is not recognized by the register. The employee can take this cash and the register will still show even. This type of employee theft happens in most retail environments so I suggest checking your void reports and associates who trend higher than the rest are likely candidates for an employee theft investigation.

  For more information on employee theft investigation, employee theft or internal theft contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia

  Visit the Loss Prevention Store to purchase CCTV Systems that can help you stop Employee Theft and Internal Theft problems and help with your Employee Theft Investigation. 

 
 Posted May 21st, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Not all internal theft is merchandise… 
 
When it comes to employee theft there is nothing more irritating, more troublesome, than the theft of supplies. Many employees do it; some deliberately, some accidentally, but it is so commonplace it is almost universally accepted as a simple fact of life regardless of the business. The problem with it being so‘accepted’is that it is almost always disregarded and usually goes completely unpunished. It is that kind of mentality that forces companies to waste millions of dollars on supplies.

Not only is there the waste factor, but there is the inherent frustration aspect of your business being short, or completely out of, a supply when it really needs it. I can recall numerous instances where pens, paper towels, cleaning supplies, and even toilet paper has suddenly gone missing only to be discovered later that another employee had pilfered an obscene amount for their personal use.

A recent incident involved our warehouse becoming short on the store supplies of paper towels and water jugs for the water coolers. At first it was just once in a while, but eventually entire stockpiles were going missing within days of shipments coming in. After a lengthy stake-out and employee theft investigation we found that a ten-year veteran of the company had been moving large amounts of supplies to his vehicle over the course of his shifts at the beginning of each week and stockpiling them at his personal residence. When it was acknowledged as a case of employee theft and he was brought in for an interview he denied any wrongdoing even when confronted with hard video evidence. Eventually he admitted that he had been stealing supplies for years but claimed that he shouldn’t be punished since‘everyone did it’. 

Don’t allow your employees to think ANY kind of internal theft is okay. Send them a message that stealing is wrong even if everyone does it.

  For more information on employee theft, employee theft investigation or internal theft  contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia 

 
 Posted May 14th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off 
 Employee Theft And Proper Employee Theft Investigations 
 
An unfortunate reality of the retail business is that internal theft will occur. By some estimates, internal theft accounts for over half of all loses across the retail sector. Many companies are well equipped with teams of investigators to deal with employee theft. For many smaller retailers this investment is not a reality. Fortunately, there are companies out there are available for employee theft investigations .

 These companies can provide your business with a thorough and conclusive employee theft investigation. The process used is standard across the retail industry. It has been developed and honed to produce consistent and measureable results. When internal theft occurs, it is most often discovered after the fact. This is why it is important to have a well-trained investigator complete the employee theft investigation. The investigation should produce key information. The first being who is responsible and the second being how the internal theft occurred. These two pieces are invaluable to have when investigating employee theft.

 These two pieces of investigative information are essential in developing a strategy for the interrogation/interview of the subject causing the employee theft. It is during this phase of the employee theft investigation that it is discovered why the employee theft has occurred. This is an important part of the overall process, as it allows the owner to discover what areas of their business are lacking. Finally, at the end of the interview, the investigator can elicit information as to who else is involved in internal theft. This gives the owner a greater return on their investment. This is a proven process that is used by the industry leaders in the retail to investigate employee theft and internal theft.

  For more information on employee theft , employee theft investigation or internal contact us or call 1.866.914.2567–Atlanta Georgia 

 
 Posted May 7th, 2012 by Staff Writer and filed in Uncategorized Tags: employee theft , employee theft investigation , internal theft Comments Off Older»  
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (2) June 2012 (4) May 2012 (4) April 2012 (3) March 2012 (10) February 2012 (11) January 2012 (13) December 2011 (9) November 2011 (9) October 2011 (10) September 2011 (10) August 2011 (10) July 2011 (8) June 2011 (9) May 2011 (7) April 2011 (14) March 2011 (12) February 2011 (9) January 2011 (15) December 2010 (16) November 2010 (13) October 2010 (22) September 2010 (17) August 2010 (11) July 2010 (1) Search for: 
More Info
 Loss Prevention Blog 
Topics
 background checks corporate fraud corporate fraud investigation corporate fraud investigator employee fraud employee theft employee theft investigation internal theft white collar crime 
 Home About Us 
 
©Copyright 2012. Stop Employee Theft. All Rights Reserved.

This site is powered by WordPress and the Lead Generation theme by Ron McDaniel
	</body>
</document>
