<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003877" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/nf/22/2126/2125/Phoenix/Tempe/Fast-Food-Places" time="2012-07-12-20:02" support="1" score="0.01028972873341825" bingtitle="Tempe Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Tempe Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="35"/>
	<description>After not having the salad we wanted, we watched our food sit up on the ... Not very helpful on the phone made my order for pick up and was told they didn&apos;t ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Phoenix » Metro Area » Tempe » Fast Food 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Albuquerque Las Vegas Los Angeles New York Orange County San Diego Tucson More... 
 
 Add Restaurant Tempe Fast Food Places 
 
Prices

 $ Cheap eats (40) 
 
Neighborhoods

 
 Metro Area 

 Avondale (16) Chandler (32) Gilbert (22) Glendale (35) Goodyear (17) Mesa (58) Peoria (25) Tempe 
 Show all 
 Phoenix 

 Deer Valley (22) Downtown (15) Maryvale (16) Midtown (33) Northeast Phoenix (23) South Mountain (18) Sunnyslope&amp;North Mountain (18) 
 Show all 
 Scottsdale 

 North Scottsdale (14) 
 Show all 
 
Cuisines

 American (99) Asian (19) Bakery (21) Breakfast&amp;Brunch (36) Burgers (41) Chinese (35) Coffee (41) Desserts&amp;Ice Cream (28) Fast Food Indian (17) Italian (25) Japanese (18) Mediterranean (19) Mexican (69) Pizza (56) Pub Food (27) Sandwiches&amp;Subs (92) Soups (15) Tacos (19) Vegetarian (17) 
 Show all 
Features

 Delivery (1) Kid Friendly (15) Late Night (8) Vegan Friendly (1) 
 Remove: Tempe | Fast Food Sort: Best
| Alphabetical | Recently added 
 1 Forefathers Gourmet... 96% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs 8707 S Priest Dr, Suite 101 2 Chopstick Express 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Chinese, Fast Food 939 E Guadalupe Rd #1 3 In-N-Out Burger 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 920 E. Playa Del Norte 4 Yc&apos;s Mongolian Grill 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Asian, Chinese, Fast Food 752 W Elliot Rd 5 El Pollo Supremo 100% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican 221 W University Dr 6 Five Guys Burgers and Fries... 84% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 680 S. Mill Ave 7 Dave&apos;s Dog House 81% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 130 E University Dr 8 Amado&apos;s Mexican Food 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican 6022 S McClintock Dr 9 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 808 S Priest Dr 10 Rally&apos;s I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 1410 West University 11 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 1380 W Elliot Rd 12 Wienerschnitzel 80% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 804 S McClintock Dr 13 Carl&apos;s Jr I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 2440 W 12th St 14 Chinatown I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Chinese, Fast Food 2700 W Baseline Rd 15 Fatburger 70% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 414 S Mill Ave 16 Steak Escape I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs 5000 S Arizona Mills Cir 17 Popeye&apos;s Louisiana Kitchen I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Southern/Soul, Chicken 1619 W Baseline Rd 18 Quiznos (Tempe, W... I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs 100 W University Dr 19 Popeye&apos;s Louisiana Kitchen I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Southern/Soul, Chicken 457 W Broadway Rd 20 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 1801 East Guadalupe 21 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 835 W Baseline Rd 22 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 1415 West Elliot Road 23 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 1674 E. Southern Ave 24 Wendy&apos;s I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1314 SOUTH RURAL ROAD 25 Wendy&apos;s I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1110 E. BASELINE RD 26 Burger King I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1210 N. Scottsdale Road 27 Burger King I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 25 West University 28 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 9960 South Rural Road 29 Wendy&apos;s I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 790 W BROADWAY RD 30 Wendy&apos;s I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1405 W. BASELINE RD 31 Wendy&apos;s Old Fashioned... I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food 2704 W Southern Ave 32 Burger King I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1139 W. Broadway Road 33 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 912 E Apache Blvd 34 Panda Express I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Chinese, Fast Food 1500 W Baseline Rd 35 Panda Express I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Chinese, Fast Food 1320 E Elliot Rd 36 Panda Express I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Chinese, Fast Food 1714 E Guadalupe Rd 37 Burger King I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 5000 S Arizona Mills Cir 38 Cajun Grill at Arizona Mills I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Fast Food 5000 S Arizona Mills Cir 39 Whataburger 57% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 1346 S. Rural Rd. 40 Burger King 35% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Tempe - Burgers, Fast Food 2011 S McClintock Dr 
 « Previous Page
1 Next » 
Critic reviews

Tempe, Fast Food

 October 5, 2010 3/5 stars Dave&apos;s Dog House By Arizona Republic Cheren does not commit the sacrilege of putting ketchup on his dogs, but does provide it for sinners. Full review July 29, 2010 Wendy&apos;s Old Fashioned Hamburgers By New Times Do Wendy&apos;s New Salads Stand Up to the Chain&apos;s Leafy Legacy? Full review July 14, 2010 3.5/5 stars Forefathers Gourmet Cheesesteaks&amp;Fries By Arizona Republic I also found what are surely the Valley&apos;s best Philly cheesesteaks. Full review 
 
Diner reviews

Tempe, Fast Food

 May 18, 2012 Forefathers Gourmet Cheesesteaks&amp;Fries Mobile review by Cameron ( 2 reviews ) Awesome! Only one complaint, they close too early. 
 
Restaurant tweets

Tempe, Fast Food

 about 1 hour ago Quiznos (Tempe, W University) Adam from @Workaholics has a cousin that sure does love Quiznos! RT if you too are addicted to Quiznos! t.co/yIQ4aTYw More tweets by Quiznos about 2 hours ago Carl&apos;s Jr Hey #Austin! Saturday, July 14, get a $1 Turkey Burger @CarlsJr 3201 Bee Caves Rd, Austin, TX (Sat. at Bee Caves location only) More tweets by CarlsJr about 23 hours ago Five Guys Burgers and Fries (Tempe, S. Mill) Attention Burlington, NC your new Five Guys is NOW OPEN! Find it at 106 Huffman Mill Road, Burlington, NC 27215. More tweets by Five_Guys 
 
 
Name and save this location
 
 
 Add Restaurant Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
