<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003850" url="http://www.ecookinggames.com/games/restaurant,1,2/" time="2012-07-12-20:00" support="1" score="0.007932571006468613" bingtitle="Restaurant Games | Page 2 | E Cooking Games" webtitle="Restaurant Games | Page 2 | E Cooking Games">
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>Leas fast food restaurant. To help me out in this restaurant game ... Then select a pie form, bake it in the oven, spread ... Choose a place for them in your restaurant, and ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Cooking Baby Baking Burger Cake Car Dress Up Food Hair Ice Cream Kissing Make Up Management Pizza Restaurant Waitress 
 
Restaurant Games Page 2
 
Be sure to come back every day for all new free online Restaurant Games
 E Cooking Games &gt;  Restaurant &gt;  Page 2 
 Sisis Sushi Bar 
Your today&apos;s task is to help Sisi in her sushi bar. Help her to prepare some delicious Asian snacks and serve up to the customer.
 Teen Park 
Bruno is wokring in a fancy restaurant. Help him to serve his customers in this busy restaurant.
 Totos Cocktails 
Help this cocktail specialist to prepare some delicious drinks. Mix some juices with your favorite fruits and serve it to the customers. Have fun!
 Penguin Diner game 
This penguin works in a restaurant and his job is to serve foods and drinks to the customers. Help him and have fun!
 Summer Buffet 
You are managing a summer buffet restaurant. Your job is to serve your customers with burgers, cookies and fruits. Enjoy!
 Ninas Pizza Restaurant 
Today many peoples are going to visit Nina&apos;s pizza restaurant. Help Nina to manage the restaurant efficiently. Make sure every customer get their food in the timely manner. Have fun!
 Pet Food Restaurant 
Today you are going to manage a restaurant reserved for pets only. Feed all the pets as fast as you can. Have fun!
 Doli Cake Laboratory 
The Doli Cake Laboratory is a special unique place filled with super delicious and yummy-looking cakes. Master your cooking skills as you will have to bake some chocolate, vanilla or fruit cakes, topped with delicious sauces, fruits and whipped cream. Start the work in the cake laboratory and turn the delicious orders into a real yummy treat. The Doli friends will enter the Doli Cake laboratory asking for special orders, so make sure you can fulfill their request right up! As the level gets higher, so does their demands for fresh strawberries or caramel sauce. Good luck and have some delicious fun in the exclusive Doli Cake laboratory.
 Instant Noodles 
Ruby`s father is out of city on a business tour. Now she is in charge of his Noodles Restaurant. Help Ruby in her father&apos;s business by running a successful restaurant. Serve everything from single noodle orders to complex combo orders. Unlock many items after each level. Serve right orders and keep your customers happy!
 Easter Bistro 
The most fancy bistro of all times is our super cute and colorful Easter Bistro. Welcome to this awesome management challenge and help the Easter Bunny serve food to our DoliDoli friends. Use your skills to serve up the cookies and the jello, color up the Easter eggs and cook the steak. Serve the drinks as well and make sure each DoliDoli friend is satisfied in the Easter Bistro. See the Easter Bunny in action, make a profit and go through all the levels, keeping up with the high demands of Mina, Lisa and Toto. Have a happy Easter and be sure to wait for the Easter Bunny to bring you treats from his special Easter Bistro.
 Leas fast food restaurant 
To help me out in this restaurant game, just like in other waitress games like this one, you need to reach the target each day, before my time runs out. You have to seat customers, take their orders, bring them their food and clear their plates away, and you have to do everything quickly so that they don&apos;t get impatient. Good luck with my new game !
 Spring Rolls 
Are you ready to step into the busiest restaurant kitchen you&apos;ve eve been before? Then put your cooking skills to a test being this talented chef&apos;s assistant and helping him prepare his customers&apos; favorite sushi rolls!
 Doli Pie Factory 
Welcome to the most awesome and delicious place on earth: the Doli Pie Factory! Here, some of the most amazing pies are being prepared right now! So how would you like to join the mega cooking fun and top some of these delicious pies? Keep an eye on the customers walking in, mainly Toto and Sisi, and see what they ask for. Then select a pie form, bake it in the oven, spread the topping and add the right fruits. Then hand the pie over and collect the bonus! It&apos;s easy and super delicious, right? The Doli Pie Factory is open for fun!
 Hamster Winter Bistro 
Today, we&apos;re going to work in a bistro in Iceland. This is an icy country, where there&apos;s even ice floating on the lakes. The Icelandic Hamsters are tiny animals, but they have a huge appetite! Choose a place for them in your restaurant, and bring them what they ordered. If you serve them quickly and friendly, your bistro will be a big success. In that case, you can even expand in the next levels. Make your bistro the most successful restaurant of the surroundings!
 Fastfood Rapidly 
Mary is running a fast food restaurant, the things she made is very delicious. More and more people like to order her fast food. Today she is really very busy and has to need your help. Please help her now! Give her a fast food rapidly.
 
 1 2 3 
 Privacy Policy - Contact Us 
All Chef, Culinary, Food, Cuisine, Recipe, Kitchen Games, and Cooking Games
Copyright©2012
	</body>
</document>
