<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003286" url="http://www.insideline.com/volkswagen/passat/2012/2012-volkswagen-passat-v6-vs-2011-honda-accord-v6-comparison-test.html" time="2012-07-12-19:25" support="1" score="0.0003407176201054312" bingtitle="2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 vs. 2011 Honda Accord V6 Comparison Test" webtitle="2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 vs. 2011 Honda Accord V6 Comparison Test">
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="151"/>
	<description>Even though styling doesn&apos;t seem to count for much in ... The Honda Accord is due for a body style change is 2013. ... Next time you drive near 5-6 years old German car look at ...</description>
	<body>
		INSIDE LINE 



 
 Cars Articles Videos Photos Blogs 
 
 
 
News

 2013 McLaren MP4-12C Spider Makes Video » 
 
News

 Monterey Reunion To Honor Carroll Shelby » 
 
News

 2012 Nissan Leaf Police Car Debuts » 
 
News

 2012 Lexus LFA Black Amethyst Debuts » 
 
News

 2013 Ford Focus ST Achieves a 32-MPG » 
 
 
 
News

 Infiniti Eyes Emerg-E Supercar, Skinnier » 
 
News

 New Technology Blocks Driver&apos;s Mobile » 
 
News

 Eggasus EV Designed To Crack Open Personal » 
 
Auto Show

 2012 Paris Auto Show » 
 
News

 2013 Dodge Dart Gets Customized With Graphics » 
 
 
 
News

 2013 Hyundai Tucson Gets Price Hike » 
 
News

 Danica Patrick Takes Katie Couric for » 
 
News

 2015 Nissan Z May Be Lighter, Leaner » 
 
News

 2013 Aston Martin V12 Vantage Roadster Debuts » 
 
News

 2013 Chevrolet Camaro ZL1 Convertible » 
 
 
 
2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 vs. 2011 Honda Accord V6 Comparison Test
 
 Share Share RSS RSS Print Print 
 
Media Player
 
 
2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 SEL Premium vs. 2011 Honda Accord EX-L V6 Navi Picture

With incrementally and measurably better overall performance and presentation, the 2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 SEL Premium gets our vote.
| October 13, 2011 | Kurt Niebuhr for Edmunds 
 
 
61 Photos
| See more photos in this gallery » 
 
Comparison
 
2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 vs. 2011 Honda Accord V6 Comparison Test

Volkswagen Builds a Better Sedan Than Honda

By Chris Walton , Chief Road Test Editor |
Published Oct 18, 2011
 Poor So-So Pretty Good Good Excellent 

 67 Ratings Comments (107) 
Honda&apos;s 2011 Accord sedan, according to the EPA, is the biggest &quot;midsize&quot; car you can buy. It&apos;s big enough, in fact, to be classified by the agency as a large car. Outsizing the competition was a bold move, which, when combined with the Accord&apos;s reputation for being reliable and not boring, continues to pay off in the form of a quarter-million or more sales annually since 2008. It&apos;s hardly surprising, then, that when Volkswagen redesigned the Passat for 2012, it chose the Accord as its primary target.

Larger in every way than the sedan it replaces, the 2012 Volkswagen Passat is designed for and is being built in America for Americans. Volkswagen even aggressively slashed pricing by as much as $7,180 to undercut comparably equipped Honda Accords and Toyota Camrys.

For 2011, the Accord receives a refresh that includes subtle sheet metal changes, increased feature content and a 1-mpg improvement in fuel economy.

 Options Are Not an Option 
Balancing features against price—a solid means to gauge value, but a complex evaluation method—was once the centerpiece of an Inside Line comparison test. However, both the Accord and Passat in this test are range-topping models and are priced only $1,120 apart.

The top-shelf 2011 Honda Accord EX-L V6 Navi is the best-equipped and most expensive version of the Accord sedan. For $32,600 it includes a 271-horsepower port-injected 3.5-liter V6, five-speed automatic transmission, 17-inch alloy wheels, remote entry and keyed ignition, leather seating, DVD navigation with traffic-flow info and a back-up camera (new for 2011), a seven-speaker audio upgrade including XM, Bluetooth phone-audio streaming, and iPod via USB. In other words, this is as premium as a midsize sedan can be, rivaling Acura&apos;s TSX in materials, features and performance.
 
The apex of the Passat model range is the 2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 SEL Premium . At $33,720 it includes a 280-hp direct-injected 3.6-liter V6, six-speed DSG auto-double-clutch manual transmission, 18-inch alloy wheels, intelligent keyless entry and ignition, leather seating, hard drive navigation with 10GB of music storage, traffic-flow info and a back-up camera, Fender-branded nine-speaker audio upgrade including Sirius, Bluetooth phone-audio streaming and iPod connectivity via a proprietary cable. It, too, rivals premium corporate siblings like the Audi A4 in size and features and even exceeds that car&apos;s power.

Also, despite what their badges might say, these cars are about as American as can be. The Accord features 80 percent North American parts content and the Passat&apos;s parts are 85 percent North American. Both are assembled in the United States—the Accord in Marysville, Ohio, and the Passat in Chattanooga, Tennessee.

 Cost vs. Benefit 
A large portion of the price disparity between these two sedans comes down to the Passat&apos;s superior versions of similar features. Its 18-inch alloy wheels and genuine wood trim surpass the Accord&apos;s 17-inch alloys and poorly rendered simulated wood trim. The relatively ancient five-speed automatic in the Honda is no match for the sophisticated six-speed automated manual in the VW. Not only is the Passat&apos;s DSG transmission smoother and more intelligent about gearchanges up and down, it also provides Manual and Sport modes the Accord does not have, plus the VW has shift buttons on the steering wheel.

The Passat&apos;s hard-drive-based navigation system (versus Accord&apos;s DVD) features far superior graphics and an intuitive touchscreen interface, plus extra disc space allotted for music storage. Even the sound quality (and two more speakers) of the VW/Fender system is superior and it better integrates/interfaces iPod use.

From the outside, neither car is styled as aggressively as Hyundai&apos;s Sonata or Mazda&apos;s 6 . Even though styling doesn&apos;t seem to count for much in this segment, it&apos;s a shame Volkswagen didn&apos;t instill a little more CC sedan into the 2012 Volkswagen Passat&apos;s styling. The Accord is less boring than a Camry but isn&apos;t really going to turn any heads.

 Size Matters 
Despite the 2012 Passat&apos;s cavernous appearance and ginormous trunk capacity (15.9 cubic feet), it misses the EPA&apos;s large car distinction by 2 cubic feet of combined passenger and cargo capacity, making it a very large midsize car. Its total interior volume falls 3 cubic feet short of the Accord. In practical terms, however, the Passat will better satisfy both your front and backseat drivers.
 
 The Volkswagen Passat has historically been almost competitive among its peers, but for 2012 all that&apos;s changed. 
 
On paper, front accommodations are nearly identical between the two: both have standard, heated leather power seats, a tilt-and-telescoping steering wheel and dual-zone HVAC. The Accord offers 0.7 inch more front headroom, but seat comfort and support are noticeably better in the Passat, front and rear. The VW further offers more rear legroom (by 1.9 inches), more rear shoulder room (0.6 inch) and more rear headroom (0.6 inch), plus vents for HVAC.

Both cars&apos; rear seatbacks fold down to expand cargo capacity. Both rely on temporary, space-saver spare tires; however, the Passat&apos;s cargo lift-over height is 1.25 inches friendlier to your back.

 Quality Is Difficult To Quantify 
Steering feel, ride comfort, interior material quality, even that door-shut thump people associate with excellence are what separate merely adequate cars from those with real merit. The Volkswagen impressed us in each of the above areas and then some. The Germans probably use one of those notorious three-words-mashed-into-one word for the door thump sound—something like Türschlieenklang , we reckon.

It probably wouldn&apos;t take the average Joe driving these two sedans a city block to say which one he suspected was the &quot;more expensive&quot; or &quot;more sophisticated&quot; sedan. The Passat supplies buttery-smooth steering (which happens to be well-executed electric-assist power steering) compared to what the Accord has had for a decade: moderately weighted and reasonably precise hydraulic steering. What&apos;s more, the Accord has lost some of the road connection or &quot;feel&quot; it once counted on to earn reviewers&apos; praises.
 
The Passat&apos;s compliant and refined ride qualities contrast with the Accord&apos;s firm-ish sometimes-busy suspension. In this way, the Passat manages to feel like a large American car while maintaining the &quot;European-inspired&quot; ride and response people associate with Teutonic sedans. Despite this difference, this Accord weighs 67 pounds more than the Passat.

 Performance Testing 
Neither of these V6 family sedans will set your hair ablaze, but they both illustrate the performance advantages of opting for a V6 rather than a four-cylinder (or in the case of VW, a turbocharged four- or five-cylinder) version of the same sedan. These domestic-duty devices are actually pretty quick.

At the end of the day, however, the Passat accelerated quicker, stopped shorter and handled better than the Accord across the board, putting yet another check in the Passat&apos;s &quot;measurably better&quot; column. It posted a 6.1-second best run to 60 mph (versus the Accord&apos;s 6.7-second run, both with 1-foot rollout like at a drag strip) and crossed the quarter-mile mark in 14.6 seconds at 96.4 mph—about a half-second better than the Accord.

The Passat stopped in 131 feet, which isn&apos;t all that impressive, but is still shorter than the Accord&apos;s 136-foot best. Its non-defeat electronic stability control (ESC) system limits its true handling potential. If possible, we test both on and off modes, and the Accord allowed full defeat of the electronics. Still, the Passat managed to weave through the slalom 0.5 mph faster at 62.6 mph and circle the 200-foot skid pad at 0.81g vs. the Accord&apos;s 0.80g.

Fuel grade is the only &quot;performance&quot; category where the Accord earned a slight advantage. It will tolerate regular fuel while the Passat demands premium (91 or higher octane). However, the Accord&apos;s superior 24-mpg EPA-combined fuel economy estimate (versus the Passat&apos;s 23-mpg combined) didn&apos;t pan out in our books. After 500 miles of combined driving in each, we earned 21 mpg in the Passat and 20 mpg in the Accord. Of course, &quot;your results may vary.&quot;
 
 Who&apos;s Trying Harder Here? 
The Volkswagen Passat historically has been almost competitive among its peers, usually offering better dynamic qualities and responses, but always being a tad small, slightly underequipped and a little expensive. For the 2012 model year, all that&apos;s changed.

The 2012 VW Passat, especially the fully equipped V6 SEL Premium, offers all the features of its competition plus a few they don&apos;t have—like its sophisticated transmission. The front- and rear-seat comfort and sheer space advantage the Passat enjoys over the Accord make it a more competent, more relaxing family sedan every day. And when strapping kids in their car seats, a couple inches really matters for the parents, too.

The Passat&apos;s interior design/presentation plus superior ergonomics imbue a daily commute, carpool duty or a weekend trip with a specialness that the Accord does not have. The Passat feels like a premium car in a transportation-appliance segment.

With the death of a thousand cuts, the reissued 2011 Honda Accord Sedan falls to the all-new 2012 Volkswagen Passat. The Accord EX-L Navi fails to move the desirability needle, while the Passat SEL Premium finally finds its American groove. It&apos;s obvious VW is pedaling (peddling?) hard with the new Passat, while Honda is coasting on the legacy of the Accord. The 2012 Volkswagen Passat V6 SEL Premium coalesces better quality, performance, ride and value, which make it a truly superior (very large) midsize family sedan. And our winner.

 The manufacturers provided Edmunds these vehicles for the purposes of evaluation. 
 


 Add A Comment » 
 
Sort By:
 Most Recent First Posted 
 of 10 prev next 
 
ford_flexer says:

08:29 AM, 05/22/2012

That passat is very tempting looks awesome
 Report It Report It 
alwaysright says:

04:58 AM, 12/30/2011

Well the passat is an amazing car as it should be since its a volkswagen, the only problem is that its made in america and this makes it less reliable. Same as chevy, chrysler, and ford even though ford is one of the better ones.
 Report It Report It 
bricknord says:

09:27 AM, 12/13/2011

Long-time VW fan.  I went and drove the new Passat.  

The interior fan sounded like it had a bearing ready to crap out.  Numerous interior creaks, rattles, and squeaks, especially from the dash and rear shelf areas.  Exterior trim misaligned at several noticeable points.  Trunk would not open with the remote no matter what we did, also stumping the salesperson.  Remote worked fine for doors.  No valet mode on, etc.  Did they ship the dealer a pre-production test mule?

On the plus side, cavernous interior, dual zone climate control standard.

Thumbs down to no rear console air vents.

Ridiculous throttle lag off idle with the 2.5&amp;automatic trans.  The 5-cyl stick shift version I drove was far superior.  With the auto, you press the gas pedal, wait...wait...press more...wait...press more...ZOOM.  Someone needs to seriously address the poor drive by wire throttle calibration on recent vintage VWs.  Noticed this on the Jetta as well.  Horrible.

Overall impression:  Lots of real estate for the money.  Awful throttle lag.  Nice standard features such as dual climate.  Was fun to drive with stick shift (more an indictment of the poor DBW than an endorsement of manuals).  Rear legroom-sweet.  Poor quality control/assembly attention to detail.

I conclude that if you can live with the shoddy attention to assembly/manufacture detail, and want a stick 2.5 or diesel, a good buy.
 Report It Report It 
audio01 says:

10:18 AM, 12/12/2011

I have driven both cars. I did not like the &quot;leatherette&quot; upholstery in the Passat. You would have opt for the more expensive SEL V6 model to get leather. The V6 Passat uses premium gas vs the Honda&apos;s &quot;VCM&quot; (Variable Cylinder Management system) on their V6.
The Passat has an  older &quot;Iron Duke&quot; engine vs the Honda&apos;s engine made of aluminum/alloy,  thus a significantly lighter engine.
The electronics in the German cars are inferior to the Japanese. Reliability problems have &quot;plagued&quot; VW for years. I do like the looks of the Passat and size but the Honda is a proven technology with higher resale value and satisfaction level.  The Accord is on it&apos;s last year for the current body style.  The Honda Accord is due for a body style change is 2013.
 Report It Report It 
wojciech says:

01:55 PM, 11/02/2011

I have owned cars from both brands.  Yes, Honda is not as comfortable as VW/Audi but most of the &quot;stuff&quot; works form many years.  On the other end, VW/Audi cannot make a car where electronics have no problems after longer mileage, not to mention exterior mirrors.  The problem with the mirrors is German. Next time you drive near 5-6 years old German car look at the mirrors - Their reflective parts are peeling off. Ridiculous.  I had an Audi A4 where heating elements in both mirrors would never work at the same time.  I had them replaced a few times under warranty.  The same for a factory radios made by Blaupunkt - these I had 3 replaced.  This is the &quot;stuff&quot; that I expect not to happen in $30K plus cars.
 Report It Report It 
jackd990 says:

08:59 AM, 11/02/2011

One other little thing that I&apos;d like to point out that seems to contradict something that was high-lighted in the Edmond&apos;s test, is that when I drove the 2.5 Passat SEL (Premium) I noted that only 40% of its parts are &quot;U.S./Canadian&quot;-sourced (not 85%), while 28% were from Germany. The engine was made in Mexico, while the tranny was Japanese. Maybe Edmonds was counting the Mexican-built engine toward the 85% they noted, but the car&apos;s sticker did not reflect the percentage reported by Mr. Walton. My Accord EX-L (4)&apos;s sticker notes 80% &quot;U.S./Canadian Parts Content.&quot;
 Report It Report It 
jackd990 says:

05:18 PM, 11/01/2011

I&apos;ve not driven the V-6 Passat SEL (Premium), but have driven a 2.5 SE and 2.5 SEL (Premium) and own a 2011 Accord EX-L (4). While I was impressed with the Passat overall, there are a couple of things that I believe that Edmonds either missed or provided inaccurate info. The first is that the driver&apos;s footell in the Passat is much narrower than I&apos;m used to or like...so make sure that your American feet fit in the space. The second is that while the Passat has vents under the front seats which aim into the rear seat area, like most cars, it does not have any vents in the end of the console. After hearing my kids complain for years about a lack of ventalation in our previous 1998 Accord LX V-6, I was very insistent that our next automotive acquisition have them. While Edmonds may have found that the V-6 Passat &quot;handled better&quot; than the Accord, I would have to point out that a recent Car&amp;Driver comparo of the same vehicles gave the nod to the Accord for handling, steering (feel) and brake (feel). I would also have to observe that both the Passat SE and SEL (Premium)...17&quot; wheels... that I test drove did not have the steering &quot;directness&quot; I expected and that the suspension was softer and less controlled than the Accords. I don&apos;t know about the V-6s, but I&apos;d still buy the EX-L (4) over the 2.5 SEL (Premium) as I don&apos;t care about the standard navi system and that there&apos;s at least a $2000 difference in price.
 Report It Report It 
5lv8 says:

05:56 PM, 10/27/2011

Who is going to pay $33,000 for a Passat or Accord?  I love my 1998 Accord, but I am not paying Acura or Audi money for a VW or a Honda.
 Report It Report It 
g35buf says:

07:09 AM, 10/27/2011

For the doubters, drive both...I have...There is a BIG difference in the general refinement and feel of the Passat vs the Accord.  They Accord driven with no comparison is a nice car...but drive the Passat back to back and the Passat is the EASY winner as noted here.

For those that want to bring up the &apos;reliability card&apos; - I&apos;d say &apos;yes&apos; there is an advantage to the Honda, but the difference in problems with most modern cars is 5% or less.

I drive a 2010 Honda Ridgeline but own 2 VWs (a 2006 Rabbit and a 2011 Tiguan), and I&apos;ve owned 4 Acuras/Hondas in the past.  Real world, the actual problem count amongst them is small (worst car I enter owned for reliability was a 2002 Acura TL-S ironically)...


 Report It Report It 
jm1212 says:

02:33 PM, 10/26/2011

@thekingofvtec

i dont know where you have been, but VW is poised to be the largest automaker in the world before the end of the year. they are on track to sell something like 8.1 million vehicles, which is a good 500-700,000 more than GM or Toyota. Honda isnt even on the radar of the largest automakers...
 Report It Report It 
Sort By:
 Most Recent First Posted 
 of 10 prev next 
 Close 

 Share on Facebook Share on Twitter Preview Comment Edit Comment Post Comment 
Advertisement
	</body>
</document>
