<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003759" url="http://www.healthychefcreations.com/Endorsements.html" time="2012-07-12-19:55" support="6" score="0.0046939883474205035" bingtitle="Fresh Delivery: Health Chef Creations" webtitle="Fresh Delivery: Health Chef Creations">
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000871" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>Or It s just easier to pull into a fast food restaurant on the way ... the right herbal therapies can not only support and ... Home Our Food Order Cooking Classes Catering About Us</description>
	<body>
		fresh delivery, organic meal delivery, whole foods delivery, meal delivery service, personal chef delivery, diet home delivery, diet delivery service, diet meals delivery, gourmet dinner delivery, diet delivered, diet meals delivered, delivery meals, healthy gourmet, diet meal delivery, home delivery diet meal, home meal delivery service, diet to your door, dine wise, diets delivered 
 
 
 
 
 
   Endorsements   Press   Testimonials   Place Order   Sample Menu&amp;Pricing   Food Facts   The Healthy Chef   Gift Certificate 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Kathy Bee, Certified Lifestyle Educator 


 William H. Andrews, Ph.D. 


 Dr. Eudene Harry, M.D. 
 
 Dr. Vagnini, M.D. 


 Rebecca Gerard R.D., L.D. 


 Monica Murray, Ed.S. 

 
 
 
 Kathy Bee endorses Healthy Chef Creations 

As a nutrition/lifestyle educator, I work with clients of all ages and all walks of life. The one thing they all have in common is that they want to be healthier. As they learn about healthier food choices they begin to understand how important it is to fuel their bodies with the right nutrients to help avoid disease and unhealthy weight gain. Every client I have worked with has commented on how fantastic they feel when they make simple lifestyle changes and better food choices. I can see their energy increase and their confidence build as they nourish their bodies and eliminate or reduce the unhealthy food choices. For some this becomes a temporary change due to the fact that they get caught up in the hectic pace of life and begin backsliding into eating foods that are fast and convenient; even though they know how it makes them feel. By putting processed, unhealthy foods in their bodies, they are inviting disease, mood swings, low energy and unhealthy weight gain back into their lives. I will hear I don t have time to prepare meals ahead of time. Or It s just easier to pull into a fast food restaurant on the way home. That s where Healthy Chef Creations has come in to save the day! Clients who use Healthy Chef Creations stay on the healthy path, enjoy delicious real food and maintain their weight loss and improved health. I am so happy that there is a company that understands the importance of healthy, real food and is there to make our lives easier. There really is no excuse to eat unhealthy with Healthy Chef Creations available to help.
- Kathy Bee, Certified Lifestyle Educator www.kathybeehealthy.com 
 
 
 
 Kathy Bee Bio 

Kathy is a nutrition/lifestyle educator who has a passion for helping people achieve their goals. With over 25 years of experience as an educator, Kathy has learned how to motivate clients while providing them with the necessary tools to help them achieve and maintain their goals. As a former classroom teacher, Kathy has a special desire to see children learn healthier eating habits while they are young. Unhealthy, overweight children are at greater risk of becoming unhealthy, obese adults; which in turn have a greater risk of experiencing debilitating diseases. Her desire to help children lead her into the role of nutrition consultant/educator for the kids healthier eating TV series, The Chefsters. Kathy takes every opportunity to learn new information and techniques that are helpful for all age groups. Whether it s expectant moms, parents, children or adults, Kathy has a program that will help them learn how to eat healthier and live healthier.


 Credentials: 

 BA Education- Nicholls State University Graduate Studies in Psychology and Counseling- Nicholls State University Certified Nutrition and Wellness Consultant- A.F.P.A. Certified Lifestyle Educator- Metagenics: First Line Therapy Certified L.E.A.N. Start Coach- Dr. Sears Nutrition Consultant for The Chefsters T.V. Show Nutrition Educator for The Chefsters T.V. Show Over 25 Years of Experience as an Educator 
 
 
 
 Endorsement for the Healthy Chef Creations 

I am Rebecca Gerard, a Registered Dietitian who has had the pleasure of working with The Healthy Chef, John Procacci. Our ideas about health and food are in complete alignment. I have eaten Healthy Chef Creation foods, so I can say without doubt that the meals are delicious and visually appealing. I have evaluated the meals for freshness, quality, and nutritional balance. Chef Procacci uses mostly organic ingredients/foods and free-range meats, which are free from preservatives and chemicals. I have also inspected and approved The Healthy Chefs kitchen and production for food safety and sanitation.
 
 
My understanding is that a regular program of Healthy Chef Creations fits right into a Whole Foods/Spa Cuisine program and has an average of 450 calories, 5 grams fat, and 350 mg sodium (unless cooked with the no added salt option). The Healthy Chef Creations cooking techniques protect the fragile, nutrient-dense organic foods from nutrition loss during cooking, which makes the meals perfect for helping to maintain health and for promoting weight loss. The fact that different meal programs are available to meet individual customer needs and still provide optimal nutrition is unique. Not only do I recommend the meals to my clients, but I also eat the meals myself.

 Are you having a challenging time deciding which program to select from the Healthy Chef Creations menu? Is it challenging for you to follow a diet? Are you not getting the weight loss results that you want? Do you feel tired all the time? Have you been sick more than twice this year? Would you like some dietary health advice? 

For consultations or to learn more about Rebecca s program, call 407-339-2433 or e-mail at eathealthy@bellsouth.net

Rebecca Gerard R.D., L.D., is a Registered and Licensed Dietitian with the American Dietetic Association. For 12 years, she has helped her clients achieve phenomenal health results. Her customized nutritional programs are easy, fun, and focus on what you want and need. Her professional history includes work in clinical dietetics and outpatient nutritional coaching for numerous South Florida Hospitals, as well as in fitness centers in South and Central Florida. Rebecca currently coaches clients to lifetime results with her private practice in the Orlando area.

Rebecca Gerard is an independent registered dietitian. She is not employed by The Healthy Chef, Inc. nor by Healthy Chef Creations Home Meal Delivery or Catering Services. She offers an independent dietary consulting service.

 &quot;Healthy Chef Creations WORKS!&quot;

&quot;Healthy Chef Creations meals are not only superior quality, but nutritionally balanced and healthy. I not only recommend this service to my clients, but I eat the food myself! It works.&quot; 
 
 
 About Dr. Vagnini 

 
 
 &quot;I endorse Healthy Chef Creations Spa-inspired Fresh Organic Wholesome Meals. This service is perfect for those wanting to lose weight or for those that have diabetes and heart disease.&quot;
 - Dr. Vagnini, M.D. 

Dr. Frederic J. Vagnini is one of the most unique physicians and health educators in the world. After graduation from St. Louis University School of Medicine in 1963, Dr. Vagnini underwent 8 years of post doctorate internship and residency. These years studying surgery, vascular, heart and lung surgery were spent at the Downstate Medical Center, Brooklyn, New York and Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center, New York.
 
 
Following completion of training Dr. Vagnini served in the United States Army as a Lieutenant Colonel and subsequently entered into private practice on Long Island, New York. For the next 25 years Dr. Vagnini practiced as a heart, lung and blood vessel surgeon.

He has operated on thousands of patients with heart and blood vessel disease. As his career continued Dr. Vagnini became interested in Health Education, Preventive Medicine and Clinical Nutrition. Because of his vast experience in the area of heart disease and nutrition he became a frequent guest speaker and has appeared numerous times on local and national radio and television.

Dr. Vagnini has extensive media experience with hundreds of radio and television appearances. He presently hosts a live call in show on WOR 710 AM. The show is called &quot;The Heart Show&quot; and airs from 4-5 PM Sundays. Dr. Vagnini formerly hosted a national health show on Fox Television.
 
 
 About Dr. Andrews 

 
 
 &quot;After being on your program for 2 weeks I have to say you have the best food on the planet. I am really enjoying the convenience, taste, and healthiness of your food plan. And, I love losing weight so easily. Thank you very much.&quot;
 - Bill Andrews Ph. D. 
President, CEO
Sierra Sciences, LLC
Cure Aging or Die Trying 


 Biography of William H. Andrews, Ph.D. 

Dr. William H. Andrews has worked in the biotech industry for 28 years, focusing the last 15 years on finding ways to extend human lifespan through the intervention of telomere shortening in human cells.
 
 
Dr. Andrews earned his Ph.D. in Molecular and Population Genetics at the University of Georgia in 1981. He was a Senior Scientist at Armos Corporation and Codon Corporation, Director of Molecular Biology at Codon and at Geron Corporation, and Director of Technology Development at EOS Biosciences. He is presently the founder, President and CEO of Sierra Sciences, a biotech company in Reno, Nevada focused exclusively on finding drugs that will transiently induce the expression of endogenous telomerase in human cells. Sierra Sciences has already identified more than 300 such drugs and is presently characterizing their mechanism of action.

While Director of Molecular Biology at Geron Corporation, Dr. Andrews was one of the principal discoverers of both the RNA and protein components of human telomerase and was awarded 2nd place as &quot;National Inventor of the Year&quot; in 1997 for this work. He is presently a named inventor on 35 US issued telomerase patents.
 
 
 Monica Oganes Murray, Ed.S. endorses Healthy Chef Creations 

In my role as a school psychologist, I have the opportunity to tell parents about the importance of nutrition on their child s development. Research indicates that a balanced and nutritious diet influences behavior, learning, and mental health. A lack of nutrients have been found in populations with ADHD, dyslexia, autism, and other neurodevelopmental and psychiatric disorders. I endorse Healthy Chef Creations Fresh Organic Wholesome Meals. Feeding children nutritious organic food increases their ability to grow healthy through improved learning, increased attention, healthy brain functioning, adequate weight, and better peer relationships.
 
 
Monica Oganes, M.A., Ed.S. is a bilingual (English/Spanish) licensed school psychologist. She is a Past President of the 
 Florida Association of School Psychologists and the Latino Co-Chair of the Multicultural Affairs Committee of the National Association of 
 School Psychologists. She is the Chair of the School Neuropsychology Committee of the Florida Association of School Psychologists. She is a 
 consultant to school districts in Florida and other states and provides presentations nationwide about cultural diversity and mental health issues. 
 Due to her vast experience, she has participated on a congressional panel speaking about mental health in the schools. She founded Monica Oganes&amp;Associates with the belief that we can shape children’s minds for a brighter future. Monica and her team offer consultation, academic diagnostics 
 testing, tutoring, counseling, and comprehensive psychoeducational and neuropsychological evaluations of children, adolescents, and young adults with 
 neurodevelopmental, behavioral, and learning needs.

For consultations contact Monica Oganes&amp;Associates www.monicaoganes.com 
 
 

 Eudene Harry M.D. endorses Healthy Chef Creations 

The body needs the mind and spirit in order to flourish. It also needs the appropriate raw materials to perform its numerous daily functions with maximal efficiency and minimal damage. Eating the right foods, taking the appropriate nutritional supplements, effective stress management and sometimes initiating the right herbal therapies can not only support and enhance the body&apos;s performance but also protect and repair further damage. Did you know that you can be proactive in prevention conditions such as diabetes, heart disease , osteoporosis and dementia? It goes well beyond taking vitamin C for cold symptoms or taking calcium to build strong bones. Remember a healthy foundation Will serve you well now and in the future.

Eudene Harry M.D. is board certified in both Emergency Medicine and Holistic Medicine. She received both her medical degree and Emergency Medicine residency training from Thomas Jefferson University. She did her undergraduate studies at New York University, where she received a Bachelor of Science degree in Biology with a minor in Chemistry.

 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home • Our Food • Order • Cooking Classes • Catering • About Us 
 Privacy Policy • Terms and Conditions 
 
Healthy Chef Creations®
1435 Howell Branch Road, Suite C, Winter Park, FL 32789•407-339-2433• info@healthychefcreations.com 
Call toll free 1-866-575-CHEF (2433)
	</body>
</document>
