<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003224" url="http://www.broadlandshoa.org/hoaforum/archive/index.php/t-4534.html" time="2012-07-12-19:21" support="4" score="0.0036789306987351136" bingtitle="Sonic&apos;s Drive-In now open [Archive] - Broadlands Homeowners ..." webtitle="Sonic&apos;s Drive-In now open [Archive]  - Broadlands Homeowners Association Forums">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000809" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>... Sonic&apos;s Drive-In in Massaponax, Virginia Exit 126 ... Since when is a fast food restaurant in Massaponax considered a ... for your own &quot;fossil fuel&quot; for a biodiesel car ...</description>
	<body>
		Broadlands Homeowners Association Forums &gt; Broadlands Community and Area Interests &gt; Area Restaurants, Dining and Food &gt;Sonic&apos;s Drive-In now open PDA 
View Full Version : Sonic&apos;s Drive-In now open 
 foodie 02-19-2007, 03:33 PM Fellow Foodies--

Speaking of the best burgers and most diverse burger&quot;joints&quot;-- Sonic&apos;s Drive-In in Massaponax, Virginia Exit 126 below Fredericksburg&apos;s Central Park Exit has just officially opened. We took kiddos and ourselves South to Richmond this weekend to visit family and to shop at Short Pump Town Center.

On the return trip home, we stopped at Massaponax and ate dinner at Sonic&apos;s Drive-In. Below is web site--

www.sonicdrivein.com (www.sonicdrivein.com)(Sonic Drive-In web site.)

Great burgers, ice cream desserts, shakes, etc. Similar to Atlanta&apos;s Varsity restaurants.

www.thevarsity.com (www.thevarsity.com)(Varsity&apos;s web site.)

Give it a try for&quot;junk food&quot;-- yes, even food scientists sometimes eat&quot;unhealthy&quot;!

Foodie dcdavis 02-19-2007, 04:34 PM Foodie-

I understand the reason you compare Sonic with the Varisty, but I don&apos;t think there&apos;s any similarity at all. Sonic is a huge chain, with funny ads and good food.

The Varsity is an Atlanta claim-to-fame, somewhere you go to eat if you need 10 parts grease to 1 part food. Tastes pretty good, but also creates horrible digestive problems (for those of us with week stomachs). I see no comparison. No offense meant, just a thought (maybe I&apos;m too protective of my hometown unique spots).

Back on the topic of Sonic- I&apos;m still frustrated we don&apos;t have one closer - their food/shakes/TOTS (Napoleon, give me some of your tots!!). mdr227 02-19-2007, 05:38 PM Would love to have a Sonic up our way. Always love stopping by one in Williamsburg or Atlanta when we are down there. Winston 02-19-2007, 06:52 PM Since when is a fast food restaurant in Massaponax considered a restaurant or dining in the area? foodie 02-19-2007, 07:05 PM dcdavis, mdr227, rolltide, and others--

Yes, the Varsity and Jr. Varsity is&quot;greasy&quot;! My husband when he was attending Georgia Tech&apos;s Engineering School sometimes frequented the Varsity (not too often!) You could probably ask the Varsity for their leftover grease for your own&quot;fossil fuel&quot;for a biodiesel car. (Ha-Ha!!)

In response, to why I posted Sonic&apos;s NEW location, I did so because we ate at the one in Williamsburg beside Great Wolf Lodge. Great Wolf Lodge is great--we visited Great Wolf Lodge when they had the grand opening last Spring. Great place for family vacations!

Also, when people travel South on I-95 (as we all do at some time), it is considerate;) to let others know of places for quick and efficient food service. Also, at Massaponax, there are some NEW restaurants at Cosners Corner Shopping Center right off the exit ramp for travelers to dine.

Good eats--

Foodie brim 02-19-2007, 07:47 PM I just thought I&apos;d let everyone know there is a Zaxby&apos;s opening up near my house so if you&apos;re ever on US441 stop in, they have chicken comparable to Motons. We Love Disney 02-19-2007, 08:07 PM We loved Sonics - from burgers to fried cheesecake bites to jalepeno poppers it is indulging yet delicious! I remember I really liked the burgers. We ate at the one in Williamsburg too. It was so much fun to drive up and have a rollergirl bring our food to us. vacliff 02-19-2007, 10:14 PM I just thought I&apos;d let everyone know there is a Zaxby&apos;s opening up near my house so if you&apos;re ever on US441 stop in, they have chicken comparable to Motons.

Get out of here!!! Really!?!?!? And only twelve hours away???? I&apos;m there!!!! :) brim 02-19-2007, 10:23 PM You&apos;re in luck...it&apos;s only 7hr away!

I&apos;ll be sure to keep you all abreast of any other new eateries opening here. neilz 02-20-2007, 02:33 AM FWIW ... there was some blurb in the Pittsburgh papers a few weeks ago that two separate franchisees will be opening about 5 or 6 Sonics in the Pittsburgh area over the next 2 years .. hornerjo 02-20-2007, 08:49 AM We&apos;re trying to keep this forum to specifcally Ashburn/Metro area Restaurants, Dining and Food. Please keep that in mind for future topics.

Thanks,

John neilz 02-20-2007, 02:04 PM We&apos;re trying to keep this forum to specifcally Ashburn/Metro area Restaurants, Dining and Food. Please keep that in mind for future topics.

Thanks,

John

Ack ... sorry John !! To bring it back to Ashburn,

I loved dining at Bonefish ;) woopity 02-20-2007, 09:38 PM what&apos;s people opinion on this&quot;original steakhouse&quot;place? :D j/k foodie 03-23-2007, 11:41 PM Since some of you are wishing for Sonic&apos;s Drive-In to have&quot;closer&quot;locations--
we were at Sonic&apos;s in Massaponax (Exit 126--I think this the exit number.) today and the manager told us that over the next year, the franchises will open three to four new stores.

One will be at the Garrisonville Road exit, Fredericksburg (Central Park) exit, and also possibly one in Fairfax (did not say which area of Fairfax). If you venture to Massaponnax and wish for email coupons--I have some that I found online for FREE Sonic blasts, etc. Ask and I will provide web site where I found them.

We were at Ikea today and ate at Sonic&apos;s restaurant.

Foodie Winston 03-25-2007, 03:24 PM You were at IKEA, and drove all the way to Massaponax to go to Sonic? You must love that place. Are the burgers worth the gas $$$? foodie 03-25-2007, 05:09 PM Roll Tide--

Yep--you win first prize today! (Just Kidding--;) ). It is quite a&quot;haul&quot;from our farm where we reside.

No,&quot;big deal&quot;. We do not worry about the gas money.

Sonic&apos;s is pretty good--read the other opinions on this thread. If you travel I-95 South and are near Massaponax--give it a try.

Have a blessed Easter for you and your family--

Foodie vBulletin®v3.8.4, Copyright©2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
