<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003808" url="http://tenismeja.itb.ac.id/lang/idn/tempat-menarik-di-bandung/" time="2012-07-12-19:58" support="7" score="0.015356273092753323" bingtitle="Tempat Menarik di Bandung | UATM CUP 2012" webtitle="Tempat Menarik di Bandung | UATM CUP 2012">
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="203"/>
	<description>Sunday Morning at Gasibu Park. After having a party ... you need to drive with your own car there ... McDonald’s, American fast food restaurant mainly in Burger and ...</description>
	<body>
		UATM CUP 2012 Last Chance For Your Turn? GSG MAU RUNTUH Skip to content 
 Home Blog Download Hubungi Kami 
 
Tempat Menarik di Bandung
 
 Bandung adalah kota yang penuh dengan tempat wisata belanja maupun kuliner yang sangat lengkap dan sudah terkenal di mana-mana. Datang untuk ikut ITB OPEN XII tentu tidak lengkap tanpa memanfaatkan waktu luang dengan berjalan-jalan di kota Bandung. Untuk melihat objek2 menarik yang harus dikunjungi saat berada di Bandung, dapat dilihat di bawah ini. 

There are many activities that you can do in the city or outside the city. As Bandung highland is surrounded by a string of mountains, activities in the outskirt of the city are mainly mountain resorts, adventures and outdoor sports. In the city, you can have culinary activities (see the Eat section) as there are so many food varieties, shopping with many clothing outlets and distros (see the Buy section) or just hanging around.

 Saturday Night at Jalan Dago . Every Saturday night, teenagers and youngsters are hanging around at Jalan Dago. The street stretches from Holiday Inn Hotel in the south and a few blocks to the north until Simpang Dago . The street is crowded with modified cars with loud music. Don’t bring your own car if you don’t want to get stuck in a traffic jam. Just walk and watch these hip-hop youngsters. There are some cafes and chic restaurants in the street that you can sit in. Don’t forget to buy some grilled sweet or hot-chili corn that is sold at the street stalls. The party usually lasts until midnight. Sunday Morning at Gasibu Park . After having a party on Saturday night, wake up very early in the morning around 5-7AM. Go to Gasibu park at the front of the Gedung Sate complex and wear your sportswear. At the park, you can go jogging and do some stretching, and after you finish, food stalls are already waiting for you with a lot of food varieties. People’s favourites are dim sum ceker (a chicken foot cooked like a dim sum) and nasi liwet (a rice cooked with coconut milk and served with chicken and other vegetables). In the walking distance, there is a famous yoghurt drink cafe with a nice and relaxing setting at Jl Cisangkuy. Lembang trip . A trip to the north of Bandung cannot be missed. Rent a car and start to go at the very early in the morning to Lembang, an uphill resort city.
 On the way to Lembang, you can make a sidetrip to Bosscha , the only observatorium in Indonesia. Please make sure you have made a reservation and take a note on its opening hours. Continue your journey to Lembang and stop at one of the food stall that sells fresh milk . You can drink fresh milk with many flavours. The milk is really fresh. Go to the Mt. Tangkuban Perahu . Go circling around Kawah Ratu (Queen’s crater) to see the volcanic activity closely. There are other craters: Kawah Upas and Kawah Domas . Beware of the tourist hawkers who sell many things at unreasonably expensive prices. Continue the journey to Sari Ater , a hot water spring complex. On the way, there is a good Sundanese restaurant, named Sindang Reret , that you can stop by for your lunch. Sari Ater [18] is a resort with natural hot water spring pools, some recreation parks and healthy spas. Stay overnight and have a good dinner at their restaurant. On the way back to Bandung, take a stop at a street food stall and have some grilled‘ sweet corns or grilled ketan (sticky rice) while enjoying the view of the tea plantation. 
 Ram fighting : Villages around Bandung host ram fights on alternate Sundays. It’s a big event for locals who turn out in their hundreds to watch 5-minute bouts between prize fighter male sheep. Tournaments are held in purpose-built rings in outlying villages. Best to hire a motorbike/guide in Bandung who knows when and where the next tournament is on. Fahtur Gunawang is a local ram enthusiast and travel guide, tel 0062-81809878336 or email fahtur_gunawan@hotmail.com. Ram fighting is not a blood sport but animal lovers may be upset at the sight of the fights, which are organised and refereed rather like boxing matches. 

 Outdoor Activities 

 Alun-alun Bandung or city square. Alun-alun is the classical central core of the democratic city in Indonesia, since the 15th century. It is typically a square of grass field with 4 sides are the city major residence, pendopo (a place to meet between citizens and the government), a mosque and a prison. The grand mosque is still visible, though it has been renovated 7 times. Now, it has undergone a major renovation and expansion with two 81 m high minarets and a Taj Mahal interior design. The pendopo is also still there, behind a high wall. The prison has been transformed into a mall with one block is preserved as a museum, a cell block where Soekarno, the first president of Indonesia, spent some time in there. The major transition is that now alun-alun serves as an entertainment park, where shopping mall buildings are surrounding the square. Bandung Zoo , built in 1930.
Location: Jalan Kebun Binatang No. 6 Bandung 40132. Tel: (+62)-22-2502770. 

 

 

Mt. Tangkuban Perahu.

 

 

Tangkuban Perahu main crater

 

 

Tracking in Tangkuban Perahu area

 Mt. Tangkuban Perahu . You can see it at almost anywhere in Bandung, but it is not complete before you see its crater. If you’re in Bandung, take a look at the north side and find an unusual shape of mountain. The name itself comes from the local Legend of Sangkuriang (“Legenda Sangkuriang”) about a disobedient son who kicks his boat upside-down and then cursed into stone. Hence the name of this mountain. Tangkuban = flipped and perahu = boat mean the shape of the mountain looks like a flipped boat. It’s still an active volcanic mountain. The crater is reachable by car, though it is fun to do hiking to the top by foot from Lembang. Its elevation is 2084 m above the sea level and the path from Lembang is not too steep. At the crater, it is a touristic spot. Near the main crater is another amazing site,‘ Kawah Upas’ , where you stand between two big craters, left and right.
Location: northern side of Bandung, the closest city is Lembang.
Angkot route: St. Hall-Lembang. 

 More about Tangkuban Perahu 
When you reach Tangkuban Perahu, the first thing you’ll see (and most popular) is the main crater (Kawah Ratu). But don’t stop there! Many tourists miss this but it’s probably the best part of Tangkuban Perahu: Kawah Domas . A 30 min walk from Kawah Ratu, track 1.3km down to Kawah Domas to get upclose and personal with volcanic activity. K.Domas looks like hell on earth and it’s a must experience–bubbling mud, boiling hot water, and hissing sulphur vapor. You can smell the sulfur, watch the hot water springs very closely or even buy a boiled egg from the hot surface. Don’t forget, the hike up is as tiring as the way down so it’s best to avoid flip flops!

 Getting to Tangkuban Perahu 
From Bandung Indah Plaza (BIP), take an‘angkut’heading to“CAHEUM–LEDENG”. The angkut will stop you at Terminal Ledeng (IDR 3000). From the terminal, take a mini van or‘Elep’towards Subang and get down at Tangkuban Perahu (IDR 12000). From the entrance of Tangkuban Perahu, it’s another 4-5km hike up on a really bad road. I’ve been told you could hire‘motorcycle cabs’to bring you up though I have not verified that information. If you can ride a motorcycle, it’s a lot easier to rent one to get there.

 Juanda Forest Park or Dago Pakar . The official name is Taman Hutan Raya ir. H. Juanda . It is a forest park, serves as a water reservoir for the city. There are some interesting parks for children or to have a picnic there. There are also some old WW II caves during the Japanese era. Some people walk through the forest to reach Maribaya park in Lembang.
Location: at the end of Jalan Dago.
Angkot routes: Abd. Muis-Dago and followed by walking or take a ride by motorcycle. Punclut-Lembang Hiking trail. Started from Puncrut, Jalan Kiputih, North Bandung. 

 Factory Outlets 

During the quality inspection, some of the products might be rejected, or they may overrun the production quota. These residual products are sold with sisa export tags, because they were made for export, but couldn’t pass through. Some of these items have Grade A (best quality, but overrun product) or Grade B (export quality, but do not pass QC) qualities. Don’t be surprised to see made in Korea or made in Singapore in their tags. Sometimes you will see the original price, such as USD$65, but they sell it for Rp. 45.000,00 (US$ 4.50).

Enjoy bargain hunting! Take a careful inspection yourself. Check for below-standard/damaged items. Beware also for the fake products with branded name.}}

It was originally meant for export garment (textile) factories that open a store directly in their area so that they can sell with bargain prices. Since it was a big success, many factory outlets without the factory itself were opening in many places in the city, also with bargain price tags. To attract people, they decorated the store with many styles: the colonial style, an old Chinese dynasty, etc. Some stores even have a small food court.

Most of factory outlets are concentrated in Jl. Riau, Jl. Dago (Jl. Ir. H. Juanda) and around Jl.Sukajadi-Jl.Setiabudi area. Some of them are listed below:

 Factory outlets in Jl. Riau: Heritage ( inside an old historical building ), Cascade , Summit , Oasis , Metropolitan , Renaritti , Secret , Terminal Tas , Edward Forrer , Stamp . Factory outlets in Jl. Dago: Rich&amp;Famous , Coconel , Glamour , Blossom , Uptown ( also opens a cafe that sells good chicken noodle and famous for the strawberry juice ), Dago Stock Centre , M&amp;M , Justine . Around Jl.Sukajadi-Jl.Setiabudi: Rumah Mode (Jl. Setiabudi 41F), Diaz (Jl. Sederhana mostly shoes ). Other places: Batian (Jl. Otto Iskandardinata 535, you can find used and new items ), Stock Center (Jl. Sukarno Hatta), Cargo (Jl. Diponegoro), Cosmo (Jl. Pelajar Pejuang 45), The Big Price Cut ( The first factory outlet in Bandung ) (Jl. Aceh) 

 Distros (Distribution Outlets) 

Distros are a new phenomenon in Bandung where a shop sells stylish products that were made by local designers. They are served as a distribution store, because these local designers do not have their own marketing label yet. The products that are sold are books, indie label records, magazines and also other fashion products and accessories. After their products receive large attention, then they make their own clothing company. Now, there are more than 200 local brand names in Bandung. One thing that makes distros stand out from factory outlet is that distros come from individual designers and young entrepeneurs, while factory outlet products come from a garment factory.

 Note that now distros are getting famous in Indonesia. The local branded name with free and independent motivation has been shifted. Be careful when buying in distros as the prices are increasing to a level almost the same as at boutique shops. 

Some of Bandung distros: unkl347 , Jl. Trunojoyo 4, Invictus ,Jl.Pager gunung 13 and Jl.Trunojoyo 6 Ouval Research , Jl. Buah Batu 64, No Label , Jl. Sumatra 24, Blackjack , Jl. Trunojoyo, Screamous , Jl. Trunojoyo, Badger , Jl. Trunojoyo, Airplane ,”starseeker”,”oglea”,“Blankwear”Jl. Sultan Agung, Cosmic , Jl. Trunojoyo, Green Light , Bandung Indah Plaza Lt. 2 and Jl. Buah Batu, Temple , Jl. Dipatiukur, Skaters , Bandung Indah Plaza Lt. 2, Jl. Cihampelas and Jl. Raya Lembang, Black ID , Jl. Lombok and Paris Van Java Mall.

Eat

Bandung is a heaven for food lovers who enjoy new experiences. There are a lot of varieties, not only local cuisine but international ones. You can find any food you want for any kind of taste. Do note, that most eateries in Bandung focus on creating new variations, not making sure it tastes good.

Everybody has their own favourites. One page is not enough to list all food stalls, food courts, restaurants and cafes in Bandung. Here are some lists that are popular or have a long history.

 Local Delicacies 

 

 

Batagor

 Bakso Tahu / Siomay is a steamed meat with/without tofu. It is served with peanut paste, sweet soy sauce and a lime. It is suitable for a snack, eat at anytime. In almost all streets you can find somebody selling this food with a wheeled stall ( gerobak ). The popular place is called Siomay Pak Lili at Jl. Geger Kalong Girang that has sold this food for 15 years. Batagor is similar to bakso tahu/siomay but it is fried instead of being steamed. It is served similar with peanut paste and sweet soy sauce. Served also as a snack. Legends are Kingsley at Jl. Veteran, selling this food already for 28 years, Batagor Riri [23] at Jl. Burangrang 41 ( in front of the BCA building ), Batagor Haji Isan at Jl. Bojongloa, and Batagor Haji Darto at Pasar Simpang Dago. Martabak is a fried stuffed pancake. There are two types: sweet and savory. Sweet martabak is a thick pancake stuffed with chocolate/cheese/banana/sugar. The savory martabak is a thin fried pancake stuffed with eggs, some vegetables, mushrooms, chicken/beef. The most popular ones are Martabak Lodaya and Martabak San Fransisco at Jln. Lodaya. Another recommended place is Martabak Andir at Jln. Jendral Sudirman, near the Andir wet market. My personal favourite is the one filled with sweet corn and cheese. One more best martabak which should not be forgotten is Martabak Canada at Jalan Kebon Kawung near the gas station. Soto Bandung is a soup with beef meat, soy beans and some vegetables. The old food stalls selling this food is at Soto Ojolali , Jl. Cibadak ( near alun-alun ), since 1940s. Lotek is a mixed boiled vegetables, served with peanut paste and some chillies, similar to gado gado. The hotter the better. The famous place is Lotek Kalipah Apo , Jl. Kalipah Apo, every day 9AM-16PM. Have been selling this food for already 48 years. One plate is about Rp. 4500, very cheap. Mie Kocok is a noodle soup, served with beef foot, beef skin and tauge or mung bean sprout. If you don’t fancy with these parts of beef, then you can ask not to have it and you can still taste its appetite. The famous place is a street vendor, Mie Kocok SKM , at Jl. Sunda. Mie Ayam is a noodle soup served with chicken and it comes with a variety of toppings. The famous place is at Mie Naripan in Jl.Naripan, they serve varieties of good noodles there. Another good place is at Bakmi Mangkok Mas in Jl. Setiabudhi. Nasi Timbel is the famous Sundanese dish. It is a tube-shaped rice that has a distinguish flavour, because it is cooked inside a banana leaf. It is usually served with lalapan (raw vegetables), fried tofu&amp;tempe, fried chicken and chili paste. You can find this type of dish in most of Sundanese restaurants. The well-known timbel food stall is located nearby Istiqomah mosque . Another good place is at Nasi Timbel Dago at Jl. Dago. One plate cost about Rp. 20.000. Laksa Bandung is the famous old traditional dish. This dish is kind of chicken soup using coconut milk with turmeric for the stock, and in side is contains rice cake (cooked inside a banana leaf), bean sprout, vermicelli, shredded chicken and for the finishing is garnished with holly basil and Oncom Bandung the traditional fermented soy bean cake. The well-known Laksa vendor is located at the junction of Jl. Pungkur and Lengkong Pondok Laksa . Its cheap and very appetizing. One plate cost about Rp.7000 

 Legendary Eateries 

Have been around for years and still famous for their delicious food:

 Sate Kardjan , Jl. Pasirkaliki, every day 24h. Lamb satay speciality, since 1970. Try sate buntel (a grilled minced lamb meat), tongseng (lamb meat in a coconut milk soup), nasi goreng kambing (fried rice with lamb) or sate cempe (satay from 10 month old lamb). Bubur Ayam Mang Oyo , Jl. Sulanjana ( near Gasibu ) and several branches. It’s a chicken porridge. Nice for starting your day. Kedai Ma’Uneh , Jl. Terasana I No. 132 Pajajaran. It’s in an alley in front of Pajajaran sport complex. Delicious Sundanese food. Baso Lela , Jl. Awiligar, everyday open until 9 PM. It’s new but getting popular. It’s in the hill side of Bandung with a nice view to the city. Try yamien , a dried boiled noodle, mixed with soy sauce. There are sweet yamien and salt yamien. Try also chicken noodle and the strawberry juice as a dessert. Santosa , Jl. Aceh, everyday open from 5 PM until 9.30 PM. It’s a hawker with open air eating experience. Opened since’60s. Try the fried kway teow/noodle/rice. They are using a special wok to enhance the taste. Located opposite of the municipal office, near KONI Jabar dorm. 

 Chic Restaurants 

For those who want a breathtaking view, eat in a local Sundanese village or have romantic international cuisine. Don’t expect the taste to be half as good as the view and experience though.

 Kampung Daun , Jl Sersan Bajuri Km 4.7 No 88 Villa Trinity Complex ( you need to drive with your own car there ). Sundanese food. Designed with natural elements as you eat at a hut in the middle of padi field, small waterfall and river. At night it’s really amazing to walk along candlelit pathways. Eating out really means eating out here. Sierra Cafe&amp;Lounge , Jl. Bukit Pakar no 33. Located on the hill of Dago Pakar in Bandung, Sierra delivers a relaxing and indulging ambience with a breathtaking view of Bandung’s city light. International cuisines (Western, Japanese and Thailand). N Cafe , Jl. Sutra Duta Kencana II/11, Bandung. Balinese&amp;European cuisines, with great scenery surrounding really make u feel comfortable.Great Coffee comes with special brew, try our balinese fried duck speciality then you will never forget the taste. Kedai Nyonya Rumah , Jl. Naripan 92. Indonesian cuisines. The interior design is very relaxing, giving a nice eating experience. Tizis Restaurant , Jl. Kidang Pananjung 3. European dishes with homemade bread and pastries. A well-known expats place to dine. Atmosphere Cafe , Jl. Lengkong Besar No. 97, Tel. : (62)(22) 4262815. The Peak Resort Dining , Komplek Girandah Desa Karyawangi, Ciwaruga, Parongpong Bandung, Tel. (62)(22) 2705429 The Valley Bistro , Jl. Lembah Pakar Timur No. 28 (Dago) Bandung , Tel. (62)(22) 2531052. The View Restaurant , Jl Resort Dago Pakar Raya No. 28 Bandung, Tel. (62)(22) 2531198 , Fax (62)(22) 2531196 

 Sundanese Restaurants 

Sunda is the ethnic name of the local people living in West Java. Sundanese food has some distinctive features than other ethnics. It mainly consists of fried fish, pepes ikan (steamed fish in a banana leaf), raw vegetables and chili pastes. To try these type of foods, there are numerous Sundanese restaurants. Some with famous name has many branches in Bandung and the vicinity. Some of the popular ones are:

 Sindang Reret , Jl. Surapati No. 53, Tel. (+62)-22-2501474. The other branche is outside the city in the north: Jl. Raya Cikole Km.22 Lembang, Tel. (+62)-22-2786500. The good one is the branch restaurant (see the Lembang Trip ). Ponyo , Jl. Malabar 60, Tel. (+62)-22-7301477. There are many branches outside the city. AA Laksana , Jl. Soekarno Hatta 494, Tel. (+62)-22-7509303. There are 2 other branches: Jl. Jakarta 21 and Jl. Cihampelas 30. A big self-service eatery with long tables already filled with plates of food. Take what you want and ask the server to count the plates when finished. Ampera , The famous Sundanese restaurant in Bandung with cheap price and lot of branch. Can be found at Jl. Sukarno Hatta (Cigereleng), Jl. Sukarno Hatta (Sanggar Hurip), Jl. Sukarno Hatta (Metro), Jl. Pajajaran, Jl. Pungkur, Jl. Dewi Sartika (Kebon Kalapa), Jl. Taman Citarum, Kepatihan Plaza and Jl. Raya Lembang. Saung Kabayan , Jl. Dr. Djunjunan. Raja Sunda , Jl. Dr. Djunjunan. Sambel Cibiuk , Jl. Merak. Bumbu Desa , newer and more prestigious sundanese traditional restaurant, branch in Bandung can be located at Jl. Laswi No. 1, Tel. (62)(22) 7100539, Jl. Pasirkaliki No. 160, Tel. (62)(22) 4234330 and Rumah Mode Jl. Dr. Setiabudhi No. 41, Tel. (62)(22) 91147980. Ibu Haji Ciganea , famous sundanese food restaurant from Purwakarta, Bandung branch can be located at Jl. Lodaya No. 29, Tel. (62)(22) 7314291 

 

 Asian Restaurants 

 Coca Suki , Jl. Ir. H. Juanda (Dago) 173. A branch of Thailand restaurant Coca [24] . Hoka Hoka Bento , Jl. Merdeka 47 Tel.: (62)(22) 424 5494. Japanese Restaurant. Menu: ekkado, chicken katsu, sukiyaki, koori kon nyaku, shrimp ball, beef yakiniku, shabu-shabu, teriyaki, udon. Opening hours: 10.00–22.00. Price: approx. US$ 4/person. Other branch : Bandung Electronic Center 3rd Fl., Bandung Trade Center 3rd Fl., Istana Plaza 3rd Fl., Mall IITC Kopo GF., Borma Jl. Terusan Jakarta No. 53E, Metro Indah Mall GF., Kings Shopping Center 1, 4th Fl., Jl. Dr. Setiabudhi No. 61, Stasiun Bandung Jl. Kebon Kawung, Hero Jl. Buah Batu No. 237, Yogya Jl. Sunda No. 60 4th Fl. Hanamasa , Istana Plaza. Jl. PasirKaliki. Jl. Merdeka 39-41 Telp: (62)(22) 4204426. Japanese restaurant. Menu: yakiniku, shabu-shabu, robatayaki, beef, chicken, seafood. Opening hours: 11.00 AM to 10.00 PM. Price: approx. US$ 22/person. Sushi Tei , Jl.Sumatra No.9. Telp : (62) (22) 4223181 

 Western Restaurants 

 Glosis Restaurant at Cihampelas Walk (Ciwalk). Jl. Cihampelas, Bandung. Price: approx. US 8/person

 Cafe Venezia . Jl. Sukajadi 205, Bandung. Telp.: (62)(22) 2031277. Italian restaurant. Menu: pasta, pizza, fried chicken, salad, soup. Opening hours: 09.00–23.00. Price: approx. US$ 15/person. Nowadays the name has been changed to Vienna cafe&amp;resto which give more variative foods. Tony Roma’s Jl. Sumatra 1, Bandung 40000 West Java Tel: (62)(22) 422 4656. Fax: (62)(22) 422 4660. American Restaurant. Menu: ribs, steaks, soup, salad. Price: splurge. Sadewa Steak Near Pajajaran, 5 minutes from Airport, 10 minutes from Railway Station. Jl. Sadewa 24, Bandung. Specialize European Steak and Pasta, Unique menus, Cozy place. Open daily at 16.30–22.00. Price: approx. US$ 4/person. Canary . Jl. Ir. H. Juanda 28, Bandung. Tel.: (62)(22) 423 8928. International Restaurant. Menu: hamburger, steak, fried chicken, sate, soup, salad. Opening hours: 07.00–21.00. Price: approx. US$ 7/person. Pizza Hut , well known international brand for Pizza, there are a lot of it branch in Bandung such as in Bandung Indah Plaza GF, Mollis GF, Kings Shopping Center 2 GF, Bandung Supermall, Istana Plaza GF, Carrefour Kiaracondong, Jl. Dr. Setiabudhi, Jl. Buah Batu, Jl. Kopo Bihbul, Jl. Ir. H. Juanda. McDonald’s , American fast food restaurant mainly in Burger and Fried Chicken, you can find McD branch in Bandung at Bandung Indah Plaza GF, Premiere Plaza GF, Kings Shopping Center 2 GF, Kepatihan Plaza 3rd Fl, Istana Plaza Parking Ground, Istana Plaza 3rd Fl, Dago Boutique Apartment, Griya Jl. Buah Batu, Jl. Dr. Setiabudhi, Jl. Jendral Gatot Subroto. Delivery number: 14045. KFC , best brand for fried chicken, located at Jl. Pajajaran No. 68, Jl. Buah Batu No. 189B, Tel. (62)(22) 7321887, Jl. RE. Martadinata No. 72, Tel. (62)(22) 4261465, Jl. Sukarno Hatta No. 423, Tel. (62)(22) 7562076, Jl. Kepatihan No. 19A, Tel. (62)(22) 4208660, Bandung Supermall, Bandung Trade Center GF, Jl. Dr. Setiabudhi No. 169, Tel. (62)(22) 2017616, Jl. Merdeka No. 27, Jl. Ir. H. Juanda No. 40-42, Tel. (62)(22) 4218965, Jl. Kopo No. 599, Paris Van Java Mall GF, Metro Indah Mall GF, 

 Mexican Restaurants 

 Amigos Restaurant at Le’aries Garden Hotel. Jl. Terusan Pasteur Annex, Bandung. Telp: (62)(22) 200 5401 Fax: (62)(22) 200 7406 Price: approx. US 6/person

 Seafood Restaurants 

 Mustika Jaya Sari Jl. Ciumbuleuit No. 39, Bandung. Tel.: (62)(22) 203 8539. Menu: fish, prawn, crab, salad, fried chicken. Price: budget.

 Ice Cream and Pastry 

Food in Bandung does not stop at the restaurants/cafes. There are plenty of bakeries in the city that you can buy some pastries. Some of them have high popularities that you must take a queue even before the shop is open in the morning.

 Pastry 

 Sumber Hidangan , it is located at Jalan Braga 20, the colonial downtown of the city. The bakery was opened as Het Snoephuis (which means The Candy House) in 1929. The interior is still the same as it was. Breads and cookies’names are in Dutch, such as Zwieback,Roomsoes, Krentenbrood, Saucijzenbrood, Suiker hagelslaag. Its old-time ambience and original menu attracts tourists and long-time patrons, but the run-down premise and declining sophistication of its foods and services suggest a (losing) struggle to remain in business. Open daily from 0830-1900 (close on Sunday). Bawean Bakery , it is located at Jalan Bawean 4. Bawean Bakery was established in 1946 and its name was Sweetheart Bakery until they changed their name during the New Order regime. The new name is taken from the shop location in Jalan Bawean. Their specialties are all kind of cake that are baked using rum, like nougat rolls, brownies, and so on. By using this alcoholic ingredient, their cakes taste a bit bitter and can be kept until 6 days. Brussel’s Spring , it is located at Jalan Sumatera next to Exsport Station, bag store. It’s steaks and waffle ice creams are very tasteful and it’s a must try culinaire. The prices are quite expensive compared to local food, which range between 20,000 and 75,000. Kartika Sari , try the famous cake: pisang molen , a cake stuffed with banana. Very delicious.
There are 6 stores: Jl. Kebon Jukut 3C, Jl. Buah Batu 165A, Jl. H. Akbar, Jl. Kopo Sayati 111A, Jl. Terusan Jakarta 77E, Jl. Ir. H. Juanda (Dago). Brownies Kukus Amanda , Jl. Rancabolang 29, Jl. Lodaya 8, Jl. Purwakarta. Try brownies kukus , steamed brownies with melted chocolate inside. Soft and very delicious. It’s very popular that you might have to queue before it opens. Brownies Primarasa , Jl. Kemuning 20, Jl. Buah Batu 169A, and Jl. Peta 169. Its speciality is the chocolate brownies. Dunkin Donuts , Jl. Ir. H. Juanda No. 51, Bandung. Tel.: (62)(22) 4208617. Airport Hussein Sastranegara. Bakery chain. Menu: donuts, croissant, sandwich. Price: approx. US$ 3/person. Sus Merdeka , Jl. Merdeka ( in front of Bandung Indah Plaza ). Famous for its Choux/Puff pastry with rum butter filling. J.Co Donuts&amp;Coffee , domestic well known donuts shop with fascinating flavor, located at : Paris Van Java Mall GF, Istana Plaza GF, Bandung Supermall GF, Cihampelas Walk GF. 

 Ice cream 

 Braga Permai (formerly Maison Bogerijn), Jl Braga 58, Bandung 40111, Tel.: (62)(22)420 1831. Famous ice cream parlor in Bandung. Baskin and Robbins , Jl Sukajadi 232, Bandung 40153. Tel.: (62)(22) 203 8457. JL. RE Martadinata No. 225, Tel.: (62)(22) 720 8122. Jl. Gatot Subroto No. 289, Bandung 40273. Tel.: (62)(22) 910 1404. Istana Plaza, Jl. Pasir Kaliki 121-123 Bandung, Tel.: (62)(22) 6000403. [26] . Ice cream parlor. Rasa Bakery , visits Rasa bakery means visits one of best ice cream, place in Bandung. It is located at Jalan Tamblong which is intersected with Jalan Asia Afrika. The traditionally made ice cream’s prices ranged between 10000 to 20000 rupiah. I Scream for Ice Cream , Jl. Hariangbanga. 

Drink

As the sale of alcoholic drinks is to be banned at public restaurants (although you can find them in upscale public restaurants), it will be difficult to find liquor, except at bars, night clubs, hotels and 24-hour mini markets. However, drinking fresh icy yogurt or juice is very tempting, especially after spending a day in a hot sun. These are some famous drinking places to try:

 Yoghurt Cisangkuy , Jl. Cisangkuy ( near Gedung Sate complex ). It has many flavours of fresh yogurt with fresh fruits. Very suitable as a resting place after walking in the hot weather. Es Cendol Elizabeth , in front of the Elizabeth bag shop at Jl. Otto Iskandar Dinata and Jl. Cihampelas. Cendol is an Indonesian drink made with coconut and coconut milk, served with ice cubes and sweet brown sugar. Bandoengsche Melk Centrale (BMC) , Jl. Aceh 30, in an old Dutch colonial house. They specialize in fresh milk beverages. Rumah Kopi , Jl. Awiligar ( near baso Lela ). It literally means“coffee house”. They serve many kinds of coffee at cheap prices. Susu Segar Lembang , at many street vendors in Lembang. It is outside the city, but it would be nice to stop if you do a sidetrip to Lembang. Es Sekoteng Bungsu , Jl. Bungsu 29. Es sekoteng is a grated ice cube with avocado, young coconut and kolang-kaling (some local preserved fruit). 

For alcoholic drinks you can buy it in these stores:

 Dago 34 , Jl. Dago no. 34. Located in the heart of Dago. Warung Internasional , Jl. Dago. it located near Dago 34. Taurus , located near Alun-Alun, it’s easy to find 
 
2 Responses to Tempat Menarik di Bandung 

 Septiano G says: 26 April 2010 at 0:50 
mantap jef, pertamax!!
 Azharuddin says: 20 November 2011 at 20:29 
Cadangan ke Bandung pada 4hb-7hb Dec 2011….
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 Security Question: What is 11 + 15 ? Please leave these two fields as-is: IMPORTANT! To be able to proceed, you need to solve the following simple math (so we know that you are a human) :-) 
 
Download

 BAP UATM CUP 2012 Formulir Pendaftaran TPB Formulir Pendaftaran untuk Mahasiswa/ Umum/ Himpunan/ Unit Jadwal UATM CUP 2012 
 
Other Languages

 English Indonesian 
 

Visitors today: 1
Total Visitor : 10300 
Organized By :
 

 
   UATM CUP 2012 WordPress   WPCharity
	</body>
</document>
