<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003767" url="http://qmato.com/guide/missoula-mt" time="2012-07-12-19:55" support="1" score="0.001519829841827774" bingtitle="Missoula Restaurant Guide - Qmato" webtitle="Missoula Restaurant Guide - Qmato">
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>Enter an address or place name ... Fast counter service; Great for delivery; Tasty takeout ... it is slightly more expensive than a typical fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Missoula, MT 
 Address or place name (optional) 
 City, State, or ZIP Enter an address or place name 
 Find my current location No recent locations 
 
 
 Restaurant guide Qmato mobile Share Qmato 

 Sign in Join 
 
Missoula Restaurant Guide

 Change or specify location Find my current location 
   
Looking for a great place to eat?
 Meal Lunch Breakfast Brunch Lunch Dinner Late night Have a drink Coffee break Occasion Just to eat Just to eat Date Special occasion Eat outside Lively and fun Party Escape the ordinary Meal with kids Cuisine Any cuisine Any cuisine American Asian Austrian Bakery Bar Barbecue Breakfast Brewpub Buffet Burgers Cafe Cajun California Catering Chicken Chinese Coffee Continental Deli Diner Eclectic English Fast Food French Greek Grill Hot Dogs Ice Cream Irish Italian Japanese Korean Latin American Mexican Micro-Brewery Middle Eastern Miscellaneous Mongolian New American Pasta Pastries and Desserts Pizza Salads Sandwiches Seafood Smoothies Soup Southern Steak Tapas Tea Thai Vietnamese Wings   
 
 Change my restaurant preferences 
My saved places

 Save some restaurants to see them here! 
 
Explore

 Most popular Hidden gem Good food, good value Vegetarian friendly Gluten-free friendly Online reservations Browse all restaurants 
 × 
Choose an occasion
 
 
Just to eat 

 
Eat outside 

 
Escape the ordinary 

 

 
Date 

 
Lively and fun 

 
Meal with kids 

 

 
Special occasion 

 
Party 

 
 
Not dining in?
 Counter service 
 Delivery 
 Takeout 
 Catering 
 Cancel × 
Choose a cuisine
 
Top cuisines in Missoula
 
 Sandwiches American Breakfast 

 Pizza Mexican Chinese 

 Deli New American Asian 
 
All cuisines
 
 American Asian Austrian Bakery Bar Barbecue Breakfast Brewpub Buffet Burgers Cafe Cajun California Catering 

 Chicken Chinese Coffee Continental Deli Diner Eclectic English Fast Food French Greek Grill Hot Dogs Ice Cream 

 Irish Italian Japanese Korean Latin American Mexican Micro-Brewery Middle Eastern Miscellaneous Mongolian New American Pasta Pastries and Desserts Pizza 

 Salads Sandwiches Seafood Smoothies Soup Southern Steak Tapas Tea Thai Vietnamese Wings 
 Cancel Any cuisine 
Recent reviews
 
 Taco Sano 

 

Delicious and cheap
 For a couple bucks I just feasted on Pork tacos during their dollar taco hour. I can&apos;t believe how many topping choices there were. Undeniably the best deal in town and every day too. Written by TDJ 
 Honey Teriyaki Express 

 

Fast&amp;Inexpensive
 Honey Teriyaki doesn&apos;t offer dine-in, and it is slightly more expensive than a typical fast food restaurant, but it is definitely cheaper than regular Chinese restuarants. The food is comparable to… Written by miszler 
 Shack Restaurant 

 

Best Brunch in Town
 I love The Shack. They have wonderful omelets, and pancakes and the best banana bread french toast. No where else in town comes close. They have fresh squeezed orange juice and make great coffee. The… 
Recently viewed

 You&apos;ll see recently viewed restaurants here. 



Best of Missoula

 5 Saving… 
 Pearl Caf 

New American • $$$ $ 
 231 E Front Street 
Great for dinner.
 5 Saving… 
 Greek Gyros&amp;Pastry Shop 

Greek • $ $$$ 
 520 S 5th St W 
Great option for a meal with the kids.
 4.7 Saving… 
 Biga Pizza 

Pizza • $$ $$ 
 241 W Main St 
Great for a must-try experience.
 4.7 Saving… 
 Hob Nob On Higgins 

Breakfast • $ $$$ 
 531 S Higgins Ave 
Excellent for a delicious breakfast.
 4.6 Saving… 
 Hoagieville 

Deli
 2413 S Higgins Ave 
Very good as a hidden gem.
 4.3 Saving… 
 Worden&apos;s Wines 

Sandwiches • $ $$$ 
 451 N Higgins Ave 
Great place to have a drink.
 3.9 Saving… 
 Sawaddee Thai Restaurant 

Thai • $$ $$ 
 221 W Broadway St 
Very good for a delicious lunch.
 
 × 
Choose a cuisine…
 
 American Asian Austrian Bakery Bar Barbecue Breakfast Brewpub Buffet Burgers Cafe Cajun California Catering Chicken Chinese Coffee Continental 

 Deli Diner Eclectic English Fast Food French Greek Grill Hot Dogs Ice Cream Irish Italian Japanese Korean Latin American Mexican Micro-Brewery Middle Eastern 

 Miscellaneous Mongolian New American Pasta Pastries and Desserts Pizza Salads Sandwiches Seafood Smoothies Soup Southern Steak Tapas Tea Thai Vietnamese Wings 
 Cancel 
 Add a restaurant About Blog Mobile Contact Sitemap Terms and Privacy policy 

Copyright©2012 RestaurantDB.
 This page was served to you in 0.786 sec.
	</body>
</document>
