<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003118" url="http://mini-diner.com/ff.html" time="2012-07-12-19:14" support="1" score="0.00118202383790657" bingtitle="Drive Thru Fast Food Diner for Sale - New Diners and Restaurants ..." webtitle="Drive Thru Fast Food Diner for Sale">
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="40"/>
	<description>Drive-In Fast Food with 8 Car Canopy. All Diners have Steel Studs and Poured Concrete Floor • 22’ x 10’ • 220 square feet with 8 car drive-thru canopy attached</description>
	<body>
		Home Models 
 Kampground Diner Lil&apos; Deli Diner Drive Thru Coffee Shop Drive In Fast Food Hot Dog Stand 
 Brochure 
 Kampground Diner Lil&apos; Deli Diner Drive Thru Coffee Shop Drive In Fast Food Hot Dog Stand 
 Lease Financing 
 Diner Leasing Tax Benefits 
 Photo Gallery Contact Us 
 Email Google Map 
 
 
Fast Food Drive Thru Diner
 Today&apos;s greatest business opportunity for today&apos;s economy! 
 
 
 

 View Diner Floor Plan and Equipment 

 

The Fast Food Drive Thru diner is very similar in architectural design to that of the famous Sonic enterprise. The major difference is the COST to you! There are no franchise fees with our product and as you can see the square foot cost is much less than that of standard diner construction. Our design allows for a small real estate footprint enabling you to locate this facility in almost any geographic location nationally or internationally.

Please view the &quot;Floor Plan and Schematics&quot; to get the look and feel of our Fast Food Drive Thru concept. All of the diner equipment is included and the menu, operational hours, and company name are all up to you. We have made owning a small business easy with leasing available to qualified applicants.
 
 
 
 

In today&apos;s economy a Drive Thru diner is always in demand. It is always important to consider the&quot;up front&quot;cost involved when planning a franchise or conventional construction enterprise. Our design and product is the most&quot;cost effective&quot;start up in the diner industry and a definite solution to today&apos;s new global economy.

If you are searching for a great Fast Food Diner for sale we are offering the best deals in the United States. Our Diners can also be sold and shipped internationally upon request and please contact us for specific export requirements.
 
 30-160 seat Stainless Steel Diners Available (View Samples) (Visit Website) 

 

 Drive-In Fast Food with 8 Car Canopy 

All Diners have Steel Studs and Poured Concrete Floor


• 22’ x 10’
• 220 square feet with 8 car drive-thru canopy attached
• exterior = stainless steel with ceramic tile
• interior walls = grease-resistant
• 1 handicap unisex restroom
• canopy parking for 8 cars
• feature short-orders and wings
• Equipment package (same as Lil’ Deli Diner)
• dishwasher
• refrigerated sandwich unit/salad prep
• 24 inch grill
• exhaust hood
• deep fat fryer
• ice maker
• coffee maker
• toaster
• under-counter freezer/under-counter compact
• hotdog steamer
• food warmer
• coffee unit
• reach-in refrigerator
• 2 handicap restrooms
• drive-thru window on end
• PRICE = $179,500 


 Please Note: 

Prices, design, specifications, and equipment are subject to change. Please contact us for current information regarding these issues in the event anything has changed since the publication of this website and / or any printed documents, brochures, and advertising material.

 Diner Search Page 
 

 
 Fast Food Drive Thru and Diner Sales available in the United States, Territories, and United States Military Installations Globally 
   
 ALABAMA AL 
 ALASKA AK 
 AMERICAN SAMOA AS 
 ARIZONA AZ 
 ARKANSAS AR 
 CALIFORNIA CA 
 COLORADO CO 
 CONNECTICUT CT 
 DELAWARE DE 
 DISTRICT OF COLUMBIA DC 
 FEDERATED STATES OF MICRONESIA FM 
 FLORIDA FL 
 GEORGIA GA 
 GUAM GU 
 HAWAII HI 
 IDAHO ID 
 ILLINOIS IL 
 INDIANA IN 
 IOWA IA 
 
 KANSAS KS 
 KENTUCKY KY 
 LOUISIANA LA 
 MAINE ME 
MARSHALL ISLANDS MH
 MARYLAND MD 
 MASSACHUSETTS MA 
 MICHIGAN MI 
 MINNESOTA MN 
 MISSISSIPPI MS 
 MISSOURI MO 
 MONTANA MT 
 NEBRASKA NE 
 NEVADA NV 
 NEW HAMPSHIRE NH 
 NEW JERSEY NJ 
 NEW MEXICO NM 
 NEW YORK NY 
 NORTH CAROLINA NC 
 NORTH DAKOTA ND 
 NORTHERN MARIANA ISLANDS MP 
 
 OHIO OH 
 OKLAHOMA OK 
 OREGON OR 
PALAU PW
 PENNSYLVANIA PA 
 PUERTO RICO PR 
 RHODE ISLAND RI 
 SOUTH CAROLINA SC 
 SOUTH DAKOTA SD 
 TENNESSEE TN 
 TEXAS TX 
 UTAH UT 
 VERMONT VT 
VIRGIN ISLANDS VI
 VIRGINIA VA 
 WASHINGTON WA 
 WEST VIRGINIA WV 
 WISCONSIN WI 
 WYOMING WY 
 United States Military Sales 
 
 

 
 Atlanta Website Design by easy2afford.com
	</body>
</document>
