<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003067" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/f/43/4223/Milwaukee/Fast-Food-Places" time="2012-07-12-19:11" support="1" score="0.036474278229233666" bingtitle="Milwaukee Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Milwaukee Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="114"/>
	<description>Milwaukee Fast Food Places. Reviews from critics, food blogs and fellow diners.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Milwaukee » Fast Food 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Chicago Detroit Green Bay Indianapolis Los Angeles New York Windsor More... 
 
 Add Restaurant Milwaukee Fast Food Places 
 
Prices

 $$ Moderately priced (7) $ Cheap eats (281) 
 
Neighborhoods

 
 Greater Milwaukee 

 Brookfield (12) Burlington (6) Delafield (7) Germantown (11) Kenosha (42) Oconomowoc (11) Racine (7) Sturtevant (9) Waukesha (10) West Bend (15) 
 Show all 
 Milwaukee 

 Buchel Park (7) East Side (8) Enderis Park (6) Menomonee Falls (8) Wauwatosa (11) Zoo (7) 
 Show all 
 
Cuisines

 American (608) Bakery (161) Barbecue (64) Breakfast&amp;Brunch (205) Burgers (299) Chinese (189) Coffee (157) Desserts&amp;Ice Cream (159) Fast Food Greek (55) Italian (188) Mexican (225) Pizza (454) Pub Food (184) Sandwiches&amp;Subs (472) Seafood (140) Soups (105) Steakhouse (100) Tacos (68) Vegetarian (56) 
 Show all 
Features

 Cash Only (2) Delivery (3) Food Truck (1) Free Wi-Fi (7) Gluten-Free Frie... (1) Happy Hour (1) Kid Friendly (76) Late Night (14) Live Music (2) Outdoor Dining (12) Romantic (1) Sports Bar (1) Vegan Friendly (3) 
 Remove: Fast Food Sort: Best
| Alphabetical | Recently added Featured restaurants 
 Rosati&apos;s Pizza I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Kenosha - Pizza, Fast Food Rocky Rococo I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Town of Lake - Pizza, Fast Food 
 
 1 Kopp&apos;s Frozen Custard Stand... 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Brookfield - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 18880 W Bluemound Rd 2 Oakland Gyros 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ East Side - Fast Food, Greek 2867 N Oakland Ave 3 Big Star Drive In 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Kenosha - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1500 Washington Rd 4 Georgie Porgie&apos;s 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Oak Creek - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 9555 S Howell Ave 5 Gilles Frozen Custard Drive... 90% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Honey Creek Parkway - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 7515 W Blue Mound Rd 6 Oscar&apos;s Pub&amp;Grill 95% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Clark Square - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1712 W. Pierce St. 7 Sobelman&apos;s Eastside Grill 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ East Side - American, Burgers, Fast Food 1952 N. Farwell 8 Oscar&apos;s Frozen Custard 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Waukesha - Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 21165 E Moreland Blvd 9 Fuddruckers 78% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Brookfield - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 16065 W Bluemound Rd 10 Alphonso&apos;s Pizza 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Zoo - Fast Food, Italian, Pizza 1119 S. 108th St. 11 Five Guys Burgers and Fries... 84% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Delafield - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 2900 Golf Rd 12 Hefner&apos;s Custard 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Cedarburg - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food N71w5184 Columbia Rd 13 Pops Frozen Custard 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Menomonee Falls - Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food N87w16459 Appleton Ave 14 Speed Queen Bar-B-Q 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Avenues West - Barbecue, Fast Food 1130 W Walnut St 15 Murf&apos;s Frozen Custard 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Waukesha - Fast Food 1345 S West Ave 16 Sammy&apos;s Taste of Chicago 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Zoo - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 10534 W Greenfield Ave 17 Chipotle Mexican Grill 95% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Yankee Hill - Fast Food, Mexican 600 E Ogden Ave 18 Chick-fil-A 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Racine - Fast Food 5802 Durand Ave 19 Oscar&apos;s Frozen Custard 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ West View - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 2362 S 108th St 20 Major Goolsby&apos;s 84% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Westown - American, Burgers, Fast Food 340 W Kilbourn Ave 21 Moondance Cafe 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Franklin - American, Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs 7001 S. 27th Strret 22 Shirl&apos;s Drive In 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Kenosha - American, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 7943 Sheridan Rd 23 Dogg Haus 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Avenues West - Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 1633 W Wells St 24 Culver&apos;s 85% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Kenosha - American, Burgers, Fast Food 5220 Green Bay Rd 25 Culver&apos;s Frozen Custard 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Waukesha - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 840 W Sunset Dr. 26 Five Guys Burgers and Fries... 89% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Wauwatosa - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 2500 N. Mayfair Road, Unit 320 27 Five Guys Burgers and Fries... 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Pewaukee - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 1279 Capitol Dr 28 Subway 92% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Racine - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 6035 Durand Ave 29 Subway 94% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Muskego - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs S74W17021 Janesville Rd 30 Cousins Subs 93% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Oconomowoc - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 1380 Pabst Farms Cir 31 Chipotle Mexican Grill 83% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Brookfield - Fast Food, Mexican 15375 West Bluemound Road 32 Shirl&apos;s Frozen Custard... I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Kenosha - Burgers, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 7943 Sheridan Road 33 Breadsmith 88% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ East Side - Bakery, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food 2632 N Downer Ave 34 Harold&apos;s Chicken Shack 55 I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Grasslyn Manor - Fast Food 4138 N 56th St 35 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Waukesha - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 1120 Delafield St 36 Dairy Queen I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Kenosha - Fast Food 2707 22nd Ave 37 Dairy Queen I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Menomonee Falls - Fast Food N86w16326 Appleton Ave 38 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Menomonee Falls - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs W174N8662 Schneider Dr 39 Taco Bell I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Mukwonago - Fast Food, Mexican, Tacos 920 Greenwald Ct Ste 800 40 Dairy Queen 87% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Muskego - American, Desserts/Ice Cream, Fast Food S69W15459 Janesville Rd 41 Ron&apos;s Cozy Corner 76% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Oconomowoc - Fast Food W359n5920 Brown St 42 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ West Bend - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 1450 W Washington St 43 Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted... 75% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Wauwatosa - Fast Food, Pizza 2330 N 124th St 44 Honeybaked Ham Company I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Brookfield - Fast Food 17395 W Bluemound Rd 45 Subway 80% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ New Berlin - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 15415 W National Ave 46 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Wauwatosa - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs, Soups 2500 N Mayfair Rd 47 Five Guys Burgers and Fries... 71% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Milwaukee River Parkway - Burgers, Fast Food, Hot Dogs/Sausages 5650 N Port Washington Rd 48 Rocky Rococo I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Town of Lake - Fast Food, Pizza 4849 S Howell Ave 49 Subway I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ East Troy - Fast Food, Sandwiches/Subs 1946 Energy Dr 50 Jimmy John&apos;s Gourmet... I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Delafield - Fast Food 2738 Hillside Dr 
 « Previous Page
1 Next » 
Critic reviews

Fast Food

 March 2, 2012 Ron&apos;s Cozy Corner By Milwaukee Journal Sentinal There is the Wisconsinite&apos;s essential devotion to fish fry. And then there is the smelt-fry subculture. People who... Full review November 2, 2011 Dogg Haus By On Milwaukee On Milwaukee - 2011 Best Hot Dogs/Sausages Full review November 2, 2011 Kopp&apos;s Frozen Custard Stand (Brookfield) By On Milwaukee On Milwaukee - 2011 Best Frozen Treat Full review 
 
Blogger reviews

Fast Food

 June 4, 2012 Major Goolsby&apos;s By Road Tips Go to the corner of West 4th and Kilbourn and get a burger. But don&apos;t pass up the chance to look at an extensive collection of sports memorabilia. Full review October 21, 2009 Oakland Gyros By Road Tips The portions are huge - one gyro was a full meal in itself; and it was cheap - with a bottle of water, the total cost of the meal was under $6 bucks. Full review 
 
Diner reviews

Fast Food

 July 4, 2012 Sobelman&apos;s Eastside Grill Never go back by lisagcc12 ( 1 review ) You place your order at the counter and pay there, then you sit down and they give you your food. Ok.. I had the worst experience I have ever had. The man working was so angry and depressed it was very unpleasant. The service ruined my experience. I will never go back. The staff should maybe smile..a little bit. June 29, 2012 Oscar&apos;s Pub&amp;Grill Mobile review by FLueNT ( 1 review ) O Burger or nothing! June 16, 2012 Five Guys Burgers and Fries (Pewaukee) Great Burger Place by Tim Denehy ( 62 reviews ) WOW!! what a great burger place. Great ingrediants, huge portions. Clean 50&apos;s style ambiance, great music piped in! Super casual, super fast with friendly staff. You wont be disapointed 
 
Restaurant tweets

Fast Food

 about 1 hour ago Sobelman&apos;s Eastside Grill MILWAUKEE, It&apos;s Thursday! Do you know what that means? t.co/EFI0y9SM More tweets by TeamSobelman about 23 hours ago Five Guys Burgers and Fries (Bayshore Town Center) Attention Burlington, NC your new Five Guys is NOW OPEN! Find it at 106 Huffman Mill Road, Burlington, NC 27215. More tweets by Five_Guys about 23 hours ago Five Guys Burgers and Fries (Mayfair Mall) Attention Burlington, NC your new Five Guys is NOW OPEN! Find it at 106 Huffman Mill Road, Burlington, NC 27215. More tweets by Five_Guys 
 
 Add Restaurant Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
