<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003130" url="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/things-should-before-opening-pizza-place-18298.html" time="2012-07-12-19:16" support="4" score="0.004288583497120371" bingtitle="Things You Should Know Before Opening a Pizza Place | Small ..." webtitle="Things You Should Know Before Opening a Pizza Place | Small Business - Chron.com">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000799" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="23"/>
	<description>The pizza place sector is a competitive market with ... Things to Consider Before Opening a Fast Food Restaurant ... Planning the Exit Strategy; Business Plans: Exit ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. 
 Subscribe Subscriber Services Make a Payment MyChronRewards 
 Chron.com chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs Opinion 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Coupons 

 Index 
 Close [X] Quick links to the best of chron.com | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Recent Headlines 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths Hurricanes 9/11 anniversary 
 
 Ultimate Astros Rockets Texans Dynamo Colleges High school Golf Outdoors More sports 
 
 FuelFix.com Markets Houston stocks World markets Your portfolio Currency Small business Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain Sports Justice TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Nick Anderson cartoons Bill King columns Editorials Op-ed columns Letters to the editor 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 Small Business by Demand Media 
 Running a Business | Money&amp;Debt | Managing Employees | Finances&amp;Taxes | Accounting&amp;Bookkeeping | Setting Up a New Business | Business Models&amp;Organizational Structure | Types of Businesses to Start | More» 
 
 » Business Communications&amp;Etiquette » Human Resources » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Advertising&amp;Marketing » Business&amp;Workplace Regulations » Business Technology&amp;Customer Support 
 
 Small Business » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Successful Business Plans » Things You Should Know Before Opening a Pizza Place 
 
Things You Should Know Before Opening a Pizza Place
 by Andrew Latham, Demand Media 

 
Pizza places are one of America&apos;s favorite restaurants.

Jupiterimages/Comstock/Getty Images
 
 Related Articles 

 5 Things to Consider When Opening a Pizza Place Things to Know Before Opening a Wine Store The Requirements for Opening a Pizza Place Things You Should Know Before Opening a Frozen Yogurt Store What Do I Need to Know to Run a Pizza Place? Things I Should Find Out Before Opening a Retail Store 
 
Pizza restaurants are in high demand in the United States food-service industry. According to a May 2011 article in Entrepreneur magazine, among those born between 1980 and 2000, pizza restaurants are the second most popular restaurant, accounting for 12 percent of all their restaurant visits. However, this does not mean opening a pizza place is going to be a walk in the woods.
 
Prepare to Succeed

Careful planning is crucial for the success of any restaurant, but especially in a sector as competitive as pizza. According to an October 2009 article in Entrepreneur magazine, many restaurants fail in the first year, frequently because of lack of planning. However, the same article points out that this does not mean your business plan needs to be complex. On the contrary, the simpler and more streamlined it is, the better.
 
Focus on Your Target Audience

If you try and please everybody, you will end up pleasing nobody. The pizza place sector is a competitive market with hundreds of restaurants fighting for a slice of the market. Focus on a small section of the market, concentrate your energies on keeping them happy and forget about the rest. For example, you could follow the example of Naked Pizza, which focused on people who were interested in healthier fast food with no sugar, no trans fats and lower calories. Now Naked Pizza is a multinational franchise with more than 300 stores under development, as of 2011.
 
Legalities

Launching a pizza place requires a mountain of paperwork before you can hang your business sign. Although the specific legal requirements change depending on state and local governments, you will need an employer identification number from the IRS, a food service establishment permit, a business license from your planning department and a health permit, to mention a few. Ensure your paperwork is in order to avoid expensive delays. The U.S. Small Business Administration provides valuable guidance and information on the business licenses and permits you must apply for.
 
Food Safety

Food safety and sanitation should be a priority when you launch a pizza place. It certainly is the priority of your local food department. Your pizza place must meet strict health code standards to get a new retail food business license. Once you receive the license, you must maintain these standards. Although regulations vary, you will usually need to ensure all food handlers are certified by the health department and that you have a supervisor with a food service sanitation manager certification.
 
References

 &quot;Entrepreneur&quot;; A Pizza Franchisee Explains the Secrets Behind His Success; Jason Daley; May 2011 &quot;Entrepreneur&quot;; How to Start a Restaurant; October 2009 &quot;Entrepreneur&quot;; The Stripped Down Strategy Behind Naked Pizza; Fawn Fitter; August 2010 U.S. Small Business Administration: Business Licenses and Permits City of Chicago: Health Inspections 
 
Resources

 New York City Department of Health: Food Safety U.S. Small Business Administration 
 
About the Author

Andrew Latham has worked as a professional copywriter since 2005 and is the owner of LanguageVox, a Spanish and English language services provider. His work has been published in&quot;Property News&quot;and on the San Francisco Chronicle&apos;s website, SFGate. Latham holds a Bachelor of Science in English and a diploma in linguistics from Open University.
 
Photo Credits

 Jupiterimages/Comstock/Getty Images 
 
More Articles

 
Things to Know Before Opening a Restaurant
 
How to Build a Business at a Pizza Place
 
Things to Know Before Opening a Small Liquor Business
 
List of Things to Think of When Opening a Business
 
 
People Also Viewed

 Five Things You Need to Know When Analyzing Corporate Debt Things to Consider Before Opening a Fast Food Restaurant Top 5 Things Every Manager Should Know How to Set Up a Pizza Shop Eight Things Every Marketing Technologist Should Know How to Start a Godfather&apos;s Pizza Franchise 
 
Related Topics

 What Is the Importance of Contingency Planning in Strategy Evaluation Results? Planning the Exit Strategy Business Plans: Exit Strategy Examples of a Business Plan Exit Strategy Business-Plan Marketing Strategy 
 
 
The Web&apos;s 6 Most Influential Tech Bloggers
 
America&apos;s 9 Most Tech-Friendly Cities
 
Phone Pas: 9 Places You Should Pocket Your Cell Phone
 
10 Highest Valued Tech Companies
 
9 Gadgets You Can&apos;t Live Without
 
 Small Business Index Powered by Demand Media 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation&amp;World Business Sports Entertainment Life Corrections Blogs Weather 
 
 City Brights Traffic 

Topics

 Small Business MomHouston.com HoustonBelief.com 29-95.com 
 
Neighborhoods

 Aldine Alief Baytown Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair East End Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Coupons Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery iPad iPhone Android Mobile RSS Feeds e-Edition 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Houston Car Dealerships in Houston Cleaning Services in Houston Family Doctors in Houston Furniture Stores in Houston Injury Attorneys in Houston New Car Dealer in Houston Real Estate Agents in Houston Real Estate Attorneys in Houston Restaurants in Houston 
 
Services

 Help/Contact us Business directory Legal notices Privacy policy Terms&amp;Conditions Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad 
 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
 Hearst Newspapers RSS My Yahoo!
	</body>
</document>
