<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003795" url="http://eatocracy.cnn.com/2012/01/12/why-your-grandma-steals-sugar-packets/?hpt=hp_c2" time="2012-07-12-19:57" support="32" score="0.05415847497777745" bingtitle="Why your grandma swipes sugar packets – Eatocracy - CNN.com Blogs" webtitle="Why your grandma swipes sugar packetsEatocracy - CNN.com Blogs">
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001132" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000377" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="001232" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000406" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001241" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001028" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="29"/>
	<description>... ketchup slowly sinking into the passenger seat upholstery because you didn&apos;t take ... a bad person because I never throw my trash away at a fast-food restaurant but ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | TV&amp;Video | NewsPulse | U.S. | World | Politics | Justice | Entertainment | Tech | Health | Living | Travel | Opinion | iReport | Money | Sports 
 January 12th, 2012 04:00 PM ET 
Share this on:
 Twitter del.icio.us Share 
 Comments ( 772 comments ) Permalink Tweet Why your grandma swipes sugar packets 
If you build it, they will come. And if you put it on the table, chances are someone is going to take it.

This includes, but is certainly not limited to, condiment sachets, paper napkins, individual coffee creamers, cracker packets, and just about anything else “not wrapped for individual sale” that can easily be stuffed into purses and/or pockets without a single qualm.

Whether it’s your best friend, grandma, crazy uncle or maybe even yourself doing the lifting, evidence of the petty pilfering can be found in drawers and car glove boxes across the nation – each with their own little cache of restaurant and sugar caddy bounty.
 
Diane Merrits of Orlando, Florida, says she saves money this way. She hasn’t had to buy coffee creamer in years, takes extra ketchup packets at fast food restaurants and saves all the leftover condiment sachets when she orders delivery. She even washes and reuses plastic tableware because “it is good for the environment and better than wasting money.”

“It’s easy for some people to say – to rationalize – taking these items is not going to have an impact.&apos;No one is going to feel it if I take five Sweet N’Lows,&apos;” says Kristene Doyle, psychologist and the Executive Director of the Albert Ellis Institute .

For those people, it’s the restaurant&apos;s way of paying it forward.

“Although there is an unwritten understanding that condiments and small spices or ingredients for making the food served at restaurants more flavorful are there for limited use, some people choose to see this as an unpaid bonus of having come to the restaurant,” agrees Patricia Farrell, clinical psychologist and author of “How to Be Your Own Therapist.”

Farrell adds some of the caddy swipers might say to themselves, “It&apos;s there for me, isn&apos;t it? Why shouldn&apos;t I take it? If they only wanted me to have a little bit, why didn&apos;t they just put out a little bit?” - an example of what psychologists call attribution of responsibility.

“In other words, the person taking all of this stuff isn&apos;t responsible; it&apos;s the establishment&apos;s problem. They should have been more careful and it wouldn&apos;t have happened,” Farrell explains.

While every freebie opportunist has their own personal reasons for the habit, there are a couple non-pathological, generational factors as well: the current age of entitlement, and what has been identified as a Depression-era mindset.

Entitlement issues are especially prevalent in Generation X and Y (roughly defined as anyone born between 1964 and the mid-1990s), says Doyle.

“They’re used to being told they&apos;re perfect; they deserve what they want; they get what they want. It&apos;s the ‘if it’s there, I want it’ mentality,” Doyle explains.

On the other hand, the generation that experienced tough economic times, rationing and salvaging during the Depression and even up into World War II, learned to save, plan for possible need and prepare to be as resourceful as possible.

“From the Depression, it was&apos;we don’t have a lot, we might not have any in the future, I will gather it, hoard and reduce anxiety to ensure I’ll be OK,&apos;” says Doyle.

And while it&apos;s easy to label younger people with a sense of entitlement and the older generation with the belief they&quot;need&quot;these items, clinical psychologist Noel Goldberg adds that age isn&apos;t always a defining factor.

“If you grew up with parents from the Great Depression, or grandparents from the Great Depression, they can pass on this learned behavior just like folks who have to ‘clean their plate’ when they eat,” he clarifies. Same goes for people who grew up with tough socioeconomic backgrounds.

In very severe cases of this behavior, deeper psychological reasons like kleptomania, hoarding or obsessive-compulsive disorder could be afoot.

Those with kleptomania will experience&quot;an increasing tension or an irresistible urge prior to engaging in the behavior, followed by a feeling of pleasure, gratification, or relief during the behavior. It may also involve shame or guilt following the behavior,&quot;says Marla Deibler, clinical psychologist and the Director of The Center for Emotional Health of Greater Philadelphia.

 Hoarding , on the other hand, tends to be distorted belief about the value of items, adds Doyle. “People that are real hoarders have this excessive attachment to items that typically aren’t valuable.”

Goldberg further explains that for those with obsessive-compulsive tendencies, the anxiety relates to lack of control, so by hoarding, counting or keeping items, they somehow feel they are in more control over some type of anxiety.

Regardless of the reason, restaurant owners feel (and accommodate for) the expected pinch.

“As a restaurant operator, it is amazing to me how much of a negative financial impact every sugar packet, ketchup packet that leaves the building unaccounted for affects our bottom line,” says Nick Pihakis, CEO of Jim&apos;N Nick&apos;s Bar-B-Q .

“Our table condiments account for about 1% of our total supply cost. I know this sounds unbelievable, but that equates to about $900,000 on an annual basis. As crazy as it may sound, we continue to stock our tables, for our guests, with these bits of convenience or opportunity, however you look at it.”

Like Pihakis, usually the business owner takes this standard of practice into account when budgeting and pricing items that are purchased.

As for the psychological takeaway, Deibler says, “The question is, where is the line drawn? Stealing a cracker, a pack of sugar, a salt shaker, a plate, or something larger and of more value? You decide.”
 Take Our Poll 
Share this:
 
 Share 
 
 Digg Email Reddit StumbleUpon Print Tumblr LinkedIn 
 
 Posted by: Sarah LeTrent -- Eatocracy associate editor 
 Filed under: Bite    Culture    Etiquette    Favorites 
 
 
We recommend
 
From around the web
 Next entry» Coffee klatsch «Previous entry Box lunch: Barbecue quilts and celery cynics 
sound off (772 Responses) 

 Glenna 

I only take the few extra napkins because I think it would be unsanitary to put back for others to use. I do ask for extra cream because I like to drink some, after I drink coffee. it is only a thimble full
 January 25, 2012 at 9:34 pm | judy 

My husband likes to take stuff and stockpile it. I hate the way it ends up unused, taking up space in the fridge and glove compartment and other places he stashes stuff. I end up having to throw it out after a suitable time. At one time he had 6 plastic bags full of paper napkins from public places. His parents complained throughout the 1950s about how poor they were, so I guess he learned it even though they were successful later.
 January 25, 2012 at 11:01 am | Shig 

I take every packet of ketchup I can get from McDonalds...even though I only want a single honey mustard for my fries, they want to charge you for that so in anger I take as much of the free ketchup as they&apos;ll give me. It&apos;s petty....sometimes I&apos;m petty....
 January 24, 2012 at 11:29 am | DJE 

I don&apos;t take extras from restaurants, but I know which restaurants always send gobs with take out. Not that it is the deciding factor in where I order food, but I like to take the extras to work, for those days that last night&apos;s leftovers need a little boost to be palatable.
 January 23, 2012 at 5:10 pm | Paul 

I remember back some 20 years going to a restaurant in Florida with my wife. There was absolutely nothing on the table–no salt and pepper shakers, no sugar-nothing. We asked the waitress and she informed me that elderly women will take just about anything that will fit in their purse and that includes silverware. They used to put out those small lobster forks and would lose about 30 a week. To me, it&apos;s just plain theft. If the people that do this are so hard up then what are they doing in a restaurant anyway? Eat at home and save $$$.
 January 23, 2012 at 10:35 am | MrsMO 

The only time I do this is when I defininately know that because it was handled by me ie..lil jelly packs they put right on the toast.
 January 22, 2012 at 4:55 pm | Chris 

Me, and I&apos;d assume a lot of people, take extra packets from restaurants (example, Taco Bell) to use at home when the restaurant fails to give you said items when going through the drive-thru. Taco Bell is notoriously bad about doling out sauce packets in their drive-thru, even when specifically asked, so I have zero problem having a few dozen at home to use when they screw up.
 January 20, 2012 at 10:55 pm | 
 Carol 

I only take what they put on my table and I don&apos;t use at the time because I understand that if it&apos;s not used they will throw it away. Mostly just napkins. I leave the little creamer cups if I didn&apos;t use them because they are not open and can be reused.
 January 22, 2012 at 1:55 pm | 
 John 

No, I don&apos;t take stuff intentionally, for use at home. What happens is, as I am going out of a restaurant or coffee shop that has napkins or condiments in self-serve bins is that I will grab some to use with whatever I have bought. Sometimes, I don&apos;t grab enough and other times I may have grabbed one or two more than I need. I will use them at work or at home later, if I have them around, but I don&apos;t go out of my way to take them intentionally. I think that is stealing if you intentionally grab a handful of condiments with the intent of takinging them for later use. I am not too poor or&quot;thrifty&quot;to need to take condiment packets or napkins from someone else. If I have an extra or two I will use them so they don&apos;t go to waste.
 January 20, 2012 at 1:16 pm | Snake-Eyes w Timber 

I tend to swipe Raw Sugar packets from Panera Bread. Goes great with unsweetended ice tea or water, don&apos;t mix. When you sip with a straw, is like tasting candy.
 January 19, 2012 at 1:26 pm | 
 Snake Man 

&quot;I&apos;m a snnnnaaaake in your garden.&quot;
 January 19, 2012 at 1:34 pm | 
 lorena 

i do, but mainly because i know they will be thrown away once&apos;touched&apos;.... cant be put back... so instead of throwing them away, im at least using them.
 January 18, 2012 at 9:09 pm | 
 Sarah, Northern Colorado 

Actually, if the packet&apos;s closed, it hasn&apos;t been touched and it is normally put back out. If it&apos;s a napkin, that&apos;s a different story, but condiments are generally considered untouched until opened.
 January 19, 2012 at 11:45 am | 
 under 50 

&quot;Entitlement issues are especially prevalent in Generation X and Y (roughly defined as anyone born between 1964 and the mid-1990s), says Doyle.

“They’re used to being told they&apos;re perfect; they deserve what they want; they get what they want. It&apos;s the ‘if it’s there, I want it’ mentality,” Doyle explains&quot;

What an absolutely ridiculous thing to say–and the kind of thing&quot;old&quot;people say about&quot;young&quot;people generation after generation. How many millions of people were born during this time? Born in 1967, I was never told I was&quot;perfect&quot;, have never felt as if I were, and I don&apos;t freaking ever take extra packets of anything, or feel entitled for anything. I would like to slap Mr Doyle in his fat, generalizing face.
 January 18, 2012 at 12:24 pm | 
 Uninformed Elder Stooge 

You, my dearie, have got to be kidding....
yous is the most entitled and self-entitled generation to ever walk this Earth.
 January 19, 2012 at 2:30 am | 
 Under 30, Current Med Student 

Uninformed Elder Stooge,

I don&apos;t believe Under 50 was referring to the generation as a whole, but just as herself as an individual. As a whole of the generation, I completely agree with you. My generation is the most self-entitled, self-serving generation that I have ever seen, but that does come down to how they were raised and what they were given as they grew up.

I, like Under 50, was never told I was perfect, told to appreciate what I had, the value of hard work and doing things yourself. My parents work in the construction and dairy industries, neither have a college degree. I paid my own way through college and worked my rear off to make into to medical school, all because my parents told me I could do anything if I worked for it, not that I deserved it. I do resent that I get lumped into the same sentiment of self-entitlement and laziness of these generations just because I was born in that time frame. My parents taught me my work ethic, my humanity, and my caring and selflessness towards others and I plan on teaching those same values to my children. I have more practical skills with automobiles and construction/home maintenance than quite a few people even know existed, all because I asked to be taught it so I could work at it own my own and not think that it was someone else&apos;s job to do.

I&apos;m not attacking you, I&apos;m just tired of the thought that all of us are bad apples. Not all of us are self-entitled brats, there are some of us who do appreciate what we have and work hard for it.
 January 19, 2012 at 9:29 am | VET 

Oh please. Even my father (born in 1960) believes his generation–the baby boomers–are easily the most selfish generation to ever walk this earth. The older generation loves using the money and resources of future generations to support their big Buicks and Social Security checks. Give us a break. We&apos;ll be paying for your debts.
 January 23, 2012 at 4:13 pm | 
 sdfa 

i was born gen x and think our entire generation (especially in the US and other well off countries) feels too entitled. everyones feels like the world owes them something, some kids and people my age throw away golden opportunities that others would kill for because they think theyre better than that. theres nothing wrong with dreaming big but there is a difference between dreaming big and dreaming unrealistically.

i feel like a lot of this is because of the MTV generation with idiotic shows like my sweet 16 that exposes impressionable teenagers to spoiled behavior that is tolerated by their parents and the viewing public.

i do tend to take extra napkins when i get takeout or take extra splenda from starbucks when i get coffee but i dont want to run out of napkins if im eating or have my coffee too bitter so i guess thats my excuse.
 January 20, 2012 at 10:33 pm | 
 Burbank 

If restaurant owners want to get rid of this problem then go back to filling ketchup bottles, sugar dispensers and creamers instead of polluting the environment with wastefullly packaged condiments.
 January 18, 2012 at 12:22 pm | 
 AMEN! 

Couldn&apos;t have said it better myself. In the long run, it will hopefully reduce the cost to the public as well and everybody wins!
 January 19, 2012 at 11:18 am | VET 

YES!
 January 23, 2012 at 4:02 pm | 
 mrhapiguy 

I&apos;ll ask for a few ketchups at the drive-thru (or taco sauces) and the worker inevitably hands me a huge pile. I hate that.
 January 16, 2012 at 8:38 pm | Mel 

I&apos;ll save extra plasticware that is delivered or if we accidentally grab too many napkins or condiments and they&apos;ll end up getting thrown away when I leave, I&apos;ll take those with me instead of wasting them. I do not take extra with the intention of taking them out of the restaurant, but I have two young children who are old enough to get their own things but still young enough that they overestimate how much is needed.
 January 16, 2012 at 11:40 am | CN Red 

Nope don&apos;t do it. Usually the stuff in the packets are loaded with corn syrup and the bottom of the barrel junk.
 January 16, 2012 at 9:10 am | 
 CT 

Much like the food that you happily paid for and ate.
 January 19, 2012 at 2:01 am | 
 JPX 

I haven&apos;t paid for Splenda for YEARS
 January 16, 2012 at 8:08 am | 
 Bernadette 

me either! My dad was a depression child...he would bring toilet paper and window cleaner home from the power plants he worked at! But was mortified when I told him how I waited for the big and bulky trash clean up and go to the richer neighborhoods to see if there was anything good in their pile of trash.
 January 19, 2012 at 5:43 pm | 
 Arthur 

If it is a take-out, I will take only what I know that I will be will be using. The staff very often will try to give you more. I occassionally take the plastic table wear that I have used and know must be thrown away due to health laws. If I want to know where I have been, while traveling, I will often take one sugar packet. That is expected advertising.
 January 16, 2012 at 12:56 am | JR 

I take what I&apos;m going to use, and most of the time when it&apos;s given to me spotaneously, they give too much. I don&apos;t want the plasticware and all of that. Chinese restaurants are the worse. I MIGHT use part of one packet of soy sauce, they&apos;re throw in ten, plus the same with Chinese mustard, which I never use.

As to eating in house, I never take anything extra.

The Depression era people, them I understand. Not the ones that empty the sugar packets, but the ones that doggy bag everything on their plate, including the extra rolls. If you know anything at all about that time, you&apos;d know that wiht 25% unemployment and other horrible economic conditions, doing without wasn&apos;t a short term thing. And yes, they save everything, reuse everything, like washing ziplock bags until the writing wears off. On one hand it&apos;s crazy making if you have a close relationship with one of them. On the other hand, we didn&apos;t live through that experience which I&apos;m sure was traumatic as hell.

I understand Granny but I don&apos;t understand the young ones. They didn&apos;t go through that. They&apos;ve pretty much had everything handed to them in spades, so why act like they&apos;re deprived when they&apos;re most obviously not?
 January 16, 2012 at 12:44 am | 
 66Biker 

We reuse zip lock bags in our house too, but not because we are poor. We do it because the Earth has limited resources and everyone should do their part. Reduce, Reuse and Recycle isn&apos;t just a trendy phrase. It&apos;s a way of life to sustain life.
 January 16, 2012 at 1:47 am | 
 Benji 

Save yourself the time and get off your high horse. Those same plastic bags are still going to end up at the garbage dump. Plastic is not a renewable/ biodegradable resource so stop patting yourself on the back
 January 16, 2012 at 4:52 pm | Nick 

Sweet. Not a bad idea.
 January 16, 2012 at 11:32 pm | 
 jdizz 

Why is it crazy? It is only your perception and most Americans WASTE WASTE WASTE. If more people saved items and reused items, there wouldn&apos;t be so much need for material waste. These items are not finite for the most part, and you can certainly save money. And that is a big generalization, many of us, who are in fact education grew up POOR and definitely always finished everything on the plate, used leftovers, recycled compost, etc. I think it is a bigger issue of people being disconnected from the land and having everything at their convenience, they don&apos;t understand what into producing these items.
 January 17, 2012 at 5:09 pm | Connor Dicken 

A lot of young people (myself included) grew up with parents with those old sentiments. My great-grandmother is notorious for stockpiling canned goods and non-perishables, she not only lived through the Depression but the Fuel Crisis in the 70&apos;s left her and my grandmother broke and homeless. They passed that onto my and my mother, and, I shamlessly take a few (between one and three) packets from these places if they give it to me, but if it&apos;s on the table, one&apos;s the limit. Restaurants have to make money too...

Regardless, a lot of young people act from the experiences of their parents, and, honestly, it&apos;s not a bad idea. Just don&apos;t over-do it.
 January 23, 2012 at 11:48 am | Connor Dicken 

A lot of young people (myself included) grew up with parents with those old sentiments. My great-grandmother is notorious for stockpiling canned goods and non-perishables, she not only lived through the Depression but the Fuel Crisis in the 70&apos;s left her and my grandmother broke and homeless. They passed that onto my and my mother, and, I shamelessly take a few (between one and three) packets from these places if they give it to me, but if it&apos;s on the table, one&apos;s the limit. Restaurants have to make money too...

Regardless, a lot of young people act from the experiences of their parents, and, honestly, it&apos;s not a bad idea. Just don&apos;t over-do it.
 January 23, 2012 at 11:48 am | Glenna 

I rewash my baggies. I use dish soap and bleach and let dry. And, it is not because I am poor. I find it wasteful to throw away a baggie after one use. I also wash plastic throw away plates and glasses, lol, so much for saving on labor.
 January 25, 2012 at 9:43 pm | 
 Allie 

I swipe the peppermints that they always seem to have at the front of restaurants, not because my parents taught me to (they didn&apos;t), but because I like to eat spicy food. Peppermint makes your mouth stop burning. Water doesn&apos;t really work, and sometimes I want to enjoy food without my mouth feeling like it&apos;s on fire for the rest of the evening.
 January 15, 2012 at 9:08 pm | 
 Allie 

Why is CNN&quot;moderating&quot;my comment? It&apos;s about peppermints making my mouth burn. It&apos;s not taboo.
 January 15, 2012 at 9:12 pm | 
 czerendipity 

Right because Europeans are perfect and sooooo much better than everyone else.
 January 15, 2012 at 8:35 pm | 
 British Girl 

Wow. Someone has issues.
 January 16, 2012 at 9:26 am | Hey, you! 

AND...
They have AWESOME accents. Just saying.
 January 20, 2012 at 7:36 pm | 
 pockaleelee 

I gave up almost all fast food years ago, learned to cook, and found it much cheaper and better tasting to eat at home. BUT, when I occasionally go to Wendy&apos;s for a burger or baked potato, I always ask for extra Honey mustard and I have no idea why.
 January 15, 2012 at 8:34 pm | bluejay 

I take extra flavored coffee creamers from Chic-Fil-A because I love them and screw everyone else. Tragedy of the commons. If it makes a difference to the self-righteous d-bags, I always use them within a few days; I don&apos;t have some disturbingly huge cache of coffee creamers.
 January 15, 2012 at 5:01 pm | 
 Soapy 

Do you have the same sense of entitlement at the bank, too? It&apos;s there for you to use in the restaurant, not to steal. But you&apos;ve already said,&quot;Screw everybody else.&quot;I feel your pain, man.
 January 15, 2012 at 5:44 pm | 
 turtlemom 

No, i don&apos;t take stuff, and I won&apos;t let my kids take more than one piece of candy at restaurants and halloween either! RUDE! All you have to do is turn it around and ask yourself how you would feel if someone did it to you. Why is this so hard to understand... and I am gen X! This behavior is a result of families with no empathy, bad values and morals, not a generational thing.
 January 15, 2012 at 4:42 pm | Jack M 

This causes restaurants to raise prices because of greedy people who always have to take more than they need. This can also be used as a metaphor to explain why socialized medicine will never work because Americans are too greedy. In Europe, when people go to a restaurant they take only as much napkins, ketchup, sugar, etc. as they need and no more.
 January 15, 2012 at 2:32 pm | 
 max 

the whole concept of one napkin with my big mac is silly. when in europe i ask for more with my meal (they dont leave the dispensers out) and usually get a dirty look. outside of fast food I havent noticed a whole lot of difference between europe and US table set-ups
 January 16, 2012 at 1:33 pm | 
 Mark G. 

In many fast food restaurants, they toss handfuls in your bag. I often throw them away afterwards.
 January 15, 2012 at 2:17 pm | 
 scooterdie 

I agree. Everytime I go to McDonalds I have to pay for my extra McChicken Sauce packets (maybe only in Canada), but I love my french fries dipped in it. I get home, no sauce half the time but a dozen packets of ketchup. What the heck??
 January 15, 2012 at 6:32 pm | 
 John G. 

I take more soy sauce packets than I need that day because you can&apos;t find that brand anywhere else, and it&apos;s my favorite. I&apos;ve looked and I only found a 5 gallon container of it... which I am considering buying though. I don&apos;t use a lot of sauces generally, so what I don&apos;t use on duck sauce, I make up on my soy. When I have unused napkins, I don&apos;t throw them out, but put them in my car, but I don&apos;t grab too many on purpose.
 January 15, 2012 at 12:52 pm | Alix 

If the waitstaff gives me more napkins that I can use, I&apos;ll usually take the rest home. They&apos;re not going to give those napkins to another table - they&apos;ll just get thrown away otherwise, and I can use them at another time.
 January 15, 2012 at 12:35 pm | GuerraT 

I have taken ketchup packets when they have put more than we used either on the tray or in the take-out bag. I also use the extra napkins. I don&apos;t go out of my way to take these items, but when I find I have extras (usually 1 or 2) then I will take them if I think I have a use for them. With two little ones, having extra napkins in my vehicle comes in very handy!
 January 15, 2012 at 12:24 pm | SHANIQUA KIKIWIWI 

Now you must admit that Whataburger ketchup only works with Whataburger fries, so there is no sense in hoarding those packets for other uses!
 January 15, 2012 at 10:56 am | 
 LaSquisha BootyLicious 

I just LOVE Whataburger...a #2 with cheese and fries, plus a Big Dr Pepper. Ain&apos;t Nothin&apos;Better.
 January 15, 2012 at 12:04 pm | Marlo 

Oohh that dang Whataburger ketchup... why is it SO good??! I have always have to ask for extra from there
 January 15, 2012 at 10:31 pm | 
 lorena 

less than $10 to make... taste just like whataburger....
Ingredients

1 (6 ounce) can tomato paste
2 tablespoons white vinegar
5 tablespoons brown sugar
1 teaspoon garlic powder
1 teaspoon onion powder
1/4 teaspoon allspice
1 teaspoon salt
1 teaspoon molasses
1 tablespoon corn syrup
1 1/4 cups water
Directions

Mix together the tomato paste, white vinegar, brown sugar, garlic powder, onion powder, allspice, salt, molasses, corn syrup, and water in a saucepan over low heat; simmer gently until you get the consistency of ketchup, 45 minutes to 1 hour. Taste and adjust salt if necessary before serving.
 January 18, 2012 at 9:21 pm | 
 Hey, you! 

I&apos;m totally lost... What&apos;s a Whataburger?
 January 20, 2012 at 7:38 pm | 
 pepette 

It drives me nuts to walk or drive away from fast food places&amp;find packets of ketchup at the bottom of the bag–usually an obscene # of them, too. I don&apos;t even like ketchup–so why don&apos;t they have a policy to just ask if you want them?
Veering off the ketchup subject, I knew a girl who pocketed toilet paper rolls from establishments–she had an endless supply and she never thought this was stealing. Needless to say, she was not allowed in my apt.
 January 15, 2012 at 10:46 am | Paul 

I don&apos;t go out of my way to take extras. I do however keep any extras that arrive in my take out. I usually end up using most of them. SO, I don&apos;t have a big drawer full of mustard somewhere. Every so often I&apos;ll throw out everything just because it may be getting a bit old.

I do take all the soaps and shampoo&apos;s from the hotels though, hehe.
 January 15, 2012 at 10:06 am | David 

I used to operate a small plane around the islands and we placed 18 lifejackets in the back of the plane. After the first day 14 were gone. The passengers, all islanders, felt that the lifejackets were&apos;paid for&apos;and they wanted them for their boats. Sugar packets? Big deal.
 January 15, 2012 at 7:10 am | moribundman 

I only pinch silverware.
 January 15, 2012 at 4:33 am | anonymous 

Are you people that destitute that you cant afford a regular thing of ketchup or sugar from the grocery store?? Cmon really.
 January 15, 2012 at 1:21 am | alice 

I don&apos;t mind about the theft of sachets. I don&apos;t take them myself, but I understand the hoarding instincts of those who do. But I do draw the line at glass salt and pepper shakers and silverware. When I was a waitress I was amazed at the number of customers in a nice restaurant who stole knives and forks, salt and pepper shakers, napkins...even dinner plates and stemware. I don&apos;t see how that&apos;s anything but theft, but you&apos;d see well dressed, respectable looking women slip all sorts of tableware in their purses, even though you knew they couldn&apos;t sell any of it and they didn&apos;t need that basic metal fork or diner-style salt shaker at all.
 January 14, 2012 at 10:29 pm | Nancy 

What about those people, like some of my relatives, who use 1/2 packet of something and insist on bringing the other 1/2 packet home, where rather than being used, it languishes in a kitchen drawer or cabinet with 100s of similarly 1/2-used packets? This psychology is beyond me!
 January 14, 2012 at 10:22 pm | 
 Annie 

Nancy, I know what you mean! My father is guilty of this practice and he&apos;ll usually leave the 1/2 packets of sweet n&apos;low in pockets, on tables, counter tops... my mom usually finds the ones left in pockets as she&apos;s moving wet laundry from the washer to the drier and finds the saccharin-based goo all over cleaned garments.. I, too, do not comprehend this practice of bringing 1/2 of used packets home from a restaurant! :)
 January 16, 2012 at 12:59 am | Hey, you! 

That only works with, like, huge packets of stevia, because you&apos;ve got to admit, it you use the entire thing, your tongue comes out of the deal still tasting like you dived face-first into a highly concentrated sugar avalanche. But that&apos;s only if you already have it at home...
 January 20, 2012 at 7:44 pm | 
 For a Reason 

Yes, I will take the leftover napkins and condiment packs. These items will be thrown away at a fast food restaurant or bussed at a sit down restaurant because they have been&quot;used&quot;or handled by someone other than a restaurant employee. Frankly, I shudder to think that these items will be returned to stock. You don&apos;t know what the patron has done to the packages or napkins. Wouldn&apos;t you want them thrown out and not used?

Taking extra sugar packets just because they are there for the taking is just wrong and not necessary.
 January 14, 2012 at 10:19 pm | MargoX 

A box of Splenda costs about six bucks at the supermarket, so when you pay $50 or more for dinner and tip, without any alcohol, then you are entitled to swipe some. Look at how much they&apos;ve made on you already. They also don&apos;t pay anywhere near what you pay for the same product, with all their corporate bulk purchasing privileges.
 January 14, 2012 at 8:43 pm | 
 MBob 

If you can&apos;t afford to eat out, then don&apos;t; if you don&apos;t want to pay the extra cost for food at a restaurant (which covers employee&apos;s salaries, rent, utilities, food costs) then just eat at home. You feel a sense of entitlement because you are paying for a service you knew the cost of before you walked in (they&apos;re making all this money off me, waaaaaaah!), but what you are doing is theft, plain and simple.
 January 17, 2012 at 12:51 pm | 
 trent 

WOW! The pop psychology in this article is amazing!

Old people took free stuff because of the depression, but young people do it out of a sense of entitlement. Except for those young people who learned the survival behavior from their great-grandparents, of course.

Then, there are the kleptomaniacs (who can&apos;t help themselves) and those who suffer from&quot;attribution of responsibility.&quot;

Finally, there are the hoarders and the obsessive-compulsive personalities.

So why, then, does grandma swipe sugar packets?
 January 14, 2012 at 7:52 pm | 
 GaryU 

You missed one. The article also quotes Patricia Farrell, author of “How to Be Your Own Therapist.”
 January 19, 2012 at 4:57 pm | 
 Robert 

Yeah, this article is basically a bunch of bunk. I you are going into a restaurant and stuffing handfuls of ketchup packets in your pants to take home, then your stealing. If you are in the restaurant eating a burger and fries and you estimate wrong and have an extra ketchup packet or two left over, those are leftovers. If you make a roll of paper towels out of the napkin dispenser, then your are stealing. If you are with your kid at the restaurant and take a generous portion of napkins for the eventual spill that almost always comes and you somehow have extras to pocket, that is just good luck. Probably the restaurants for whatever weird health reasons would not want you to put these items back even when sealed. And if it is a real problem for the restaurants, then just do what most of them do now: McDonald&apos;s has the cup and ketchup spout; Subway keeps the napkins behind the counter; it&apos;s not rocket science. If fact, I can&apos;t believe I have wasted this much time reading the article and commenting on it. Five minutes of life I&apos;ll never get back.
 January 14, 2012 at 7:36 pm | 
 Robert 

And I apologize for the poor use of prepositions and I do know that it is suppose to be&quot;you&apos;re&quot;for&quot;you are&quot;and&quot;yours&quot;for something that you own. Sorry.
 January 14, 2012 at 7:38 pm | Grim Reaper 

Hold your breath for 5 minutes. Normal people want their air back.
 January 14, 2012 at 7:42 pm | 
 signalfire 

Best. Response. Ever.
 January 19, 2012 at 4:31 pm | 
 c s 

Robert–The reason grandma does it is really simple. She has Alzheimer or other dementia and is reliving her childhood during the depression. She was probably poor or at least lived on a very limited budget or experience food rationing during WW II. This is quite common amongst people who have experienced prolong periods of food deprivation. Many ex-POW do the same thing; they hoard food. Until you have been poor and hungry, you do not understand what some people have lived through. Go to the library and read about how people were able to survive the Great Depression.
 January 14, 2012 at 8:51 pm | 
 Elle 

Dear c s, please learn about Alzheimer&apos;s pathology before you start spouting. Neural degradation is not the same as regression - grandma isn&apos;t reliving her childhood. With dementia, and Alzheimer&apos;s in particular, she is losing the ability to make sound judgment, control impulse, and conform to social rules.
 January 14, 2012 at 9:57 pm | 
 wavejump1100 

i know people that always ask for extra condiments but never use them. i think its a mental issue. i had a friend that had literally many hundreds of ketchup packets in his car yet at the drive thru he asked for extra ketchup. i razzed him about it for the next 5 minutes but he just told me to shut up and mind my own business.

when i went to his apartment he had his entire end table covered in duck sauce packets in fact there was no open space anywhere to set anything down.
 January 14, 2012 at 9:59 pm | 
 CG 

These are the people who fear being&quot;without&quot;what they need. My mother also gathers things and takes them home. She grew up poor on a farm with 11 people in her family. At times she went without shoes and many times there was no food either. Even now, having married a doctor and living comfortably in their retirement, she acts like she has nothing and will hoard every penny she can by saving money any way she can. Some people are obsessive about hoarding material items, but others have experienced lack of some kind in their childhood and are trying to prevent it from happening again.
 January 14, 2012 at 11:07 pm | 
 
 George 

Yes , Because if i do not take the ones given they will be in the trash as soon as the bus boy or girl comes and cleans the table ! I have seen it to many times !
 January 14, 2012 at 5:06 pm | 
 c s 

Very true.
 January 14, 2012 at 8:53 pm | 
 bigDizzle 

First off–entitlement generation is crap. Every generation claims it about the next. If you want to see entitlement then ask a senior citizen to give up their SS Check. Yes, I know they did put some money in...but they&apos;re also the benefactors of 3 decades of passing SS increases w/o tax increases to pay for them.

Second off–if you&apos;re spending money eating out then you aren&apos;t serious about saving money in the first place and those extra ketchup packets aren&apos;t offsetting the cost of your fast food/eat out diet. Needless to say the medical costs...
 January 14, 2012 at 4:52 pm | anonymous 

I remember when I was at university students taking extra catsup and taking it home and making&quot;tomato&quot;soup from it. Pretty nasty stuff. But if you&apos;re hungry...
 January 14, 2012 at 4:18 pm | savage 

The financial impact of guests pocketing condiments is a drop in the ocean compared to the waste that is an unavoidable part of running a restaurant–especially a chain. The minimum wage waitstaff delivers far more creamer packets than are necessary for a single cup of coffee to ensure they don&apos;t have to make another run to the kitchen for the odd occasional guest who wants 6 creamers for their coffee. The minimum wage bus-staff throws out everything on the table rather than saving their employer $0.002 per unit by sifting through creamer packets to pick out the unused ones. There is a huge amount of waste in the restaurant industry; it&apos;s called&quot;overhead&quot;, and it&apos;s unavoidable. (And that&apos;s just a small component of the waste on the restaurant floor; don&apos;t even look in the kitchen if you don&apos;t want to be horrified.) I won&apos;t fault the waiter or the busboy; they&apos;re predictably minimizing their own workload. But I also won&apos;t weep for the restaurant owner&apos;s condiment budget.
 January 14, 2012 at 1:40 pm | Maywind 

We were poverty stricken students in Pittsburgh and would always grab a few extra packets at McDonalds or wherever, sugar for tea, catsups, mayonnaises, jellies, whatever, just to get by. And I worked pt-time as a waiteress and took a few artificial sweeteners from that restaurant as well.
I suppose we just continued as we are still poverty stricken even in our senior years. Never take handfuls, just a few extras.......
 January 14, 2012 at 1:24 pm | jdoe 

I take packets of condiments just to annoy the self-righteous posters on this thread.
 January 14, 2012 at 11:11 am | t3chsupport 

Only at Taco Bell, when they short me on sauce. I don&apos;t take all of it, but I will walk in there and grab a big handful of it if they scrooge me at the drive-through.
 January 14, 2012 at 10:39 am | 
 DDM 

Agree. Scrouged me on sauce at drive thru. I parked, walked in and grabbed a handful of the hot sauce, therefore having more than needed. Too bad!
 January 15, 2012 at 2:30 pm | 
 Mary 

You all do realize that the people who are so frugal to take the little sweetner packages are keeping a lot of people at splenda in a job dont you LOL ? The resturant is charging for it , anyone who thinks that they are not is just kidding themselves.
 January 14, 2012 at 10:03 am | 
 alan seago 

Yes, Mary, you&apos;re right: the restaurant is charging us for it. And therein lies the problem: those of us who don&apos;t pilfer pay for those who do.
 January 14, 2012 at 6:43 pm | 
 Mary 

Good point , but I am willing to bet that if everyone just quit pilfering the condiments the price still wouldnt go down!
 January 14, 2012 at 6:56 pm | 
 
 DanTheMan650 

Don&apos;t try to slide a few cookies into your purse from the Chinese buffet or you&apos;ll have half a dozen waiters chase you across the parking lot. A friend from work found that out the hard way!
 January 14, 2012 at 7:59 am | Mushster 

The food industry, including restaurants, has done some not-so-petty pilfering from our healthcare system for years. Extremely few have noticed that big elephant in the room. My brother-in-law loved eating at a certain BBQ franchise, and he ended up needing coronary bypass surgery at 40 years old.
 January 14, 2012 at 12:20 am | 
 Abby Normal 

He must have been a really big pig.
 January 14, 2012 at 2:41 am | 
 Timon and Pumba 

You can be a big pig too!
 January 14, 2012 at 1:31 pm | 
 Jeremy 

Really?! You&apos;re going to blame his coronary bypass on a BBQ restaurant. No one forced him to eat there every day. This is what&apos;s wrong with America. No one takes personal responsibility for their actions and has to blame their problems on everyone else. It&apos;s not a BBQ restaurant or McD&apos;s or anywhere else that makes people fat. It&apos;s the people who eat those foods in excess and don&apos;t exercise. I&apos;ve got a few more pounds than I like right now–is it the fault of the restaurants that cooked the food I like to eat? NO! It&apos;s mine because I&apos;ve eaten too much of it, had a few extra beers, and haven&apos;t run as much as I used to.

America–take responsibility for your actions and stop laying blame on the industries that you frequent a little bit too much.
 January 14, 2012 at 2:41 am | 
 Mike 

Here here, Jeremy. I couldn&apos;t have said it better myself!
 January 14, 2012 at 7:34 am | Mushster 

Apparently, taking responsibility hasn&apos;t helped too much with changing your behavior. Duly noted.
 January 14, 2012 at 3:15 pm | MBob 

YES!!
 January 17, 2012 at 12:54 pm | 
 Porky the Pig 

So,your brother-in law is a fat slob with no self control. Yeah, blame it on the restaurant.
 January 14, 2012 at 6:59 am | 
 trista 

It&apos;s true though that restaurants (and prepared-food companies) load up the servings with extra salt and fat, thereby making the food both more&quot;delicious&quot;to our childish tastes and more fattening/unhealthy. That tweaking of our natural senses does promote overeating, making it more difficult to stop. Once hunger is satisfied people continue eating becaue of&quot;appetite&quot;- or what my husband calls&quot;sport eating.&quot;Once I learned the difference - becoming aware of when the hunger pangs were satiated and I was eating because of&quot;deliciousness,&quot;I was able to cut down and sotp earlier; I had a rationale. But a lot of people - men in particular - are still big kids who eat innocently for the sheer joy of it. And so I do in a sense&quot;blame&quot;those who put the food in front of them. I&apos;m able to sit down to a plate of green beans and make a meal out of them, forego the sauces and seasonings... without the ketchup, we would probably eat far fewer french fries. Without the&quot;secret sauce&quot;a hamburger would be just as filling and nutritious but we might leave some over. To lose weight, just try eating foods plain - even fast foods. Ask for a hamburger plain, no sauce, no ketchup. You&apos;ll get the nutrition and your hunger pangs will cease, but you won&apos;t be tempted to keep eating past the point of satiety.
 January 16, 2012 at 11:29 am | 
 scott 

The restaurant isn&apos;t responsible for your brother-in-law&apos;s inability to take care of himself.
 January 14, 2012 at 12:43 pm | Mushster 

It&apos;s well-known in modern medicine that most medical conditions have a combination of influences including genetic, nutritional, environmental, and lifestyle choices. Anything that contributes to illness is called a&quot;contributing factor&quot;. Excess fat and sodium in one&apos;s diet can be a contributing factor to coronary disease. Some single restaurant meals have been tested to be so far off the scale of U.S. RDA upper daily limits that they should be outlawed (or at least labeled as such).
 January 14, 2012 at 3:22 pm | 
 Eve 

Maybe your relative should refrain from eating out all together and cook his own meals. Just an idea.
 January 15, 2012 at 1:37 pm | MBob 

How about instead of outlawing something, people learn self control and take responsibility for their own health? There are choices we make every day that can help or hurt us, and WE decide what to do.
 January 17, 2012 at 12:56 pm | CT 

Really, we need to outlaw things because you&apos;re too much of a glutton to not stuff your mouth with things you know are bad for you?
 January 19, 2012 at 2:12 am | Mushster 

Allowing the restaurant industry to get away with what they get away with on a regular basis isn&apos;t all that much different than letting the corner drug dealer peddle his illicit wares. When you knowingly sell a product that contains substances in a quantity known to cause harm to human health, there should be consequences. In either case, the consumer is often ignorant of the potential harm until it has already occurred.
 January 21, 2012 at 4:18 am | 
 
 
 «Previous 1 2 3 4 5 6 Next entry» Coffee klatsch «Previous entry Box lunch: Barbecue quilts and celery cynics Recent Posts 
 Barbecue Digest: Cook the opossum, spare the bear Wine has notes of cherries, leather, smoke and...stink bugs? National pecan pie day Coffee klatsch CSI: CSA - multiplying greens and the mystery of amaranth Food freebies for the next few days Beware the grill brush bristle! Shell no! Clam trapped on salty tabletop seems to have problem licked National blueberry muffin day Coffee klatsch 
 Eatocracy on Twitter follow» #thatawkwardmoment at a BBQ when you&apos;re all &quot;Bring whatever!&quot; and people show up with 134 possums and a live bear: http://t.co/DAMolEXA
	</body>
</document>
