<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003677" url="http://gomestic.com/cooking/tiramisu-italian-fast-food-pick-me-up/" time="2012-07-12-19:50" support="1" score="0.00021071738811424357" bingtitle="Tiramisu: Italian Fast Food Pick-me-up | Gomestic" webtitle="Tiramisu: Italian Fast Food Pick-me-up | Gomestic">
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>you find yourself needing a well-deserved pick-me-up, instead of ordering from your favorite fast food restaurant, go to your local café, order a steaming hot cappuccino ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Contact Advertise with us Submit an Article 
 
 Apartment Living Consumer Information Cooking Do-It-Yourself Emergency Preparation Entertaining Family Gardening Home Home Business Home Improvement Homemaking 
 Home » Cooking » Tiramisu: Italian Fast Food Pick-me-up 
 Tiramisu: Italian Fast Food Pick-me-up 
 by Maria Liberati on May 11, 2011 with 3 Comments 

Celebrity Chef/Award winning Author Maria Liberati shares facts and the history on this Italian version of a fast food pick-me-up. Maria’s books series is the winner of the Gouramnd World Cookbook Awards, her blog at http://www.marialiberati.com/blog2 is read by over 100,000 worldwide subscribers.

 
Fast food joints are
at practically every intersection splattered across America,
satisfying those unbelievable cravings within minutes. Sometimes
it’s too difficult to resist a cheeseburger, fries and milk shake
and all of their addicting greasiness. After a long stressful day’s
work, occasional pick-me-ups can be the perfect cure to get through
the day. Americans aren’t the only ones with their go-to
indulgences or love of fast food. Italians have pick-me-ups of their
own, an addicting delight loaded with caffeine and : Tiramisu, 
a dessert staple for Italian cuisine, which is literally translated
into “pick me up” in English.
 
Traditionally
Tiramisu is a chilled dessert with alternate layers of cake, and
cream. Basic Tiramisu consists of ladyfingers soaked in rum and/or
espresso, ultra creamy mascarpone cheese and shavings of dark
chocolate sprinkled with cocoa. The moistness of the coffee-soaked
cake along with the richness of the whipped custard makes for a rich
yet light treat. All ingredients, delicious on their own, create a
mouth-watering dessert when paired together. Tiramisu has
found its way into many homes and bakeries with countless variations.
Some may choose to add raspberries, almonds or hazelnut cream while
others cut the sugar by replacing the ladyfingers with fruit, or by
substituting the mascarpone for low-fat cream cheese. Whether in its
original form or not, Tiramisu can morph into a tailor-made treat
that satisfies a sweet tooth, or a friendlier waist-watching version,
which may be why it has become such a widely embraced dessert.
 Read more in Cooking « Adult Chocolate Gingerbread Recipe for Diabetic Cake Apple Pecan Friendly with Many Variations Including » 
The history of
Tiramisu is somewhat of a mystery. Some argue that the dessert is
actually of Greek origin, and it is served in many Greek restaurants
as well as Italian. Others believe that a similar custard creation,
which may have inspired the modern-day dessert, was created in the
17 th century in Siena, Italy. Others suggest that Tiramisu
is a fairly young dessert, which was recorded in cookbooks in the
1980s. However, one of the most common beliefs is affirmed by food
critic and author Giuseppe Maffioli, who reviewed the restaurant Le
Beccherie, in Treviso, Italy. In 1981 Maffioli wrote an article
saying:



“Tiramisu’ was
born recently, just 10 years ago in the town of Treviso. It was
proposed for the first time in the restaurant Le Beccherie. The
dessert and its name became immediately extremely popular, and this
cake and the name were copied by many restaurants first in Treviso
then all around Italy.”



It wasn’t long
before the dessert found its way to America. Tiramisu became popular
in the San Francisco area. Places like “Café Tiramisu” create
authentic Italian cuisine much like “Le Beccherie.” Now over the
course of a debatable 40 years, according to Maffioli, the dessert
can be found in just about any cookbook, or Italian or Greek
restaurant, and the irresistible flavors have breathed new life into
traditional pastries or other sweets like cupcakes, ice cream or even
Tiramisu- flavored popsicles.

Maybe the next time
you find yourself needing a well-deserved pick-me-up, instead of
ordering from your favorite fast food restaurant, go to your local
café, order a steaming hot cappuccino and a generous piece of
Tiramisu, and take time out of your day to enjoy a little pick-me-up,
the Italian way.




 Flag It Spam Adult Content Plagiarism Insufficient Quality Wrong Category Select the Right Category About Writing Autos Books Business Computers Creative Writing Domestic Gaming General Health Internet Movies Music News Offbeat Pets Poetry Recipes Religion Science Short Stories Society Sports Television Travel Women 0 
 Liked it I Like It 
 Published in : Cooking 

 Tags : Award winning author-Maria Liberati • Celebrity Chef Maria Liberati. Celebrity Spokesperson Maria Liberati • easy dessserts • espresso • fast food • italian cooking • Italian desserts • Italian food • ladyfingers • The Basic Art of Italian Cooking by Mar • Tiramisu 
 Comments: 3 |  Post a Comment 
 
 thresiapaulose | May 11, 2011 | Reply 

Quite interesting. Thank you
 
 Prometheus Ridley Scott | May 11, 2011 | Reply 

Sounds tasty and thanks for the history lesson also. Good piece.
 
 Nandini Deshmukh | May 11, 2011 | Reply 

nice post!!!!
 
 Post a Comment 
 Subscribe via RSS Feed Follow Us on Twitter 
 Popular Articles 
 Parents AND Teenagers-a Must Read! Teen Pregnancy is The Way According to Britain&apos;s Youngest Mum To be a Mommy This Baby Born with Six Foot in Pakistan Could Having Mangoes Lessen Your Possibility of Receiving Cancers? Easy DIY Maxi Skirt Tutorial Hoarding: How to Not 10 Good Financial Habits That Make You Wealth Modernising The Style of Your Home Easy Steps on How to Paint Furniture Items 
 Search Gomestic Loading 
 Home About Contact Advertise with us Submit an Article 

©Copyright Gomestic. All Rights Reserved.    Terms of Use     Privacy Policy 
 Powered by
	</body>
</document>
