<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003565" url="http://www.treehugger.com/green-food/fast-food-trash-how-to-reduce-your-waste-video.html" time="2012-07-12-19:44" support="12" score="0.01337183707359318" bingtitle="Fast Food Trash: How to Reduce Your Waste (Video) : TreeHugger" webtitle="Fast Food Trash: How to Reduce Your Waste (Video) : TreeHugger">
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000385" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="17"/>
	<description>- Leave the lid and the straw: you don&apos;t need one at ... almost certainly wondering what the heck a fast food restaurant is ... Discovery Store; DVDs &amp; Books; Custom Gear; Gift Sets</description>
	<body>
		TreeHugger 
 All Design Technology Living Transportation Energy Science Business Slideshows 
 
Fast Food Trash: How to Reduce Your Waste (Video)
 
 

 Sami Grover 
 Living / Green Food 
March 9, 2009
 
 The Enviromentals Take on Fast Food Waste On Friday I wrote about a very funny, and very useful, video about how to build your own worm composter , which was brought to us by The Enviromentals - aka Hal Brindley and Leigh Ramsdell of Dodo Films. Now the fearless duo have been joined by their friend Mike for a rather disgusting yet strangely entertaining mission - eating fast food for an entire weekend, in a quest to find out how we can reduce our fast food trash. The result is a kind of a mini Super Size Me (if that&apos;s not a contradiction in terms). And they found out that a little awareness can go a long way, even in fast food hell...Of course the pedants among us might argue that the best way to reduce fast food trash would be, well, to not eat as much fast food. But given that fast food consumption, particularly in the US, is at outrageous levels, the Enviromentals quest may be a wise one. If Hal, Leigh and Mike can help spread a consciousness about the extraordinary and often completely unnecessary waste that accompanies almost every fast food meal, they will have done the planet - if not their waste lines - a huge favor.

And let&apos;s not forget that the Dogwood Alliance has shown some compelling links between fast food trash and unsustainable forestry . For those who can&apos;t view the video, here are a few tips &apos;to go&apos; on reducing your fast food trash:

- Leave the lid and the straw: you don&apos;t need one at home, why do you need it in the restaurant?- Bring your own bottle: it saves trash, and can even save you money if you don&apos;t buy a drink.- Share your trays: who needs those stupid tray liners anyway?- Carry a reusable napkin: or you can always use your hand.- Learn to ask for less: it takes a bit of harrassing, but ask your server to forego items you don&apos;t need.

Now the more hardcore greenies out there are almost certainly wondering what the heck a fast food restaurant is anyway - but even many of us who eat green and healthy on a daily basis end up in a Subway, Taco Bell or whatever from time to time (ever tried finding an organic cafe on I-40?). And anything we can do to reduce the mountains of trash that these places churn out can only be a good thing.

 
 The Enviromentals (Episode 2) How to Reduce Your Fast Food Trash from Hal Brindley on Vimeo .
 
Tags: Diet | United States | Waste 
 Tweet Pin It 
 Follow @foo 

 RSS for Sami 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments. 
Related

 
 10 Best Green Baby Diapers on the Market 
 
 More Hot Poop on Composting and Alternative Toilets 
 
 Spring Back Now Recycles What Landfills&amp;Other Recyclers Don&apos;t Want: Mattresses 
 
 
Most Popular
 
 
 

 Paris Tests Out Snazzy New &apos;Bus Stop of the Future&apos; 

Multi-purpose public space outside Gare de Lyon offers bike rentals, a book lending ...

by Jennifer Hattam in Public Transportation
 
 

 Most Popular Articles of June 

City of Tulsa destroys an edible garden, funny prank on Shell, and more.

by Mairi Beautyman in Culture
 
 

 Prisoners in Brazil Can Reduce Their Sentences by Producing Electricity 

Thanks to an innovative new initiative underway at a correctional facility in Brazil, ...

by Stephen Messenger in Renewable Energy
 
 
Featured
 
 
 

 Summer-Blooming Bulbs You Should Plant in Your Garden 

Get bold, beautiful, and exotic summer blooms in your garden with these garden ...

by Ramon Gonzalez in Lawn&amp;Garden
 
 

 How The DIY Electronics Trend Is Empowering People, Communities, Businesses 

There&apos;s a reason for the maker mantra of &quot;If you can&apos;t open it ...

by Jaymi Heimbuch in Gadgets
 
 

 How to Become a Vegetarian in One Easy Bite 

Scientists find a strange explanation for some recent conversions to vegetarian dining choices.

by Christine Lepisto in Sustainable Agriculture
 
 

 10 Electricity-Free iPhone Speakers 

From a piece of bamboo to repurposed old trumpets, here are ten iPhone ...

by Megan Treacy in Gadgets
 
 
Our sites

 Animal Planet Discovery Channel Discovery Health Discovery Kids Discovery Fit&amp;Health HD Theater Investigation Discovery Military Channel Oprah Winfrey Network Parentables Planet Green Science Channel TLC Turbo 

 Consumer Guide Auto Consumer Guide Products Discovery Education Discovery News HowStuffWorks Petfinder Student Competitions TreeHugger 
 
Video

 Discovery Channel Video 

Mobile

 iPhone App 
 
Shop

 Discovery Store DVDs&amp;Books Custom Gear Gift Sets Sale Discovery Adventures Student Adventures Discovery TSX Discovery Corporate Sales 
 
Stay connected

 About Us Contact Us Email Newsletters RSS Twitter Facebook Jobs 
 
Corporate

 Discovery Communications, LLC Careers @ Discovery Privacy Policy Visitor Agreement 
 
Copyright©2012 Discovery Communications, LLC. The number-one nonfiction media company. Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
