<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003951" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/7/1446917/restaurant/DC/Penn-Quarter/Cedar-Restaurant-Washington" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="3" score="0.00181370394742868" bingtitle="Cedar Restaurant - Penn Quarter - Washington | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Cedar Restaurant - Penn Quarter - Washington | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000301" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>Cedar Restaurant, American Restaurant ... for one, it&apos;s a basement restaurant accessed from a set of stairs that you enter upon. ... staff was welcoming and the seating ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Washington DC » DC » Penn Quarter » Cedar Restaurant 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Baltimore Hampton Roads Los Angeles New York Philadelphia Pittsburgh Richmond More... 
 
Cedar Restaurant
 
(202) 637-0012
 Penn Quarter 822 E Street NW 
 Washington , DC 20004 
 cedardc.com 
 See all 27 reviews Cuisine American Features Late Night , Romantic Menu $$$ $15-25 per entree White Corn Soup, Oyster Pan Roast, Market Lettuce Salad, Grilled Prawns... View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   89 people have voted 86 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Cafe Mozart 85% $$ Downtown - German, Sandwiches/Subs, Desserts/Ice Cream 1331 H St NW 
 
 The Capital Grille 89% $$$$ Penn Quarter - Steakhouse, American, Seafood 601 Pennsylvania Ave NW 
 
Critic reviews

 January 1, 2010 2/4 stars Washingtonian Modern American menu offers just a handful of appetizers and entrées, forgoing the chance to dazzle diners with... More from Washingtonian July 29, 2009 Washington Times Cedar&apos;s wine list is an intelligent assortment of international wines by the glass and the bottle. On a recent warm... More from Washington Times June 17, 2009 Washington Post Neatly pared asparagus, lemon mousseline and golden&quot;olive oil&quot;croutons are a nice nod to the season, and a pan... More from Washington Post 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 May 19, 2012 Likes it Been There, Eaten That ... our party of four scores a win that night at Cedar with excellent food, outstanding service, and a warm atmosphere. More from Been There, Eaten That April 18, 2012 Johnna Knows Good Food Grilled Elk Sausage Visiting a restaurant when it first opens and then two years later can make a world of difference. The first time I set foot in Cedar Restaurant, I wasn&apos;t sure the... More from Johnna Knows Good Food April 11, 2012 Likes it Capital Cooking Show Photo by Lauren DeSantis Is your mouth watering? You can find this Grilled Elk Sausage with wild mushrooms, walnut puree, and mustard jus for $28 at Cedar . Chef Aaron McCloud&apos;s menu... More from Capital Cooking Show March 1, 2012 Girl Meets Food Like three-course dinner chewing gum, Cedar&apos;s decadent lobster and white chocolate soup is like a multi-course dinner all in one. Warm, sweet bisque poured over generous chunks of fresh... More from Girl Meets Food December 23, 2010 Bitches Who Brunch When I walked into Cedar in Penn Quarter, I immediately felt like I should be dining with my grandparents. Between the fake-tree wallpaper and white tablecloths on the... More from Bitches Who Brunch 
 Show 3 more 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 April 21, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by buff crone ( 21 reviews ) Lovely food and attentive service. We had the plank smoked salmon and the boar shank. Both were extraordinary, with fresh veggies and lovely broth. We came back later for the duck fat fries and mint limeades. May 7, 2012 Likes it Solid not exceptional by Big Daddy 63 ( 11 reviews ) The restaurant is solid, but not exceptional. I had a soft shell crab that was OK. The salad before dinner was excellent. Others had the salmon plank, which was very good and the elk sausage which was average. Interesting menu with boar an other non-standard fare. Good wait staff - very friendly and professional. I would go again, but there are a number of the restaraunts that are better like Blue Duck Tavern. November 28, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Mike Landers ( 11 reviews ) Visited Cedar on weekend for lunch. Had the mushroom streusel with spinach, walnuts and goat cheese. Streusel essentially a thin crispy buttery wrap around insides. Spinach and mushrooms fresh and not overlooked. White sauce over, not much walnuts. Served with a really nice side salad. Atmosphere really nice. Service top notch. I would return and would try something new, although I liked streusel a lot, something different, well prepared. January 30, 2011 Likes it Restaurant Week Menu by PG AKA ( 28 reviews ) If it is not restaurant week I would not go here (too pricey). The food was good the service was amazing. Everyone from the valet, host, bar tender, waiter and the manager were smiling friendly and very attentive. Once we paid our bill the manager already had our car pulled around front, or to-go boxes were packed and located near our coats. Butternut Squash soup was delicious!!! Chucks of think bacon&amp;apples made this ssoooo good. My Salmon was charred and just ok it came with slides apples and horrible watercress puree ( usually 24). Other had Pork Tenderloin with goat cheese grits (usually $26), and Glazed Beef Short Ribs (usually 28). The main coarse was pretty much the price of the whole meal for restaurant week and it wasn&apos;t that good Now the bread pudding dessert was amazing!!! It was filling I just had to toss off the raspberries to my table mates plate.Maybe I&apos;d return for brunch but not for dinner not worth the money. October 16, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by sck ( 153 reviews ) Yummy modern American food and really good cocktails. We&apos;ll be back. My only complaint would be the crazy amount of butter in all of their food. May 23, 2010 Likes it Diamond in the Basement by ARL2601 ( 153 reviews ) We went for Saturday brunch - it was pretty dead, and we had reservations about sitting down in a basement on a nice sunny afternoon. But the food was excellent, service was excellent, and we all decided we&apos;d rather have a great meal in the basement, than a mediocre one at a rickety outdoor table. Can recommend all three dishes we had: mushroom/spinach omlette, deviled chicken hash, hang town fry. Split a side of (warm!) banana bread fand the tres leches coconut cake for dessert. Both of which were excellent without being overly sweet. The housemade ice cream and sorbet also sounded good. Cocktails are unique without being too over the top. Our server was extremely knowledgeble about how the food was prepared. Manager visited the table. Will definately be back for happy hour or dinner when we have a chance. July 22, 2009 Likes it A walk in the woods by Greggndc ( 105 reviews ) Do not be dismayed by the descent into Cedar, a new Penn Quarter restaurant. The twisting staircase reveals a rather pleasant, airy room with walls covered in stone, wood, and murals of cedar trees to complete the theme (however the carpeting looks like an after thought). I was initially dismayed by a basement restaurant (my office is in one so sunlight and street life are a welcome change) but the warm welcome and subsequent attentive service changed my mind. The restaurant hypes its food as&quot;clean&quot;in flavor and&quot;vibrant&quot;in presentation and I would agree. My guest and I settled in for a nice leisurely dinner and started with the asparagus salad with lemon dressing and seared scallops on tomato fondue with basil aioli. The dishes arrived and were beautifully presented and the contrasting and complimentary flavors. We each preferred the other&apos;s dish, but sent back clean plates, scraping the sauces up with the crusty bread. For entrees we had the New York Strip... more» Do not be dismayed by the descent into Cedar, a new Penn Quarter restaurant. The twisting staircase reveals a rather pleasant, airy room with walls covered in stone, wood, and murals of cedar trees to complete the theme (however the carpeting looks like an after thought). I was initially dismayed by a basement restaurant (my office is in one so sunlight and street life are a welcome change) but the warm welcome and subsequent attentive service changed my mind. The restaurant hypes its food as&quot;clean&quot;in flavor and&quot;vibrant&quot;in presentation and I would agree. My guest and I settled in for a nice leisurely dinner and started with the asparagus salad with lemon dressing and seared scallops on tomato fondue with basil aioli. The dishes arrived and were beautifully presented and the contrasting and complimentary flavors. We each preferred the other&apos;s dish, but sent back clean plates, scraping the sauces up with the crusty bread. For entrees we had the New York Strip (with Jinga-stacked French fries!) surrounded by a watercress puree that formed a moat for the wine sauce, and pork tenderloin served on a bed of wilted Swiss chard and bacon flecks. Both were splendid. My first thought upon seeing the pork was that it was encrusted in black pepper but it seemed to be a dusting of herbs instead. Both of the meats were perfectly cooked (although we weren&apos;t asked how we wanted them cooked). We split dessert - peach sorbet and small slices of cake on a pool of spicy peach compote. The compote and sorbet were great compliments to ach other but I found the cake- while tender, overly sweet. The wine selection is varied in origin and price and the selections by the glass were thoughtfully chosen to compliment the food offerings. We started with a Cosmopolitan as we perused the menu and found it overly sweet and lacking any of the citrus tang that makes them delectable. Perhaps cocktails are best avoided here. Cedar shows a lot of promise as a contender in the DC food scene. The basement setting may prove their major detriment. Perhaps if they had embraced the subterranean setting by making it more cave-like rather than fight it with mirrors and pictures of forests they would become a trendy hit. As it is, the food will need to speak for them and it is up to the challenge. August 15, 2011 by nkaye ( 7 reviews ) I was in town for business and realized it was restaurant week. I chose this restaurant because it looked like an interesting menu and was near my hotel. What a fabulous meal! I had the corn soup w/blue crab, the grilled swordfish, and the tres leches dessert. I also chose the wine pairings. The swordfish was excellent--but the first and the last courses were fabulous!!! I highly recommend this restaurant to others and will most definitely return when I am in the area. March 12, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by PMB151 ( 16 reviews ) Terrific food. Best beet salad and squash soup I&apos;ve ever had. The oyster bake, pork tenderloin, and poached lobster were up there, too. This place is going to climb to the top of most DC foodie lists as word gets around the community. September 4, 2011 Likes it Great neighborhood place by P2 in PQ ( 11 reviews ) This is a great little restaurant with quality food (crab soup) and a great little bar scene. The service is excellent from the bartender to the waiters to the management. It is small and out of the way, but for the price it&apos;s one of the better deals around. Very much a popular place for people who live in Penn Quarter. July 12, 2009 Likes it Mobile review by Magnolia ( 6 reviews ) A fun new haunt. Everything on the menu is delicious, especially the tuna. Don&apos;t forget to order the chef&apos;s fries in duck fat. Ask for Matt at the bar to pour you one of his specialty drinks. Too good to pass up! August 27, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Patrick ( 3 reviews ) As a local, the food can range from good to excellent (but getting more consistent). Service is always spot on and management is great. The bartenders are a bit of a local legend and the wine prices are reasonable. Great enviroment. +1 more review from Patrick August 27, 2011 Mobile review Ad a local, the food can range from good to excellent (but getting more consistent). Service is always spot on and management is great. The bartenders are a bit of a local legend and the wine prices are reasonable. Great enviroment. May 12, 2011 Likes it Comfortable and Enjoyable by Tim Kirkpatrick ( 3 reviews ) Very enjoyable evening. The walk down the stairs feels as if you&apos;re walking into a warm forest. The staff was welcoming and the seating arrangement was more intimate than other DC restaurants. The service was prompt without feeling overwhelming. We had ordered drinks and appetizers quickly without feeling rushed. I had a couple of questions about the dishes, and our server was able to answer them honestly and legitimately. The wine list was short but thorough and we settled on a sparkling wine that was tasty and reasonably priced. The lobster entree was prepared well, as was the New York strip. The restaurant was busy, given it was a Thursday night, but it was never loud nor uncomfortable. Cedar is a perfect place for a nice dinner when you&apos;re excited to enjoy conversation and dine in a comfortable environment. April 15, 2011 great! by susanlarson67 ( 2 reviews ) My colleagues and I usually go to Cedar after work on Friday&apos;s for their awesome drinks! Truth be told.. we never leave disappointed! June 16, 2010 Really likes it Mobile review by Trjdmc ( 1 review ) Went here for lunch when around the national archives.service was amazing and waitresses were really nice and we started talking. The scallops appetizer was incredible and the dry aged burger with gorgonsola cheese was the best I&apos;ve had away from home. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Girl Meets Food Lobster White... by Linda Szewczyk Cedar Restaurant 
 All 6 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Riot Act Comedy Theater $$ Penn Quarter - American Austin Grill 71% $ Penn Quarter - Tex-Mex, Mexican, Latin American Social Reform Kitchen&amp;Bar 86% $$ Penn Quarter - American, Gastropub, Wine Bar America Eats Tavern 56% $$$$ Penn Quarter - American, Pub Food Subway $ Penn Quarter - Sandwiches/Subs, Fast Food 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Flashpoint -
916 G St NW Ford&apos;s Theatre -
511 10th St NW International Spy Museum Complex -
800 F St NW Oakwood Lexington -
400 8th St NW Platinum Club -
915 F St NW 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 cedar dc cedar restaurant dc reviews cedar restaurant in penn quarter cedar restaurant cedar restaurant dc 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
