<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003807" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Fort-Gibson/Simple-Simons-Pizza_27" time="2012-07-12-19:58" support="1" score="0.002045293263196768" bingtitle="Simple Simons Pizza - Fast Food Restaurant Fort Gibson, OK 74434" webtitle="Simple Simons Pizza - Fast Food Restaurant  Fort Gibson, OK 74434">
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="27"/>
	<description>Simple Simons Pizza a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 1551 ... They are always nice and have my food ready I really ... Fort Gibson Hotels Motels See all Fort Gibson Parks</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Simple Simons Pizza
 
Average User Rating
 
8
 
Great

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(918) 478-2400

 http://www.simple-simon.com/ 
 OK &gt; Fort Gibson &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Simple Simons Pizza listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Simple Simons Pizza to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Simple Simons Pizza
 Simple Simons Pizza is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1551 S Lee St in Fort Gibson, OK 74434. Simple Simons Pizza has been described as an Great Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 8 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Pizza, Take Out Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Simple Simons Pizza
 
 
 
All Reviews for Simple Simons Pizza

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
8
 
Decor
 
8
 
Service
 
8
 
They are always nice and have my food ready I really like there service
 
Overall Rating
 
8
 
&quot;Great&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Simple Simons Pizza:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
Simple Simons Pizza News
 Dining capsules Patsy&apos;s: Famous New York Italian restaurant &quot;that Sinatra built&quot; comes to Atlantic City with the same great recipes in a much more upscale setting. Pricey. $$$ Simon Prime ... Harry&apos;s Oyster Bar&amp;Seafood: Simple, casual and impressively ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Bleecker Street Pizza - West Village - New York, NY Category: Restaurants Pizza Pizza. 69 7th Ave S (between Commerce St&amp;Bleecker St) New York, NY 10014 Neighborhood: West Village (212) 924-4466 Patzeria Perfect Pizza - Midtown West - New York, NY Category: Restaurants Pizza Pizza. 231 W 46th St (between Broadway&amp;7th Ave) New York, NY 10036 Neighborhoods: Midtown West, Theater District (212) 575-7646 New York Pizza: Slice Harvester&apos;s Quest to Try Pies in the Big ... Manhattan is home to some of the country&apos;s oldest and most celebrated pizzerias, but the great metropolis also holds many mediocre slices. Colin Hagendorf ... New York City Restaurants, New York City Menus, Ratings, Reviews ... What&apos;s a hot menu?Every night we calculate the most-clicked restaurants of the preceding 24 hours and display them here. If a restaurant makes the Hot Menus list for ... NYC.com | New York Hotels - Broadway Tickets - New York ... Save more with NYC.com, the trusted New York City experts. Book New York hotels and lodging, buy New York Broadway tickets and event tickets, reserve New York ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 91° 
Fri
 
 73° - 97° 
Sat
 
 73° - 95° 
Sun
 
 75° - 95° 
 
Address
 
Simple Simons Pizza

1551 S Lee St

Fort Gibson, OK 
 
74434
 
Telephone
 (918) 478-2400 
Simple Simons Pizza
 
 Rating :  8 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Simple Simons Pizza Photos
 
 Fast Food Pizza Take Out 
 
 Local Places
 
 Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Bozena Polish Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Macs Drive-Inn 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Simple Simons Pizza 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Ft Gibson Classic Kitchen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food International Merchant Services Incorporated 
Cuisine: ATMs Cedar Inn 
Cuisine: Hotels Motels Fort Gibson Lake 
Cuisine: Parks Fort Gibson Historic Site 
Cuisine: Tourist Attractions Garrett Historic Home 
Cuisine: Tourist Attractions 
 

See all Fort Gibson ATMs 
See all Fort Gibson Hotels Motels 
See all Fort Gibson Parks 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Simple Simons Pizza Coupons 

 Simple Simons Pizza Fort Gibson 

 Simple Simons Pizza Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Fort Gibson Restaurants 
 B | F | M | S 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
