<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003698" url="http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m1038/is_n4_v40/ai_20141959/" time="2012-07-12-19:51" support="3" score="0.0040045429115155755" bingtitle="&quot;Customers for life&quot;: does it fit your culture? | Business ..." webtitle="&quot;Customers for life&quot;: does it fit your culture? | Business Horizons | Find Articles">
			<query id="001001" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="130"/>
	<description>... type teen behind the counter at a fast food restaurant. ... she reaches under the counter and hands him his pre-bagged, &quot;regular&quot; order ... customers know what to expect ...</description>
	<body>
		FIND ARTICLES IN THE INTERACTIVE BUSINESS NETWORK RESOURCE LIBRARY Business Library http://findarticles.com/ 
 Business Money Life&amp;Health 
 Search 
Departments

 Business Reference Technology News 
 
Popular Publications

 Economic Review Entrepreneur Business Wire Chief Executive, The Market Wire 
 
Departments

 Economy Careers Saving Spending Investing Retirement 
 
Popular Publications

 Better Nutrition Natural Health New American, The Encyclopedia of ... Real Estate Weekly 
 
Departments

 Arts Home&amp;Garden Autos Sports Health 
 
Popular Publications

 New York Times Upfront Health Management Technology Automotive Manufacturing&amp;... Sierra Automotive Industries 
 FindArticles / Business / Business Horizons / July-August, 1997 
&quot;Customers for life&quot;: does it fit your culture?

by Diana L. Deadrick, R. Bruce McAfee, Myron Glassman
 Tweet 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Next 
 More Articles of Interest 
 America&apos;s most wanted j-o-b-s - 10 hottest employment opportunities Effective organizational communication: a competitive advantage 7 tips for effective listening: productive listening does not occur naturally. It requires hard work and practice - Back To Basics - effective listening is a crucial skill for internal auditors Culture, leadership, and power: the keys to organizational change - includes bibliography The dropout dilemma: One in four college freshmen drop out. What is going on here? What does it take to stay in? 
 
By choosing the right philosophy, you can avoid placing your employees in a cross-fire and making promises to customers that can&apos;t be kept.

The television commercial shows a smiling, cheerleader-type teen behind the counter at a fast food restaurant. She has just finished serving an all-American couple and is cheerfully thanking them for their patronage. Because no one else is in line, she has a clear view of a regular customer rushing through the door. As the customer approaches the counter, she reaches under the counter and hands him his pre-bagged, &quot;regular&quot; order, saying, &quot;I thought you might be running a little late.&quot; The customer thanks her and says, &quot;That&apos;s why I always come here. I&apos;ll see you tomorrow.&quot;

Compare the above scenario with this one: Jane shows up at 2 p.m. to work a four-hour shift at the fast food restaurant. Although she wasn&apos;t scheduled to work and had made other plans, her boss had called her saying he was expecting a busy afternoon because of a local high school event and he desperately needed her. At about 2:30, the boss comes up to Jane and says, &quot;Things are slower than I expected, so you have to leave at 3:00. You know, I have to keep payroll costs down.&quot; Jane is upset for the remainder of her shift and the next day as well.

These scenarios illustrate two trends emerging today. The first represents the way most marketers of the 1990s view the world. Pick up any book or magazine, from the popular press to academic journals, and you will read about the importance of providing customers with quality service. A &quot;customers-for-life&quot; philosophy has evolved whereby companies attempt to cater to the unique needs and expectations of their customers, thus recognizing customer loyalty as a key factor for organization success. The second scenario represents the way most managers of the 1990s view the world. Again, pick up any book or magazine and you&apos;ll read about the importance of streamlining the organization and its work force. As a result, a &quot;flexible work force&quot; philosophy has evolved whereby employee loyalty and lifelong careers at one company are viewed as artifacts of the past. The key factor for success here is organizational efficiency, and employees are considered to be labor costs rather than resource investments.
 
Taken together, these two trends cause problems because they are at cross purposes. The first problem is the inherent goal conflict they represent. The customers-for-life philosophy implies a long-term, relationship-based approach to attracting and retaining customers. In contrast, the flexible work force philosophy implies a short-term, economic-based approach to attracting and retaining employees. When viewed this way, the marketing goal of customer loyalty cannot be supported by the human resource management (HRM) goal of labor cost reduction.

A second problem is also apparent in the combination of these two trends, a problem that develops at a somewhat deeper level than the first. Given the divergent goals these trends represent, a role conflict develops between a firm&apos;s customers and its employees. Based on a marketing strategy of customers-for-life, customers expect a long-term relationship with not only the company but also its employees, the service providers. Because customers are willing to invest time and energy in developing and maintaining this relationship, they expect high and consistent quality service. However, the HRM strategy of a flexible work force conveys different role expectations to the employees. Because employees are used as a buffer to shield the firm from economic downturns, their relationship with it is tentative and short-term. As a result, they are not willing to invest any more time or effort in their job than the company is investing in them.

These two problems take place at different points in time, yet they are inextricably interrelated. The initial conflict is a strategic one; the espoused goals of marketing and HRM are not only inconsistent with one another but also imply very different values with respect to the role of employees in the success of the organization. Over time, a cultural conflict develops based on these value differences: the external image, or culture, the firm is trying to convey to customers is inconsistent with the internal culture its employees have developed. Employees eventually begin to treat their customers in much the same way they are being treated by the company--as expendable.

ORGANIZATIONAL CULTURE AND CONSISTENCY

The concept &quot;organizational culture&quot; refers to the &quot;personality&quot; of a firm, what makes it unique in the eyes of insiders and outsiders. Although there are numerous definitions of culture, the common theme among all of them is the importance of shared values, beliefs, assumptions, and patterns of behavior. Inherent in this theme are two critical elements of a culture.

The first element is the shared nature of job or role expectations. Based on a history of interactions with the organization, employees develop a common understanding about what is really expected of them. Over time, customers also develop a common understanding about what kind of service they can expect to receive. In this sense, there are two perspectives of organizational culture: the internal culture that characterizes employee expectations, and the external culture that characterizes customer expectations.

The second element is the stability of a culture. Based on shared expectations, employees develop behavioral norms that are consistent with those expectations. These norms represent predictable patterns of behavior that determine how, and to what extent, customer service is provided. When viewed internally, organizational culture provides employees with a common frame of reference about what needs to be accomplished, how the work can best be done, and how their efforts relate to the success of the company. Role expectations have been defined such that employees know what to expect from the company and the company knows what to expect of its employees. As long as both have a mutual understanding about these role expectations, there is a common and strong organizational identity.

When viewed externally, organizational culture conveys to customers what kind of service they can expect, how reliable the service delivery will be, and how much effort they need to expend to complete a transaction with the firm. These service expectations have been defined such that customers know what to expect from the company and the company knows what to expect from its customers (such as how much loyalty they have). To the extent that all customers are treated alike, they will develop a common understanding about the firm&apos;s image and the extent to which it values them.

It is important to note that the internal culture determines the nature of the external culture or organizational image. Customer perceptions about service quality are heavily influenced by the employees that provide that service. Therefore, cultural consistency is characterized by &quot;met expectations&quot;: Both employees and customers not only know what to expect from the organization, they also agree on how those expectations are to be met, and they act accordingly. In this situation, one would expect a high degree of employee job satisfaction as well as a high degree of customer satisfaction. In contrast, cultural conflict is characterized by &quot;unmet expectations&quot;: There is a discrepancy between the employees&apos; service (role) expectations and those of the customers. This discrepancy will eventually lead to both employee and customer dissatisfaction, which in turn will lead to higher costs for the firm, both direct and indirect.

SERVICE STRATEGIES AND CONSISTENCY

A company&apos;s service strategy is a combination of its marketing and HRM strategies. In general, each of these can be categorized as being relationship-based or transaction-based. A relationship-based marketing strategy emphasizes customer loyalty to the firm, creating a long-term relationship (investment) with its customers. Similarly, a relationship-based HRM strategy emphasizes employee loyalty to the firm, leading to a long-term relationship (investment) between the firm and its employees.
 Tweet 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Next 
 Search 
 All ResourceLibrary 
 
Business

 Business Reference Technology News 
 
Money

 Economy Careers Saving Spending Investing Retirement 
 
Life&amp;Health

 Arts Home&amp;Garden Autos Sports Health 
 ie8 fix 
 Most Recent Business Articles 
 
 Neonatal diabetes mellitus/ Yenidoganda diyabetes mellitus Demographic and clinical features of child abuse and neglect cases: one-year experience of The Hospital-Based Child Protection Team of Ege University, Turkey/Cocuk istismari ve ihmali olgularimizin demografik ve klinik ozellikleri: Ege Universitesi Cocuk Aseptic meningitis due to zona zoster infection/ Zona zoster enfeksiyonu sirasinda gelisen aseptik menenjit Acute cyanide poisoning after eating apricot pits: a case report/ Kayisi cekirdegi yeme sonrasi akut siyanur zehirlenme olgusu Determining causes and frequency of misdosing of antipyretics in patients presenting with fever to pediatric emergency/Ates yakinmasi ile cocuk acile basvuran hastalarda uygunsuz dozda ates dusurucu kullanma sikliginin ve nedenlerinin belirlenmesi 
 
 Most Recent Business Publications 
 
 Brandweek Latin Trade Business Asia Store Equipment&amp;Design Cheers 
 
 Most Popular Business Articles 
 
 America&apos;s most wanted j-o-b-s - 10 hottest employment opportunities Effective organizational communication: a competitive advantage 7 tips for effective listening: productive listening does not occur naturally. It requires hard work and practice - Back To Basics - effective listening is a crucial skill for internal auditors Culture, leadership, and power: the keys to organizational change - includes bibliography The dropout dilemma: One in four college freshmen drop out. What is going on here? What does it take to stay in? 
 
 Most Popular Business Publications 
 
 Market Wire Chief Executive, The Entrepreneur Brandweek Business Wire 
 
Content provided in partnership with 
 
 Business Reference Technology Newspaper 

 Economy Careers Saving Spending 

 Investing Retirement Arts Home&amp;Garden 

 Auto Sports Health All RSS Feeds 
 Search ©2011 CBS Interactive. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use | Advertise | Jobs
	</body>
</document>
