<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003358" url="http://www.drug3k.com/drug/mucinex-16806.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:30" support="1" score="0.0019127597720927907" bingtitle="mucinexGuaifenesin-Oral - Drug Information and Side Effects on ..." webtitle="mucinexGuaifenesin-Oral - Drug Information and Side Effects on Drug3k.com">
			<query id="001252" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>When I see my friends, theyre all somewhere near 5&apos;8&quot;. ... any instant cure to feeling like you&apos;re gonna throw up ... Storage. Store at room temperature between 59 and 86 ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Links | Contact 
 Us | Top 50 | News | Bookmark 
 
 Find a drug: 
 
 

 

 A     B     C     D     E     F     G     H     I     J     K     L     M     N     O     P     Q     R     S     T     U     V     W     X     Y     Z     #    

 

 

 

 Health Discussion Forum Alternative Medicine Dental Diet&amp;Fitness Diseases&amp;Conditions Allergies Cancer Diabetes Heart Diseases Infectious Diseases Respiratory Diseases STDs Skin Conditions Other - Diseases General Health Care First Aid Injuries Pain&amp;Pain Management Other - General Health Care Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Optical Women&apos;s Health Other - Health 


 
   Is procrastination inherited? ... 
 



 
   How does gargling salt water help a sore throat? ... 
 



 
   How do you give mosquitoes CPR? I think I accidentally killed one. How can I resuscitate it?... 
 



 
   BUTT CHEEKS WON&apos;T STOP ITCHING!!!!? So I work at a camp and wear airy basketball shorts since I&apos;m sweating pretty much all day long. Yesterday with normal underwear the sweat was too much, you know how that is girls. So then today ... 
 



 
   Am I too short? I&apos;m 5&apos;2&quot;and I&apos;m 15. Everyone seems so much taller.? When I see my friends, theyre all somewhere near 5&apos;8&quot;. Do you think ethnicity and genetics are a big factor?... 
 



 
   well if my hands get swollen when i go for my fitness walk is it normal or should i go to the doctor? ... 
 



 
   would you bite the tip of your own finger off for $50,000? pretend theres no doctor bill. just the first section of ... 
 



 
   When i get a cut, it bleeds alot!? lately i have notcied that i am bleeding more than usual when i get a cut. ( i am a kultz so i am prone to getting them!) A few days ago i cute my finger while picking up my binder (i dont know how ... 
 



 
   whats the best thing to go on a burn from steam? ... 
 



 
   Is there any instant cure to feeling like you&apos;re gonna throw up when you&apos;re drunk? ... 
 


 

 
 Drug Guide     M   mucinex 
 
 
     Prescription 
drug information       User 
opinions and reviews (4)     

 
     Prescription 
drug information       User 
opinions and reviews (4)     

    Mucinex 

 
 
 Mucinex 
 Guaifenesin-Oral 


Mucinex is used to relieve a dry cough and helps to loosen phlegm and mucous in the lungs so you can cough-up (expectorate) mucous.
 
 ALTERNATE 
NAMES 

Guaifenesin, Guaibid La, Humibid L.a., Gua-Sr, Q-Bid La, Guaifenesin La, Aquamist, Guaifenex La, Guaifenesin Er, Amibid La, Fenesin, Mucobid L.a., Allfen-M, Muco-Fen-La, Sinumist-Sr, Guaifenesin-Sr, Respa-Gf, Liquibid, Ambi 600
 

 

 
 
   
 
 Avg Consumer 
Rating 3.2 out of 5 4 
Reviews | Post your 
opinion 
 
   Mucinex 
images:
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex DM Tablets Drug pic 1 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral mucinex.jpg pic 2 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex Expectorant, Guaifenesin pic 4 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex 600mg 500 tabs pic 5 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral pic 6 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex D Official FDA information, side effects and uses. pic 7 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex Expectorant/Cough - and Save on all Cough&amp;Cold Products pic 8 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex Children\&apos;s Jr Str Mini-Melts, Bubble Gum, 12-Count (Pack of 2) pic 9 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex DM Official FDA information, side effects and uses. pic 10 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral MUCINEX D pic 11 
 mucinex 
prescription drug /side effects/Guaifenesin-Oral Mucinex® EXPECTORANT MINI-MELTS for Kids pic 12 
 


 Overview Photos How 
To Use Side 
Effects Precautions Missed 
Dose Drug 
Interactions 
 
 

 


 mucinex 
Guaifenesin, Guaibid La, Humibid L.a., Gua-Sr, Q-Bid La, Guaifenesin La, Aquamist, Guaifenex La, Guaifenesin Er, Amibid La, Fenesin, Mucobid L.a., Allfen-M, Muco-Fen-La, Sinumist-Sr, Guaifenesin-Sr, Respa-Gf, Liquibid, Ambi 600

 Uses 
Mucinex is used to relieve a dry cough and helps to loosen phlegm and mucous in the lungs so you can cough-up (expectorate) mucous.


 Storage 
 Store at room temperature between 59 and 86 degrees F (between 15 and 30 degrees C) away from moisture and sunlight. Do not store in the bathroom. Do not freeze liquid forms of Mucinex. Do not store syrup in the refrigerator.



 Overdose 
 If overdose is suspected, contact your local poison control center or emergency room immediately. Symptoms of overdose may include drowsiness, fatigue, weakness, dizziness, and unusually slow heartbeat.


 Photos 
 
Mucinex DM Tablets Drug 
mucinex.jpg 
Mucinex Expectorant, Guaifenesin 
Mucinex 600mg 500 tabs 
 

 How 
To Use 
 Take each dose of Mucinex with a full glass of water. Water will also help break-up the mucous and clear congestion. Drink plenty of fluids while taking Mucinex, unless your doctor instructs you otherwise. Do not take Mucinex for a chronic, persistent cough such as occurs with smoking or asthma unless directed by your doctor. If the cough lasts for more than one week, tends to recur, or is accompanied by a fever, headache or rash, consult your doctor.


 Side 
Effects 
 Mucinex may cause stomach upset or rash. If these effects persist or worsen, inform your doctor. If you notice other effects not listed above, contact your doctor or pharmacist.


 Precautions 
 If you have any of the following health problems, consult your doctor before using Mucinex: breathing problems such as emphysema/chronic bronchitis/asthma, smoking, any allergies. Mucinex should be used only when clearly needed during pregnancy. Discuss the risks and benefits with your doctor. It is not known if Mucinex is excreted into breast milk. Consult your doctor before breast-feeding.


 Missed 
Dose 
 If you miss a dose, take as soon as remembered; do not take if it is almost time for the next dose, instead, skip the missed dose and resume your usual dosing schedule. Do not double the dose to catch up.


 Drug 
Interactions 
 Tell your doctor of all the medicines you may use, (both prescription and nonprescription), especially: other cough-and-cold medicines. Guaifenesin may affect the results of certain lab tests. Be sure your caregivers are aware you use Mucinex before lab tests are performed. Do not start or stop any medicine without doctor or pharmacist approval.

 
 

 
 
 
 
 Add a Rating - Post your 
opinion about this drug 

 Post your opinion about mucinex 
 Ratings 
Legend 5 Stars = Excellent    4 Stars = Good    3 Stars = Average    2 Stars = Fair    1 Star  = Poor 

 *  Required 
Field poor excellent * Satisfaction 
 
 Low 
adverse Reactions 
 
 Healing 
Power 
 
 No 
dependency problems 
 
 Cost-Benefit 
 
 

 
 * Why 
were you taking mucinex ?
 
Briefly describe any side effects you experienced:
 

Additional Comments about mucinex :
 

 * Your gender: male   female  
 * Your 
age:    

Location : 

 * Length of time taking drug? Days Weeks Months Years Times 
 (use&quot;comments&quot;for other time 
length) 

Email (optional):   

 Posting rules 
 Please no foul language English only No 
commercial advertising No SPAM. No pyramid schemes of any kind Read 
before you post. No ALL CAPS, they are considered impolite 

If 
you don&apos;t follow the above rules, your post will be probably deleted.
 
 
 

 

 
 
 User Medicine 
Opinions for mucinex   
 
 
 
 Overall: 
 
 Low 
adverse Reactions Healing Power: No dependency problems: Cost-Benefit: 
 Sex: M
 Age: 83
 Location: Redding, Ca 96001
 Time Taken: 1 day days
 

 Reason: cough Date: 23 June 2010 
 Side 
Effects
 Took mucinex 600 mg in am&amp;the same eve I had chest pain&amp;breatging difficulty. It is lasting two whole days.

 Additional Thoughts
 I have never used this before&amp;have never had ththis breathing / pain problem before in chest.

 
 
 
 Overall: 
 
 Low 
adverse Reactions Healing Power: No dependency problems: Cost-Benefit: 
 Sex: M
 Age: 52
 Location: MI
 Time Taken: 3 days
 

 Reason: Sinus congestion in head and throat. Date: 18 February 2010 
 Side 
Effects
 Nosebleeds, 5 1/2 hours after taking Mucinex.

 Additional Thoughts
 Nosebleeds awaken me, clog nose, countering positive effect of Mucinex. Only nhaving nosebleed in one nostril, so at least I can still breathe. Consistent pattern over 2 years. I get postnsasl drip which gags me and makes feel like I can&apos;t breathe. although I can; true symptom is I cannot swallow. Regardless, I awake in a panic thinking I am dying. Mucinex relieves this.

 
 
 
 Overall: 
 
 Low 
adverse Reactions Healing Power: No dependency problems: Cost-Benefit: 
 Sex: F
 Age: 66
 Location: Mississippi
 Time Taken: months
 

 Reason: sinus infection Date: 12 January 2010 
 Side 
Effects
 I can take mucinex but not mucinex D because of my prolapsed mitral valve syndrome. Makes me too jittery. But plain mucinex works wonders!

 Additional Thoughts
 How long should one take mucinex. I&apos;ve been on it for a month. The sinus infection cleared and then I caught a cold. Mucinex is helping yet again! Is it all right to take for long periods of time? I would appreciate an email answer

 
 
 
 Overall: 
 
 Low 
adverse Reactions Healing Power: No dependency problems: Cost-Benefit: 
 Sex: M
 Age: 18
 Location: Maryland
 Time Taken: 4 days days
 

 Reason: Cough Date: 17 October 2009 
 Side 
Effects
 Nosebleeds

 Additional Thoughts
 It isn&apos;t workng I can&apos;t stop coughing.

 
 
 

 CONDITIONS 
OF USE: The information in this database is intended to supplement, not substitute 
for, the expertise and judgement of healthcare professionals. The information 
is not intended to cover all possible uses, directions, precautions, drug interactions 
or adverse effects, nor should it be construed to indicate that use of a particular 
drug is safe, appropriate or effective for you or anyone else. A healthcare professional 
should be consulted before taking any drug, changing any diet or commencing or 
discontinuing any course of treatment. 
 
 
 

 
 Large Text 
 
 Archive: All drugs - Links - Forum - Forum - Forum - Medical Topics 
Drug3k does not provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. 
0.014
Copyright (c) 2011 Drug3k Thursday, July 12, 2012
 Terms of use - Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
