<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003974" url="http://www.bakersfieldcalifornian.com/local/x1967163236/Sex-offender-takes-plea-deal-in-case-that-prompted-change-to-state-law" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="3" score="0.01912210130532819" bingtitle="Sex offender takes plea deal in case that prompted change to ..." webtitle="Sex offender takes plea deal in case that prompted change to ... - BakersfieldCalifornian.com">
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>Wednesday morning&apos;s hearing before Kern County ... She had agreed to meet him at a local fast-food restaurant, and ... How do I change my delivery address/phone number?</description>
	<body>
		Bakersfield.com Contact Us Subscriber Services Newsletters Mobile RSS Sitemap 
 
 News Jobs Homes Web Obits 
 
 TheBakersfieldCalifornian.com 
 Clear 81° LOW 104° HIGH 88° CURRENT 
 News Home 
 Subscribe: e-Edition Print&amp;e-Edition 
 Local 
 Breaking News Business Blogs Columnists Politics Californian Radio Social Media Special Sections Weather 
 Obits 
 Funeral Notices Funeral Directory Place an Obit 
 Sports 
 Preps BC CSUB Community Bakersfield Blaze Condors Outdoor/Fishing Motorsports 
 A&amp;E 
 Music Community Dining Art Theater Bakotopia.com KernEvents.com 
 Lifestyle 
 Columnists Health BakersfieldLife.com BakersfieldMom.com 
 Opinion 
 Our View Letters to the Editor Community Voices National Voices Submit a Letter BakersfieldTalks.com 
 Photos 
 News Community HS Sports Bakersfield Life 
 Business Guide 
 Find A Business New Reviews All Categories List Your Business 
 Buy&amp;Sell 
 Merchandise Pets&amp;Animals Service Directory Place An Ad 
 Homes 
 Resale Homes New Homes Rentals Foreclosures Real Estate News 
 Jobs 
 Search Videos Post A Resume Place An Ad 
 Drive 
 Search New Used Dealers Place An Ad 
 

 
 
Local News
 Home &gt; Local News Tweet My Yahoo Print Wednesday, Nov 02 2011 04:54 PM 
 Sex offender takes plea deal in case that prompted change to state law 

BY JASON KOTOWSKI Californian staff writer jkotowski@bakersfield.com
 
Convicted sex offender German Baeza pleaded no contest Wednesday to forcible sodomy and assault to commit rape in connection with sexually assaulting two teenage girls last year in a case that led to changes in notifying the public when a sex offender skips parole.

Prosecutor Melissa Allen said that Baeza agreed to a stipulated sentence of 30 years in prison. She said she&apos;s happy with the plea agreement, especially because the victims won&apos;t have to come to court and testify.
 
Fred Gagliardini, Baeza&apos;s attorney, said he advised his client to accept the plea deal because he was facing multiple life terms if convicted at trial. By taking the deal, 27-year-old Baeza could possibly have a couple of decades outside prison after serving his sentence.

Wednesday morning&apos;s hearing before Kern County Superior Court Judge Michael G. Bush took only a few minutes, Gagliardini said.

Sentencing is scheduled for Dec. 6.

Baeza cut off his ankle monitor July 5, 2010 and was on the loose two and a half weeks, police reported. The attacks happened during that time, police said.

Deputies said a 15-year-old girl reported being raped by a man, later identified as Baeza, she met on an Internet social networking site. She had agreed to meet him at a local fast-food restaurant, and after dinner he lured her into his vehicle by saying he would drive her to a family member&apos;s home.

Instead, he drove her to an orchard east of Bakersfield and raped her, deputies reported.

The other incident, investigated by Bakersfield police, happened in the north alley in the 700 block of Monterey Street, police reported. A 14-year-old girl walking through the alley was confronted by Baeza, who brandished a gun and forced her into a vehicle parked nearby.

Baeza tried to remove her pants, but she fought and managed to escape, police reported.

The California Department of Corrections and Rehabilitation notified local law enforcement when Baeza went missing, but the public wasn&apos;t notified because Baeza had not been classified as a violent sexual predator. Gov. Arnold Schwarzenegger issued an executive order in early August 2010 ordering the department to notify the public when a sex offender skips parole.

Baeza pleaded no contest to a rape charge in 2004 and was sentenced to six years in prison, according to the Kern County Superior Court website.
 Tweet My Yahoo Print close 
 Most Commented Most Popular 
 from the last 7 days 
 Kern divided on high-speed rail vote (14) 
Those who have watched intensely as the debate over California&apos;s high-speed rail project heated up continued to line up on two sides Friday -- some expressing delight, others dismay.
 Texas lures pioneering space firm from Mojave (12) 
Did Texas Gov. Rick Perry snatch a growing company from its home in Kern County? Or does California make it easy for companies to say adios? A commercial aerospace firm based in eastern Kern County announced Monday that it is expanding its operations to Texas, a move characterizied by some...
 LOIS HENRY: Something seems rotten at the VA facility here (5) 
Local veterans became alarmed last month after learning that a doctor at the Bakersfield Veterans Administration clinic had allegedly been taking confidential patient information including names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, addresses, etc., out of the facility -- possibly over...
 New bullet train plan &apos;mangled,&apos; perhaps illegal, ex-rail booster says (5) 
Even as the state Senate voted last week to approve California&apos;s $68 billion high-speed rail plan, opponents filed yet another lawsuit to stop the controversial construction project.
 
 from the last 7 days 
 One man dies, another injured in Coffee Road collision 
On July 4, at approximately 2:03 a.m. Bakersfield Police responded to the 1300 block of Coffee Road regarding a major injury traffic accident.
 Campbell Soup Co. to acquire Bolthouse 
Bolthouse Farms says the local agribusiness giant&apos;s acquisition by Cambden, N.J.-based Campbell Soup Co.
 Crash victim identified 
A motorist killed in a crash on Coffee Road Wednesday has been identified as 26-year-old Raul Angulo Lopez.
 For love and money: Married business owners balance personal with practical 
In Brooke and Brad Antonioni&apos;s old office, they sat back to back at their respective corner desks.
 
 

 
Bakersfield.com
 
 Wells Fargo to pay at least $175 million to settle bias in lending allegations Study: Bakersfield veterans find local housing more affordable Coble, Ronald Eugene Gadberry, Olive Greenlee, Mary Lou 
 
BakersfieldBuyandSell.com
 
Californian Photos
 
Bakosphere.com
 
 TIME LAPSE: Bakersfield to Woodland in a minute Bakersfield Christian alum headed to Olympics Angels star Trout doesn&apos;t think much of Bakersfield FOR SALE: This Lamborghini once prowled Bakersfield MUSIC VIDEO: Californian&apos;s bullet train to nowhere 
 
Facebook
 
 The Bakersfield Californian Bakotopia Bakersfield Daily Deal 
 
TehachapiBuyAndSell.com
 
BakersfieldCalifornian.com
 
 Wells Fargo to pay at least $175 million to settle bias in lending allegations Study: Bakersfield veterans find local housing more affordable Coble, Ronald Eugene Gadberry, Olive Greenlee, Mary Lou 
 
Twitter
 
 Matt Munoz 
Free Bakersfield community concerts continue TONITE: http://t.co/sRxMQwg1 # BCali # Bakersfield 
 The Bakersfield Cali 
We could see some thunder and lightning today http://t.co/7swgtSsY 
 
 
BakersfieldDrive.com
 
BakersfieldLife.com
 
 
 
BakersfieldVoice.com
 
 Promotional USB Drives - Adaptable and Moveable How Do You Link Two Monitors To 1 Laptop or computer? Natural Deodorant For Delicate Pores and skin Shangri-La Dinnerware For Your Asian-Impressed Table Get That Lovely Long Evening Gown And Be A Head Turner 
 
Bakotopia.com
 
 Club celebrates all things Irish Better move quickly if you want tickets A bike, an ipod, and a vacation... The Growlers&apos;Southern California-style experimentalism It&apos;s no catastrophe - it&apos;s fate 
 
Tehachapi News
 
 Red Flag Warning, thunderstorms predicted Motorhome fire ignites grass in Hart Flat area Alexis Schoenberg is 2012 Tehachapi Junior Miss Identity theft is on the rise locally TVRPD will hold special meeting Tuesday, July 10 
 
MyBakersfieldSports
 
 July 10: Community Sports Announcements Baseball : 12 year old Central California Cal Ripken State Champions Youth and Prep Basketball : SWOOSH Endless Summer League Set to Launch Ocean Fishing : Team Outlaws of Bakersfield Takes 1st Place in Bloodydecks 2012 Yellowtail Shootout Han&apos;s Taekwondo Has High Medal Count in Dallas 
 
Bakersfield Business Guide
 
 Featured Home - Jason Rodriguez with Keller Williams Combine&amp;SAVE!! - FARMERS | Ruth Escobar Insurance Agency&amp;Multi Service, Inc Save 20%!! - Tech Electronics septic tank pumping suwanee - septic tank pumping suwanee write my admissions essay - Edward J Thomas Law Offices 
 
Bakersfield Talks
 
 RosemarysAbortionist replied to the forum thread Dirty, Rotten, Lying Scoundrel in the topic National news James Harris replied to the forum thread Obie uses Executive Privilege to protect AG Holder from Contempt of Congress in the topic National news paxchristi3 replied to the forum thread Dirty, Rotten, Lying Scoundrel in the topic National news 
 
Californian Radio
 
 Californian Radio July 11, 2012 Californian Radio July 10, 2012 Californian Radio July 9, 2012 Californian Radio July 6, 2012 Californian Radio July 5, 2012 Californian Radio July 3, 2012 
 
Senior Healthcare Directory
 
The Kern County Senior Healthcare Directory is a resource for seniors, their families and caregivers, providing them with information and resources to help address health and lifestyle changes.

The Directory contains articles, checklist materials, and features business and services that specialize in assisting seniors and their loved ones with their changing needs.
 
Bakersfield Mom
 
 Another Meet-Up this week! Study: 1 in 4 teens has sent nude photos via text, email Frumpy Middle-Aged Mom: My kids are in hot water again Tip Tuesday: Healthy Hydration for Kids Survey: Top 10 ways kids hide their online activity from parents 
 
Bakersfield Wellness Magazine
 
B Well Magazine focuses on health and wellness issues designed for the Bakersfield lifestyle, with information from local people who inspire us to live well and local specialists including doctors and professionals who provide insight on ways to live healthier lives.
 
 Ask TBC | Customer Service 
 
 Name: 
 

 Email: 
 

 Question: 
 

 
 
 Name: 
 

 Email: 
 

 Category: 
 Print Subscription Online Subscription Classified Ads News Releases General Advertising General Newsroom Other 

 Comment: 
 

 
 Bakersfield.com Network Site Map 
News
 Breaking News 
 Local News 
 Obituaries 
 Sports 
 Business 
 Health 
 A&amp;E 
 Lifestyle 
 Staff Blogs 
 Politics 
 Opinion 
 Columnists 
 Weather 
 E-mail Newsletters 
 RSS Feeds 
 
Community
 Kern Events 
 Bakersfield Pictures 
 Worship Guide 
 Bakersfield Life 
 Bakersfield Voice 
 Tehachapi News 

Business Guide
 Find Businesses 
 List Your Business 
 All Categories 
 New Reviews 
 
Classifieds
 Jobs 
 Homes 
 Drive 
 Rentals 
 Stuff 
 Place An Ad 

Mobile
 661411.com 
 SMS Alerts 
 Android App 
 Blackberry App 
 iPhone App 
 
Advertise With Us
 Media Kit 
 Rate Cards 
 Contact Advertising 

Other Resources
 Contact Us 
 
 Californian Subscriber Services
 Phone: (661) 392-5777 
 Toll Free: 1-800-953-5353 
 Email: circulation@bakersfield.com 
 Office Hours: 
 Mon-Fri 5:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m. 
 Sat 5:30 to 10:30 a.m. 
 Sun 5:30 a.m. to Noon 
 Holidays 5:30 to 10:30 a.m. 

FAQs

 How do I report a missing paper or delivery problem? How do I place or resume a vacation hold? How do I change my delivery address/phone number? Click for more FAQs 
 
Copyright © 2012 The Bakersfield Californian

 Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | About Our Ads | Advertise With Us
	</body>
</document>
