<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003316" url="http://www.navigon.com/portal/int/produkte/navigationssysteme/navigon-plus/navigon-70-plus-eu-20_23-navi-vom-testsieger.html" time="2012-07-12-19:27" support="1" score="0.005173521694499393" bingtitle="NAVIGON 70 Plus Europe 23 | NAVIGON - a Garmin company." webtitle="NAVIGON 70 Plus Europe 23 | NAVIGON - a Garmin company.">
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>Do you place value on greater comfort in navigation? Do you want to be able ... know exactly how far away the nearest filling station or your favourite fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Navigon. All the world is yours. 

 Navigation überspringen 
 
 MyNAVIGON log-in International EN 
 
 Shop Products Maps and services Customer services MyNAVIGON About NAVIGON Navigon Flow 
 - Products - Navigation systems - NAVIGON Plus - NAVIGON 70 Plus Europe 23 

Practically hands-free navigation
 Please select a product Windows Phone 7 NAVIGON 42 Easy Europe 23 NAVIGON 92 Premium NAVIGON 70 Premium iPhone Android NAVIGON 70 Premium Live NAVIGON 92 Premium Live NAVIGON 92 Plus Europe 44 NAVIGON 42 Plus NAVIGON 72 Easy Europe 23 NAVIGON 72 Plus Europe 44 NAVIGON 40 Plus NAVIGON 20 Plus Europe 23 NAVIGON 70 Plus NAVIGON 72 Plus Live Europe 44 NAVIGON 72 Premium Europe 44 NAVIGON 42 Premium Europe 44 NAVIGON 70 Plus Live NAVIGON 70 Easy Europe 23 NAVIGON 20th Anniversary Edition NAVIGON 40 Easy Europe 23 NAVIGON 40 Premium NAVIGON 3310 max Europe 22 NAVIGON 8410 NAVIGON 20 Easy Europe 23 Windows Mobile / PDA NAVIGON 70 Plus Europe 23 NAVIGON 40 Premium Live NAVIGON 1400 NAVIGON 1410 NAVIGON 2410 NAVIGON 2400 NAVIGON 1300 NAVIGON 1310 NAVIGON 1410 Europe 22 NAVIGON 4350 max NAVIGON 7310 NAVIGON 4310 max NAVIGON 3310 max NAVIGON 3300 max NAVIGON 2510 Explorer NAVIGON 8450 Live NAVIGON 2510 Explorer Europe 23 NAVIGON 6310 NAVIGON 6350 Live 
 Overview 
 
 Overview Functions Design Maps Technical data 
 
NAVIGON 70 Plus Europe 23

 NAVIGON 70 Plus: the navigation device for virtually hands-free navigation from the award winners NAVIGON 
Do you place value on greater comfort in navigation? Do you want to be able to concentrate on the traffic more? Then Motion Sensor is what you need! With our NAVIGON 70 Plus, you can interact with the device without touching it. Thanks to our new Motion Sensor, all you have to do is move your hand towards the device and the NAVIGON MyBest POI display and Options menu will be revealed in the display. After a short while, the menu items will be hidden again and you will only be shown the information you need for navigation. Motion Sensor allows you to drive more safely in traffic with an eye on the road ahead. The NAVIGON 70 Plus offers significantly better orientation and a larger visible section of the map, thanks to its large 5&quot;display, so you can get to your destination as safely and relaxed as possible.

 

 Always find your way with the NAVIGON 70 Plus 
Use your navigation device to find your way around large cities with the Active Lane Assistant. The NAVIGON 70 Plus from the award winners NAVIGON shows you the best lane for you in a dynamic travelling animation. The Active Lane Assistant displays the stretch of road realistically and directs you in good time into the right lane. So you can be sure you’ll never miss another junction or exit again! With Text-to-Speech, the navigation device announces the distance to the next turn ahead of time. The NAVIGON 70 Plus also reads out road names and exits in plenty of time, so you can just concentrate on the traffic.
 
Active Lane Assistant

 Active Lane Assistant provides a realistic display of the actual route ahead, including bends, in a dynamic live animation. It lets you accurately estimate the distance to your next turn-off or lane change, and makes it even easier to see when and where you have to change to which lane. 

 EXPERIENCE MORE 
 
Motion Sensor

And you get all this only from multiple award winners NAVIGON: moving your hand near to the device displays or hides your three favourite special destinations and the options menu, and quickly ensures that you have a better overview on the display.

 EXPERIENCE MORE 
 
NAVIGON MyBest POI

Your three favourite points of interest, always at a glance: with the NAVIGON MyBest POIs function, you can choose your three favourite points-of-interest categories and see how far away you are from these POIs at the top of the display screen. So you’ll always know exactly how far away the nearest filling station or your favourite fast food restaurant is on your route. Or the nearest cinema or hotel. You decide what is displayed based on your individual requirements!

 EXPERIENCE MORE 
 
 Europe map with 23 countries Active Lane Assistant Motion Sensor 

 Download product info Download manual 
 Proceed to functions 
 Visa VisaElectron AmericanExpress MasterCard JCB Carte Bleue Maestro Maestro PayPal Cash on delivery Cash on delivery Prepayment Prepayment 
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Pay safely with your credit card. Your credit card will be charged directly after the sale is completed.
 
Payments via PayPal are always free. You can pay with just a few clicks as your data is safely saved with PayPal. What is more, your purchases will arrive sooner, as the payment reaches the retailer quickly.
 
Pay in cash upon delivery of your order. The dispatch company will charge an additional cash-on-delivery fee.
 
Pay in advance within seven days by bank transfer.
 
Social bookmarks:
 
© Thu Jul 12 19:27:23 CEST 2012
 Garmin Würzburg GmbH - All rights reserved
 
 NAVIGON international Site map Contact Imprint Data protection General Terms and Conditions Terms of use 
 Shop 
 Navigation systems Navigation software Maps and services Accessories Offers 
 Navigation systems 
 NAVIGON Plus NAVIGON Premium NAVIGON 92 Premium Live NAVIGON 72 Premium 
 Maps and services 
 FreshMaps Maps Software-Upgrades Live Services Safety&amp;Comfort Safety Camera Text-to-Speech Real Roadsign Pro NAVIGON LPG Filling Stations Curve Warner Circumnavigation of traffic congestion Premium TMC Traffic Live TMC activation Sound&amp;Fun Funny Voices Digital Codec Package 3D functions Panorama View 3D All-in-one 3D package City View 3D Reality View Landmark View 3D Travel guide The MICHELIN Green Guide Sightseeing Tours Sightseeing Food&amp;Hotels MICHELIN Restaurant and Hotel Guide ADAC Camping Guide Navigation profile Camper and Caravan Navigation Truck Navigation Points of interest All in one Health Food and drink Shopping Leisure activities Park&amp;Ride 
 Customer services 
 Questions and answers Report map errors NAVIGON newsletter 
 Press 
 News Journalist contact Twitter Facebook YouTube Flickr
	</body>
</document>
