<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003685" url="http://hotlinec.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:51" support="2" score="0.0018762569092489899" bingtitle="Hotline Engineering" webtitle="Hotline Engineering">
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="68"/>
	<description>College, Madrasa, Canteen, Fast Food, Restaurant, Hotels, Wedding hall, and domestic trade. ... Why only traditional get introduced special cold drink. Apple, litchi ...</description>
	<body>
		Copyright 2010 All Rights Reserved Hotline Engineering. SPECIAL FEATURES:- 
 
 Auto ON when Utility Power restores Auto Shutdown at Low Battery Battery Low Indication Beep Electronic Overload protection Controlled Frequency at 50 Hz Visual&amp;Audible Indications Microprocessor Controlled Regulated output voltage Noise less Operation Controlled charging PWM Technology Built in AVR, etc 
 more.... UPS TANKLESS WATER HEATER You can get instant hot water at any time with the hotline- No wait of hot water like geezer. Just turned tap and get hot water according to your need. it is very easy to fit, wel safe in use and easily repairable. It is very less than geezer in installation and working of geezer Hotline automatically works with the flow of water. 
 more.... more.... more.... more.... DRINK MAKER DRINK MAKER Commercial Make every type of bottle with slander filling facility in each city. 100 bottles production per hour. College, Madrasa, Canteen, Fast Food, Restaurant, Hotels, Wedding hall, and domestic trade. Ideal for everyone. Tastes that win the heart. Why only traditional get introduced special cold drink. Apple, litchi, strawberry, pomegranate and guava also look to try. 
        1-   Hotline water purifier is the latest sample of Mechanical Design. 2-   Three units of work done by one unit of Hotline water purifier. 3-   Hotline water purifier 50% better then the others. 4-   Used standard size cartridge that can be used any other filter.
	</body>
</document>
