<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003975" url="http://www.ethics.wv.gov/advisoryopinion/EthicsAO/Pages/default.aspx" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="1" score="0.00130502593649994" bingtitle="Ethics Advisory Opinions - Welcome to the West Virginia Ethics ..." webtitle="Ethics Advisory Opinions">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>... line item . 2010-14 County Board of Education Member County BOE may not contract with Member’s fast food restaurant to ... change ... County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		State Agency Directory | Online Services Text size A   A   A 
 Ethics Opinions Open Meetings Opinions Contract Exemptions ALJ Opinions School Board Opinions 
 
West Virginia
Ethics 
 Commission
 210 Brooks 
 Street, Suite 300
Charleston, WV 25301
 Phone 
(304) 558-0664
WV Toll Free
1-866-558-0664
 Fax 
(304) 558-2169
 Office Hours 
8:30 a.m. - 5:00 p.m.
Email comments and feedback to:
 ethics@wv.gov Ethics Commission &gt; Advisory Opinions &gt; Ethics Opinions 
Ethics Advisory Opinions 
 The West Virginia Ethics Commission Advisory Opinions listed below are available for viewing in .pdf format.

Advisory Opinions issued by the Commission at its most recent meeting are posted here by number in blue type. Please note that the opinions referenced in this section in blue are subject to reconsideration by the Commission at its next regular meeting, in the event a Commissioner who voted to approve the opinion asks to rescind his or her vote in accordance with Robert&apos;s Rules of Order.
Once an Advisory Opinion is no longer subject to reconsideration, it will be indexed and posted along with other precedential opinions in the Advisory Opinion Table below.

New Advisory Opinions issued:
 June 28, 2012 : A0 2012-20 ; AO 2012-22 ; AO 2012-23 ; AO 2012-25 ; AO 2012-26 ; AO 2012-27
 Tabled until next meeting, no opinion issued :  AO 2012-21; and AO 2012-24

Opinions that are available for viewing start with AO 2005-02. 

 To view the Index of  Ethics Advisory Opinions by Topic starting with 2005-02, click here: AO INDEX 

Numbers marked NP refer to advisory opinions that do not have precedential effect.  They are not available for viewing on this website. Numbers  marked void mean no opinion was issued, because the request was withdrawn.

Please contact the Commission office if you have any questions. (304) 558-0664.

 Note: Advisory Opinions open in a new window
 
 2005-2006 
 
 2007-2008 
 
 2009-2010 
 2011-2012 AO 2005-02 AO 2007-01 AO 2009-01 AO 2011-01 AO 2005-03 AO 2007-02 AO 2009-02 AO 2011-02 AO 2005-04 NP AO 2007-03 AO 2009-03 AO 2011-03 AO 2005-05 NP AO 2007-04 AO 2009-04 AO 2011-04 AO 2005-06 AO 2007-05 AO 2009-05 AO 2011-05 AO 2005-07 AO 2007-06 void AO 2009-06 AO 2011-06 NP AO 2005-08 AO 2007-07 AO 2009-07 AO 2011-07-void AO 2005-09 AO 2007-08 AO 2009-08 AO 2011-08 AO 2005-10 AO 2007-09 void AO 2009-09 AO 2011-09 AO 2005-11 AO 2007-10 AO 2009-10 AO 2011-10 AO 2005-12 AO 2007-11 AO 2009-11 AO 2011-11 AO 2005-13 AO 2007-12 AO 2009-12 NP AO 2011-12 AO 2005-14 AO 2007-13 AO 2009-13 NP AO 2011-13 AO 2005-15 AO 2007-14 AO 2009-14 AO 2011-14 AO 2005-16 AO 2007-15 NP AO 2010-01 AO 2011-15 AO 2005-17 void AO 2008-01 AO 2010-02 AO 2011-16 AO 2005-18 AO 2008-02 void AO 2010-03 AO 2011-17 AO 2005-19 NP AO 2008-03 AO 2010-04 AO 2011-18 AO 2005-20 NP AO 2008-04 NP AO 2010-05 AO 2011-19 AO 2005-21 AO 2008-05 AO 2010-06 AO 2011-20 AO 2005-22 AO 2008-06 AO 2010-07 AO 2011-21 AO 2005-23 AO 2008-07 AO 2010-08 AO 2011-22 AO 2006-01 AO 2008-08 AO 2010-09 AO 2012-01 AO 2006-02 NP AO 2008-09 AO 2010-10 AO 2012-02 AO 2006-03 AO 2008-10 AO 2010-11 AO 2012-03 AO 2006-04 AO 2010-12 void AO 2012-04 AO 2006-05 AO 2010-13 AO 2012-05 AO 2006-06 AO 2010-14 AO 2012-06 AO 2006-07 AO 2010-15 AO 2012-07 AO 2006-08 NP AO 2010-16 AO 2012-08 AO 2006-09 AO 2010-17 AO 2012-09 AO 2006-10 void AO 2010-18 AO 2012-10 void AO 2006-11 AO 2010-19 AO 2012-11 AO 2006-12 AO 2010-20 AO 2012-12 AO 2006-13 AO 2010-21 AO 2012-13 AO 2006-14 AO 2010-22 AO 2012-14 - void AO 2006-15 AO 2010-23 AO 2012-15 AO 2006-16 AO 2010-24 AO 2012-16 AO 2006-17 AO 2012-17 AO 2006-18 AO 2012-18 AO 2012-19 AO 2012-20 AO 2012-21-Tabled AO 2012-22 AO 2012-23 AO 2012-24-Tabled AO 2012-25 AO 2012-26 AO 2012-27 

 
In d e x of Ethics Opinions by Topic
(Indexed Opinions start with 2005-02

 Conflict of Interest 
Confidential Information
 Double Dipping 
 Employment
 Financial Disclosure
 Gifts – Acceptance and Solicitation
 Higher Education
 Lobbying 
 Persons Covered by the Act 
 Private Gain 
 Public Contracts 
 Public Contract Exemptions 
 Revolving Door
 Vote and Deliberate 
 W. Va. Code § 61-10-15 County Officers (Criminal Provision ) view §61-10-15 code text 


 CONFLI CT OF INTEREST 

 2005-11 State Official
No Ethics Act provision prohibits state elected official from holding appointed federal position, but State constitutional limitations may apply

 2006-01 County Solid Waste Authority
Rewards program for law enforcement officers reporting illegal dumps not permissible.

 2006-03 State Administrative Law Judge
Not prohibited from conducting outside law practice
May not represent individuals he regulates
May not use state resources for private business activities
 
2006-04 County Employee
Spouse’s work for developer does not bar him from providing support services to county agencies considering developer’s permit applications

 2006-05 Mayor
May not serve as Mayor and payroll clerk where Mayor supervises all town employees

 2006-06 State Legislator
May not use position to influence appropriations to non-profit employer

 2007-04 Assistant Attorney General
May send letter at own expense to clients he represented as government attorney advising of his move to private practice

 2007-05 County Commissioner
May provide information on web site for law practice which relates to his role as an elected Commissioner

 2007-07 Mayor
Appointment of Mayor’s son as City Attorney would create “inescapable” conflict of interest
 
2007-13 Administrative Law Judge
Permitted to engage in outside practice of law, provided certain limitations are followed

 2011-01 County Council Member
County Council Member’s business may appraise estates so long she recuses herself from any matters coming before the County Council involving the probate of any estate her business has appraised.County Council Member’s business may not appraise any estates over which the Sheriff has been appointed by the County Council as the administrator.  County Council Member’s business should be removed from the Fiduciary Supervisor’s list of available appraisers.
County Council Member may not appear, as a representative or witness, before the Council, either about the appraised value, or the amount of her compensation.
County Council Member may not accept protected persons from the Sheriff for placement in her nursing home, absent a contract exemption for the Sheriff.

 2011-02 County Council Member
County Council Member’s business may contract with a multi-county Conservation District under the following circumstances:
(1) the contract is let via a sealed bid process;
(2) the project is not funded by County money;
(3) the project is not the subject of an agreement between the District and the County including any agreement for flood control as authorized by W.Va. Code § 19-21A-13 ; and
(4) the affected Member recuses himself from the District’s appropriation request or any request for funding.

Opinion does not authorize the employment of County Commissioners or County Council Members, their spouses or dependents, by Conservation Districts in the County where they serve

 2011-09 County Hospital 
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of equipment and related services from appointed board member.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member so long as:  there are no financial conditions associated with the property transfer; and the body notifies the public of the member’s offer and allows other property owners to offer their property.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member even if there are unresolved issues requiring mitigation (e.g. environmental hazards, or outstanding liens), but only if an independent evaluation determines that the overriding benefit is to the governing body rather than the donor and it receives permission from the Ethics Commission.
 Modifies AO 95-09 by clarifying that the donation (as opposed to the leasing) of property does not constitute a public contract.

 2012-17 Presiding Officer of a house of West Virginia Legislature
 May not be retained to provide legal services to an Association which is actively engaged in lobbying Legislature on behalf of its members who are public employees.
Proposed employment contract presents an inescapable conflict, given the unique position held and power wielded by the presiding officer.
Access to confidential information may have chilling effect on other legislators, if proposed employment contract permitted.
Public may perceive that Association has hired him because of his unique ability to influence legislation.
Other Associations that do not employee a high ranking member of the Legislature may believe that they are at a disadvantage in the legislative process.
Opinion limited to Presiding Officers of houses of West Virginia Legislature.

 2012-19 Member of the Legislature
 May be retained to provide consulting services to Public University during and after his term of office.
Conflict of interest cured by his removal from potentially overlapping committees.
Must consult with Presiding Officer of his house and abide by appropriate legislative voting rule.
May not use influence of legislative position to attempt to affect the actions of University personnel to enhance his contractual benefits; introduce, sponsor or advocate legislation to benefit the University in any way; influence either the State’s distribution of federal grant money or State funds to the University for any purpose, not just those related to his consulting contract; or influence the appropriation of public funds to benefit the University in any way.

..................................................................................................
 CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION
 
 2012-17 Presiding Officer of a house of West Virginia Legislature
 May not be retained to provide legal services to an Association which is actively engaged in lobbying Legislature on behalf of its members who are public employees.
Proposed employment contract presents an inescapable conflict, given the unique position held and power wielded by the presiding officer.
Access to confidential information may have chilling effect on other legislators, if proposed employment contract permitted.
Public may perceive that Association has hired him because of his unique ability to influence legislation.
Other Associations that do not employee a high ranking member of the Legislature may believe that they are at a disadvantage in the legislative process.
Opinion limited to Presiding Officers of houses of West Virginia Legislature.

..................................................................................................

 DOUB LE DIPPING back to top 

 2006-06 State Legislator
Pay from private employer permitted during Legislative session, if consistent with job duties

 2008-05 County Parks&amp;Recreation Commission
A golf pro employed at a public golf course may accept pay for private lessons if he clocks
out before conducting the lesson.
..............................................................................................

 EMPLO YMENT: RESTRICTIONS back to top 

 2006-03 State Administrative Law Judge (h)
May not represent individuals he regulates while engaging in part-time private law practice

 2009-07 County Commissioner (g)
County  Commissioner, a private attorney, may prepare wills, but must fully recuse himself from County Commission&apos;s probate therof;
County Commissioner may not appear in a representative capacity in any probate proceeding before the County Commission, even if uncontested;
County Commissioner may testify as witness to will&apos;s validity before County Commission but must recuse himself from decision-making on any such will.

 2009-10 State Employee (h)
A State employee whose employer has accreditation oversight of institutions of higher education may be compensated for teaching a course at a public university so long as he
Notifies his supervisor;
Has his work relating to the accreditation of the public university as part of his doctoral program reviewed by his supervisor and his employing Agency&apos;s Review Board;
Prepares for and teaches the course on his own time;
Does not use any public resources
 
 2011-04 Per Diem Legislative Attorney 
Per Diem Legislative Attorney, who is not, on July 1, 2011, a Legislative employee as defined by the internal Revenue Service, is not subject to the newly enacted revolving door prohibition.
Independent contractors are not covered by the Ethics Act.

 2011-14 Candidate for County Assessor
 May not continue career as owner and broker of real estate business within county where he will serve, if elected.
May continue career as owner and broker of real estate business in other counties so long as he does not: use his official position in any way that would give him an advantage; conduct his business on county time; or use county resources (including staff) to conduct his private real estate business.

 2012-03 County Agency
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son, even though they live in the same house, so long as the Supervisor is completely removed from the hiring process. 
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son even though they live in the same house. 
 Supervisor employed by County Agency is not a county officer and therefore is not subject to provisions of W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
General rule:  Public servant should not supervise a relative.
Supervisor employed by County Agency may supervise son on emergency calls and while in the field.

 2012-04 Attorney for Municipal Water Board
General Rule:  Ethics Act does not prohibit Chairperson of Municipal Water Board from being employed by Board after resigning as Chairperson.
Job description so narrowly tailored that only Board’s Chairperson qualifies fails to satisfy requirements of nepotism guidelines.
When a public body knows in advance that one of its preferred candidates is a relative, close friend, or fellow member of the public body, public body must follow the Commission’s nepotism guidelines.

 2012-07 Mayor
may not use public resources for the benefit of his private business;
may not use subordinate staff to perform work associated with his private business while the subordinates are on the government time clock;
may not solicit private business from subordinates;
may not distribute promotional materials concerning his private business from his office and/or in City/Town Hall;
may not have an interest in a public contract, with certain exceptions;
must recuse himself when a current customer appears before Council; and
must recuse himself from: drafting bid specifications or requests for proposals;
recommending selection of the vendor; and/or
approving the method or manner of payment to the vendor; and
when serving as municipal judge, must:
if customer within past six months appears, disclose the fact thereof and recuse himself if either party requests; and
recuse himself from cases involving customers within the past six months.

 2012-17 Presiding Officer of a house of West Virginia Legislature
 May not be retained to provide legal services to an Association which is actively engaged in lobbying Legislature on behalf of its members who are public employees.
Proposed employment contract presents an inescapable conflict, given the unique position held and power wielded by the presiding officer.
Access to confidential information may have chilling effect on other legislators, if proposed employment contract permitted.
Public may perceive that Association has hired him because of his unique ability to influence legislation.
Other Associations that do not employee a high ranking member of the Legislature may believe that they are at a disadvantage in the legislative process.
Opinion limited to Presiding Officers of houses of West Virginia Legislature.

 2012-18 Registered Lobbyist
 Not required to register as lobbyist on behalf of client who retained her to provide advice on State procurement process and to serve as a liaison to a State Agency during client’s efforts to successfully bid on State contract.
Statutory definition of “lobbying” excludes procurement lobbying.
Required to register only if she communicates with State Officials or Members of the Legislature in regard to the passage or defeat of Legislation or Rules on client’s behalf.

 2012-19 Member of the Legislature
 May be retained to provide consulting services to Public University during and after his term of office.
Conflict of interest cured by his removal from potentially overlapping committees.
Must consult with Presiding Officer of his house and abide by appropriate legislative voting rule.
May not use influence of legislative position to attempt to affect the actions of University personnel to enhance his contractual benefits; introduce, sponsor or advocate legislation to benefit the University in any way; influence either the State’s distribution of federal grant money or State funds to the University for any purpose, not just those related to his consulting contract; or influence the appropriation of public funds to benefit the University in any way.

...........................................................................................................

 EMPLOYMENT: POST-EMPLOYMENT RESTRICTIONS back to top 

 2005-22 Former Public Official (g)
General counsel to Cabinet Secretary not barred from appearing before all agencies in department
One-year ‘revolving door’ prohibition applies to positions held on or after July 1, 2005
 
2007-04 Assistant Attorney General (f ) ( g)
Must wait 1 year before representing clients before state agency where he served

 2007-10 Former County Deputy Assessor  (f)
May operate consulting business relating to contesting property assessments where all property has been re-evaluated since person retired

 2010-22 Retired State Employee  (g)
May contract with his former agency within one year of his departure from the agency.
One year “cooling off” period prohibits elected and appointed public officials, full-time staff attorneys and accountants from appearing back before their former agencies.
Unit Leader not an appointed public official
An appointed public official’s position must be created by law

 2012-09 State Employee
 Not a public official subject to revolving door prohibitions
Ethics Act permits post retirement communication with former agency on general matters.Must seek advice from Commission before representing private interests regarding matters in which he was substantially involved. 

......................................................................................................

 FINANC IAL DISCLOSURE STATEMENTS back to top 
 
2008-01 Candidate for Public Office
Must disclose veteran’s disability benefits exceeding $1000 annually
May describe as “federal benefits” or “veterans benefits” on form
.....................................................................................

 GIFT S - ACCEPTANCE back to top 
 
 2006-07 State Employee
Hotel stay “door prize” won at conference hosted by State vendor may not be accepted

 2008-06 City Manager
May not accept free golf from vendor, consultant or other interested person in conjunction with annual association conference of public employees
Gift limitation applies even if funds from event go to charitable cause
Authorizes&quot;buy down&quot;with reduces gift to $25 limit

 2009-09 State Employee
It would violate the Ethics Act for certain State Agency employees to accept a lower lodging rate from a resort which the State Agency regulates.

 2010-02 Attorney for City
City may participate in a vendor&apos;s program to provide discount to city employees for personal cell phone use.

 2010-05 Public Employees / Higher Ed
Agency&apos;s decision to allocate more than $25 to recognize one or more employees, in lieu of expending up to $25 per employee per fiscal year, does not violate the Ethics Act so long as the expenditure on any one employee does not exceed $100, and the total amount expended for this purpose during the fiscal year does not exceed the sum total of $25 per employee.

 2010-11 State Legislator
May not accept two free airline tickets won in a random drawing at a public reception hosted by a State Agency for which the Legislature provides funds.
Prohibition against use of office for private gain applies to expenditures by public entities.

 2011-13 State Agency
Public funds may not be spent to pay for health club or gym fees for public servants when the hotel does not provide free exercise facilities to lodgers.
Public servants who receive an expense-paid trip to participate in a conference may not accept payment or reimbursement for health club or gym fees, when the hotel does not provide free exercise facilities to lodgers, and the total value of the fees exceeds $25.
Public servants who participate in a conference or event as a panelist or speaker may not accept payment or reimbursement for health club or gym fees when the hotel does not provide free exercise facilities to lodgers.

 2012-06 Elected Member of the Board of Public Works 
Public official may not endorse business or product of the sponsor of an international government forum that is paying travel expenses related to forum.
Must notify forum participants that the West Virginia Ethics Act prohibits him from endorsing a particular product and that presentation relating to fraud control should not be construed as endorsement of the sponsor’s business or product.
Appearance at international government forum paid for by business which has financial relationship with State provides benefit to West Virginia by allowing State to be recognized for achievements in fraud control and allowing first-hand observation of Australian state governments’ approach to financial management and procurement.
Must decline invitation to participate in proposed meetings with senior level government officials because these meetings do not provide an overriding benefit to the State of West Virginia.

........................................................................................

 GIFTS - SOLICITATION back to top 

 2005-02 County Board of Health
May solicit donations for public health programs
Establishes guidelines for non-coercive solicitation
 
2005-15 County Commissioner
Proceeds from calendar sales featuring county officers may only be used for charitable purposes

 2007-01 Association of Hunter Education Instructors
May solicit donations to support hunter safety education program and program for hunters with disabilities
Law enforcement personnel may not solicit for charity while on duty and in uniform [NOTE: Overrules AO 2004-07]
Prohibits issuance of window decals or bumper stickers to donors

 2010-01 Elected member of the Board of Public Works
May solicit donations to underwrite the costs of a national conference and use the funds for meals and breaks, and certain social events, excluding golf.
May acknowledge sponsors, but may not attribute an event to a single sponsor; may not indicate amount any sponsor donates.
Use of funds Legislature appropriated to pay for attendees&apos; meals does not constitute use of office for private gain.
Opinion limited to Elected Members of the Legislature of Elected Members of the Board of Public Works who are soliciting for national or regional conferences in accordance with W. Va. Code §§ 6B-2-5(c)(6) and 6B-2-5(c)(7).

 2010-17 State Agency  (non-precedential)
May solicit funds for itself, pursuant to its enabling legislation, without violating the Ethics Act. (non-precedential)
May use public resources, including public employees, pursuant to its enabling legislation, to solicit funds for itself, without violating the Ethics act. (non-precedential)
May not use public resources, including public employees, to solicit funds for its related private, non-profit organizations.  Implementation delayed until July1, 2011 (non-precedential)

 2010-19 - Elected Public Official
May not use public funds to purchase funeral flowers or other expressions of sympathy, including  monetary donations.
May not solicit subordinate employees for a contribution towards the purchase of flowers or payment into an established office fund.
May take up a voluntary donation among co-workers, under certain conditions.

 2010-23 County Board of Education
May not use public resources, including personnel, to promote the passage of an excess levy wherein school personnel are the primary beneficiaries.
County Superintendent, as the appointed voice of the County BOE, may advocate for passage of any excess levy.
County Superintendent’s advocacy for passage of an excess levy constitutes the performance of usual and customary duties associated with the position permitted by the Ethics Act
 
 2011-11 State Agency 
May accept funds for its Recreation Department, pursuant to its enabling legislation.
May solicit funds for its Recreation Department, under certain conditions:  solicitation must benefit residents, not public servants; may not endorse a donor business; must comply with Legislative Rule if soliciting vendors; may not solicit a subordinate or Agency client; and may not use Agency clients to solicit.

 2012-08 Municipal Police Department
 Ethics Act prohibits the solicitation of donations to purchase a police canine and gun racks for police cars.
Ethics Act permits Department to accept the unsolicited contribution of funds to purchase a police canine and gun racks for police cars

............................................................................

 HIGHER EDUCATION back to top 

 2011-05 University President
May spend public funds to pay membership dues for the President, but not the President’s spouse, to join the local Rotary club.
Public funds may only be spent for President’s membership dues (and one-time new member fee), not on meals or any other cost or fee associated with Rotary membership, such as contributions to a related philanthropic organization.
Ethics Act does not prohibit the University Foundation—a separate, non-government entity—from paying for the spouse’s membership in Rotary and/or for paying for meals associated with Rotary meetings or functions for the President and/or the President’s spouse.
Higher Education exemption available only when the activity has been approved as part of the employment contract.

......................................................................................................................

 LO BBYING back to top 

 2005-08 Registered Lobbyist
2005 amendments to Act require multiple employees of lobbying firm to pay additional $100 filing fee for each client they represent

 2005-21 Private Company
Employees whose regular duties involve sales may participate in a “Day at the Capitol” without registering as lobbyists

 2007-12 Non-Profit Corporation
Inviting all Legislators to a charitable fund raising event during regular Legislative session triggers lobbyist registration requirement
Host organization may provide free tickets to Legislators for reception where food and beverages are served even if ticket price exceeds $25
Businesses who contribute to event not required to report contributions

 2008-06 City Manager
May not accept free golf from vendor, consultant or other interested person in conjunction with annual association conference of public employees
Gift limitation applies even if funds from event go to charitable cause
Authorizes&quot;buy down&quot;which reduces gift to $25 limit

 2010-07 Registered Lobbyist
Must register as lobbyist for entity even if she lobbies for free since she is already a registered lobbyist for another entity, therefore she must identify both her paying and non-paying clients.



 2011-04 Per Diem Legislative Attorney 
Per Diem Legislative Attorney, who is not, on July 1, 2011, a Legislative employee as defined by the internal Revenue Service, is not subject to the newly enacted revolving door prohibition. Independent contractors are not covered by the Ethics Act.

 2011-19 - A State Licensing Board
 May spend public funds to hire registered lobbyist, to serve as a Legislative liaison.
Registered lobbyist retained by public agency as Legislative liaison must register as a lobbyist
Revolving door prohibition does not apply to contract employee/former executive director who terminated employment before July 1, 2011 cut-off date.

 2012-17 Presiding Officer of a house of West Virginia Legislature
 May not be retained to provide legal services to an Association which is actively engaged in lobbying Legislature on behalf of its members who are public employees.
Proposed employment contract presents an inescapable conflict, given the unique position held and power wielded by the presiding officer.
Access to confidential information may have chilling effect on other legislators, if proposed employment contract permitted.
Public may perceive that Association has hired him because of his unique ability to influence legislation.
Other Associations that do not employee a high ranking member of the Legislature may believe that they are at a disadvantage in the legislative process.
Opinion limited to Presiding Officers of houses of West Virginia Legislature.

 2012-19 Member of the Legislature
 May be retained to provide consulting services to Public University during and after his term of office.
Conflict of interest cured by his removal from potentially overlapping committees.
Must consult with Presiding Officer of his house and abide by appropriate legislative voting rule.
May not use influence of legislative position to attempt to affect the actions of University personnel to enhance his contractual benefits; introduce, sponsor or advocate legislation to benefit the University in any way; influence either the State’s distribution of federal grant money or State funds to the University for any purpose, not just those related to his consulting contract; or influence the appropriation of public funds to benefit the University in any way.

.................................................................................................

 PERSONS COV ERED BY THE ACT back to top 

 2005-09 County School Superintendent
School Superintendent’s service on Board of Directors of private organization does not subject organization to Ethics Act jurisdiction

 2010-09 County Rescue Service
Members and employees of a nonprofit corporation which is not a public entity are not covered by the Act, even though three of the seven members are appointed by the county commission, the corporation is funded by county ambulance fees, and the county commission reviews and approves its budget.



 2011-04 Per Diem Legislative Attorney 
Per Diem Legislative Attorney, who is not, on July 1, 2011, a Legislative employee as defined by the internal Revenue Service, is not subject to the newly enacted revolving door prohibition.
Independent contractors are not covered by the Ethics Act.

..................................................

 PRIVATE GA IN back to top 
 
2005-10 State Division Director
Division Director in agency which regulates motor vehicle dealers may not appear in commercials advertising automobile dealer even though his division does not regulate dealers

 2005-16 County Health Department Employee
May reference professional certification which employer paid for in advertising for private consulting business

 2006-13 County Commissioner
Use of county resources to provide shuttle services for a private picnic is not permitted

 2006-14 State Board Members
May not conduct training programs for third-parties regulated by their Board without a written waiver from the Ethics Commission
Exec Dir may grant temporary waiver which must be ratified by Commission

 2006-17 County School Teacher
Teacher who directs Show Choir may not sell music compositions to be performed by choir he directs

 2008-05 County Parks&amp;Recreation commission
May authorize employees to play golf for free under certain conditions

 2008-07 Town Council
May authorize employees to use town swimming pool for free as fringe benefit of employment

 2008-09 Public University
May give discount to faculty and staff on bookstore purchases
[notes: partially overrules AO 2001-21 only applies to higher education institutions

 2009-02 Elected County Officials
County Funded Employee Wellness Program may not be extended to elected county officials whose compensation is set by statue( § 7-5-20)
To increase compensation (through the extension of benefits) beyond statutory maximum constitutes use of office for private gain.

 2009-03 County Employees
May be reimbursed for government calls placed on personal cell phone

 2009-07 County Commissioner
County Commissioner, a private attorney, may prepare wills, but must fully recuse himself from County Commission&apos;s probate therof;
County Commissioner may not appear in a representative capacity in any probate proceeding before the County Commission, even if uncontested;
County Commissioner may testify as witness to will&apos;s validity before County Commission but must recuse himself from decision-making on any such will.

 2009-08 Board of Directors of State Agency
Board members associated with entities which may have financial interest in Agency&apos;s contracts may not serve on subcommittee which reviews and recommends funding proposals.
Board members associated with entities which may have financial interest in Agency&apos;s contracts may continue to serve on Board, but must recuse themselves from discussion, deliberation and decision-making on matters related to those entities with which they are associated.

 2009-09 State Employee
It would violate the Ethics Act for certain State Agency employees to accept a lower lodging rate from a resort which the State Agency regulates.

 2009-10 State Employee
A State employee whose employer has accreditation oversight of institutions of higher education may be compensated for teaching a course at a public university so long as he
Notifies his supervisor;
Has his work relating to the accreditation of the public universityas part of his doctoral program reviewed by his supervisor and his employing Agency&apos;s Review Board;
Prepares for and teaches the course on his own time;
Does not use any public resources

 2009-12 Elected Member, Board of Public Works
Payroll deductions to purchase products does not consitute use of office for private gain since all businesses have equal opportunity to participate.
Neither state official nor his office may endorse any product offered through payroll deduction.

 2010-01 Elected member of the Board of Public Works
May solicit donations to underwrite the costs of a national conference and use the funds for meals and breaks, and certain social events, excluding golf.
May acknowledge sponsors, but may not attribute an event to a single sponsor; may not indicate amount any sponsor donates.
Use of funds Legislature appropriated to apy for attendees&apos; meals does not constitute use of office for private gain.
Opinion limited to Elected Members of the Legislature of Elected Members of the Board of Public Works who are soliciting for national or regional conferences in accordance with W. Va. Code §§ 6B-2-5(c)(6) and 6B-2-5(c)(7).

 2010-02 Attorney for City
City may participate in a vendor&apos;s program to provide discount to city employees for personal cell phone use.

 2010-03 County Board of Education Candidate
Spouse of county BOE member may be employed as Chief mechanic, a service position that meets exception in § 61-10-15.
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2010-04 County Board of Education Member
Board may contract with a private non-profit when one of the Board of Education members sits on the Board of the non-profit so long as the common Board member does not vote on any matters relating to the non-profit and recuses himself from the decision-making process and vote. (This portion overruled by AO 2011-12; common Board member is no longer required to recuse himself, and may vote.)
 
 2010-05 Public Employees / Higher Ed
Agency&apos;s decision to allocate more than $25 to recognize one or more employees, in lieu of expending up to $25 per employee per fiscal year, does not violate the Ethics Act so long as the expenditure on any one employee does not exceed $100, and the total amount expended for this purpose during the fiscal year does not exceed the sum total of $25 per employee.

 2010-08 City Elected Officials
Public official may not vote to extend his or her own current term beyond that statutorily or constitutionally prescribed - to do so would be use of office for private gain.

 2010-10 Board of Directors of a County Authority
Ethics Act does not prohibit part time appointed officials from bidding at auction on items sold by Board on which they serve, so long as they recuse themselves from all related matters; but § 61-10-15 prohibits part time appointed officials from bidding at auction on items sold by Board on which they serve.

 2010-11 State Legislator
May not accept two free airline tickets won in a random drawing at a public reception hosted by a State Agency for which the Legislature provides funds.
Prohibition against use of office for private gain applies to expenditures by public entities.

 2010-13 County Board of Education Member
Spouse of County BOE member may be employed as auditor in Central Office, a service position that meets exception in § 61-10-15.
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.
May not vote on matters specific to his wife including raise, renewal of employment contract, or discipline.
May vote on overall budget, but must recuse himself if line item affects wife or all four auditors if BOE specifically addresses any such line item .

 2010-14 County Board of Education Member
County BOE may not contract with Member’s fast food restaurant to provide food for special events
County schools and/or school sports teams may not contract with County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant to provide food for school sports teams using school funds
County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant may not sponsor fundraisers on behalf of school teams
County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant may, under certain conditions, sponsor fundraisers on behalf of booster organizations
County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant may, under certain conditions, sell food to credit union even though BOE provides office space to credit union

 2010-15 County Board of Education Member
County BOE Member may not be paid to officiate as a sports official in his own county
County BOE Member may volunteer as a referee and receive $1 to obtain insurance coverage

 2010-16 County Board of Education Member
County BOE Member may contract with State Department of Education for online teaching even though some teachers from her county may participate.
Subject contract with State, not County BOE, and thus Member lacks control over contract
County BOE Member lacks control over County BOE’s reimbursement of county teachers’ expenses incurred in taking Member’s online course .

 2010-17 State Agency  (non-precedential)
May solicit funds for itself, pursuant to its enabling legislation, without violating the Ethics Act. (non-precedential)
May use public resources, including public employees, pursuant to its enabling legislation, to solicit funds for itself, without violating the Ethics act. (non-precedential)
May not use public resources, including public employees, to solicit funds for its related private, non-profit organizations.  Implementation delayed until July1, 2011 (non-precedential)

 2010-18 City Council
May use public funds to purchase Sam&apos;s Club cards for the City&apos;s use.
May not use public funds to purchase Sam&apos;s Club cards for the personal use of its employees or their family members.
City officials and employees may not use the City&apos;s card to gain admission to the Sam&apos;s club and/or to make personal purchases.

 2010-19 - Elected Public Official
 May not use public funds to purchase funeral flowers or other expressions of sympathy, including monetary donations.
May not solicit subordinate employees for a contribution towards the purchase of flowers or payment into an established office fund.
May take up a voluntary donation among co-workers, under certain conditions.

 2011-01 County Council Member
 County Council Member’s business may appraise estates so long she recuses herself from any matters coming before the County Council involving the probate of any estate her business has appraised.County Council Member’s business may not appraise any estates over which the Sheriff has been appointed by the County Council as the administrator.  County Council Member’s business should be removed from the Fiduciary Supervisor’s list of available appraisers.
County Council Member may not appear, as a representative or witness, before the Council, either about the appraised value, or the amount of her compensation.
County Council Member may not accept protected persons from the Sheriff for placement in her nursing home, absent a contract exemption for the Sheriff.

 2011-05 University President
 May spend public funds to pay membership dues for the President, but not the President’s spouse, to join the local Rotary club.
....Public funds may only be spent for President’s membership dues (and one-time new member fee), not on meals or any other cost or fee associated with Rotary membership, such as contributions to a related philanthropic organization.
....Ethics Act does not prohibit the University Foundation—a separate, non-government entity—from paying for the spouse’s membership in Rotary and/or for paying for meals associated with Rotary meetings or functions for the President and/or the President’s spouse.
.....Higher Education exemption available only when the activity has been approved as part of the employment contract.

 2011-06 County Public Service District Member
 An appointed board member, who in his private capacity has participated in other rate cases related to a particular utility company, may not participate in the PSD’s deliberations and actions related to the PSD’s role in the West Virginia Public Service Commission’s investigation of that utility company.
Although not expressly prohibited by the voting provision of the Ethics Act since he is a member of a class of five or more, the member’s membership in the Home Owners Association, as well as his representative advocacy on its behalf, constitute a personal interest.
There could be an appearance that the member is using the PSD to bring suit in the District’s name for his personal benefit, thus constituting the prohibited use of public office for private gain.

 2011-08 Part-Time Prosecuting Attorney
 Part-Time Prosecuting Attorneys may continue to use office space in their respective county courthouses for their private law practices without reimbursing the County for the pro-rata rental value thereof.
Part-Time Prosecuting Attorneys may continue to use public resources, including office equipment and staff in their respective county courthouses for their private law practices, but must reimburse the County for the pro-rata rental value thereof, or make direct payment for such equipment and/or services.
Assistant Prosecuting Attorneys may not use courthouse office space, equipment, supplies or staff for their private law practices.

 Overrules AOs 89-15, 89-27 and 91-61. 

 2011-09 County Hospital 
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of equipment and related services from appointed board member.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member so long as:  there are no financial conditions associated with the property transfer; and the body notifies the public of the member’s offer and allows other property owners to offer their property.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member even if there are unresolved issues requiring mitigation (e.g. environmental hazards, or outstanding liens), but only if an independent evaluation determines that the overriding benefit is to the governing body rather than the donor and it receives permission from the Ethics Commission.
 Modifies AO 95-09 by clarifying that the donation (as opposed to the leasing) of property does not constitute a public contract.

 2011-10 County Board of Education (BOE)
 Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may not be employed as Director of Student Services, a prohibited administrative position under W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may be employed as School Psychologist, a position that meets the exception in W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may be continue to be physically located in the central office without violating W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.  The nature of the work performed, not location, is outcome determinative.
Superintendent may not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2011-11 State Agency 
May accept funds for its Recreation Department, pursuant to its enabling legislation.
May solicit funds for its Recreation Department, under certain conditions:  solicitation must benefit residents, not public servants; may not endorse a donor business; must comply with Legislative Rule if soliciting vendors; may not solicit a subordinate or Agency client; and may not use Agency clients to solicit.



 2011-12 Town Attorney
Town’s elected officials may vote to appropriate funds to a non-profit organization on which they and/or their family members serve as uncompensated board members and/or officers.

 Overrules portion of AO 2010-04 wherein member of a non-profit board was prohibited from voting as a member of the Board of Education. 

 2011-13 State Agency
Public funds may not be spent to pay for health club or gym fees for public servants when the hotel does not provide free exercise facilities to lodgers.
Public servants who receive an expense-paid trip to participate in a conference may not accept payment or reimbursement for health club or gym fees, when the hotel does not provide free exercise facilities to lodgers, and the total value of the fees exceeds $25.
Public servants who participate in a conference or event as a panelist or speaker may not accept payment or reimbursement for health club or gym fees when the hotel does not provide free exercise facilities to lodgers.

 2011-14 Candidate for County Assessor
 May not continue career as owner and broker of real estate business within county where he will serve, if elected.
May continue career as owner and broker of real estate business in other counties so long as he does not: use his official position in any way that would give him an advantage; conduct his business on county time; or use county resources (including staff) to conduct his private real estate business.

 2011-17 - State Licensing Board
 Executive Directors and Members of the Board may be members of professional associations consisting of licensees which the Boards regulate.
Members may be officers of professional associations consisting of licensees which the Boards regulate, with limitations.
Executive Director may not be an officer of or employed by a professional association consisting of licensees which the Board regulates.

 2011-18 - Industry representatives on the governing council of a State Agency
 May not serve on the initial review panel for grant applications.
May not serve on the comittee to draft legislative rules relating to the award of grants.
May participate as a member of council, and vote on approval of recommended grant application absent a prohibited interest necessitating recusal.
May participate as a member of council, and vote on draft legislative rules relating to the award of grants absent a prohibited interest necessitating recusal.

 2011-19 - A State Licensing Board
 May spend public funds to hire registered lobbyist, to serve as a Legislative liaison.
Registered lobbyist retained by public agency as Legislative liaison must register as a lobbyist
Revolving door prohibition does not apply to contract employee/former executive director who terminated employment before July 1, 2011 cut-off date.

 2011-20 An Elected County Commissioner
 May purchase tax liens at a Sheriff&apos;s sale or through the State Auditor&apos;s Office, or both, when County Commission had no direct involvement in the assessment of the property.
May not purchase a tax lien on property for which the owner requested adjustment of assessed value or other relief from County Commission sitting as the board of equalization and review.

 2011-21 A City
 May adopt ordinance or change charter to compensate Mayor at flat rate of pay for extra duties not statutorily required of the mayor; provided, that, the change becomes effective for the next term of office.
 
 2011-22 State Agency employee 

Ethics Act does not prohibit employee of State agency from serving on board of non-profit organization that State agency funds

 2012-01 Mayor
 Ethics Act does not prohibit city employed building inspector from serving on City Council, but he must perform his Council duties on his own time, not during his public work hours.  Ethics Act does not prohibit a building inspector/city employee from serving on City Council.
City council member employed by city may not vote on a personnel matter which affects him directly as opposed to affecting five or more employees in the same or similar manner.
City employed building inspector serving on City Council must recuse himself when citizens who are affected by his official actions come before City Council to address or dispute his official actions. 

 2012-02 County Commissioner
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County from purchasing property from real estate business with which a County Commissioner is associated, with limitations:  Commissioner may not use his position to influence purchase of the property; specifically, he may not communicate with fellow County Commissioners, or Members or staff of the Building Commission, on matters relating to the property.
No prohibited financial interest where neither Commissioner nor his immediate family members have ownership interest in property County Commission seeks to purchase from real estate business with which he is associated.
No prohibited financial interest where Commissioner is not: a director or officer; the listing agent for the property; or, entitled to receive any commission from the sale of the property.
County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County meets statutory exemption so long as he recuses himself.  ( See Voting) 
 County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County must recuse himself from all matters related thereto.

 2012-03 County Agency
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son, even though they live in the same house, so long as the Supervisor is completely removed from the hiring process. 
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son even though they live in the same house. 
 Supervisor employed by County Agency is not a county officer and therefore is not subject to provisions of W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
General rule:  Public servant should not supervise a relative.
Supervisor employed by County Agency may supervise son on emergency calls and while in the field.

 2012-04 Attorney for Municipal Water Board
General Rule:  Ethics Act does not prohibit Chairperson of Municipal Water Board from being employed by Board after resigning as Chairperson.
Job description so narrowly tailored that only Board’s Chairperson qualifies fails to satisfy requirements of nepotism guidelines.
When a public body knows in advance that one of its preferred candidates is a relative, close friend, or fellow member of the public body, public body must follow the Commission’s nepotism guidelines.



 2012-06 Elected Member of the Board of Public Works 
Public official may not endorse business or product of the sponsor of an international government forum that is paying travel expenses related to forum.
Must notify forum participants that the West Virginia Ethics Act prohibits him from endorsing a particular product and that presentation relating to fraud control should not be construed as endorsement of the sponsor’s business or product.
Appearance at international government forum paid for by business which has financial relationship with State provides benefit to West Virginia by allowing State to be recognized for achievements in fraud control and allowing first-hand observation of Australian state governments’ approach to financial management and procurement.
Must decline invitation to participate in proposed meetings with senior level government officials because these meetings do not provide an overriding benefit to the State of West Virginia.

 2012-07 Mayor
may not use public resources for the benefit of his private business;
may not use subordinate staff to perform work associated with his private business while the subordinates are on the government time clock;
may not solicit private business from subordinates;
may not distribute promotional materials concerning his private business from his office and/or in City/Town Hall;
may not have an interest in a public contract, with certain exceptions;
must recuse himself when a current customer appears before Council; and
must recuse himself from: drafting bid specifications or requests for proposals;
recommending selection of the vendor; and/or
approving the method or manner of payment to the vendor; and
when serving as municipal judge, must:
if customer within past six months appears, disclose the fact thereof and recuse himself if either party requests; and
recuse himself from cases involving customers within the past six months.

 2012-11 County Commissioner
 Ethics Act permits living with county employee so long as nepotism rules followed.
W. Va. Code § 61-10-15 prohibits living with county employee even if nepotism rules followed and/or even if employee transferred to another county office.

 2012-12 Local Board of Health
 Board of Health’s part-time appointed Health Officer may accept patient referrals from the Health Department so long as s/he does not make, participate in making, or in any way attempt to use his or her office or employment to influence a government decision affecting his or her financial or limited financial interest.
Full-time health officer may not contract with own Board of Health unless Board seeks and receives advice or a contract exemption from Ethics Commission.
Local Board of Health formed by a county and a municipality not subject to strict provisions of § 61-10-15.
County Boards of Health are subject to strict provisions of § 61-10-15; their health officers (part time and full-time) may not contract with own Board of Health unless Board seeks and receives advice or a contract exemption from Ethics Commission.

 2012-13 Member of a County Board of Education (BOE)
 May contract with a public university to supervise university students during their placement in public schools in the county where he serves so long as he does not use any public resources, including BOE staff, to perform his private contractual duties.
Agreement between public university and BOE not a public contract.

 2012-15 Sheriff
 May use his public title to endorse Chief Deputy or other candidate for public office, including through newspaper advertisements or radio announcements.
 May not spend public funds for these purposes.
 
 2012-16 County Commission
 Prohibited from purchasing private property from appointed member of County Building Commission.
Purchase of property from appointed member creates impermissible conflict and a prohibited interest in a public contract.
May seek Contract Exemption if it believes the property is only viable option.

 2012-17 Presiding Officer of a house of West Virginia Legislature
 May not be retained to provide legal services to an Association which is actively engaged in lobbying Legislature on behalf of its members who are public employees.
Proposed employment contract presents an inescapable conflict, given the unique position held and power wielded by the presiding officer.
Access to confidential information may have chilling effect on other legislators, if proposed employment contract permitted.
Public may perceive that Association has hired him because of his unique ability to influence legislation.
Other Associations that do not employee a high ranking member of the Legislature may believe that they are at a disadvantage in the legislative process.
Opinion limited to Presiding Officers of houses of West Virginia Legislature.

..............................................................................................................

 PUBLIC CONTR ACTS back to top 

 2007-03 County Assessor
Continued employment of Assessor’s fiancé&apos; in Assessor’s Office following marriage to County Assessor would not violate (d) but would violate W. Va. Code § 61-10-15

 2007-08 Public School Teacher
May enter into vending services contract with school system by which he is employed

 2007-11 Municipal Utilities Commission Board Member
Commission may contract with company owned by part-time appointed Board Member to install water tank, provided Member is recused

 2008-08 City Attorney
Conflict would arise from spouse&apos;s business contracting with city
Full-time City attorney is equivalent to a General Counsel or Prosecuting Attorney with inherent authority over municipal contracting.

 2010-04 County Board of Education Member
Board may contract with a private non-profit when one of the Board of Education members sits on the Board of the non-profit so long as the common Board member does not vote on any matters relating to the non-profit and recuses himself from the decision-making process and vote. ( This portion overruled by AO 2011-12; common Board member is no longer required to recuse himself, and may vote.)

 2010-06 Public Library
Ethics Act&apos;s prohibition against interest in public contract does not apply to part-time appointed official.
Board member whose law firm represents library may serve on the board, but must recuse himself from all matters related to the law firm&apos;s contract.
Board member of Public Library created by Special Act of the Legislature and joint venture of county and city entities not subject to § 61-10-15.

 2008-10 County Commissioner
Contract between County Airport Authority and business owned by County Commissioner not subject to prohibition where Commissioner does not serve on Airport Authority (but see 61-10-15)

 2009-08 Board of Directors of State Agency
Board members associated with entities which may have financial interest in Agency&apos;s contracts may not serve on subcommittee which reviews and recommends funding proposals.
Board members associated with entities which may have financial interest in Agency&apos;s contracts may continue to serve on Board, but must recuse themselves from discussion, deliberation and decision-making on matters related to those entities with which they are associated.

 2009-11 Board of Education / Assistant Principal
Assistant Principal is subject to the prohibitions in § 61-10-15.
Assistant Principal has voice, influence, or control over subject Board of Education contract affecting his school by virtue of his responsibility to oversee all school activities at his school.
Board of Education may not contract with Assistant Principal&apos;s private business to provide after-school driver&apos;s education program to County students.

 2010-03 County Board of Education Candidate
Spouse of county BOE member may be employed as Chief mechanic, a service position that meets exception in § 61-10-15.
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2010-04 County Board of Education Member
Board may contract with a private non-profit when one of the Board of Education members sits on the Board of the non-profit so long as the common Board member does not vote on any matters relating to the non-profit and recuses himself from the decision-making process and vote. (This portion overruled by AO 2011-12; common Board member is no longer required to recuse himself, and may vote.) 
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2010-10 Board of Directors of a County Authority
Ethics Act does not prohibit part time appointed officials from bidding at auction on items sold by Board on which they serve, so long as they recuse themselves from all related matters; but § 61-10-15 prohibits part time appointed officials from bidding at auction on items sold by Board on which they serve.

 2010-14 County Board of Education Member
Regarding sales to schools and booster clubs from his restaurant

 2010-15 County Board of Education Member
County BOE Member may not be paid to officiate as a sports official in his own county
County BOE Member may volunteer as a referee and receive $1 to obtain insurance coverage

 2010-16 County Board of Education Member
County BOE Member may contract with State Department of Education for online teaching even though some teachers from her county may participate.
Subject contract with State, not County BOE, and thus Member lacks control over contract
County BOE Member lacks control over County BOE’s reimbursement of county teachers’ expenses incurred in taking Member’s online course .

 2010-20 Conservation Districts
May not spend public funds (in excess of $1,000) to construct project on an Elected Board Member’s property, absent a contract exemption.
Public contract provision in Ethics Act contains no exception for part-time elected officials.
Not subject to the prohibitions of West Virginia Code § 61-10-15.

 2010-21 - County Board of Education
Ethics Act does not prohibit contract with a private club in which an Elected Board Member and Treasurer own less than five percent of the outstanding shares of stock.
May not contract with a private club in which an Elected Board Member, Treasurer and spouse of the Superintendent own stock, absent a contract exemption, due to the prohibitions of West Virginia Code § 61-10-15.
May not contract with a business with which public officials or their spouses serve as a director, pursuant to the Ethics Act.

 2010-24 Board of Education
May purchase property owned, in part, by a Sheriff’s Chief Tax Deputy.
Chief Tax Deputy does not exercise control over BOE contracts.
Chief Tax Deputy not subject to § 61-10-15 since position is neither statutorily created nor does she take an oath of office.
May not purchase property owned, in part, by a part-time Assistant Prosecutor, absent contract exemption due to the prohibitions of West Virginia Code § 61-10-15.
Assistant Prosecutor exercises control over BOE contracts by providing legal representation.
Assistant prosecutor meets the “part-time appointed public official” exception to the Ethics Act’s public contract limitation.
Assistant Prosecutor is a public official for purposes of § 61-10-15 since position is statutorily created and he takes an oath of office.
Assistant Prosecutor exercises voice, influence, or control over BOE contracts.

 2011-01 County Council Member
 County Council Member’s business may appraise estates so long she recuses herself from any matters coming before the County Council involving the probate of any estate her business has appraised.County Council Member’s business may not appraise any estates over which the Sheriff has been appointed by the County Council as the administrator.  County Council Member’s business should be removed from the Fiduciary Supervisor’s list of available appraisers.
County Council Member may not appear, as a representative or witness, before the Council, either about the appraised value, or the amount of her compensation.
County Council Member may not accept protected persons from the Sheriff for placement in her nursing home, absent a contract exemption for the Sheriff.

 2011-02 County Council Member
County Council Member’s business may contract with a multi-county Conservation District under the following circumstances:
(1) the contract is let via a sealed bid process;
(2) the project is not funded by County money;
(3) the project is not the subject of an agreement between the District and the County including any agreement for flood control as authorized by W.Va. Code § 19-21A-13 ; and
(4) the affected Member recuses himself from the District’s appropriation request or any request for funding.

Opinion does not authorize the employment of County Commissioners or County Council Members, their spouses or dependents, by Conservation Districts in the County where they serve.

 2011-03 County Hospital
County Hospital, whose members are appointed by the County Commission, may modify an existing contract with a city-owned hospital that employs a County Commissioner.
....The County Commission does not have direct authority or control over the contract; neither the County Commission nor the County Hospital appoints the members of the city-owned hospital’s board of trustees or appropriate money to the city-owned hospital.
....The County Commissioner may not use his position to influence the award of the contract.
....If a matter relating to the subject contract comes before the County Commission, the County Commissioner/city-owned hospital employee should recuse himself from voting.

 

 2011-09 County Hospital 
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of equipment and related services from appointed board member.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member so long as:  there are no financial conditions associated with the property transfer; and the body notifies the public of the member’s offer and allows other property owners to offer their property.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member even if there are unresolved issues requiring mitigation (e.g. environmental hazards, or outstanding liens), but only if an independent evaluation determines that the overriding benefit is to the governing body rather than the donor and it receives permission from the Ethics Commission.
 Modifies AO 95-09 by clarifying that the donation (as opposed to the leasing) of property does not constitute a public contract.

 2011-10 County Board of Education (BOE)
 Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may not be employed as Director of Student Services, a prohibited administrative position under W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may be employed as School Psychologist, a position that meets the exception in W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may be continue to be physically located in the central office without violating W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.  The nature of the work performed, not location, is outcome determinative.
Superintendent may not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.



 2011-12 Town Attorney
Town’s elected officials may vote to appropriate funds to a non-profit organization on which they and/or their family members serve as uncompensated board members and/or officers.

 Overrules portion of AO 2010-04 wherein member of a non-profit board was prohibited from voting as a member of the Board of Education.
 

 2011-20 An Elected County Commissioner
 May purchase tax liens at a Sheriff&apos;s sale or through the State Auditor&apos;s Office, or both, when County Commission had no direct involvement in the assessment of the property.
May not purchase a tax lien on property for which the owner requested adjustment of assessed value or other relief from County Commission sitting as the board of equalization and review.

 2012-01 Mayor
 Ethics Act does not prohibit city employed building inspector from serving on City Council, but he must perform his Council duties on his own time, not during his public work hours.  Ethics Act does not prohibit a building inspector/city employee from serving on City Council.
City council member employed by city may not vote on a personnel matter which affects him directly as opposed to affecting five or more employees in the same or similar manner.
City employed building inspector serving on City Council must recuse himself when citizens who are affected by his official actions come before City Council to address or dispute his official actions. 

 2012-02 County Commissioner
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County from purchasing property from real estate business with which a County Commissioner is associated, with limitations:  Commissioner may not use his position to influence purchase of the property; specifically, he may not communicate with fellow County Commissioners, or Members or staff of the Building Commission, on matters relating to the property.
No prohibited financial interest where neither Commissioner nor his immediate family members have ownership interest in property County Commission seeks to purchase from real estate business with which he is associated.
No prohibited financial interest where Commissioner is not: a director or officer; the listing agent for the property; or, entitled to receive any commission from the sale of the property.
County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County meets statutory exemption so long as he recuses himself.  ( See Voting) 
 County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County must recuse himself from all matters related thereto.

 2012-03 County Agency
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son, even though they live in the same house, so long as the Supervisor is completely removed from the hiring process. 
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son even though they live in the same house. 
 Supervisor employed by County Agency is not a county officer and therefore is not subject to provisions of W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
General rule:  Public servant should not supervise a relative.
Supervisor employed by County Agency may supervise son on emergency calls and while in the field.

 2012-05 Public Employee
Although public employee has personal financial interest in employer, interest does not create prohibition against employer contracting with agency on which employee serves as public official.
Employment by public agency constitutes personal financial interest which prohibits employee who serves as public official from voting on matters that affect public employer.
Matters affecting the BOE uniquely affect public official’s employer, not a class of five or more similarly situated County BOEs.

 2012-07 Mayor
may not use public resources for the benefit of his private business;
may not use subordinate staff to perform work associated with his private business while the subordinates are on the government time clock;
may not solicit private business from subordinates;
may not distribute promotional materials concerning his private business from his office and/or in City/Town Hall;
may not have an interest in a public contract, with certain exceptions;
must recuse himself when a current customer appears before Council; and
must recuse himself from: drafting bid specifications or requests for proposals;
recommending selection of the vendor; and/or
approving the method or manner of payment to the vendor; and
when serving as municipal judge, must:
if customer within past six months appears, disclose the fact thereof and recuse himself if either party requests; and
recuse himself from cases involving customers within the past six months.



 2012-12 Local Board of Health
 Board of Health’s part-time appointed Health Officer may accept patient referrals from the Health Department so long as s/he does not make, participate in making, or in any way attempt to use his or her office or employment to influence a government decision affecting his or her financial or limited financial interest.
Full-time health officer may not contract with own Board of Health unless Board seeks and receives advice or a contract exemption from Ethics Commission.
Local Board of Health formed by a county and a municipality not subject to strict provisions of § 61-10-15.
County Boards of Health are subject to strict provisions of § 61-10-15; their health officers (part time and full-time) may not contract with own Board of Health unless Board seeks and receives advice or a contract exemption from Ethics Commission.

 2012-13 Member of a County Board of Education (BOE)
 May contract with a public university to supervise university students during their placement in public schools in the county where he serves so long as he does not use any public resources, including BOE staff, to perform his private contractual duties.
 Agreement between public university and BOE not a public contract.

 

 2012-16 County Commission
 Prohibited from purchasing private property from appointed member of County Building Commission.
Purchase of property from appointed member creates impermissible conflict and a prohibited interest in a public contract.
May seek Contract Exemption if it believes the property is only viable option.

........................................................................................................

 PUBLIC CONTRACTS - EXEM PTIONS back to top 

 2006-11 County Prosecuting Attorney
Commission will not grant hardship waiver where contract is prohibited by W. Va. Code 61-10-15 [Note: Subsequent amendment to W. Va. Code § 61-10-15 provides discretion to Commission to grant waivers]
..........................................................................................................

 REVOLVING DOOR

 

 2011-04 Per Diem Legislative Attorney 
Per Diem Legislative Attorney, who is not, on July 1, 2011, a Legislative employee as defined by the internal Revenue Service, is not subject to the newly enacted revolving door prohibition.
Independent contractors are not covered by the Ethics Act.

 2011-19 - A State Licensing Board
 May spending public funds to hire registered lobbyist, to serve as a Legislative liaison .
 Registered lobbyist retained by a public agency as Legislative liaison must register as a lobbyist.
Revolving door prohibition does not apply to contract employee/former executive director who terminated employment befor July 1, 2011 cut-off date.  (§6B-3-2(e))

...........................................................................................................

 VOT E&amp;DELIBERATE back to top 

 2005-06 City Council Member
A City’s procedural rule purporting to require a Council Member to vote despite abstention at direction of presiding official are inconsistent with state ethics statute that requires public servants refrain from voting on matters in which they have a personal financial interest.

 2005-12 County Planning Commission
Board Member may not vote on matters regarding developers or contractors who are current business customers

 2005-14 County Commission
May adopt more specific recusal procedure

 2006-06 State Legislator
Voting on matters relating to employer controlled by rules of each house

 2006-09 City Mayor
Voting permitted where only hypothetical private gain involved
Not voting recommended to avoid appearance of impropriety

 2009-04 County School Board Member
May vote on matters pertaining to the continuation of superintendent employment contract despite civil litigation against superintendent by school board member&apos;s employer&apos;s department head since school board member lacks financial interest in outcome of lawsuit.

 2009-06 City Council Member
May vote on matters relating to a church in which he is a member absent a financial interest

 2009-07 County Commissioner
County Commissioner, a private attorney, may prepare wills, but must fully recuse himself from County Commission&apos;s probate therof;
County Commissioner may not appear in a representative capacity in any probate proceeding before the County Commission, even if uncontested;
County Commissioner may testify as witness to will&apos;s validity before County Commission but must recuse himself from decision-making on any such will.

 2009-08 Board of directors of State Agency
Board members associated with entities which may have financial interest in Agency&apos;s contracts may not serve on subcommittee which reviews and recommends funding proposals.
Board members associated with entities which may have financial interest in Agency&apos;s contracts may continue to serve on Board, but must recuse themselves from discussion, deliberation and decision-making on matters related to those entities with which they are associated.

 2009-14 Part-time Appointed Board member of a Public Agency
Member must recuse herself from discussion, deliberation and decision-making on all matters related to a contract between the Agency and her employer since she is the Executive Director and oversees the contract on her employer&apos;s behalf.

 2010-04 County Board of Education Member
Board may contract with a private non-profit when one of the Board of Education members sits on the Board of the non-profit so long as the common Board member does not vote on any matters relating to the non-profit and recuses himself from the decision-making process and vote. (This portion overruled by AO 2011-12; common Board member is no longer required to recuse himself, and may vote.) 

 2010-13 County Board of Education Member
Spouse of County BOE member may be employed as auditor in Central Office, a service position that meets exception in § 61-10-15
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee
May not vote on matters specific to his wife including raise, renewal of employment contract, or discipline
May vote on overall budget, but must recuse himself if line item affects wife or all four auditors if BOE specifically addresses any such line item.

 2011-01 County Council Member
 County Council Member’s business may appraise estates so long she recuses herself from any matters coming before the County Council involving the probate of any estate her business has appraised.County Council Member’s business may not appraise any estates over which the Sheriff has been appointed by the County Council as the administrator.  County Council Member’s business should be removed from the Fiduciary Supervisor’s list of available appraisers.
County Council Member may not appear, as a representative or witness, before the Council, either about the appraised value, or the amount of her compensation.
County Council Member may not accept protected persons from the Sheriff for placement in her nursing home, absent a contract exemption for the Sheriff.

 2011-02 County Council Member
County Council Member’s business may contract with a multi-county Conservation District under the following circumstances:
(1) the contract is let via a sealed bid process;
(2) the project is not funded by County money;
(3) the project is not the subject of an agreement between the District and the County including any agreement for flood control as authorized by W.Va. Code § 19-21A-13 ; and
(4) the affected Member recuses himself from the District’s appropriation request or any request for funding.

Opinion does not authorize the employment of County Commissioners or County Council Members, their spouses or dependents, by Conservation Districts in the County where they serve.

 2011-06 County Public Service District Member
 An appointed board member, who in his private capacity has participated in other rate cases related to a particular utility company, may not participate in the PSD’s deliberations and actions related to the PSD’s role in the West Virginia Public Service Commission’s investigation of that utility company.
Although not expressly prohibited by the voting provision of the Ethics Act since he is a member of a class of five or more, the member’s membership in the Home Owners Association, as well as his representative advocacy on its behalf, constitute a personal interest.
There could be an appearance that the member is using the PSD to bring suit in the District’s name for his personal benefit, thus constituting the prohibited use of public office for private gain.

 2011-09 County Hospital 
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of equipment and related services from appointed board member.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member so long as:  there are no financial conditions associated with the property transfer; and the body notifies the public of the member’s offer and allows other property owners to offer their property.
County Hospital may accept unsolicited offer of real property from appointed board member even if there are unresolved issues requiring mitigation (e.g. environmental hazards, or outstanding liens), but only if an independent evaluation determines that the overriding benefit is to the governing body rather than the donor and it receives permission from the Ethics Commission.
 Modifies AO 95-09 by clarifying that the donation (as opposed to the leasing) of property does not constitute a public contract.



 2011-12 Town Attorney
Town’s elected officials may vote to appropriate funds to a non-profit organization on which they and/or their family members serve as uncompensated board members and/or officers.
 Overrules portion of AO 2010-04 wherein member of a non-profit board was prohibited from voting as a member of the Board of Education.

 2011-15 - An Appointed Member of a Board of Health
 An Appointed Member of a Board of Health who is the past president of a fraternal organization which sued the Board of Health is required to recuse himself from being involved in deliberations or votes relating to the lawsuit.
An Appointed Member of a Board of Health who has business interests affected by the Board of Health regulations may vote on regulations or policies which govern smoking in public places.  The fact that he is a member and/or officer of an organization which has an interest in Clean Air regulations does not prohibit him from voting on the Clean Air regulations as five or more such organizations are affected.

 2011-16 - An Appointed Member of a Board of Health
 An appointed Member of a Board of Health who is a member of a fraternal order which belongs to a fraternal organization which sued the Board of Health is required to recuse himself from being involved in deliberations or votes relating to the lawsuit.
An Appointed Member of a Board of Health who is a member of a non-profit fraternal order which has an interest in Board of Health regulations may vote on Clean Air Regulations or other policies.  The member does not have a financial interest in the fraternal order, and does not need to recuse herself.

 2011-18 - Industry representatives on the governing council of a State Agency
 May not serve on the initial review panel for grant applications.
May not serve on the comittee to draft legislative rules relating to the award of grants.
May participate as a member of council, and vote on approval of recommended grant application absent a prohibited interest necessitating recusal.
May participate as a member of council, and vote on draft legislative rules relating to the award of grants absent a prohibited interest necessitating recusal.

 2012-01 Mayor
 Ethics Act does not prohibit city employed building inspector from serving on City Council, but he must perform his Council duties on his own time, not during his public work hours.  Ethics Act does not prohibit a building inspector/city employee from serving on City Council.
City council member employed by city may not vote on a personnel matter which affects him directly as opposed to affecting five or more employees in the same or similar manner.
City employed building inspector serving on City Council must recuse himself when citizens who are affected by his official actions come before City Council to address or dispute his official actions.
 
 2012-02 County Commissioner
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County from purchasing property from real estate business with which a County Commissioner is associated, with limitations:  Commissioner may not use his position to influence purchase of the property; specifically, he may not communicate with fellow County Commissioners, or Members or staff of the Building Commission, on matters relating to the property.
No prohibited financial interest where neither Commissioner nor his immediate family members have ownership interest in property County Commission seeks to purchase from real estate business with which he is associated.
No prohibited financial interest where Commissioner is not: a director or officer; the listing agent for the property; or, entitled to receive any commission from the sale of the property.  County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County meets statutory exemption so long as he recuses himself.  ( See Voting) 
 County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County must recuse himself from all matters related thereto.

 2012-05 Public Employee
Although public employee has personal financial interest in employer, interest does not create prohibition against employer contracting with agency on which employee serves as public official.
Employment by public agency constitutes personal financial interest which prohibits employee who serves as public official from voting on matters that affect public employer.
Matters affecting the BOE uniquely affect public official’s employer, not a class of five or more similarly situated County BOEs.

 2012-07 Mayor
may not use public resources for the benefit of his private business;
may not use subordinate staff to perform work associated with his private business while the subordinates are on the government time clock;
may not solicit private business from subordinates;
may not distribute promotional materials concerning his private business from his office and/or in City/Town Hall;
may not have an interest in a public contract, with certain exceptions;
must recuse himself when a current customer appears before Council; and
must recuse himself from: drafting bid specifications or requests for proposals;
recommending selection of the vendor; and/or
approving the method or manner of payment to the vendor; and
when serving as municipal judge, must:
if customer within past six months appears, disclose the fact thereof and recuse himself if either party requests; and
recuse himself from cases involving customers within the past six months.
 
 2012-13 Member of a County Board of Education (BOE)
 May contract with a public university to supervise university students during their placement in public schools in the county where he serves so long as he does not use any public resources, including BOE staff, to perform his private contractual duties.
 Agreement between public university and BOE not a public contract. 

 2012-17 Presiding Officer of a house of West Virginia Legislature
 May not be retained to provide legal services to an Association which is actively engaged in lobbying Legislature on behalf of its members who are public employees.
Proposed employment contract presents an inescapable conflict, given the unique position held and power wielded by the presiding officer.
Access to confidential information may have chilling effect on other legislators, if proposed employment contract permitted.
Public may perceive that Association has hired him because of his unique ability to influence legislation.
Other Associations that do not employee a high ranking member of the Legislature may believe that they are at a disadvantage in the legislative process.
Opinion limited to Presiding Officers of houses of West Virginia Legislature.



 2012-19 Member of the Legislature
 May be retained to provide consulting services to Public University during and after his term of office.
Conflict of interest cured by his removal from potentially overlapping committees.
Must consult with Presiding Officer of his house and abide by appropriate legislative voting rule.
May not use influence of legislative position to attempt to affect the actions of University personnel to enhance his contractual benefits; introduce, sponsor or advocate legislation to benefit the University in any way; influence either the State’s distribution of federal grant money or State funds to the University for any purpose, not just those related to his consulting contract; or influence the appropriation of public funds to benefit the University in any way.

..............................................................................................................

 61-10-15 CO UNTY OFFICERS (CRIMINAL PROVISION) back to top 

 2005-03 County Board of Education Member
Board Member may serve as volunteer coach for $1 annually

 2005-13 County Prosecuting Attorney
Part-time Prosecuting Attorney may not be employed to perform additional legal work for county under grant administered by County Commission

 2005-18 County Board of Education Member
May fill competitive position as part-time assistant athletic coach if he declines compensation other than $1 annually

 2006-12 County Board of Education Member
May be employed to conduct educational testing by contractor working for federal Department of Education where no county funds involved

 2006-15 County Solid Waste Authority
Where Board Member has exclusive tariff from PSC to haul waste in county, Board may contract with Member to haul waste it collects

 2006-16 County Board of Education
May not contract with Superintendent’s spouse to provide specialized training to teachers

 2007-03 County Assessor
Marriage to employee who works in Assessor’s Office will result in prohibited interest in spouse’s employment contract

 2007-08 Public School Teacher
May enter into vending services contract with school system by which he is employed

 2008-10 County Commissioner
Contract between Commissioner&apos;s business and County Airport Authority which was approved prior to Commissioner&apos;s election may remain in effect
Commissioner may not serve on Airport authority
Commissioner may not vote on appointments to Airport authority
Commissioner must follow limitations on voting in regard to Airport Authority matters
 
2009-01 County Commissioner/Spouse
Spouse may not be employed by County Hospital..appointment power of county commissioner constitutes voice, influence, or control over county hospital (overruled by statute)
Ethics Commission lacks authority to grant exemption to employ spouse except for positions expressly included in  § 61-10-15.

 2009-05 Prosecuting Attorney
May not contract with local extension service agency because he exercises voice, influence or control over extension agency contracts.

 2009-11 Board of Education / Assistant Principal
Assistant Principal is subject to the prohibitions in § 61-10-15.
Assistant Principal has voice, influence, or control over subject Board of Education contract affecting his school by virtue of his responsibility to oversee all school activities at his school.
Board of Education may not contract with Assistant Principal&apos;s private business to provide after-school driver&apos;s education program to County students.

 2010-03 County Board of Education Candidate
Spouse of county BOE member may be employed as Chief mechanic, a service position that meets exception in § 61-10-15.
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2010-04 County Board of Education Member
Board may contract with a private non-profit when one of the Board of Education members sits on the Board of the non-profit so long as the common Board member does not vote on any matters relating to the non-profit and recuses himself from the decision-making process and vote. (This portion overruled by AO 2011-12; common Board member is no longer required to recuse himself, and may vote.) 
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2010-06 Public Library
Ethics Act&apos;s prohibition against interest in public contract does not apply to part-time appointed official.
Board member whose law firm represents library may serve on the board, but must recuse himself from all matters related to the law firm&apos;s contract.
Board member of Public Library created by Special Act of the Legislature and joint venture of county and city entities not subject to § 61-10-15.

 2010-10 Board of Directors of a County Authority
Ethics Act does not prohibit part time appointed officials from bidding at auction on items sold by Board on which they serve, so long as they recuse themselves from all related matters; but § 61-10-15 prohibits part time appointed officials from bidding at auction on items sold by Board on which they serve.

 2010-13 County Board of Education Member
Spouse of County BOE member may be employed as auditor in Central Office, a service position that meets exception in § 61-10-15
May not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee
May not vote on matters specific to his wife including raise, renewal of employment contract, or discipline
May vote on overall budget, but must recuse himself if line item affects wife or all four auditors if BOE specifically addresses any such line item

 2010-14 County Board of Education Member
County BOE may not contract with Member’s fast food restaurant to provide food for special events
County schools and/or school sports teams may not contract with County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant to provide food for school sports teams using school funds
County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant may not sponsor fundraisers on behalf of school teams
County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant may, under certain conditions, sponsor fundraisers on behalf of booster organizations
County BOE Member’s fast food restaurant may, under certain conditions, sell food to credit union even though BOE provides office space to credit union

 2010-15 County Board of Education Member
- County BOE Member may not be paid to officiate as a sports official in his own county
-County BOE Member may volunteer as a referee and receive $1 to obtain insurance coverage

 2010-16 County Board of Education Member
County BOE Member may contract with State Department of Education for online teaching even though some teachers from her county may participate.
Subject contract with State, not County BOE, and thus Member lacks control over contract
County BOE Member lacks control over County BOE’s reimbursement of county teachers’ expenses incurred in taking Member’s online course

 2010-20 Conservation Districts
May not spend public funds (in excess of $1,000) to construct project on an Elected Board Member’s property, absent a contract exemption.
Public contract provision in Ethics Act contains no exception for part-time elected officials.
Not subject to the prohibitions of West Virginia Code § 61-10-15.

 2010-21 - County Board of Education
Ethics Act does not prohibit contract with a private club in which an Elected Board Member and Treasurer own less than five percent of the outstanding shares of stock.
May not contract with a private club in which an Elected Board Member, Treasurer and spouse of the Superintendent own stock, absent a contract exemption, due to the prohibitions of West Virginia Code § 61-10-15.
May not contract with a business with which public officials or their spouses serve as a director, pursuant to the Ethics Act.

 2010-24 Board of Education
May purchase property owned, in part, by a Sheriff’s Chief Tax Deputy.
Chief Tax Deputy does not exercise control over BOE contracts.
Chief Tax Deputy not subject to § 61-10-15 since position is neither statutorily created nor does she take an oath of office.
May not purchase property owned, in part, by a part-time Assistant Prosecutor, absent contract exemption due to the prohibitions of West Virginia Code § 61-10-15.
Assistant Prosecutor exercises control over BOE contracts by providing legal representation.Assistant prosecutor meets the “part-time appointed public official” exception to the Ethics Act’s public contract limitation.
Assistant Prosecutor is a public official for purposes of § 61-10-15 since position is statutorily created and he takes an oath of office.
Assistant Prosecutor exercises voice, influence, or control over BOE contracts.

 2011-01 County Council Member
County Council Member’s business may appraise estates so long she recuses herself from any matters coming before the County Council involving the probate of any estate her business has appraised.County Council Member’s business may not appraise any estates over which the Sheriff has been appointed by the County Council as the administrator.  County Council Member’s business should be removed from the Fiduciary Supervisor’s list of available appraisers.
County Council Member may not appear, as a representative or witness, before the Council, either about the appraised value, or the amount of her compensation.
County Council Member may not accept protected persons from the Sheriff for placement in her nursing home, absent a contract exemption for the Sheriff.

 2011-02 County Council Member
County Council Member’s business may contract with a multi-county Conservation District under the following circumstances:
(1) the contract is let via a sealed bid process;
(2) the project is not funded by County money;
(3) the project is not the subject of an agreement between the District and the County including any agreement for flood control as authorized by W.Va. Code § 19-21A-13 ; and
(4) the affected Member recuses himself from the District’s appropriation request or any request for funding.
Opinion does not authorize the employment of County Commissioners or County Council Members, their spouses or dependents, by Conservation Districts in the County where they serve

 2011-03 County Hospital

County Hospital, whose members are appointed by the County Commission, may modify an existing contract with a city-owned hospital that employs a County Commissioner.
....The County Commission does not have direct authority or control over the contract; neither the County Commission nor the County Hospital appoints the members of the city-owned hospital’s board of trustees or appropriate money to the city-owned hospital.
....The County Commissioner may not use his position to influence the award of the contract.
....If a matter relating to the subject contract comes before the County Commission, the County Commissioner/city-owned hospital employee should recuse himself from voting.

 2011-10 County Board of Education (BOE)
 Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may not be employed as Director of Student Services, a prohibited administrative position under W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may be employed as School Psychologist, a position that meets the exception in W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
Spouse of county BOE Superintendent may be continue to be physically located in the central office without violating W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.  The nature of the work performed, not location, is outcome determinative.
Superintendent may not use position to obtain, increase or promote the interests of spouse as a BOE employee.

 2011-20 An Elected County Commissioner
 May purchase tax liens at a Sheriff&apos;s sale or through the State Auditor&apos;s Office, or both, when County Commission had no direct involvement in the assessment of the property.
May not purchase a tax lien on property for which the owner requested adjustment of assessed value or other relief from County Commission sitting as the board of equalization and review.

 2012-02 County Commissioner
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County from purchasing property from real estate business with which a County Commissioner is associated, with limitations:  Commissioner may not use his position to influence purchase of the property; specifically, he may not communicate with fellow County Commissioners, or Members or staff of the Building Commission, on matters relating to the property.
No prohibited financial interest where neither Commissioner nor his immediate family members have ownership interest in property County Commission seeks to purchase from real estate business with which he is associated.
No prohibited financial interest where Commissioner is not: a director or officer; the listing agent for the property; or, entitled to receive any commission from the sale of the property.
County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County meets statutory exemption so long as he recuses himself.  ( See Voting) 
 County Commissioner associated with real estate business selling property to County must recuse himself from all matters related thereto.

 2012-03 County Agency
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son, even though they live in the same house, so long as the Supervisor is completely removed from the hiring process. 
 Ethics Act does not prohibit County Agency from employing Supervisor’s son even though they live in the same house. 
 Supervisor employed by County Agency is not a county officer and therefore is not subject to provisions of W. Va. Code § 61-10-15.
General rule:  Public servant should not supervise a relative.
Supervisor employed by County Agency may supervise son on emergency calls and while in the field.

 2012-11 County Commissioner
 Ethics Act permits living with county employee so long as nepotism rules followed.
W. Va. Code § 61-10-15 prohibits living with county employee even if nepotism rules followed and/or even if employee transferred to another county office.



 2012-12 Local Board of Health
 Board of Health’s part-time appointed Health Officer may accept patient referrals from the Health Department so long as s/he does not make, participate in making, or in any way attempt to use his or her office or employment to influence a government decision affecting his or her financial or limited financial interest.
Full-time health officer may not contract with own Board of Health unless Board seeks and receives advice or a contract exemption from Ethics Commission.
Local Board of Health formed by a county and a municipality not subject to strict provisions of § 61-10-15.
County Boards of Health are subject to strict provisions of § 61-10-15; their health officers (part time and full-time) may not contract with own Board of Health unless Board seeks and receives advice or a contract exemption from Ethics Commission.

 2012-13 Member of a County Board of Education (BOE)
 May contract with a public university to supervise university students during their placement in public schools in the county where he serves so long as he does not use any public resources, including BOE staff, to perform his private contractual duties.
 Agreement between public university and BOE not a public contract.

 2012-16 County Commission
 Prohibited from purchasing private property from appointed member of County Building Commission.
Purchase of property from appointed member creates impermissible conflict and a prohibited interest in a public contract.
May seek Contract Exemption if it believes the property is only viable option.


 back to top 
..................................................................................................................

......................................................................................................................


 Contact Us | Site Map 
 Privacy, Security and Accessibility | WV.gov | USA.gov |©2012 State of West Virginia
	</body>
</document>
