<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003535" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20101130190742AAXHqwI" time="2012-07-12-19:40" support="2" score="0.0030679471296190973" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - When is it okay to NOT tip your waiter ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - When is it okay to NOT tip your waiter/waitress?">
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>If I don&apos;t get what I expect, then no tip. ... to do that would be repeatedly getting my order ... When was the last time you ate at a fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Other - Dining Out &gt; Resolved Question 
 Pianist Member since: October 13, 2009 Total points: 9,073 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
When is it okay to NOT tip your waiter/waitress?
 What things will make you consider not leaving your waiter/waitress a tip at a restaurant? :) 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by endpov Member since: July 07, 2006 Total points: 25,037 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 When you are at a restaurant, if it is a brunch or buffet style, then you probably don&apos;t have to tip, unless you see signs saying&quot;gratuities appreciated&quot;. Otherwise, unless there is something seriously wrong with your server, you should always tip... 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 29% 2 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; When is it okay to N… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (13)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by It Member since: April 26, 2009 Total points: 377 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 i was a chef i went to college but i still started as a waiter like everyone else. and the meaning if tip is
T=to , I=improve, P=performance. tips are meant to tell a waiter of waitress that you think they are doing a good job and that they are appreciated. so to tip a waitress or waiter even if you are unhappy then you may send the wrong message that they are doing fine checking on tables every thirty minute or something of that range. i hope i helped. 
Source(s):
 chef school, and experience. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by smrtblon... Member since: December 30, 2007 Total points: 8,467 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Average to good service gets 10-15% of the PRE-TAX bill. But there&apos;s zero tip if:
- People who arrive after me get water, order taken and/or food before me
- The waitress gives me anything less than a friendly smile and charming attitude
- They appear lazy, insincere, would rather talk or hang out with coworkers than work the tables
- Simply doing the bare minimum.

However, if something goes wrong but the room is crowded and she&apos;s running around trying to keep up, I&apos;ll still tip. It&apos;s not her fault if the owner is too cheap to hire adequate staff. But NO WAY do I believe waitresses deserve a tip simply for showing up to work. I couldn&apos;t care less if they live off tips - I work hard for my money and I don&apos;t get tips, so when I go out to dinner I EXPECT excellent service. If I don&apos;t get what I expect, then no tip.

Period. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Duck is Quackers is Married! Member since: October 17, 2010 Total points: 38,726 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 It&apos;s a rare occasion when that&apos;s ok. Wait staff usually have to work really hard. I would say that I would be more likely to decrease a tip than to leave no tip. Things that would cause me to do that would be repeatedly getting my order wrong, not offering drink or water refills throughout an entire meal, bringing food that is supposed to be hot to the table cold. If the service is decent, I tip a minimum of 20%. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Lemonade dude Member since: June 17, 2007 Total points: 816 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Being anything where you have to tend to the customers is a very difficult job.
I usually tip them almost always
I don&apos;t tip them if they are trying to work as little as possible and being rude

Tip: Just because they don&apos;t smile, dosen&apos;t mean they can&apos;t provide excellent service 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Pamela Member since: August 28, 2010 Total points: 340 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I am a FnB trainer, and I always tell my students not to expect tips from customer. I was a waitress once, and I don&apos;t think I deserve for tips, that&apos;s my job and my employer paid me to do the job not to expect tips from guest. 
Source(s):
 my life experience 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by whatques... Member since: April 11, 2008 Total points: 15,996 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The absolute only time it is okay to NOT tip your server is if they do something vindictive, in which case you tell the manager. If you tip less than 10%, the server actually loses money while serving you because they have to tip out the kitchen. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote by knight35... Member since: November 01, 2008 Total points: 3,786 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 bad service + bad attitude = 2 pennies each with a pain reliever on top

its not fair to not tip for just the food being wrong or service is slow, wait staff cannot control the cooks or if they are understaffed, as long as they are giving me 100% of their ability, I tip. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by joemomma Member since: November 30, 2010 Total points: 335 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 always tip your waiter/waitress, most people dont know how the hard they actually work! you dont HAVE to tip them if they are rude/ignore you...but its always nice that you do because you dont know how busy they are 
Source(s):
 life 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by George Bernard Shaw Member since: March 06, 2008 Total points: 9,940 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I don&apos;t tip them. I don&apos;t conform to society. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by trentjus... Member since: March 22, 2006 Total points: 620 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Bad attitude+Poor Service= NO TIP FOR YOU! 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 5 people rated this as good 
 by social class Member since: November 01, 2008 Total points: 4,009 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 If they spill stuff on me and give me dirty looks&gt;:] 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by curious Member since: November 23, 2010 Total points: 135 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 if your have to wait more than 2 hours for something to eat 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 

 by Ae F Member since: November 30, 2010 Total points: 162 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Answer hidden due to its low rating
 I waitressed for a year and there were a few occasions when I knew I didn&apos;t deserve a tip:
-There was something wrong with your food that was NOT the kitchens fault. Waitresses have very little control over what happens in the kitchen.
-No re-fills for an unreasonable amount of time.
-Extreme rudeness
-Dirty table, cups, silverware, ect.
* But always remember that waitresses live off of tips, yeah they get a paycheck but they are a joke and normally void because of taxes. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Dining Out 

 Why do I get food poisoning from fast food places? My boss serves up old out of date food , what to do ? What do you usually get at Panera? Where to buy good cheesecake thats NOT from Cheesecake Factory? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 TIP Stock (+0.18%) TIP stock closed last at (+0.18%) a share. Get info and rate... localnewsnow.org/TIP See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
