<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003902" url="http://zelenocklaw.com/legal-expertise.php" time="2012-07-12-20:04" support="1" score="0.0007685177877416898" bingtitle="Jay Zelenock Cases | Traverse City, MI" webtitle="Jay Zelenock Cases | Traverse City, MI">
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>... electrical system was like a car&apos;s, and had a battery that would keep ... and drainage defect at a fast food restaurant. She ... were paid later, when the receipts from ...</description>
	<body>
		Jay Zelenock Law Firm
 Home        About Us        Legal Expertise        Contact Us Wrongful Death Auto Accidents and Insurance Claims Products Liability Workplace Injuries Civil Litigation Contract and Property Matters Employment Law Legal Advice and Counsel Personal Injury and Insurance Law Small Business Law Wills, Trusts and Probate Law Wrongful Termination 
 Sample cases and successes* 

 *Every client and every case is unique. The following summaries are examples of a few of the problems Mr. Zelenock has assisted clients with solving successfully. Your case or legal problem is also unique, and arises out of unique facts and circumstances. Your results will depend on the facts of your case and the legal principles that apply to your unique situation. These illustrations are intended to help you understand some of the complex issues that can arise in civil litigation and insurance coverage disputes. They are not intended to imply that all cases are equally successful. 

 Commercial truck accident - Work Injury -- Hit-and-run driver - Uninsured/Underinsured Motorist Insurance -- Insurance Coverage Litigation - Arbitration Award enforcement

A commercial truck driver had a terrible day at work, when a car pulled out into the path of his 18-wheeler. He braked and tried to swerve, and suffered severe right wrist fractures when his tractor trailer jack-knifed. Sadly, the at-fault car driver fled the scene without taking responsibility for causing the crash or even calling for help. The truck driver&apos;s employer had purchased $1 million in uninsured/underinsured motorist insurance coverage from an international insurance company. Unfortunately, the employer and insurance company joined forces to fight the truck driver&apos;s claim. The insurance company had sold the policy to the employer with a &quot;$150,000 self-retention&quot; (essentially, a huge &quot;deductible&quot; payable by the employer in the event of a claim) which provided the employer a powerful incentive to &quot;cooperate&quot; with the insurer&apos;s arguments that there was no coverage intended for employees, like the truck driver who suffered disabling injuries in this hit-and-run accident. Extensive investigation and discovery of internal insurance documents led to a favorable result for the client. The trial court granted Mr. Zelenock&apos;s motion to enforce a $775,000 arbitration award in favor of the trucker and also granted Mr. Zelenock&apos;s motion on the insurance coverage issues, defeating the arguments of the employer and the international insurance giant. Judgments totaling approximately $1 million were entered against the employer and insurer. They appealed and lost. $1.2 million was recovered, as taxable costs and interest were also collected from the insurer. After losing the appeal, the insurer filed an additional motion in the trial court to attempt to reduce the recovery. The insurer asserted it was entitled to reduce the award by the amounts of all worker&apos;s compensation benefits paid to the trucker pursuant to the worker&apos;s compensation statute. Mr. Zelenock filed a motion to extinguish the insurer&apos;s alleged statutory lien. The trial court granted Mr. Zelenock&apos;s motion, entered an order extinguishing the alleged lien, and sanctioned the insurer an additional $4,400 for raising the lien issue.

 Wrongful death -snowmobile accident-scientific evidence--forensic evidence

A 19-year-old man was killed when his snowmobile ran into a pickup truck illegally parked over a hill on the shoulder of a narrow rural road. The defense sought to blame the dead snowmobiler, arguing that he was operating his sled with the headlight &quot;off&quot; on a dark winter night. There were no eyewitnesses. Unfortunately, the state police laboratory and insurance defense experts concluded that the snowmobiler&apos;s headlight was &quot;off,&quot; based on state police lab microscopic examination and photography of the filament inside the snowmobile&apos;s headlamp, and a reading of academic literature. Mr. Zelenock reviewed the scientific and academic literature and discovered that these experts had made a critical mistake in their analysis of the scientific, materials and electrical issues presented: They assumed that the snowmobile&apos;s electrical system was like a car&apos;s, and had a battery that would keep electricity flowing to the headlamp, even after the engine stopped running as the result of the crash. This assumption was incorrect, and as a result, so were the experts&apos; conclusions. In fact, the snowmobile involved did not have a large battery to keep electricity flowing to the light when the engine was stopped. The snowmobile was an older sled with a small &quot;pull start&quot; motor like a chain saw or lawn mower. The trial court granted Mr. Zelenock&apos;s motion to exclude the conclusions of the state police laboratory scientist and the insurance expert, based on their critical mistakes in analyzing the scientific issues. Fortunately, the state police lab preserved the filament and the microscopic photographic evidence for further review. The evidence was reviewed again, and the only expert testimony permitted was that the snowmobiler&apos;s headlamp was &quot;on&quot; at the time of the fatal crash. With the key scientific issue resolved in favor of Mr. Zelenock&apos;s client, the case quickly settled for the insurance policy limits.

 Wrongful death - drowning - scientific/medical evidence

A young man drowned in a northern Michigan river. A rescue team was prevented from making a rescue. The insurance attorneys argued that the rescue team could not have rescued the man, even if their clients had not interfered with the rescue team. Mr. Zelenock briefed the scientific issues relating to cold water drowning and the federal court allowed plaintiff&apos;s medical expert to testify on the issues, with a $1 million recovery for the client&apos;s estate and family resulting.

 Wrongful Discharge -- Wrongful Termination-Employment Discrimination--Age discrimination-Internet Law and Investigation-Myspace internet website

A 54-year-old female employee was terminated on a Friday afternoon, after 19 years of hard work and exemplary service to her employer. The employer said &quot;the economic downturn&quot; and the recommendations of a business &quot;consultant&quot; lead to the &quot;elimination of her position.&quot; Yet, a 21-year-old female was hired one month later. The client was devastated by the loss of her job, her livelihood, and her sense of betrayal and lack of fair play resulting from the employer&apos;s actions. The employer&apos;s insurance lawyers fought hard, but a fair result was obtained for the client. The defense argued that the young 21-year-old women had not been hired as a replacement, but instead was doing a &quot;totally different job with a new title,&quot; while sitting at the same desk and appearing to do the same tasks. This is a common defense argument in employment discrimination cases. The defense typed-up a new title and job description for the younger worker, and argued that this &quot;new job description&quot; added weight to its arguments that the 21-year-old was hired into a &quot;new job,&quot; rather than given the older woman&apos;s job. However, deposition testimony showed that the young woman was doing many or most of the same tasks. Also, an internet investigation revealed that the young woman&apos;s Myspace internet page listed her job with the company with essentially the same job title/description as the 54-year-old worker had over her 19 years of service, rather than the &quot;new title&quot; that was presented during the litigation by the defense. The defense also argued that it had &quot;hired a consultant&quot; to review its business operations and, allegedly, this consultant recommended the &quot;elimination&quot; of the 54-year-old woman&apos;s job. However, neither the employer nor the consultant could produce any documentary evidence that the consultant had done any consulting work for the business, until after the client was terminated. All receipts, invoices, checks and work descriptions dealt with time periods after the client was terminated. Thus, it appeared that the consultant had been hired to train the new worker after the termination, not to help decide to terminate the older employee. The insurer filed 3 motions to have the case dismissed. Such &quot;dispositive motions&quot; are staples of employment discrimination litigation, and are almost always filed by the employer. The trial court denied all 3 motions by the employer, and described certain defense arguments as &quot;disingenuous&quot; (i.e. dishonest or lacking in candor).

 Civil Litigation -Employment Law--Whistleblower-Appellate Court Jurisdiction

A northern Michigan county wrongfully terminated several employees and the case was tried to a large verdict. The county&apos;s attorneys sought to take the cases to the Michigan Court of Appeals, which could potentially extend the proceedings for another year or more, but did not follow certain procedural steps in post-trial pleadings and filings. Mr. Zelenock filed motions and obtained rulings that effectively deprived the County of the opportunity to take an appeal &quot;as of right&quot; to the Michigan Court of Appeals and stepped up collection efforts against the County and its insurer. A large settlement was paid in full within several months, rather than years later, without an appeal.

 Motorcycle Accidents - Future Damages - Loss of Future Earnings or Earning Capacity -- ORV Accidents - No Fault Insurance Coverage-- Litigation

Mr. Zelenock obtained a verdict of $500,000 in past, present and future damages for a 31-year-old factory worker, who suffered serious wrist fractures in a head-on collision between two &quot;4-wheeler&quot; off road vehicles (ORVs). The ORVs collided in a blind curve on a &quot;two track&quot; dirt road. The accident and jury trial were in rural Northern Michigan County. The other driver&apos;s No Fault car insurance coverage was triggered in this accident, because the ORVs had 4 wheels and were operated on a &quot;two-track&quot; road that was publicly maintained or used. The verdict exceeded insurance policy limits. The client suffered a broken wrist, but kept his factory job. The other driver&apos;s insurance lawyer argued that he could not prove any vocational damages or earning loss, because he was &quot;still on the job.&quot; However, the client expected to suffer significant future losses, because his surgeon believed that he would need to have his wrist surgically &quot;fused&quot; in the future. The case was hard fought. The insurer never made a significant offer to settle the case before trial. Issues of social class, regional and age bias seemed to come into play. The insurance claims representative and attorney could not seem to accept that an &quot;Up North&quot; jury would be fair to the young 31-year-old factory worker from lower Michigan. The defense portrayed the case as a contest between a young, reckless &quot;hooligan&quot; from downstate, who was suing a kindly, 67-year-old, white-haired grandfather and retired factory manager who was a county resident. But the truth came out in the trial process. The client was a nice man, not like the defense attempted to portray him. The older rider, while also a nice man, made serious mistakes. Older drivers can make mistakes, just like everyone else. Both riders shared some responsibility for causing the collision. Michigan law contemplates such as situation and requires the jury to &quot;allocate&quot; percentages of fault to each party. MCL 600.6304. The client collected 50 times the insurer&apos;s highest pre-trial settlement offer.

 Insurance Litigation -Civil Litigation--Insurance Law-Alleged Overpayments of Benefits-Summary Judgment-Claims of &quot;Mistake&quot; of Law

A major insurer filed claims against Mr. Zelenock&apos;s client, claiming that it had &quot;overpaid&quot; tens of thousands of dollars in insurance benefits to the client, due to &quot;miscalculations&quot; of benefits owed. The insurer periodically increased its demand for money during the litigation, starting with a demand for approximately $77,000 in &quot;repayments,&quot; then increasing to the $135,000 range, and finally demanding more than $295,000 from the client. Mr. Zelenock investigated these claims and deposed several insurance representatives, who eventually admitted that the client had provided accurate information to the insurer and that any &quot;overpayment&quot; resulted from the insurer&apos;s own mistakes in applying the No Fault Law to the facts of the case. Mr. Zelenock filed a motion for summary disposition based on the legal principle that an insurer generally cannot recover payments made due to its own &quot;mistake of law.&quot; The motion was granted, and the insurer collected nothing on its $295,000+ claim against the client.

 Wrongful Death -Insurance Coverage Litigation-Assignment of Rights under Liability Insurance Policy-Worker&apos;s Compensation Law-&quot;Temporary workers&quot;

Wrongful death cases are brought under Michigan&apos;s Wrongful Death Act, which can be found at MCL 600.2922 et seq. The Act defines the persons (generally family members) who may recover damages for wrongful death, when someone dies and another party is liable for causing the death. In one case, a young man working part-time in a factory warehouse was crushed by a stack of materials that tipped over. The company owner carried no worker&apos;s compensation benefits, indicating that the young man was an independent contractor, not an employee. On the other hand, the company&apos;s liability insurer took the opposite position, arguing that the young man was an employee, not an independent contractor, so it refused to pay insurance benefits. The young man&apos;s widow was stuck in the middle. A $725,000 settlement was reached after extensive research, investigation and litigation with the liability insurer over the insurance coverage issues.

 Automobile Accident Claim --No Fault Insurance-Insurance Coverage-Insurance Underwriting

A 16-year-old boy with behavior problems was given 2 Camaro Z-28&apos;s to play with by his father. The boy caused a serious crash, while driving over 80mph and passing four cars at once during a rainstorm. He eventually spun-out, lost control and hit the client head-on. The father&apos;s attitude was &quot;boys will be boys.&quot; He had a history of refusing to discipline his son, or to even see anything wrong with his destructive behavior. &quot;He wanted to be a friend, not a father,&quot; the mother (and ex-wife) testified in her deposition. The father&apos;s insurance company recognized the boy was at fault for causing the accident and injuries, but attempted to reduce the amount it was liable to pay by trying to limit the claim to the boy&apos;s minimal $20,000 insurance policy. Mr. Zelenock did a thorough investigation and discovered proof that the father was liable under theories of negligent entrustment and ownership liability. The trial court ruled that the father&apos;s full $100,000 insurance policy was available to the client as a result -i.e. five times the $20,000 the insurer had attempted to limit the client&apos;s recovery to.

 Motorcycle Accident -No Fault Insurance-Uninsured/Underinsured Motorists-Insurance Coverage--

A motorcyclist sustained serious leg injuries, when a pickup truck turned left into his path. The at-fault driver only had a minimal insurance policy. Fortunately, the motorcyclist had purchased Uninsured Motorist and Underinsured Motorist protection on his own insurance policies (a type of insurance that protects you, if you are injured by a driver with no insurance or too little insurance). Unfortunately, his insurance company fought his claim with numerous arguments to try to get out of paying. Mr. Zelenock filed civil lawsuits for the motorcyclist. Insurance proceeds were eventually collected from both the pickup truck driver&apos;s insurer and the motorcyclist&apos;s own Underinsured Motorist insurance policy.

 Wrongful Death --Civil Litigation-Federal Civil Rights-Federal Court Jurisdiction-Appellate Court Jurisdiction

A large verdict was obtained in a federal civil rights trial. The governmental defendants sought to appeal to the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit in Cincinnati. However, Federal courts are courts of &quot;limited jurisdiction&quot; under the principles of the U.S. Constitution. Federal courts have jurisdiction over only specific types of claims, as spelled out in the Constitution and federal law. These principles and other specific rules apply in the U. S. Courts of Appeal. Mr. Zelenock filed motions in the trial court defeating appellate court jurisdiction. The case was settled within months for more than the full amount awarded at trial, rather than years later or at a discounted amount.

 Premises Liability -Slip and Fall on Ice and Snow-Construction Defect

An woman slipped and fell on an icy patch created by a construction and drainage defect at a fast food restaurant. She suffered several lower leg fractures. The company sought to blame her for falling, despite the restaurant&apos;s failure to clear the walkways. A site visit during a snowstorm provided key evidence regarding the restaurant&apos;s snow and ice removal practices (are the lack thereof), and a fair settlement was promptly reached in the case.

 Pre-existing Conditions -Head trauma-Aggravation of Pre-Existing Conditions and Mental Illness

A woman with a significant history of pre-existing medical and difficult emotional problems was hurt in a low-speed automobile accident. Both the other driver&apos;s insurer and her own No Fault insurer fought her claims, seeking to blame her &quot;pre-existing conditions&quot; for all her problems, rather than the accident. However, Michigan law follows the traditional common law &quot;eggshell skull rule&quot; - i.e. if a pre-existing condition makes a person more susceptible to injury, that does not excuse the at fault party from paying damages resulting from the accident. Investigation showed that the women was functioning quite well immediately before the accident, despite her pre-existing problems. Then, the accident sent her on a downward spiral with devastating health consequences (her body weight dropped below 90 lbs). With proper medical help, her condition slowly improved. Mr. Zelenock&apos;s litigation work secured payment for medical bills and also provided a large cash settlement. You don&apos;t have to be in perfect health to have legal rights. You can recover insurance benefits, even if you have significant pre-existing health problems, injuries or conditions.

 Drunk Driver - House damage-Coordination or Competing Insurance Coverages

A drunk driver fleeing the police lost control, left the road, and drove into the side of the client&apos;s home. No Fault automobile insurance and home owner&apos;s insurance policies both may provide coverage for this type of accident. There are advantages and disadvantages to both. It often makes sense to check your policies and to consult with an experienced insurance attorney at the outset of a claim to choose the best approach to protect your family. In this case, the insurance coverages and property damages were assessed, and the claims settled so that the home could be repaired.

 Uninsured Motorist -Excess Economic Loss Damages--

In this case, the client had allowed her insurance to lapse in violation of Michigan law. Another driver ran a stop sign and caused very serious lower leg injuries to the client. As an uninsured driver, the client was barred from recovering non-economic damages (i.e. pain and suffering). However, she could recover her future wage loss expected due to her permanent leg injuries. A civil case was filed and $90,000 was recovered, despite her uninsured status. In some cases, a client who loses some legal rights and privileges due to her own mistakes, still has other legal rights that can be vindicated in civil litigation. Careful evaluation of your legal rights with an attorney can prepare you to deal with problems successfully.

 Self employment -Lost Wages-No Fault Insurance Coverage

A hardworking excavation and timbering worker sustained injuries in an automobile accident. He was an independent contractor or &quot;self employed.&quot; The No Fault insurer took issue with his recordkeeping, and refused to pay wage loss benefits. The client was assisted with his bookkeeping and banking records. His wage loss claims were put in order, and full payment was obtained from the No Fault insurer.

 Timber Theft -Property Damage-Property Rights-Hardwood Timber

During the housing boom of the mid-2000&apos;s, the theft of hardwood timber from Northern Michigan land (for use in hardwood flooring) was a serious problem. Michigan law provides protection for landowners in the form of a statutory cause of action that allows for the recovery damages and even &quot;treble damages&quot; in some cases involving harm to land, timber or minerals on land. MCL 600.2919 et seq. A landowner&apos;s property was &quot;overcut&quot; by a timbering contractor, with many more valuable hardwoods removed than was agreed to originally. An expert forester was hired to assess the damages, and a civil litigation was filed. A good result was obtained from the timber company&apos;s insurer.

 Employment Law --Sales Commissions-Breach of Contract

A salesman worked for a company under a commission agreement. He decided to resign and start up his own business in a different field. Under his commission agreement, he earned sales commission when he &quot;closed sales,&quot; and then the commissions were paid later, when the receipts from the sales were received from the customer. The former employer withheld payment of his commissions, arguing no commissions were owed because the salesman quit the company. Disputes over unpaid commissions are a common problem faced by commissioned salesmen and saleswomen. Michigan has enacted a statute to help provide relief, the Sales Representative Commissions Act, MCL 600.2961. The Act allows a salesmen or saleswomen to recover unpaid commissions from an employer, and treble damages, interest, costs, and attorneys&apos; fees in proper circumstances. Mr. Zelenock filed a civil action for the salesman, and the unpaid commissions were recovered in full. 
 Home  |  About Us  |  Legal Expertise  |  Contact Us Old City Hall | 160 E State St, Suite 203 | Traverse City, MI 49684 | Phone: 231-929-ZLAW(9529) Jay Zelenock Law Firm | Website created by Knorr Marketing
	</body>
</document>
