<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003273" url="http://finance.groups.yahoo.com/group/WaiterNews/messages/1?xm=1&amp;m=e&amp;l=1" time="2012-07-12-19:24" support="13" score="0.017854061977763187" bingtitle="WaiterNews : Messages : 1-30 of 4212" webtitle="WaiterNews : Messages : 1-30 of 4212">
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000521" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="68"/>
	<description>The menu offers duck breast with &quot;cassoulet,&quot; and the ... plans to add nutritional information to its paper tray ... To receive an accurate representation, researchers visited ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Groups 
 
 Search Search Web 
 WaiterNews ·Waiter News 
 
 Home Messages Post Attachments Links 
 
 Members Only Files Photos Database Polls Members Calendar Promote 
 
 Info Settings 
 
Group Information

 Members: 72 Category: Restaurants Founded: May 5, 2004 Language: English 
 Already a member? Sign in to Yahoo! 
Yahoo! Groups Tips

Did you know...
 Message search is now enhanced, find messages faster. Take it for a spin. 
 
Messages
   Messages Help 
 
 Message # Search: Advanced Start Topic 

 Messages 1 - 30 of 4212  Oldest  |  &lt; Older  |  Newer &gt;  |  Newest 
 
 Messages: Show Message Summaries  ( Group by Topic ) Sort by Date   #1 From: &quot;Mr Paul C. Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Wed May 5, 2004 11:44 pm
 Subject: Waiter News from WaitersWorld waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Having bombarded all of you with my enthusiastic
effort to keep our group abreast of the most current
waiter related breaking news stories I finally slowed
down for a moment to put some thought into this news
concept.

So!

I have created&quot;Waiter News&quot;and will post all the
news stories on this website. You can go to this link http://finance.groups.yahoo.com/group/WaiterNews at
your choosing/leisure.
I&apos;m feeling a little sheepish about not having thought
of doing this previously. I really do admire all of
your patience with my light-speed efforts to improve
our network of professionals and how we communicate.
This change is my effort to stop cluttering your email
boxes. :-)!


I hope you will find this more flexible for your
Internet uses. In the mean time: Make it fun, make it
easy, make some money!!! TM

Sincerely,

Paul C. Paz
www.WaitersWorld.com





__________________________________
Do you Yahoo!?
Win a $20,000 Career Makeover at Yahoo! HotJobs http://hotjobs.sweepstakes.yahoo.com/careermakeover 
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #2 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Wed May 5, 2004 11:59 pm
 Subject: Restaurant association launches online job site (Portland, OR 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Portland Business Journal 5.5.04

Restaurant association launches online job site

In an industry where employee turnover can be especially
challenging, Oregon restaurant owners now have a new tool: a job
recruitment Web site.


The Oregon Restaurant Association, in partnership with the
California Restaurant Association, has created a program designed to
help restaurants seeking to fill existing or new positions as well
as identify employment opportunities for their managers.&quot;We are very excited about OregonRestaurantJobs.com,&quot;said Mike
McCallum, president and chief executive officer of the Oregon
Restaurant Association, based in Wilsonville.&quot;Our industry will
need an estimated 1.2 million more managers and staff over the next
several years. We must ensure that we create a steady stream of
employees interested in careers in the food service industry. To do
that, we provide a location for owners and managers to easily
connect with interested employees.&quot;The Oregon restaurant and foods service industry is projected to
have $9.5 billion in 2004 sales and more than 108,000 employees.

The job recruitment Web site can be reached through the ORA site at
www.ora.org or by going directly to www.OregonRestaurantJobs.com.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #3 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 12:03 am
 Subject: Maine - restaurant staff - illegal aliens face deportation (Boston Globe 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Restaurant workers nabbed at traffic stop could be deported

Boston Globe
May 5, 2004

WATERVILLE, Maine -- Eleven illegal aliens employed at a newly
opened restaurant faced deportation proceedings following their
arrest by federal agents after an unplanned traffic stop,
authorities said.

After being taken into custody late Monday in Waterville, the two
Chinese nationals and nine Mexicans were transported to the
Department of Homeland Security office of Border Patrol in Rangeley,
according to Supervisory Border Patrol Agent Frank Blauvelt.

All 11 were employed by Grand Asian Buffet, which opened in late
March.&quot;We had a couple of agents there (in Waterville) on other business
when they encountered a van and performed a vehicle stop,&quot;he
said.&quot;There was no planned operation.&quot;One of the agents is an intelligence specialist whose suspicions
were aroused by the large 2001 Dodge van with New Mexico license
plates registered to a Chinese man and being driven by a white
female with about 20 passengers, Blauvelt said.

He said seven passengers in the van were found to be without
documents. Waterville police later visited the nearby Budget Host
motel, where four more were arrested, bringing the total to 11.

Blauvelt said the Chinese people, a man and a woman both in their
late 20s, had been smuggled into the United States.

Chen King, co-owner of the Grand Asian Buffet, said Tuesday the
Border Patrol visit did not happen by chance. He said his popular
restaurant, which seats 420 people, has become the target of
competitors.

King said he hires people with immigrant identification, but some
lie and tell him they are waiting for their work visa, or green card.

Blauvelt said the two Chinese people claimed that they paid to be
smuggled into the United States.

The Chinese man was released on his own recognizance and must appear
in federal court in Boston for a deportation hearing. The Mexican
nationals will be sent back to their homeland.

Blauvelt said the process of handling illegal workers differs for
each country under U.S. law and agreements with the various nations.

He said the case involving Grand Asian Buffet has been turned over
to criminal investigators because hiring illegal aliens is against
the law. Blauvelt added that employers often get the benefit of the
doubt when it comes to workers and their status as legal immigrants.&quot;There are several steps in the process,&quot;he said.&quot;Proving
knowledge is a very difficult thing to do.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #4 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 6:03 am
 Subject: Senate Votes to Temper Overtime Rules (RestaurantBusiness.com 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Senate Votes to Temper Overtime Rules

MAY 05, 2004 -- WASHINGTON, DC -- The U.S. Senate voted yesterday to
block an aspect of the new overtime regulations that could have
ended a flood of lawsuits seeking back pay from foodservice
employers.

The lawmakers, in a relatively close vote, approved a measure that
would prevent the new rules from denying overtime wages to anyone
currently entitled to time-and-half for work time exceeding 40 hours
a week. In recent years, a number of restaurant employers have been
sued by managers claiming they were entitled to that premium pay
scale because the tasks they performed were identical to the work of
subordinates collecting overtime. The plaintiffs allege that their
duties were not managerial in nature, and hence should not be
covered by the overtime exemptions that apply to management
personnel.

The rules issued last month by the U.S. Dept. of Labor would have
likely ended the lawsuits by redefining management personnel. The
new criteria would have clearly applied to restaurant managers and
assistant managers, according to the NRA.

By stating that anyone entitled to overtime by the old rules would
continue to quality under the new regulations, the Senate&apos;s
stipulation clouds the issue once again.

However, Beltway observers were quick to note that the measure has
to clear a number of additional hurdles before it takes effect. The
qualification was offered in the form of an amendment to a corporate
tax bill that has yet to move forward in the Senate after months of
consideration. Even if that tax proposal is approved by the Senate,
it would still have to be weighed by the House.

The Bush Administration quickly mustered a defense of its new
regulations. U.S. Wage and House Division Administrator Tammy
McCutchen told a Senate subcommittee that yesterday&apos;s stipulation,
put forth by Sen. Tom Harkin, a Democrat from Iowa, could backfire
and deny overtime to many workers who would otherwise be covered
under the new rules.

The revised regulations are scheduled to go into effect in August.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #5 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 7:04 am
 Subject: Kids welcome here: Small fries mean big business (Canada.com - Edmonton Journal waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Kids welcome here: Small fries mean big business for some restaurants

Judy Schultz
The Edmonton Journal

Wednesday, May 05, 2004

They don&apos;t eat much, they&apos;re messy, they&apos;re noisy, they don&apos;t tip,
and they never buy the happy hour special.

The truth is out: Some restaurants just don&apos;t want kids to darken
their doorways. But that&apos;s a minority opinion.

The trend? More restaurants than ever are welcoming children, and
actively courting their business.

Children&apos;s meals represent a relatively small chunk of their per-
person profit; as little as three per cent at Boston Pizza, or five
per cent in Moxie&apos;s Classic Grill.

But that isn&apos;t the issue.&quot;No child comes in for dinner by himself,&quot;says Lindy Rawlinson of
the Alberta Foodservice and Restaurant Association.&quot;He&apos;s always
going to have adults with him.&quot;Ah. Now there&apos;s the issue.

BRING ON THE KIDS

Certain independents, like Tony&apos;s Pizza and Italian Restaurant in
Edmonton, have always made room for children. Tony, of the famous
flying pizza, installed a special window so children can watch him
flinging the dough in his kitchen. Meanwhile, the parents can relax
and enjoy their meal.

In Toronto, Tommy Zora is the co-owner of Jawny Baker&apos;s, a 400-seat
family restaurant that has become a model among independent family
restaurants across the country.

A high percentage of his regular clients, almost a fifth of them,
are children.

Kids don&apos;t dine out alone. In Zora&apos;s experience, even one child can
potentially have as many as six adults in tow.

He doesn&apos;t believe in feeding his junior customers junk food.&quot;Our kids&apos; menu is a pared-down version of the adult menu,&quot;says
Zora.&quot;Kids have different tastes now. They still like pizza and
french fries, but they also like skewered shrimps and caesar salad.&quot;We&apos;re community-minded, and you can&apos;t be that way without embracing
the whole family unit -- kids, parents, grandparents.&quot;Jawny Baker&apos;s staff are trained to treat children as individuals.
Like the chains, JB has a kids&apos; club, a VIP card, and on their
birthday they get a card in the mail, but when it comes to price,
Zora doesn&apos;t try to compete. There&apos;s no $3.99 whole meal deal for
kids.

For $6 they get adult food and some child-friendly perks: A colour-
me placemat with kids games, and a toy box,&quot;So they can choose one
thing when they leave.&quot;Kids grow up fast,&quot;says Zora.&quot;They&apos;re an investment in the
future.&quot;Family concepts pay off for chains&quot;We&apos;re a family restaurant concept, and children are a key component
in family,&quot;says Kristine Carrick, field marketing manager for
Ricky&apos;s All Day Grill.&quot;Children at a much younger age are influencing parental decisions
about where to eat.&quot;With 46 outlets, Ricky&apos;s will serve an average of 31,000 child meals
per month.

Their Blue Placemat program targets children age 10 and under,
providing colouring sheets and crayons, stickers and puzzles. The
treasure chest offers small prizes for after dinner.

The child&apos;s meal is inclusive, and they offer lots of options.&quot;Adults are making healthier choices, why not kids?&quot;says
Carrick.&quot;For $4.99 they get a burger, and they can have a salad with
that instead of fries. They know milk or pop is coming, so is
dessert.&quot;One of their most popular dessert items is a kid-friendly special
called worms-in-dirt: Chocolate pudding, Oreo cookie crumbs, yummie
gummie worms. They also have the Jello cloud -- sky-blue raspberry
jello layered with real whipped cream.

Another successful chain, Moxie&apos;s Classic Grill restaurants, has 40
outlets across Canada.

Moxie&apos;s started in Calgary in 1986, and president Laurids Skaarup
pegs them as&quot;upscale casual -- come in jeans or dressed up.&quot;The roots that built our success are family-friendly,&quot;says the
father of two.&quot;We hire good natured, wholesome people with family
values, and children will always be welcome in Moxies.&quot;In Edmonton, the average Moxie&apos;s seves about 5000 meals per week, of
which only 5 per cent are for customers under 12 years of age.&quot;Kids are the most important things in their lives, but mom and dad
still want to have great food, a glass of wine, be treated well, and
we want those little humans to have a great time along with their
parents.&quot;Infants get a free cold or hot plate,&quot;Whatever mom wants,&quot;he
says.&quot;Mashed vegetables or fruit.&quot;&quot;We&apos;re planning some healthier choices across the board, including
the kids&apos; menu. But kids like basic stuff, like our ice cream
volcano (an ice cream dessert in a special suspended dish with dry
ice that smokes) and we won&apos;t lose those basic pleasures.&quot;Sean Flynn, president of Smitty&apos;s Canada Ltd., says&quot;Children are of
fundamental importance in our business segment.&quot;With 115
restaurants, they design their children&apos;s menu by committee, meeting
twice a year to update it.

Their average family unit brings in two children, infant to age 14.

Two-thirds of their customers, or 66.6 per cent, are accompanied by
children. Most of their weekend breakfast segments, and their dinner
segments, are families with children.&quot;We try to provide a family environment. Come as you are, be
comfortable. We have a kids&apos; club. They&apos;re eligible for a free
birthday meal, a free toy, and they get a birthday card in the mail.&quot;The strength of our menu management is that we&apos;re very sensitive to
trends in dietary issues. We have 128 items on our menu, including
low carbs and higher protein, low fat and low calorie.

Smitty&apos;s allows, even encourages, substitutions, and the mid-year
menu committee stays on top of trends.&quot;It&apos;s not our place to put people on diets,&quot;he says.&quot;But as soon
as they say they want a crudite and dip for the kids, they&apos;ll have
it.&quot;Joanne Forrester, directing of marketing for Boston Pizza Canada,
says the company has been family-friendly since the day the first
one opened, right here in Edmonton, in 1964.

With 180 restaurants across the country, they do hot dog days,
fundraisers, tools for schools, reading programs&quot;Depends on the
franchisee,&quot;she says.&quot;These days, children have great influence on
where a family meal will be.&quot;Although the child meal isn&apos;t a profit
maker, fifty per cent of their tables are often families.&quot;We have colouring sheets, activity books, puzzles, a kids menu. Our
number one seller is a pint-sized pepperoni pizza, after that
chicken fingers with fries, and they can substitute tossed or caesar
salad for fries.&quot;BP instituted that change because of parent requests that came
through franchisees -- the same reason they offer milk or juice
instead of pop, at no extra charge.

Bruce Derochie manages Chuck E. Cheese, a 390-seat restaurant and
entertainment venue designed especially for customers aged two to 12.

This is no ordinary restaurant, and chances are, if you don&apos;t have
children, you&apos;d rather not be here.

But if you do? Yippee.

The big draw for the small fry is the large friendly mouse, Chuck E.
Cheese.

He&apos;s furry, hugable, and&quot;More popular than Mickey Mouse,&quot;says
Derochie.

Chuck E. ambles around the room at all times, communicating with
body language (he doesn&apos;t speak).

There are three rooms -- one for games, one for rides, and a
showroom with interactive television.&quot;Our food is good,&quot;says Derochie, who offers pizza, cinnamon
sticks, wings, submarine sandwiches and an all-you-can-eat salad
bar. Beverages are bottomless, refills are self-serve, always a big
hit with kids.

A second Chuck E Cheese will open in Edmonton in January. jschultz@... FUN TREATS FOR SMALL FRIES

Most adults, faced with an original Fear Factor dessert called
Dirt &apos;n&apos; Worms, would suddenly remember urgent business in another
room.

Little kids, on the other hand, love it. They giggle, they make
faces, they dig in with spoon and fingers.

We&apos;re talking about chocolate pudding, crumbled chocolate Oreos, a
few multicoloured gummy worms and a lollipop. How bad could it be?

Bistro uses a milk-based cornstarch pudding for this. Instant is OK,
but, if you have time, real chocolate pudding without the starchy,
over-sweet taste of an instant pud is infinitely better.

DIRT &apos;N&apos; WORMS

Serves 4

- 1 cooked chocolate pudding, 4- serving size

- 2 cups whole milk

- 2 chocolate Oreo-style fudge cookies

- 12 gummy worms or marshmallow caterpillars

- 4 round lollipops

Prepare chocolate pudding according to directions on box. Pour into
4 pot-shaped glasses and refrigerate. (May also be frozen to soft-
ice texture.) Crumble cookies and scatter over the top of the
pudding pots. Add worms, allowing them to hang over the edge. Just
before serving, add a lollipop. (They stand in the pudding if it&apos;s
slightly frozen.)

It doesn&apos;t get any easier than this, and the blue Jell-O seems to
intrigue those sophisticates who have already decided that green,
red and yellow Jell-O are passe.

BLUE SKY, FLUFFY CLOUDS

Serves 4

- 1 blue raspberry Jell-O powder

- 1 cup (250 mL) boiling water

- about 8 ice cubes

- 1 cup (250 mL) whipped cream, lightly sweetened

- candy stars

Dissolve Jell-O in boiling water. Add ice cubes and stir until
melted and Jell-O is syrupy. Pour small amount into four clear
serving glasses. Whip cream until stiff; sweeten lightly with sugar
and add vanilla to taste.

Spoon cream onto first layer of blue Jell-O. Spoon remaining Jell-O
over whipped cream, dividing it evenly. Top with the remaining
whipped cream and sprinkle with candy stars.

These are just plain good, but they&apos;re cute, too. Don&apos;t stop with a
teddy -- dogs, cats, chicks, funny faces, clowns all make good
candidates for banana pancakes.

BANANA PANCAKE TEDDIES

Serves 4

- 1 egg

- 1 ripe banana, mashed

- 2 cups (500 mL) pancake mix

- milk to make a thin batter

- dried cranberries

Beat egg and mashed banana together. Add pancake mix and stir. Stir
in enough milk to make a thin batter -- do not overmix. To make
teddy bears, start with a large round for a body. Add a smaller
round for the head, two very small rounds for ears, and finally four
small rounds for arms and legs. Cook only until bubbles form and
begin to break. With a long spatula, carefully turn the teddy. Cook
until firm. Lift to wire racks and add cranberry face. Serve with
bacon or a sausage, plus buttered maple syrup.

Ran with fact box&quot;Only if You Bring Kids&quot;, which has been appended
to this story.

 The Edmonton Journal 2004
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #6 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 7:07 am
 Subject: 1/4 of all fish sold in Australia is deceptively labelled (SYDNEY 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 DNA tests find something fishy in Aussie restaurants

Wed May 5, 1:04 PM ET Add Offbeat - AFP

SYDNEY (AFP) - A survey using DNA testing has found that up to a
quarter of all fish sold in Australia is deceptively labelled as the
wrong species, it was reported.

While Australia prides itself on being a major exporter of quality
seafoods, notably to the highly discerning Japanese market, the
survey by the Food Standards Australia New Zealand agency found
widespread shortchanging of consumers at home according a report by
The Daily Telegraph.

Some 200 DNA tests on raw and cooked fish across Australia found
systematic mislabelling by retailers and restaurateurs who offered
customers popular fish like barramundi and red emperor but actually
gave them other types.

The worst rate of deception, according to the survey, was in
restaurants and other food service businesses, where barely 60
percent of the fish sold was what the customer ordered.

The best compliance was at the wholesale level where mislabelling
occurred in less than 12 percent of cases.

Industry-wide, fish samples were correctly labelled 76.8 percent of
the time, the newspaper said.

New South Wales state Primary Industries Minister Ian MacDonald
responded to the survey by announcing a new crackdown on phoney fish
with fines for cheating of up to 275,000 dollars.

But he stressed that the problem did not affect the wholesale or
export trade.&quot;It&apos;s not at the wholesale level, it&apos;s retail and food service,&quot;he
told ABC radio.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #7 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 7:16 am
 Subject: Play about waiters&quot;Nickel and Dimed&quot;(From the same book) (Cleveland 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Labor Intensive - Low-wage workers sweat and suffer in the excellent
Nickel and Dimed.
BY CHRISTINE HOWEY feedback@... clevescene.com originally published: May 5, 2004

Nickel and Dimed
Details: Through May 29; 216-631-2727
Where: Produced by Cleveland Public Theatre in association with
Great Lakes Theater Festival at Cleveland Public Theatre, 6415
Detroit Avenue

Stage
Blues Clues
Great singing only suggests the story behind Cookin&apos; at the Cookery.

Almost everyone in the so-called middle class and above has worked
at a menial job at some point -- waiting tables in college or
working at Kmart during summer break. And after they move on to
other, more remunerative pursuits, those fortunate folk have the
luxury of thinking back on their brutal employment experiences with
a faint shudder of amazement, asking themselves,&quot;How did I ever put
up with all that bullshit for chump change?&quot;But when menial hourly employment is the only kind of work you can
get to support your family, the issues become much more stark. How
can a man earning $6 an hour put a deposit down on a decent living
space? He can&apos;t, so he has to spend more money to live in a
marginally sanitary motel. How can a woman with similar income and
young children afford day care? She can&apos;t, so she turns her eight-
year-old into a baby-sitter while she&apos;s at work.

The working poor and their plight in benignly indifferent America is
the subject of Nickel and Dimed by Joan Holden -- presented by
Cleveland Public Theatre in association with the Great Lakes Theater
Festival -- a dramatic adaptation of Barbara Ehrenreich&apos;s popular,
identically titled nonfiction book. For one year, Ehrenreich
embedded herself in the ranks of low-income workers, laboring as a
waitress, a housecleaner, and a retail clerk to experience the
workaday humiliations and the cash-flow challenges firsthand. And
while her foray into desperate economic straits wasn&apos;t entirely
genuine (she held on to some emergency parachutes, including her ATM
card), Ehrenreich was able to convey with telling immediacy the
cruel conundrums of low-wage life.

Holden&apos;s reworking hews closely to the source material, which
doesn&apos;t always work dramatically. But this production sparkles like
a restaurant&apos;s well-scrubbed kitchen counter, thanks to imaginative
direction by Melissa Kievman and an ever-inventive six-person cast.
Jill Levin is perfectly believable as Barbara herself, narrating her
experiences as she moves from Florida to Maine and then to Minnesota
in search of the primary punch-clock sensibility. Along the way, she
shares with her co-workers cigarette breaks (one of the few job
perks, and even that generates tumors) and hatred of control-freak
corporate bosses.

Director Kievman&apos;s staging is continually involving from several
perspectives. For one, she has created a theater-in-the-round space
inside CPT&apos;s Gordon Square facility, so that the audience can
observe itself as well as the action in the center. Indeed, the
working poor are curiously invisible most of the time, even when
they&apos;re standing next to us, and this production dissolves that
barrier, if only for a couple of hours. The stage structure also
suggests a Roman coliseum, where the privileged watch as doomed
gladiators battle economically with capitalism&apos;s beasts of prey. In
addition, Kievman and scenic designer Todd S. Krispinsky keep the
action moving by mounting virtually all set pieces on casters,
wheeling them in and out as in a well-oiled roller derby.

But the supporting players, all of whom play multiple roles, furnish
much of the sting of Ehrenreich&apos;s discoveries and loads of the
humor. George Roth is consistently surprising as, among other
things, a barely fluent immigrant busboy, Barbara&apos;s clueless
husband, and a selection of grubby supervisors. Equally flexible and
talented is Nina Domingue, as an aggressively comical Puerto Rican
cook and a slow-talking, slow-walking hotel maid. Tracee Patterson
etches a couple of memorable characters -- in particular the sweet,
helpful, but totally intimidated Holly, who is the pregnant&quot;team
leader&quot;of the housecleaning crew. Nan Wray and Sheffia W. Randall
also have fine moments as, respectively, a gimpy but game cleaning
person and a born-again&quot;Mall-Mart&quot;shelf-stocker.

Since the play&apos;s structure is so episodic, there is little
opportunity for any real character development -- a difficulty that
is augmented by Barbara&apos;s continually breaking character to comment
on the proceedings. In fact, in the second act, the entire cast
drops the fourth wall and has a brief talk-back with the audience
about the patrons&apos; experiences cleaning houses or offices and their
employing of others to do the same. This fragmentation means that,
from time to time, Nickel and Dimed feels like loose change
theatrically. Even with these minor quibbles and a dialogue pace
that on this night was a bit spongy, the production is a triumph.
Credit goes to CPT&apos;s James Levin and GLTF&apos;s Charles Fee for
combining their companies&apos; imposing talents on such a worthy effort.

So, after all is said and done, who is to blame for the awful lives
of the working poor? As one character revealingly explains, it&apos;s no
one&apos;s fault. It&apos;s all about the numbers: the profit numbers that
drive corporations to deny their employees decent compensation and
the bargain-price numbers that draw millions of customers through
Wal-Mart&apos;s smiley-face doors.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #8 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 7:23 am
 Subject: The Waiting Game (Denver, CO 5.6.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 The Waiting Game
Bistro Vendome marks an important milestone.

BY JASON SHEEHAN Jason.Sheehan@... westword.com originally published: May 6, 2004

Bistro Vendome
Details: 1424 Larimer Street, 303-825-3232. Hours: 5-10 p.m. Sunday-
Thursday, 5-11 p.m. Friday-Saturday; brunch 11 a.m.-2 p.m. Friday-
Sunday. Closed Mondays
Mussels: $9
Steak tartare: $11
Mashed potatoes: $5
Chilled asparagus: $6
Trout amandine: $17
Duck breast: $19
Rabbit blanquette: $17
Steak frites, all varieties: $19

Three months. For most critics, that&apos;s the amount of time that must
pass before a brand-new restaurant is considered fair game for a
review. Ostensibly, three months should be long enough for a place
to survive its opening jitters, find a true tone and voice, and get
a good set of legs under it. During that time, the kitchen should
have winnowed down its original menu and ditched any dogs -- those
plates that look great on paper but never really work -- and
management should have let go of any losers who couldn&apos;t hack the
daily grind of regular service.

All through my time in The Life -- during the dozen years I spent on
one side of the swinging doors and the handful I&apos;ve now had on the
other -- I&apos;ve seen every extreme of what can happen in those first
ninety days. Whole staffs fired, chefs&apos; menus scrapped and reworked
by committee (certain death for any restaurant that doesn&apos;t take its
orders through a giant clown head on a pole), owners who&apos;ve suffered
major nervous breakdowns and blown every dime of operating capital
on a red MG convertible and enough Bolivian marching powder to send
them straight into bankruptcy arbitration. I once opened and ran a
kitchen that, in the course of its first three months, went from
French to French-Asian to Asian-Southwestern to (no lie) Gourmet
magazine&apos;s best recipes of 1987. By the time the first critic
arrived, I was cooking a menu that looked like a psychotic lawn fete
for foreign-service diplomats: melon balls and prosciutto in sugar-
cane syrup, cucumber-bean sprout canaps, Balinese shrimp satay,
cold rosemary chicken in bourbon mustard sauce and mustard ham
custards -- all served in a cafe with posterized van Gogh
lithographs on the walls and freaky Middle Eastern pop on the
stereo. We never got a review, just a phone call from the critic
saying there was no point. And she was right. The place was a hair
salon before its six-month anniversary.

In the restaurant world, three months is both a blink and a
lifetime. In Denver, there have been restaurants that never saw
their ninetieth night of service (Bistro 250); ones that did but
were so clearly doomed that you could almost hear the life-support
machinery beeping in the background (Aquarela); still others that
three months out bore almost no resemblance to how they&apos;d started
(Flow). And while three months is as acceptable a standard as any,
it&apos;s also totally arbitrary. There are some houses that come right
out of the gate doing the kind of excellent work for which they&apos;re
known forever after, and some that limp along for months, going
nowhere, until somehow -- for reasons known only to the food gods
and their minions here on earth -- they begin to glow with that
special kind of light that only spills from a restaurant that has
suddenly, sometimes inexplicably, found its groove.

For Bistro Vendome, it took a year almost to the day from its
opening last April.

Had I reviewed this restaurant at its three-month mark, I would have
written something like this:&quot;Chef Eric Roeder&apos;s little bistro-that-
couldn&apos;t is a waste. Of space, of talent, of potential, but most of
all, it&apos;s a waste of time. From the staff that barely manages to
bumble its dopey way through service, to plate after plate of dull
French cruise-ship fare only notable for the way that the kitchen
manages to tragically mishandle at least one ingredient in every
single presentation, dinner here isn&apos;t much more than an overpriced
exercise in deliberate self-abuse. In the mood for a nice French
lunch? You&apos;d be better served by one of the new chicken baguette
sandwiches at Burger King.&quot;I know that&apos;s what I would have written because that&apos;s what I did
write. I found that little nettle in my notes a while back,
scribbled down on the back of a Bistro Vendome credit-card slip
along with some cryptic reference to the steak frites. My meal there
was awful, but chef/owner Eric Roeder was trying so hard that I
decided to give him more time.

At around the seven-month mark, I dropped by again for a solo
dinner. Although the place was half empty, I was seated at a table
next to a busser&apos;s station; I was brought the wrong wine; my trout
amandine was overcooked and bitter with a mismatched vinaigrette.
And then -- because adding insult to injury is such a good business
practice -- I had to wait for my check. There&apos;s just nothing like
suffering through a mediocre dinner at a lousy table and then being
made to wait for the privilege of paying for it. I figured my server
was busy updating his resum.

Still, I held my tongue. Or my pen, anyway. What stopped me -- what
kept stopping me -- was a niggling, back-brain itch that said the
place had promise, but its potential kept getting tripped up by
rookie mistakes.

For starters, there was the beautiful, understated space, all warm
mustard and candlelight, not overly Frenched-up but not Left Bank
theme restaurant, either. Tucked into a quiet corner behind Larimer
Square with a chalkboard pointing the way, a picturesque patio and
views of a peaceful garden square and the display window of a Vespa
dealership, Bistro Vendome boasted one of the greatest restaurant
addresses in the city -- hidden enough to feel isolated from the
Saturday-night scrum, welcoming enough to feel like a spot you&apos;ve
stumbled on accidentally, even if you&apos;ve just spent twenty minutes
fighting for parking and looking for the entrance. Although Roeder
initially said his place was&quot;designed to evoke the look and feel of
a long-established, family-owned bistro plucked from a Parisian
street corner,&quot;you didn&apos;t feel moved to Paris when you stepped
through the doors, but rather like you&apos;d walked into a drop-dead
lovely American restaurant that had made good use of every physical
advantage and happened to serve French food.

Roeder&apos;s resum also indicated unfulfilled potential: a degree from
the Culinary Institute of America, time at Gray Kunz&apos;s Lespinasse
and Seattle&apos;s Painted Table, stints locally at Q&apos;s, the Flagstaff
House and Micole, his restaurant that opened in 2000 and closed two
years later. Roeder had serious street cred as a hard-core French
classicist with enough Zagat and Mobil stars on his shoulders to
look like a battlefield general. And while no chef is ever magically
immune from making bad food, when bad food keeps coming out of the
kitchen of a cook who should know better, I have to wonder what&apos;s
going wrong. By the time a chef has put in ten years knocking around
haute-French kitchens, by the time he&apos;s opened and shut the first
place where his name is on the menu, he&apos;s probably cooked 10,000
plates of trout amandine and could cook trout amandine in his sleep.
So when the trout amandine is anything less than perfect, that&apos;s a
sign of something gone seriously awry.

In Roeder&apos;s case, there were clues. When Bistro Vendome first
opened, it was serving breakfast, lunch and dinner all week, with
Sunday brunches thrown in -- a fine-dining recipe for cataclysmic
burnout. By then, Roeder had been without a galley of his own for
over a year, and kitchen work is just not the kind of thing you jump
back into like you&apos;d never left. It requires heavy readjustment to
get back into the swing of things, and if you don&apos;t have a killer
crew already set and in place, it&apos;s even harder.

All of this flavored my decision to wait, my belief that something
good would come from Vendome -- an instinct wholly different from
merciful reviewing silence.

And in this case, my instinct was right. Over the months, Roeder
made decisions that finally got Vendome moving in the right
direction. He dumped breakfast, then lunch. He extended his brunches
to Friday, Saturday and Sunday. A new manager and partner was
brought into the mix -- Scott Tallman, late of Flow -- who ably
whipped the front of the house into shape, leaving Roeder free to
turn his attention to the back. And with time, these changes pulled
the restaurant from the brink of what was looking like a nosedive
into mediocrity, if not pure suck. Like the sculptor says,&quot;I just
looked at the stone and chipped away everything that wasn&apos;t a
statue.&quot;At Vendome, Roeder and Tallman did the same thing, taking a
long look and removing everything that wasn&apos;t a good restaurant.

So now, on a Saturday night, Bistro Vendome has that glow, that
quality of warmth and joy and light that seems to flow through the
front windows in wavelengths only visible to the gut and the
subconscious. Where once I felt a culinary-death-ship vibe, now I
know in my bones that the place has righted its course. I know this
before I even step inside, as I hear other diners saying their
goodbyes.&quot;Tell him everything was great, will you?&quot;&quot;It was good, sooooo good. Tell the chef we can&apos;t wait to come
back.&quot;I hear those and a half-dozen more exclamations before I reach my
seat. Pretty girls are walking by in a swoon, talking to random
waitresses and busboys, sending their love back to the galley. Men
are pumping Tallman&apos;s hand and offering their appreciation in tones
of sudden, surprised reverence. In the small dining room -- where
this time we&apos;re given a good table, far from the crash and tinkle of
the bus station -- couples are spearing bites off each other&apos;s
plates, closing their eyes, pitching woo over big, white bowls of
fat mussels in curry cream, in a classic garlic beurre blanc, or
steaming in a broth of saffron and vermouth.

I avoid the trout amandine in favor of a rabbit blanquette that&apos;s so
classically, historically French that I fully expect it to jump up
off my plate and surrender to the first German it runs into. The
creamy white stew of mild, wine-braised shredded rabbit has the
texture of a tuna casserole, but it&apos;s filled with deep and solidly
balanced flavors of meat, salty cream, onion and garlic. It comes
with sweet, glazed baby carrots and baby artichokes with their
vegetable taste rather than their nutty character highlighted, all
over a flaky biscuit that lends some bulk and a distinct soul-food
flavor. Unfortunately, there are also three stalks of white
asparagus on the plate that are undercooked, hard and fibrous.

We fill the table with mussels, with petit plats of good, tender
green asparagus served cold with a spoonful of spicy rouille, with
mashed red potatoes left chunky, touched with vinegar and topped
with shreds of bacon and a fall of perfect crme frache. I devour
an entire plate of Roeder&apos;s steak tartare -- caper-heavy and bloody,
sweet and sour and salty all at the same time -- without sharing
with anyone, then move on to steal bites from everyone else&apos;s
plates. The menu offers duck breast with&quot;cassoulet,&quot;and the
preparation earned those quote marks, because the white beans had
been tossed into the hot pan just before service instead of cooking
for hours in a stew of onions and meat and stock. Still, they serve
as a nice counterpoint to the tender duck that shines in a
caramelized orange sauce. There&apos;s pork belly over field greens, a
paillard of veal, and sugared, herbed frites with steak done three
ways: classique, with a tiny tin cup of lemon and tarragon
barnaise; au poivre, with a green peppercorn sauce; and the
wonderful Roquefort, sprinkled with bleu cheese and paired with a
sweet port-wine reduction.

Finally, I have the dinner that I knew Vendome was capable of: a
simple but beautiful spread of French classics, handled with care by
a skilled kitchen, served by excellent staffers with a depth of
knowledge and a command of dining-room French that runs so counter
to the dreadlocks, the tattoos and the facial hair that I can&apos;t help
but love the juxtaposition. It&apos;s taken a long time -- a lot more
than three months -- but today Bistro Vendome is the restaurant I
had always hoped it would become. Now Burger King doesn&apos;t have
anything on Roeder.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #9 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Thu May 6, 2004 7:27 am
 Subject: Ex-restaurateur owes them thousands of dollars to employees. (Florida 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Ex-restaurateur faces string of lawsuits
Creditors, lawyers and an employee say BackWaters Bar and Grille or
founder Larry Layton owe them hundreds of thousands of dollars
altogether.

By KELLY VIRELLA
Published May 5, 2004

St Petersburg Times 5.5.04

SPRING HILL - The kitchen manager went to work at 10:30 a.m. April
10, expecting to prepare food for BackWaters Bar and Grille&apos;s noon
lunch rush.

From the parking lot, Jennifer Pearce, 27, could see that the
restaurant, west of Weeki Wachee, was dark inside and that manager
and founder Larry Layton hadn&apos;t come to unlock it. The day before he
had closed the restaurant early, citing a lack of food.

But the Spring Hill woman waited an hour for Layton because she
wanted the $1,950 in back pay that she said he owed her. BackWaters
Bar and Grille never opened. Pearce and most of her 10 co-workers
never got their pay from Layton, she said.

Now Pearce is taking Layton to Hernando County&apos;s small claims court.&quot;It&apos;s just really quite a big mess,&quot;Pearce said.&quot;I had no idea the
restaurant was going to be shutting down and I wasn&apos;t going to be
getting my money.&quot;With her April 12 claim, Pearce may have to wait in line behind
others who are trying to get paid by Layton.

In the past three months, six other creditors have sued Layton or
his restaurant in Hernando County courts.

Compass Bank initiated foreclosure proceedings on the restaurant
March 30, alleging that BackWaters owes about $260,000 on the
mortgage. Layton or BackWaters is behind on payments to two other
banks, a credit card issuer and a law firm that allege he or the
restaurant owes them a total of $145,000.

Bank One, the Pitney Bowes Bank, GE Capital Corp., and Papy,
Weissenborn, Vraspir,&amp;Puga have all filed suits against Layton or
BackWaters since February.

None of BackWaters&apos; other employees have filed a suit against him or
the company. But Pearce said Layton hasn&apos;t paid them their last two
weeks&apos; wages.

Layton did not return calls for comment.

But court records filed in connection with his year-old divorce
proceedings show that the 5-year-old restaurant posted two years of
losses in 1999 and 2000 before earning a $38,000 profit in 2001.

Last October, Layton attempted to sell the restaurant. He entered
into a contract with Maria Belavilas of Spring Hill and her son
Dimitrios Belavilas for $550,000, but the sale failed for reasons
that are not specified in the divorce files.

Also, Layton&apos;s wife objected to the sale, according to court records
filed last October. At the time, Lisa Marie Layton believed the
restaurant was worth more, and a court order issued during their
divorce proceedings prevents him from selling it without her
approval.

Pearce had worked at the restaurant since April 2003. She said she
knew something was wrong when Layton stopped giving her money to
replace food a few weeks before shutting down. But Pearce wasn&apos;t
particularly alarmed that she hadn&apos;t been paid in two weeks, she
said. Layton had trouble paying her several times before, she said.&quot;It was pretty obvious that he was running down&quot;his kitchen
supplies, Pearce said.&quot;But the way he was relaying it to me was
that he was just having a few financial problems.&quot;On April 9, Layton told the bartender to announce that everyone was
free to leave the restaurant because there was no more food. After a
group of diners finished, most of the waitresses left, while some
sat down at the bar for a drink.&quot;All the members of the kitchen kept coming up there looking for
their pay&quot;for the next few days, Pearce said, who has not found a
new job.&quot;I&apos;m sure this has happened at other businesses. But I&apos;m
not sure it goes on to this extent.&quot;- Staff researcher Kitty Bennett contributed to this report. Kelly
Virella can be reached at 352 848-1434. Send e-mail to kvirella@... 
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #10 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Fri May 7, 2004 5:35 am
 Subject: Waiter steals identity of U.S. attorney! Oops (Pittsburgh, PA Post-Gazette 7.7.0 waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Thief may get a charge out of this
&apos;Swiped&apos; credit card belongs to U.S. attorney
Friday, May 07, 2004

By Torsten Ove, Pittsburgh Post-Gazette

U.S. Attorney Mary Beth Buchanan, who has made identity theft one of
her priorities, has a new perspective on the crime -- as a victim.

U.S. Attorney Mary Beth Buchanan had her credit card number stolen
while dining in San Francisco.

At the same San Francisco restaurant where she and her husband, Tom,
had their first dinner as a honeymoon couple in 1990, someone on the
staff apparently swiped her credit card number last month.&quot;What happened to me is something I&apos;ve been talking about for the
last couple of years,&quot;she said yesterday in her Downtown
office.&quot;It truly shows that this can happen to anyone.&quot;Buchanan was in San Francisco on April 18 for a seminar on corporate
fraud when she had lunch at her favorite restaurant in Union Square.

She won&apos;t identify it because federal agents are conducting an
investigation there, but she said a staffer skimmed her Visa card
using a&quot;wedge,&quot;a device thieves use to gain information from the
magnetic strips on credit cards.

Typically, a waiter or waitress hides the wedge in an apron, swipes
the cards through the wedge and makes counterfeit cards to ring up
fraudulent purchases.

It&apos;s exactly what Scott Zimmerman, 22, a former waiter at Don
Pablo&apos;s Mexican Kitchen in North Fayette, was doing as part of a
theft ring prosecuted by Buchanan&apos;s office last year.

Often, unsuspecting diners don&apos;t find out about the thefts until
much later, but Buchanan said she got lucky. The next evening, she
tried to use her card to buy a new suit before her trip home.

When the card wouldn&apos;t go through, the store owner called Visa. A
company representative told Buchanan that Visa had flagged a $31.45
purchase made at 5 a.m. that day for computer equipment ordered over
the phone.

Buchanan said the company told her the purchase was&quot;out of pattern&quot;for her shopping habits.

Credit card companies keep track of the buying patterns of customers
and&quot;red flag&quot;any purchases that seem odd.

Buchanan knew she didn&apos;t buy anything at 5 a.m., so she canceled the
account.

If she hadn&apos;t tried to buy the suit, she said, the thief likely
would have rung up many more charges before she used the card and
discovered the fraud.

The $31 purchase was small, but it&apos;s typical of skimmers.&quot;They try to use the card for small transactions first,&quot;she
said,&quot;to make sure it goes through.&quot;If the card works, the thieves often run up large numbers of
purchases in a short time, something else the credit card companies
look for.

In talks to citizens&apos; groups about identity theft, Buchanan has
often said one way to avoid it is to never give your credit card to
anyone.

But in the real world, she admitted, that can be unrealistic,
especially in a restaurant where you have eaten many times and have
some trust in the staff.

Last year, Buchanan announced a roundup of 50 people on charges of
stealing credit card numbers. In 2002 she announced a similar
roundup of 24, including a man from Duquesne who made $81,000 in
purchases using a credit card in the name of Steven D. Smith of the
Atlanta Hawks.

And in the late 1990s, federal prosecutors jailed a ring of Asian
employees skimming cards at the China Palace in Sewickley, Tai Pei
in Shadyside and Kotobuki Japanese restaurant in McCandless.

Buchanan said the San Francisco restaurant has been her favorite in
that city since her honeymoon, and the service has always been
excellent.&quot;The only way to prevent this is if you use cash or go up to the
counter and pay,&quot;she said.&quot;Like most customers, I gave my credit
card to the waitress and waited for her to return. I would never
have expected that this would happen.&quot;Buchanan said she expects agents in San Francisco will catch the
thieves. When they do, it&apos;s a safe bet the government won&apos;t have to
worry about the credibility of its chief witness.

(Torsten Ove can be reached at tove@... or 412-263-
2620.)
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #11 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 6:21 am
 Subject: Arizona House OKs weapons where alcohol is served (Arizona Daily Star 5.3.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Arizona House OKs weapons where alcohol is served

FROM The Arizona Daily Star

By Howard Fischer

PHOENIX (May 3) - The House of Representatives voted to repeal laws
that prohibit people who are armed from going into bars, restaurants
and other places where alcoholic beverages are sold.

The 32-17 preliminary vote came after Rep. Randy Graf, R-Green
Valley, a key supporter of the bill, agreed to a provision saying
those who have weapons cannot drink. He said that should satisfy
foes who say guns and alcohol do not mix.

The legislation also would permit business owners to post signs in
their establishments to say guns are not permitted. That&apos;s the same
legal premise that already exists for all other kinds of businesses.

But Graf refused to include another provision sought by bar and
restaurant owners. It would have reversed that presumption and said
weapons are allowed only if the business owner specifically hangs a
sign permitting gun-carrying patrons. Graf said that would be unfair
to people exercising Second Amendment rights.

The measure, SB 1210, appears to have more than enough votes for
final House approval. But its future remains uncertain in the
Senate. And Gov. Janet Napolitano has refused to say what she will
do if it reaches her desk.

Rep. Russell Pearce, R-Mesa, said people have a right to protect
themselves.&quot;I find the best the best safety we have out there
today in this world . . . are good citizens that are armed,&quot;he
said, including those who go through background checks and training
for permits to carry concealed weapons.

The proposal is not limited to those with state-issued permits. It
would also apply to any citizen allowed under state law to carry a
gun in the open.

House Minority Leader John Loredo, D-Phoenix, worried about the
chance of confrontations when someone working in a bar or restaurant
that has posted signs against weapons spies what appears to be a gun
in a waistband or a fanny pack.

Graf said that&apos;s no different from what occurs now as guns are
outlawed in these establishments. But Loredo said these kinds of
incidents would increase&quot;because now we&apos;re creating the presumption
that guns are allowed anyplace that serves alcohol.&quot;Graf called confrontation worries&quot;far-fetched.&quot;&quot;There are 34 other states that currently have this legislation on
the books,&quot;he said.&quot;There has not been an incident.&quot;Rep. Ted Downing, D-Tucson, said the owner of one tavern told him
that permitting guns where beer, wine and liquor are sold would
result in higher liability insurance premiums.

 2004 The Arizona Daily Star. via ProQuest Information and Learning
Co.; All Rights Reserved.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #12 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 6:38 am
 Subject: Rising food costs put higher prices on restaurants&apos; menus (Tennesean.com 5.8.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Rising food costs put higher prices on restaurants&apos; menus

By NAOMI SNYDER
Staff Writer

Soaring food costs are affecting a full menu of items, ranging from
the baker&apos;s flaky croissants that depend on the creamy flavor of
butter fat to the fried chicken pieces served by fast-food
restaurants.

Many restaurants have already increased prices to keep pace, and
more are likely to follow suit.

&apos;&apos;No one saw this coming,&apos;&apos; said Rick Hobson of Hobson Food Service
in Nashville, which specializes in selling custom cuts of chicken to
restaurants.

Market prices for chicken have risen 40% on some types of poultry. A
boneless chicken breast from the producer, for example, sells for
$2.31 a pound, up from a five-year average of $1.64, Hobson said.

And prices at grocery stores are going up as well. The Bureau of
Labor Statistics, which publishes the consumer price index, said
beef prices in March were 12.8% higher than a year earlier, and the
price of eggs reached a 10-year high, averaging $1.65 a dozen in
stores.

Hobson said he didn&apos;t remember a time when chicken prices soared
this high and stayed there so long. He expects the steep prices to
last through August.

Hobson said outbreaks of bird flu in Canada and Hong Kong forced the
killings of millions of birds and that those countries had to import
chicken from other countries to meet demand. That led to a shortage
of supply and to the higher prices.

Beef prices, while more moderate than they were after the mad cow
scare last fall, are still a problem for many restaurant owners.

Take Sylvan Park Restaurant owner Eleanor Clay, who has suffered
through a 22% increase in ground beef costs in less than three
months. She says the typical meat-and-three customer is extremely
sensitive to even small price increases.

Clay estimates she&apos;ll have to charge 25 cents more for some dishes,
and she worries how her customers will react.

&apos;&apos;We&apos;re going to have to implement an increase in the next few
months, and I hate doing that,&apos;&apos; she said. &apos;&apos;But (we) can&apos;t
survive.&apos;&apos;

Nashville meat distributor and retailer Munn&amp;Tillman said some
customers were buying less expensive cuts of meat or taking steak
off the menu to save on costs. Owner Robert Smiley said that could
mean lower profits for his company.

On another front, the higher price of dairy products is hurting
bakeries and cafes, which whip lots of butter into cakes and fancy
pastries.

Butter is a big part of Provence Breads&amp;Cafe&apos;s pastries. Its
European-style delicacies such as coconut macaroons and croissants
made with orange peel and egg use high-end dairy products to
improve texture and flavor.

Owner Terry Carr-Hall says dairy products cost roughly 50% more than
three months ago, and that his suppliers expect prices to rise even
more this summer. The price spike could last until November.

&apos;&apos;We haven&apos;t had to raise prices in six years,&apos;&apos; Carr-Hall
said. &apos;&apos;It&apos;s going to force us to raise prices.&apos;&apos; Some pastries
could go up by 20%, he said.

Many chain restaurants have already increased prices. Overall, the
National Restaurant Association projects 3% menu inflation this year.

Restaurant prices went up an average of 2.1% last year.

Chick-fil-A is raising prices about 2% at some restaurants starting
this weekend. Cracker Barrel raised prices an average of 1.7% in
January. J. Alexander&apos;s, its hand forced by higher beef prices,
announced a 3% average price hike in March and is considering
another increase, the company said.

Independent restaurant owners, though, sometimes have to increase
their prices more sharply because many don&apos;t have the long-term
contracts or negotiating prowess of the bigger chains.

Rick Bolsom is a part owner of white table-cloth restaurants Tin
Angel, Mirror, Zola&apos;s and Red Wagon.

&apos;&apos;Taxes, utilities, all things have gone up,&apos;&apos; he said. &apos;&apos;The
pressure is really significant.&apos;&apos;

&apos;&apos;We held firm last year, but we can&apos;t continue to absorb all the
price increases,&apos;&apos; Bolsom said, adding that he&apos;s still tinkering
with how much he&apos;ll have to raise the prices of certain dishes.

Price increases at chain restaurants don&apos;t seem to be scaring away
many customers.

Barry Stouffer, an analyst with BB&amp;T Capital Markets in Nashville,
said the publicly traded restaurants that he tracks hadn&apos;t seen much
consumer resistance to the moderate price increases pushed through
so far.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #13 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 6:41 am
 Subject: Man in corset denied service at restaurants (HERALD-LEADER Kentucky 5.8.04 waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Man in corset denied service at restaurants
UK INSTRUCTOR &apos;WAS BARELY COVERED&apos;

By Scott Sloan
 STAFF WRITER

A male University of Kentucky and Georgetown College instructor was
denied service at two UK-area restaurants yesterday afternoon for
wearing women&apos;s clothing.

About 2 p.m., Jeremy Kerr, 32, attempted to eat at Tolly-Ho wearing
a pleated miniskirt and a white lace-up corset.

An employee told him he would have to change or he would not be
served.&quot;I told him girls come in dressed in these clothes all the time and
don&apos;t get kicked out,&quot;Kerr said.

Owner Roy Milling, who did not witness the incident, said his
employees told him Kerr&apos;s corset revealed too much. Milling said his
restaurant does not discriminate against transvestites or cross-
dressers.&quot;You&apos;ve just got to cover yourself up,&quot;he said.&quot;He was barely
covered. We would have asked a female to do the same.&quot;After being refused service at Tolly-Ho, Kerr walked to Pazzo&apos;s
Pizza Pub and ordered a drink while sitting on the pub&apos;s front patio.

Shortly after receiving the drink, the restaurant&apos;s manager told
Kerr he would have to leave because he was distracting other
customers.&quot;There was a guy sitting out on the patio with his daughter,&quot;said
Josh Hertzenberg of Pazzo&apos;s.

Kerr said it&apos;s a strong possibility he&apos;ll file a case in small
claims court and donate any money to the Anti-Defamation League or a
similar charity.&quot;I&apos;m ultimately being discriminated against because of my sex,
because I&apos;m wearing gender-inappropriate clothes,&quot;Kerr said.

He said he has never been denied service at any other restaurants.

Kerr, who is working on his sociology Ph.D. at UK, said he has worn
similar clothing in his classes. He said he typically dresses in
that manner about two to three times each week.

He does not consider himself a transvestite or a cross-dresser.&quot;I&apos;m a 100 percent straight male,&quot;he said.&quot;I do not try to pass as
a woman. In fact, I have a beard. ... You can look at me from 50
feet or 100 feet away and tell I&apos;m a guy.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #14 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 6:48 am
 Subject: The kids studied division by learning about pooling tips (New York Times 5.8.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 May 8, 2004, 4:58PM

A lesson made to order
New York first-graders explore the restaurant business

By JULIA MOSKIN
New York Times
NEW YORK -- Weepy waiters. Dubious customers eyeing the pasta. Power
failures. And, amid the chaos, a dazed-looking guy supposedly in
charge, who looks as if he could use a stiff drink.

An episode of the NBC reality series The Restaurant?

No. It was the first-grade class at Public School 212 in Midtown
Manhattan, where the Red Eagle Cafe and the Seaside Restaurant,
staffed entirely by students, served breakfast and lunch to a highly
uncritical clientele -- their parents.

While it lasted, its workers were remarkably realistic, with a
brigade of chefs jockeying for room at the stove, busboys whisking
plates away before diners put down their forks, and even the usual
award framed on the wall, this one for Exceptional Culinary Skills
in Pancakes. Bills were settled with Monopoly money.


Rebecca Saletan&apos;s 6-year-old twin daughters were there, Anna as a
chef at the Red Eagle and Simone busing tables at the Seaside
Restaurant.&quot;It was really ingenious,&quot;Saletan said.&quot;The kids
studied division by learning about pooling tips and fractions by
measuring the ingredients for cake.&quot;The walls of both classrooms
were covered with flow charts detailing each staff member&apos;s
responsibilities, along with spelling quizzes (&quot;What&apos;s missing from
these words: sau-a-e, b-c-n, h-m?&quot;), and lists of discarded
restaurant names (the Scary Diner did not make the cut).

Although one hostess had to chase a departing guest down the hall,
waving the tip jar, and a busboy&apos;s little brother had to be removed
screaming from the premises, the restaurants did manage to make hot
food to order, deliver it quickly to the customers who ordered it,
and even refill the occasional water glass.

And, as Principal Liz Saplin observed,&quot;There&apos;s nothing better than
a restaurant where the maitre d&apos; walks you to your table holding
your hand.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #15 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 6:52 am
 Subject: The pianist&apos;s name is Issam. (CASABLANCA, Morocco FoxNews.com 5.8.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Saturday, May 08, 2004

CASABLANCA, Morocco There&apos;s a new gin joint in town, and now
everybody comes to Rick&apos;s. In homage to the movie&quot;Casablanca,&quot;a
former U.S. diplomat has opened a Rick&apos;s Cafe (search) in this
bustling port city. But you won&apos;t find Sam at the keyboard these
days, the pianist&apos;s name is Issam.

The elegant nightclub where Humphrey Bogart&apos;s (search) character
Rick pined for Ingrid Bergman&apos;s (search) Ilsa was just a set on a
Warner Bros. sound stage in California.

The new Rick&apos;s has the same warm atmosphere as the Hollywood
original. It&apos;s a white villa near the port, with palm trees flanking
the door. Inside are arched passageways and traditional hanging
lamps of colored glass.

And there&apos;s not a single photo of Bogart on the walls.&quot;Rick&apos;s Cafe is no longer just a film, it&apos;s not a museum, it&apos;s a
reality,&quot;said founder Kathy Kriger, sipping a glass of Moroccan
cabernet. Nearby, waiters in traditional fez caps and wide-legged
pants serve customers at candlelit tables.

The elegant restaurant, which debuted in March, is open for lunch
and dinner seven days a week. A typical meal costs around $30.

Pianist Issam Chabaa, who is from the capital, Rabat, plays songs
from the &apos;40s and &apos;50s. On Sunday nights, Kriger serves popcorn and
chili con carne and screens Casablanca.

Kriger, 57, says she watched the classic film hundreds of times to
study the atmosphere, lighting and lines.&quot;I&apos;m surprised my tape didn&apos;t wear out,&quot;she said.

Kriger left her job as a commercial attache at the U.S. consulate in
Casablanca when she was supposed to transfer to Tokyo in 2002. She&apos;d
become too attached to her new home.

She scouted for locations and decided to open the restaurant in
Casablanca&apos;s medina, a bustling labyrinth of narrow streets and
shops. It took months to get the various authorizations, including a
liquor license no small task in this mostly Muslim nation.

Kriger said she wanted to promote American-Moroccan dialogue in the
North African kingdom, which stretches from the Mediterranean to the
Sahara.&quot;After Sept. 11, I realized that maybe certain authentic American
values were no longer understood in the Muslim world,&quot;Kriger
said.&quot;I wanted to show how Americans can be: open, determined and
persevering.&quot;Many Moroccans have become deeply resentful of U.S. policies,
especially after the war in Iraq.

The Moroccan government, however, is one of the Muslim world&apos;s
closest U.S. allies, and Washington has routinely praised Morocco
for its democratic changes under King Mohammed VI, who took the
throne after the death of his father, King Hassan II, in 1999.

It also is battling an extremist movement at home. Last May, suicide
bombings in Casablanca killed 33 bystanders and a dozen bombers.
Most of the suspects charged in the March 11 train bombings that
killed 191 people in Madrid, Spain, were Moroccans.

Kriger, a native of Portland, Ore., says she hopes to show a
positive image of Americans by doing business in Morocco. And she
hopes that Rick&apos;s will prove Morocco is ripe for investment and open
to female entrepreneurs.&quot;Because there has never been a Rick&apos;s Cafe here, I could be
reasonably assured that it would succeed,&quot;she said.&quot;It was already
an institution, and it never even existed. It&apos;s not often you get a
chance to turn myth into reality.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #16 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 6:59 am
 Subject: The help&apos;s still hopping at 50 (ASBURY PARK PRESS, NJ - 5.8.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ASBURY PARK PRESS
THE JERSEY SHORE&apos;S
LARGEST NEWS
SOURCE

Published in the Asbury Park Press 5/08/04

The help&apos;s still hopping at 50
By DAN KAPLAN
COASTAL MONMOUTH BUREAU

WALL -- Talk to the customers or the staff at the Circus Drive-In on
Route 35, and you&apos;ll find the secret to success at this 50-year-old
seasonal landmark isn&apos;t all that complicated.

A novel atmosphere, friendly service, great food and reasonable
prices: That&apos;s all it takes. Oh, and the pretty carhops don&apos;t hurt.&quot;(I come) for the girls, the good food, and I can just sit here and
enjoy the food right in the car,&quot;said Joe Applegate, 60, who has
frequented the restaurant for the past 15 years. The Bradley Beach
man comes so often that his grandchildren got him a professional
photograph of the iconic smiling clown sign outside the 200-seat
restaurant as a Christmas present.&quot;I&apos;ve tried just about everything on the menu,&quot;he said proudly.

Circus Drive-In will celebrate its golden anniversary today, marking
50 summers as a Jersey Shore mainstay for the hungry, and in the
past couple of decades, for the nostalgic. In an era when chain
restaurants have become part of suburban life, the building designed
like a circus big-top tent, with 22 spaces for car service, is much
the same as when it opened in the summer of 1954 -- except that the
menu has grown to 124 items.

This year, ironically, the restaurant is facing its greatest change
to date.

Owners Richard and Bobbi Friedel of Wall sold the drive-in last
month to William E. Kayal, a longtime Wall resident and former owner
of a Wall private school, marking the first time the eatery has
changed hands since its inception. The price hasn&apos;t been disclosed.

The Friedels, in their 70s, cited health problems. Selling the
establishment was a difficult, yet logical, decision, they said.&quot;Nothing is forever,&quot;Richard Friedel said.

Still, the two said they already miss running one of the Shore&apos;s
most popular summer stops, known for its homemade onion rings and
for soft-shell crabs. Richard Friedel used to pilot a plane down to
Maryland to get the crabs.&quot;I&apos;m lost,&quot;Friedel said.&quot;We were one generation that stayed for 49
years. Now we&apos;re not doing anything except getting used to not doing
anything.&quot;Bobbi Friedel recently fondly recalled designing the first waitress
uniforms after Judy Garland&apos;s get-up in the film&quot;A Star is Born,&quot;in which Garland played a carhop.

She also recalled the eatery&apos;s 30th anniversary, when menu prices
were rolled back to 1954 levels. There was so much traffic that day
that seven police officers had to be hired to direct it.

New owner Kayal said that after selling the Brookside School about
three years ago, he became bored, trying to pass the time with jobs
as an executive assistant at a local car dealership and as a
supervisor of student teachers at Monmouth University.&quot;I wanted to be my own boss again,&quot;he said.

Unlike some Shore landmarks that have been sold recently, including
the Tradewinds nightclub in Sea Bright, which has been demolished --
the Circus Drive-In will remain pretty much the same under Kayal&apos;s
ownership.

Kayal, in his 50s, said the transition has been seamless because
he&apos;s followed the philosophy that if it ain&apos;t broke, don&apos;t fix it.&quot;We didn&apos;t change a thing,&quot;he said.&quot;Why change it?&quot;Margaret Peterson, 84, of Neptune and Marie Winter, 80, of Wall
certainly wouldn&apos;t want to see the place change.

They remember coming to the drive-in with their parents several
decades ago.

Nowadays, the two eat lunch together almost every day.&quot;We don&apos;t have to do dishes,&quot;Winter said.&quot;Besides, the food is
delicious.&quot;The same attachment to the restaurant can be found back in the
kitchen, where Terrence Rutledge, 40, oversees the cooking staff.

The Belmar resident said he has been working at Circus for 25 years,
starting as a window washer. He credits his longevity to the
Friedels, who took him under their wing and sent him to culinary
school.&quot;I&apos;ve just never left,&quot;he said.&quot;I&apos;ve been here so long, I know
what the customers order. You see a car pull in, and you know what
they&apos;re going to order.&quot;The cars should be rolling in today, Kayal said, when a clown and a
magician will entertain the children in honor of the 50th
anniversary.&quot;It&apos;s a very happy atmosphere here,&quot;said Katy Davidson, 22, of
Wall, one of the 20 waitresses.

Dan Kaplan: (732) 643-4024 or dkaplan@... 
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #17 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 3:43 pm
 Subject: Super Size Me! Movie examines McDonalds&amp;Obesity. (USA Today ) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Legal experts predict new rounds in food fight By Laura Parker
USA TODAY

&apos;Fat litigation&apos; could follow path of lawsuits against tobacco
A controversial obesity lawsuit against McDonald&apos;s may have been
thrown out of court. But it inspired the movie Super Size Me, which
opens today and promises to raise the volume in the debate over fast
food and obesity.

In September, a federal judge in New York rejected a claim by two
obese teenage girls that eating McDonald&apos;s made them fat. Morgan
Spurlock, the movie&apos;s director decided to test that conclusion. His
film documents a 30-day immersion into McDonald&apos;s-only cuisine in
which he gained 24 pounds and his liver accumulated fat so quickly
that it turned, in the words of his doctor, into &apos;&apos;pt.&apos;&apos; He has
since regained his health.

Spurlock wants his movie to launch a national conversation over fast
food and nutrition, not prompt more litigation. But it may be too
late. Now that obesity is recognized by the federal government as a
looming public health crisis -- on its way to surpassing smoking as
the nation&apos;s No. 1 killer -- the battle lines are drawn.

A number of fronts

Although no fast food lawsuits have been filed since the McDonald&apos;s
case was dismissed, legal experts say they expect suits to be filed
this year. The most promising legal avenue is to invoke state
consumer protection laws to accuse companies of misleading consumers
about calories or nutritional value, or to accuse companies of
marketing fast food to children.

&apos;&apos;There are obviously a number of fronts,&apos;&apos; says Richard Daynard, a
law professor at Northeastern University in Boston.

Joseph Price, a Minneapolis defense lawyer, warns food companies not
to ignore the threat. He has represented the manufacturers of
silicone breast implants and sponsored a conference this year in
Washington to assist defense lawyers and food manufacturers in
avoiding and defending &apos;&apos;fat litigation.&apos;&apos;

&apos;&apos;There are things a company can do to protect itself,&apos;&apos; he
says. &apos;&apos;You ought to be looking at labeling to see if there are
potentially misleading references.&apos;&apos;

Many of the agitators in the coming legal food fight are lawyers who
successfully sued tobacco companies. They say they expect fat
litigation to follow the same course as tobacco litigation. They say
predictions that obesity lawsuits will fail because people are
responsible for the food they eat are premature. Lawyers lost
tobacco cases for decades before they began winning in the 1990s.

&apos;&apos;Personal responsibility was the mantra of tobacco litigation. It&apos;s
the smokers&apos; fault,&apos;&apos; Daynard says. &apos;&apos;It was a successful argument
for a long time. Sure people should take care of themselves. One,
they need accurate information to do it, and two, Madison Avenue
knows how to manipulate people so they are less able to protect
their own interests.&apos;&apos;

Defense lawyers point to key differences. For starters, it may be
hard to convince juries Big Macs are as addictive as nicotine. &apos;&apos;Is
it the food industry&apos;s fault that Americans will happily choose a
larger size?&apos;&apos; asks Alice Johnson, a defense lawyer in Pittsburgh,
who spoke at the Washington conference. &apos;&apos;It is an open issue about
what constitutes good nutrition. Can you eat carbs or not? Is it
better to have meat or not? There is absolutely no unanimity.&apos;&apos;

There have been eight &apos;&apos;fat&apos;&apos; lawsuits. Five of them were at least
partially successful. McDonald&apos;s paid $12 million to settle a suit
that charged it had failed to disclose that its french fries were
cooked in beef fat. The makers of Big Daddy&apos;s Ice Cream and Pirate&apos;s
Booty, a puffed snack food, paid a combined $8 million for not
disclosing the proper calorie count in those products. Kraft changed
its recipe for Oreo cookies to remove trans-fatty acids. A suit
against the New York school board served as a catalyst for the
board&apos;s decision to ban the sale of soft drinks from schools.

Ironically, the rejected McDonald&apos;s obesity suit leaves the door
open for future litigation. In dismissing the suit, U.S. District
Court Judge Robert Sweet outlined how the complaint could be amended
to include allegations that McDonald&apos;s preparation of its food made
it more dangerous than consumers could expect. The amended suit did
not meet that test, and Sweet dismissed it a second time.

&apos;&apos;People who don&apos;t like these suits have called it (the decision) a
road map for future success,&apos;&apos; says John Banzhaf, a law professor at
George Washington University in Washington, who pioneered the
tobacco litigation.

The McDonald&apos;s suit prompted lawmakers to act. Nineteen states have
passed legislation that would ban obesity lawsuits. Similar
legislation in Congress, the so-called cheeseburger bill, passed the
House of Representatives in March and is before the Senate.

More modest goals

Lawyers on both sides say the goals of the &apos;&apos;fat litigation&apos;&apos; are
less sweeping and easier to obtain than those of tobacco litigation.
Cigarettes can&apos;t be turned into healthy products. But food companies
can reduce portions, alter recipes, disclose nutritional data and
change marketing promotions.

McDonald&apos;s has announced it intends to end super-size servings and
plans to add nutritional information to its paper tray liners at
restaurants. The fast food giant also is promoting a new &apos;&apos;GoActive!
Happy Meal&apos;&apos; with a pedometer and bottled water. Other restaurants
are making similar changes.

A McDonald&apos;s spokesman could not be reached for an interview. But a
statement on McDonald&apos;s Web site disputes the message of Spurlock&apos;s
film: &apos;&apos;The movie is all about one individual&apos;s decision to act
irresponsibly by consuming more than 5,000 calories a day -- twice
the recommended level for adult males -- and by purposely limiting
his physical activity.&apos;&apos;

Spurlock decided to make his film after watching news coverage of
the McDonald&apos;s lawsuit.

&apos;&apos;It was crazy,&apos;&apos; he says. &apos;&apos;Sue a food company for selling us the
food that we eat. But the more I started reading about the
marketing, manufacturing, and nutritional content of food, I
thought, there&apos;s a basis for an argument here.&apos;&apos;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #18 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 3:50 pm
 Subject: Wild Salmon Prices Boosted by Campaigns (AP Charleston, OR 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Wild Salmon Prices Boosted by Campaigns
By JEFF BARNARD
The Associated Press
Wednesday, May 5, 2004; 7:17 AM

CHARLESTON, Ore. - Sitting on his boat, the Dragnet, Loren Dixson
had to think back to when his daughter was a baby to remember a time
when prices for his salmon were this good.&quot;Hannah is 17 now,&quot;Dixon said,&quot;and it was the year she was born.&quot;Since those high prices in the late 1980s, West Coast salmon
fishermen have struggled. A strong El Nino in 1994 depleted food in
the ocean, drastically reducing salmon landings. Salmon farms in
Chile, Norway and Canada filled the gap, driving down prices as they
cranked up production.

But over the past two years, campaigns promoting the+health+, taste
and environmental benefits of ocean-caught salmon have converged
with efforts by fishermen to produce a better fish through careful
handling. Along with scientific studies on fish contamination and
new laws, ocean-caught salmon prices have been pushed back up.&quot;It&apos;s the perfect storm, pardon the pun,&quot;said Dalton Hobbs,
administrator of the Oregon Department of Agriculture&apos;s marketing
division, which last month launched its Seafood Oregon advertising
campaign.

Accounting for inflation, the $5.50 a pound Oregon fish buyers were
paying last week for large chinook, the West Coast&apos;s premier
commercial species, would have been the equivalent of $3.33 in 1987.
That&apos;s the year Dixson got $4.50 for one boatload in San Francisco.&quot;It means I actually expect to do reasonably well this year,&quot;said
fisherman Scott Boley, who has a fish market in Gold Beach where he
was retailing chinook filets for $9.60 a pound.

Prices this week dropped to about $3.50 a pound as the California
and Washington fleets hit the water and weather improved, but
observers expect them to stay strong all summer.

Fish marketing consultant Howard Johnson of H.M. Johnson&amp;Associates has tracked a slight increase in farmed salmon prices but
noted wild prices are up much more. He added the buzz was all wild
salmon at this year&apos;s International Boston Seafood Show, where Legal
Sea Foods, a Boston-based chain of 26 restaurants, announced a new
line of wild Alaskan salmon dishes.

Last January, the journal Science published a major study that found
increased levels of cancer-causing PCBs in farmed fish over wild
fish.

And in 2002, a court ruling required grocery stores to label farmed
fish as containing dye to turn the flesh pink. Next fall, federal
law requires stores to label fish with the country they come from.&quot;What we have now is an informed public that wants our product,&quot;said Daryl Bogardus, skipper of the Pices, tied up across the dock
from Dixson&apos;s Dragonet.&quot;Instead of taking a back seat to farmed
fish, we&apos;re getting the price we should.&quot;Two years ago, chinook dipped below $1 a pound due to the glut of
farmed salmon, which account for 60 percent of the world supply.

Laura Anderson, vice president of Local Ocean Seafoods in Newport,
has worked with fishermen the past two seasons to handle their fish
more carefully to command a higher price. She labels each fish with
a photo of the fisherman who caught it.&quot;I can move as many as I can get,&quot;said Anderson.&quot;Plus, there&apos;s a
lot of competition in the market now. More buyers are coming to
Oregon ports to source fish directly.&quot;Last year, EcoTrust, a Portland group that promotes environmentally
sustainable economic development, launched its Salmon Nation
campaign, calling on seafood lovers to buy ocean-caught fish to
protect the environment and promote local economies.

Surveys in Oregon have tracked a steep rise in consumer preference
for wild fish, said Eileen Brady, EcoTrust&apos;s vice president.

In 2002, when asked what salmon they would choose at the grocery or
a restaurant, 29 percent said wild salmon, 26 percent farmed salmon,
and 35 percent had no preference, according to the survey done by
Riley Research Associates of Portland. This year, 58 percent
preferred wild salmon, and 10 percent farmed.

At Higgins restaurant in Portland, chef Greg Higgins will serve only
ocean-caught fish. The price of an entree has risen to $29 a plate.&quot;People are paying it,&quot;said co-owner Paul Mallory.&quot;They don&apos;t
think twice.&quot;On the Net:
EcoTrust: www.ecotrust.com
H.M. Johnson&amp;Associates: www.hmj.com
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #19 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Sun May 9, 2004 3:54 pm
 Subject: Senate blocks new overtime pay rules. (WAshington Post 5.5.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 By Helen Dewar
Washington Post Staff Writer
Wednesday, May 5, 2004; Page A04

The Republican-controlled Senate voted yesterday to block new Labor
Department rules that critics said would deny overtime pay to
millions of white-collar workers, handing an embarrassing rebuff to
the Bush administration on a politically sensitive jobs issue.

The Senate voted 52 to 47 to scrap the new rules despite recent
changes to address earlier criticism, an intense lobbying campaign
by Labor Secretary Elaine L. Chao and a last-ditch GOP effort to
avert defeat by proposing a long list of jobs for which overtime pay
could not be eliminated.

Although the GOP&apos;s concessions were approved unanimously, they did
not satisfy five moderate Republicans who broke ranks to vote with
nearly all Democrats in favor of keeping the administration from
cutting anyone&apos;s overtime pay.&quot;This was a great victory for American workers and families&quot;and
sent a&quot;clear message to the administration&quot;to drop its efforts to
rewrite the nation&apos;s overtime pay rules, said Sen. Tom Harkin (D-
Iowa), who led the fight against the new regulations.

The issue has enormous resonance in an election year for workers in
a vast array of jobs, including nurses, oil rig workers, insurance
claim adjusters and restaurant managers. According to Democrats,
they could lose overtime pay under the new administration rules.

But the fate of Harkin&apos;s proposal was unclear. It was approved as an
amendment to a corporate tax bill that faces continuing obstacles in
the Senate. The House voted in favor of blocking the new regulations
last year but has not acted on the subject this year. Harkin said he
believed opposition to changing overtime rules has increased since
the last House vote and expressed optimism that the House will
approve his proposal.

The dispute over overtime pay began last year when the Labor
Department proposed the first comprehensive updating of the rules in
50 years, including broadening coverage for low-paid workers but
cutting back on eligibility for those who are better paid -- as many
as 8 million, according to Democrats.

In response, the Senate voted to block the plan and the House voted
to go along, although Republican negotiators later bowed to veto
threats from the White House and agreed to accept the Labor
Department plan. Democrats angrily vowed to continue fighting it.

Under pressure from critics, the department rewrote its proposal
last month, substantially reducing the number of workers who might
lose their overtime pay under a final rule that is due to take
effect in late August.

Workers could still qualify for overtime if they make as much as
$100,000 a year, instead of $65,000, as initially proposed. Police,
firefighters and other first responders were also protected, the
department said. Eligibility for low-income workers was also
expanded.

With these and other changes, the department said&quot;few if any&quot;workers making less than $100,000 would lose their eligibility for
overtime pay and only about 100,000 workers making more than
$100,000 would become ineligible.

But Democrats countered that the department&apos;s assessment was faulty
and that as many as 4 million workers might lose overtime pay under
the department&apos;s new proposal, in part because of language used to
define how work is classified.

The Democrats&apos; proposal would, in effect, leave overtime rules as
they are, although it would allow the provisions expanding
eligibility for low-income workers to take effect.&quot;We have progressed -- if that is the right term -- from a proposal
[by the administration] that was profoundly terrible to a final rule
that is just plain terrible,&quot;Harkin contended during the two-day
debate.

Republicans disagreed, describing the department&apos;s proposal as fair
and necessary to keep overtime rules in line with the nation&apos;s
changing job structure. But, sensing defeat, they offered an
amendment specifying that workers in 55 job categories -- from
refinery workers to nurse midwives -- would still qualify for
overtime. It was approved 99 to 0.

But, on the final vote, Republicans Ben Nighthorse Campbell (Colo.),
Lincoln D. Chafee (R.I.), Lisa Murkowski (Alaska), Olympia J. Snowe
(Maine) and Arlen Specter (Pa.) joined all Democrats present except
Zell Miller (Ga.) in voting to protect overtime pay.

 2004 The Washington Post Company
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #20 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Wed May 12, 2004 6:03 am
 Subject: Food Small Percentage Of Your Restaurant Bill (San Jose, CA - NBC11.com 5.11.01) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Food Small Percentage Of Your Restaurant Bill
Restaurant Staff&apos;s Salaries Make Up One-Third Of Check

SAN JOSE, Calif. -- According to the Zagat Restaurant Survey, if you
dine out in the Bay Area, you can expect to pay, on average, $34.07
for a meal.

So what do you get for your money besides whatever shows up at the
table?

You&apos;re also paying for things you may have never thought of, yet
they&apos;re just as important as what you put in your mouth, NBC11&apos;s
Ethan Harp reported.

The management, the waiters and cooks at The Grill in San Jose can
make up one-third of your bill, while the food makes up one-fourth,
Harp said.

But the other ingredients that can make up your bill are office
supplies, laundry and linen, janitorial supplies, paper supplies,
glasses, plates and silverware.&quot;It can go from $3,000 to $4,000, depending sometimes on how busy
the restaurant is a month -- talking about napkins, silverware,
depending on how much money you spend on silverware,&quot;said Philippe
Azoulay, the general manager of The Grill.

There&apos;s also the cost that goes towards the dcor, like candles and
other utilities.&quot;Obviously our utility costs have been through the roof these last
few years. Workers comp costs have been much higher, almost doubled
in the last year, all the insurance costs in general,&quot;said Aaron
Noveshen of the Pacific Catch.

A good restaurant is lucky to make 10 percent more than it spends,
Harp reported.&quot;All of this adds up and I don&apos;t think people think about it. It
doesn&apos;t come to their mind,&quot;Azoulay said.

Restaurant owners aren&apos;t complaining. They&apos;re not only happy to get
your business, but some believe they&apos;ll have to work even harder to
ensure good service in the years ahead.&quot;Service is what now people are demanding a little more (of),&quot;Azoulay said.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #21 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Wed May 12, 2004 6:07 am
 Subject: Woman Find Mouse in Her Soup (Newport News, VA 5.10.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Woman Find Mouse in Her Soup at Newport News, Va., Cracker Barrel
Restaurant By Peter Dujardin, Daily Press, Newport News, Va.
Knight Ridder/Tribune Business News

May 10--A woman enjoying an early Mother&apos;s Day lunch at a Newport
News restaurant Saturday discovered a mouse in a bowl of vegetable
soup.

The woman, Carla Patterson of Hampton, was eating with her two sons
and her godson at the Cracker Barrel Old Country Store restaurant,
on Jefferson Avenue across from the Patrick Henry Mall, when she
scooped up a small, black mouse, about an inch and a half long, with
her soup spoon.

Patterson, who already had eaten several scoops of the red tomato
vegetable soup before she came across the mouse, let out a scream.&quot;It was just shocking,&quot;said Patterson, who went outside while
several waiters and waitresses tried to calm her down.&quot;Anybody
would be shocked by it.&quot;Several other patrons got up and left the restaurant in the middle
of their meals. One patron who was in the restaurant at the time
said about 20 other diners got up and left, while Cracker Barrel
spokeswoman Julie Davis, at the company&apos;s headquarters in Lebanon,
Tenn., said six customers left.

Cracker Barrel has ordered all 497 restaurants in the country to
stop serving the vegetable soup while the matter is investigated.&quot;Obviously, the health and safety of our guests is our primary
concern,&quot;Davis said.&quot;We immediately stopped serving the soup, and
isolated the product. We&apos;re investigating every possible cause for
how this happened.&quot;She said it&apos;s safe to eat at the restaurant, and a Peninsula Health
District inspector visited the restaurant Monday and found no
evidence of rodent infestation.

An employee from a Virginia restaurant, Davis said, drove the mouse
to Tennessee over the weekend, where the rodent will be tested.
Laboratory analysis, she said, will determine whether the mouse got
into the soup in Newport News or came packaged with soup provided
from the vendor.

The vegetable soup, which contains potatoes, tomatoes and other
vegetables, is one of the few final products Cracker Barrel buys
from an outside company rather than making it in-house, Davis said.
The soup is delivered to the restaurant in bags, but she declined to
identify the name of the vendor pending the outcome of the
investigation.

Patterson said she had planned to order the pot pie for her Mother&apos;s
Day lunch, but when she discovered the restaurant wasn&apos;t serving it,
she ordered the soup. She said the soup tasted fine, until she made
the discovery.&quot;I have to admit, it was good,&quot;said Patterson, who plans to hire a
lawyer. She has not yet thought about whether she would file a suit
against Cracker Barrel.

But she got sick when she went home, and checked into Hampton
Sentara hospital. She felt sick again Monday, and checked back into
the hospital again. The doctors told her she is probably OK, and
that her nerves from the incident could cause her to be feeling
sick.

Dr. Bill Berg, of the Hampton Health District, said mice carry
several viruses and bacteria, both in their bodies and in their
droppings and urine, that are not healthy for humans. That includes
a respiratory virus that can cause pneumonia.

But as long as the mouse is well cooked, he said, it would be safe
to eat. If the mouse were boiled at 212 degrees Fahrenheit, it would
need to be cooked for about a minute to eliminate contamination. At
160 degrees, he said, the viruses and bacteria would be killed off
after five minutes.

But even if the threat of virus and bacteria were completely
eliminated, he said, the body still might feel sick, but if the
mouse is cooked adequately, it will be a short-term sick feeling.&quot;That&apos;s not to say it&apos;s a pleasant experience,&quot;to eat a mouse, he
said.&quot;If it&apos;s well cooked, it&apos;s probably safe. But the asthetics
are a different matter.&quot;The Newport News restaurant last got a pest control service April
13, from a local company, and no signs of rodents were discovered at
that time. She said that for good measure, the company&apos;s employees
gave the restaurant a good cleaning on Saturday afternoon.

Cracker Barrel&apos;s president, Donald M. Turner, has been heavily
involved in the monitoring the situation, Davis said, and managers
have kept in touch with Patterson to check on her well being over
the weekend.

Patterson, who is vice president of athletics, for Denbigh Youth
Football and Cheerleading Association with the city&apos;s Parks and
Recreation department, said she had no complaints about how she was
treated.&quot;They were nice to me,&quot;she said.&quot;I do want to know how and where
it came from, but I don&apos;t want to make it look like some big thing.
I&apos;m angry about what happened, but I&apos;m not mad at management.&quot;-----To see more of the Daily Press, or to subscribe to the
newspaper, go to http://www.dailypress.com (c) 2004, Daily Press, Newport News, Va. Distributed by Knight
Ridder/Tribune Business News. CBRL,
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #22 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Wed May 12, 2004 6:20 am
 Subject: Who Really Cooks Your Food? (New York Times 5.12.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Who Really Cooks Your Food?
By JULIA MOSKIN
The New York Times May 12, 2004

HERE&apos;S how it was supposed to work: Thomas Keller, star chef of the
Napa Valley, temporarily shutters his renowned restaurant, the
French Laundry, and opens a feverishly anticipated restaurant in New
York. Per Se opens in the Time Warner Center in a burst of glory,
with Mr. Keller in the kitchen. Once the New York team is up to
speed, the chef de cuisine, Jonathan Benno, takes the reins at Per
Se, freeing Mr. Keller to fly back to California and reopen the
French Laundry with its chef de cuisine, Eric Ziebold. Finally, with
two acclaimed restaurants thousands of miles apart, Mr. Keller joins
the international corps of red-eyed chefs who shuttle between
multiple kitchens, with well-honed chefs de cuisine holding down the
fort at each end.

Instead, shortly after its Feb. 16 opening, Per Se was closed by a
fire in the kitchen. Mr. Ziebold gave notice. From New York, Mr.
Keller is managing the (delayed) reopening of the French Laundry; he
has not yet named a chef de cuisine there. And Per Se quietly
reopened on May 1, with Mr. Benno in charge at the stove on six
days&apos; experience, facing a now-ravenous New York audience.&quot;Obviously, I am incredibly anxious,&quot;Mr. Keller said.&quot;I&apos;ve spent
years trying to make sure this wouldn&apos;t happen. One faulty electric
cable, and that was that.&quot;Whatever happens next in Mr. Keller&apos;s drama will depend on the
talents and abilities of two behind-the-scenes players: his chefs de
cuisine. Alert restaurant customers already know that when a second
in command is announced on a restaurant menu under the title of chef
de cuisine or executive sous-chef, it signifies that the chef whose
name is on the marquee might be a few blocks, or a few time zones,
away.

Chefs de cuisine have always been the workhorses who make every
restaurant empire run, but they have never been more necessary, or
more visible.

American chefs can now command the kind of global respect once
reserved for the French, and many are succumbing to the siren song
of expansion. Even the purists are starting to cave: in addition to
Thomas Keller, the legendary sticklers David Bouley and Charlie
Trotter have put their names on restaurants thousands of miles from
their home kitchens. Last year, Daniel Boulud opened a Caf Boulud
in Palm Beach; Jean-Georges Vongerichten&apos;s new place in Shanghai is
his 15th restaurant.

Meanwhile, who&apos;s minding the stoves?&quot;People always ask, `Who does the cooking when you&apos;re not here?&apos;&quot;Mr. Vongerichten said last week at his flagship restaurant, Jean
Georges, at Columbus Circle.&quot;It&apos;s the same person who does it when
I am here: the chef de cuisine.&quot;As Tony Soprano needs captains, unquestionably loyal henchmen who
know exactly what the boss would do in any situation, chefs need
chefs de cuisine to run their kitchens, from hiring and firing to
choosing between chives and chervil as the garnish for a new dish.
And some do a great deal more than that.&quot;Have I served dishes at the French Laundry that the chef has never
tasted?&quot;said Eric Ziebold, who resigned last month after five years
at his post and will become chef at the Mandarin Oriental in
Washington.&quot;Sure.&quot;At ambitious restaurants like the French Laundry, where the menu
changes by 30 percent each day, chefs de cuisine must become more
than deputies, devising new dishes in the style of their
mentors.&quot;It&apos;s a position of extraordinary trust,&quot;said Zach Bell,
chef de cuisine at Caf Boulud in Palm Beach, where an entree,
whether it is a Boulud classic or a Bell creation, costs about $35.

Many American chefs, like Mario Batali, Tom Colicchio and Suzanne
Goin, have built strings of restaurants in their home cities, and
manage to personally oversee them all. Entrepreneurs like Wolfgang
Puck and Todd English have gone another route, opening chains of low-
rent spinoffs that demand little attention from the chef.

But running serious kitchens via long distance requires a deep
bench. A chef with an expansion plan needs a corps of chefs de
cuisine who are handpicked for loyalty, modesty and stability 
qualities that are often in short supply among talented young
cooks.&quot;Any sous-chef in my kitchen is a good enough cook to become
chef de cuisine,&quot;Daniel Boulud said.&quot;But only the ones who can
keep a cool head, teach my cuisine and philosophy, and understand my
business will get the job.&quot;Chefs with multiple restaurants frequently talk about the philosophy
that permeates their kitchens, as a way of describing how someone
else can cook their food without following their recipes. (Alain
Ducasse, a pioneer in empire building, famously answered this
quandary with a sweeping,&quot;I am in all of my kitchens all of the
time.&quot;)

Some chefs, like Mr. Vongerichten, have a chef de cuisine in every
kitchen (or two, in his case; Tony DiSalvo and Gregory Brainin share
the title at the Columbus Circle restaurant). Others, like Mr.
Boulud, always keep one kitchen under their personal
command.&quot;Restaurant Daniel is my home,&quot;he said.&quot;A chef needs a
kitchen where he can stay connected with the food.&quot;Mr. Boulud&apos;s chefs de cuisine have often managed to become highly
visible chefs in their own right without leaving the Boulud nest.
Andrew Carmellini of Caf Boulud in New York and Jean Franois Bruel
of DB Bistro Moderne have both won James Beard awards for their
work a rare acknowledgment for a chef de cuisine but have
remained within the well-funded Boulud organization.

But more often, chefs de cuisine quickly leave to feather their own
nests. Many of New York&apos;s top young chefs are recent alumni of the
kitchens of Mr. Vongerichten, David Bouley, Alfred Portale and a
handful of other influential chefs.&quot;The patience of young chefs has
been greatly reduced,&quot;Mr. Bouley said.&quot;That French tradition of
apprenticeship is almost gone, and now the young Americans think
they don&apos;t have to learn to butcher their own meat, or make their
own pastry.&quot;&quot;Of course we all want our own place, with our name on the door,&quot;said Guillermo Tellez, who is chef de cuisine in Charlie Trotter&apos;s
kitchen at Restaurant C in Los Cabos, Mexico, and held the same post
at the Chicago mother ship for more than 10 years.&quot;But I&apos;m not in a
rush. I&apos;ve seen that blow up too many times.&quot;Mr. Tellez, like many of his colleagues, is charged with recreating
a chef&apos;s elaborate cuisine and high standards under more challenging
conditions. The part of the Baja peninsula in which C is located, he
said, is a government-designated pure zone, which means that almost
no produce can be imported from the United States or the Mexican
mainland. Only frozen meat is allowed, he said, and since the
opening rush in February, he has had little time to establish the
network of local purveyors and farmers so beloved of Mr. Trotter and
other top American chefs.&quot;I got a farmer to raise quails, so that I could have the eggs, and
we&apos;re trying to rig up a cool house for growing vegetables in the
hot season,&quot;he said.&quot;But a lot of things are just not available
here.&quot;Eric Johnson, chef de cuisine of Jean Georges in Shanghai, also
opened Mr. Vongerichten&apos;s Paris restaurant, Market.&quot;Well, it&apos;s
different,&quot;he said of sourcing Western ingredients in China,&quot;but
FedEx makes everything possible.&quot;Other than bamboo hearts instead
of artichoke hearts on the famous orange-dusted prawns, and a few
other cosmetic changes, Mr. Johnson&apos;s menu is an uncanny recreation
of dinner at Jean Georges in New York, right down to the scallops
with caper-raisin emulsion and caramelized cauliflower.&quot;That&apos;s what our customers want,&quot;Mr. Johnson said.&quot;The greatest
hits, the same dishes they had in New York.&quot;&quot;The Shanghai-style stuff Jean-Georges did at 66,&quot;he said,
referring to Mr. Vongerichten&apos;s Chinese restaurant in TriBeCa,&quot;I
could never do that here.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #23 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Wed May 12, 2004 6:58 am
 Subject: Bars grapple with social repercussions of drinking (Denver, CO 5.7.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 May 7, 2004 print edition of the The Denver Business Journal http://www.bizjournals.com/industries/retailing_restaurants/restauran ts/2004/05/10/denver_newscolumn1.html?page=1

Bars grapple with social repercussions of drinking
By Paula Moore

Denver-area restaurants and bars find themselves in the middle of a
trend that&apos;s good for business, but has harmful social
repercussions.

In this area, and the rest of the country, young people often skip
one-on-one dates for drinking-oriented group socializing, and that
behavior has caused local restaurants to beef up their bars and new
bars to pop up here. The new dating craze benefits those businesses&apos;
bottom lines, since alcoholic beverage sales are more profitable
than food sales, according to local restaurant industry insiders.

In group dating, several men and women, usually in their 20s and
including college students, spend an evening or two bar-hopping and
binge drinking. Binge drinking often leads to casual sex --
or&quot;hooking up&quot;-- and sometimes to rape, which troubles social
scientists. Young people are looking for love but settling for
emotionally damaging sex without intimacy, according to groups such
as the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA).

The physical consequences of excessive drinking range from simple
intoxication to injuries from drunk driving to death.

The NIAAA defines binge drinking as having five drinks or more in a
row for men and four drinks or more for women.&quot;It&apos;s the Generation Xers who are into pack dating -- drinking and
barely eating when they go out,&quot;said Kelly Greene, a veteran Denver-
area retail broker specializing in restaurants and a vice president
at Trammell Crow Co.&quot;They might eat at home before they go out, or
go someplace cheap like Noodles&amp;Company to save money. ... Food is
not that important, but drinking is a giant part of a night out.&quot;Greene, whose family owned the old Lafyette&apos;s seafood restaurant
where the Tamayo Mexican restaurant now is in Larimer Square, has
followed the local restaurant scene for several years as a retail
leasing and sales broker.
Lower Downtown Denver -- LoDo for short -- typically attracts the
young crowds, and restaurants and bars there accommodate their
propensity to drink.

Relatively new places such as the Samba Room in Larimer Square
have&quot;major&quot;bars, according to Greene. Tamayo just added a rooftop
lounge with&quot;special tequila cocktails.&quot;Tamayo creator Richard Sandoval&apos;s new concept, Zengo in Riverfront
Park, offers Latin-Asian cuisine plus a 20-seat bar and 30-seat
lounge. Its&quot;beverage program&quot;includes 75 wines, 75 sakes and 60
tequilas as well as Asian and Latin beers.

Last fall, the Rio Grande Tex-Mex restaurant on Blake Street turned
its top floor into the 2,700-square-foot Rio Cantina bar, while
maintaining its downstairs bar. At the time, the Rio Grande chain&apos;s
marketing director, Christine Sullo, said the cantina was added
because&quot;the downtown Denver bar has been very popular and gets
quite crowded.&quot;Adega Restaurant + Wine Bar on Wynkoop Street across from Union
Station boasts one of the largest wine lists in the region. The Tom
Tom Room sushi restaurant at Market and 14th streets offers more
than 35 varieties of sake and promises&quot;our theme of communal
indulgence is carried into the bar and lounge.&quot;LoDo bars ranging from The Soiled Dove on Market and Larimer
Square&apos;s Mynt True Lounge to Bash on Blake Street have gotten
company in the form of Lotus in Union Station on Wynkoop, Rise
Nightclub on Blake and Hush Lounge in Larimer Square. Also in
Larimer Square, Martini Ranch is scheduled to open this spring in
the old Soapy Smith&apos;s Eagle Bar space.

Hush, calling itself an&quot;atmospheric parlor,&quot;plays on the sexual
nature of group dating by having a unisex bathroom. Tom Tom Room
clientele use separate bathrooms, but share a common sink area.

Restaurants outside the inner city also have pumped up their bars,
and bars have enhanced themselves.

In the Golden Triangle area, the new Minturn Saloon on Broadway
offers a rooftop patio -- and a Mountain Margarita billed to be 43
percent alcohol. The newly opened Moda Ristorante&amp;Lounge Italian
restaurant in the Beauvallon condominium property on Lincoln Street
boasts 150 wines.

A new Mexican-food place, Mezcal on East Colfax Avenue across from
the Bluebird Theater, advertises&quot;lively ambiance, affordable prices
and an extensive list of tequilas and mezcals.&quot;Opened in December,
Mezcal&apos;s liquor roster includes more than 100 tequilas and mezcals,
and the average margarita runs $5.75.

It&apos;s not known how much the group-dating phenomenon contributes to
Colorado restaurant and bar sales. But those sales should grow 6
percent this year to $6.26 billion, according to the Colorado
Restaurant Association. Average U.S. sales for eating places in 2004
are expected to grow only 4.4 percent.

Because of drinking&apos;s overall popularity, the association counsels
its 4,000 members to serve alcohol responsibly and not to serve
minors. One of the group&apos;s mottos is&quot;We serve food and drinks, not
drunks.&quot;&quot;We encourage training for responsible alcohol service; we have
classes once a month,&quot;said Cindy Weindling, the CRA&apos;s executive
vice president.&quot;Training is especially important if you have big
groups of people that can be harder to police.&quot;Restaurants and bars need to be on their toes not only for ethical
reasons, but legal ones. There are more -- and stiffer -- state and
local laws designed to rein in excessive drinking, and businesses
that don&apos;t comply can lose their liquor licenses, according to
Weindling.&quot;You have to be vigilant.&quot;Paula Moore covers retail issues. Reach her at 303-837-3528 or via e-
mail at pmoore@... .
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #24 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 5:16 pm
 Subject: EEOC files suits against two restaurant chains (NRN 5.24.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 EEOC files suits against two restaurant chains

ST. LOUIS (May 24) - The U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity
Commission&apos;s district office here reportedly filed lawsuits against
Steak N Shake, for alleged job discrimination, and Bob Evans Farms,
for alleged sexual harassment of female employees.

Representatives of Columbus, Ohio-based Bob Evans Farms and Steak N
Shake, based in Indianapolis, could not be reached for comment.

The lawsuits stem from incidents at St. Louis area branches of the
restaurant companies. Steak N Shake is accused of refusing to hire a
deaf job applicant, Kerry Gillian, because of his disability. He
reportedly interviewed in 2001 to work as a dishwasher or cook at a
Steak N Shake in Fenton, Mo. Gillian allegedly was told by a manager
that he would not be able to hear a bell signaling when to add soap
to the dishwasher.

Bob Evans Farms reportedly faces the EEOC&apos;s accusations that a Bob
Evans restaurant manager in Bridgeton, Mo., directed vulgar sexual
comments and conduct toward female employees. A spokeswoman for Bob
Evans Farms said the company does not tolerate sexual harassment and
that all of its managers are trained on sexual-harassment prevention.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #25 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 5:20 pm
 Subject: Calif., Mass. on opposite sides of tip-pooling (NRN 5.24.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Calif., Mass. on opposite sides of tip-pooling fence

By Alan J. Liddle

SACRAMENTO, Calif. (May 24) - Even as the California Restaurant
Association alters its strategy for winning legislative authority to
mandate the sharing of pooled tips with dishwashers and cooks, the
Massachusetts Restaurant Association is moving in the opposite
direction.
The MRA is backing Massachusetts House bill 4431, which would permit
restaurateurs to mandate tip pooling as would a pending CRA-backed
bill in California but would forbid back-of-the-house workers from
receiving any of the gratuities. Advocates of tip pooling in
Massachusetts cite the similarly restrictive stance of the U.S.
Department of Labor.

However, the movement of H4431 through the Massachusetts Legislature
coincided with the release of a formal opinion by California&apos;s
nonpartisan Office of Legislative Counsel that the proposed sharing
of pooled tips with kitchen workers does not appear to violate the
Federal Fair Labor Standards Act, or FLSA.

Federal labor officials base their opposition to forced tip sharing
with nontipped workers on an interpretation of the FLSA.

The diametrically opposing natures of the California and
Massachusetts tip-pooling bills appear to reflect the divergent tip-
credit policies of those states, both of which have minimum hourly
wages of $6.75.

In Massachusetts operators can count servers&apos; gratuities to offset
up to $4.12 of their hourly minimum rate. But in California
operators are prohibited from any such tip credit, leaving many to
complain that paying the full $6.75 an hour to well-tipped service
workers unfairly leaves fewer payroll funds to allocate for kitchen
employees. California&apos;s pending tip-pooling measure Senate Bill
1511 by Dede Alpert, D-San Diego would help rectify that inequity,
restaurant industry leaders contend.&quot;With no tip credit in California and finite labor dollars, this is
a creative way for operators to incentivize everyone on their team,&quot;CRA senior legislative director John Kabateck said. SB1511 is aimed
at codifying restaurateurs&apos; rights to create mandatory tip pools for
sharing with kitchen staff and servers.

MRA chief executive Peter Christie sees things differently.&quot;Management can&apos;t be using tips intended for service personnel to
augment the compensation of people who are not part of that
service,&quot;Christie said. Thirty years ago orders from restaurant
owners that wait staff had to&quot;tip out&quot;cooks and dishwashers might
have been&quot;common,&quot;he added, but times have changed.

Christie said H4431, drafted in cooperation with the MRA and the
Massachusetts attorney general&apos;s office, would prohibit owners from
diverting away from service staff any monies collected as&quot;service
fees&quot;or&quot;gratuities.&quot;However, the bill would permit employers to
add&quot;administrative&quot;or&quot;house&quot;fees of any size and for any purpose
to guest checks and private-party invoices as long it was made
clear to customers that the charge was not earmarked for servers.

H4431 also would require Massachusetts restaurants to pay out tips
collected from credit cards by the end of the corresponding payroll
period. Servers increasingly have complained that tips are being
held for extended periods, with blame sometimes placed on
purportedly slow accounting systems.

Christie said the MRA helped draft H4431 because of a disagreement
between the association and the state attorney general&apos;s office.

The MRA, which believes state law permits owners to mandate tip
pooling benefiting servers, has won some court cases supporting that
position, Christie said. But he noted that the attorney general&apos;s
office has contended in the past that tip pools must be voluntary in
nature.

California Restaurant Association officials contend that laws in
their state do not expressly prohibit mandatory tip pooling, though
past court cases and regulatory enforcements have made some
operators hesitant to impose pooling rules. CRA executives assert
that SB1511 is needed to give restaurateurs&quot;confidence&quot;that they
legally can mandate tip pooling and sharing with kitchen workers 
and that back-of-house workers do, in fact, affect guests&apos; dining
experience.

But recently the CRA changed its strategy for achieving its tip-
sharing goals. Alpert, author of SB1511, in recent weeks acted upon
the CRA&apos;s request by introducing an amendment to her bill that
essentially would move the matter out of the Democrat-controlled
Legislature. The amendment would do that by directing Republican
Gov. Arnold Schwarzengger&apos;s appointees on the Industrial Welfare
Commission to study tip pooling in the restaurant industry. The IWC,
which unilaterly can set the state&apos;s minimum-wage rate, also could
exert its powers to change rules governing tip pooling and sharing,
according to the amended wording of the Alpert bill.

SB1511 was passed recently by both the state Senate Labor and
Industrial Relations Committee and Alpert&apos;s own Senate
Appropriations Committee, which approved the bill by a 10-0 vote.
Though cleared for a vote by the full Senate, the bill has some
powerful enemies, including the California Labor Federation, or CLF,
an arm of the AFL-CIO.

CRA legislative chief Kabateck said the restaurant association knows
that SB 1511 is&quot;no slam dunk&quot;for passage, and that the CRA&apos;s
request for an IWC review of tip pooling might not succeed anytime
soon. That&apos;s because Democrat-backed bills in the state Assembly and
Senate call for defunding the IWC, he explained.

Those funding cuts purportedly are being sought to help close a
projected multibillion-dollar gap in the state budget, but the IWC
several times in the past has seen partisan threats to its funding
fall flat.

Kabateck said the CRA believes that the&quot;fairness&quot;of extending tip
pooling to kitchen employees would be among the topics addressed by
the IWC if that body is assigned to review the matter.&quot;We
determined that the IWC was the right place to take that up, and we
will certainly be a voice if and when it does,&quot;he said.

Of the more restrictive Massachusetts tip-sharing bill, the MRA&apos;s
Christie said he was&quot;cautiously optimistic&quot;it would be passed by
the Legislature and signed into law by Gov. Mitt Romney.

The Massachusetts House approved an earlier form of the measure,
then carried in House bill 499, and the Senate more recently
approved the amended H4431, sending it back to the House for
reconsideration.&quot;I hope it will contemporize our labor laws&quot;and&quot;clearly define
things,&quot;Christie said of the pending authorization for tip pooling
that disallows back-of-the-house sharing.&quot;Not 100 percent of the
people in the industry will enjoy this [law], but I know that 100
percent of the industry will be the beneficiary of it in the long
run.&quot;Some of the industry&apos;s legal observers, including National
Restaurant Association general counsel Peter Kilgore, believe that
even if the California association is successful in winning employer
rights to mandate tip sharing with kitchen workers, the victory
would be challenged in court. Such an effort likely would be led by
federal labor officials, who long have held that pooled tips cannot
be shared with any employee not tipped directly by diners.

The CRA, for its part, appears to feel that its proposal could
withstand a court challenge because of the recent Office of
Legislative Counsel opinion. It held that SB1511 does not violate
the FLSA because California&apos;s $6.75 hourly minimum wage exceeds the
$5.15 federal minimum. According to the CRA&apos;s Kabateck,&quot;Congress
did not intend to impose any additional requirements [on states]
once the minimum wage is paid.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #26 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 5:29 pm
 Subject: 100% business meal tax deductibility to return? (NRN 5.24.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 SBA study fuels campaign to restore 100% business meal tax
deductibility

WASHINGTON (May 24) - Restaurant operators and industry association
officials are optimistic that a recent study published by the U.S.
Small Business Administration will help spark efforts on Capitol
Hill to restore the full deductibility of business meals.
Commissioned by the SBA&apos;s Office of Advocacy, the study found that
small businesses derive considerably more benefit from the current
50-percent meal-and-entertainment tax deduction than do large
companies and, correspondingly, would profit more from its 100-
percent restoration.

Titled&quot;The Impact of Tax Expenditure Policies on Incorporated Small
Business,&quot;the study reports that small companies realize an average
reduction of 0.86 percent in their effective tax rate from the
current deduction level, compared with a 0.11-percent reduction
received by large companies.&quot;The study validates what the [National Restaurant Association] has
been saying since the business meal deductibility was reduced,&quot;NRA
lobbyist Kathleen O&apos;Leary said.&quot;[The reduction] hit small
businesses and self-employed individuals the hardest. They use it to
grow their businesses.&quot;O&apos;Leary added that federal lawmakers tend to view business meal
deductibility strictly as a restaurant issue.&quot;This shows that it is
not,&quot;she said.&quot;It&apos;s a user issue; it&apos;s a small-business issue.
We&apos;re pleased to have the support from the Small Business
Administration&apos;s study, urging small-business groups to make this a
tax policy priority.&quot;However, NRA economists estimate that reinstating the business meal
deductibility to 100 percent would increase restaurant sales by $12
billion annually. And allowing for an umbrella effect on food and
beverage suppliers and other businesses supporting the restaurant
industry, a restoration of the deductibility could create an overall
economic impact of $24 billion, the NRA says.

Currently, no bills are before Congress recommending a return to
full deductibility. However, Rep. Mark Foley, R-Fla., and Sen.
Daniel Inouye, D-Hawaii, both introduced bills last year seeking to
set the meal and entertainment deductible at 80 percent.

In 1986 federal lawmakers, claiming abuse by large corporations and
assailing the idea of the&quot;three-martini lunch,&quot;reduced the
deductibility from 100 percent to 80 percent. Congress took another
swipe at the rate seven years later, chopping it down to 50 percent
in the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993.

The NRA argues, however, that two-thirds of business meal users are
small businesses that rely on the deduction to remain competitive
and expand their businesses. High-ticket restaurants are not the
sole beneficiaries of the business meal deduction. Richard Kubach,
owner of the 24-hour Melrose Diner in Philadelphia, says his
family&apos;s 69-year-old business registered a decline in sales when the
deduction was trimmed back.&quot;We&apos;d get groups of delivery drivers in uniform who would come in
early in the morning for breakfast with their supervisors and
discuss any problems or business,&quot;Kubach explained.&quot;They would
spend about $5 each, and the supervisor would pick up the check. It
was certainly no three-martini breakfast.&quot;He said the diner also would attract small groups from local firms
who would discuss business over lunch.&quot;We&apos;d find a lot of blue-
collar customers coming in for business meetings,&quot;Kubach said.&quot;But
once the deductibility was reduced, suddenly they weren&apos;t there
anymore.&quot;It&apos;s not at all like the way they portray this issue in
Washington.&quot;Chad Moutray, chief economist for the SBA&apos;s Office of Advocacy,
acknowledged that while most tax expenditure programs favor large
businesses, the return of the business meal deduction to 100 percent
clearly would benefit small businesses across the nation.&quot;An
increase would give them additional tax relief,&quot;he said.

For the purpose of the study, the SBA defines a small business as
having fewer than 500 employees.

He estimated that if the meal tax deductibility rate were returned
to 100 percent, small businesses would enjoy a 1.9-percent reduction
in their effective tax rate. Large firms, by comparison, would see
only a 0.22-percent reduction.

However, with lawmakers in Washington voicing concerns about the
soaring federal deficit which is projected to top out at $500
billion this year few may be inclined to cut any potential revenue
streams.

Peter Ashton, president of Innovation and Information Consultants in
Concord, Mass., the authors of the SBA study, estimated that a
return to 100-percent deductibility would subtract about $1.5
billion annually from U.S. tax revenues. A return to 80 percent
would deduct about $1.2 billion in tax income.

Proponents of full restoration of the meal tax deduction argue,
however, that while it might cost the government in the short term,
the surge in spending in restaurants would more than
compensate.&quot;We&apos;ve always maintained that if you put the money back
into the hands of the taxpayers, it will get back into the economy
and generate additional revenue,&quot;O&apos;Leary said.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #27 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 5:32 pm
 Subject: Higher food prices hurt restaurant operators (Philadelphia Inquirer 5.18.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Higher food prices hurt restaurant operators, consumers

The Philadelphia Inquirer

By Harold Brubaker

PHILADELPHIA (May 18) - The price of the chicken breasts John
Kerentzis piles on 150 grilled chicken salads a day at City View
Pizza has climbed more 50 percent since March.

Making 150 pizzas a day at the Philadelphia shop is more expensive,
too: Mozzarella and colby cheeses cost 50 percent to 80 percent more
now than two months ago, depending on the distributor.

And Cheez Whiz an essential ingredient in the 85 cheese steaks he
sells daily costs $87 a case, up 55 percent from a low of $56 a
year ago.

The upshot?&quot;At the end of the week,&quot;said Kerentzis, a 30-year-old
who has spent half his life in the pizza business,&quot;I have 25
percent less for my pay.&quot;Kerentzis&apos;s earnings are suffering from a nationwide trend toward
higher prices at the wholesale and retail level for such staples as
meat, dairy products and vegetable oils and many other food items.

While the increases affect restaurant operators most directly
because food is their business, consumers are paying more at the
supermarket. A market basket of 16 basic items was up 10 percent in
the first quarter this year from the same period in 2003, the
American Farm Bureau Federation said.

The price increases are rooted in supply and demand cycles of farm
commodities.&quot;Food prices have been very low for 10 years,&quot;said Lou Moore, a
professor of agricultural economics at Pennsylvania State University
in State College.&quot;This is the first time grain farmers have had
anything to be enthusiastic about since 1994.&quot;Field corn, which is used to feed cattle and poultry, was more than
$3 a bushel this month on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange, up from
less than $2.40 a year ago. Soybeans, a legume that is a major
component of cattle feed and the biggest source of cooking oil, are
over $10 a bushel, compared to $6.20 a year ago.

But Moore sees little reason for worry.&quot;I can&apos;t imagine this is
going to create great hardships for consumers,&quot;he said. Americans
spent 10.1 percent of their disposable income on food in 2002,
according to the U.S. Department of Agriculture. That&apos;s among the
lowest in the world and is down from 12.7 percent in 1982 because of
greater efficiency in farming and food processing.

Kerenztis has not yet raised prices at City View Pizza in
Philadelphia because he doesn&apos;t think the economy his customers
experience is strong enough.

Meanwhile, he&apos;s hoping the price of ingredients
moderates.&quot;Basically, what we&apos;re doing is waiting for it to come
down.&quot;At Five Points Diner in Gloucester County, N.J., Sam Mastrodimas had
held most prices steady for four years - until this past Christmas,
when he raised them by 10 cents across the board.

Now he&apos;s boosting them by another 25 cents, and printing a new set
of menus at a cost of $3,000.

Ruth Moskowitz and her mother, Delores Marocca, who eat at the busy
diner about once a month, said after lunch that they had barely
noticed the December increase.&quot;Fifty cents to a dollar you would,&quot;said Moskowitz.

High-quality steaks are the biggest problem for Mastrodimas. Some
cuts of beef are up as much as 50 percent this year.&quot;We&apos;re not making money on steaks,&quot;he said, even though he has
raised prices. For example, he raised his price for a large Black
Angus Filet Mignon in November by $6 to $28.95.

He said he&apos;s thinking about taking steaks off the menu because as he
raises the price enough to make a profit, diners choose less-
expensive items.

The high beef prices making business tough for Mastrodimas and other
restauranteurs have many causes, including the seven-year cattle
cycle, said Joe Muldowney, an editor for Urner Barry Publications
Inc. in Toms River, N.J.&quot;We are now in the point of that cycle where we have the least
amount of supply,&quot;he said.

Muldowney said the seven-year supply-and-demand cycle in cattle is
caused by the amount of time it takes have a calf and bring it to
market and the amount of time it takes for farmers to react to
changes in prices.

The current market has been complicated by Canada&apos;s bout with mad
cow disease, which means the border is closed so U.S. herds can not
be restocked as easily.

Also, U.S. cattle farmers are exporting more, and milk prices are
up, which means that cows that might have been sold for ground beef
have been kept as milkers.

Milk prices are now at a high in their own cycle, causing butter
prices to soar from a $1.10 per pound last year on the Chicago
Mercantile Exchange to $2.13 now, said Glenn Millar, executive vice
president and partner at Keller&apos;s Creamery Inc. in Telford.

Millar said there could be butter shortages in the second half of
this year, as there were in the first quarter.

The hike in butter prices has contributed to a 20 percent increase
in the cost of supplies Greg Safos has experienced since he took
over Towne House Restaurant&amp;Bakery in Merchantville, N.J., seven
months ago.&quot;In making cookies, you have to use butter,&quot;Safos said as he tipped
three pounds of it into an old floor mixer to blend with sugar.

Safos, who has worked in restaurants for 35 years, mostly in diners
baking cakes and cookies, said he will close the breakfast and lunch
place in June or July because he has been taking home only about
$500 a week.&quot;That&apos;s not enough when you&apos;re working at least 80 hours a week, he
said.

 2004, The Philadelphia Inquirer. Distributed by Knight
Ridder/Tribune News Service.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #28 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 5:36 pm
 Subject: NYC bars and restaurants have cleanest air (US Newswire 5.21.04) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Study: NYC bars and restaurants have cleanest air

NEW YORK (May 21) - The air in New York City bars and restaurants is
the safest and cleanest, according to a seven-city study release
today. The study found that establishments in cities that protect
workers and patrons with smoke-free workplace laws have dramatically
lower levels of indoor air pollution than those without such
protections. The worst city, Washington D.C., had almost 15-times
more pollutants in the air of bars and restaurants than New York
City; Hoboken was nine-times worse. The New York&apos;s Smoke Free
Workplace Law went into effect fourteen months ago.

At the press conference announcing the study, Fred Jacobs, chair of
the Medical Society of New Jersey&apos;s Council on Public Health, urged
New Jersey residents with heart disease to go out to eat in New York
because of the cleaner air and the lack of secondhand smoke.

The study, conducted by researchers at the Roswell Park Cancer
Institute in Buffalo, used state-of-the-art air pollution monitors
to measure the levels of fine particulate air pollution in the bars
and restaurants of seven major U.S. cities. Three of the cities 
Buffalo, New York and Los Angeles have comprehensive smoke-free
workplace laws covering restaurants and bars, and four Baltimore,
Washington, D.C., Philadelphia, and Hoboken, N.J. do not have such
laws.

The study found that air pollution levels were 82 percent lower on
average in venues required by law to be smoke-free compared to those
where smoking was permitted. In cities without smoke-free laws, full-
time bar and restaurant employees are exposed on the job to more
than four times the average annual limits of fine particulate air
pollution recommended by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency
(EPA), the study found.

The study found that New York City&apos;s restaurants and bars had the
lowest level of air pollution, followed in order by Buffalo, Los
Angeles, Hoboken, Philadelphia, Baltimore and Washington, DC, which
had the highest levels of indoor air pollution.

Secondhand smoke contains more than 4,000 chemicals, including at
least 69 known carcinogens and hundreds of toxic chemicals, and is a
known cause of lung cancer, heart disease, bronchitis and asthma.
The study measured just one of the many forms of pollutants in
secondhand smoke.&quot;This study shows precisely why Mayor Bloomberg, the City Council
and subsequently the New York legislature were right to enact
comprehensive smoke-free air policies that cover all indoor
workplaces and all workers,&quot;said William V. Corr, executive
director of the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, which commissioned
the study along with the Flight Attendant Medical Research
Institute.&quot;The study demonstrates conclusively that New York&apos;s
smoke-free air law protects workers and patrons from the harmful air
pollutants in secondhand smoke. New York&apos;s law saves lives it&apos;s
that simple.&quot;The study, conducted between March 25 and April 17, 2004, involved
53 bars and restaurants in the seven cities. To receive an accurate
representation, researchers visited a minimum of three bars and
three restaurants in at least two popular entertainment districts in
each of the seven cities. Most sampling was performed on Thursday,
Friday and Saturday evenings between 6 p.m. and 3 a.m. The study is
the largest of its type ever conducted to measure the impact of
smoke-free laws on the indoor air quality of restaurants and bars.&quot;Regardless of location, levels of tobacco smoke pollution were
dramatically lower in bars and restaurants that were smoke- free,
and this should translate into lower disease rates for these
workers,&quot;said Andrew Hyland, lead investigator of the study.

The EPA has found that fine particulate air pollutants can penetrate
deeply into the lungs and have serious health effects, including
increased respiratory symptoms and disease, decreased lung function,
and alterations in lung tissue and structure. These particles also
carry other dangerous chemicals, including carcinogens, into the
lungs. There is a direct link between RSP levels and levels of
polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAH), which are known carcinogens
in cigarette smoke.

The study comes amidst accumulating evidence of the health harms
caused by exposure to secondhand smoke. Because of evidence that
even short-term exposure to secondhand smoke can trigger heart
attacks, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in
April advised persons with heart disease to avoid indoor settings
where smoking is allowed. The CDC recommendation accompanied a study
published in The British Medical Journal that found the number of
heart attacks reported in Helena, Montana, fell by 40 percent during
a six-month period in 2002 when the city&apos;s comprehensive smoke-free
law was in effect (the law is currently on hold due to a legal
challenge). The CDC estimates that secondhand smoke causes 35,000
heart disease deaths a year in the United States and expects to
revise that estimate upward as a result of the Helena study.

A study issued in 2002 by the International Agency for Research on
Cancer of the World Health Organization concluded,&quot;Nonsmokers are
exposed to the same carcinogens as active smokers. Even the typical
levels of passive exposure have been shown to cause lung cancer&quot;among people who have never smoked. Children exposed to secondhand
smoke are especially vulnerable, suffering more asthma, bronchitis,
ear infections and other ailments.

Several studies have also shown that there is no negative impact on
restaurant sales or employment from smoke-free policies. A recent
report by the New York City Department of Finance, Department of
Health and Mental Hygiene, Department of Small Business Services,
and Economic Development Corporation, found that since New York
City&apos;s smoke-free policy took effect March 30, 2003, business
receipts for restaurants and bars have increased, employment has
risen, the number of liquor licenses has increased, virtually all
establishments are complying with the law, the vast majority of New
Yorkers support the law, and customers and workers alike are being
protected from the harmful health effects of secondhand smoke.&quot;A smoke-free workplace law is a win-win-win for every community. It
protects workers and customers from harm, it is politically popular,
and it may even help improve the business climate,&quot;Corr concluded.

 2004 US Newswire
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #29 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 6:19 pm
 Subject: Computer game allows users to open virtual restaurant (The Wall Street Journal) waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Computer game allows users to open virtual restaurant

In&quot;Restaurant Empire,&quot;users assume the role of French bistro chef
Armand LeBoeuf, and have to navigate their way through staffing,
handling customers and food critics, and improving the menu, while
still maintaining a profit. The game has sold 150,000 copies since
its release last year, and the game&apos;s programmer says future
editions are in the works. The Wall Street Journal
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #30 From: &quot;Paul Paz&quot;&lt;waitersworld@...&gt;
 Date: Mon May 24, 2004 6:26 pm
 Subject: Hard Rock Cafe&apos;s use of technology to build customer loyality. waitersworld 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Hard Rock Cafe&apos;s loyalty programs turns customers into groupies
With its strong commitment to customer service, Hard Rock Cafe has
made development of robust loyalty solutions a prime focus of its
information technology department. The company&apos;s&quot;All Access&quot;loyalty program helps track customer spending habits and preferences
over time, and the program is now tied in with a new branded loyalty
points credit card.


Hospitality Technology (Randolph, N.J.) (5/20) http://www.htmagazine.com/HT/archive/0504/0504_4.shtml Rock Solid IT
Hard Rock Caf builds a solid technology infrastructure for
consistent quality and improved customer loyalty
By Reid A. Paul, Managing Editor

When you visit a Hard Rock Caf you can rest assured that a
cheeseburger really is a cheeseburger. Ensuring a consistent high-
quality experience has been the main focus of the information
technology department. From the website customers visit, to the
music they hear, to the points they earn, consistency has become
Hard Rock&apos;s hallmark.

That&apos;s no easy task with 114 Hard Rock Cafs stretching from Beijing
to Bogot, Kuala Lumpur to Copenhagen, and Niagara Falls to Newport
Beach. Managing store systems is a round-the-clock affair for Kelly
Maddern, Hard Rock&apos;s senior director of information systems.&quot;At the
end of a day, we&apos;re a customer service organization for our field,&quot;Maddern recently told Hospitality Technology in an exclusive
interview.&quot;Without the cafs, there is no corporate IT department.&quot;That commitment to service, leads to some long nights for the head
of the global restaurant company (the Hard Rock hotels are managed
separately).&quot;Depending on daylight savings,&quot;Maddern reveals,&quot;we
either have an hour of system maintenance time or we don&apos;t have a
maintenance window&quot;at all. According to Maddern, Hard Rock&apos;s IT
department works day and night in the pursuit of a single
mission:&quot;Love all, serve all.&quot;Whether it is guests or restaurant
managers, the approach to customer service is the same at Hard Rock.

Loyal Groupies
Given the focus on customer service, it should come as no surprise
that developing robust loyalty solutions has been a prime focus of
IS at Hard Rock Caf. Beginning in 2001, Hard Rock began a concerted
effort to get to know their most loyal customers.&quot;We really didn&apos;t
understand who our customer was, where they were coming from and
what their preferences were because we didn&apos;t have a way of tracking
them,&quot;Maddern admits.

Beginning with a database of fewer than 10,000 names and little
data, Hard Rock designed its&quot;All Access&quot;loyalty program to first
enhance its customer database and then to allow the restaurant chain
to track the customer demographics and purchasing patterns.&quot;We knew our primary guest was a tourist or somebody that was
traveling,&quot;Maddern notes.&quot;We really wanted to keep the program
simple, as well. So we put out a loyalty card that could be swiped
through our Micros 8700 point-of-sale system, and feed all that
transactional information back to the corporate office.&quot;After looking around, Hard Rock elected to build the program in-
house for flexibility and to facilitate future customization.&quot;When
we put the foundation and the architecture together, we really
started to design it in a way that we could add functionality with
minimal effort,&quot;Maddern recalls.&quot;Before we had put the loyalty
programs in place, we had really worked a few years back to make
sure our infrastructure was sound, and that our databases were
consistent. We have a data warehouse at corporate that does
aggregate sales level and labor level tracking so that we had
consistency that a cheeseburger was a cheeseburger in every single
caf.&quot;That focus on consistency across the board has helped Maddern and
Hard Rock Caf function smoothly.&quot;It&apos;s essential that we&apos;re doing
projects like business intelligence and data reporting because data
integrity is the key for everything,&quot;Maddern insists.&quot;If I can&apos;t
report the numbers accurately, then we&apos;re going to have some serious
problems.&quot;Instead of problems, what Maddern has discovered is a rich treasure
trove of customer data. With many customers visiting multiple
different Hard Rock Cafs nationally and internationally Hard Rock
has been able to track down to the SKU level what individual
customers are buying. Hard Rock analyzes the data and selects
merchandise and menu options based in part on the guests&apos;
preferences and especially the loyalty guests&apos; preferences.&quot;Since the loyalty program is integrated with the point of sale and
all that information feeds back, we can tie the transactions to the
actual person and see what their spending habits and preferences are
over time,&quot;Maddern says.&quot;We have the ability to do an e-mail
marketing campaign direct out to those groups or those segments, if
you will, to try and drive different behaviors.&quot;Seeking to keep on top of the trend, Hard Rock recently rolled out a
new branded loyalty points credit card.&quot;The biggest thing that we
need to do is to be tightly integrated with the bank because they
will be sending across as applicants become approved, they become
instant members into the All Access program,&quot;adds Maddern.

Offering a credit card that is tied into the loyalty program has
forced Hard Rock to handle a range of issues that are relatively new
to the foodservice industry. Hard Rock now must ensure that all the
customer data is entered into the credit card account info as well
as Hard Rock&apos;s own customer database as well as the credit card.
Since credit card users are awarded points for the All Access
loyalty program based on their credit card spending (one point for
every $100 purchased with the card), data must be updated regularly
and integration between the accounts has become a paramount concern.

That process is made far simpler with the use of an XML interface
between the accounts. Having the XML interface was a key to rolling
out the credit card program.&quot;It&apos;s important to have development standards, just for the sake of
making sure that it&apos;s supportable by my team,&quot;Maddern insists.&quot;Our
philosophy is to do it right, do it right the first time, but also
be quick to market. We try to balance all those ends.&quot;For Hard Rock the process is not as simple as it might seem. Still,
Maddern has no doubt that the credit card program will add value to
the guest experience and boost the loyalty program.&quot;We have to
integrate the credit-card information into our customer database,&quot;explains Maddern.&quot;We expect the Hard Rock credit card will be an
accelerator to our All Access loyalty program. Wel have to do the
data integration to make sure that those loyalty balances are up to
date. We will be using secure FTP to transfer the files and will
pick up files in near real-time and convert to XML.&quot;HardRock.com
Perhaps one of the most unusual aspects of IT at Hard Rock Caf has
been its control of the HardRock.com website. Before most other
restaurants, Hard Rock recognized the potential for e-commerce and
began selling branded merchandise online as well as more common
tools.&quot;We launch the new look and feel for HardRock.com back on
September 10, 2001,&quot;Maddern recalls.&quot;I remember the day because it
was my birthday, and also the day before September 11. But really
what we want to do with hardrock.com is we wanted it to be an
extension of the experience within the cafs as well as to use it as
a tool to make our cafs and our other branding initiatives visible
to our guests.&quot;Interestingly, the design and technology for the website fall within
the information technology department at Hard Rock. IT works closely
with marketing and other departments for large scale promotions. Not
surprisingly, Hard Rock has found its website to be a successful
customer acquisition tool source as well.

Early on, Hard Rock developed an intranet portal with operational
reporting updated on a daily basis. Hard Rock is also in the process
of extending its current agreement with MicroStrategy for business-
intelligent and data mining. According to Maddern, Hard Rock is
hoping to take advantage of MicroStrategy&apos;s Web-based ASP solution
to expand its reporting capability out to the cafs and to move
toward digital dashboard capabilities for on-site restaurant
managers.&quot;We&apos;re actually bringing in the MicroStrategy Web product
to expand our portal to launch further reporting capabilities out to
our cafs,&quot;Maddern explains.&quot;This will incorporate dashboard and
scorecarding capabilities into the data and consolidate key metrics
it into one area.&quot;&quot;We have a lot of great information out on our intranet and a lot
available to us,&quot;says Maddern.&quot;The digital dashboard brings all
these key metrics into one portal. What it really does is ensure
that our operations are consistent and that everybody&apos;s looking at
the same information. You&apos;ll be able to roll up for region to
company and then down to the caf level and then actually drill down
into the lowest level of detail to what you need to do to get to the
information.&quot;Development Standards
Although each restaurant has unique music memorabilia and even music
(piped in through the frame relay wide-area network), consistency in
service and menu has been a priority.&quot;When you look at it from an
experience based standpoint, each caf is unique in some way,&quot;notes
Maddern.&quot;Obviously, we want everybody to have an awesome experience, but
depending on what market you&apos;re in or the reason why you&apos;re visiting
the caf, that experience may changeyou know, if you&apos;re there for a
birthday party as opposed to a business lunch. We really try and go
that extra mile to make it very special.&quot;Not surprisingly, many aspects of making it special are handled from
Hard Rock&apos;s Orlando, Florida headquarters. Music is carefully
programmed&quot;From an experience standpoint, the biggest technology
that impacts the customer is our music system,&quot;We have a frame
relay out to all our cafs and download content to the cafs on a
regular basis.&quot;Hard Rock has taken a similar approach with other systems as
well.&quot;We have a full-blown retail inventory merchandising system
that&apos;s central to all our corporate owned cafs,&quot;Maddern
continues.&quot;All the data are running through that, as well as the
food and beverage system. Last year, we went through a warehousing
outsourcing initiative and brought on a third party logistics
company. We had a lot of near real-time XML feeds going back and
forth between the warehouses and their warehouse-management system
to our WMS. It is critical so we can have complete visibility to our
inventory supply throughout the chain.&quot;That holds equally true for the technology-side of operations. The
technology footprint in each caf, Maddern notes, except for slight
variations in the number of PCs or the number of terminals, is
consistent from caf to caf.&quot;We have very set standards of
operational procedures and processes as it relates to the
technology,&quot;she adds. When you run a 24 hour a day operation, that
may be the only thing letting you sleep at night.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) 
 
 Messages 1 - 30 of 4212  Oldest  |  &lt; Older  |  Newer &gt;  |  Newest 

 Start Topic 
      What&apos;s This? Actions Start Topic 
Just address an email to WaiterNews@yahoogroups.com

 Jump to a particular message Message # Search Messages Advanced 
SPONSOR RESULTS
 
 Free Mobile POS Software ePOSpos.com - Use From Any Phone, No Hardware Required. Get Your Free Copy Today 
 

 Matot Dumbwaiters www.matot.com - Lift 2 to 2000 lbs. We engineer, manufacture&amp;ship internationally 
 

 Happy Chef Uniforms HappyChefUniforms. com - Low, Low Prices&amp;No Minimums. Factory Direct. Fast&amp;Affordable. 
 
 
 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
