<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003968" url="http://thailandbirding.com/trip-reports/wildlife-sanctuaries.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:08" support="1" score="0.00036214229544338" bingtitle="Ton Pariwat Wildlife sanctuary trip report" webtitle="Ton Pariwat Wildlife sanctuary trip report">
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="168"/>
	<description>... Sanctuary, Manora Forest Park, Raman Forest Park and ... to the tip of its bill. It’s quite a sight. Carrying ... and Yellow Broadbill calling near #5 ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Birding NEWS Favorite Birds Starting Out Bird Glossary Image Galleries Destination Trip Reports Kayaking Info Inquiries More About us Site Map 
 
 TRIP 
 REPORT PHUKET 
 DAY TRIP DAVE&apos;S 
 THAILAND LIFE LIST 
 
 Birding 
 Destinations Khao 
 Sok National Park _ Krung 
 Ching Phuket 
 Birding Day Trip Phuket 
 Birding Itinerary Thai 
 Muang Birding add-on Phuket 
 Bird List Phuket 
 - Phang Nga combo Khao 
 Nor Chuchi -- Hala 
 Bala Wildlife Sanctuary Khao 
 Sok / Phang Nga Province Krabi 
 birding Ultimate 
 Southern Series Khao 
 Sok National Park Khao 
 Luang National Park Khao 
 Pu Khao Ya Thale 
 Noi Khao 
 Nam Kang Thale 
 Ban 

 
 
 
 Ton 
 Pariwat Wildlife Sanctuary birding trip report 
   



 

 
 
 
 
 

 Story 
 and photos by Dave Williams 

 On 
 May 18th, 2005, Andrew, Stijn and I went on a 
 two-day journey to Manora Forest Park , Raman Forest Park , Phang 
 Nga National Park and Ton Paliwat 
 Wildlife Sanctuary . The weather was a 
 bit hot, but the birds were very active. 

 We 
 started off in Manora Forest Park on the morning 
 of May 18th. A tree was in fruit in the parking 
 lot. We saw a Spectacled Bulbuls , Plain Sunbirds , a couple of Buff-vented 
 Bulbuls , Purple-naped Sunbirds (male&amp;female), a Spectacled Spiderhunter , Brown-throated Sunbird (female) 
 and a pair of Emerald Doves . 
 A Blue Flycatcher , probably a Tickell’s , flew by and 
 Andy grabbed his spotting scope. Unfortunately, 
 the bird had its back to us most of the time. 
 We got a momentary look at the breast, but not 
 long enough to tell exactly what it was. 

 A 
 lovely creek streams through this small forest 
 park. The manager of the park is a very friendly 
 gentleman who speaks a good bit of English. He 
 is doing a wonderful job of keeping the park clean. 
 He’s also interested in keeping locals from 
 cutting down trees…more on this later. 

 We 
 headed up the trail. It starts with some attractive 
 cascading waterfalls. The trail is well-maintained 
 and the footing is excellent. Steps are cut into 
 the earth on the steeper bits. Concrete steps 
 are provided in the steepest parts. Stijn saw 
 a Little Heron on the bank. 

 We 
 proceeded past the waterfall area and into the 
 jungle. The trail here is also superb. We were 
 looking at a cave, when suddenly we heard a Green 
 Broadbill ! There it was, a beautiful 
 male in the same spot as it was a week before. 
 This is one of the most stunning birds in the 
 area. Its lime-green feathers grow all the way 
 to the tip of its bill. It’s quite a sight. 

 Carrying 
 on, we came upon a Blue Whistling Thrush . 
 A towering limestone cliff sits to the left of 
 the trail. Stijn spotted some Striated 
 Swallows circling up high. Later, we 
 saw some Germaine Swiftlet coming 
 out of a cave. 

 At 
 one point, we saw a group of about a dozen locals 
 cutting down trees across the creek. They had 
 set up a tent and a campfire was smoldering. I 
 took some photos of them. They yelled at us to 
 ask us what we were doing. We didn’t reply. 
 A Blue-eared Kingfisher was near 
 where they were cutting. 

 Along 
 a bit further, we saw a female Crimson-breasted 
 Flowerpecker and Ochraceous Bulbuls . 
 Andy heard a Banded Kingfisher . 
 Stijn had a mini-disc player with the call. He 
 turned it on and the kingfisher appeared within 
 seconds. We enjoyed watching it for a few minutes. 
 A male Black-naped Monarch made 
 a guest appearance too. 

 Andy 
 had been to this forest park recently and he heard 
 a Streaked Wren-Babbler . It was 
 a bird he really wanted to add to his Thailand 
 list. We heard one calling. Within a couple minutes, 
 Andy’s face lit up. He whispered,“There 
 it is, right in front of me!”He tried not 
 moving to much, but his excitement alarmed the 
 bird. However, it wasn’t so disturbed that 
 it left. Instead, it flew all over the place around 
 us. It was up in the cliffs for a bit, and then 
 it would zip over to a shrub. Then it zipped over 
 to some other trees. It called constantly. We 
 now have that call engrained in our brains. This 
 was a new bird for both Andy and me. 

 A Yellow-breasted Flowerpecker was 
 spotted in this area too. This was at trail mark 
 #9. 

 We 
 walked up the trail a bit more and spotted a Red-throated 
 Barbet . It’s always a treat seeing 
 these birds. 

 We 
 went to the end of the trail. There’s a 
 cave here. Germaine Swiftlets flew in and out of the cave. Andy and Stijn went 
 up to investigate it. I sat on a bench watching 
 butterflies. In addition to a nice variety of 
 birds, this park has some gorgeous butterflies. 
 My 12X optical zoom digital camera proved to be 
 a useful tool. 

 Once 
 rested up a bit, we headed back. Shortly, we saw 
 an adult male Asian Paradise- Flycatcher streamed past us. Stijn pointed out a Grey-throated 
 Babbler to us. 

 When 
 we got back to the parking lot, we saw the manager 
 and told him about the guys cutting down the trees. 
 He was visibly upset. He said that he was going 
 to go up right away…and he did. We were 
 a bit concerned as he was by himself and there 
 were twelve bad guys. We had lunch at the restaurant 
 by the creek. 

 Mangrove 
 Walkway 

 On 
 the drive from Phuket to Krabi, there’s 
 a small mangrove walkway. The trees here are much 
 taller than most of the mangrove in the Phang 
 Nga, Phuket, Krabi area. I don’t know how 
 or why these few trees were spared the chainsaw, 
 but I’m glad they were. Andy has visited 
 this spot a few times. He told stories of Mangrove 
 Pittas and other very cool birds. I found 
 it hard to believe that this small area would 
 harbor such uncommon birds. Boy, was I ever wrong. 

 The 
 first birds we spotted were three female Streak-breasted 
 Woodpeckers . We got incredibly close 
 to them, closer than I’ve ever been to any 
 woodpeckers. Suddenly, we heard Mangrove Pittas! 
 They were very close. There it was, a beautiful Mangrove Pitta . It was up off 
 the ground in a mangrove tree. It was calling 
 constantly. May is a wonderful time to go birding 
 here as it’s breeding season for so many 
 species. It’s odd, but as much time as I 
 spend in mangroves, I hadn’t seen one of 
 these guys for over a decade. But there it was, 
 in plain view. We heard three in this very small 
 area. We satisfied our visual appetite and moved 
 on. 

 Stijn 
 spotted a White-chested Babbler . 
 It was right beside the walkway. Andy and I were 
 astonished. This is a bird we’ve both been 
 wanting for a while. The babbler hopped around 
 the mangrove forest floor. A second one was spotted 
 nearby. We heard a Banded Bay Cuckoo off in the distance, but not too far away. We 
 didn’t see it. 

 Phang 
 Nga National Park - Small Mangrove Walkway 

 Next, 
 we headed to Phang Nga National Park. There’s 
 a nice walkway/boardwalk through the mangrove 
 forest. Both Andy and Stijn had been there before. 
 I hadn’t. 

 We 
 checked into the bungalows and headed to the walkway. 
 Right off the bat, we saw a Ruby-cheeked 
 Sunbird , a Common Iora , 
 an Ashy Tailorbird , a male Brown-throated 
 Sunbird and an Ashy Drongo . 
 A male Common Flameback Woodpecker made a brief appearance. A pair of White-chested 
 Babblers were calling each other. One 
 was very close to us. I’ve noticed that 
 once you see a bird that you dream of seeing, 
 suddenly you start seeing them all over the place. 
 This was the case with the White-chested Babbler. 

 Raman 
 Forest Park 

 On the morning of the 19th, we hopped over to Raman Forest Park . 

 I 
 had been there recently while researching some 
 mountain biking trails. I heard Blue-winged 
 Pittas and broadbills while I was there, 
 but I didn’t see them. 

 Starting 
 in the parking Lot, we saw a Purple-naped 
 Sunbird and an Emerald Dove . 

 The 
 trails in this forest park are also very well-maintained. 
 The trail parallels a lovely stream with nice 
 waterfalls. We saw a Chestnut-breasted 
 Malkoha , a Plain Sunbird , 
 a Red-eyed Bulbul , and a Grey-throated 
 Babbler as we worked our way up the gentle 
 hill. 

 Stijn 
 spotted a Crimson-breasted Flowerpecker and Andy and I got a brief glimpse of 
 it as well. Next, we saw a Yellow-bellied 
 Warbler . Both of these birds were around 
 the #5 trail mark. We also heard a Black 
 and Yellow Broadbill calling near #5 
 too. 

 We 
 made our way to the end of the trail and turned 
 around. On the way back we saw an adult male Asian 
 Paradise-Flycatcher , a Yellow-bellied 
 Bulbul and a Little Spiderhunter . 
 When we got back to the parking lot area, Stijn 
 spotted a male Crimson Sunbird , 
 one of the most attractive small birds in Thailand. 
 We also saw a Streak-eared Bulbul in the parking lot. It’s amazing how many 
 birds you can see in parking lots. It seems to 
 be a great place to bird in every park I’ve 
 ever visited. 

 

 In 
 the afternoon, we decided to head to Thai Meung 
 town. We wanted to take the scenic route and somehow 
 we got sidetracked, first by a big shallow river 
 and then by a sign we saw. We surveyed the river 
 for the River Lapwing , but didn’t 
 see one. We saw a sign for Ton Paliwat 
 Wildlife Sanctuary . Andy had heard that 
 it was a nice place to go birding, so we took 
 a right. 

 I 
 thought that there wasn’t any whitewater 
 in Southern Thailand. There are however a few 
 companies running a river in this area. I had 
 never visited this region. We drove up higher 
 and higher up the mountain. We traveled past several 
 rafting outfitters. The river was small and very 
 shallow. How on earth could they raft this? Up 
 a bit further and the answer became obvious. Someone 
 had built a dam on the river. When they want to 
 run the river, they open the dam. Still, it was 
 not very much water. We drove up higher. 

 Finally, 
 we came to the top and the headquarters for the 
 wildlife sanctuary. Right off the bat, we saw Grey-rumped Treeswifts . In the 
 distance, White-handed Gibbons made their strange 
 calls. The mountains surrounding the wildlife 
 sanctuary were covered exquisite high 
 canopy trees. From the top however you can see 
 vast areas that have been cut down and converted 
 into boring rubber trees and oil palms. Almost 
 all of the lowland jungle in Thailand and elsewhere 
 has been cut down for the rubber oil palm business. 
 The word“overkill”comes to mind. 

 Anyway, 
 we walked up the waterfall area near the headquarters. 
 The river was very nice, but again, it wasn’t 
 anything worth paddling. It was way too low. I 
 could see that if there was enough water, it would 
 be a class III-ish run. We decided that birding 
 here would be difficult as the sound of the water 
 killed all the bird sounds. So, we opted to walk 
 down the road. It was an excellent choice. 

 First 
 off, we saw a few Whiskered Treeswifts . Silver-rumped Swifts , with their 
 bat-like fluttering, whiz by. A Crimson 
 Sunbird and an Asian Fairy-Bluebird was spotted. Andy had his spotting scope. He fixed 
 it on a pair of Vernal Hanging Parrots up in a dead tree. We heard a Puff-throated 
 Babbler nearby. Three Black-headed 
 Bulbuls flew by, as did some Pacific 
 Swifts. 

 The 
 next sighting was a real treat. A pair of Scarlet 
 Minivets (male and female) were hopping 
 around in a nearby tree. We were able to spend 
 a few minutes watching these stunning birds. 

 Shortly 
 thereafter, we saw a Streaked Bulbul , 
 an Emerald Dove , a female Greater 
 Green Leafbird and a Yellow-vented 
 Flowerpecker . Andy called us over. He 
 had a Brown Barbet in his scope! 
 It was a new bird for me and most likely a new 
 bird for Andy. Stijn had seen them elsewhere outside 
 of Thailand. This was a dream bird for me. 

 Further 
 down, we spotted a Grey-headed Flycatcher , 
 a Bar-winged Flycatcher-Shrike , Stripe-throated Bulbuls and Asian 
 Paradise-Flycatchers . 

 Stijn 
 pointed out a new bird for Andy, a Scaly-breasted 
 Bulbul ! Andy was ecstatic. He’d 
 been wanting this bird for a long time. I saw 
 one in Khao Sok National Park last August. I climbed 
 up a mountain for four hours. It was rather difficult. 
 My reward however, was getting to see a Scaly-breasted 
 Bulbul from a fairly close distance. 

 It 
 was late in the afternoon so we started heading 
 back to the car. Along the way we spotted a Blue-eared 
 Barbet . There was a tree full of Vernal 
 Hanging Parrots, Whiskered Treeswifts and Grey-rumped 
 Treeswifts making a lot of noise. I can’t 
 recall ever seeing that many parrots or treeswifts 
 in one place before. Upon reaching the card, a 
 small group of White-rumped Munias bid us farewell. 
 

 

 
 
 
   
 
 
 
 
 


 


 Contact 
 Us! 

 

 
 CONTACT 
 US 18/58 Thanon Rasdanusorn,
Ban Kuku, Phuket 83000
Tel/fax: +66 76 241519
Dave&apos;s mobile: 081 8936558
Moo &apos;s mobile: 081 7974855 
 
  RELATED WEB SITES Thailand Seakayaking 
 Kayaking in Thailand 
 Thailand Eco tours 
 Thailand Khao Sok Adventure 
 Thailand Mountain Biking 
 
 
 Sign up for our PaddleAsia 
 Newsletter . It covers what we are doing, what 
 we have done, trip reports, and interesting facts about the natural 
 world. Send us an email to subscribe. 
 
Tourism Authority of Thailand 
License Number 31/0204
Insurance by New Hampshire Insurance Co. of Manchester New Hampshire Policy 
 #670158
Page last updated:October 4, 2011
Copyright©1999 - 2010 Paddle Asia Co., Ltd. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
