<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003457" url="http://www.talusweb.com/10/1509/www-TalkToSonic-Sonic-Survey-Coupon?p=5" time="2012-07-12-19:36" support="7" score="0.01907659279179041" bingtitle="www.TalkToSonic.com - Sonic Survey Coupon" webtitle="www.TalkToSonic.com - Sonic Survey Coupon">
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>Sonic Drive-In is a fast food restaurant chain in the United ... To participate in this survey, you need to enter ... My order is always right and they serve me with a ...</description>
	<body>
		Trusted Reviews 
 
 
www.TalkToSonic.com - Sonic Survey Coupon
 posted on Apr 20, 2011 
 Sonic Drive-In is a fast food restaurant chain in the United States. Every day it offers over 3 million customers, like you, the facility to drive in their automobiles in any of its more than 3,500 restaurants and enjoy dining. It was established in 1953 and is currently operational in forty-four states of America.

Www.TalkToSonic.com is the site through which its corporate office at Oklahoma City, Oklahoma aims to gather its customers’views about this unique dining experience. You, too, can share your recent dining experience and express your candid views to the company by participating in its‘Guest Satisfaction Survey’through this site. To participate in this survey, you need to enter the ID number located at the bottom of your receipt and complete the survey within 14 days of your recent dining. Your views are very valuable to the company and to show its gratitude, the company will award you a validation code at the end of the survey. You can redeem this code to get a free SONIC Burger on a purchase of medium tot or Single-Patty Burgers, during your future visit to any of its drive-ins.

 Website: www.talktosonic.com   Tags: restaurant survey , restaurants   Category: Surveys&amp;Sweepstakes 
 Advertisement 
 
 
Comments 
 
I have two receipts and wanted to do a suvey about customer satisfaction and it kicked one out as it had expired BUT the other receipt hadn&apos;t expired BUT it won&apos;t let me take the survey. Whats up with that ??? I want my FREE dink and want to take the survey ! - posted 

12 months ago by 
 sherry 
 
Free drink, duh ! - posted 

12 months ago by 
 sherry 
 
Service was great - posted 

12 months ago by 
 Michael Twa 
 
I just love Sonic and the Cherry Limeades. The carhops are all very friendly. - posted 

11 months ago by 
 RaLenn 
 
good food and good freindly service. I always buy my cherry water there only. I think i will go have my lunch there.. mmmmm!! - posted 

11 months ago by 
 Delores Tapia 
 
The clinton utah store treats me very well every time I go there. My order is always right and they serve me with a smile. Especially Kelsey. - posted 

11 months ago by 
 Steve Hammontree 
 
Great job very friendly - posted 

11 months ago by 
 juanita crosse 
 
Great service - posted 

11 months ago by 
 juanita crosse 
 
Good job Steve Richard. Everyone courteous and supported of our kids at Grolee Elementary in Opelousas. Our visit is always great1 by Mrs. S. Jackson - posted 

11 months ago by 
 Shirley C. Jackson 
 
Great service Steve Richard. friendly and courteous employees. Job well Done! - posted 

11 months ago by 
 Shirley C. Jackson 
 Page:  1     2     3     4     5     6     7     8     




 Found a great website? Submit and share your review. 

 Categories 
 Blogs | Business | Entertainment | Food | Health | Jobs&amp;Career | Legal | Money&amp;Investing | Politics | Shopping | Surveys&amp;Sweepstakes | Travel | World News 

 Other reviews 
 www.RepforVets.com - Rep For Vets for Veterans 
 www.MySymbicort.com - My Symbicort 
 www.GolfChannel.com/LuckyBreak - Golf Channel Lucky Break Sweepstakes 
 www.MerchantMembershipSettlement.com - Merchant Membership Settlement 
 www.Blbglaw.com - BLB&amp;G Law 

 Recent reviews 
 www.ePayItOnline.com - ePay Online 
 www.GiftCardMall.com/mygift - Gift Card Mall MyGift 
 www.tellkroger.com - Tell Kroger Customer Satisfaction Survey 



 

 



©2010 TalusWeb      Home      About Us      Terms      Privacy      Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
