<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003727" url="http://melaniezoltan.suite101.com/subway-gluten-free-fast-food-menu---gf-meal-options-for-celiac-a271790" time="2012-07-12-19:53" support="4" score="0.010921537453872077" bingtitle="Subway Gluten Free Fast Food Menu - GF Meal Options for Celiac ..." webtitle="Subway Gluten Free Fast Food Menu - GF Meal Options for Celiac | Suite101.com">
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000856" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>Learn more about GF meal options for celiac ... Condiments &amp; Dressings. Chipotle Southwest Sauce; Honey ... If you&apos;re looking for other fast food restaurant menus wiih ...</description>
	<body>
		Subway Gluten Free Fast Food Menu - GF Meal Options for Celiac
 Tweet 
 Aug 10, 2010 Melanie Zoltan 
 Subway Gluten Free Fast Food Menu - Image by Michal Zacharzewski Subway, one of the largest chain restaurants in the U.S., offers many gluten free fast food menu items. Learn more about GF meal options for celiac clients. 
At first glance, Subway - known for its large sub sandwiches, made on gluten-filled rolls - doesn&apos;t seem like the best GF meal option for people with celiac disease or other forms of gluten intolerance. Most of the restaurants bake their rolls onsite, so for people with celiac just breathing in a Subway can be like inhaling a Kryptonite mist. And yet - sometimes the ubiquitous Subway is the only restaurant within an easy walk. Learn how to use the Subway gluten free fast food menu to find GF meal options for celiac disease and gluten intolerance.

Gluten Free Fast Food Menu

Celiac disease and gluten intolerance involves following a strict gluten-free diet to repair digestive problems caused by an autoimmune response when gluten (wheat, barley, rye) is ingested. The gluten protein destroys the villi in the intestines, breaking down the body&apos;s ability to digest properly and to absorb needed vitamins and minerals. People with celiac diease and gluten intolerance can become malnourished and develop osteopenia and osteoporosis, so following a GF diet is critical.

In the U.S., fast food is everywhere, and a GF diet doesn&apos;t mesh well with these quick-meal restaurants. More gluten free fast food menus are becoming available, with restaurants such as;
 
 Arby&apos;s McDonald&apos;s Wendy&apos;s Carl&apos;s Jr. Kentucky Fried Chicken 

creating GF meal options for customers. So what how can GF dieters find celiac support at a sandwich shop known for its bread?

Subway GF Meal Options

With 33,000 locations in 92 countries, and often two or three stores within an easy walk of any downtown location in the U.S., a celiac patient can almost throw a rock and hit a Subway - but might not think they can eat there. On the contrary - the Subway gluten free fast food menu does not include its sandwiches, but there are a surprising number of meals a customer can create to stick to a celiac diet. The GF items at Subway include:

 Salads 
 
More on this topic
 
 Gluten Free Valentine&apos;s Day Dinner - Restaurants With GF Menus Gluten Free Menus - Legal Seafoods Celiac Friendly, GF Meals Gluten Free Menus and Travel Near Splash Lagoon in Erie, PA 
 
 Chicken and Bacon Ranch Cold Cut Combo Ham (Black Forest) Italian BMT Oven Roasted Chicken Roast Beef Tuna Turkey Breast Turkey Breast and Ham Spicy Italian Subway Club Steak&amp;Cheese Veggie Delite 

 Meat, Poultry, Seafood and Eggs 

 Bacon strips Oven Roasted Chicken Chicken strips - plain Cold Cut Combo meats Egg (Regular) Omelet Egg (White) Omelet Ham (Black Forest) Italian BMT meats Roast Beef Steak Tuna Turkey Breast 

 All cheeses 

 Condiments&amp;Dressings 

 Chipotle Southwest Sauce Honey Mustard Sauce Light Mayonnaise/Regular Mayonnaise Mustard (Yellow and Deli Brown) Oil Ranch Dressing Red Wine Vinaigrette Sweet Onion Sauce Vinegar 

 Vegetables 

 Banana peppers Jalapenos Olives Pickles Fresh vegetables 

 Note: all information taken from the Subway Ingredient Information for People With Food Allergies and Sensitivities, March 2010 date - accessed August 2010. 

Celiac Diet and Subway

While most of Subway&apos;s GF meal options are the old standby for those following a GF diet - salad with some sort of meat - the variety of dressings and meat flavors can make this store a viable GF diet option. As with any restaurant experience, be careful to ask staff to avoid cross contamination and to use safe food handling practices.

Eating out on a celiac diet doesn&apos;t have to be hard, but patrons do need to carefully research area restaurants and work to make eating out as safe as possible. Subway&apos;s gluten free fast food menu is yet another tool for any celiac patient to use.

If you&apos;re looking for other fast food restaurant menus wiih gluten free choices, please read:

 Chipotle Gluten Free Menu - want safe, GF Mexican food? Look here.

 Gluten Free Menu at Arby&apos;s - find out which items are GF and safe for people with gluten intolerance.
 Copyright Melanie Zoltan . Contact the author to obtain permission for republication. 
 Melanie Zoltan - Melanie Zoltan is a former college professor and administrator who has written for About.com, PCWorld, Brain Child, Thomson Gale, and ... 
 Print Article Tweet Advertisement 
 Comments 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. comments powered by Disqus Advertisement 
More on this topic
 
 P.F. Chang&apos;s Gluten-Free Menu Provides Safe, Stress Free Dining Gluten Free Menu - Ted&apos;s Montana Grill Gluten-Free Restaurants Near Skyzone Boston - GF Menus for Celiac 
 more in food trends » Advertisement Latest Articles • About Us • Terms&amp;Conditions • Privacy Policy • suite101.de • suite101.fr • suite101.net • Suite101 Blog Food Trends @ 
 Write for Suite101 Sign In 
 
 Food Trends Kitchen Gadgets Food Websites 
 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Food Trends
	</body>
</document>
