<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003423" url="http://www.businessesforsale.com/search/Businesses-for-sale-in-South-Africa" time="2012-07-12-19:34" support="1" score="0.00045709999109554134" bingtitle="Businesses for sale in South Africa, buy a Business in South ..." webtitle="Businesses for sale in South Africa, buy a Business in South Africa on BusinessesForSale.com">
			<query id="001402" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>... network referenced supermarket, hypermarket and fast food restaurant (McDonald’s, Burger King…) register receipts. ... is part of an industry where over 400 million cups ...</description>
	<body>
		BusinessesForSale website uses cookies. To understand more about cookies and their benefits please see our Cookie Policy . By continuing to use this site you consent to our use of cookies on this device in accordance with our cookie policy.
 Choose country 
Choose your country

 Argentina France Mexico Spain Australia Germany New Zealand Sweden Brazil Greece Poland Thailand Bulgaria India Portugal UAE Canada Ireland Singapore UK China Israel South Africa USA Cyprus Malaysia 

Or view all businesses for sale

 Worldwide 
 
 Log in Help 
 Business for sale 
 Buy a Business 
 Advanced search Mid Market Register as a buyer Business resources Email alerts Business wanted Shortlist Services directory 
 Buy a Franchise 
 Browse franchise opportunities Franchise A-Z Franchise resales Advertise your franchise 
 Sell a Business 
 Create a business for sale advert Buyers seeking businesses Buyer leads by email preferences Prospect buyers shortlist 
 For Brokers 
 Buyers seeking businesses Services directory 
 
 
 
 This search: Save Get Email Alerts Clear Edit with advanced search 
 
 
 filter All Sectors (1327) filter (0) filter (0) 
 
 filter South Africa (1327) filter All Regions filter All States filter All Cities 
 
 
Businesses For Sale in South Africa

 Buy a Business in South Africa. Filter and sort your results by Date Listed, Asking Price, Turnover or Profit to see more Business opportunities in South Africa.
 
 If you are looking to sell your business, visit our selling a Business in South Africa section.
 (What is RSS?) 
 Results per page: 10 25 50 

 Sort by: Time: newly added/updated Asking Price: lowest first Asking Price: highest first Asking Price: newly reduced Sales Revenue: lowest first Sales Revenue: highest first Cash Flow: lowest first Cash Flow: highest first 
 
 Showing 1 - 10 of 1327 Businesses for sale in South Africa 

 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 NEXT 

 
 New 
 Sensory Motor Classes For Babies And Toddlers In Gauteng Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R605,000 Sales Revenue: Undeclared Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 Sensory motor classes for babies and toddlers
This business opportunity would be perfect for a person who loves to work with children (from tiny ones to toddlers) and lives on a big property in the n... 
See more businesses in:

 Child Care Nurseries in Gauteng Leisure Resale Franchises in Gauteng Health Care Businesses in Gauteng Children&apos;s Play Businesses in Gauteng 
 
 
 
 Afrikaans Educational Children&apos;s Video Production Company Pretoria, Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R160,000 Sales Revenue: Undeclared Cash Flow: Not Applicable 
 A high quality AFRIKAANS series of animated educational videos for kids aged 2 to 7 yrs. Episodes 1, 2 and 3 completed and ready for market. Described as &quot;propvol vermaak, fantasie en genot&quot;, each ep... 
See more businesses in:

 Film Businesses in Pretoria Miscellaneous TV, Audio, Video&amp;Photographic Businesses in Pretoria Miscellaneous Media Businesses in Pretoria 
 
 
 
 Popular And Successful Ladies Boutique On West Rand Krugersdorp, Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R300,000 Sales Revenue: R500k to R1.5m Cash Flow: R500k to R1.5m 
 Well known and established ladies clothing store with proven track record in busy centre. Business operating in area for 11 years. Solid monthly profit / income . No bad debts or debtors role. Perfect... 
See more businesses in:

 Ladies Wear Shops in Krugersdorp Miscellaneous Clothing Shops in Krugersdorp Fashion Accessory Businesses in Krugersdorp 
 
 
 
 Loan Origination Business Within South Africa And Africa South Africa 
 Asking Price: R350,000 Sales Revenue: R3m to R8m Cash Flow: R500k to R1.5m 
 Sole Trading Loan Origination Licenses available throughout South Africa assisting LSM 4 – 12 including poor and listed credit profiles accommodating commodity purchases through securing personal fina... 
See more businesses in:

 Credit and Finance Companies in South Africa Financial Related Businesses in South Africa Consultancy Businesses in South Africa 
 
 
 
 Stunning Vintage Styled Coffee And Clothing Shop Brackenfell, Western Cape 
 Asking Price: R99,999 Sales Revenue: R208,000 Cash Flow: R10,000 
 We have built this little empire and its now time to pass it on ! 
Our coffee/Clothing shop is now officially for sale. 
Hours was spent to make it the Jewel it is today . 
Our Shop is based in Bra... 
See more businesses in:

 Coffee Shops in Brackenfell Miscellaneous Clothing Shops in Brackenfell Party Stores in Brackenfell 
 
 How to Buy a Good Business at a Great Price Recommended by BusinessesForSale.com: 
100s of strategies&amp;techniques to help you find&amp;buy the right business. Click here for more 
 
 Successful Hair And Nail Salon In Pretoria Pretoria, Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R425,000 Sales Revenue: R100k to R500k Cash Flow: up to R100k 
 Successful Hair&amp;Nail Salon for sale thats been up and running for 5 years. Furniture, stock all inclusive.
5 Years basic clients, well known and established in a busy area.... 
See more businesses in:

 Hair and Beauty Salons in Pretoria 
 
 
 
 Successful Established National Online Franchise Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R650,000 Sales Revenue: R550,000 Cash Flow: R100k to R500k 
 A well-established national franchise for sale. Full financials available back to 2009. Work from home. Low overheads. Low risk - clients pay before any work commences. High profit margins. Full ... 
See more businesses in:

 Educational and School Related Businesses in Gauteng Miscellaneous Resale Franchises in Gauteng 
 
 
 
 Supermarket Franchise In Cape Town Northern Suburbs Cape Town, Western Cape 
 Asking Price: R9,000,000 Sales Revenue: R48,000,000 Cash Flow: R2,400,000 
 Operating from the same premises for over 20 years. Recently revamped, and all equipment upgraded. Experienced staff, and very loyal customer base.... 
See more businesses in:

 Supermarkets in Cape Town Food Resale Franchises in Cape Town Retail Resale Franchises in Cape Town 
 
 
 
 Very Successful Pet Grooming Parlour In Gauteng Centurion, Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R480,000 Sales Revenue: R500k to R1.5m Cash Flow: R10,000 
 Very successful newly established grooming parlour situated in a very upmarket area 2km from Midstream Estate Centurion, with over 8000 homes mostly being middle aged people with children and animals,... 
See more businesses in:

 Pet Grooming Businesses in Centurion 
 
 
 
 Upmarket DVD Franchise Store In Pretoria Pretoria, Gauteng 
 Asking Price: R145,000 Sales Revenue: Undeclared Cash Flow: Undeclared 
 This store belongs to the leading DVD rental Franchise in South Africa. It has great growth potential with a solid rental client database and a strong emerging market for the sale of DVD’s&amp;Games. Lo... 
See more businesses in:

 Video and DVD Rental Businesses in Pretoria Leisure Resale Franchises in Pretoria Retail Resale Franchises in Pretoria 
 
 
 Showing 1 - 10 of 1327 Businesses for sale in South Africa 

 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 NEXT 

 
Franchise Opportunities that match your search
 
 Bizzone Franchise 
 
At the Bizzone franchise, Sarah Trotman and her team have a passion and a vision for the business support sector. The goal of creating growth within this important sector is one inspired by our collaboration with business support organisations, their courageous vision stems from a genuine desire to make a difference to the big world of small to medium business.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 National Business Brokers Franchise 
 
National Business Brokers is a leading international franchise network of consultants specialised in Mergers and Acquisitions (M&amp;A), Business Brokerage and Corporate Finance. Currently we have partners in over 28 countries on 4 continents and are permanently looking for the best applicants for International Masters and Franchisees in any part of the world.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 Canas Y Tapas Franchise 
 
At the Canas Y Tapas franchise we are a real Spanish restaurant and bar, with authentic Spanish food served in a youthful, funny and different atmosphere. This is the formula that has made Cañas&amp;Tapas successful for over 5 years, and which has made us the undisputed leader in our sector in Spain.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 Activ Web Design franchise 
 
We know the Activ Web Design franchise is a unique opportunity to run your own web design business with NO ONGOING FEES, no technical knowledge needed and full technical support is provided.

 Request Information&gt;&gt; 

 
 See more franchises&gt;&gt; 
 
 Sector Sub Sector (optional) Category (optional) All Sectors (1327) 

 All Countries (59309) South Africa (1327) All Regions All States All Cities 
Filter your search

Age of Listing

 Anytime (1327) Last 3 Days (57) Last 14 Days (192) Last Month (352) Last 3 Months (710) 

Type of Business

 Real Property (189) Lease (548) Relocatable (362) Work From Home (150) Accommodation Included (50) Franchise (193) Price Reduced (102) Mid Market (42) In Receivership (1) Owner Financed (49) Unique (0) 
 
Asking Price (R)
 
 min: max: Disclosed Only 
 
Cash Flow (R)
 
 min: max: Disclosed Only 
 
Sales Revenue (R)
 
 min: max: Disclosed Only 
 
 
Start a new search
 
 
 
 
Buy a Business for sale in South Africa or find a Business Broker at BusinessesForSale.com. If you own a Business and are considering selling, visit our Sell a Business in South Africa section.
 
 Franchise Opportunities Acheter une Franchise Business Opportunities Blog Find a Business Opportunity Starting a Business 
 
 © 1997 - 2012 Dynamis Ltd 

 
 
BusinessesForSale website uses cookies. To understand more about cookies and their benefits please see our Cookie Policy . By continuing to use this site you consent to our use of cookies on this device in accordance with our cookie policy.
	</body>
</document>
