<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003355" url="http://blog.timesunion.com/tablehopping/author/stevebarnes/page/1095/" time="2012-07-12-19:30" support="1" score="0.0006046853271039943" bingtitle="Steve Barnes, senior writer - Table Hopping - Steve Barnes ..." webtitle="Steve Barnes, senior writer - Table Hopping - Steve Barnes - Restaurants and Dining Blog - timesunion.com - Albany NY">
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... Spears, who is depicted as working in a fast-food restaurant after ... family status, day and evening phone numbers and ... Links for Table Hopping. Albany County restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content ALL BLOGS | City Brights | Capitol Confidential | Crime Confidential | On the Edge | Table Hopping | The Advocate | The Buzz | Read&amp;React | Hot Topics 
 
 
 Table Hopping 
 Eat, drink and be candid By Steve Barnes | E-mail | About Table Hopping 
 
Posts by: Steve Barnes, senior writer
 
 Restaurant Week menus available 
 September 11, 2007 at 5:17 pm by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
 The 20 restaurants participating in downtown Albany’s next Restaurant Week, running Sept. 24-29, have posted their menus for the promotion. Find them here .

My quick glance turns up the following appetite-whetters: mozzarella and tomato bruschetta, stout-marinated grilled steak with shrimp scampi, and apple crisp, at Albany Pump Station; beet salad with Swiss chard, risotto with duck and mushrooms, and strawberry-glazed cheesecake, at Cafe Capriccio; and hubbard squash soup with foie gras butter, seared scallops with corn risotto, and chocolate mousse with berry compote, at Marché at 74 State.

The full list of restaurants: Mansion Hill Inn, Albany Pump Station, Amo La Bella, Bayou Café, Broadway Joe’s, Café Capriccio, Franklin’s Tower, Hudson Harbor Steak&amp;Seafood, Jack’s Oyster House, Jillian’s, Kelsey’s Irish Pub, La Serre, Marche at 74 State, McGeary’s, Nicole’s Bistro, Pagliacci Ristorante, Savannah’s, V&amp;R Restaurant, Victory Café and Webster’s Corner. Call each individually to make reservations (required). 

 This will be the seventh Restaurant Week since the BID began the effort in fall 2004. During the week, between 12,000 and 13,000 people visit downtown eateries for three-course meals costing $16.09, a price chosen to reflect the year Henry Hudson set foot in what is now Albany. 
 Posted in General , News , Restaurants/chefs | Add a comment 
 Chicks at the Scotia airport 
 September 11, 2007 at 4:49 pm by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
As in The Three Chicks, a restaurant, and the Mohawk Valley Airport, home to a skydiving school west of Scotia.

The restaurant, which shares the building with the airport, was the Big Boys and Lock 9 eateries in the past. It is the brainchild of business partners MaryRose Rostocki and Sue Wenner, who both have many years’experience in the restaurant industry.

The 50-seat Three Chicks serves breakfast, lunch and dinner seven days a week. The lunch menu features hot dogs, sandwiches, burgers and salads ($2.25 for grilled cheese to $6.95 for Cobb salad). Dinner offerings include basic pastas ($6.25-$9.45), turkey with stuffing, pork chops, grilled chicken and fried seafood ($6.95-$12.95).

The restaurant is open 6 a.m. to 8 p.m. daily. Reservations are accepted; call 892-0313. The address is 4281 Amsterdam Road (Route 5), between Scotia and the bridge over Lock 9 to Rotterdam Junction.

 Update : My parents stopped in for lunch today (9/13) and were impressed with the place’s portions, quality and prices.“It’s the first time I’ve never been able to finish a salad,”said my father. Both had Cobb salads ($6.95) and report that they’re stuffed with good romaine, moist chicken, eggs and abundant blue cheese. The folks say they’ll definitely go back for a Sunday breakfast.
 Posted in General , News , Restaurants/chefs | Add a comment 
 Friends Lake Inn wine dinner set 
 September 11, 2007 at 4:30 pm by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
Friends Lake Inn in Chestertown has announced the details of a dinner this weekend featuring wines from Standing Stone Vineyards in the Finger Lakes.

The six-course meal, with matching Standing Stone wines, is scheduled for 7:30 p.m. Friday (9/14). The cost is $85 per person, plus tax and tip. Reservations are required; call 494-4751.

The lineup:

 Pan-seared Hudson Valley foie gras, grilled pineapple marshmallow, reduction of muscat, golden raisin and brown sugar; Standing Stone vidal ice wine Reserve chardonnay sorbet with a Campari gelee Smoked oyster and ahi tuna tartare, passion fruit glaze, citrus-micro green salad; Standing Stone Smokehouse (dry vidal blanc) Nettle Meadow Kunik cheese, puff pastry, vanilla buerre blanc, caramelized pear and apple compote; Standing Stone Riesling 2006 Oven-roasted pheasant breast, duck confit, juniper berry demiglace, rose water, black barley, steamed purple cauliflower; Standing Stone gewurztraminer 2006 Orange sherbet baked Alaska, mango tea creme anglais; Standing Stone Cailloux (eight-grape ice wine) 
 Posted in General , News , Recommendations , Restaurants/chefs | Add a comment 
 Stories and supper 
 September 10, 2007 at 11:30 am by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
The Story Circle of the Capital District has announced the dates for its fall and spring Story Sundays at Glen Sanders Mansion in Scotia. The evening feature“splendid stories and fabulous food”from 5 to 8 p.m.

The series starts Sunday (9/16) with internationally acclaimed storyteller Elizabeth Ellis from Dallas. Ellis’program is titled”Stories from the Heart of the Matter.”

The Oct. 14 program:“Leaves, Loves and Lunacy: Tales to Fall Back On,”with the storytelling quartet Four Stories High (Jane Ainslie, Carol Connolly, Mary Murphy, and Barbara Palumbo).

Future dates are Dec. 2, Jan. 13, Feb. 10, March 9, April 6 and May 4.

The price is $27 per person. Available entrees for the three-course meal include London broil, chicken primavera and pasta with grilled vegetables.

To make a reservation (mandatory), call 384-1700 or e-mail sc@katedudding.com .
 Posted in Food/dining media , General , Musings , Restaurants/chefs | 2 Comments 
 Food bank fete set 
 September 10, 2007 at 11:12 am by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
The Regional Food Bank of Northeastern New York will host its 13th annual Chefs and Vintners Harvest Dinner on Thursday, Sept. 27, at Glen Sanders Mansion in Scotia.

The event begins with a 5:30 p.m. cocktail hour and food-demonstration tables, followed at 7 p.m. by a six-course meal prepared by area chefs using ingredients grown and produced in New York state, paired with state wines. The lineup is after the jump.

Because the dinner historically sells out its 350-person capacity in advance, early reservations are strongly recommended. Tickets cost $125 per person; call 786-3691 ext. 231.

Look in Thursday’s (9/13) paper for a special insert section, produced by the Times Union’s advertising department, in observance of the food bank’s 25th anniversary.

 (more…) 
 Posted in Food/dining media , General , News , Recommendations , Restaurants/chefs | Add a comment 
 Opening date set for P.F. Chang’s 
 September 7, 2007 at 11:57 am by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
 The area debut of the national chain P.F. Chang’s China Bistro happens Oct. 8, when the restaurant opens on the Wolf Road side of Colonie Center mall.

Check out the menu here .
 Posted in General , News , Restaurants/chefs | 9 Comments 
 Food Network says‘Arrivederci’to Mario—or not 
 September 6, 2007 at 2:07 pm by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
This is dismaying: The New York Post is reporting that Mario Batali has been let go by the Food Network, where he’s been a fixture for 11 years.

According to the report, Batali was told his shows, including the long-running“Molto Mario,”weren’t being renewed, so Batali refused to return to“Iron Chef America.”

Booooooo.

 Update : Thanks to the commenter below, who links to a TV Guide story. TV Guide, unlike the New York Post, went to the sources—Batali and the Food Network:
 
“Not true!”Batali tells TV Guide emphatically.“I’m taping two episodes of Iron Chef America in a few weeks. I’m the best Iron Chef, why would I quit? And why would I threaten the network? Molto Mario ’s been out of production for two-and-a-half years. [Reruns still air weekly.] We have a fine relationship.”

A channel spokesperson backs him up:“Mario is still a major part of the Food Network family,”she says.
 
Booooooo on the New York Post!
 Posted in Food/dining media , General , News , Restaurants/chefs | 10 Comments 
 Ladies’night or happy hunting? 
 September 6, 2007 at 12:54 pm by Steve Barnes, senior writer 
 I was entertained by the parenthetical at the end of this item in Tavern Times, an e-newsletter from Wayne Beale , who owns the Rusty Nail and Bentley’s taverns in Saratoga County.
 
The April 26 Ladies’Night at Bentley’s Tavern was such a smashing success that we’re planning one at Rusty Nail Grill and Tavern. The Nail’s Ladies’Night will be Thursday, Sept. 27, from 8-11 p.m. Outta Hand Band starts playing at 9 p.m. Swing by to check out our drink specials, unusual shopping opportunities (unique jewelry, handbags and facial products) and door prizes. (Guys: this is the perfect night to meet women if you don’t mind watching the Lifetime or Oxygen channels.)
 
The Rusty Nail Grill&amp;Tavern is located at 1781 Route 9, Clifton Park; Bentley’s Tavern, at Parade Ground Village (4 Hemphill Place), Malta.

Beale’s third neighborhood tavern, The Mill on Round Lake, at 2121 Route 9, was scheduled to open in August. According to the newsletter,“Challenges such as obtaining an En Con permit have prevented us from setting a grand opening date.”

The new place was formerly The Red Mill and, most recently, Arlene and Bob’s Country Inn.
 Posted in Food/dining media , General , Musings , News , Recommendations , Restaurants/chefs | Add a comment Page 1,095 of 1,158 « First ... « Previous 1,093 1,094 1,095 1,096 1,097 Next » ... Last » 
 
 Ads by Yahoo! Posts | Comments Log in 
The A-List Business Directory

 Search for restaurants and other businesses in the Capital Region:
 • Browse the listings 
 
Recent Comments

 Report: Dinosaur eyeing Buffalo location  ( 17 ) 
 hotrod107 : #3 nick, what you fail to realize is john stage is a figure head. his majority share was purchased by... 
 Jamaican restaurant coming to Morton Ave. in Albany  ( 6 ) 
 julie : I know everyone hears Morton Ave and/or the B&amp;B bar and thinks the worst, but it has gotten somewhat... Woodrow : Another new Jamaican restaurant is now open. Some young guys were walking the streets, handing out menus for... 
 Man accidentally eats steel grill brush bristle  ( 11 ) 
 ifeedkids : I once had a dream that I was eating giant marshmallows. When I woke up, all my pillows were gone. 
 Flying Chicken opens in downtown Troy  ( 14 ) 
 colleen (with a little c) : yup all those yelp reviews are what i like to call“rubber chickens”plopped... 
 Patio party Saturday at Sperry’s  ( 2 ) 
 CL : Bad move, I miss Frank too. 
 Miyako in Guilderland has closed  ( 19 ) 
 KR : I ate there right before they closed and the owners said that they were moving to a smaller location in Troy,... 
 
 
Categories

 Contests/giveaways Dining deals Food/dining media General Mother&apos;s Day 2012 Musings News Q&amp;A Recommendations Restaurants/chefs 
 
 
Archives

 ▼  2012  (993)
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 
 ►  2011  (2010)
 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 
 ►  2010  (1941)
 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 
 ►  2009  (2014)
 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 
 ►  2008  (1498)
 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 
 ►  2007  (738)
 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 
 ►  2006  (70)
 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 
 
 
 
Latest Table Hopping columns

 Mulling the morality, politics of foie-gras ban Driving diners to Central Avenue In search of the new Memories of good time roll on World of flavors at GlobalCafe 
 ...more columns 
 
Pages

 What makes a critic? About Table Hopping 
 
 
 
Links for Table Hopping

 Albany County restaurant inspections site Albany Eats! All Over Albany Cooking classes/food calendar derryX Docsconz—The Blog Drinking New York by Bill Dowd FUSSYlittleBLOG Healthy-Delicious blog Matt Baumgartner&apos;s blog Recipe Box Ridiculous Food Society Times Union restaurant reviews Vinoteca
	</body>
</document>
