<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003656" url="http://thepaleodiet.com/testimonials" time="2012-07-12-19:49" support="4" score="0.007513743842102573" bingtitle="Testimonials | The Paleo Diet" webtitle="Testimonials | The Paleo Diet">
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="182"/>
	<description>Dr. Loren Cordain is a member of the faculty of the Department of Health and Exercise Science at Colorado State University. During the past two decades he has ...</description>
	<body>
		search 
 
 Home About 
 Profile 
 Paleo Book Store&amp;More 
 The Paleo Answer The Paleo Diet (Revised) The Paleo Diet Cookbook The Paleo Diet for Athletes Dietary Cure for Acne Book Acne Products MS Products Papers Paleo Diet Newsletters 
 Nutritional Tools 
 Body Mass Index Nutrient Composition Fats and Fatty Acids (A Primer) 
 Fatty Acid Content of Refined Vegetable Oils Fatty Acid Content of Nuts Fatty Acid Content of Seeds 
 Omega 3 Fats: Fish Fruits and Sugars Carbs&amp;Glycemic Index Acid / Base Balance 
 Public Speaking Published Research Newsletter 
 Newsletter Back Issues 
 FAQ Contact 
 
 Testimonials 
 
We love hearing from our satisfied customers.

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Acne&amp;Skin

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Asthma

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Athletes

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Autoimmune Disease

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Diabetes

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Fitness

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Inflammation, Arthritis, and Joints

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Menstrual Cramps

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Miscellaneous

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Menstrual Cramps

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Prader-Willi Syndrome

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
Weight Loss and More Energy

 View Testimonials▼ 
 
 about us 
 
 
Dr. Loren Cordain is a member of the faculty of the Department of Health and Exercise Science at Colorado State University.

During the past two decades he has researched the effects of diet on human health and specifically examined links between modern diets and disease. He is the author of numerous scientific articles examining the link between diet and health, and has published three popular books, The Paleo Diet, The Paleo Diet for Athletes, and The Dietary Cure for Acne. Additional information and specifics may be found in the articles, books, and materials listed on this web site, and through The Paleo Diet.

 
 random posts 
 Dr. Cordain’s Rebuttal to PSU Student’... Old genes, new fuels: Nutritional changes since ag... Cordain L, Toohey L, Smith MJ, Hickey MS. Modulati... The Paleo Diet Cookbook O’Keefe JH, Vogel R, Lavie CJ, Cordain L. Ac... Hunter Gatherer Energy Expenditure 
 recent comments 
 
 Debra : I have a fairly severe form of psoriatic arthritis. The infl... Rena : Dr. Cordain, thank you for this vital information. I am also... Rachel Rubinger : I am 33 and understand the frustration with feeling &quot;out of ... Norma : You could check out &apos;Mark&apos;s Daily Apple&apos;

 http://www.mark... Margie Roberts : I was diag., w/RA 16 yrs., ago. Always had gut prob., diag.... Mark : Hi. My wife has fibromyalgia and UCTD. I&apos;ve helped her diet ... 
 ©Copyright 2010-2012 The Paleo Diet / Flash Buddy :: All rights reserved.
Powered by Quick Colorado :: WordPress Theme created by Flash Buddy .
	</body>
</document>
