<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003569" url="http://www.wikihow.com/Evaluate-a-Restaurant" time="2012-07-12-19:44" support="2" score="0.0020964867592741685" bingtitle="How to Evaluate a Restaurant - wikiHow" webtitle="How to Evaluate a Restaurant - wikiHow">
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>If making reservations, are they quick to pick up ... Are you served your order? Is the food served the ... Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant: Get Served Quickly at the Bar</description>
	<body>
		the how to manual that you can edit 
 Sign Up or Log In or Log In via 
 Follow us on Pinterest 
 Home Articles Community My Profile Edit 
 Home » Categories » Food and Entertaining » Dining Out 
 
 How to Evaluate a Restaurant 

Edited by Carolyn Barratt and 5 others 
 Pin It Article Edit Discuss History 
The pastime of eating out at restaurants is enjoyed by a wide variety of persons, young and old, from different walks of life. But of course, not every restaurant has the mass appeal - for reasons other than just the food! If you&apos;re a picky eater, this article will help you choose a good eatery - that is, if you ever had trouble finding good spots to recommend to friends. 
 
 Edit Steps 
 
There are many types of restaurants - some fast food, others fine dining, still others casual dining and so on. Each kind offers a different type of service or cuisine, and may attract different clientele based on those. Whatever the restaurant, however, there are some main things to look for in a good restaurant. Four are listed below:

 1 Atmosphere/Ambiance - As you step into the restaurant, what is the feeling you get ? Is it neat, comfortable, elegant, accommodating? Your first impression can be very telling about the restaurant. After all, if you plan to spend at least 20 minutes sitting somewhere eating, you should feel comfortable, right? 2 Cleanliness - Does the restaurant appear clean ? Do you find yourself wiping the seats and perhaps the table before you sit down? Do you find yourself even judging where to sit, and not because of the view? 3 Service - Were the servers pleasant, communicative, efficient, knowledgeable ? This makes for a very high percentage of the dining experience. 4 Food - Of course, this may arguably be the most important part of eating out . But how does it look? How is it presented? How does it taste? And how much does it cost? 

 
 
 Edit Tips 
 
 

 Cleanliness 

 Check the bathroom. It is the most revealing factor of a restaurant&apos;s hygiene habits. If it doesn&apos;t look suitable - and it&apos;s in public view - consider the kitchen where your food is being prepared! Check the floor. Is the floor clean? is there evidence of pests or rodents on the floor are anywhere? Observe the servers. Do the servers themselves look clean and tidy? If they do not take much pride in their own appearance, then most likely, little care will be taken in your food! Are there any offensive odours in the restaurant? This is usually a red flag that things are not properly regulated. Note the silverware, glasses and plates/food containers. Are they clean? Also, note the tables and chairs for cleanliness. 

 

 Atmosphere/Ambiance 

 Observe the decor in the restaurant. Is it attractive and appealing? Are the tables and chairs comfortable and neatly arranged? If there are plants and/or flowers used in the decor, are they fresh? Is there any artwork to lift the appearance and create a warm, exotic, or ethnic feel, etc. Check the lighting. is it suitable for the restaurant? Too dark? Too bright? Note the temperature. Is it too hot? Perhaps too cold? Once again, check the servers. Are they neatly dressed to complement the atmosphere of the restaurant? Do they seem warm and accommodating? 

 

 Service 

 If making reservations, are they quick to pick up the phone? Do they respond in a courteous and professional tone? Do they listen to you and your needs, or do they interrupt you to give you a standard line, like &quot;Seating can be arranged between 2:00pm and 9:00pm&quot;? If fine dining, note how you are greeted. Are you greeted at the door? How long do you wait on an available table? Do they compensate for long waiting by offering an appetizer or drink, etc.? Note your servers. Are the servers professional? Are they also polite, or do they seem annoyed, impatient, pushy, sarcastic, or just plain unpleasant? Does the server attempt to answer any questions you may ask, and if the answer is not known to them, do they seek to find out and quickly return to answer you? Note the time it takes for your food to get to you. Is the food cold by the time it gets to you? Are the waiters/waitresses communicative about any delays in the meals, or do they simply leave you to wait? Check your food. Are you served your order? Is the food served the exact way you want it, down to the &quot;gravy on the rice only&quot; or &quot;sandwich cut in two with lettuce, tomato and extra mayo on the side&quot;? If you have a comment or complaint, does the server listen keenly and act accordingly? Does the server apologise for any mistakes or shortcomings and try to appropriately make amends? 

 

 Food 

 Check the other persons dining around you. How are they responding to their meals eaten? If you spot someone with your dish of choice, is it presented in a similar attractive manner? Check out your menu. Are the prices reasonable, given the surroundings, service and dish? Do the choices seen well balanced to put things together for a meal? Is there a wide variety available for persons with different tastes, e.g. vegetarian options, weight watchers options, etc.? How is your food presented? Does your food look and smell appetizing? Does it look fresh? Does it look mediocre or sloppy? Does it smell offensive? (Note, sniffing food in public is considered bad manners to many people. A good suggestion is to simply take a small whiff as the food passes your nose and heads to the counter or table.) Note the food as you take your first bite, or sip. Does the food taste good? Great? Mediocre? Terrible? Bland? Does it taste like something you could have easily made at home, or does it taste like something &apos;extra&apos;? How is the texture of the food? Does the texture of the protein vary from the starch and the vegetables, or is everything one uniform mush? Is the food undercooked, overcooked, underseasoned, undersalted or oversalted, too sweet, too sour, too spicy or too fresh? Do you long to eat more of the food? With these tips in mind when eating out, you can develop your own personal rating scale of any restaurant you find yourself dining in. Of course, good restaurants will generally have good ratings across the span of customers! Best of all, if you own a restaurant and these points are up to par, you will see flocks of customers in a really short time! Also, as a diner, you will be able to find a few really good gems of restaurants worth telling your friends about and visiting again and again! Happy eating!!! 
 

 
Articles for You to Write
 Here is a list of suggested articles that have not yet been written. You can help by researching and writing one of these articles. To get started writing one of these articles, click on the red link of a title below.


 How to Evaluate Service in a Restaurant 
 
Article Info
 
Last edited:
 August 16, 2011 by Maluniu 

Categories:
 Dining Etiquette | Dining Out 

Recent edits by: BR , Scarlet.pirate , DifuWu ( see all )
 
Article Tools
 Share this Article: Tweet 
 
 Discuss Print Email Edit Send fan mail to authors 
 + Embed this: Republish this entire article on your blog or website. 


 Thanks to all authors for creating a page that has been read 4,424 times. 
 
Was this article accurate?

 Yes No 
 

 Write An Article Random Article Follow wikiHow on facebook 
Related Articles

 Eat with Chopsticks Turn Down a Drink Seat Dinner Guests Navigate a Wine Festival 
 
 Featured Articles 

 Curb Your Addiction to News Make a Baby Sling Teach Kids to Garden Recognize a Potentially Abusive Relationship 
 
Meet a Community Member
 
Meet You Might Be Giants , an editor from Colorado who joined over two years ago. In that time he&apos;s started over 40 articles and made nearly 5,000 edits. He likes starting articles about the human condition and patrolling recent changes . When asked why he&apos;s stuck around wikiHow for so long, he says contributing to this site has matured him as a writer and editor.
 
 Join The Community 
 
 - collapse Things to Do 

 Write an Article Edit this Article Request a New Article Answer a Request Login for more! 

 + expand Places to Visit 

 Recent Changes Forums Community Portal 
 
Follow Us On...

 
 
 
the how to manual that you can edit

 Home About wikiHow Terms of Use RSS Site map 
 

Explore Categories
 
 Arts and Entertainment Cars and Other Vehicles Computers and Electronics Education and Communications Family Life Finance and Business Food and Entertaining Health Hobbies and Crafts Holidays and Traditions Home and Garden Other Personal Care and Style Pets and Animals Philosophy and Religion Relationships Sports and Fitness Travel wikiHow Work World Youth 
 All text shared under a Creative Commons License . Powered by Mediawiki. 
 x 
Thank Our Volunteer Authors.

Give this article a +1.
	</body>
</document>
