<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003537" url="http://www.dimensionsguide.com/energy-bars-dimensions/" time="2012-07-12-19:40" support="1" score="0.0007400626391422019" bingtitle="Energy Bars Dimensions | Dimensions Guide" webtitle="Dimensions InfoEnergy Bars Dimensions">
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>How Big is a Harley Davidson? 7 Eleven Cup Sizes ... brands in the food industry as well as a good number ... The Average Size for a Fast Food Restaurant can be anywhere from ...</description>
	<body>
		Because Size Matters
 

 
Energy Bars Dimensions
 
Energy bars are called as such because they provide you with a boost in energy whenever you take them. A single bar is packed with energy-giving ingredients that readily get you energized as you go about your daily routine.

These are also compact in size so you can easily slip them into your purse, bag or even pocket to keep them handy. Energy Bars Dimensions usually come in measurements of 5.5 inches by 4.5 inches by 10 inches.

In terms of grams, standard weights are between 60 grams and 65 grams; while a mini energy bar weighs just around 30 grams per bar.

However, no matter what Energy Bars Dimensions you get, you will be sure to get an instant energy boost when you take any one of these energy bars available in the market today.

What Goes Into Energy Bars?

Energy bars contain several high-energy ingredients that can easily pick-up your sagging energy as you go about your daily duties. Since these are packed with energy-boosting components whatever the Energy Bars Dimensions, a lot of people take these bars particularly those who do not have the time to prepare regular meals during the day.

Oats or cereals, rice crisps, nuts and seeds are usually found in energy bars. To give consumers good taste variations, these bars may contain fruits, honey, and chocolate, among others.

Standard Energy Bars Dimensions, which are around 60 to 65 grams, contain approximately two hundred and thirty kilocalories. Usual calorie content per 65-grams bar is around forty-five grams, protein is around ten grams and fat is approximately only at two grams per bar.

In terms of Energy Bars Dimensions for the mini bars, average kilocalories are at 108.

What Energy Bars are Available Today?

There are actually a good number of energy bars now being sold in the market today. These are made by some of the leading brands in the food industry as well as a good number of energy food and drinks manufacturers worldwide.

Among these energy bars are Mule Bar, which comes in two Energy Bars Dimensions, the standard size and a mini; Balance Nutrition and Energy Bars, Power Bar Performance Bars, Maxim Energy Bars and High5 Energy Bar.

You can find all of these energy bars plus all the other available bars right on the internet. These are usually sold in boxes of eight, twelve, and twenty-four; depending on the brand and the supplier.

You may also find more information about the nutrition content of each bar and their ingredients so you can also check if any of these contain ingredients that you may be allergic to.
 
 Tags: dimensions energy bars food snack 
 Food and Drinks No comments 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

 

 
 
No related posts.
 
 Search for: 
Categories

 Business Cars and Vehicle Clothes and Fashion Computers and Internet DIY and Construction Entertainment and Sport Food and Drinks Health and Beauty Home and Furniture Nature Pets and Animals Places and Events Recreation Reference Seasonal Sports Tools Travel What is Hot 
 
Recent Posts

 Bike Sizes Cyclocross Bed Sizes for RVs Belvedere Vodka Bottle Sizes Beer Keg Sizes Canada Truck Bed Dimensions of a Chevy Avalanche 
 
Recent Comments

 mike on 20ft Container Size William F. L. Burgess on What are the Sizes of Barbells? aangela on Size of a Beakers Edwin Sharp on Interior Door Sizes . on Smallest House 
 
 



 

 Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
