<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003891" url="http://commonlaw.findlaw.com/food_and_drink/" time="2012-07-12-20:03" support="1" score="0.0016182106456044743" bingtitle="FindLaw&apos;s Common Law: Food and Drink" webtitle="FindLaw&apos;s Common Law: Food and DrinkFindLaw&apos;s Common Law">
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>And it&apos;s not just refined table sugar, the consumption of which has actually ... also attractive because it does not contain the sugar found in energy and soft drinks.</description>
	<body>
		FindLaw |
Find a Lawyer. Find Answers.
 
 
Are you a legal Professional?
 Visit our professional site 
 Learn about law firm marketing 
 Learn About the Law Find a Lawyer FindLaw Answers Forms&amp;Store News Commentary 
 Search 
 
 FindLaw&apos;s Common Law 

Legal news you can use from FindLaw.com. Updated each weekday.



 
July 2012
 
 Sun Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri Sat 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31         
 
FindLaw Blogs

 FindLaw Blotter 
 Free Enterprise 
 Injured 
 Law&amp;Daily Life 

 
Bookshelf
 
 Full-text books you can read for free on FindLaw:
 ABA Family Legal Guide 
 ABA Guide to Marriage, Divorce&amp;Families 
 ABA Guide to Wills&amp;Estates 
 Consumer Action Handbook 
 Disability Rights Laws 
 Don&apos;t Get Taken! Protect Yourself Legally Against Common Abuses and Rip-Offs 
 Social Security Handbook 
 The Working Woman&apos;s Legal Survival Guide 
 From Hiring To Firing: The Legal Survival Guide for Employers 
 
 
If you&apos;re looking for information on common law marriage , please visit the Common Law Marriage section on FindLaw.
 
 Is NYC&apos;s Proposed Ban on Big Sugary Drinks Legal? 
 
Mayor Michael Bloomberg has plans to introduce a sugary drink ban in New York City and, as predicted, the industry is not happy. The proposed NYC sugary drink ban would prohibit food service establishments from selling sugar-laden beverages that contain more than 25 calories per 8 fluid ounces.

If approved by the Board of Health, restaurants , corner bodegas and even movie theatres will need to cut down on the size of their sugary drinks. Grocery and convenience stores will be the only places to purchase oversized soft drinks.

The fearful need to keep in mind that the NYC sugary drink ban does not cover diet sodas, fruit juices or dairy-based drinks. It also doesn&apos;t prohibit the purchase of two drinks or refills, reports The New York Times. Patrons will just need to drink 3 small cups of soda instead of 1.

Despite this reassurance, some are probably still scratching their heads and wondering how such a law can be legal. The reason is a bit complicated.

Under the U.S. Constitution, local governments are given a significant amount of leeway when it comes to matters of health, morality and safety. States and cities have successfully banned synthetic marijuana, trans fat in restaurant food, shark fin soup and foie gras.

Such prohibitions are usually upheld unless they discriminate against out-of-state businesses or between products without a valid reason to do so. Arguably, there&apos;s a good reason to allow diet, milk and juice beverages while banning other large sugary drinks. They have less calories and provide some nutrition.

Nonetheless, if the NYC sugary drink ban comes to fruition, there&apos;s a good chance someone will sue. People want the government out of their stomachs and companies want to sell their goods.

Related Resources:

 NYC mayor proposes ban on sugary drinks larger than 16 ounces (CBS News) What California&apos;s Trans Fat Ban Teaches Us About Federalism (FindLaw&apos;s Writ) Don&apos;t Pass the Salt! NYC Mayor Calls for Salt Reduction (FindLaw&apos;s Legally Weird) 
 
 May 31, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : drink ban , mayor bloomberg , new york city , sugar 
 
 Radioactive Bluefin Tuna from Japan Caught Off California 
 
Low levels of radioactive compounds have been detected in bluefin tuna off the California coast .

Cesium-137 and cesium-134 were found in 15 tuna captured near San Diego last August, Reuters reports. Scientists believe the fish carried the radioactive materials from the Fukushima nuclear power plant in Japan. The chemicals were released into the waters along the country&apos;s eastern coast following the tsunami last year.

So how bad is the radiation?

Apparently, it&apos;s still below the Japanese safety limit, according to lead author Daniel Madigan of Stanford University&apos;s Hopkins Marine Station. However, he wouldn&apos;t say whether the fish was or wasn&apos;t safe to eat.

&quot;It&apos;s become clear that some people feel that any amount of radioactivity, in their minds, is bad and they&apos;d like to avoid it,&quot;Madigan said.&quot;But compared to what&apos;s there naturally ... and what&apos;s established as safety limits, it&apos;s not a large amount at all.&quot;

Though some cesium-137 is naturally found in bluefin tuna, the amount discovered in the fish in the study was five times the usual amount. On the other hand, cesium-134 is made only through human activities, such as nuclear power.

Bluefin tuna is sold all over the world, including in America. While the amount is reportedly still within Japanese safety limits, if people here get sick from eating it, a product liability lawsuit could be possible . In such situations, all retailers and companies in the chain of distribution could be held legally responsible.

But perhaps the most disturbing revelation uncovered in the study is that the bluefin tuna transported the radioactive materials faster than water and wind.

Related Resources:

 Radioactive Bluefin Tuna Crossed the Pacific to U.S. (Chicago Sun-Times) &apos;Radioactive Man&apos;Pulled Over by Conn. Police (FindLaw Blotter) Government Owes Damages in Spent Nuclear Fuel Litigation (FindLaw&apos;s Federal Circuit) What to Do After Food Poisoning (FindLaw&apos;s Injured) 
 
 May 30, 2012 in Food and Drink , Legal Topic: Products Liability Law | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : cesium-134 , cesium-137 , Fukushima nuclear power plant , product liability , radiation food poisoning , radioactive bluefin tuna , tsunami fallout 
 
 Drinking Energy Drinks is Like &apos;Bathing Teeth With Acid,&apos; Dentists Say 
 
Sports drinks -- and especially energy drinks -- are so acidic, they can cause irreversible damage to teeth in as little as five days, a new study by dentists finds.

&quot;Young adults consume these drinks assuming ... that they are &apos;better&apos; for them than soda,&quot; the study&apos;s lead author said in a statement. But &quot;these drinks are essentially bathing their teeth with acid.&quot;

Researchers looked at acid levels in 13 sports drinks and nine energy drinks. They submerged human tooth enamel in each drink for 15 minutes, then in artificial saliva for two hours, to try to simulate how the drinks are consumed. Researchers repeated the tests four times a day over five days.

Results showed irreversible damage to tooth enamel with all drinks they tested. But energy drinks caused twice as much damage as sports drinks, the dentists&apos; study found.

Damage to tooth enamel can make teeth overly sensitive, and more susceptible to cavities and tooth decay, researchers said.

To prevent those consequences, dentists recommend:

 Cutting back on sports and energy drinks. About 30% to 50% of U.S. teenagers consume energy drinks, and 62% consume at least one sports drink a day, according to the Academy of General Dentistry.

 Lowering the acidity levels in your mouth after consuming a sports or energy drink -- by rinsing your mouth with water, or chewing sugar-free gum that can get your saliva flowing.

 Waiting at least one hour before brushing your teeth after consuming a sports or energy drink. Brushing sooner could spread the acid and cause more damage to your teeth, dentists warn.

But critics challenged the study&apos;s real-life application . No one holds energy drinks &quot;in their mouths for 15 minute intervals over five day periods,&quot; the American Beverage Association said, according to CBS News.

The dentists&apos; energy and sports drink study appears in the May/June issue of General Dentistry .

Related Resources:

 Energy Drinks Can Take Teeth On An Irreversible Acid Trip (NPR) Monster Energy Drink: Mouse Suit a &apos;Shakedown&apos; (FindLaw&apos;s Injured) Four Loko&apos;s Alcohol Content Will be on Can Label (FindLaw&apos;s Injured) You Can&apos;t Handle The Tooth! Kid&apos;s Toothbrush Law in MA (FindLaw&apos;s Legally Weird) 
 
 May 08, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : acid , cavities , dentists , energy drinks , sports drinks , study , tooth decay , tooth enamel 
 
 Nutella Lawsuit: Company to Pay Up Over Misleading Advertising 
 
It looks like the Nutella lawsuit will finally be paying off for some customers. Ferrero, the company that makes the chocolate-hazelnut spread, has settled the misleading ad lawsuit for $3 million .

As part of the agreement, any customers who bought Nutella between January 1, 2008 and February 3, 2012 will be able to request a refund for up to five jars. For California customers, the purchase window is between August 1, 2009 and January 23, 2012.

But the fun doesn&apos;t end there. Ferrero will also have to make some changes to its iconic packaging.

Nutella labels will no longer say the product is&quot;An example of a tasty yet balanced breakfast.&quot;The line has been on the jar&apos;s back panel for years.

The class action lawsuit was filed by two San Diego mothers. They claimed Nutella deceived customers into thinking the product was healthy. They cited Nutella&apos;s website and commercials as examples of the company&apos;s false advertising.

The ads depict a mother giving her children toast and fruit covered in Nutella.

Typically, many class action lawsuits result in more than payouts. Parties often agree to limit or change their practices. Ferrero&apos;s case is no different.

While it&apos;s hard to imagine that anyone could be duped into thinking dumping chocolate on bread is healthy, Ferrero has agreed to remove the offending ads.

As part of the Nutella lawsuit, the company has also set up a Website to process claims . So if you bought Nutella during the time period stated above, fill out the online form to get your refund. And don&apos;t worry about receipts either. You won&apos;t need to send any to get your money back.

Related Resources:

 Two SD Moms Win Nutella Lawsuit (NBC San Diego) Mom Sues Nutella for Being&apos;Next Best Thing to a Candy Bar&apos; (FindLaw&apos;s Common Law) When to Opt-Out of Class Action and Go to Small Claims (FindLaw&apos;s Law&amp;Daily Life) 
 
 May 02, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : class action settlements , Ferrero , misleading advertisement , Nutella lawsuit , San Diego 
 
 Salmonella in Sushi Sickens Women for 6 Weeks 
 
The sushi-linked Salmonella outbreak that led to a nationwide recall has spawned its first lawsuit, which details two victims&apos;slow and painful road to recovery.

Two Wisconsin women, 22 and 33, claim they were victims of Salmonella poisoning when they ate tuna rolls at a local restaurant, MSNBC reports.

The rolls were distributed by California-based Moon Marine USA, which has recalled 59,000 pounds of ground yellowfin tuna allegedly linked to a nationwide Salmonella outbreak. The outbreak has sickened more than 140 people in 20 states and the District of Columbia, according to MSNBC.

At least a dozen people have sought treatment at hospitals, including the Wisconsin women who filed suit against Moon Marine last week. The company did not respond to MSNBC&apos;s request for a comment.

The women claim they ate Salmonella-contaminated sushi about six to nine weeks ago. One victim complained of pain&quot;from head to toe,&quot;along with bloody diarrhea; a hospital exam also revealed an ulcerated colon, she told MSNBC.

Scientific tests show the victims were sickened by a rare type of bacteria called Salmonella Bareilly, which is not usually associated with fish, the women&apos;s lawyer said. Investigations are underway to determine where bacteria came from.

The women&apos;s Salmonella sushi lawsuit focuses on a product called&quot;Nakaochi Scrape&quot;-- meat that&apos;s taken off fish bones and later added to raw, ground yellowfin tuna, MSNBC reports.

&quot;The problem is this product got repackaged and resold,&quot;one of the women&apos;s lawyers said.&quot;There are sushi restaurants that may not even know they&apos;re serving this tuna.&quot;

Salmonella infections generally lead to diarrhea, fever, and abdominal cramps within 72 hours, according to the FDA. Victims usually recover after about a week, but severe cases may require medical treatment.

Consumers who may be affected by the Salmonella sushi outbreak should consult a doctor, the FDA advises. Medical bills and treatment can also be used to prove damages in a food-poisoning lawsuit ; such cases generally fall under product liability laws.

Related Resources:

 Women sue firm over salmonella outbreak (Milwaukee Journal Sentinel) Types of Food Poisoning: Salmonella (FindLaw) Food Poisoning Illness FAQ (FindLaw) Food Poisoning: What Are Your Rights? (FindLaw&apos;s Injured) 
 
 April 26, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : food poisoning , lawsuit , Moon Marine , Nakaochi Scrape , outbreak , recall , Salmonella , sushi , yellowfin tuna 
 
 What is Mad Cow Disease? 
 
Just when you thought consuming pink slime was the worst thing about eating American beef, mad cow disease suddenly decides to stage a comeback.

Following an investigation of a cow that died suddenly in California, the USDA has announced the bovine&apos;s death was caused by mad cow disease. The discovery marks the first U.S. case of mad cow disease since 2006, the Seattle Post Intelligencer reports.

So what does this revelation mean to consumers and what can mad cow disease do to you? Surprisingly, the answer is a mix of good and bad.

Known formally as bovine spongiform encephalopathy , mad cow disease is a neurological disorder that attacks a cow&apos;s brain and spine. It&apos;s caused by a protein called prion, which gets stuck in the cattle&apos;s spinal tissue and brain.

Humans can contract the disease by eating tainted beef. The disorder attacks a person&apos;s body in much the same way as it does to cattle. Symptoms include disorientation, hallucination, speech impairment, and loss of coordination. These symptoms become progressively worse over time.

Unfortunately, there&apos;s no treatment for humans or cows. Victims can die within months after infection.

Previous outbreaks were controlled by destroying tainted cattle. Britain did this in the 1990s.

Fortunately though, this most recent case is only the fourth to be discovered in America. Furthermore, the investigation also revealed the dead cow contracted the disease by way of a random genetic mutation. Not through feeding.

This is good news for American beef eaters as it means none of the other cattle in the food supply currently pose the risk of infection.

There have been very few product liability lawsuits based on mad cow disease in America. However, if an outbreak were to occur, every tainted beef producer and retailer in the chain of distribution could be liable for the fallout.

Luckily, this latest report of mad cow disease appears to be an isolated incident. Beef, for now, remains safe to eat, according to the Department of Food and Agriculture.

Related Resources:

 Mad Cow Disease Confirmed in California Dairy Cow, USDA Says (The Huffington Post) First Salmonella Sushi Lawsuit Filed (FindLaw&apos;s Injured) What is Product Liability? (FindLaw) 
 
 April 26, 2012 in California , Food and Drink , Legal Topic: Products Liability Law | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : bovine spongiform encephalopathy , California , mad cow disease , product liability , tainted beef , USDA 
 
 Yellowfin Tuna Recalled After Sushi Salmonella Outbreak 
 
The cause behind the countrywide reports of sushi-related salmonella poisoning might have finally been found. A Cupertino, Calif. company has issued a voluntary recall of yellowfin tuna .

Moon Marine USA Corporation is flagging 59,000 pounds of frozen yellowfin tuna for the recall. The salmonella outbreak has sickened 116 people across 20 states. No deaths have been reported, but 12 people have been hospitalized, CBS News reports.

But which states have been affected so far by the salmonella outbreak?

The Food and Drug Administration has gotten reports of poisoning in Alabama (2), Arkansas (1), Connecticut (5), District of Columbia (2), Florida (1), Georgia (5), Illinois (10), Louisiana (2), Maryland (11), Massachusetts (8), Mississippi (1), Missouri (2), New Jersey (7), New York (24), North Carolina (2), Pennsylvania (5), Rhode Island (5), South Carolina (3), Texas (3), Virginia (5), and Wisconsin (12).

The recalled frozen yellowfin is sold to restaurants and grocery stores nationwide under the name&quot;Nakaochi Scrape AA or AAA.&quot;In addition to sushi, yellowfin is often used in ceviche, sashimi and other raw dishes.

 Salmonella poisoning can last between four to seven days. Symptoms include fever, abdominal cramps, and diarrhea. Most people can recover without treatment. But in cases where the diarrhea is severe, hospitalization may be required. In some people, long-term effects such as joint pain, eye irritation, and painful urination can develop.

There&apos;s no word yet of any legal action, but sushi salmonella poisoning on this scale could serve as the basis for a products liability lawsuit. Under this cause of action, the manufacturer and any retailers and restaurants that sold the recalled yellowfin tuna could be liable for damages.

Related Resources:

 Cupertino Company Issues Tuna Recall After Salmonella Outbreak in 20 States (San Jose Mercury News) Food Poisoning: What Are Your Rights? (FindLaw&apos;s Injured) Food Poisoning and the Law (FindLaw) 
 
 April 19, 2012 in Food and Drink , Legal Topic: Products Liability Law | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : California , Cupertino , food recall , salmonella , sushi , yellowfin tuna 
 
 Average American Consumes 130 Pounds of &apos;Toxic&apos; Sugar Each Year 
 
Americans consume nearly 130 pounds of sugar per person, per year -- so much, it should be classified as a toxin, a new report says.

The amount of sugar in U.S. diets -- about a third of a pound per person, per day -- poses as big a risk to public health as alcohol, according to the report by three obesity researchers at the University of California, San Francisco School of Medicine. Their report appears in the journal Nature , and was featured on CBS&apos;&quot;60 Minutes.&quot;

High sugar intake is linked to obesity and Type 2 diabetes, along with hypertension and heart disease, the report&apos;s lead author, Dr. Robert Lustig, said.

And it&apos;s not just refined table sugar, the consumption of which has actually declined 40% since the 1970s, according to&quot;60 Minutes.&quot;Sucrose and high fructose corn syrup are making up the difference.

Independent research seems to back up those claims. A new study at the University of California, Davis found people who ingested high fructose corn syrup showed increased LDL cholesterol levels and other risk factors for heart disease,&quot;60 Minutes&quot;reports.

&quot;Ultimately this is a public health crisis. And when it&apos;s a public health crisis, you have to do big things and you have to do them across the board,&quot;Lustig told&quot;60 Minutes&quot;about why he believes sugar is&quot;toxic.&quot;

&quot;Tobacco and alcohol are perfect examples,&quot;Lustig continued.&quot;We have made a conscious choice that we&apos;re not going to get rid of them, but we are going to limit their consumption. I think sugar belongs in this exact same wastebasket.&quot;

Lustig&apos;s recommendation: Men should limit themselves to 150 calories of added sugars a day, while women should limit themselves to 100 calories.

Lustig also wants more regulations and health warnings on sugary products. You can hear more from Lustig in this 90-minute lecture, viewed more than 2 million times, about the damage caused by&quot;toxic&quot;sugar:

 

Related Resources:

 Toxic Sugar: Should We Regulate It Like Alcohol? (The Huffington Post) Public health: The toxic truth about sugar (Nature) Should US Regulate Sugar like Tobacco, Alcohol? (FindLaw&apos;s Law and Daily Life) Could Junk Food, Sugar Addiction Be the Next Big Practice Area? (FindLaw&apos;s Strategist) 
 
 April 03, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : alcohol , diabetes , heart disease , high fructose corn syrup , hypertension , obesity , regulation , sucrose , sugar , tobacco , toxic , warnings 
 
 Is AeroShot Safe? Inhalable Caffeine Will be Tested by FDA 
 
The Food and Drug Administration plans to investigate whether AeroShot, an inhalable caffeine sold in small canisters, is safe for consumer use. The agency will also decide whether the product is properly branded as a dietary supplement.

Unlike medications, supplements are not subject to FDA review before being placed on the market.

For the uninitiated, AeroShot allows consumers to breathe in a fine caffeine powder that then dissolves in the mouth. Each canister contains 100 milligrams of caffeine, which the Associated Press reports is equivalent to a large cup of coffee. There are no other energy additives, such as taurine or guarana.

The main concern is that kids, teens and younger adults will use the inhalable caffeine in conjunction with alcohol. Such concerns are what ultimately forced the alcoholic energy drink Four Loko off the market.

Even when not combined with alcohol, caffeine consumption can lead to serious side effects . High levels of caffeine can cause an increase in heart rate, anxiety, tremors and headaches. An overdose can lead to breathing trouble, convulsions and hallucinations.

While AeroShot should not be used more than 2 times a day , the product&apos;s small size makes it easy for consumers to imbibe more frequently and in dangerous situations. It&apos;s also attractive because it does not contain the sugar found in energy and soft drinks.

As the FDA investigates AeroShot and the safety of inhalable caffeine, it&apos;s important that you continue to exercise caution during use. If you have teens that might be drawn to the product, have a conversation about caffeine safety.

Related Resources:

 AeroShot caffeine inhalers: The next club drug? (CBS) Four Loko Banned? Cities Looking to Block Caffeine/Alcohol Drink (FindLaw&apos;s Common Law) Is Alcoholic Whipped Cream the Next Four Loko? (FindLaw&apos;s Common Law) 
 
 February 22, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : aeroshot , caffeine , club drugs , dietary supplements , fda , food and drugs 
 
 Amish Farmer Banned from Selling Raw Milk, Judge Rules 
 
Is raw milk safe?

The federal government doesn&apos;t think so, which is why the Food and Drug Administration spent the last two years investigating Amish farmer Daniel Allgyer . Allgyer runs Rainbow Acres Farm in Lancaster, Pa. and sells unpasteurized, or raw, milk.

Though Pennsylvania permits intra state sales of raw milk, federal law prohibits inter state sales. Allgyer delivers raw milk to customers in Maryland.

Or better put, he did. A federal judge has ordered Daniel Allgyer to stop selling raw milk across state lines, reports the  Washington Times. If he doesn&apos;t comply, his farm will be shut down and he will be ordered to reimburse the FDA for the cost of his prosecution.

The FDA sent Allgyer a warning letter before taking him to court, explains the Lancaster New Era . But he ignored its requests to cease all interstate sales. Instead, he had customers&quot;lease&quot;cows so he could claim he was merely delivering their rightful property.

The judge called this&quot;subterfuge.&quot;

The consumption of raw milk has been part of an ongoing debate about food autonomy. The FDA believes raw milk is not safe because it does not undergo sterilization. As a result, there have been a number of bacterial outbreaks connected to the product.

Fans believe raw milk has higher levels of vitamins and folic acids, and can help the body fight cancer. Pasteurization arguably deflates, or destroys, milk&apos;s health benefits.

A compromise between federal regulations and raw milk supporters doesn&apos;t yet seem probable. The two sides will likely have to figure out how to make raw milk safe before we see any regulatory changes.

Related Resources:

 Amish farmer shuts down under fed pressure (San Francisco Chronicle) Food Poisoning Prevention Basics (FindLaw) Man in Cow Suit Steals Milk, Caught by Cops at Burger Joint (FindLaw&apos;s Legally Weird) 
 
 February 15, 2012 in Food and Drink | Permalink | TrackBack (0) 

 Technorati Tags : amish , dairy , FDA , food safety , raw milk 
 Next » 

 
Subscribe

 
Subscribe in a reader 

 

 See all FindLaw RSS Feeds 
 

Archives

 
 archives by month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 December 2005 November 2005 October 2005 archives by category Alabama (6) Alaska (3) Arizona (14) Arkansas (5) California (106) Colorado (6) Connecticut (23) Current Affairs (14) Delaware (3) District Of Columbia (18) Executive Branch: Agencies&amp;Regulations (309) Executive Branch: President (33) Film (3) FindLaw for the Public Announcements (84) FindLaw for the Public: Announcements (48) Florida (28) Food and Drink (87) Games (17) Georgia (13) Hawaii (1) Idaho (3) Illinois (23) Indiana (10) Iowa (6) Kansas (3) Kentucky (6) Legal Topic: Adoption Law (3) Legal Topic: Alternative Dispute Resolution (2) Legal Topic: Bankruptcy Law (45) Legal Topic: Civil Rights (108) Legal Topic: Consumer Protection (719) Legal Topic: Criminal Law (130) Legal Topic: Death Penalty (11) Legal Topic: Divorce&amp;Child Custody (10) Legal Topic: DUI/DWI (11) Legal Topic: Education Law (19) Legal Topic: Elder Law (10) Legal Topic: Election Law (9) Legal Topic: Employee Rights (59) Legal Topic: Environmental Law (21) Legal Topic: Estate Planning (11) Legal Topic: Family Law (54) Legal Topic: Health&amp;Health Care Law (274) Legal Topic: Immigration&amp;Naturalization Law (17) Legal Topic: Internet (87) Legal Topic: Lemon Law (7) Legal Topic: Litigation&amp;Appeals (36) Legal Topic: Marriage&amp;Living Together (27) Legal Topic: Medical Malpractice (8) Legal Topic: Mesothelioma&amp;Asbestos (2) Legal Topic: Motor Vehicle Accidents (47) Legal Topic: National Security (18) Legal Topic: Nursing Home (4) Legal Topic: Personal Injury (121) Legal Topic: Pets (6) Legal Topic: Probate&amp;Estate Administration (8) Legal Topic: Products Liability Law (279) Legal Topic: Real Estate Law (61) Legal Topic: Securities Law (21) Legal Topic: Small Business (12) Legal Topic: Social Security – Disability (7) Legal Topic: Tax Law (53) Legal Topic: Toxic Mold (2) Legal Topic: Traffic Violations (12) Legal Topic: U.S. Supreme Court (56) Legal Topic: Workers’ Compensation (2) Legislation: Federal (128) Louisiana (14) Maine (1) Maryland (7) Massachusetts (19) Michigan (8) Minnesota (5) Mississippi (8) Missouri (5) Montana (2) Music (1) Nebraska (6) Nevada (6) New Hampshire (2) New Jersey (19) New Mexico (5) New York (43) North Carolina (11) Ohio (14) Oklahoma (1) Oregon (11) Pennsylvania (13) Recalls: Auto, Cars, and Motor Vehicles (66) Recalls: Drugs (21) Recalls: Food (33) Recalls: Infant Products (37) Recalls: Other (13) Recalls: Pet Food (3) Religion (2) Rhode Island (2) Science (5) South Carolina (8) Sports (8) Television (3) Tennessee (4) Texas (30) Travel (4) Utah (8) Vermont (2) Virginia (9) Washington (14) Web/Tech (30) Weblogs (3) West Virginia (1) Wisconsin (6) 
 

 
Common Law Vanguard Panel
 The following firms have assisted the FindLaw editorial team in identifying emerging trends in consumer protection law and topics of importance to readers of this blog:


 Corsiglia McMahon&amp;Allard, LLP - San Jose, CA Knapp&amp;Roberts - Phoenix-Mesa, AZ McKeen&amp;Associates - Detroit, MI Carter Law Offices - Kansas City, MO-KS David G. Smith - Oakland, CA Dollar, Burns&amp;Becker, L.C. - Kansas City, MO-KS Foley, Griffin, Jacobson&amp;Faria, LLP - Nassau-Suffolk, NY James P. Ginzkey, Trial Attorney - Bloomington-Normal, IL 
 
 
Copyright 2008 FindLaw
	</body>
</document>
