<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003617" url="http://www.foodnut.com/464/pho-miss-saigon-restaurant-review-san-mateo/" time="2012-07-12-19:47" support="7" score="0.01229176199377938" bingtitle="Pho Miss Saigon Restaurant, San Mateo | Foodnut.com" webtitle="Pho Miss Saigon Restaurant, San Mateo | Foodnut.com">
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="138"/>
	<description>Picks: Three Color Bean Drink ($2.95) had red, yellow ... It came with the usual noodle raw veggie condiments. ... We had to hit the cashier to get our bill. This is ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Contact Best San Francisco Restaurants San Francisco Food 
 2009 
Pho Miss Saigon Restaurant Review, San Mateo

Posted by Foodnut.com
 Be Sociable, Share! 
 
 
 
 
 Tweet 
 Hello there! If you are new here, you might want to subscribe to the RSS feed for updates on this topic. Powered by WP Greet Box WordPress Plugin 
 
Reviewer: Foodnut.com
 
Pho Miss Saigon
 
147 East 3rd Ave (Near San Mateo Drive)

San Mateo, CA 94401

650-685-6151
 
 
 

Pho Miss Saigon is an inexpensive Vietnamese noodle place in downtown San Mateo. You can order a bowl of noodles and have them in 5 minutes, making this a good alternative to fast food. 

 

Decor, Vibe–Nice big room with elegant chairs, lighting, and paint scheme leftover from last restaurant. Couples, friends, and families of all races were there getting a quick bite.

 Menu Pictures (Click to zoom into any picture)

 

Printed to go menu

 

Menu Page 2

 Picks: 

 

Three Color Bean Drink ($2.95) had red, yellow, and brown beans in coconut milk with lots of ice on top. A nice combination for a hot day. The beans are an acquired taste, but being so sweet, anyone can down them.

 OK: 

 

Beef Noodle Soup ($7.95 large) with special rare steak, well done flank, brisket, tendon, tripe, and beef ball was in a huge bowl. The meat was low in quality and there are a lot of parts, so make sure you like this. The noodles are average and the broth on the salty side. It came with the usual noodle raw veggie condiments.

 

Seafood Combo ($7.25 large) with rice noodle soup was also a huge bowl full of similar broth with chunks of imitation crab (fish), squid, fish cakes, and tons of thin rice noodles. It hits the spot for a quick meal but is nothing special.

 

BBQ Boneless Chicken over rice ($6.95) is a good value for the money but the chicken was pretty tasteless and thin. It came with some lettuce that clearly should have been composted. It came with a little bowl of soup.

 Pans: 
None

Pho Miss Saigon had marginal service with the guy showing up to order and get our food and refill once. We had to hit the cashier to get our bill. This is strictly a fast meal place that serves some average noodles. Do not look for gourmet food here.
 
 $25 Dining Certificate for $5 


 Pho Miss Saigon Overall Rating: (Average 1.5 )
 
 Come Back? 

 Food Rating: (Average) Service Rating: (Below Average) Atmosphere Rating: (Average) Value Rating: (Good) 

 Guide: 0 = poor, 1 = Below/Average, 2 = Good, 2.5 = Very Good, 3 = Excellent , 4 = Extraordinary

 Alcohol: No Attire: Casual Hours: Daily 10am - 9pm Parking: Street Reservations: No Prices: $6.25 - $8.95 
 
 Be Sociable, Share! 
 
 
 
 
 Tweet 
 
Related posts:
 Saigon Cuisine Restaurant Review The Noodle Shop Restaurant Review, San Mateo Little Sichuan Restaurant Review, San Mateo Himawari Restaurant Review, San Mateo ABC Cafe Restaurant Review, San Mateo The Noodle Shop San Mateo Spiedo Restaurant Review, San Mateo Cerviche Taqueria Restaurant Review, San Mateo 

 
 Filed under: $ , 1.5 stars , California , Dine Again? , Maybe Again , Restaurant Cost , Restaurant Cuisine , Restaurant Location , Restaurant Rating , Restaurant Review , San Francisco Peninsula , United States , Vietnamese Restaurant | Tags: Pho , San Mateo 
 
 No Comments» 
 Posted on October 23rd, 2009
If you enjoyed this post, be sure to subscribe to our RSS feed. 
Leave a Reply

 Please do not put your URL in the comment text and please use your PERSONAL name or initials and not your business name. 
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
 Currently you have JavaScript disabled. In order to post comments, please make sure JavaScript and Cookies are enabled, and reload the page. Click here for instructions on how to enable JavaScript in your browser.
	</body>
</document>
