<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003762" url="http://cshels.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:55" support="3" score="0.0008840271119950865" bingtitle="B + C &amp; Baby" webtitle="Scattered Seashells">
			<query id="000704" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>Airplane bathrooms, front car seats, back car seats, trunks, the bench at a fast food restaurant... ... Valentines Day Veterans Day volunteer Wants water park waterfalls ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, July 12, 2012 
 
 Nom Noms 
 In the past month, our entire diet has changed. I feel like we&apos;re in a whirlwind as I&apos;m scrambling to find entirely new meals to make or twists on the ones that I&apos;ve been making for six plus years. It&apos;s fun, it&apos;s exciting, but it&apos;s terrifying and stressful, because every Monday (the day before grocery shopping) I&apos;m searching and searching for inspiration. I&apos;m not a natural-born, throw-a-gourmet-meal-together, kind of girl.

You know we&apos;re doing the juicing thing and that is going great.  We feel healthy, we feel energized, and we&apos;ve lost some weight! (To brag, I&apos;m down to 133.4 and haven&apos;t been this low for over 3 years. Brandon is at 178 and looking trim!) We juice for breakfast and have one with our lunch, or for our lunch, depending. In between those two &quot;meals&quot; we&apos;re eating fruits and veggies.

Except Brandon. With flight school keeping him busy, he eats when he&apos;s home. So I&apos;m snacking in between on fruits and veggies.
 (My weekly menu on the wall!) It&apos;s just dinner that has me in a scramble. We&apos;ve been cutting down our meat intake significantly, but still including it with every meal. We&apos;ve reduced our dairy intake to, um, ice cream and coffee creamer (for Brandon, I don&apos;t do coffee). We&apos;ve cut out grains pretty much entirely.

That&apos;s my problem: a lot of my meals centered around grains! Yeah, we&apos;re going towards the Paleo style of eating, and that&apos;s cool with me. We&apos;ve just super upped the fruits and veggies, add in a bit of meat, and there we go!

Now I need some lunch and dinner ideas... any takers? And then, what do I feed Penny?

Anyway, here are some photos of the last few dinners I&apos;ve made!
 Some notes... 1. We don&apos;t eat everything in bowls! It just so happens the last 4 nights we have! 2. We love sweet potatoes, they show up in 3 of the meal. 
 Blue Bowl: &quot;Spaghetti&quot; - Wait, weren&apos;t we cutting out grains? Yes, we are! This is spaghetti squash and I will tell you what, we&apos;re addicted. I think we like this better than with pasta, and it made our tummies feel so much better. Plus, Penny looooveeedd the squash! Green Bowl:   This recipe , or what I call &quot;chicken bake&quot; for short. It&apos;s basically chicken, potatoes, and asparagus (and I throw in onions, mushrooms, zucchini, and this time, turnip, because I had it), all baked together! One of our new favorites, so easy to do, and so healthy! Yellow Bowl:  Our shepherd&apos;s pie. Grass-fed tasty ground beef mixed with zucchini, mushrooms and onions, and topped with mashed sweet potatoes. And I cheated a bit and put some shredded cheese on top. I can&apos;t let good cheese go to waste! Red Bowl: Roast! I stuck a shoulder roast in the crock pot with some sweet potatoes (surprise!), carrots, onions, mushrooms, and celery. Cooked all day. It fell apart. Penny approved of this too!

I&apos;m feeling pretty confident with our eating habits. Now the tough part will be making lunches for Brandon to bring to work! That&apos;ll be interesting! 1 comment: Labels: Food , healthy living , juicing , Paleo 
 Wednesday, July 11, 2012 
 
 Independence Day 
 The Fourth of July was a somber day for us. Dexter was off who-knows-where on some adventure, and we were a little bit sad about it. We drove around post four or five times with no luck. We had no idea where he could be! Thank goodness he came home the next morning or else our whole week would&apos;ve been thrown off.

However, while we were having a sad time, someone else was having the time of his life. No, not Dexter. Winston was experiencing his very own Independence Day.

 You woke me up for this? 
Winston has a tough time in this house. It&apos;s our fault, really. Border collies are smart, too smart, and they&apos;re eager to please. Early on, Winston would sneak up and try to eat Dexter&apos;s food, right in front of our eyes. Quickly, we yelled at him. When that stopped working, we got a spray bottle, and from our spots on the couch we could spray him and he&apos;d run off. Dexter quickly learned that the spray bottle meant someone&apos;s bad, and he knew when we yelled &quot;Winston&quot; that he needed the chase the cat.

It&apos;s all fun and games until the dog won&apos;t stop.

Now, our poor cat is terrorized. Dexter hears anything  and he chases off the cat, thinking he&apos;s in trouble. We have no idea how to un-train him of this habit, either, so poor Winston suffers.

But Dexter was gone! What freedom! No one to bite his tail when he was being bad, no one to chase him down the hall and under the bed.
 And now I have to sit up? 
Winston took full advantage of his independence; he was a different cat! Of course, it was all naughty kitty things, like... jumping on the counters, using the carpet as a scratching post, getting up on the bathroom counters and messing with stuff, chewing on hairties, laying on the couch...

It was a good day for Mr. Kitty. I do feel bad that he doesn&apos;t get this freedom every day, but that is life! We try to help as much as we can with the doggy. The Fourth was an Independence Day for both of them, huh?

 How was your Independence Day? :D 1 comment: Labels: Dexter , Winston 
 Tuesday, July 10, 2012 
 
 Family Photos&amp;Penny 6 Months 
 Back on June 20th, I packed up the family and we headed down to a local old-time village to get some family photos done. It was our first time getting all of us together and I thought it was great! The photographer did such a great job, too. Mostly, I wanted photos of Penny for her 6 months, because halfway through a year is just a special time. Her next professional photos will be for one year!

So here are some of my favorites. Well, I love them all, but I can&apos;t post them all on here. Hope you enjoy!

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 8 comments: Labels: Brandon , Chantal , Family , Penny , photos Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Hello There!
 
Hi, I&apos;m Chantal .
I&apos;m a fiction writer, Army wife and mom to a little girl. This is my blog about parenthood, marriage, military life, and everything in between.
Glad you could stop by! 
 
This is my family .
Brandon, my husband and best friend, helicopter pilot-to-be. Penny, our daughter, full of life and laughter. 
Follow Me
 
 
 
 
 
 
Grab Me
 
 
 
 
Sponsors
 Personalized Floor Puzzle 
Ramblings
 101 in 1001 200 days 2010 30 Day Photo 300 Days Adjustments AFAP age Airplanes Alabama Amazon America Ancestry anniversary apocalypse Army art Auntie Pasto&apos;s Australia Avelyn Aviation Babies Baby clothes Baby Expo Baby S baby wearing ball banner beach beef bike rides Birthdays Black Friday Blake Block leave Blog Award blogging Bloghop BLW board games book club books Brandon bras breastfeeding Broken Stuff bus Canada Captain care package catamaran celebrities Chantal Christmas Citizenship Day cleaning cloth diapers collars Colorado concealed carry concert cosleeping Costco country music crepes Crock Pot Week Dating debt Delurker Day deployment Dexter Doctor dogs DOM Double Rainbow drive-in Easter fair Family Fandango Farmer&apos;s Market Fathers Day Featured Blogger FedEx Fire alarm Five Love Languages fleas flight school Florida Flying Following Food football FRG Friday Featured Blogger friends furniture Future plans Georgia giveaway Glee Goodbye Grandpa Guest Post Hair Haleiwa Art Festival Halloween Hawaii healthy living Helicopter Hey It&apos;s Okay Tuesday Hiking history Homecoming homeschooling house Hui HUN Instagram iPod Jenny Jessica juicing kickboxing Killer Kona Brewing Company Kualoa Ranch label maker Lt Dan Band luau luncheon mall Mallory map Memorial Day Mervin MilSpouse Milspouse Fill-In Milspouse Weekly Roundup Money motherhood Mothers Day Movies Moving museums music NaNoWriMo neighbors nerves New Years Nursery Oil Changes Osama bin Laden P90x Paleo Pampered Chef Parenthood Penny Penny says photos Pineapple Festival pizza play Polo Pregnancy Product review promotion Questions rain Random Research resolutions rings RnR road trip Royal wedding Running Saturday Dinner Scentsy Scots Festival Sewing shoes shooting shopping Showstoppers sick Sims sisters skiing Skype sleep slippers spa SpouseBUZZ staff duty Storms Super Bowl surfing surprises Teething necklace termites thankful Thanksgiving The Counter Toby Keith traveling TV Unexpected USS Arizona USS Missouri Valentines Day Veterans Day volunteer Wants water park waterfalls weather webcam Weddings Weight loss Whatcha Reading? Whole Foods Winston Work Working out writing yard sale Yoga zoo 
MilSpouse
 
 
 
 View My Milblogging.com Profile 
 
 
 
Like Me
 
Followers
 
History
 
 ▼  2012 (157) 
 ▼  July (11) 
 Nom Noms Independence Day Family Photos&amp;Penny 6 Months Photo-a-Day June Friday Featured Blogger - The Few, The Proud, The ... Where&apos;s the beef? Lost Dog Penny Says... BFF It has begun! Penny Says... 
 

 ►  June (25) 
 Friday Featured Blogger - The Tervo Times Penny&apos;s Outfits for the Week First Date Colorado The Unexpected I stopped reading Fifty Shades of Grey Leading Lady Review Family Time Continued First Father&apos;s Day June 18th Penny - Six Months Friday Featured Blogger: This is Me; Consequently Family Time Eating Habits Redefined All of everything! GIVEAWAY: Journey 2 DVD/BluRay Another One? I Heart Instagram The Art of Sitting Up Penny&apos;s Nursery The Problem with Having Babies Photo-a-Day May Penny says... GIVEAWAY: $100 Amazon GC! Four Years! 
 

 ►  May (29) 
 Friday Featured Blogger - It Started with a Bump Baby Jewelry? Georgia&amp;the News Memorial Day (Links) Busy Bee! C-Section Pain Live Your Life Debt Free (Part Two) - Monthly Budgeting Debt Free (Part One) - 7 Baby Steps Friday Featured Blogger: The Optimistic Army Wife Baby-led Weaning Penny - Five Months Yet another sleep post! Debt Free and I know it! 
 

 ►  April (25) 

 ►  March (24) 

 ►  February (20) 

 ►  January (23) 
 

 ►  2011 (312) 
 ►  December (26) 

 ►  November (27) 

 ►  October (27) 

 ►  September (21) 

 ►  August (17) 

 ►  July (20) 

 ►  June (29) 

 ►  May (31) 

 ►  April (31) 

 ►  March (23) 

 ►  February (28) 

 ►  January (32) 
 

 ►  2010 (192) 
 ►  December (31) 

 ►  November (31) 

 ►  October (31) 

 ►  September (30) 

 ►  August (31) 

 ►  July (36) 

 ►  June (1) 

 ►  May (1) 
 
 
 
 
 
 Content owned and operated by Chantal S. (Scattered Seashells). Simple template. Template images by merrymoonmary . Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
