<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003145" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/china-lane-restaurant-boynton-beach-314484" time="2012-07-12-19:17" support="1" score="0.0018651651881965235" bingtitle="China Lane Restaurant - Reviews &amp; Menu - 6621 W Boynton Beach Blvd ..." webtitle="China Lane Restaurant - Reviews&amp;Menu - 6621 W Boynton Beach Blvd, Boynton Beach 33437">
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="109"/>
	<description>Description: China Lane Restaurant is a Chinese and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism ... and wanted a veggie meal.I got a take out dish.I did not even get a napkin ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 China Lane Restaurant Menu 

 China Lane Restaurant Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu 
 Boynton Beach Restaurants » Chinese » China Lane Restaurant Share | 
China Lane Restaurant
 
 2.5 star rating           
  2.5 rating over 1 review 
 (561) 737-5539 

 6621 W Boynton Beach Blvd ( ) 

 Boynton Beach , FL 33437 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Read Reviews (1) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  China Lane Restaurant is a Chinese and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for a meal on the go and paid between $10 and $25 . Tags: Chinese and Fast Food Stats: 
 178 dishes entered by diners at China Lane Restaurant 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own China Lane Restaurant? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for China Lane Restaurant
 Write a review 
 1 review First reviewed by rainbow 
 
 0 helpful votes over 1 review 
 rainbow 
 1 Restaurant Review 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 China Lane Restaurant rainbow 
 February 5, 2010 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
this is worst chinese food I ate in my life
 
I ordered a veggie delight to go .I told the guy working there I am a vegetarian and wanted a veggie meal.I got a take out dish.I did not even get a napkin with the meal.Ithrew out the whole meal after a few bites .I went back in the place for a refund he said he couldn’t .That is why I AM WRITING THIS REVIEW !!!!!!!!!
 
Dishes I tried:
 
veggie delight
 
 1.0 star rating           
 
The egg roll was burnt.It was dark brown with a slight black coating on it.It had a rancid oil smell to it. ITHEY DONTCHANGE THEIROILOFTENI TOOK ONE BITE AND SPIT IT OUT THE FRIED RICE TASTED par boiled precooked variety.The veggies looked old and it tasted like theywascooked with animal fats.I told the guy I wanted vegetarian dish.He lied to me.i BROUGHT THE MEAL IN TO SHOW HIM .hE SAID HE COULD DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
Best Dishes at China Lane Restaurant

These dishes from the China Lane Restaurant menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
11. Sweet&amp;Sour Chicken
 
 0.0 star rating           
 
10. Moo Goo Gai Pan
 
 0.0 star rating           
 
veggie delight ( $12.00 ) 
 
 1.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Village Chiropractic Center of Boynton Beach Wasser, Howard, Dc - Village Chiropractic Ctr UPS Store The J&amp;O;Electronics (Affordable and Reliable Service you can trust) Walgreens Rosenstein, David A MD FACS Rosenstein, David A MD FACS Rosenstein, David A MD FACS Perfect Smile Dentistry Paint It Rite 
 China Lane Restaurant is located near the cities of Boynton Beach Delray Beach, Ocean Ridge, Gulf Stream, Village Of Golf, and Hypoluxo. People found this by searching for: China Lane Boynton Beach Fl, China Lane Boyton Beach, China Lane Menu Boynton Beach, China Lane Boynton Beach, China Lane Boynton Beach Menu, China Lane Restaurant, China Lane Boynton, and China Lane Restaurant Boynton Beach Fl Menu. 
Featured in Boynton Beach
 
 4.5 star rating           
 Dominic&apos;s 
 4.5 star rating           
 Wing Wah Express 
 4.0 star rating           
 Josie&apos;s Ristorante&amp;Pizzeria 
 3.0 star rating           
 Kingsburg 
 5.0 star rating           
 Golden Star II 
 5.0 star rating           
 Virzi&apos;s Pizza&amp;Deli 
 3.0 star rating           
 Porto Bella Italian Restaurant 
 1.0 star rating           
 Snappers Seafood&amp;Pasta 
 star rating           
 BOYNTON VILLAGER FLORIST 
 0.0 star rating           
 Brooklyn Water Bagel Co. 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Nearby Restaurants
 DaVinci Restaurant Lucille&apos;s Bad To The Bone BBQ China Lane Restaurant Duffy&apos;s Sports Grill Richard&apos;s Steakhouse 
Link to China Lane Restaurant
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
