<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003987" url="http://www.dining.vt.edu/nutrition/yes.php" time="2012-07-12-20:09" support="3" score="0.004766203806425333" bingtitle="Y.E.S. - You&apos;re Eating Smarter | Menus &amp; Nutrition | Dining ..." webtitle="Y.E.S. - You&apos;re Eating Smarter | MenusNutrition | Dining Services | DSA | Virginia Tech">
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>Waste ... – You’re Eating Smarter ... Fast Food Nutrition Facts: This site gives you nutrition information for popular fast food restaurant chains.</description>
	<body>
		Skip Menu

 Skip to Search Skip to Main Navigation Skip to Main Content Skip to Featured Content Skip to Footer 
 Housing 
 Campus Alcohol Abuse Prevention Center Career Services Cook Counseling Center Corps of Cadets Cranwell International Center 
 
 Dean of Students Office Dining Services Fraternity&amp;Sorority Life Housing&amp;Residence Life Multicultural Programs&amp;Services 
 
 Recreational Sports Schiffert Health Center Services for Students with Disabilities Student Centers and Activities Student Conduct 
 Dining Pages VT People Return to Skip Menu 
Search
   Return to Skip Menu 
Main Content
 Return to Skip Menu 
Main Navigation
 Dining Services   Your Dining Plan Options   Select Your Dining Plan   Major Dining Plans   Minor Dining Plans   Summer Dining Plans   Dining Dollars   Add Money to Your Plan   Refunds&amp;Terms   Dining Center Hours   Dining Centers   Au Bon Pain   Overview   Menu   Hours   GLC   Squires Café   Squires Kiosk   D2   Overview   Menu   Hours   Deet&apos;s Place   Overview   Menu   Hours   DXpress   Overview   Menu   Hours   Hokie Grill&amp;Co.   Overview   Menu   Hours   Owens Food Court   Overview   Menu   Hours   Sbarro   Overview   Menu   Hours   Turner Place   Vet Med Café   Overview   Menu   Hours   West End Market   Overview   Menu   Hours   Catering   Menus&amp;Nutrition   Daily Menus   Y.E.S. - You&apos;re Eating Smarter   Special Diets&amp;Food Allergies   Nutrition FAQ   Dining Policies   Dining Events&amp;Extras   Backyard Barbecues   Dine with Faculty   Family Flex Plans   Guest Dining Program   Home Sweet Home   Special Events&amp;Theme Dinners   Table Card Reservations   Food Safety   Our Commitment to our Customers   Maintaining Sanitary Facilities   Food Safety Inspection Scores   Safe Handling of Meals to Go   Sustainability   Guiding Principles   Composting   Dining Services Garden   Farms&amp;Fields Project   Food Diversion   Local Sustainable Purchasing   Recycling   Waste   How do we compare?   Employment   Salary&amp;Wage Positions   Why work for us?   Apply   Student Positions   Why work for us?   Apply   Dining Services Leadership Team   About Dining Services   Feedback   Online Comment Card   Student Advisory Council   Table Talk   Contact Us     
Y.E.S. - You&apos;re Eating (and Living) Smarter
   
With the Y.E.S. – You’re Eating Smarter Program, Virginia Tech Dining Services is doing its part to keep you and the planet healthy. We&apos;ve made commitments that will benefit your health and minimize our impact on the environment.

When designing our menus, we strive to provide healthy options in all dining centers. Throughout our venues you will find whole grain options, lots of fruits and vegetables, low-fat dairy, and protein options. Additionally, in 2006, we made a commitment to eliminate trans fats where possible. In 2009, the YES to Go program was created in response to student requests for healthier grab-n-go options. A total of 21 options are available at DXpress; with several of these also available at Hokie Grill and Shultz Express. All items have less than 600 calories and contain heart healthy fats.

As part of our commitment to a healthy planet, we have created the Farms&amp;Fields Project in Owens Food Court. This venue features sustainable, local, and organic foods. Check out the menus and other notes of interest on the Farms&amp;Fields blog .

The final component of the program is education. As part of the Division of Student Affairs, we are committed to providing learning outside the classroom. The YES program has several components that focus on this mission:

 Websites (listed below) with reliable nutrition information Table Cards in dining centers focusing on healthy eating topics Educational events in dining centers that promote learning about healthy eating Presentations to student groups Students can talk about their nutritional needs directly with the Dining Services&apos; administrative dietitian, Jenny Lindsey. One-on-one appointments may be scheduled with Jenny or for individual questions, yes@vt.edu . 


Nutrition Information for Menu Items

You can use our interactive nutrition analysis program to view today&apos;s menu and find nutrition information for menu items. Additionally, you can use our allergen filter to find menu items that do or do not contain one of the eight most common allergens.

Check out our blog!

If you are looking for a great place to find more nutrition information including facts, recipes, and discussions on a wide range of topics, check out the Healthier Hokie blog. 

Reliable Nutrition Web Sites

Are you looking for more on a nutrition topic and don&apos;t know where to get reliable information? You are not alone. There are many websites that seem to give knowledgable advice, but in reality, they&apos;re not a reliable source.

Check out the list below to find reliable information on various nutrition topics.

General Information

 Center for Nutrition Policy : Click on the MyPlate to receive valuable feedback on your dietary intake and physical activity levels. American Dietetic Association : An informative site with good information on nutrition, exercise, and general health. If you are interested in becoming a nutrition professional, this site is for you! Nutrition.gov : This government website has basic nutrition information that everyone can understand. Fast Food Nutrition Facts : This site gives you nutrition information for popular fast food restaurant chains. Schiffert Health Center : You may also visit Virginia Tech&apos;s health center for any questions and problems you may have. 


Vegetarianism

 The Vegetarian Resource Group : A reliable source of information on topics of interest for vegetarians and vegans. Vegetarianism in a Nutshell : A site sponsored by the Vegetarian Resource Group. 


Special Dietary Needs

 Celiac.com : Information on Celiac disease, gluten free products and recipes. American Cancer Society : Find all the latest information on cancer prevention and treatment at this official website. American Diabetes Association : Check out this site to find current diabetes information for yourself or a loved one. American Heart Association : This site provides the latest research and recommendations on how to live a heart-healthy life. Food Allergy Network : Good information on coping with food allergies, including tips on recipe substitutions. 


Eating Disorders

 National Eating Disorders Association : NEDA supports individuals and families affected by eating disorders and serves as a catalyst for prevention, cures, and access to quality care. Eating Disorder Recovery Online : Provides services and information to assist people exhibiting characteristics of eating disorders. 


Sports Nutrition

 Gatorade Sports Science Institute : Access to articles on the latest research regarding areas of sports nutrition and exercise. Sportsmedicine.com : A site dedicated to anything and everything about sports medicine. 


For questions, comments, and suggestions regarding the YES program contact Jenny Lindsey, Dining Services&apos; administrative dietitian, at yes@vt.edu or 540-231-8668.
 Return to Skip Menu 
Featured Content
 
DSA News
 Wed, 27 Jun 2012 First house of Oak Lane Phase IV set to open for fall semester Mon, 11 Jun 2012 Two x Two exhibit at Perspective Gallery features faculty artwork through Aug. 11 Thu, 31 May 2012 Associate faculty principals selected for Residential College at West Ambler Johnston 
 DSA News Archive 
 
 
DSA Events
 
No Current Events

 More VT Events 
 Return to Skip Menu 
Footer
 
Ways to Support Student Life at Virginia Tech
 
 Bookstore  | Jobs at VT  | Contact Us  | Equal Opportunity  | Principles of Community 

 Privacy Statement  | Acceptable Use Policy  | Accessibility  | VT Web Guidelines 

 We Remember  | Campus Security  | VT Alerts 
 
©2012 Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
 
A university program to further support a diverse and inclusive campus community
	</body>
</document>
