<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003894" url="http://stleats.com/" time="2012-07-12-20:03" support="7" score="0.016934659748240127" bingtitle="Saint Louis Eats - Start Here - Metropolitan St. Louis places to ..." webtitle="Saint Louis Eats - Start Here - Metropolitan St. Louis places to go to eat">
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>St Louis Eats - eat St Louis, eating in St Louis, restaurants in St Louis, St Louis dining, lunch, dinner, breakfast, meals Restaurants of St Louis</description>
	<body>
		Saint Louis Eats - St. Louis MO places to go to eat

Restaurants, Cafés, Delis, Bakeries, Groceries, Markets, Coffee Houses, Tea Rooms, Ice Cream Parlors, and a few just plain Joints

St Louis Eats - We want to be your St Louis Dining Guide

From fine dining to casual dining. From simple grub to fine food to fast food.
 St Louis Eats - eat St Louis, eating in St Louis, restaurants in St Louis, St Louis dining, lunch, dinner, breakfast, meals

Restaurants of St Louis

anything to eat?

St Louis area Restaurants

Saint Louis Area Restaurants
 
 
 Saint Louis Eats
Start Here 
Metropolitan St. Louis places to go to eat 


Restaurants, Cafés, Delis, Bakeries, Groceries, Markets, Coffee Houses, Tea Rooms, Ice Cream Parlors, and a few just plain Joints

We want to be your St Louis Dining Guide 
 Retirement Planning Estate Planning Educational Planning Asset Management Life Insurance Health Insurance Long Term Care Insurance 401k Plans Financial Planning 

 
 Scott W. Yanker , CFP  © , CFS
 
 LPL REGISTERED PRINCIPAL 
http://scottyanker.com/ 
 Guajillo Mexican Grill 
 location/coupon 
http://GuajilloMex.com/ 
 Your Dream Journey: 
 Travel Concepts 
http://YourDreamJourney.com/ 
 Classic Dogs And More 
http://ClassicDogsAndMore.com/ Viviano&apos;s coupon 
Save on a sandwich or salad or large pasta at
 Viviano&apos;s 
in Chesterfield or Fenton 
 
 Spencan Properties 
Rental Homes and Apartments
Years of experience in residential rental property and property management in St. Louis.
 more ... rent house property Maryland Heights MO Overland MO Breckenridge Hills MO 
http://www.spencan.com/ 
 Eisha 
http://eishahitz.com/ 
Restaurants of St. Louis

 
Places to go in St. Louis

 Foods of St. Louis

 Current weather 
(experimental)
 Watches-Warnings 

 
Traffic help 

 New Bridge 

 Power outages by ZIP    

 
 Earthquake information. 

 
U.S. Constitution 

 Modem help 

More than you
want to know about
 
Night Vision - the Red Myth

If the e-mail says
 Forward to everyone? Groove Forums 
 
It&apos;s not what you think...
just that you think! 
http://TheChurchOfGroove.com/ Smoking won&apos;t kill you ...
all at once ...
or right away. - GWB 
 
This page is by location (see further down).
Or select first letter restaurant name:
 # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 

Before you pick a place to eat you might want to read the Foods of Saint Louis, Missouri. (opens in a new window) 
 Always call before travelling to be sure of hours, cuisine and location - information in this list may be out of date despite efforts to keep it as accurate as possible.
A sample of the neighborhoods:
 “ The Loop ”  in University City. This area is not a pasteurized and homogenized mall. It has theater, a wide variety of places to eat, shops of all types (books, clothes, funiture, news, tatoo, smoke ...), art galleries, art studios, a farmer&apos;s market, a laundramat, sidewalks (including the Walk of Fame), traffic and people. Basically what most downtowns used to be a long time ago.
 “ The Hill ”  means Italian. While good Italian is not limited to this area, it has the hightest concentration of Italian restaurants.
 “ Dogtown ”  just south of Forest Park is really three neighborhoods. Though mostly residential it does have a interesting variety of places to eat, markets, coffee shops and more.
 “ Grafton IL ”  the Great River Road or the Sam Vadalabene Bike Trail, eagle watching, or just a destination on it&apos;s own.

Groceries or Market means just that and no eat-in unless otherwise stated. Deli includes eat-in unless otherwise stated. Coffee or Tea means prepared unless otherwise stated.

clickable map - selected neighborhoods
 
Select by neighborhood: [ or place name ]

 Missouri
 City of Saint Louis MO 63101 63102 63103 63104 63106 63107 63108 63109 63110 63111 63112 63113 63115 63116 63118 63120 63139 63147 63105 63117 63119 63123 63125 63130 63133 63136 63137 63138 63143 
Saint Louis City - neighborhoods
 51 Academy 74 Baden 22 Benton Park 30 Benton Park West 05 Bevo Mill       Bottle District 04 Boulevard Heights 01 Carondelet 61 Carr Square 38 Central West End 41 Cheltenham 42 Clayton-Tamm 11 Clifton Heights 66 College Hill 62 Columbus Square 26 Compton Heights 26 Compton Hill 77 Covenant Blu      CWE 48 DeBaliviere 47 DeBaliviere Place       Dogtown 35 Downtown 36 Downtown West 16 Dutchtown 10 Ellendale 67 Fairground Neighborhood      Forest Park 39 Forest Park Southeast 53 Fountain Park 24 Fox Park 43 Franz Park 31 The Gate District      Grand Center 19 Gravois Park 56 The Greater Ville 78 Hamilton Heights 12 The Hill 44 Hi-Pointe 03 Holly Hills 65 Hyde Park 59 JeffVanderLou 40 Kings Oak 55 Kingsway East 52 Kingsway West 20 Kosciusko       Laclede&apos;s Landing 32 Lafayette Square 34 LaSalle 54 Lewis Place 09 Lindenwood Park       The Loop 18 Marine Villa 71 Mark Twain 70 Mark Twain / I-70 Industrial 23 McKinley Heights 28 McRee Town 37 Midtown 17 Mount Pleasant 64 Near North Side 14 North Hampton 73 North Point 79 North Riverfront 68 O&apos;Fallon 63 Old North St Louis 46  Parkview 02 Patch 33 Peabody, Darst, Webbe 69 Penrose 06 Princeton Heights 26 Reservoir Square 75 Riverview 27 Shaw 46 Skinker 21 Soulard 07 South Hampton       Southtown 13 Southwest Garden 08 St Louis Hills 60 St Louis Place 29 Tiffany 25 Tower Grove East 15 Tower Grove South 58 Vandeventer 57 The Ville 49 Visitation Park 72 Walnut Park East 76 Walnut Park West 50 Wells/Goodfellow 48 West End 45 Wydown / Skinker Lambert International Airport MO 63145 

 Saint Louis County MO 
 Mid County MO 
 Bel-Nor MO 63121 - mailing St. Louis MO 63121 Bel-Ridge MO 63121 - mailing St. Louis MO 63121 Bellerive MO Beverly Hills MO Breckenridge Hills MO Brentwood MO Charlack MO Clayton MO 63105 63124 Frontenac MO 63131 Glen Echo Park MO Glendale MO Greendale MO Hanley Hills MO Hillsdale MO Huntleigh MO Kirkwood MO 63122 Ladue MO 63124 - mailing St. Louis MO 63124 The Loop Maplewood MO Normandy MO Northwoods MO Norwood Court MO Oakland MO Olivette MO Overland MO Pagedale MO Pasadena Hills MO Pasadena Park MO Pine Lawn MO Richmond Heights MO 63117 Rock Hill MO Sycamore Hills MO University City MO Uplands Park MO Velda City MO Velda Village Hills MO Vinita Park MO Vinita Terrace MO Warson Woods MO Wellston MO 

 North County MO 
 Bellefontaine Neighbors MO Berkeley MO Black Jack MO Bridgeton MO Calverton Park MO Champ MO Cool Valley MO Country Club Hills MO Dellwood MO Edmundson MO Ferguson MO Flordell Hills MO Florissant MO Hazelwood MO Jennings MO Kinloch MO Moline Acres MO Riverview MO Saint Ann MO Saint John MO Woodson Terrace MO 

 South County MO 
 Bella Villa MO Crestwood MO Fenton MO Grantwood Village MO Green Park MO Lakeshire MO Mackenzie MO Marlborough MO Saint George MO Shrewsbury MO Sunset Hills MO Webster Groves MO Wilbur Park MO 

 West County MO 
 Ballwin MO Chesterfield MO 
 East Mid Valley South Gumbo 
 Clarkson Valley MO Country Life Acres MO Creve Coeur MO Crystal Lake Park MO Des Peres MO Ellisville MO Eureka MO Manchester MO Maryland Heights MO 63117 Pacific MO Town &amp; Country MO Twin Oaks MO Valley Park MO Westwood MO Wildwood MO 63005 63011 63021 63025 63038 63040 63069 Winchester MO 
 

 Saint Charles county MO 
 Augusta MO Cottleville MO Dardenne Prairie MO Defiance MO 63341 Flint Hill MO Foristell MO Josephville MO Lake Saint Louis MO New Melle MO O&apos;Fallon MO Portage Des Sioux MO St Charles MO 63301 63302 63303 63304 St Paul MO St Peters MO 63303 63304 63376 Weldon Spring MO Weldon Spring Heights MO Wentzville MO West Alton MO not IL 

 Jefferson county MO 
 Arnold Township MO Big River Township MO Central Township MO High Ridge Township MO Imperial Township MO Joachim Township MO Meramec Township MO Plattin Township MO Riverview Township MO Rock Township MO Valle Township MO Windsor Township MO Arnold MO Byrnes Mill MO Cedar Hill Lakes MO Crystal City MO DeSoto MO Festus MO Herculaneum MO Hillsboro MO Kimmswick MO Olympian Village MO Parkdale MO Pevely MO Scotsdale MO 

 Franklin county MO 
 Lyon Township MO Central Township MO Prairie Township MO Boles Township MO Boeuf Township MO Meramec Township MO St. Johns Township MO Union Township MO Calvey Township MO Boone Township MO Gerald MO New Haven MO Pacific MO St Clair MO Sullivan MO Union MO Washington MO 

 Gasconade county MO 
 Bland MO Gasconade MO Hermann MO Morrison MO Owensville MO Rosebud MO 

 

 Illinois
 Madison county IL 
 Alhambra IL Alton IL Bethalto IL Collinsville IL East Alton IL Edwardsville IL Fairmont City IL Glen Carbon IL Godfrey IL Granite City IL Grantfork IL Hamel IL Hartford IL Highland IL Livingston IL Madison IL Marine IL Maryville IL Mitchell IL New Douglas IL Pierron IL Pontoon Beach IL Rosewood Heights IL Roxana IL South Roxana IL St Jacob IL Troy IL Venice IL Williamson IL Wood River IL Worden IL 

 St Clair county IL 
 Alorton IL Belleville IL Brooklyn IL Cahokia IL Caseyville IL Centreville IL Collinsville IL Columbia IL Dupo IL East Carondelet IL East St Louis IL Fairmont City IL Fairview Heights IL Fayetteville IL Freeburg IL Hecker IL Lebanon IL Lenzburg IL Marissa IL Mascoutah IL Millstadt IL New Athens IL New Baden IL O&apos;Fallon IL Sauget IL Scott Air Force Base IL Shiloh IL Smithton IL St Libory IL Summerfield IL Swansea IL Washington Park IL 

 other
 Grafton IL Carbondale IL 62901, De Soto IL, Murphysboro IL(day trip) Springfield IL (day trip) 
 

 

Eateries not yet in the neighborhood list may be in the alphabetical list.
In alphabetizing St. is treated as Saint,“the”is ignored as are“le”,“el”and“la”and names beginning with“cafe”. Use the next word of the name.
Select first letter restaurant name:
 # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 


If you are looking for a particular name thats not in the alphabetical list try renamed or closed 



Until it can be confirmed a restaurant is closed or if it operates on a appointment only basis, the words &quot;Call first!&quot; will appear after the name.

 A quick word if you are from out of town, the mailing address for many places is stated as St. Louis but the name of the city they are in is something else. (List is currently a mixture of local and mailing city names. This will change.) These city names will be on a map. Also note that parts of St. Louis county do not have cities even though they have large populations.
Also St. Charles city and all or part of that and other counties, and part of Illinois are considered parts of the St. Louis metropolitan area.
Clayton is the county seat for St. Louis county.



Population of the St. Louis metropolitan area is ~2.6 million people.
St. Louis City ~0.3 million (not a part of St. Louis county) on ~62 sq. mi. (~5623 persons/sq. mi.)
St. Louis County ~1 million on ~508 sq. mi. (~2001 persons/sq. mi. ~400,000 housholds)
St. Charles County ~0.3 million (includes St. Charles city) on ~560 sq. mi. (~507 persons/sq. mi.)
Jefferson County ~0.2 million on ~657 sq. mi. (~302 persons/sq. mi.)
Franklin County ~0.1 million on ~932 sq. mi. (~102 persons/sq. mi.)
Madison County IL ~0.26 million on ~725 sq. mi. (~357 persons/sq. mi.)
St. Clair County IL ~0.26 million on ~664 sq. mi. (~386 persons/sq. mi.)
the rest of the counties included (or partially included are):
Clinton County IL, Jersey County IL, Monroe County IL, Lincoln County MO, Warren County MO
(resident population NOT work force)
Note that St. Louis County makes up not quite 40%, and the City a little over 11% of the population of the metro region.
To compare.
Population of the Chicago metropolitan area is ~8.2 million people.
Cook county ~5.2 million of which ~2.9 million are in Chicago

Missouri ~5.7 million on ~68,886 sq. mi. (~83 persons/sq. mi.)
Illinois ~12.7 million on ~55,584 sq. mi. (~228 persons/sq. mi.)
US ~291 million
(the ~ symbol is read as: about) 
 Contact for corrections, additions, deletions or your own web page. Please email:  (It is an image to try to reduce spam, sorry no clickable link.)
 
Web page design&amp;hosting. # # #     Abbreviations, acronyms and other information which may be used on this site:
 St Louis MO - Saint Louis Missouri MO - Missouri IL - Illinois ZIP - Zone Improvement Plan MSA - Metropolitain Statistical Area Misc. info. phone area code 314- phone area code 636- phone area code 618- 
 Food&amp;restaurant related keywords. take away take out fax orders carry out eat in dine in sit down catering course side dish entrée entree entremets dessert regale regalement refreshment entertain refection déjeuner déjeuner fourchette tiffin dinner supper snack whet bait potluck hearty square substantial full meal blowout light refreshment chota hazri bara hazri bara khana cuisine bill of fare table eating house abode vittles victuals snack food grub chow EATABLES comestibles victuals edibles ingesta pabulum aliment nourishment nutriment sustenance sustentation nurture subsistence provender corn feed fodder provision ration keep commons board commissariat plate dish mess feed spread repast junket banquet feast collation provisions posh nosh nosh refection victuals vittles Where can I eat Why Who has What food How do I cook 
 Misspelled keywords. resturants resturant resteraunts resteraunt 
 Food related quotes. &quot;But hark! the chiming clocks to dinner call.&quot;-Pope &quot;Across the walnuts and the wine.&quot;-Tennyson &quot;Blessed hour of our dinner!&quot;-O. Meredith &quot;Now good digestion wait on appetite, and health on both!&quot;-Macbeth &quot;Who can cloy the hungry edge of appetite?&quot;-Richard II &quot;Sit down and feed and welcome to our table.&quot;-As You Like It &quot;My dinner was noble and enough.&quot;-Pepys &quot;food glorious food&quot;-from Oliver 
 

 GeoURL 
 Page generated: Thu, 12 Jul 2012 18:03:46 GMT

Mozilla/4.0 (compatible; MSIE 6.0; Windows NT 5.0)
requested :Thursday 12 July 2012 - 13:03:46 completed: Thursday 12 July 2012 - 13:03:46
Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:00:00 GMT genuflusant
	</body>
</document>
