<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003407" url="http://www.activediner.com/restaurant/us/nv/henderson" time="2012-07-12-19:33" support="5" score="0.006477733700949438" bingtitle="Henderson Restaurants Guide and Dining Reviews in NV - ActiveDiner" webtitle="Henderson Restaurants Guide and Dining Reviews in NV - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="000115" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>“Watch your receipt, they have overcharged my friend ... “For a fast food restaurant, Rubios is our favorite. ... the tropical fish tank while we wait for our order.”</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Italian 
 Mexican 
 Japanese 
 Chinese 
 Burger 
 Mediterranean 
 American Traditional 
 Thai 
 
 more... 
 24 Hours Alcohol American American Traditional Asian Bakery Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Billiard/Pool Tables Breakfast Brewery/Pub/Tavern Brunch Buffet Burger Business Lunch Cafe Cajun/Creole Californian Call Ahead Pickup Candy/Dessert Shop Casual/Family Catering Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Coffee Shop Comfort Food/Home Cooking Continental Dance Floor Darts Deli/Sandwich/Subs Delivery Diner Dinner Early Bird Special Fast Food Filipino Fine Dining Fireplace French Fun and Games Greek Happy Hour Hawaiian Health Hot Dog Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop Indian Irish Italian Japanese Karaoke Kids Friendly Late Night Dining Latin Live Entertainment Lunch Meat Shops Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern New American Organic Outdoor Seating Pasta Peruvian Pizzeria Romantic Scenic View Seafood Senior Discount Smokers Friendly Smoking/Non Smoking Spanish Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Sushi Bar Take Out/Carry Out Tapas Thai Truck Stop TV/Satellite Valet Parking Wheelchair Access Wi-Fi/Internet Access Wings 
 
 


Popular Cities
 Las Vegas 
 North Las Vegas 
 Laughlin 
 Boulder City 
 Pahrump 
 Tonopah 
 Jean 
 Round Mountain 
 Amargosa Valley 
 Beatty 



 
 Best Restaurants in 
Henderson

 Frediani&apos;s Authentic Italian Restaurant , Henderson

 Quiznos Sub , Henderson

 El Torito Cafe , Henderson

 Capriotti&apos;s Sandwich Shop , Henderson

 Bangkok Orchid , Henderson

 Best Restaurants in Henderson 2011 
 
 Henderson Restaurant Coupons&amp;Deals 

 
 
 United States &gt; Nevada &gt; Henderson 
Henderson Restaurant Guide&amp;Dining Reviews
 
  Featured Review 
 Half Shell Seafood&amp;Gaming 
  I was at the Halfshell for a Dinner party during Christmas this past year. The table was ready when we arrived and our drinks were delivered within 10 minutes of being seated. The salad was very fresh, love the loaf of bread which is served with dinner and my shrimp was great and didn&apos;t smell fishy and I&apos;m fussy being from San Diego, I like fresh! I would definitely recommend this restaurant and I always enjoy the upstairs patio. 


Check out the Best Henderson Restaurant Deals .





Recent Henderson Restaurant Guide Reviews

 Gaetano&apos;s Ristorante   
 “We ate here in 2011 and had the BEST meal ever! The son of the owners was our waiter and he was funny, very helpful and gave us excellent service. We are returning to Las Vegas this year and are looking forward to...” 

 Mugshots Eatery&amp;Pub   
 “Love this place! Those sliders are SO good and the atmosphere is just what I like... friendly and homey. Can&apos;t get better than this Cold beer, Good food and Friendly people. Oh! and try the pancakes!” 

 Emery&apos;s   
 “Great food great people great place.
David Ford” 

 Capriotti&apos;s Sandwich Shop   
 “Great Service and staff friendly” 

 China Inn   
 “Great food great service. I would recomend all to try.” 

 China Inn   
 “Take out is fast, food is great, and the people are very friendly.

Ask for their fried wontons with meat. Not on the menu, but they are so so good.” 

 Lucille&apos;s Smokehouse Bbq   
 “Fun atmosphere, but the food wasn&apos;t as good as I had heard it would be... We had a couple of children with us and the people working dealt with them well. Big portions for the money. Gotta like BBQ to go there an...” 

 El Torito Cafe   
 “I love this place!! I was born in Henderson and moved to Minnesota. Every time I visit that is where I eat!!! Yum, yum, yum enchiladas!” 

 Mugshots Eatery&amp;Pub   
 “The service was great, though there was a limited menu. The bar is ALL about Chicago and was packed for the game. It was cool.” 

 Kennedy Restaurant&amp;Lounge   
 “This restaurant was very good but has gone down hill. Staff turnover is extremely high. The menu has been reduced so much it does not resemble what it was 4 months ago. More of a Dennys style now instead of a Good q...” 

 Frediani&apos;s Authentic Italian Restaurant   
 “My favorite restaurant in Las Vegas/Henderson by far.” 

 Half Shell Seafood&amp;Gaming   
 “As the other reviewer stated there was no one their to greet us (lunch time) for a few mins. I ordered the crab cakes which were good,but a friend ordered the tuna (sushi) roll and indicated that the rice tasted o...” 

 Half Shell Seafood&amp;Gaming   
 “I attended weekly luncheons at The Half-Shell in their upstairs meeting room. I always ordered the grilled salmon which was ALWAYS exceptional. The server was always friendly and helpful. The meeting room is quite...” 

 El Torito Cafe   
 “I love this place, a locals secret. Great food, great people.” 

 Half Shell Seafood&amp;Gaming  
 “Watch your receipt, they have overcharged my friend before when she went there, then when I went their with friends they overcharged us. They gave us a bill that was double what we should have had, and they didn&apos;t ...” 

 Quiznos Sub   
 “This Quiznos is probily the best in Henderson. Friendly staff and sandwhiches made right all the time with the feeling like your at home when your eating your meal. Because of this store I eat Quiznos, others are le...” 

 Alba Brothers Ristorante   
 “Good food at a reasonable price. Staff was really friendly even though they were busy.” 

 Rubio&apos;s Restaurant #43   
 “For a fast food restaurant, Rubios is our favorite. The options are healthy, and it&apos;s very kid friendly - they like to investigate the tropical fish tank while we wait for our order.” 

 Villa Pizza - East   
 “dirty, bad food, trouble service.” 
   »  Read More:   Henderson Restaurant Reviews 


 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
