<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003106" url="http://www.merchantcircle.com/business/Angelos.Brick.Oven.Pizza.Cafe.Howell.NJ.732-683-0400" time="2012-07-12-19:13" support="6" score="0.0047122854353378475" bingtitle="Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe, Howell NJ 07731" webtitle="Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe, Howell NJ 07731">
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001206" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>The Hall: An adorable tuscan style room seats about ... Angelo&apos;s puts out dipping olive oil (you can taste the ... luckly we didn&apos;t pay with a credit card!!! we woun&apos;t be ...</description>
	<body>
		Loading... Autos Home&amp;Garden Real Estate Health&amp;Beauty Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining All Join Now Login Help Dashboard Sign Out Autos Business to Business Community Education Electronics Entertainment and Arts Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Professional Services Real Estate Recreation Retail Shopping Travel&amp;Lodging Find A Merchant Find A Deal Get Advice 
Find
 Merchants Deals Advice 
In or Around
 I&apos;m Insured I&apos;m Uninsured National  NJ  Howell  07731 
 Food&amp;Dining | Banquet Rooms | Restaurants 
 
 Info Map Blog Products Offers Newsletter 
 
 Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 
 
           
 ( 14 ) reviews Write a Review 806 Us Highway No 9 , Howell , NJ 07731 732-683-0400 
Member since October 2008
 Hours: restaurant hours mon-sat 11am-10pm sun 12-9 .Banquet hall hours upon request. Payment: cash and all major credit cards Neighborhood: Freehold/howell Book Appointment Get Directions Connect to Merchant Report Abuse Follow Follow 
11
 Reviews 
&quot;For my grandmother&apos;s 90th birthday our family needed to find a restaurant open early on Sunday&apos;s and close to her assisted living facility. Angelo&apos;s was our only option and am glad it was. The portion sizes were huge yet they didn&apos;t sacrifice quality for quantity. The food was cooked to serve - fresh, fresh, fresh! Angelo came by our table to make sure we were satisfied. Our party of 18 thoroughly enjoyed our appetizers and meals and plan on having our next holiday or family party here. Hats off to Angelo who brought NY style Italian to Route 9 and thanks for the delicious Staten Island baked bread!&quot;
 Joe 
About Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe
 
Categories: Food&amp;Dining | Banquet Rooms | Restaurants | Pizza | Retail Shopping | Events&amp;Occasions 


family oriented italian restaurant and banquet hall. new private banquet room, booking sweet sixteens, bridal and baby showers,engagement parties,rehersal dinners,birthday parties, corporate lunches and dinners.catering on and off premises for all events.



Tags: italian , restaurant , private , banquet , room , howell , freehold , nj ,
 Sponsored Links 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed 
 0.0 Chance 234 Incorporated 732-905-0011 Howell, NJ, 07731 0.0 Family Ties Breakfast&amp;Banquets Inc 732-761-3000 Howell, NJ, 07731 0.0 Southard Grange 732-901-0388 Howell, NJ, 07731 0.0 Southard Grange 218 732-901-0388 Howell, NJ, 07731 
Related Businesses
 
Write a review about Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe
   Rate:
           
 Review I would recommend Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe to my Facebook Friends 
 

 
 
Reviews about Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe
 Sort by:  Most Helpful | Highest Rated | Most Recent Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 5 
Just what the neighborhood needed!‎
 
As a local business owner, I am always on the go and I am rarely ever home for lunch. I depend on the local vendors in this department. Sometimes I just want a pie, other times I enjoy a complete sit down lunch. Well let me tell you the staff over at Angelo&apos;s always take care of us. From the warm friendly telephone greetings to delivery we are covered. Every meal we order is fresh and hot, just the way I enjoy my meals. I especially enjoy the Brick oven pizza that Angelo&apos;s serves. Keep up the good work and keep smiling!
 By Vinny on January 05, 2010 at 10:22 AM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 3 
nice restaurant
 
I went recently and thought it was good stuff! The service was a little slow but the room, live entertainment and food was good. A bit overpriced overall.
 By Dianne on October 20, 2009 at 11:42 AM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 5 
Great Service
 
Excellent Food. Excellent Service.
 By Anonymous on May 20, 2009 at 05:23 PM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 5 
Great Banquet Facility!
 
I just booked my engagement party at this location. I had never been to Angelo&apos;s before, so I wanted to taste the food. 
The Hall:
An adorable tuscan style room seats about 130 with a dance floor. The walls are painted with an antique look and appropriate sconces and mirrors hang on the walls.
The Food:
The house tossed salad is fabulous- greens, fresh mozarella, roasted red pepper. 
The bread is brought in from the best bakeries and some is even baked on premise. Angelo&apos;s puts out dipping olive oil (you can taste the quality) and their own blend of spices- delicious!
The penne vodka has fresh peas (not frozen!), which is so hard to come by. 
The tilapia stuffed with crab meat was sensational (sometimes a special on the restaurant menu): fresh, tender, and not at all fishy.
Angelo&apos;s own creation, Veal a la Angelo, is also worth noting. A tender piece of veal stuffed with eggplant, spinach, and mozarella.

Can&apos;t wait for my party!
 By Ashley on March 16, 2009 at 01:33 PM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 5 
Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe
 
Nice food and nice atmosphere. I highly recommend !!!
 By Dean Laumbach on January 19, 2009 at 01:46 PM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 5 
Title
 
The whole credit card thing happened to me and completely destroyed my credit. I lost my bankaccount over exactly the same thing. I did not know this happened to others as well. And after serious attempts for Angelo to simply write a check to my bank re the over withdrawl (Twenty four dollar order-charged eight hundred something on debit card-wiping out and overdrafting my acct0Angelo reluctantly gave me eighty dollars cash with the promise of a letter that never happened. Theyve since closed down and im unable to open another checking account. Thank you for this info. Wish I knew sooner. Howell resident.
 By andypro on June 09, 2012 at 07:28 AM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 1 
Bad
 
Do not trust this man!
 By Anonymous on July 15, 2010 at 06:20 PM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 5 
Delicious food, generous portions, and reasonable prices!
 
For my grandmother&apos;s 90th birthday our family needed to find a restaurant open early on Sunday&apos;s and close to her assisted living facility. Angelo&apos;s was our only option and am glad it was. The portion sizes were huge yet they didn&apos;t sacrifice quality for quantity. The food was cooked to serve - fresh, fresh, fresh! Angelo came by our table to make sure we were satisfied. Our party of 18 thoroughly enjoyed our appetizers and meals and plan on having our next holiday or family party here. Hats off to Angelo who brought NY style Italian to Route 9 and thanks for the delicious Staten Island baked bread!
 By Joe on May 17, 2010 at 11:02 AM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 1 
Not worth it!!
 
I just didn&apos;t like anthing about it!! staff very rude!!! my stuffed sheels still frozen in the middle!! saw our waitress once???? --after reading other reveiws Yes I remember seeing them on the news for ripping people off!!! wish I remembered berfore I went!! luckly we didn&apos;t pay with a credit card!!! we woun&apos;t be back!
 By dave ferraro on March 19, 2010 at 08:56 PM Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 1 
NEVER AGAIN!!!!!!!!!!! NEVER
 
Never again what rude uncareing people!! our 14 yearold waitress spent all her time hanging out with her friends had to get up and ask for more drinks??? was told i&apos;m busy will get to you when I can!!! 2 other tables to be served between a few of them -I guess the owner???? manger??? cared more about hitting on his staff then caring about his customers! I red the &quot;good&quot; reports but they only have so much family!!!!
 By jenny wayne on March 19, 2010 at 08:49 PM   Next 10 Results Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe 3.1428571428571429 out of 5 14 11 
Browse By Category 
 Banquet Rooms Beverages Candy&amp;Sweets Catering Services Grocery Stores Organic Foods Produce Retailers Restaurants Specialty Food Stores Beverage&amp;Drinks Fast Food Restaurant Equipment&amp;Services view more 
Get in touch with Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe
 Get in touch with Angelos Brick Oven Pizza Cafe (20 Characters Min, 140 Characters Max) Ask Me 
Please tell me the next date that the Streethearts will be playing there.

 
joyce, May 30, 2010
 
 Read all comments 
 See my entire network 
8 In My Network
 
Related Businesses
 
Sponsored Links
 
Other Local Businesses 
 
Follow Us
 MerchantCircle on Facebook Twitter @merchantcircle MerchantCircle Blog Home | About Us | Blog | Forums | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Support | Answers | Advertise with Us | Developers | Expert Articles Our Partners: Ask Answers  |  Life 123  |  Citysearch  |  Insider Pages  |  Urbanspoon MerchantCircle is a Reply! Inc. property. Other Reply! sites include: Bloglines | iMotors | Contractors.com | EducationHub ©2012 Reply! Inc. All Rights Reserved. CLOSE
	</body>
</document>
