<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003192" url="http://ezlocal.com/nc/harrisburg/fast-food-restaurant/51663" time="2012-07-12-19:19" support="5" score="0.020494243062753773" bingtitle="Tony&apos;s SteakOut - Fast Food Restaurant - Harrisburg, NC 28075" webtitle="Tony&apos;s SteakOut - Fast Food Restaurant - Harrisburg, NC 28075">
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="25"/>
	<description>... Fast Food Restaurant » Tony&apos;s SteakOut ... He grew tired of eating processed meals from burger joints. ... need an extremely long time to make my food. I ...</description>
	<body>
		Recent Listings 

 Business Owners 
 Search for near 
Top Local Cities: Chicago , Dallas , New York , Phoenix , San Diego , Tampa 

Local Business Search Made EZ! 
 Home » NC » Harrisburg » Fast Food Restaurant »
 Tony&apos;s SteakOut 
 
 Business Details Map Reviews Photos Offers 
 
Business Details
 
Tony&apos;s SteakOut 
 

   
| Write a Review 
 1 out of 5 based on 0 ratings 
 4628 Hwy 49 South Harrisburg , NC 28075 
(704) 455-4545 
 Website: tonyssteakout.com 0 
 
Business Description:

Hoagies - Wings - Salads - Wraps - Burgers

Freshness: the Central Focus of Tony&apos;s Steak Out

Tony&apos;s is divided into 3 major areas:
Fresh ingredients, Friendly Service, and Affordable pricing.

These key factors control the success for each and every customer. There is MORE to choose from when you dine at Tony&apos;s, Quality Food Priced Right.

Tony began in the service industry over 20 years ago and one of the most difficult things was to find good hot and fresh fast food. He grew tired of eating processed meals from burger joints. With his passion for cooking and using recipes that require only the freshest ingredients, Tony’s Steak Out was born.

For service workers, salesmen, those that work on the go,and mom’s that prefer healthier choices for there families.

Tony&apos;s Steak Out where fresh just taste best!

Hours:
Monday - Thursday 11am - 10pm
Friday - Saturday 11am - 11pm
Closed Sunday

Open Late

We are available until 10:00 P.M. on weekdays.

We are available until 11:00 P.M. on Fridays.

We are available until 11:00 P.M. on Saturdays.
 
Category:

 Fast Food Restaurant 


 Latitude: 
35.321963
 Longitude: 
-80.653096


 
 Reviews
   Write a Review 
They do not want your business

 Reviewer: Ed | 1/31/2012 
 1 out of 5 stars   
 These guys do not want your business. I tried calling when they first opened. No one answered the phone. I tried placing an order online. There website did not work. I had to go to the grocery store for my wife and really wanted a sub, so I stopped in. There were no customers and no one at the front. After about 5 minutes, a worker drove up in the parking lot and went in the back and got, I guess the owner or manager. He must have been sleeping. I told them of my saga, they offered me $2 off my NEXT order. They made a sub, it was OK but they were stingy with the meat. I asked for a menu to take home. They did not have any. I have tried several times since to give them my money, but I have had no luck. One time their driver did not come in, one time they need an extremely long time to make my food. I tried using them again today, but the guy who answered the phone was such a jerk, I hung up. I get the feeling that this is their second job, and they are not serious about making it work. The web site looks like my 12 year old made it. It is sad. I really would like to get a good hot sub in Harrisburg, but 4 strikes you’re out. I wish they would go ahead and close, so another sub business would move to Harrisburg. 
DON&apos;T EAT HERE

 Reviewer: Nicole | 1/27/2012 
 1 out of 5 stars   
 We called to have a menu faxed and was told they didn&apos;t know how to work the fax machine. We then placed an order online and then called 20 minutes later to make sure they had received it and were working on it. When I called they checked they had received the order but had not started on it. I called back about 30 minutes later to speak to the manager because we still had not received our food. I was told that the person speaking was the manager and that their food was made to order and it was in route at that time. Twenty minutes later I tried calling back to see where our food was since we are less than a mile away and their phone was off the hook. About an hour and half after we ordered our food I went to the place to ask for our food and our money back. They had sent the food to the billing address, not the shipping address and I was told that I could stay and wait for the food to come back but she didn&apos;t know how long that would be. I asked how to reach the owner and was told that it was her dad and she could call him. Then she said she couldn&apos;t call him because this had happened before with another customer and I would have to come back when he was there around noon (this was after 2:00). She and the driver were very rude. The driver stated that he had been at the address for 15 minutes knocking on the door for&quot;just two sandwhiches&quot;. When I tried to explain to the girl why I was angry she said she didn&apos;t want to hear it and I needed to let her explain. 
Related Harrisburg Searches


 Search for near 
Browse Harrisburg Businesses:
 Popular | # | A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H | I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P | Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X | Y | Z 
 Directions | Print Details | View Larger 
 High 80°/Low 67° 
Cloudy / Thunderstorms
 
Browse By Category

 Advertising Agency Auto Body Shop Auto Repair Shop Beauty Salon Car Dealer Cleaning Service Clothing Store Consultant Electrician Florist Furniture Store Greeting Card Shop Hair Salon Home Builder Insurance Agency Jeweler Landscape Designer Lawn Care Service Marketing Agency Painter Party Planner Pet Store Photographer Pizza Restaurant Plumber Print Shop Real Estate Agency Restaurant Roofing Contractor Used Car Dealer 
 
Local Search Made Easy!
 
 Submit a Business 

If you do not see your business listed on EZlocal, please
 add your business listing .
 
 Recent Happenings 

 New Reviews Recent Zuluz®Added Recently Added Businesses 
 
 Information 

 About Us Blog Privacy Terms of Use Sitemap 

 AdWords Qualification Contact Careers Radius Calculator 
 
 Find us on Google+ Join us on Facebook . @EZlocal is on twitter! Our YouTube Channel 
 
 
some business data provided by
  

©2007-2012 EZlocal.com, Inc. All right reserved.
	</body>
</document>
