<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003133" url="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2007/08/070829143638.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:16" support="4" score="0.012341759580704196" bingtitle="You&apos;re Likely To Order More Calories At A &apos;Healthy&apos; Restaurant" webtitle="You&apos;re Likely To Order More Calories At A &apos;Healthy&apos; Restaurant">
			<query id="000981" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001169" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>&quot;When we see a fast-food restaurant like Subway advertising its ... lower-calorie foods has not led to the expected ... Number of stories in archives: 117,389</description>
	<body>
		Science News
 ... from universities, journals, and other research organizations  Save  Email  Print  Share 
You&apos;re Likely To Order More Calories At A &apos;Healthy&apos; Restaurant
 
 ScienceDaily (Aug. 29, 2007) An important new study from the Journal of Consumer Research explains the&quot;American obesity paradox&quot;: the parallel rise in obesity rates and the popularity of healthier food. In a series of four studies, the researchers reveal that we over-generalize&quot;healthy&quot;claims. In fact, consumers chose beverages, side dishes, and desserts containing up to 131% more calories when the main dish was positioned as&quot;healthy&quot;.
 See Also: Health&amp;Medicine 
 Diet and Weight Loss Staying Healthy Nutrition 
 Mind&amp;Brain 
 Dieting and Weight Control Nutrition Research Consumer Behavior 
 Living Well Reference 
 Fast food Weight Watchers Calorie South Beach diet 
 
&quot;In our black and white view, most food is good or not good,&quot;explain Pierre Chandon (INSEAD, France) and Brian Wansink (Cornell University).&quot;When we see a fast-food restaurant like Subway advertising its low-calorie sandwiches, we think, &apos;It&apos;s OK: I can eat a sandwich there and then have a high-calorie dessert,&apos; when, in fact, some Subway sandwiches contain more calories than a Big Mac.&quot;

In one study, Chandon and Wansink had consumers guess how many calories are in sandwiches from two restaurants. They estimated that sandwiches contain 35% fewer calories when they come from restaurants claiming to be healthy than when they are from restaurants not making this claim.

The result of this calorie underestimation? Consumers then chose beverages, side dishes, and desserts containing up to 131% more calories when the main course was positioned as&quot;healthy&quot;compared to when it was not--even though, in the study, the&quot;healthy&quot;main course already contained 50% more calories than the&quot;unhealthy&quot;one.

&quot;These studies help explain why the success of fast-food restaurants serving lower-calorie foods has not led to the expected reduction in total calorie intake and in obesity rates,&quot;the authors write.

What should people and health agencies do&quot;In the final study, the researchers show that encouraging people to examine whether the restaurant&apos;s health claims actually apply to the particular food they ordered eliminates the&quot;health halo&quot;effects.

As they explain:&quot;More generally, we need to think about food not just qualitatively (as in&quot;good food -- bad food&quot;) but also quantitatively (as in&quot;how many calories are in this meal?&quot;).&quot;

Pierre Chandon and Brian Wansink.&quot;The Biasing Health Halos of Fast Food Restaurant Health Claims: Lower Calorie Estimates and Higher Side-Dish Consumption Intentions&quot;Journal of Consumer Research: October 2007.
 Share this story on Facebook , Twitter , and Google : 
 Other social bookmarking and sharing tools: 
 | 
 Story Source: 
 
The above story is reprinted from materials provided by University of Chicago Press Journals , via EurekAlert!, a service of AAAS.

 Note: Materials may be edited for content and length. For further information, please contact the source cited above. 
 Need to cite this story in your essay, paper, or report? Use one of the following formats: APA

 MLA 
 Note: If no author is given, the source is cited instead. 
 
 Disclaimer : This article is not intended to provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. Views expressed here do not necessarily reflect those of ScienceDaily or its staff. 
 enlarge 
 In the study, consumers chose beverages, side dishes, and desserts containing up to 131% more calories when the main course was positioned as &quot;healthy&quot; compared to when it was not. (Credit: iStockphoto) 
Related Stories
 Is Fructose Being Blamed Unfairly for Obesity Epidemic? (Feb. 21, 2012) Is fructose being unfairly blamed for the obesity epidemic? Or do we just eat and drink too many calories? Researchers reviewed more than 40 published studies on whether the fructose molecule itself ... &gt;  read more Chefs Can Create Reduced-Calorie Restaurant Foods (Nov. 6, 2010) Restaurants could play an important role in helping to reduce the growing obesity epidemic by creating reduced-calorie meals, according to ... &gt;  read more Flow of Empty Calories Into Children&apos;s Food Supply Must Be Reduced, Experts Urge (Oct. 1, 2010) With over 23 million children and adolescents in the US overweight or obese, the risks for many chronic diseases continue to increase. A new article examines the diets of American youth and finds ... &gt;  read more School Vending Machines Dole Out Excess Calories, Fat (Oct. 6, 2008) Recent figures from the HEALTHY Study, a nationwide effort led by Temple University to curb obesity and type 2 diabetes in middle school students, found vending machines beverages had added sugars, ... &gt;  read more 
 Search ScienceDaily 
 Number of stories in archives: 120,298 Find with keyword(s):   Enter a keyword or phrase to search ScienceDaily&apos;s archives for related news topics,
the latest news stories, reference articles, science videos, images, and books. 
   Just In: Giant Round Fossil Turtle from Colombia Eyes Don&apos;t Give Away a Liar Transforming Cancer Into a Manageable Illness? Super Smart Responsive Materials Skulls Shed Light On Cat Evolution Trigger for Past Rapid Sea Level Rise Native Americans Came from 3 Key Migrations New Kind of Thermoelectric Heat Engine?      more breaking science news 
Social Networks
 Recommend and share this story on Facebook , Twitter , and Google +1 : Tweet Follow @sciencedaily Other bookmarking and sharing tools: | 
 Breaking News 
 ... from NewsDaily.com 
 No crustacean, no cry? Bob Marley gets his own species Giant ice telescope hunts for dark matter&apos;s space secrets Texas to test 1965 voting rights law in U.S. court Employers not rattled yet by &quot;fiscal cliff&quot; Hawking&apos;s rival says Higgs wager win is icing on cake Japanese inventor hopes &quot;ro-butt&quot; can develop communication South Korea proposes &quot;scientific&quot; whaling at Panama meeting From a vial of mom&apos;s blood, a fetus&apos;s entire genome more science news 

In Other News ...

 U.S. states look to enter Libor manipulation case Pentagon spending plans will exceed projected budget: CBO Senators urge reform of tariff waiver bill Insight: A secret plea for money from a mountain in N.Korea Analysis: Latin America&apos;s love affair with China may sour White House says &quot;will be prepared&quot; if spending cuts bite U.S. sends man accused as Osama bin Laden&apos;s cook back to Sudan Exclusive: Riggers sought evacuation before deadly Chevron blast more top news 
 Copyright Reuters2008. See Restrictions . 
 Free Subscriptions 
 ... from ScienceDaily Get the latest science news with our free email newsletters, updated daily and weekly. Or view hourly updated newsfeeds in your RSS reader: 
 Email Newsletters RSS Newsfeeds 
 
Feedback
 ... we want to hear from you! Tell us what you think of ScienceDaily -- we welcome both positive and negative comments. Have any problems using the site? Questions? 
 Your Name: Your Email: Comments: Click button to submit feedback: 
  Save  Email  Print  Share   About ScienceDaily ®  |  Editorial Staff  |  Awards&amp;Reviews  |  Contribute News  |  Advertise With Us  |  Privacy Policy  |  Terms of Use 
 Copyright ©1995-2011 ScienceDaily LLC — All rights reserved — Contact: editor@sciencedaily.com 
Note: This web site is not intended to provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment.
 Part of the iVillage Your Total Health Network 
 Health&amp;Medicine 
 Allergy Alternative Medicine Bird Flu Birth Control Breast Cancer Cancer Diabetes Diet and Weight Loss Diseases and Conditions Fitness Gene Therapy Heart Disease HIV and AIDS Lung Cancer Men&apos;s Health Nutrition Obesity Pharmacology Pregnancy and Childbirth Sexual Health Skin Care Stem Cells Women&apos;s Health ... more topics 
 Mind&amp;Brain 
 ADD and ADHD Addiction Alzheimer&apos;s Anxiety Autism Depression Gender Difference Headaches Insomnia Intelligence Language Acquisition Parkinson&apos;s Perception Psychology Relationships Schizophrenia Social Psychology ... more topics 
 Plants&amp;Animals 
 Agriculture and Food Animals Behavior Biology Biotechnology Cell Biology Cloning Developmental Biology Dogs Dolphins and Whales Endangered Animals Extinction Frogs and Reptiles Genetically Modified Marine Biology Microbes and More Nature New Species Pests and Parasites Spiders Zoology ... more topics 
 Earth&amp;Climate 
 Air Quality Climate Coral Reefs Earthquakes Ecology Environmental Science Geography Geology Global Warming Hurricanes and Cyclones Ice Ages Oceanography Ozone Holes Pollution Renewable Energy Tsunamis Weather Wildfires ... more topics 
 Space&amp;Time 
 Astronomy Astrophysics Big Bang Black Holes Dark Matter ESA Extrasolar Planets Mars Moon NASA Pluto Saturn Solar System Space Missions Space Station Space Telescopes Stars Sun ... more topics 
 Matter&amp;Energy 
 Alternative Fuels Aviation Biochemistry Biometric Chemistry Detectors Electronics Energy Technology Forensics Fossil Fuels Inorganic Chemistry Nanotechnology Organic Chemistry Physics Quantum Physics Solar Energy Technology Wind Energy ... more topics 
 Computers&amp;Math 
 Artificial Intelligence Communications Computer Graphics Computer Modeling Computer Science Encryption Hacking Mathematics Quantum Computers Robotics Software Statistics Video Games Virtual Reality ... more topics 
 Fossils&amp;Ruins 
 Ancient Civilizations Anthropology Archaeology Dinosaurs Early Climate Early Humans Early Mammals Evolution Human Evolution Lost Treasures Origin of Life Paleontology Tyrannosaurus Rex ... more topics 
 
   
 News 
 Front Page Today&apos;s Summaries Latest Headlines Top News Search Archives Living Well Strange Science Most Popular RSS Newsfeeds Email Newsletters News Sections Health&amp;Medicine Mind&amp;Brain Plants&amp;Animals Space&amp;Time Earth&amp;Climate Matter&amp;Energy Computers&amp;Math Fossils&amp;Ruins Science&amp;Society 
 Articles 
 Health&amp;Medicine Mind&amp;Brain Plants&amp;Animals Space&amp;Time Earth&amp;Climate Matter&amp;Energy Computers&amp;Math Fossils&amp;Ruins Science&amp;Society 
 Videos 
 Health&amp;Medicine Mind&amp;Brain Plants&amp;Animals Space&amp;Time Earth&amp;Climate Matter&amp;Energy Computers&amp;Math Fossils&amp;Ruins Science&amp;Society 
 Images 
 Health&amp;Medicine Mind&amp;Brain Plants&amp;Animals Space&amp;Time Earth&amp;Climate Matter&amp;Energy Computers&amp;Math Fossils&amp;Ruins Science&amp;Society 
 Books 
 Health&amp;Medicine Mind&amp;Brain Plants&amp;Animals Space&amp;Time Earth&amp;Climate Matter&amp;Energy Computers&amp;Math Fossils&amp;Ruins Science&amp;Society 
 
 Post this page to your favorite social bookmarking site: close 
 del.icio.us Digg Furl Netscape Yahoo! My Web StumbleUpon Google Bookmarks Technorati BlinkList Newsvine ma.gnolia reddit Facebook Tailrank Slashdot Fark 
 Include this item in your blog or web site: close 
 Title: Link: Summary: Click button to copy above text for pasting into your site: 
 Cite this article in your essay, paper, or report: close 
 APA style: MLA style: Click button to copy above text for pasting into your document: 
 Email this page&apos;s link to a friend or colleague: close 
 To Email: Your Name: Your Email: cc to self
	</body>
</document>
