<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003155" url="http://www.trulia.com/property/3030391100-5-Repton-Cir-111-Watertown-MA-02472" time="2012-07-12-19:17" support="1" score="0.0010315528374675537" bingtitle="5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA - Trulia" webtitle="5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA - Trulia">
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>Offers are contingent upon receipt of a fully executed ... What is your opinion about Repton Place in Watertown.? 7 ... Communities near 5 Repton Cir 111, Watertown</description>
	<body>
		Homes ▼
 Homes Rentals Local Info Advice Professionals Mortgages Advanced Search 
 Buy 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Rent 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Advice 
 Q&amp;A Advice Blogs Guides Ask a Question Write a Blog Post 
 Mortgage 
 Home Loans Mortgage Refinance Mortgage Trends Mortgage Advice Mortgage Calculators 
 Local Info 
 Local Home Foreclosure Center Directory 
 Find a Pro 
 Real Estate Agents Brokers Mortgage Brokers or Lenders Builders/Developers Property Managers 
 
 Help Log in Sign up 
 
 Trulia Mobile For Professionals 
It looks like Javascript is disabled in your browser.
 Trulia requires Javascript to be enabled in order to use our site.
 Please follow these instructions to enable Javascript. 
 sale pending $179,900 
5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA 02472
 housing Home Facts Mortgage Sales Trends View large map 
 Bedrooms:  180+ days on Trulia Bathrooms: 1 Property type: Apt/Condo/Twnhm Size: 566 sqft Lot:  Price/sqft: $318 /sqft Year built: 2007 MLS/ID: 71143563 Zip: 02472 This info was not provided by this listing source. Ask an agent for more details about this home. Listing agent: KIERAN BROSNAN Broker: Fannie Mae 
 Contact agent Follow home Share 
 Send email Share on Facebook 
 Check your credit Report error Get Prequalified More 
 Print this page Ask a question Write a note Report an error 
 
CONDO_COOP - WATERTOWN, MA
 Description provided by Trulia This Apt/Condo/Twnhm is located at 5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA. 5 Repton Cir 111 is in the 02472 ZIP code in Watertown, MA. The average listing price for ZIP code 02472 is $425,155. 5 Repton Cir 111 has 1 bath, approximately 566 square feet, and was built in 2007 
Listing Info for 5 Repton Cir 111 
 Most recent information provided by Fannie Mae on 07/12/2012 05:26 AM: 
 Price: $179,900 MLS/Source ID: 71143563 1 Bathroom 566 sqft Apt/Condo/Twnhm Built In 2007 
 
Brokered by
 Fannie Mae 123 main, morgantown, WV, 26505 Thank you, your email has been sent to the agent. Sorry -- An error occurred. Please try again. 
Contact local agents near 5 Repton Cir 111 
 From Subject Schedule a viewing Property still available? Learn more details Alert me on similar homes Make an offer Other Message I am searching for a home in 02472 and I found 5 Repton Cir 111, Watertown MA 02472 with 1 bathroom for $179,900. Please send me more information about this or other similar listings in this area. 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Medea Palandjian (617) 674-0887   5 Kim Walker-Chin,MBA (617) 274-8784 Patrick Murphy (617) 904-9556 Joseph Dacey (617) 249-3381   1 Want to be listed here? Learn more Done «See similar homes Prev Next Sponsored Resource Center Buying a Home? Check your Credit Score today for - $0 Unpack discounts up to 40% with Discount Double Check. Get A Quote. This property may be overpaying their property taxes. Check For Free Discussions in Watertown, MA 259 followers Ask Question Recent Activity Does the buyer&apos;s agent need to be present at home inspection to recieve their portion of commission from seller&apos;s agent? 25 answers Did condo prices fall recently? Is this a good time to buy a condo? 13 answers What is your opinion about Repton Place in Watertown.? 7 answers I am saving some searches but they are not getting saved. Why? 3 answers I&apos;ve found a property and look for a flat fee buyers agent. may you recommend one? 3 answers I&apos;ve found a property and look for a flat fee buyers agent. may you recommend one? 2 answers We are considering to buy a condo in Malden, but we wonder if the trend on this area might continue going down even after the overall real estate 3 answers View recent questions More local advice More Advice: 
 Recent Q&amp;A in Watertown, MA Recent blog posts in Watertown, MA Find a real estate professional Watertown, MA 
 
 Send this property to a friend 5 Repton Cir 111, Watertown MA $179,900 , 1 ba , Apt/Condo/Twnhm Friend&apos;s email: [+] Add another friend&apos;s email Your email: Your name:
 (optional) Message:
 (optional) Cancel Send 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Done       

 My Notes Done Save a personal note that only you can view. Clear Save my note       

 Report Listing Error 5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA Error Type: Please select... Property Sold/Withdrawn Price has changed Incorrect Agent/Broker Link Doesn&apos;t Work Incorrect Photo Incorrect Property Details Incorrect Map Other   Current Revised Price: $179,900 $ Property Type: Apt/Condo/Twnhm Select One Single-Family Home Condo Townhouse Coop Apartment Loft TIC Apartment/Condo/Townhouse Mobile/Manufactured Farm/Ranch Lot/Land Multi-Family Income/Investment Houseboat Unknown Listing Type: -- Select One Resale New Home Beds: n/a Baths: 1 Sqft: 566 Lot size:
 (acres) n/a Year Built: 2007     Please remove this listing
until this issue is resolved Details: Your name Your email
 (optional): 
 Cancel Send 
 Done       

 Ask a question about this property Sorry, we couldn’t find contact information for this agent. Try asking your question on Trulia Voices below. 
 Did you know? You can ask the Trulia Voices community about this property to get information and advice from real estate experts and locals .
 150 characters left Question Ask real estate experts,locals, and friends... 1000 characters left More Details (Optional) Optional details about your question This question is about this property: http://www.trulia.com/property/3030391100-5-Repton-Cir-111-Watertown-MA-02472   Get email alerts as people answer my question ASK!       

 Success! DONE       
 6b193982949324c230886678c4ad2999 
 What do you think of this area? 
Thanks! Your review has been submitted

Thanks! Both your review and ratings have been submitted
 
Thanks! Your changes have been saved
 Done We are collecting ratings for the surrounding area, not for this or any other specific property or listing.       
 
 Communities near 5 Repton Cir 111, Watertown 
 Watertown Real Estate Watertown Real Estate Watertown Foreclosures Watertown Apartments/Condos/Townhomes 02472 Real Estate 02472 Apartments/Condos/Townhomes 02472 Apartments for Rent Watertown Apartments for Rent 
 
 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Cambridge Homes for Sale East Watertown Homes for Sale North Cambridge Homes for Sale Allston Homes for Sale Brighton Homes for Sale New Town Homes for Sale See All Nearby Cities 
 
 Real Estate and Mortgage Guides Watertown Real Estate Guide Watertown Schools Middlesex County Home Prices Heat Map Massachusetts Home Prices Heat Map Watertown Mortgage Watertown Refinance Watertown Home Loan 
 

 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Cambridge Homes for Sale East Watertown Homes for Sale North Cambridge Homes for Sale Allston Homes for Sale Brighton Homes for Sale New Town Homes for Sale Belmont Homes for Sale Waverley Homes for Sale Riverside Homes for Sale West Somerville Homes for Sale       

Residential Real Estate

 San Francisco real estate  |  New York real estate  |  Los Angeles real estate  |  Orlando real estate  |  Miami real estate  |  Philadelphia real estate  |  Phoenix real estate  |  San Diego real estate  |  San Jose real estate  |  Chicago real estate  |  Arizona real estate  |  California real estate  |  Florida real estate  |  Illinois real estate  |  Massachusetts real estate  |  New Jersey real estate  |  Pennsylvania real estate  |  Texas real estate  |  Other local real estate  |  California apartments  |  New York apartments  |  Texas apartments  |  Apartments for rent  |  Home price maps  |  Real estate community  |  U.S. Property records 
 
Explore Trulia

 Homes for Sale  |  Homes for Rent  |  Stats&amp;Trends  |  Real Estate Advice  |  Real Estate Apps  |  Trulia Labs  |  Trulia API  |  Trulia Estimates 
 
For Professionals

 Agents  |  Brokers  |  MLS  |  Advertisers&amp;Partners  |  Tools&amp;Widgets  |  Submit Your Listings  |  Real Estate Leads 
 
Corporate

 About Trulia  |  News Room  |  Trulia Blog  |  Careers  |  Privacy  |  Terms of Use  |  Subscription Terms of Use  |  Community Guidelines 
 This Apt/Condo/Twnhm is located at 5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA. 5 Repton Cir 111 is in the 02472 ZIP code in Watertown, MA. The average listing price for ZIP code 02472 is $425,155. 5 Repton Cir 111 has 1 bath, approximately 566 square feet, and was built in 2007 Copyright©2012
 Trulia, Inc. All rights reserved. |  Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity Have a question? Visit our Help Center to find the answer 
 
 $179,900 5 Repton Circle 111, Watertown MA
 Follow Share Contact agent
	</body>
</document>
