<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003709" url="http://www.delish.com/food/recalls-reviews/fast-food-fish-fridays-for-lent" time="2012-07-12-19:52" support="3" score="0.021721694829840814" bingtitle="Fast Food Fish for Lent - Fish Sandwiches Offered at Fast Food ..." webtitle="Fast Food Fish for Lent - Fish Sandwiches Offered at Fast Food Restaurants - Delish.com">
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>Check out the fish sandwiches offered at fast-food restaurants during Lent.</description>
	<body>
		Cocktails • Grilling • Summery Bites MSN Search: Search recipes Search this site Search the web Recipes&amp;Menus Popular Recipes Cookies Chicken Pasta Desserts Drinks Appetizers Lunch Dinner Under 30 Minutes Low Calorie Kids Comfort Food Chinese Mexican Special Features Recipe Finder My Recipebook Delish Cooking School Delish Cupcakes by Color The Essential Wine Guide Martha Stewart&apos;s Recipes Appetite for Life Summer Treats Grilling Guide Celebrate the Olympics Healthy Summer Meals Bold Flavors Poolside Snacks Kitchen Savings Easy Entertaining Guide Hints&amp;Help Recipe Videos Measurement Equivalents Ingredient Equivalents Substitution Ideas Metric Conversions Freshness Guide Flower Arranging Table Settings Napkin Folding Food in the News Blogs Food in the News Best of the Food Blogs News&amp;Events Award-Winning Recipes Chefs&amp;Shows Taste of Place Kitchen Cookoff World&apos;s Best Chefs Dinner&amp;a DVD Chefs at Home Parties&amp;Holidays Holidays Labor Day Halloween Thanksgiving Hanukkah Christmas New Year&apos;s Valentine&apos;s Day Easter Cinco de Mayo Mother&apos;s Day Memorial Day Father&apos;s Day Fourth of July Parties Baby Showers Bridal Showers Cocktail Parties Dinner Parties Graduation Grilling and Barbecue Kids&apos; Parties Picnics Weddings Super Bowl Parties Special Features Invitations&amp;eCards Coupons&amp;Deals Coupons Fun&amp;Games Quizzes Games Recipe Contests My Recipebook My Recipebook Create a Recipe My Shopping Lists My CookChat ™ Edit Profile 
 Home » Blogs, News&amp;Events » Food in the News » (Fast Food) Fish Fridays for Lent 
 
 Food in the News 
 
Serving up all the latest food news, cool foodie products, gossip, and good deals that are fit to print!
 Search this Blog: Email Print Comments Share High Gas Prices Affecting Restaurant Business Food in the News   Sweet (Salty, Savory, Sour and Spicy) Dreams: Food and Your Dreams Posted in: 
(Fast Food) Fish Fridays for Lent
 March 10, 2011 at 9:06 AM by Katie Robbins |  Comment 
 

We&apos;ve officially entered the Lenten season, which means
there&apos;s something fishy going on in the nation&apos;s fast food chains. To cater to
observant Catholics and members of other Christian faiths who abstain from
eating meat on Fridays during Lent, restaurants around the country roll out
limited time seafood specials.

Though it&apos;s now offered year round, even what is arguably
the nation&apos;s most famous fish sandwich, McDonald&apos;s Filet-O-Fish, was created to
offer a meatless option for &quot;Fish Fridays.&quot; In 1962, Cincinnati McDonald&apos;s
franchisee Lou Groen invented the sandwich to compensate for plummeting burger
sales during Lent.

 More from Delish: Find the Perfect Fish Sandwich to Enjoy 

 

Here&apos;s a look at some of the other fishy (and a few veggie)
fast food options popular this time of year:



 Wendy&apos;s Premium Fish Fillet : Available for a limited time (and marketed with the pretty
catchy slogan &quot;Oh my cod&quot;), the sandwich features panko-encrusted North Pacific
cod, lettuce and tartar sauce.

 

 

 KFC Fish Snacker: In 2007 KFC launched this fried fillet of Alaskan Pollock,
served with tartar sauce on a sesame seed bun.

 Arby&apos;s Fish Sandwich : A limited time fried Pollock sandwich from the roast beef
specialist.

 

 
 

 Taco Bell Pacific Shrimp Taco and Burrito: This week Taco Bell rereleased its crustacean taco (chipotle
marinated shrimp, avocado ranch, salsa, and lettuce) and introduced its burrito
cousin.

 

 More from Delish: Fresh Fillings - Fish Tacos Recipes 

 What-a-Burger&apos;s Whatacatch : The regional burger chain wins big points for its cleverly
named fish fillet sandwich.

 Jack in the Box Fish Sandwich: Served with the requisite lettuce, tartar sauce and sesame
seed bun, Jack&apos;s version comes with not one, but two battered fillets of
Alaskan Pillock. For Lent the chain is offering the sandwich as part of a
limited combo meal, with small fries and a drink for $2.99.

 

 More from Delish: Ten Swoon-Worthy Grilled Cheese Sandwiches 

 In-N-Out ; Five Guys Grilled Cheese : For a truly meatless experience, try grilled cheese from
these regional burger darlings. And, not to worry if you get hooked - they&apos;re
available year round.

 

 



 

 

 
  Comment Permalink Tools: Email Print Comments Share Tags:  fast food , KFC , mcdonald&apos;s , lent , in-n-out , Whataburger , wendy&apos;s , Jack in the Box , arby&apos;s , Five Gys 
Posted by Katie Robbins
She has written for Saveur , Psychology Today , BlackBook , theatlantic.com, and LA Weekly&apos;s blog, Squid Ink, among other publications. Although her writing is generally of a culinary persuasion, she has covered issues such as the New Orleans school system, America&apos;s health insurance crisis, and the Secret Service for PBS NewsHour , ABC News, and the National Geographic Channel.
While hard-pressed to pick an actual favorite, some foods that stand out in her memory as exemplary are rabbit escabeche in Ushuaia, Argentina; Russ and Daughters&apos; white fish salad in New York City; kua kling phat tha lung (dry beef curry) in Los Angeles; and mustard based barbecue in Columbia, SC. Read More 
 Find all posts by Katie Robbins Contact Katie Robbins 
 

 Advertisement 
Post a Comment

When using Facebook Connect your image and name may display on Delish. All privacy settings are controlled by Facebook.
 High Gas Prices Affecting Restaurant Business Food in the News   Sweet (Salty, Savory, Sour and Spicy) Dreams: Food and Your Dreams 
 Advertisement 
 
 
 About this Blog: Curious about the latest fast-food freebie? Looking for the dish on the newest cooking-show star? Delish&apos;s Food in the News blog provides daily reports on all things food. From wacky trends to the media frenzy surrounding product recalls, our bloggers will satiate your appetite for all that&apos;s newsworthy in food. Read More Subscribe to this blog via RSS 
 Girl Scout Cookies Get Deep Fried at State Fair of Texas Successful Sandwich Chain, Cheba Hut, is Marijuana-Themed 7-Eleven Giving Away Free Slurpees to Celebrate 85th Birthday Cows In France Fed Fine Red Wine to Improve the Beef New Breakfast Sandwich Uses Waffles as Bread, Plus Other Crazy Sandwich Creations 
 
 Illegal Marijuana Dispensary Found Selling&quot;Baked&quot;Goods in Restaurant Back Room $460,000 Bottle of Whisky Crowned World&apos;s Most Expensive Cold Brew Coffee and Other Summer Food Trends About This Blog &quot;Foie You!&quot;Dinner Defies California Foie Gras Ban 
 Categories: Archives: Tags: alcohol   beer   burger king   burgers   candy   celebrity chefs   children   china   chocolate   Christmas   coffee   diet   e. coli   fast food   fast foods   FDA   food history   food safety   food science   freebies   ground beef   health   holidays   hunger   ice cream   jamie oliver   japan   kids   mcdonald&apos;s   mcdonalds   nutrition   pizza   recall   recalls   recipes   research   restaurant news   restaurants   Salmonella   school lunch   seafood   soda   starbucks   studies   study   Thanksgiving   usda   weird food   white castle   wine Blog Roll: 

 MSN Search: Search recipes Search this site Search the web Cocktails • Grilling • Summery Bites 
Delish

 Home Site Map Site Tour About Us Feedback Advertise Online About Our Ads Privacy Policy Your California Privacy Rights Terms of Use Free Newsletters Community Guidelines RSS Topics 
 
Delish.com

 Cooking Basics: Tips&amp;Recipes Easy Weeknight Recipes Grilling Guide 100+ Chicken Recipes Recipes for Chocolate Lovers Italian Recipes&amp;Cooking Tips Favorite Cookie Recipes Healthy Family Recipes Cupcake Recipes&amp;Decorating Tips Pie Central: Recipes&amp;Tips Easy No-Cook Recipes Slow-Cooker Recipes 
 
Home&amp;Decor
 Small Apartment Decor Entryway Ideas Kitchen Remodeling Bathroom Remodeling DIY Decorating Ideas Kitchen Designs Dressing Tables Window Dressings Table Setting Ideas Family Room Decorating Decorating Ideas 
Food&amp;Recipes
 Salmon Recipes Chicken Breast Recipes Sweet Potato Fries Low Fat Desserts Low-Calorie Recipes French Macaron Recipe Soup Recipes Ground Turkey Recipes 
Seasonal Ideas
 Fruity Alcoholic Drinks Picnic Recipes Summer Sandwiches Grilled Chicken Recipes Picnic Food Ideas Watermelon Recipes Fish Taco Recipe Summer Salads Summer Fruit Desserts Hamburger Recipes Salad Recipes 
How-To&amp;Crafts
 Fabric Drawer Pulls Napkin Ring Craft How to Lose 20 Pounds Bedroom Lighting How to Get Organized How to Fold Napkins Best Blenders Best Paint Colors DIY Home Decor Sew a Button 
 
 
Delish on Twitter
 @delishcom 
Delish on Pinterest
 Sign up for Delish&apos;s free newsletters! ©2012 Hearst Communications Inc. All Rights Reserved. | Why did I get this ad?
	</body>
</document>
