<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003616" url="http://ireport.cnn.com/docs/DOC-675865" time="2012-07-12-19:47" support="2" score="0.002605776831912241" bingtitle="Are you ready for New Menu Labeling? - CNN iReport" webtitle="Are you ready for New Menu Labeling? - CNN iReport">
			<query id="001250" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>Yet, instead of running, they are driving to the nearest fast food restaurant. ... Will they throw caution to the wind and order a slice or will they run for ...</description>
	<body>
		You&apos;ve selected the U.S. Edition. Would you like to make this your default edition? YES | NO Close  
 EDITION: U.S. CNN INTERNATIONAL MÉXICO CNN ARABIC 
 
 Home Video NewsPulse U.S. World Politics Justice Entertainment Tech Health Living Travel Opinion iReport Money Sports 
 
 SIGN UP | LOG IN 
 
 
 
 1  of 2       
Share this on:
  Facebook  Twitter  Tumblr  E-mail 
  Tweet 
 
 
 56 
VIEWS   
RECOMMENDS 0 
SHARES About this iReport Not vetted for CNN 
 
 Posted September 19, 2011
 by LG091911   | Follow 
 Location
Atlanta, Georgia 
 
 
 More iReports you should see 
 Paterno: saved by death By  omekongo Meeting and greeting By    nsaidi &apos;Twas the preview night before SDCC By    nsaidi Columbus ohio By  unclaimed Because of the Internet...I&apos;m in Japan By  maddogza 
 
Are you ready for New Menu Labeling?
 By LG091911  | Posted September 19, 2011 | Atlanta, Georgia   
 CNN PRODUCER NOTE    
 


 Written by – Lisa Giles, MS, RD, LD, CDE 

 New menu labeling regulations are just over the horizon. Many large national restaurant chains have had their nutrition information available at point of purchase for years. This article is aimed at the rest of you who are waiting until the final rules come in. It you haven’t already, it would be a good idea to begin preparing now. 

 

 As a registered dietitian and diabetes educator, I have been telling my patients about the proposed menu labeling rules for some time now. I am looking forward to their implementation because this valuable information will help them make more informed choices. On the flip side, I have also worked with both retail and hospital food service operations and understand the struggle from your end as well. It is a big responsibility to communicate this level of detailed information to your customers in a cost effective way that is clear, concise, and most importantly, accurate. Many may see it as forced compliance, but from where I am standing, it is information worth providing. 

 

 The bottom line is people need to know what they are eating. Just as they can look at a Nutrition Facts panel on packaged foods in the grocery store, that same type of transparency is appreciated when eating out at a restaurant. Let’s take a brief look at what this legislation may require, taking into consideration America’s collective health status and insight from the new Dietary Guidelines for Americans 2010 . Then, we’ll look at how your food service operation can begin preparations now to meet this challenge. A product relatively new to this country may be your secret weapon to help you improve nutrient content of menu items and save money at the same time. 

 

 The Proposed Rules 

 On April 6, 2011, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) released proposed rules for “nutrition labeling of standard menu items in restaurants and similar retail food establishments.” This will require restaurants that are part of a chain with 20 or more locations to provide calorie and other nutrition information for their customers. [i] On June 5, 2011, the National Restaurant Association (NRA) filed their comments regarding the proposed rules on behalf of the over 250,000 restaurants that will be affected. [ii] Final rules are expected before the end of the year once they have had time to review all industry comments. 

 

 The good news is that these new rules have the potential to offer national consistency, taking the place of inconsistent menu labeling laws that have been enacted in some states and local jurisdictions. They will hopefully offer clarity where there was none. Some of the proposed rules require menu or menu boards to include the following information: [iii] 

 

 · A posting of calories contained in each standard menu item as usually prepared and offered for sale. 

 · A short statement concerning suggested daily calorie intake to help the public understand the context of a total daily diet. For example: “A 2,000 calorie diet is being used as a basis for general nutrition advice. However, individual calorie needs may vary.” [iv] 

 · A statement noting the availability of additional written nutrition information upon request. This may include total fat, saturated fat, trans fat, cholesterol, sodium, total carbohydrate, dietary fiber, sugars and protein. 

 

 Once the many details are ironed out and the final rules are announced, the FDA is proposing restaurants will have 6 months to comply, while The National Restaurant Association (NRA) proposes an implementation period of no less than one year. [v] That means at the earliest, you likely have until mid-2012 to get ready. To stay updated, visit www.restaurant.org/menulabeling. 

 

 Why the Rush? 

 Because swift compliance is expected to yield “significant public health benefits,” [vi] the FDA states that it is reasonable to make these requirements effective sooner rather than later. Therefore, the potential health benefit of an informed consumer outweighs the cost of implementation. The costs to you will include nutrient analysis of your menu items, replacing menus and menu boards, training your staff, and promotion and marketing efforts. 

 

 The beneficiary of your hard work will be the American public, whose collective health status is not good. The hope is that efforts like menu labeling, among others, will have a positive impact on one of the most alarming issues facing this country - the fast climbing rate of obesity in all age groups. Recent data indicate that more than two-thirds of adults and more than one-third of children in the U.S. are overweight or obese. [vii] In the early 1990’s, there were no states having an adult obesity rate of more than 25 percent. Fast forward to 2008, where 32 states had an adult obesity rate exceeding 25 percent. [viii] Poor eating habits and lack of physical activity are prime factors in this epidemic. 

 

 As obesity rates rise, so do other diet-related chronic diseases. The new Dietary Guidelines for Americans 2010 site the “heavy toll” this is taking. For example, over a third of Americans have cardiovascular disease, [ix] and a third could have type 2 diabetes by 2050 if current trends continue. [x] This is likely since over a third of the population ages 20 or older have pre-diabetes. [xi] And, almost one in two men and women will be diagnosed with cancer in their lifetime. [xii] My patients are living proof of these statistics every day. Hectic schedules, lack of physical activity, and eating whatever, whenever are taking a toll. 

 

 Americans Eat Out – A Lot 

 When I evaluate the food records of my new patients, I often tell them they are eating enough to feed a marathon runner. Yet, instead of running, they are driving to the nearest fast food restaurant. It seems most people do not have time to cook anymore. The days of dining to together as a family have fallen by the wayside. Taking its place - grabbing a quick bite between ballet and soccer practice or rushing from one meeting to the next. All this means big money to restaurants that see these busy folks come through their doors or drive-throughs daily. 

 

 Americans now consume an estimated one-third of their total calories and spend almost half of their food dollars on foods prepared outside the home. [xiii] According to the new Dietary Guidelines for American’s 2010 , “the overall environment in which many Americans now live, work, learn, and play has contributed to the obesity epidemic.” As a whole, we have become a victim of our “obesogenic environment.” [xiv] Research has shown that communities with a larger number of fast food or quick service restaurants tend to be more overweight. The fact that the proportion of daily calories eaten away from home has increased makes sense considering the number of these restaurants has more than doubled since the 1970’s. [xv] Average daily calories available per person in the marketplace have increased approximately 600 calories over this time, with the greatest increases coming from added fats and oils, grains, dairy products, and caloric sweeteners. [xvi] Portion sizes have also increased. 

 

 These trends are no surprise to me. In fact, when patients leave diabetes education class, they aren’t heading home to eat; they are usually heading to a restaurant nearby. I end most classes by reinforcing strategies for putting their nutrition knowledge into practice when they get there. 

 

 Education is the Key 

 Unfortunately, many of my patients did not begin to make wise choices until after they were diagnosed with a chronic disease like type 2 diabetes. The sad truth is it could have been prevented with healthy eating habits and regular physical activity. My ultimate goal is to educate people to make health-minded choices up front so they don’t become another statistic. With so many Americans eating out, it will be crucial for them to learn to use menu labeling to their benefit. It will not be enough for people to merely glance at the calorie or fat amount. It will take understanding how to put these numbers in context of their individual needs. How do the numbers relate to me? Helping customers understand this will be key as new menu labeling rules go into effect. 

 

 For example, let’s say your individual needs are 1600 calories per day. In keeping with the Dietary Guidelines for Americans , you are trying to keep your saturated fat at 10 percent of your calorie intake (18 g) and you are keeping sodium less than 2300 mg per day. If your deluxe breaded chicken sandwich with cheese, large fries and a small shake bring you to 1570 calories, 25 g saturated fat and 2410 mg sodium, you can see how one trip through the drive-through will max out your whole day. Hopefully, education will help consumers connect the dots and make this type of meal a rare treat – which may elevate lower calorie items to your bestseller list. 

 

 The New Dietary Guidelines are Worth a Look 

 The newest installment of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans 2010 reflects the current downward health spiral. These guidelines are published every 5 years by The U.S. Department of Agriculture and The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. This new edition has a more serious tone in keeping with current health trends. Where earlier editions were intended for “healthy” Americans, this version takes into consideration the serious health issues related to our rising obesity epidemic. These new guidelines are aimed at Americans 2 years and older, “including those at increased risk of chronic diseases.” [xvii] 

 

 As I comb the pages of this 95-page document, I can see how restaurant owners can use it as a helpful reference. (Download a copy at www.dietaryguidelines.gov.) Your menu offerings and new menu labeling can help your customers put these guidelines into practice. Creative menu development and recipe modification can help reduce solid fats (sources of saturated and trans fatty acids), added sugars, and sodium. But you don’t always have to subtract. You can add more fruits, vegetables, whole grains, lower-fat dairy products, seafood and heart healthy oils (e.g. olive, canola) as the guidelines suggest. 

 

 A Shift Toward Healthy Eating Grows Stronger 

 Thankfully, all the attention now being paid to our national health crisis is forcing a shift toward healthy eating – a trend worth embracing. The National Restaurant Association’s Chef Survey: What’s Hot in 2011 attests to this with the inclusion of “nutrition/health” and “children’s nutrition” listed in their top 20 trends. [xviii] Even the deli industry is taking notice as the cover story for the April/May 2011 edition of Deli Business, entitled “Eating Better,” points out. It discusses how this shift is prompting the manufacturers of deli foods to reconfigure their tried and true recipes. It brings up the universal challenge - to make food taste as good, if not better, than the products they replace . [xix] 

 

 Even with widespread education, will customers use menu labels? As I talk to my patients, they usually fall into three categories – 1) those that don’t care and never will, 2) those that always try to eat healthy and will always check the menu information, and 3) those that want to eat healthy but don’t know how to use the information. These last two categories are where menu information will be a driver influencing buying behavior. They will be the impetus for restaurant owners to join this healthy eating trend for the long haul. 

 

 Step 1 - Take a Close Look at Your Recipes 

 The first step and the biggest challenge you will face in complying with new menu labeling rules will be standardizing your recipes. This will have to be done up front to prepare them for analysis to estimate their nutrient content. Most restaurants will turn to using a computerized database as a “reasonable basis” for determining this, [xx] also known as nutrient calculation or nutrient analysis by database . [xxi] You may be thinking about investing in computerized database software and doing it yourself. The catch is, without a professional with culinary expertise and special training in recipe analysis, accuracy will be questionable at best. 

 

 It’s all in the details. You will have to keep fine points like these in mind: Are you using white meat, dark meat or skinless chicken? Does the tomato have peel or seeds? Is the salt Kosher or iodized table salt (Kosher contains less sodium)? How does cooking change the original ingredients? Did you pour fat off during preparation? That needs to be accounted for and then subtracted from the total. How much oil do you add to the pan or grill while cooking? Do you make flavor adjustments before serving like adding salt? All these details and more need to be accounted for before you are ready to analyze your recipes. 

 

 Wait, There is More . . . 

 If you do it yourself, once the analysis is complete, you may not know how to interpret the numbers or how to communicate them to your consumers. It would be wise to call in an expert. A registered dietitian (RD) with culinary expertise, specializing in recipe and menu analysis is your best resource. These experts understand the legislative background and can help with recipe standardization, nutrient analysis, and also guide you in how to communicate this information to your customers. In April, the American Dietetic Association (ADA) announced a new Certificate of Training Program in Restaurant Menu Labeling to help RD’s better respond to anticipated demand for their services as restaurants begin to comply with new labeling rules. This training program was developed as a combined effort of the ADA Menu Labeling Work Group and the NRA. [xxii] To find dietitian resources in your area, contact your local or state dietetic or restaurant associations. These groups will likely have a contact list of professionals who offer this type of service. 

 

 What To Do When the Numbers Roll In? 

 When the nutrient analysis is complete, you may be dumbstruck that your house favorite fettuccine Alfredo contains a jaw-dropping 1220 calories or that the chocolate mousse cake contains 760 calories per slice. What will patrons think when they see these numbers? Will they throw caution to the wind and order a slice or will they run for hills? If they are part of the first group of customers mentioned earlier that don’t care, you are in luck, but what if they fall into one of the other two groups trying to eat healthy? Then what? 

 

 Recipe modification is a viable option worth considering. But, what will make the biggest impact? The first thing customers will see is the calorie level staring them straight in the face. If you want to improve this number, reducing fat should be the first place to go. This is because fat has twice the calories per gram (9 kcal/g) compared to carbohydrate and protein (4 kcal/g each). But fat carries flavor. How can you reduce it and still have good taste that customers require? After all, a lower calorie item that lacks flavor won’t help anyone. As restaurant owners and chefs look for options to lighten their recipes, they will surely look to innovative products to help them improve nutritional content without sacrificing taste or quality. 

 

 QimiQ® to the Rescue 

 This little known product with a funny name has the ability to improve your nutrient analysis results and create a product that tastes as good as the original. The word “QimiQ” is a word blend stemming from the words “quick” and “milk,” paying tribute to how quick and easy this product is to use. It is a dairy product made from 99% cream (15% fat content) and 1% top quality gelatin that is Ultra Heat Treated (UHT) to ensure a long shelf life. It is 100% natural without chemical additives such as preservatives, stabilizers, artificial flavoring and artificial trans fat. It is guaranteed to succeed in all areas of cooking with full taste, despite 50% less fat than traditional cream products. You can use it in recipes to (completely or partially) replace gelatin, heavy cream, butter, egg and starch. [xxiii] This gives you potential never seen before to drastically reduce the total calorie content, fat and cholesterol in your items. And, since fat sources will bring with it the most calories, this product can be a secret weapon for recipe modification. 

 

 Does all of this sound too good to be true? I thought so too until I researched this item for myself. It owes its unique abilities to its patented production process. According to Chef Hans Mandl, when he began working on this discovery twenty years ago in Austria, it was very “calculated.” He was looking for three things: 1) an all-natural product, 2) lower in fat, and 3) offering a clean label. He achieved this and more by taking sensitive milk protein, coating it with milk fat from cream using a physical process, and then adding a thin layer of gelatin. This stabilizes the product and provides superior functionality, enabling its unique application possibilities. Most importantly – it has the ability to be an excellent flavor carrier with significantly less fat content. 

 

 The Nutritional Benefits are Many 

 Chef Mandl sees the possibilities of his discovery coming full circle. He says when he began development years ago, no one was interested, “there was no such thing as 15% cream, most people were very active and obesity was not an issue.” Fast-forward 20 years and the nutritional benefits QimiQ® offers is in high demand. 

 It can help you achieve the following recipe magic that you may have thought impossible: [xxiv] 

 

 · Mayonnaise, dips and salad sauces that contain up to 64% less fat and 79% less cholesterol than traditional mayonnaise recipes. 

 · Creams, mousses and sliceable gateau fillings that contain up to 25% less fat and 37% less –cholesterol than traditional recipes made with cream and eggs. 

 · Spreads and sandwich fillings that contain up to 80% less fat than traditional recipes made with butter or mayonnaise. 

 · Soups and sauces that contain 67% less fat than traditional recipes refined with heavy cream. 

 

 Some of Europe’s largest food service operations have been taking advantage of these attributes for years. According to Mandl, the European Union is as interested in promoting health as the U.S. with stringent food labeling requirements for supermarket labels. He says menu labeling will be coming to their restaurants too. 

 

 The U.S. just recently began realizing the many advantages QimiQ® has to offer when Atlanta Foods International began distribution here in the states two years ago. It is used in huge operations like King Soopers, Morrison’s and the Hyatt to name a few. Vice President and Corporate Executive Chef Helmut Holzer, CMC , WGMC of Atlanta Foods was instrumental in bringing QimiQ® to the U.S. He travels around the country to work with restaurants and food service outlets large and small to demonstrate how they can incorporate QimiQ® into their menu items. According to Certified Master Chef Holzer, his goal is to “get clients to the threshold” of trying something new. From there, he wants to build a “long-term relationship” with his customers. This relationship includes perks no other product can boast. Holzer and his team will examine your recipes and offer guidance on those that can benefit most from QimiQ®. They will help you modify your recipes and provide the computer analysis for those containing QimiQ®. All this is at no extra cost. 

 

 At a recent taste demonstration in Atlanta for Smith&amp;Sons (S&amp;S) Foods Incorporated, the team offered samples of fifteen S&amp;S recipes they had modified to include QimiQ®, from vegetable lasagna and macaroni and cheese to cream potatoes and red velvet cake. Mike McCasland, their regional director remarked after the taste demonstration, “I am more than pleased – plus the simplicity of it.” Holzer’s team is now moving forward to modify recipes for them to use in hospital facilities where they manage food service operations. Once this process is complete, training for S&amp;S kitchen staff will be offered to ensure a smooth transition. 

 

 According to Holzer, “there is no other product like it.” His customers agree. Patrick Gebrayel, Executive Chef and owner of Heywood’s in Marietta, Georgia says, 

 “QimiQ® being an all natural product is just a plus for me, but if you look at the ingredients, there are only three – cream, milk and gelatin - products that any kitchen would have. I cannot think of any product that can do so much and still save money.“ This savings comes from using fewer ingredients like eggs and butter, shorter production times, and increased shelf life since products retain their shape, consistency and appearance longer. This cost savings is a plus since you will be spending extra dollars on recipe analysis and revamping your menus. To learn more visit www.QimiQ.com or send an email to QimiQ@atlantafoods.com . 

 

 Putting It All Together 

 Yes, new menu labeling rules are coming soon, and given America’s current health status, it has been a long time coming. You may not know the final details, but you know enough to get started. The new Dietary Guidelines for American’s 2010 can offer valuable insight and hopefully spark ideas for creating more health-minded menu items. Gather your recipes and begin to standardize them in preparation for nutrient analysis. Call in a professional such as a registered dietitian (RD) who specializes in menu and recipe analysis to help you with this tedious, detailed process to ensure the most accurate results possible. Finally, consider utilizing an innovative product like QimiQ® to help you improve the nutritional content of your menu items and save money at the same time. All this preparation and forward thinking will help you # meet this challenge and become part of a healthy eating trend that is here to stay. My patients will thank you. 
 
 
 [i] Food and Drug Administration. Proposed Rule, Food Labeling: Nutrition Labeling of Standard Menu Items in Restaurants and Similar Retail Food Establishments. 76 Fed. Reg. 19192 ( April 6, 2011 ). http://edocket.access.gpo.gov/2011/2011-7940.htm . 
 
 [ii] National Restaurant Association. National Restaurant Association Files Menu Labeling Comments. [press release]. http://www.restaurant.org/pressroom/pressrelease/?ID=2134 . 
 
 [iii] 76 Fed. Reg. 19193 (April 6, 2011). 
 
 [iv] 76 Fed. Reg. 19209 (April 6, 2011). 
 
 [v] National Restaurant Association. National Restaurant Association Files Menu Labeling Comments. [press release]. http://www.restaurant.org/pressroom/pressrelease/?ID=2134 . 
 
 [vi] 76 Fed. Reg. 19219 (April 6, 2011). 
 
 [vii] U.S. Department of Agriculture. USDA and HHS Announce New Dietary Guidelines to Help American’s Make Healthier Food Choices and Confront Obesity Epidemic. [press release]. http://www.fns.usda.gov/cga/pressreleases/2011/0040.htm . 
 
 [viii] Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. U.S. Obesity Trends. 

 http://www.cdc.gov/obesity/data/trends.html . 
 
 [ix] American Heart Association, Heart Disease and Stroke Statistics, 2010 Update At-A-Glance. http://dbbs.wustl.edu/dbbs/website.nsf/forms/forms/$file/HeartStrokeUpdate2010.pdf 
 
 [x] Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Number of Americans with Diabetes Projected to Double or Triple by 2050. [press release] http://www.cdc.gov/media/pressrel/2010/r101022.html 
 
 [xi] Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. National Diabetes Fact Sheet, 2007. http://www.cdc.gov/diabetes/pubs/pdf/ndfs_2007.pdf . 
 
 [xii] National Cancer Institute. Surveillance Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) Stat Fact Sheets: All Sites. http://seer.cancer.gov/statfacts/html/all.html . 
 
 [xiii] 76 Fed. Reg. 19192 (April 6, 2011) 
 
 [xiv] U.S. Department of Agriculture and U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Dietary Guidelines for Americans, 2010. 7 th Edition, December 2010; 10. http://www.cnpp.usda.gov/Publications/DietaryGuidelines/2010/PolicyDoc/PolicyDoc.pdf 
 
 [xv] Stewart H, Blisard N, Jolliffe D. Let’s Eat Out: American’s weigh taste, convenience, and nutrition. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Economic Research Service; 2006 Economic Information Bulletin No. 19. http://www.ers.usda.gov/publications/eib19/eib19.pdf . 
 
 [xvi] Adjusted for spoilage and other waste. ERS Food Availability (per capita) Data System. http://www.ers.usda.gov/Data/FoodConsumption . 
 
 [xvii] U.S. Department of Agriculture and U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Dietary Guidelines for Americans, 2010. 7 th Edition. December 2010. Executive Summary; viii. 
 
 [xviii] National Restaurant Association. Chef Survey: What’s Hot in 2011. http://www.restaurant.org/pdfs/research/whats_hot_2011.pdf 
 
 [xix] Ramirez J, Eating Better. Deli Business. April/May 19, 2011; 19. 
 
 [xx] 76 Fed. Reg. 19235 (April 6, 2011). 
 
 [xxi] Powers C, Hess M, Kimbrough M, How Accurate Are Your Nutrient Calculations? Why Culinary Expertise Makes a Difference. J Am Diet Assoc. 2008;108:1418. 
 
 [xxii] American Dietetic Association. Food and Culinary Professionals Practice Group. ADA News and Views. New Online Certificate of Training Program in Restaurant Menu Labeling. April 1, 2011. http://www.foodculinaryprofs.org/fcp.cfm?page=ada_information 
 
 [xxiii] Handels GmbH. Qimiq® Product Information – Classic, Whip, Sauce Base. March 15, 2011 ; 2, 6. 
 
 [xxiv] Qimiq® Product Information. March 15, 2011 ; 8. 

 

 
 
 TAGS: 

 
What do you think of this story?
 Select one of the options below. Your feedback will help tell CNN producers what to do with this iReport. If you&apos;d like, you can explain your choice in the comments below. Be and editor! Choose an option below: 
 
 
Comments 
 Log in to comment 
iReport welcomes a lively discussion, so comments on iReports are not pre-screened before they
 post. See the iReport community guidelines for details about content that is not welcome on iReport.
 
 iReport 101
 About | Blog Community Guidelines Meet the Team Terms of Use 
 We are Everywhere
 Facebook Twitter Tumblr Flickr 
 Get Help
 StoryTelling Toolkit FAQs Contact Us Advertising Contacts 
 Tools
 How to post iReports CNN Mobile apps 
 
 Home Video NewsPulse U.S. World Politics Justice Entertainment Tech Health Living Travel Opinion iReport Money Sports 

 Tools&amp;widgets RSS Podcasts Blogs CNN mobile My profile E-mail alerts CNN shop Site map 
 
 ©2011 Cable News Network. Turner Broadcasting System, Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Terms of service Privacy guidelines Advertising practices Advertise with us About us Contact us Help 
 
 CNN en ESPAÑOL CNN Chile CNN Expansión 

 CNN TV HLN Transcripts 
 Welcome! Let&apos;s get started. 
 Member Log In 
 
 Reset Successful 

 Log in now. 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me for two weeks 
 Forgot Password 

 Enter your e-mail address below and we will send you an e-mail with a link and reset code to reset your password. 
 Continue if you already have the reset code 
 Password Selection 
 
 Grab the reset code we e-mailed to you.
Type it in, and create your new password. 
 
 Create your new password 
 
 Sign Up   Be sure to fill in everything with an * 
 
 Providing your contact information helps us verify your stories to include in CNN coverage. 

 
 Can&apos;t read this? 
 
 By clicking on &quot;sign up&quot; you agree with CNN&apos;s Terms of Service , CNN iReport&apos;s Terms of Service , and CNN&apos;s Privacy Policy and consent to the collection, storage and use of this information in the U.S. subject to U.S. laws and regulations. (learn more) 

 For our international users, please be aware that the information you submit when registering for our services is collected in the United States of America. In addition to being subject to our Privacy Policy, the collection, storage, and use of your data will be subject to U.S. laws and regulations, which may be different from the laws and regulations of your home country. By registering for this service, you are consenting to this collection, storage, and use. 
 
Create your screen name

Please create a screen name. This screen name will be associated with your
iReport stories and comments on this site.
It cannot be changed once you make a selection.
 
Select one with 3-12 characters, numbers and letters only
	</body>
</document>
