<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003927" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/article/1489602/nikos_nikos_in_houston_texas_restaurant.html" time="2012-07-12-20:06" support="2" score="0.006678271227407554" bingtitle="Nikos Nikos in Houston, Texas: Restaurant Review - Fast Greek Food ..." webtitle="Nikos Nikos in Houston, Texas: Restaurant Review  - Fast Greek Food with Long Lines, Big Crowds and Average Food - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>Fortunately Nikos Nikos is a fast food restaurant where you order at the front, receive a buzzer, and find a seat. ... for 15 years - it made it OK for me to spit out my food in ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Nikos Nikos in Houston, Texas: Restaurant Review - Fast Greek Food with Long Lines, Big Crowds and Average Food
 Bobbi Leder , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Feb 26, 2009 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Houston Texas Greek Food Restaurant Reviews Texas Restaurants 
 Flag Close Post a comment Nikos Nikos Neighborhood: Montrose
Houston, TX 77006
United States of America Apparently I am in the minority when it comes to my opinion of the Greek restaurant, Nikos Nikos , in Houston, Texas. It has won numerous awards - including awards for being clean - however I can&apos;t find any recent awards; no the most recent one was back in 2005 so maybe I&apos;m not in the minority after all.
My big gripe with Nikos Nikos is that it is an expensive joint with uneven floors, massive crowds and average food. You&apos;d never know the economy was down in the dumps with the amount of Houstonians lining up to eat on a Saturday afternoon.

 Parking 

If you live in the Montrose area then consider walking to Nikos Nikos because parking is a nightmare. Despite having a large parking lot, drivers were waiting anxiously for customers to exit so they could take their parking spot - imagine a supermarket the day before a hurricane. We finally found a spot after playing tactical games with the other cars, and made our way to the entrance only to find ourselves waiting in a long line.

Fortunately Nikos Nikos is a fast food restaurant where you order at the front, receive a buzzer, and find a seat. When your buzzer flashes it&apos;s time for you to go to the pick-up counter and get your food, so that made ordering much faster than we had anticipated. We grabbed a menu and decided to share the hummus as an appetizer - it turned out to be a smart move since that was one of the menu items they had made plenty of which meant we didn&apos;t have to wait long for it. We wound up waiting 20 minutes for our entrees but we were given advance notice so we were prepared.

 Appetizer 

The hummus was green and tasted like it was mixed with cucumber but the flavor was not overwhelming. One large pita (sliced into several pieces) was served with the hummus as well as bell pepper slices, tomato slices, and Kalamata olives. Part of the pita was baked and crispy while the other slices were soft and fluffy. I suspected the soft ones were put in the microwave but my husband did not concur. The half order of hummus cost $5.95 which is a bit high for an appetizer in a joint if you ask me.

 Entrees 

 Greek Salad 

I ordered the small Greek salad ($4.75) and added grilled chicken breast ($3.75). The salad had all of the usual suspects: lettuce, tomatoes, Kalamata olives, feta cheese (in a block that looked like tofu), and even one banana pepper. The grilled chicken had a lot of fatty gristle in it so I was glad I had been with my husband for 15 years - it made it OK for me to spit out my food in front of him. The salad dressing was all at the bottom and tasted better as I went along, but I wish they would have tossed the salad more. The portion size did not look large but because I had the hummus and pita as an appetizer and added the grilled chicken, the Greek salad was too big for me to eat all at once. So my husband grabbed a plastic cover for my plastic container - yes, that&apos;s how they serve the food - and I ate the rest at home.

 Gyro 

My husband had the gyro sandwich ($7.95) which along with the Greek salad seemed to be the most popular item on the menu. He said it was hard to eat because it was so messy but he enjoyed it nonetheless. His gyro sandwich came with a huge plate of fries - and I mean huge - so I thought his meal was better value than mine.

 Nikos Nikos has good food but it&apos;s not amazing enough to warrant their popularity, especially considering there are so many restaurants in the Houston area that serve similar cuisine.

 Atmosphere 

The wooden booths were wobbly (which made it uncomfortable for me whenever the patrons sitting at the table behind me moved), the floors were uneven and dangerous, and the long lines made it difficult to get to the soda fountain area where the plastic utensils were - notice the trend, only plastic is served at Nikos Nikos.

Although I was glad to know Nikos Nikos puts an emphasis on having a clean restaurant, I found it a bit off-putting that the cleaning woman swept every five seconds by our table. The one thing that struck me about Nikos Nikos was its popularity with people of all ages, classes, and ethnicities. I guess Houstonians really like their Greek food no matter where they come from.

 Contact Information 

Nikos Nikos is located at 2520 Montrose Boulevard, Houston, Texas, 77006. Their phone number is 713-528-4976. To view their menu or find out more about Nikos Nikos visit their web site at http://www.nikonikos.com .
 
Published by Bobbi Leder 

Bobbi Leder is the author of the picture book, THE SECRET POLICE DOG. Leder has been published with a variety of print and web-based magazines, websites, anthologies, and newspapers.  View profile 
 
 Hotel Guide: Houston, Texas There are some amazing hotels in Houston, Texas. The only problem is - there are some amazing hotels. That&apos;s why I reviewed the top three of these hotels for potential guests. Houston DWI Defense Conviction of a DWI (Driving While Intoxicated) offense in Houston can produce a negative stain on your record for the rest of your life. Texas Attractions: Houston Visitor Center Houston visitor&apos;s center is an attraction in itself, with over 7000 square feet of space holding displays, replicas, items for sale, thousands of pamplets and brochures and a fi... Halloween Houston Haunts! Suggestions for where to go for a good scare on Halloween in Houston, TX, and an suggestion for a kid-friendly Halloween event as well. Smoking Ban in Houston: Specious Reasoning, Cynical Politics, or Just Plain Stupid?! The Houston City Council, ignoring their own commissioned study done by major Texas universities, have banned smoking in order to clean the air of the most polluted city in the U.S. 

 Product Review: Kraft Greek Vina... Review of Wishbone Italian Salad... Exploring Town Lake in Austin, T... 
 
 Houston, Texas&apos; Top 5 Gay Bars Best Places to Buy Christmas Trees in Texas Lottery and Gambling Options in the State of Texas Mysterious Caddo Lake and Other East Texas Travel Destinations The Travelers Guide to RV Renting in Houston Texas East Texas Reacts to Over 400 Water Utilities Being Cited for Non-Compliance Since... Employment Staffing Agencies in Houston, Texas 
 
 
 
 Resources 
 
 www.nikonikos.com 
 
10 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Linda M. McCloud 3/5/2009 
Great review. Very well written.
 Sheri Fresonke Harper 3/4/2009 
Maybe it was just because it was busy, well written :) Sheri
 SAIKAT KUMAR DUTTA 3/3/2009 
very good review...
 Sheryl Young 3/3/2009 
Altho&apos; not leaving a comment on each, your food reviews make me so hungry. Doesn&apos;t every city have a Greek restaurant called Niko&apos;s? (Ours is Nikko&apos;s with 2 k&apos;s).
 Baconator 3/2/2009 
Yet another great honest review!
 Sophie 3/2/2009 
Sorry to hear about the food. Gyros?!! It irks me to read about so-called &quot;Greek&quot; food that is not actual, authentic Greek fare.
Sophie
 cheryl m brown 2/28/2009 
Good review. I love Greek salad. Don&apos;t think I would visit this place...I really don&apos;t like plastic utensils...especially for salad!
 Nikki 2/26/2009 
bummer!
 Kay Whittenhauer 2/26/2009 
Doesn&apos;t it kill you when everyone makes a big deal out of something that you find mediocre? Sometimes restaurants are popular by default, meaning that there&apos;s really nothing else around that&apos;s better and since this one has never been bad we&apos;ll go there. We had one like that called Bogey&apos;s that we frequented often... after saying, &quot;Bogey&apos;s by default?&quot;
 jobythebay 2/26/2009 
One food that I&apos;ve never tasted and never will are olives:)
 
 Displaying Comments 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Travel. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
