<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003651" url="http://www.bestfreestuffguide.com/Free_Sbarro%27s_Italian_Eatery_Coupons" time="2012-07-12-19:49" support="3" score="0.001487972324023488" bingtitle="Free Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery Coupons - Best Free Stuff Guide" webtitle="Free Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery Coupons - Best Free Stuff Guide">
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery is an Italian-themed fast food restaurant chain primarily found in ... After dining at the restaurant, look on your receipt for a website link or ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery Coupons
 
From Best Free Stuff Guide
 Jump to: navigation , search 

Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery is an Italian-themed fast food restaurant chain primarily found in mall food courts and highway rest areas. Sbarro coupons may be offered for a BOGO (buy one, get one) deal, dollars off savings or for a percentage savings on your entire purchase. Coupons often vary by franchise location. Sbarro pizza coupons can also be found in mall-specific coupon books, Valpak mailers , and Entertainment Coupon Books .


 
 
 Flickr: playfullibrarian Founded 1956 Owned by MidOcean Partners [1] Phone number 1-800-456-GUEST Type of Food Italian and Pizza Types of coupons BOGO, dollars off, percent off   


 

 
 



 
Contents
 
 1 About Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery 2 Sbarro Italian Eatery Coupons 3 Sbarro Menu 4 References 
 
 
 About Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery 

Founded in 1956 in Brooklyn, New York by an Italian family, Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery broke from its roots as a neighborhood grocery store and eatery in 1967 when the first mall-based restaurant was established. The restaurant maintains that it focuses on fast, yet fresh fare. [2] 

In addition to pizza, the chain serves pasta, meatballs, salad, and other Italian entree items in a buffet that&apos;s priced by the pound.
 
 Sbarro Italian Eatery Coupons 

 One of the most routine methods of receiving coupons is by filling out a &quot;Guest Experience Survey.&quot; After dining at the restaurant, look on your receipt for a website link or phone number to complete a short survey. In exchange for completing the survey, you will be given a coupon code good for 25% off your next Sbarro purchase. [3] Some local &quot;The Entertainment Book&quot; editions include coupons for Sbarro. [4] Coupon booklets distributed by local malls may include money saving coupons for food court-based restaurants. Groups visiting New York City can take advantage of Sbarro specials for breakfast, lunch or a dinner buffet. Groups of up to 175 can be accommodated with at least one day&apos;s notice. Sbarro locations are convenient to many NYC attractions such as Chinatown, Times Square and Madison Square Garden. [5] 
 
 Sbarro Menu 

Menu items can vary by day and by location, but generally include pasta, pizza, salad and Italian entrées. If you are so inclined, you can also sample desserts and other treats. All items are offered in single-serve portions.

Specific menu items include New York-style thin-crust pizzas topped with pepperoni or sausage, specialty pizzas and deep dish pizza options. If the pizza you want is not immediately available, you may be able to order a whole pizza. The chain also offers stromboli, spaghetti, baked Ziti, lasagna, chicken parmigiana and meatballs. [6] 



 A visual overview of some of the Sbarro&apos;s Italian Eatery menu items. 
 Also See: Free Papa John&apos;s Pizza Coupons , Free Pizza Hut Coupons , Free Domino&apos;s Pizza Coupons , Free Pizza Coupons , Free Godfather&apos;s Pizza Coupons , Free Olive Garden Coupons 

 

 

 

 
 
 References 

 ↑ http://sbarro.com/aboutUs/history.php ↑ http://sbarro.com/aboutUs/history.php ↑ https://research.tlg.com/collector/Survey.ashx?Name=SBarroFeedback&amp;Loginid=?source=sbcs ↑ http://www.entertainment.com/discount/Sbarro/coupon/12111180121RED00126992EPC00496999PRD00000001.html;jsessionid=6+lpjTesQwhN9rRfFZD9OQ**.register3v ↑ http://sbarro.com/groups/newyork.php ↑ http://sbarro.com/ourFood/entrees.php 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.bestfreestuffguide.com/Free_Sbarro%27s_Italian_Eatery_Coupons &quot; Categories : Coupons | Free Food | Free Restaurant Food | BOGO Offers 
 
 
 
 Search 
 Advanced search 
Views
 
 Page Discussion View source History 
 
Personal tools
 
 Log in / create account 
 
Navigation
 
 Home Restaurants Stores Help Contact Us 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Special pages Printable version Permanent link 
 
 This page was last modified on 3 July 2012, at 14:20. This page has been accessed 2,530 times. Privacy policy About Best Free Stuff Guide Disclaimers
	</body>
</document>
