<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003228" url="http://www.whattoexpect.com/forums/hot-topics-1/archives/what-would-you-do-if-ou-found-cash-in-a-store.html" time="2012-07-12-19:21" support="2" score="0.0007455328929739328" bingtitle="What would you do if ou found cash in a store? - Hot Topics - What ..." webtitle="What would you do if ou found cash in a store? - Hot Topics - What to Expect.com">
			<query id="001000" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Log-in with your What To Expect Account ... and I thought it was just a single 5 dollar bill ... Well we went to a local fast food restaurant one day on the weekend.</description>
	<body>
		3 Things To Do Today » Save on baby accessories » Introduce new foods to your baby » Get prepared for childbirth 
 
Follow Us On
 Sign in Close Register 
Log-in to What To Expect with one click!
 
 OR 
 Log-in with your What To Expect Account: 
E-Mail Address:
 
Password:
 Forgot Your Password? That&apos;s ok, we can send you a new one. Click Here 
 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler 
 
 Community Groups 
 Community Find a Group Start a Group My Preferences 
 Blogs 
 Word of Mom 
 Members&amp;Friends 
 Meet Members 
 Photos 
 Recent Photos Popular Photos 
 Local Resources 
 New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Find Groups Near You 
 Contests&amp;Deals 
 Diaper Deals Feeding Deals Wipes Deals More Family Deals Photo Contests Group Giveaways The WTE Bookstore 
 
 
 
 Group Main Page Message Board Events Meet Group Members Email Group Members Group Settings Browse All Groups My Preferences 
Related Articles
 
 Our First Community Swimming Pool Experience Cool Mother and the Neighborhood Pool Party Toddlers and Swimming Pool Safety Toddler Water Safety- What To Do When They Hate The Pool Ways to Prevent Toddler Drowning 
 
 Get great deals up to 90% off 
 for mom, baby, and the whole family 
 
 Featured Deal 

 55% Off Comfy (and Cool) Baby Carriers 
Show off your baby and your sense of style with this adjustable baby carrier from Hotslings.

 Get This Deal 
 
 Advertisement 


 Find a Group Whether you&apos;re looking for support from other expecting moms, a playgroup in your hometown, or even a Glee fan club, WTE has groups you&apos;ll love. Find a group now or start your own group . Advertisement Community » Groups » Hot Topics » Archives »What would you do if ou found cash in a store? Hide Signatures Share this discussion: 
What would you do if ou found cash in a store?
 Next Discussion» From: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 05:23 PM (1 of 50) 
So a couple weeks ago I had $40 in my back pocket. I went grocery shopping and forgot to take it out. I keep my phone in the same pocket. I got to the check out and pulled my phone out of my poket to give her a fabric sticker. Then went to get the money out and it was not in mypacket :( I said something to the checkout lady about dropping $40 (she was being trained so there was 2 ladies there) I went around the store and looked for it, of course I did not find it. I left my name and number just in case. When I went back up to the ladies to let them know didn&apos;t find it, the one lady said that right after I said I dropped the money, she saw the man behind me bend over, pick something up and then he immediately went to anther register. He was with his family. She said it didn&apos;t register right away that he may have picked up my money.

If you found money would you turn it in?

I was really bummed I lost the money. I know I should have taken it out of my pocket (which I meant to do) I believe in karma, so if the man picked up my money and left with it, he will get his.

I have turned in money before. I did find a $20 in a parking lot of a mini strip mall. I did keep that though, since there were several stores and it was really dirty. It looked like it may have been there for a little while. Maybe this was my payback for that money. Who knows!
 
 

 

 
 From: LegenWAIT4ITdary To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 05:26 PM via the iPhone app (2 of 50) 
If I saw someone drop it I would definitely give it back. If I didn&apos;t; I honestly don&apos;t know. I guess it depends where I was.
 
   

   

  

 






 
 From: Master_debater To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 05:26 PM (3 of 50) 
Finders keepers..

Seriously though it would depend on the place I found it and the amount/way its found.
 



 




 From: kiwi_berry33 To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 05:36 PM (4 of 50) 
He was right behind you and didn&apos;t say anything when you dropped it? What a jerk! I would have been super p!ssed!
I&apos;ve seen people drop money and I&apos;ve stopped them and gave it back to them.

10 dollars was the most I ever found (two 5&apos;s were folded up and I thought it was just a single 5 dollar bill)and it was by a school and everyone had gone home for the day. I decided to be a jerk... I kept it. If people were still around, I more than likely would have gone to the office and turned it in.

I guess depending on how much I found and where I found it, I&apos;d more than likely turn it in, though.
 From: jocelyn81889 To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 05:37 PM (5 of 50) 
If I saw money fall out of someone&apos;s pocket/purse, I&apos;d let them know. But If I just see money somewhere and didn&apos;t see who it came from, I&apos;m not going to look for the owner. I&apos;m keeping it.

If I was in line behind you and heard you mention you dropped 40$ and I saw it on the ground beside me, I&apos;d pick it up and give it to you.
 
 &quot;If religious people could be reasoned with, there would be no religious people.&quot; 
 &quot;I dislike arguments of any kind. They are always vulgar and often convincing.&quot; 


 
Jack Channing Lockhart
Born 6.26.2011 9:15am
6lbs, 7oz; 21 in long

 From: chambette To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 05:46 PM (6 of 50) 
Yeah, if I saw someone looking around for some money...or saw someone actually drop it, I would definitely give it back. But I have to be honest...I found $40 in the parking lot of a shopping center one time. I did look around to make sure no one was walking around&quot;looking for something&quot;. There was no one around, so I kept it. 

Sorry you lost your money though :( sucks when that happens. I don&apos;t know...I like to think when I lose money like that, that a lady with 4 kids and part time job whose husband has run off and left her and her children are starving, finds it. And it&apos;s like the answer to her prayers you know?
 




 

 

 
 
 
 From: SexyNamesR4Uglies To: jocelyn81889 Posted: May-12 05:52 PM (7 of 50) 
&quot;If I saw money fall out of someone&apos;s pocket/purse, I&apos;d let them know. 
But If I just see money somewhere and didn&apos;t see who it came from, I&apos;m 
not going to look for the owner. I&apos;m keeping it.&quot;

Ditto.
 
 


 
 From: getoveryourself To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:03 PM (8 of 50) 

If I found money in a store I would leave my phone number with customer service. 

If I found money in the street I would keep it. 

I have found cell phones before and called everyone in the phone book. I have found purses, wallets and money. I have never had a problem finding the owner. 

My step dads mother found money in a back envelope with the slip. She kept it. My mother never talked to her again haha.

 From: anne_2 To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:04 PM via the iPhone app (9 of 50) 
It is horrible to watch somebody drop money and then keep it. You know exactly where it came from, so there&apos;s no excuse in not giving it back.
I found money ($12) one time in a hospital. I brought it to the information desk and told them where I had found it. The woman seemed completely uninterested in an explannation. I&apos;m betting she took the $12 home, based on our interaction.
I think it depends. If you find $20 blowing around in an empty field somewhere, you are obviously never going to be able to find the person who lost it.
That man that took your money has no morals! What if you were buying necessities for your family and that was your only money???
 From: holysmokes To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:09 PM (10 of 50) 
Yeah, keeping cash that you just witnessed someone drop right in front of you is pretty low. I have had this happen with store coupons that are treated like cash (like DSW rewards or Kohls cash)...fell out of my purse while I was getting my wallet out, person behind me in line scooped it up and used it on their purchases.  Scummy.

But random cash just laying there? Eh, open season.  I found a $100 bill on the ground on a hiking trail once.......no one around, had not seen another person on the trail the entire time. That puppy was mine! 

Like the person you would turn this lost cash into wouldn&apos;t end up pocketing it anyway.
 
 
      From: Perdita To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:14 PM via the iPhone app (11 of 50) 
As most have said, if I saw who dropped the money I would, and have, give them their money back. But if there wasn&apos;t anyone around I would keep it.

I&apos;ve worked retail management for the last 6 years. I&apos;ve had many good Samaritans turn cash that they&apos;ve found while shopping but I have never had anyone actually come looking for the lost money.
 

 
 From: jesslynn8705 To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:31 PM (12 of 50) 

About 2 years ago DH and I were at Toys R Us and we were leaving. I looked down and saw a bank envelope so I kicked it and it was heavy. I picked it up and took it to the car, when I opened it it was full of 20&apos;s. I counted it and there was $720 in it and I was soooo excited until I found the womans i.d. DH told me I should keep it because if she is irresponsible enough to lose all that money then it must not have been important to her. I just couldn&apos;t take the money and know who it belonged to so I went back into the store and made sure they called the police to get inform the woman. They said if she didn&apos;t pick it up I could have it back and I left my name and number. Well I never heard any more of it and honestly I was kind of bummed to not even get a thank you. I didn&apos;t expect a reward just a simple thanks for not stealing anything from me. DH said&quot;see you should have kept it, that was probably her allowance from her husband and she didn&apos;t care whether she lost it or not.&quot;Still I think it was the right thing to do because I&apos;d hope if it happened to me a nice person would do the same.

 From: BrycensMomJasonsWife To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:43 PM (13 of 50) 
If I saw someone drop the money I always give it back to the person, if I find it somewhere then I say finder&apos;s keepers... However when I was 17 we stopped at a gas station about 3 hours away from my house and when I went to wash my hands in the bathroom there was an envelope full of 100 dollar bills, $1200 to be exact which happened to be the exact ammount needed to pay our rent, so I stuck it in my pocket and left... about 3 months later though I was home alone after having surgery at 8 months pregnant and one of my boyfriends friends stopped by to pick up his hat that he had left the night before, there was $900 sitting on our table and I went and got his hat, fell back asleep and when my boyfriend got home we realized it was missing, it was out Christmas money :( So I chalked that one up to karma.
 
 

 
      
 
 
 

 Jason and Lacey 

 

 Brycen Christopher 12-21-07 

 
 From: Kater85 To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 06:59 PM (14 of 50) 
I would turn it into the customer service desk. If I saw someone drop it I would definitely give it back to them. I&apos;m suprised at how many people would just keep it if they didn&apos;t see anyone drop it. Maybe I would if it was like $5 because I doubt anyone would come back looking for it.
   

 

 
   From: mommy2jackncaitie To: ALL Posted: May-12 07:01 PM (15 of 50) 
It was at walmart that is happened.

I guess I just hope she was wrong and it wasn&apos;t them, because that is way uncool if they did that. I could have really used that $40, but it didn&apos;t mean I couldn&apos;t get my groceries. If it wasn&apos;t them, then I really hope it was someone who needed it!

the money I turned in was in a store, it was quite a while ago.

it is kind of funny, when the check out lady told me about the guy she whispered that he was&quot;mexican&quot;. So was she....

wow, the amount that some of you have found, if only I could be that lucky lol! I do agree that money found in random places you can keep.

to the PP where the ladies DL was in it, I think that was for sure the right thing to do, giving her the money back. Although you are right, even a thank you would have been nice!
 
 

 

 
 From: JustAName To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 07:13 PM (16 of 50) 
If I found a large sum of money, and I would consider $40 to be a large sum just laying around, I would try to turn it in, if I was in an area where I could turn it in.

My ex from high school used to cash his entire checks. I always told him it was stupid, but he did it anyways. Well we went to a local fast food restaurant one day on the weekend. He had just cashed his cash, so there was nearly $1,000 in his wallet. All we did was stop in and eat then go home. He had his wallet when he paid, he did not have his wallet when we got home. Seeing that it was not in his car, we knew it had to have been left behind at the restaurant. Needless to say it was never turned in. I think it is pretty sh**ty that someone would NOT turn in a wallet, with that much cash in it, if they found it right there locally in a restaurant. Even if they stole the cash, couldn&apos;t they have at least turned in the wallet? The ex. had to cancel his debit card, get a new drivers license, etc. Needless to say he learned his lesson on cashing his whole checks.
   
 
 
 From: AbigailRose To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 07:36 PM (17 of 50) 
I am a firm believer in karma.  I would turn in something that did not belong to me, especially if there was ID attached.  If cash was randomly lying around and it was a small amount, I&apos;d pick it up and pass it on (to a waitress or someone).  I&apos;d feel guilty keeping something that I did not earn.

 I am a teacher and currently have a student teacher.  She donated $10 to our field trip fund in case anyone couldn&apos;t pay.  All of the kids could pay so I passed on that $10 to an elderly guy in front of me in line at the grocery store.  He was completely confused as to why his debit card wasn&apos;t working.   (His account was out of money.) He didn&apos;t ask me for $, but I had the $10 that wasn&apos;t meant for me, so I passed it on.   Maybe he swindled me, but I doubt it. 

 If more people were honest and kind, then the world would be a much better place. 
 
   
 From: amribeiro To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 07:47 PM (18 of 50) 
If I saw you drop it I would either pick it up and hand it to your or tell you that you dropped it. If I just found it I would turn it in. Last year I was leaving the bank and found an envelope in the parking lot, it had $1200 dollars and a bank reciept in it. I went back into the bank wher a police officer I know happened to be in line I told her about it, her and I both went to the bank manager to report finding it. They were able to look up the customer information off the banking reciept, turns out it belonged to our Chief of Police.I&apos;m a firm believer in Karma so anything I find will get turned in, well I draw the line at turning in change (quarters, nickels, dimes or pennies) unless it&apos;s a whole bag of them. I would hope that someone would do the same if I dropped it.
   
 

 

 
 From: Mama2KOA To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 07:51 PM (19 of 50) 
In a parking lot where I dont know who/when it was dropped... woohoo, my lucky day.

In a checkout line, even if I didnt see someone drop it, I&apos;m going to pick it up and ask the people around me if someone dropped&quot;any money&quot;. If it&apos;s enough of an amount, I might ask how much they think dropped. I know how I&apos;d feel if I&apos;d lost it.

That being said, this past weekend my family and I were in IHOP when the waitress went running into the parking lot. The person she&apos;d waited on had dropped $200 on the floor under the table and she found it. Instead of pocketing, she chased them down in the parking lot and returned the money. I thought it was great and tipped her extra for her honesty.
 From: Kwoppy To: mommy2jackncaitie Posted: May-12 07:51 PM (20 of 50) 
If I actually saw who dropped it I would absolutely give it back to them. If it were right next to someone I would ask if they dropped it. If no one where around I would probably keep it unless it was a large amount (probably over $100), then I would turn it in to someone.
 www.lettersfromazoo.blogspot.com 

 
     
 
   
 From: Jenneskimo To: ALL Posted: May-12 07:51 PM via the iPhone app (21 of 50) 
Oi. I have had $300 stolen out of my wallet before, I feel your pain.

If I saw the person who dropped the money, I would return it to them.

If it was laying there with no one around, I would take it. What&apos;s the difference between that and stealing, you ask? My $300 was stolen by the lost and found worker. If I found it and could not return it, I would keep it because unfortunately there are less honest people than me out there. I&apos;d be afraid the lost and found people would pocket the money without even thinking about who lost it in the first place.

Frankly, I am NOT well off, at all, but I still value honesty over the extra bag of groceries that would keep me fed. Some people just aren&apos;t like that.
 Back to Hot Topics Archives «Previous 1 2 3 Next» 
 
 
Browse

 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler Community Family Deals 
 
About

 About What to Expect What to Expect Foundation What to Expect Bookstore Everyday Health Network Contact Us Word of Mom 

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Advertising/Editorial Policy Advertise With Us Partnerships Press Room 

 Facebook Twitter Pinterest Help Feedback Careers 
 The material on this website is provided for educational purposes only and is not to be used for medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment, or in place of therapy or medical care. See additional information . Use of this site is subject to our terms of use and privacy policy. Advertising Notice 
This Site and third parties who place advertisements on this Site may collect and use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like to obtain more information about these advertising practices and to make choices about online behavioral advertising, please click here
	</body>
</document>
