<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003783" url="http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/archive/index.php/t-518519.html" time="2012-07-12-19:56" support="6" score="0.007922046802581718" bingtitle="The Ethics of Getting a Free Drink Refill [Archive] - Straight ..." webtitle="The Ethics of Getting a Free Drink Refill [Archive]  - Straight Dope Message Board">
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="143"/>
	<description>... shocked and said it wasn&apos;t right to get another drink ... Every fast food restaurant I&apos;ve ever encountered has had this ... who keep a McDonald&apos;s coffee cup in their car ...</description>
	<body>
		Straight Dope Message Board &gt; Main &gt; In My Humble Opinion (IMHO) &gt;The Ethics of Getting a Free Drink Refill PDA 
View Full Version : The Ethics of Getting a Free Drink Refill 
 Fiddle Peghead 05-22-2009, 02:07 PM I was at a restaurant with my brother the other day where the soda machine is in the dining area and customers get their own drinks. After finishing my drink, I went back for a refill (actually just a few swigs, not a full glass, which is what I usually do). My brother was somewhat shocked and said it wasn&apos;t right to get another drink without paying. I was taken aback because I always figured that going back for more was okay. I reasoned that the purpose of putting the soda machine in the dining area was to free up the workers from the task of getting drinks, thereby cutting down on personnel needed and saving the restaurant some money, which would more than make up for the cost of soda refills. Further, and correct me if I&apos;m wrong, but from my days working in fast food many years ago, I believe the profit margin on a soda is huge for the restaurant, because you&apos;re paying a few dollars for what is essentially water and bit of high fructose corn syrup, so even if every customer got a full refill (which of course they don&apos;t), the restaurant would come out ahead anyway. And finally, if free refills weren&apos;t allowed, I would think that there would be a sign to that effect, which I have never, ever seen.

So, what say you? Are refills okay or not? Also, if you thought before reading this that getting a refill was unethical, but my reasoning has changed your mind, please let me know. And finally, if you have never stopped to consider the ethics of the refill, let me know that too. For some reason, I think that will be the case for most of you normal people. :) Amp 05-22-2009, 02:12 PM Free re-fills on fountain drinks is de facto now a days. If the restaurant didn&apos;t allow free refills I would think a sign would be up saying so. Freudian Slit 05-22-2009, 02:13 PM I read some post where the poster admitted to asking for an empty water cup and then filling up at the fountain area. I&apos;m not sure who it was...but that would probably really freak out your brother. The Hamster King 05-22-2009, 02:15 PM If a restaurant makes the soda machine publicly available to me, I&apos;m going to assume they don&apos;t care if I get a refill. If they don&apos;t want me to, they should post a sign.

It&apos;s just like with salad bars. Some places limit you to one trip through, but they make a point of telling you. Fiddle Peghead 05-22-2009, 02:18 PM And it&apos;s not that my brother is especially uptight, in fact he&apos;s just the opposite, except for a few weird things like this. When applying to a job while in college, he took one of those personality profile tests, and when asked if he ever stole anything at another job, he admitted to taking french fries on occasion without paying for them, especially if they were past their prime, so to speak. He didn&apos;t get the job. Bayard 05-22-2009, 02:24 PM I also assume that if the soda machine is in the dining area, free refills are allowed. I probably wouldn&apos;t bring in my own Culligan water bottle and hold it under the spigot, but I&apos;ve never been squeamish about topping off the cup before I leave. Maybe I&apos;ve been violating the rules all along, though. Rigamarole 05-22-2009, 02:25 PM Weird. Just refill it, nobody cares. (if you want an actual number by the way, at the restaurant I worked at the profit margin was about 2000% on a soft drink - we sold them for $2.49 with a cost to us of $0.12-0.13) bouv 05-22-2009, 02:37 PM Weird. Just refill it, nobody cares. (if you want an actual number by the way, at the restaurant I worked at the profit margin was about 2000% on a soft drink - we sold them for $2.49 with a cost to us of $0.12-0.13)

It&apos;s about double that where I work (my manager said it costs us almost $0.25 a glass.) I don&apos;t work in fast-food, though, it&apos;s a&quot;sit-down and wait&quot;type of restaurant, so there&apos;s a higher overhead for everything. But still, even in our case, a customer would have to have about nine refills before they started costing us money...and that&apos;s assuming they didn&apos;t order any food. Driver8 05-22-2009, 02:50 PM There is no ethical dilemma here, in the United States unless otherwise posted refills are free. It is a part of the local social contract: the restaurant is selling you as much soda as you want to drink while you are in the store. They understand this, you understand this, everything is good.

There are of course limitations to this: you can&apos;t ask for a water cup and then fill it with soda. Nor should you leave the store and keep coming back for&quot;free&quot;refills.

This is not necessarily true in other countries, although typically you can&apos;t make this mistake because the soda machine is not publicly accessible. Swallowed My Cellphone 05-22-2009, 02:57 PM In Canada, if it&apos;s a fast food place where the soda fountains are in the dining room and accessible to everyone, refills are free (I&apos;ve seen very few of these in Ontario). In such cases, the soda cups are distinguishable from water cups (usually enormous with colorful graphics), so if you just get a cup of water (plain white styrofoam) then try to cheat and fill it at the soda fountain, they will get mad.

In the fast food places where the soda fountains are behind the counter and accessible only by staff, refills are usually not free.

If you&apos;re in a moderately priced place (say, on par with TGI Fridays) where they serve you at the table, you should check the menu carefully or ask the wait staff because YMMV in those establishments. Lynn Bodoni 05-22-2009, 03:01 PM If the soda machine is accessible, the place expects you to get your own refills. I&apos;ve never seen this in a full-service restaurant, just in fast food places.

When I worked in a movie theater, soda was incredibly cheap, so cheap that we were generally allowed to bring in our own cups and fill them up. This place didn&apos;t like to give us more than a handful of free popcorn at a time, too, so soda MUST have been cheap then.

Each person has to purchase one bottomless cup, of course, no sharing. And asking for a water cup and filling it with soda is right out. It&apos;s OK to fill up the disposable cup and take it with you as you leave. In fact, in some regular restaurants they ask me if I want a cup of tea or whatever to take with me, no extra charge. It&apos;s a cheap way of getting some goodwill. Gary T 05-22-2009, 03:04 PM My brother was somewhat shocked and said it wasn&apos;t right to get another drink without paying.~Twenty years ago that was the norm; free refills were unusual. Nowadays, it&apos;s the other way &apos;round - free soda refills are the norm, even where they must be brought by the server.

Your brother&apos;s ethics are a few decades out of date. Contrapuntal 05-22-2009, 03:10 PM When applying to a job while in college, he took one of those personality profile tests, and when asked if he ever stole anything at another job, he admitted to taking french fries on occasion without paying for them, especially if they were past their prime, so to speak. He didn&apos;t get the job.Well, to be fair, that might not be the reason. Finagle 05-22-2009, 03:19 PM There is no ethical dilemma here, in the United States unless otherwise posted refills are free. It is a part of the local social contract: the restaurant is selling you as much soda as you want to drink while you are in the store. They understand this, you understand this, everything is good.


Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups? KneadToKnow 05-22-2009, 03:23 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?

Because people are stupid keep buying them. friedo 05-22-2009, 03:25 PM Your brother is completely insane and needs to be locked up before he attempts to assassinate Mayor McCheese for conspiring with the Hamburglar to embezzle a 55-gallon drum of Dr. Pepper syrup. Swallowed My Cellphone 05-22-2009, 03:25 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?The places I&apos;ve seen that had the fountains accessible in the dining room, as far as I remember, had only one size of soda cup: pee-your-pants-ginormous!

But I haven&apos;t seen a free refill soda fountain in years and years (don&apos;t go to fast food places) so I can&apos;t tell you what it may be like now. Cliffy 05-22-2009, 03:27 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?

Because it&apos;s worth the extra forty cents for some consumers not to have to get up and fill the cup every minute and a half.

--Cliffy sugar and spice 05-22-2009, 03:28 PM People getting food&quot;to go&quot;will pay more for the big cup. It&apos;s only an extra $.50 or so, some people just don&apos;t worry about change.

And I agree, if the fountain is in the eating area then it&apos;s free refills until you walk out the door. Otherwise they&apos;d keep them behind the counter. Freudian Slit 05-22-2009, 03:31 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?

For people who are eating to go, maybe? Lynn Bodoni 05-22-2009, 03:37 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups? In my case, I buy the large because I have bad knees and a bad back. Getting up HURTS, I have to use my cane or stick, and even then, there&apos;s a chance I&apos;ll fall down. I&apos;d rather pay the extra half dollar for a large and not have to get up for any refills. Half a buck doesn&apos;t make a difference to me.

Small, medium, and large are also useful for&quot;to go&quot;orders. If you&apos;re gonna take your food back to your office or shop, you might want a large drink to sip on all afternoon. The price difference between large and small is almost certainly less than the price of a vending machine soda at work. Telemark 05-22-2009, 03:37 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?
Because many people buy fast food to go. Kingspades 05-22-2009, 03:43 PM In the fast food places where the soda fountains are behind the counter and accessible only by staff, refills are usually not free.
The one notable exception to this in the States seems to be Wendy&apos;s: refills are free, but up until a couple of months ago I&apos;d never seen a store with the soda fountain in the dining room. As it is I&apos;ve only spotted it that one time, and Wendy&apos;s is about my favorite fast food. brad_d 05-22-2009, 03:51 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?Most fast-food joints also sell their food to go, and in such a case it clearly makes sense to offer multiple sizes of drinks - those customers won&apos;t be around to avail themselves of the free refills, and can decide how much drink they want to buy.

Given that multiple sizes are on the menu, then, it wouldn&apos;t make a lot of sense for them to restrict dine-in customers to only purchasing the smallest size. Somebody who wanted a large, for whatever reason, would not be pleased to be told they couldn&apos;t have one unless they were ordering their food to go. That would just be a silly move on the restaurant&apos;s part, pissing off a customer for absolutely no reason (and turning down a larger sale in the process). Contrapuntal 05-22-2009, 04:23 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?I&apos;m going to go out on a limb here and suggest that the different cup sizes are due to the fact that some patrons wish to purchase their comestibles for consumption off premises. voguevixen 05-22-2009, 04:24 PM The one notable exception to this in the States seems to be Wendy&apos;s: refills are free, but up until a couple of months ago I&apos;d never seen a store with the soda fountain in the dining room. As it is I&apos;ve only spotted it that one time, and Wendy&apos;s is about my favorite fast food.

I wanted to point this out too - even if the fountain ISN&apos;T open to the public sometimes they&apos;ll give you a free refill if you ask. Our Wendy&apos;s does as well. Not sure if that&apos;s true of every Wendy&apos;s. Diogenes the Cynic 05-22-2009, 04:37 PM I&apos;ve never seen an establishment with customer accessible soda fountains that did not intend for refills to be free. You&apos;re really only paying for the cup and the access, not any specific quantity of soda. If they did want to charge for refills, they&apos;d have no chance to collect on them by putting the fountains in the dining room with no signs. I can&apos;t swear that no establishnent anywhere has never done this, but I think it would be extremely unlikely and extremely hard to enforce. YamatoTwinkie 05-22-2009, 05:05 PM I&apos;ve never seen an establishment with customer accessible soda fountains that did not intend for refills to be free

I&apos;ve seen establishments that do this (usually large cafeterias), but the cash register separates it from the dining area. ivylass 05-22-2009, 05:54 PM In my experience, (except in working as a server in a Connecticut restaurant about 20 years ago, where we charged for refills on soda) tea, coffee, and soda are free refills. The raspberry lemonades and mocha lattes, however, were not free on the refills. Bosstone 05-22-2009, 05:59 PM The only places I&apos;ve seen in the last, I dunno, five years or more that sell soda that have the fountain publicly accessible and make you pay for refills are convenience stores. Even then, I&apos;ve never hassled or been hassled for pouring a cup, taking a drink, then filling up what I just drank. Harmonious Discord 05-22-2009, 06:29 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?

Drive through and take outs are the main reason.

Worrying about this is about as bizarre as worrying you had to use their restroom. Lobohan 05-22-2009, 06:56 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?To add to the chorus of answers for this, I get a large cup because I refill before I leave and I like having a large cup to take with me. IvoryTowerDenizen 05-22-2009, 07:42 PM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?

I usually get the small cups, because it helps control my soda intake. I like having some root beer or coke, but I don&apos;t want to drink too much. I fill a small cup with lots ice (I love soda ice cold), add soda and rarely go up for more than a little bit more.

I get my soda and have portion control. Lynn Bodoni 05-23-2009, 02:20 AM In my experience, (except in working as a server in a Connecticut restaurant about 20 years ago, where we charged for refills on soda) tea, coffee, and soda are free refills. The raspberry lemonades and mocha lattes, however, were not free on the refills. I believe it&apos;s Olive Garden that has the raspberry lemonade that I like, and they refill it free. Argent Towers 05-23-2009, 02:42 AM You have to rudely shout,&quot;Gimme another refill.&quot;This only works if your name is Waingro. Markxxx 05-23-2009, 09:13 AM Using a strict interpretation unless it&apos;s told to you refills are free, you shouldn&apos;t take one.

Some places it&apos;s on the cup. I knew one place awhile ago, it said on the cup.&quot;ONE free refill, you&apos;re on the honor system so don&apos;t cheat.&quot;

When I started out in life I worked at Red Roof Inn and we used to give away coffee and USA Today (when the paper first came out, so this was the early 80s). We were among the first discount chains to do this.

So people would come in and look around, they wouldn&apos;t know if the coffee was free, so they&apos;d ask, we&apos;d say yes. Then they&apos;d look around and see the paper and they didn&apos;t know what to do. Then they&apos;d grab one and start to the door and I&apos;d look at them and they&apos;d look all guilty and say&quot;Ah these are free right?&quot;

I felt like saying&quot;Well you were just gonna take it anyway.&quot;LOL

To the OP though just ask are the refills free?

I remember at Taco Bell once, there was a lady that came in and her kid had McDonalds, she orders and they sit down. And the kid finishes his soda, and goes to get more, and she say&quot;No, you didn&apos;t get that here, you aren&apos;t entitled to a refill&quot;So she dumps her soda into his empty McDonalds cup and give him her now empty Taco Bell soda cup and he gets a refill.

See how logic works Strinka 05-23-2009, 09:52 AM Does your brother also object to getting more than one plate of food at a buffet? Fiddle Peghead 05-23-2009, 10:42 AM Drive through and take outs are the main reason.

Worrying about this is about as bizarre as worrying you had to use their restroom.

Oh, I don&apos;t worry about it. I get refills with no qualms whatsoever. Brown Eyed Girl 05-23-2009, 10:57 AM I have it on good authority that free refills is teh LAW!!1! And further, the menu is KING! :D Nava 05-23-2009, 11:22 AM Then why do they still sell small, medium, and large cups?

Because people are stupid keep buying them.

I must be stupid, but thing is, if I&apos;m only going to have a small drink I won&apos;t pay for the BIGGERTHANTHEPLATE size.

In Spain the few places that have soda fountains usable by the customers usually give free refills (I ask, if I think I may want a refill). I haven&apos;t seen that many, but of the ones I&apos;ve been to there has never been one which wanted you to pay for the second cup. Fiddle Peghead 05-23-2009, 03:45 PM Using a strict interpretation unless it&apos;s told to you refills are free, you shouldn&apos;t take one.



It looks like you and my brother are the only people who feel this way. :) Apocalypso 05-23-2009, 10:45 PM Most of the fast food chains near me require you to fill your own drink. When I leave I always refill my drink before heading out. The drink station is always right near the counter, so I&apos;m in full view of most of the employees. No one has ever said anything to me about it. Not so much as a&quot;I&apos;ll let it go this time, but...&quot;. They obviously know I&apos;m doing it, and if it wasn&apos;t allowed, they&apos;d say something. drastic_quench 05-24-2009, 12:41 AM My brother would get a solid punch in the shoulder for such nonsense. Argent Towers 05-24-2009, 03:39 AM Do I really need to point out: best username/thread combo ever? GuanoLad 05-24-2009, 05:06 AM Here in Australia, most places don&apos;t let you do it. But Hungry Jack&apos;s, aka Burger King, do let you, as evidenced by my visit yesterday and the drinks fountain having the words&quot;Free Refills&quot;clearly marked upon it. KneadToKnow 05-24-2009, 01:58 PM I must be stupid, but thing is, if I&apos;m only going to have a small drink I won&apos;t pay for the BIGGERTHANTHEPLATE size.

In Spain the few places that have soda fountains usable by the customers usually give free refills (I ask, if I think I may want a refill). I haven&apos;t seen that many, but of the ones I&apos;ve been to there has never been one which wanted you to pay for the second cup.

The point of my original comment was that people will keep paying for the BIGGERTHANTHEPLATE size even when they can get the smaller size an keep refilling it, Nava. msmith537 05-24-2009, 04:26 PM People don&apos;t beat the crap out of little brothers anymore? Proudest Monkey 05-24-2009, 04:39 PM I have it on good authority that free refills is teh LAW!!1! And further, the menu is KING! :D

Teehee!
I can hardly go into a restaurant thread or an actual restaurant these days without at least a passing thought of that whack-job and her utterly entertaining trainwreck.

I bet she&apos;d have some Humble Opinions to share with the OP! Bosstone 05-24-2009, 04:44 PM The point of my original comment was that people will keep paying for the BIGGERTHANTHEPLATE size even when they can get the smaller size an keep refilling it, Nava.I don&apos;t think a lot of people realize they can usually ask for a small drink and large fries with a combo, too. The fries and drink are always packaged together as Small, Medium, or Large. Plus, even if they do know...well, they&apos;re (read: I&apos;m) lazy and would rather just order a large combo rather than taking the time to specify small drink and large fries, and also to avoid potentially tripping up the poor guy at the register. kaylasdad99 05-25-2009, 03:47 PM Teehee!
I can hardly go into a restaurant thread or an actual restaurant these days without at least a passing thought of that whack-job and her utterly entertaining trainwreck.

I bet she&apos;d have some Humble Opinions to share with the OP!I spy with my little eye something that could be an entertaining thread.

Linky, please?

ETA: Oh, and in SoCal, soft drink refills are the rule, rather than the exception, even in sit-down restaurants, where the staff has to bring it to you. This includes iced tea and lemonade. Proudest Monkey 05-25-2009, 04:44 PM I spy with my little eye something that could be an entertaining thread.

Linky, please?



Ok, kaylasdad, I&apos;ve always enjoyed reading your posts, so I am stepping out of my comfort zone in linking to another page, but for your pleasure and amusement, I&apos;ll give it a shot.
http://http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/showthread.php?t=509580&amp;highlight=restaurant+drink+refills

It started out as a tipping/working wage debate. The real fun starts on page 5 with the first post by our abovementioned whackjob. (post # 247) She went by the name Springs1. The thread ended up in the Pit, and several posters surely must have sustained head injuries from bashing their heads against the solid wall of her intractability and illogic regarding drink refills (and more!).

She&apos;s banned, but I&apos;ll never forget her.

on edit: Crap, looks like my link attempt failed. Will continue to try. kaylasdad99 05-25-2009, 08:11 PM Well, that&apos;s one of the nicest things anyone has said to me all week! I thank you for the plaudits, and don&apos;t worry about the link; I found it based on your search criteria.

http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/showthread.php?t=509580&amp;highlight=restaurant+drink+refills

Just for the record, the broken link was because you let an extra&quot;http//&quot;sneak in there. Let me just check this out...

Oh.

My.

STARS. :eek:

ETA: Holy Moly, her first post to the thread began&quot;Are you just that dense, or what?&quot;:eek: :eek: metacritic 07-14-2010, 02:08 PM Thanks, Proudest Monkey and kaylasdad99. The link to the Bad Tippers forum was priceless.

I&apos;m still working my way through the messages, and they keep getting better.

It&apos;s a shame no one ever brought up the basic etymology of the word&quot;refill&quot;to Springs1. A simple statement that showcases that it is a re-filling (i.e., meaning the cup is being filled again with the same filling as before) should have caused even more ruckus.

I wonder if anyone here has considered the ethics of throwing away one&apos;s original cup and getting a new one as a free refill. This is what Wendy&apos;s is doing now, which is what led me to this thread.

Thanks everyone! Peremensoe 07-14-2010, 02:23 PM I expect unlimited free refills of water, tea, coffee and soda (any water-based nonalcoholic beverage, I guess) in real restaurants with table service.

I do tip more for the extra service if my party ends up sitting around and having several extra cups of coffee or whatever. Brown Eyed Girl 07-14-2010, 02:56 PM More bbrrraaaaaiiiiinnnns, ppleeeeeaaaaaasssse. msmith537 07-14-2010, 02:57 PM Why is this an&quot;ethical&quot;issue? If the restaurant in question offers free refils (which most do), they have certainly taken this into account in their business model. control-z 07-14-2010, 03:18 PM I saw a sign in an Arby&apos;s that said something to the effect of&quot;Enjoy free refills, same visit only.&quot;So you can&apos;t fill up a cup you bring into the restaurant. Fair enough. Skammer 07-14-2010, 03:34 PM Using a strict interpretation unless it&apos;s told to you refills are free, you shouldn&apos;t take one.&quot;Strict interpretation&quot;of what? If there&apos;s no sign that says&quot;no free refills&quot;and the machine is accessible to the customers, you&apos;re expected to refill as much as you want (during your visit). Achren 07-14-2010, 04:21 PM Oh.

My.

STARS. :eek:Wow. Out of morbid curiosity I thought I&apos;d google the username and Google was able to auto-complete it! I am amazed at her, um, dedication. billfish678 07-14-2010, 05:19 PM &quot;Strict interpretation&quot;of what? If there&apos;s no sign that says&quot;no free refills&quot;and the machine is accessible to the customers, you&apos;re expected to refill as much as you want (during your visit).

The SAFEST ethical interpretation is that they DO NOT want you to have free refills (though apparently that is the norm these days) unless they specify otherwise. You don&apos;t take something you could have (no ethical harm). You take something you shouldnt have (big ethical harm).

They could just have the machines out there for several reasons. You get to decide how full you want it (easy to carry or filled to the brim). You get to choose how much ice you want. Also, they are getting you to choose the drink and do it yourself which makes their work behind the counter that much easier.

And, as far as that goes, I can certainly remember the days where the soda machines were&quot;out front&quot;and free refills WERE NOT the norm. DianaG 07-14-2010, 06:17 PM More bbrrraaaaaiiiiinnnns, ppleeeeeaaaaaasssse.
That Bad Tipping thread was some seriously delicious brains, though. I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve ever seen the word&quot;fair&quot;, let alone the word&quot;moral&quot;applied to eating out before.

Oh, I&apos;m sorry... I meant FAIR and ***MORAL***.

Awesome. msmith537 07-14-2010, 06:48 PM It&apos;s a little known fact, but McDonalds gave free refils for as long as I can remember, even if the fountains are behind the counter. perfectparanoia 07-14-2010, 06:55 PM It&apos;s a little known fact, but McDonalds gave free refils for as long as I can remember, even if the fountains are behind the counter.

Still do. I usually get them to refill my drink on the way out when I bring the kiddos. Bosstone 07-14-2010, 07:35 PM The SAFEST ethical interpretation is that they DO NOT want you to have free refills (though apparently that is the norm these days) unless they specify otherwise. You don&apos;t take something you could have (no ethical harm). You take something you shouldnt have (big ethical harm).

They could just have the machines out there for several reasons. You get to decide how full you want it (easy to carry or filled to the brim). You get to choose how much ice you want. Also, they are getting you to choose the drink and do it yourself which makes their work behind the counter that much easier.

And, as far as that goes, I can certainly remember the days where the soda machines were&quot;out front&quot;and free refills WERE NOT the norm.I keep my furniture within my property if I want to restrict access to it. I put my furniture outside my property if I want someone to take it. It&apos;s completely senseless to allow free access to the fountain and yet not allow free refills, and you&apos;re just going to wind up with a lot of shrinkage that way. dalej42 07-14-2010, 07:55 PM I saw a sign in an Arby&apos;s that said something to the effect of&quot;Enjoy free refills, same visit only.&quot;So you can&apos;t fill up a cup you bring into the restaurant. Fair enough.

I think that is to discourage the homeless from hanging out in the restaurant with the same cup day after day. Moonlitherial 07-14-2010, 09:08 PM That thread was a thing of beauty.

On the actual topic of this thread, I used to seriously abuse the free refill option but I&apos;ve cut way down on my diet coke intake now. Serenata67 07-14-2010, 09:41 PM If a restaurant makes the soda machine publicly available to me, I&apos;m going to assume they don&apos;t care if I get a refill. If they don&apos;t want me to, they should post a sign.

It&apos;s just like with salad bars. Some places limit you to one trip through, but they make a point of telling you.

That&apos;s how I see it. Fill me up! Spectre of Pithecanthropus 07-14-2010, 10:17 PM This thread is something of a zombie, but I don&apos;t see any problems with it. We&apos;ll leave it open for now. BigT 07-14-2010, 10:35 PM It&apos;s a little known fact, but McDonalds gave free refils for as long as I can remember, even if the fountains are behind the counter.

I actually am always surprised that this is so little known. Every fast food restaurant I&apos;ve ever encountered has had this--long before they started putting the fountain drinks out front.

I have maybe encountered a handful of restaurants period that don&apos;t offer free refills on fountains soda. The one exception I can think of right now is such an oddity that people talk about it like its&apos; the strangest thing ever.

And, yes, if you don&apos;t want something to be taken for free, you have an ethical obligation to make it clear, or at least to protect. Taking something that someone else does not want you to take is not itself unethical if they offer it. You have no one to blame but yourself if you do not counter possible communications that taking is okay. billfish678 07-15-2010, 08:22 AM I It&apos;s completely senseless to allow free access to the fountain and yet not allow free refills, and you&apos;re just going to wind up with a lot of shrinkage that way.

I gave several PERFECTLY valid reasons why the soda machines would be out front that has NOTHING to do with free refills. Saves the business behind the counter space, saves them some work (and the possibility of messing up your drink), and it allows you to make the drink just the way you like it. None of those are a function of whether they are charging for every fill or not.

You can argue the norm is now free refills for everyone. You can argue its worth it (or just easier) to the company to give away something thats nearly free. You can argue if there isnt a sign saying otherwise free refill away if you want. You can argue if they don&apos;t want people refilling, there should be an obvious sign.

But don&apos;t say it makes no sense whatsoever to have em out front even without free refills, cause it does. Bosstone 07-15-2010, 08:39 AM I gave several PERFECTLY valid reasons why the soda machines would be out front that has NOTHING to do with free refills. Saves the business behind the counter space, saves them some work (and the possibility of messing up your drink), and it allows you to make the drink just the way you like it. None of those are a function of whether they are charging for every fill or not.And yet the biggest reason for putting it behind the counter -- restricting access -- trumps all of those soundly. A restaurant that is going to charge 25 cents for 5 cents worth of soda isn&apos;t going to care terribly much about any of the reasons you give. After all, many of them offer to make your burger exactly the way you like it, but they sure as hell aren&apos;t putting the burger ingredients out in the commons.

Putting a soda machine out in the commons and then expecting people to pay means putting an employee in charge of watching the fountain and tracking who uses it, which wastes their time. If they don&apos;t, then they&apos;re offering free refills whether they like it or not, because there&apos;s always been plenty of people who just won&apos;t care and will happily abuse whatever&apos;s available to them. Khaki Campbell 07-15-2010, 09:06 AM I gave several PERFECTLY valid reasons why the soda machines would be out front that has NOTHING to do with free refills. Saves the business behind the counter space, saves them some work (and the possibility of messing up your drink), and it allows you to make the drink just the way you like it. None of those are a function of whether they are charging for every fill or not.

But it helps to worsen the obesity epidemic, if there&apos;s a limited choice of taps (i.e. no diet anything). Autolycus 07-15-2010, 12:30 PM This thread is something of a zombie, but I don&apos;t see any problems with it. We&apos;ll leave it open for now.

You listen! You really listen! Thank you. Oh frabjous day, I&apos;m so happy :)


***

I&apos;ve heard of some people who keep a McDonald&apos;s coffee cup in their car at all times, so whenever they stop into one they can get a free refill. I&apos;d suggest that raises some ethics issues. Bosstone 07-15-2010, 12:45 PM I&apos;ve heard of some people who keep a McDonald&apos;s coffee cup in their car at all times, so whenever they stop into one they can get a free refill. I&apos;d suggest that raises some ethics issues.On the contrary, it inspires loyalty for almost nothing. I mean, it may be unethical in the sense that it&apos;s not McD&apos;s policy, but setting that aside it&apos;s good for business. If you hang onto a McD&apos;s cup with the expectation of a freefill, you&apos;ll be more inclined to go back to them for your next fast food meal than Burger King. Kolga 07-15-2010, 12:49 PM Wow. Out of morbid curiosity I thought I&apos;d google the username and Google was able to auto-complete it! I am amazed at her, um, dedication.

Good. Fucking. Gods.

Now that there is a person who&apos;s definitely a few sandwiches shy of a full picnic. vBulletin®v3.7.3, Copyright©2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
