<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003712" url="http://thehongkongtravelguide.com/restaurants.html" time="2012-07-12-19:52" support="12" score="0.04068894345785634" bingtitle="Hong Kong travel guide" webtitle="Hong Kong travel guide">
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000809" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>Exit D2 of MTR Central Station, then walk southbound ... Yu is famous for its Dim Sum, and is a popular place ... Ser Wong Fun Restaurant does not make tourism any easy, it ...</description>
	<body>
		The HONG KONG travel guide
  In this page : Top 10 eateries Types of eateries 10 best Hong Kong local food Food for souveniour Exotic foods Restaurant rows Top 
 
 General information 
  Orientation  Population  Language  Religion  Climate  When to visit  Currency / money  To fly to Hong Kong  Airport  Visitors center  Local travel agencies  Visa/passport  Useful phone numbers  Electricity  Innoculation  Time zone  Smoking regulations  Tippings  Traffic  Calendar 
 

 Major Attractions 
 Victoria Peak Victoria Harbour ferry ride Po Lin Monastery / Big Buddha Statue Tsing Ma Bridge Symphony of light Tai O Fishing Village Theme parks Museums Dried seafood market Horse race Lei Yue Mun seafood Floating restaurants Outlying islands Tailors Shopping 5 best souveniour Beaches Night lives Red light districts Other Interests 
 

 Public Transport 
 Taxi Mass Transit Railway(MTR) Bus Airport Express Cityflyer / Airbus Public Light Bus(Minibus) Tram Peak Tram Light Rail Ferry 
 

 Itinerary Suggestion 
 5 day energetic route 5 day easy route 7 day Macau extended route 
 

 Hotels 
 High end Mid range Low range Low end Budget 
 

 
Restaurants
 

 Festivals, holidays 
 New Year Chinese New Year Chinese Valentine&apos;s Day Bun Festival Dragon Boat Festival Ghost Festival Mid Autumn Festival Halloween Christmas Easter Hong Kong SAR Establishment Day China National Day Public holidays Exhibitions and fairs 
 

 Healthy Travel 
 Travel makes you sick? Remedy 
 

 Film crew 
 
RESTAURANTS

Find food, find food. &quot;Find food&quot; is the slang of &quot;to work&quot; in local Hong Kong language, implying that the major reason to work is to eat. Eating is their important culture, Hong Kongers work hard, and they are gurus for food. You can find cuisines from all around the world. Each year, the International Food Festival held in Hong Kong draws tens of thousands of visitors. Even though you are in Hong Kong for business, certainly you have time to taste some good food. Now, follow me to find food, I&apos;ve picked the best 10 eateries for you -
 
10 best eateries :

 Spring Deer Restaurant 
 Spring Deer has been in Hong Kong for over 30 years, the restaurant has a 70&apos;s look, but clean and comfortable. Several years ago it underwent a remodeling to achieve a modern look, however, the staff found the new look did not harmonize with the restaurant theme, so the owner remodelled it again to resume an old-style look. The waiters are all long-term employees, and are very enthuaistic in talking with you about the restaurant&apos;s history, and the owner&apos;s past business ventures. Location : 42 Mody Road, Tsim Sha Tsui, Kowloon. Phone : (852)23664201, reservation is recommended. Cuisine : Beijing food. Specialty : Peking roast duck - Spring Deer has a fixed number of Peking roast ducks each day as marination takes hours. It only serves the entire duck so do not go there alone, allow 20-30mins cooking time, 

 Chim Chai Kee Noodle Shop
 Around a decade ago Mark&apos;s Noodle Shop was the best, Chim Chai Kee opened branches nearby every Mark&apos;s Noodle Shop so as to accomodate noodle customers who did not like the long queues in Mark&apos;s. Although Mark&apos;s noodle was good and famous, it was expensive and small portion; While Chim Chai Kee emphasized on cleaniness eating environment, coupled with its fast improvement in noodle taste, and a reasonable price, customers gradually switchd to Chim Chai Kee. Nowadays, Chim Chai Kee has the best wonton noodle. Cuisine : Hong Kong style noodle Location :
 98 Wellington Street, Central, Hong Kong. opening hrs : 9:00am - 10:00pm. Exit D2 of MTR Central Station, then walk southbound(uphill) along D&apos;Aguillar Street, right on Wellington Street. 153 Queen&apos;s Road Central, Hong Kong. opening hrs : 9:00am - 10:00pm. Exit D2 of MTR Central Station, then walk westbound along Queen&apos;s Road Central, the shop is on your right. 
 Specialty : Wonton noodle. 
 
 Yung Kee Restaurant 
 Yung Kee was founded in 1942 as a tiny stall selling roast goose, the restaurant went through wars and crises, the owner&apos;s belief has never been changed - his secret recipe of roast goose will become popular. He&apos;s correct, this gourmet roast goose soon became famous and attract a lot of tourists everyday. This award-winning restaurant is not particularly expensive, but many Hong Kong billionaires and celebrities come to dine here often. It is moderately decorated, not too fancy but practicle, there is an Indian security guard at the door, and will help to open restaurant door and car doors for you. To fully enjoy the roast goose, you should go there for dinner, after 5:30pm. Location : 32-40 Wellington Street, Central, Hong Kong. Exit D2 of MTR Central Station, then walk southbound(uphill) along D&apos;Aguillar Street, right on Wellington Street. Phone : (852) 25221624, reservation is recommended for weekends and Chinese festivals. Business hrs : 11:00am - 11:30pm daily except the first 3 days of Lunar New Year. It serves dim sum as lunch and high tea until 5:30pm. Cuisine : Chinese food. Specialty : Roast goose. Upon request, the restaurant can pack the roast goose in a special way so that tourists can take it home by plane, so Yung Kee&apos;s roast goose is nicknamed &quot;Flying Roast Goose&quot;. Other dishes that you should try : perserved eggs with pickled ginger, bbq suckling pig, shredded jelly-fish. 

 Yuk Yip dessert 
 Yuk Yip is a street dining stall. Table and chairs are shared with its neighbouring noodle shop, very primitive, service is not great but fast. Location : outside of 2 Elgin Street, near Hollywood Road, Central, Hong Kong. Phone : (852)25443795 Opening hours : Noon to late night. Specialty : bascially all desserts here worth trying - seasame soup, read bean soup, green bean soup, sticky rice balls ( tong yuen ), you can even mix any 2 of the desserts, the most popular one is read bean soup with seasame soup. price is low, every dessert is around HK$7.00. 

 Felix 
 Felix is a high-class, ultra-contemporary restaurant, with splendid view of the Victoria Harbour, besides dining, don&apos;t miss out the chance to visit the specially designed restrooms. Location : 28/F Peninsula Hotel, Kowloon. Phone : (852)23153188. Reservation is recommended, children under 12 are not allowed. Cuisine : Western. Opening hrs : dinner(6:00pm-10:30pm), snack(10:30pm-12:30am), drinks(6:00pm-1:30am). Dress code : casual smart. No flip-flops, sneakers; For men - full lenght pants and no sleeveless shirts. Specialty : steak.

 Luk Yu Tea House 
 Luk Yu is famous for its Dim Sum , and is a popular place for local celebrities and business people. It is still decorated the same way as when it was opened in 1933, tables and chairs with marble inlay, wooden booths, spittoon, split-level, half-vase on the walls, and an Indian security guard to get the door for you. Location : 2426 Stanley Street, Central, Hong Kong. 
 Exit D1 of MTR Central station, walk south bould(turn right) along Pedder Street, right on Queen&apos;s Road Central, left at the first set of light on D&apos;Aguilar Street, right on Stanley Street. Luk Yu is on your left. From the Central Star Ferry Pier, walk southwest bound along the raised walkway(over Man Yiu Street), go down to the MTR Central station, do NOT enter any gate, but get out of the station from exit D1, walk south bould(turn right) along Pedder Street, right on Queen&apos;s Road Central, left at the first set of light on D&apos;Aguilar Street, right on Stanley Street. Luk Yu is on your left. 
 Phone : (852)25235464 Cuisine : Dim Sum, Cantonese dinner. Opening hrs : 7:00am-10:00pm daily, dim sum is served until 5:30pm Specialty : bbq pork bun, taro cake 

 Crystal Jade La Mian Xiao Long Bao 
 Jade is a quick service restaurant that provides simple but good service. In busy hours, customers queue up outside the restaurant waiting their numbers to be called. Tables are small so do not order too many at a time, you can always order more later on, service is fast. Location : Shop 2018-2020, Level 2, IFC Mall 2, 8 Finance Street Central, Hong Kong. Phone : (852)22953811 Cuisine : Northern Chinese food Specialty : xiao lung bao(meat dumpling), orthmantus dessert. 


 Bo Innovation 
 Bo Innovation is an very unique diner and serves non-traditional dim sum . The food has traditional dim sum as base, but uses more precious ingredients such as truffle and carviar, whereas the main ingredient in dim sum, such as prawns in prawn dumplings, remain unchanged. Presentation of food is good, the ultensils are nice looking, tables are new and pretty. Location : Shop 13, 2/F, J. Residence, 60 Johnston Road, Wan Chai, Hong Kong. Phone : (852)28508371 Opening hrs : lunch(12:00pm-3:00pm, Mon-Fri). Cuisine : Dim Sum, Cantonese food dinner Specialty : dim sum 

 Lin Heung Tea House 
 Lin Heung is an 80-year old tea house . With no glamerous decoration, no great service, not prestige location, Lin Heung is always packed with customers. In Lin Heung, you have to share a table with other customers that you don&apos;t know, no one arranges table for you, so you need to find vacant seats yourselves, or wait behind seated customers. For tea, you can choose to use tea pot to hold tea for your group, or individual covered tea cups which requires a little practice to pour tea to your own cups. Lin Heung has 2 stories, ground floor sells Chinese style cakes, whilst a stair case leads to second floor which is the restaurant/tea house. At the stairway, there is a 2 feet by 3 feet white board, you can find signatures of many celebrities including Anthony Bourdain. Location : 160-164 Wellington Street, Hong Kong. 
 Exit D1 of MTR Central station, walk south bould(turn right) along Pedder Street, right on Queen&apos;s Road Central, left at the first set of light on D&apos;Aguilar Street, right on Wellington Street. Lin Heung is on your left. From the Central Star Ferry Pier, walk southwest bound along the raised walkway(over Man Yiu Street), go down to the MTR Central station, do NOT enter any gate, but get out of the station from exit D1, walk south bould(turn right) along Pedder Street, right on Queen&apos;s Road Central, left at the first set of light on D&apos;Aguilar Street, right on Wellington Street. Lin Heung is on your left. 
 Phone : (852)2544-2556 Cuisine : Dim Sum, Cantonese dinner. Specialty : lotus seed paste bun, bbq pork bun, taro cake, big bun(chicken bun) 

 Malaysian Chinese Restaurant - currry briquete, red bean ice 
 Malaysian Chinese Restaurant is a half-decade-old restaurant that is famous for its curry dishes. It&apos;s decoration is of very tipical 60&apos;s-70&apos;s style, after several major renovation, it remains the same style. Location : G/F., 12 Jordan Road, Jordan, Kowloon. Phone : (852)23673552, (852)23665302. Cuisine : Hong Kong style Malaysian Chinese food. Specialty : currry briquete(beef stew) with rice, red bean ice dessert. Red bean ice dessert is a Hong Kong specialty, many tea restaurants sells this, but Ma Wah uses shave ice, with non-diluted evaporated milk, so it tastes much better. 



 go to top 

 
Types of eateries
Besides restaurants, cafe, and fast food chain stores, Hong Kong has other types too -
 Tea cafe(Cha Chaan Teng) - commonly found in busy areas of Hong Kong, fast service, standard food, and affordable price. They have a la carte menu, set menu and daily special, in busy hours, you had better order food from a set menu or daily special menu, otherwise the waiting time could be long. Food that tea cafes serve are non-fancy, non-complicated local Hong Kong household food. Usual breakfast is ham, egg, toast and macroni in soup. Usual beverage in a tea cafe is milk tea, coffee, yin-yeung(half milk tea, half coffee), and lemon water. Usual food for high tea is chicken wing, toast, French toast, sandwich, noodles. Your bill will be placed on your table before you are done with your food, to pay the bill, simple take the bill to the cashier, tipping is not required, cash only. 
 Street food stall(Dai Pai Dong) - an open-air food stall, the main portion is sheltered, whilst the dining tables and chairs may or may not be sheltered. It demonstrates the unique dining culture and history in Hong Kong. The HK government is gradually getting rid of Dai Pai Dong, so no new Dai Pai Dong is allowed or licenced. Existing Dai Pai Dong licences are attached to owners only, and are not transferrable, so once the owner dies, there is 1 less Dai Pai Dong in Hong Kong. Tipping is not required, cash only. 
 Tea house(Cha Lau) - Traditional Chinese style restaurants which serves dim sum in day time, and Cantonese food at evenings. They are usually big in area, but packed with tables and chairs. To dine in tea house or any Chinese style restaurant, in addition to the price of food that you order, you are required to pay the price for tea and sauce(several dollars per person, depending on rank of the tea house.), and 10% service charge, they are all shown on you bill.
	</body>
</document>
