<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003369" url="http://www.amchegoa.com/restaurants_in_goa.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:30" support="3" score="0.012181075662510152" bingtitle="Goa Restaurants, Coffee Shops &amp; Beach Shacks" webtitle="Goa Restaurants, Coffee Shops&amp;Beach Shacks">
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>A good place to sit out and while away ... popular fast food restaurant for quick eat ... serve good snacks, and meals too</description>
	<body>
		of 
 your Dreams... 
 
 
 
 
 
  Welcome 
 to amchegoa.com - Come! Discover 
 Goa with us ... 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 
 
 :: Search the Web :: 
 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 
   
   Hotels   Travel   Business   Services   NRI 
 Services   About 
 Goa   Night 
 Life 
   home 

 
   

 
 
 
 
 
 
 RESTAURANTS 
 IN GOA 
 South 
 Goa  |  North 
 Goa  |  Chinese  |  Speciality  |  Panaji  |  North 
 Indian 
 Goa 
 has multitude of restaurants spread across 
 all over Goa. Varied Indian cuisine from the 
 simple Goan 
 fish curry and rice to rich Punjabi, tasty 
 Manglorean, unlimited Gujarati Thalis&amp;the most popular Udipi style food is available. 
 The evergreen roadside&quot;gadas&quot;(carts) 
 serving panipuri, bhel, pauvbhaji, omlette 
 pauv, puri-bhaji and sugarcance juice are 
 abundant. 
   Recomended 
 Hotels...   Pubs 
 in Goa...   Beaches 
 of Goa...   Night 
 Life in Goa...   Real 
 Estate...   Health 
 Holidays...   Goan 
 cuisine... 
 
 Delicious 
 international cuisine is also a hallmark in 
 Goa especially seen in scores of Chinese restaurants. 
 Besides Chinese, you will find, German, Thai, 
 Continental, Mexican, Lebanese, Italian and 
 Health food restaurants. 

 Goa 
 being a very liberal state, most of the restaurants 
 serve alcohol freely. 

 We 
 give below some of the popular restaurants 
 in each category, where food&amp;service 
 is supposed to be of excellent quality and 
 they are all worth visiting time and again. 

 Goan 
 Food - North Goa 

 Souza&apos; 
 Lobo - Calangute Beach. 
 In 
 existence for the past 65 years, this restaurant 
 has earned its reputation on good food, good 
 service&amp;location. However, lately its 
 been reported to have lost its quality of 
 food. Still it&apos;s worth visiting at least once 
 during your stay. 

 Mirabai&apos;s 
 Goan Village - Calangute/Baga Road 
 Opened 
 just about four months ago, this restaurant 
 claims to offer only genuine goan food. Located 
 on the main road, it has a simple ambience 
 and is known to be quite popular. Food is 
 supposed to be reasonably good but the service 
 lacks in quality. 

 Sparrows 
 Nest - Calangute Main Road 
 Located 
 right besides the only Petrol Station in Calangute, 
 this simple restaurant serves a mean Goan 
 fish curry and rice dish, very popular with 
 the locals and the tourists. Its prices are 
 also very reasonable compared to others in 
 the vicinity. 

 St. 
 Anthonys Bar&amp;Restaurant Baga Beach 
 One 
 of the oldest restaurants, it has a simple 
 shack like ambience and some good food with 
 friendly staff. Quite popular with tourists 
 and well worth a visit. 

 Florentine 
 - Saligao 
 Located 
 in Saligao, a 10-minute drive from Calangute, 
 this restaurant has been in existence for 
 quite some time. Earlier known for its great 
 food, its service has deteriorated, but still 
 serves some good Goan dishes and chicken cafreal. 

 BACK 
 TO TOP 



 Chinese 
 Restaurants 

 Pagoda 
 Chinese Restaurant 
 Situated 
 on Baga Road, this is a neat place. Good Food 
 and good service, but a bit steep on the prices. 

 Kim 
 Fa Chinese Restaurant 
 On 
 the Baga Road, next to Ronnils Resort, this 
 is quite a popular Chinese joint with good 
 food at the right price. Quite popular with 
 a lot of tourists and the owner Michael is 
 a charmer. 

 China 
 Highway 
 On 
 the Calangute/Panaji Highway, this so called 
 restaurant is situated in the fields and serves 
 decent Chinese food at the right price. If 
 you like outdoors, this is the place for you. 

 Multicuisine&amp;Speciality Restaurants 

 Oceanic 
 Right 
 in Calangute Market Place, Oceanic is a multicuisine 
 restaurant. Good food, good ambience its clientele 
 is mostly regulars who visit them time and 
 again. 

 Redonda 
 Located 
 on the junction of Calangute/Baga Road, this 
 restaurant is quite popular with tourists 
 because of its location. A good place to 
 sit out and while away your time looking around. 
 Popular for Breakfasts. 

 Infantaria 
 In 
 Calangute near the football field, this is 
 a popular fast food restaurant for quick eat 
 outs and breakfasts. It is however known to 
 serve good snacks, and meals too. 

 Brittos 
 This 
 popular restaurant is located right near the 
 beach in Baga. Good Food and reasonable prices 
 makes it quite popular with the locals as 
 well as the tourists. 

 Fiesta 
 A 
 great ambience with beautiful settings, this 
 restaurant situated opposite Titos Night 
 Club in Baga, serves good Mediterranean and 
 Italian cuisine. 

 Little 
 Italy 
 Fighting 
 for the same name, are two restaurants situated 
 at different locations. Both claim to good 
 genuine Italian food and both worth visiting. 
 One is on the Calangute/Candolim road and 
 the other one is in Little Baga opposite the 
 river. 

 Plantain 
 Leaf 
 Situated 
 in the market place at Calangute this is a 
 sprawling Vegetarian Restaurant, serving all 
 kinds of Udipi style and now North Indian 
 dishes. Reasonable food but sloppy service. 

 Udipi 
 Restaurant 
 Just 
 opposite the temple in Calangute, near Bank 
 of Baroda, is this Indian vegetarian restaurant. 
 Serves good udipi style south Indian food, 
 but being small it is too crowded for some. 

 Palms 
 N Sands 
 This 
 restaurant is in Candolim, right on the beach 
 with a 3 tier sit out. Serves good seafood 
 and has great outdoor view of the sea. 

 Village 
 Siesta 
 Unmatched 
 ambience, quality food and personalized service 
 is the trade mark of this restaurant situated 
 in Siquerim. Serves multicuisine food. 

 Dom 
 Pedros 
 If 
 you feel like Mexican food, visit this place 
 in Porvorim, which serves reasonable Mexican 
 cuisine. 

 BACK 
 TO TOP 

 Goan 
 Food - Panaji 

 Mums 
 Kitchen 
 Situated 
 on the road to Miramar in Panaji, this restaurant 
 is quite famous with the local residents and 
 tourists alike for its good Goan food. 

 Jasima 
 Located 
 near the Junta House just off the 18 th June road. The food is decent and is reasonably 
 priced. Service during lunchtime is lousy 
 because the management and staff are busy 
 watching the TV. 

 Vegetarian 
 Restaurants 

 Hotel 
 Kamat 
 Located 
 on the church square in Panaji, this popular 
 restaurant serves vegetarian food in Udipi 
 style. 

 Satkar 
 Hotel 
 Situated 
 on 18 th June Road in Panaji, this 
 is another Udipi style restaurant serving 
 the standard South Indian dishes. 

 Multicuisine&amp;North Indian Restaurants 

 Delhi 
 Darbar 
 Ask 
 anybody and they will guide you to this most 
 popular restaurant. Nice ambience, good Tandoori 
 and North Indian food. The prices are a bit 
 steep for Indian Standards. 

 Sher 
 e Punjab 
 Another 
 popular name in the North Indian food scene, 
 they have two restaurants with the same name 
 in Panaji and serves decent North Indian cuisine. 

 White 
 House - Donna Paula 
 Situated 
 on the Donna Paula hillock overlooking the 
 Governor&apos;s Palace, it has an excellent view 
 of both Panaji and Marmugoa harbour. The place 
 is more for relaxing for an evening drink 
 and some snacks, but as far as the food is 
 concerned it is nothing special. 

 South 
 Goa 

 Martins 
 Nest - Betalbatim 
 Located 
 close to the Betalbatim beach, this restaurant 
 is known for its genuine goan food. A family 
 run business, its service is good by goan 
 standards. Best to visit during weekdays, 
 as Saturdays&amp;Sundays are awfully crowded. 

 Lounginohs 
 - Margao 
 Situated 
 in the heart of Margao city near to the Municipal 
 Buildings, this restaurant has the ambience 
 of a pub and serves excellent Goan, Chinese 
 and continental dishes. Their cocktails are 
 well recommended. 

 Coco 
 Loco 
 At 
 Agassaim, on the way between Panaji and Margao, 
 this restaurant is situated in the midst of 
 shady palm groove. Good for seafood and Goan 
 food 

 Kentuckee 
 On 
 the Colva Beach in South Goa. This restaurant 
 serves good seafood and also has a multicuisine 
 menu. Open till late night, its sea front 
 location is ideal for a night out with good 
 food. 

 Zeebop 
 Restaurant 
 Right 
 on Utorda Beach, opposite Kenilworth Beach 
 Resort. This outdoor restaurant has a great 
 setting. While you wait for you food, you 
 can relax on one of the cane chairs or a hammock 
 sipping a cool drink. Serves exotic goan food. 

 Banjara 
 Located 
 in Margao, this restaurant takes pride to 
 call itself the finest Indian restaurant in 
 Goa. Worth one visit if you are in Margao. 

 Fiplees 
 Restaurant 
 On 
 Benaulim beach, this restaurant is a one-stop 
 hot spot serving multicuisine meals. They 
 also conduct a lot of theme parties and Buffet 
 Dinner. 
 
   
 
 
 BACK 
 TO TOP     Pubs 
 in Goa     Night 
 Clubs     Map 
 of Goa
	</body>
</document>
