<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003631" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/the-do-not-call-list-how-it-works-what-it-does-and-why-your-phone-number-should-be-on-the-do-not-call-list/" time="2012-07-12-19:48" support="2" score="0.0035209013274983074" bingtitle="The Do Not Call List - How it works, what it does and why your ..." webtitle="The Do Not Call List - How it works, what it does and why your phone number should be on the Do Not Call List! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000737" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>... it works, what it does and why your phone number ... It is a scam trying to get my credit card info! // I ... fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 (702)318-1523 WTF Who is calling me? It is a scam trying to get my credit card info! Elite Brights Teeth Whitening Complaint - Bought A Groupon For A Sonic Powered Toothbrush And Recieved A Junk Product South Miami Taekwondo martial arts review - this place teaches flowery kicks and other skills that will not help in a real fight! Words With Friends Game Review - Amazing Scrabble like game for Facebook, Android, and IOS phone system Papa Johns Pizza Complaint - They tried to overcharge me and also messed up my order Hodges farm Charlotte NC review - there are other better farms to go to! Aetna health insurance - if you are looking for health insurance coverage at a good price be sure and skip right over Aetna especially if you have a pre-existing condition! Tilex Mold and Mildew Bathroom Cleaner Compliment - This Cleaner Actually Works On Tough Mold And Mildew Stains Hot fast food restaurant complaints here on ReportYourComplaint! Public Storage-$1 For First Month is Really a Scam!! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
The Do Not Call List–How it works, what it does and why your phone number should be on the Do Not Call List!
 By chelsea 
The national do not call registry really works! The feds finally got something right!
 



What’s funny is that I recently added a new phone line through AT&amp;T and the minute that phone number was turned on I was getting hundreds of telemarketing phone calls. Now I had that number boarded to my main number and that may number is under the federal Do Not Call List.

But the new number obviously was not because I had just had it turned on or installed by AT&amp;T. The first thing I did was call AT&amp;T to complain about the telemarketing calls. They said that they have nothing to do with that and that as soon as a new number is started once it gets listed in the local directory and phone books you will get telemarketing calls to it.

The problem I have with that is that this was the day the number was turned on and there was no way for it to have been listed in the local directory and in the local phone books that quickly. In other words, it is quite obvious that AT&amp;T sells their customer lists to telemarketing companies. They sell them so fast that as soon as you turn one on who you are ready on numerous telemarketing companies prospect lists.

I told him that that was wrong and they told me that they don’t do that. Must be these telemarketing companies have a crystal ball that they can tell exactly when a new customer signs up for a new phone number–yeah, right. So anyway, I went online to the national Do Not Call Registry at DoNotCall.gov and registered my new phone number there. It is very easy to register her phone number with the do not call Registry and only takes a minute or two.


 Your Ad Here 


The telemarketing calls still kept coming but I told the people calling that I was not interested in anything they were selling or offering and to remove me from any and all lists they have me on. One persistent telemarketer calling from ADT and their local authorized retailer Lock Tite told me that they don’t pay attention to or subscribe to the do not call list.

I told them that the federal do not call list is federal law and that they have to abide by it. I then told that person to take me off their list and not to call me ever again. Their response to me was rude and they said that since I was mean and abusive that they would try to remember not to call me–that was unbelievable. I will be reporting ADT and Lock Tite on the DoNotCall.gov website for what they said in disregards to the Do Not Call laws and their persistent phone calls.

 Want to know how to download movie torrents with complete anonymity and security so you can’t get caught? You need to read this post! 

Basically, the Do Not Call registry protects your household and your telephone from abusive telemarketing companies.  You should list all of your phone numbers with the Do Not Call registry.  If a telemarketer continues to call you after doing this they can be fined, charged with crimes, etc…The laws is that once a month and he and every telemarketing company needs to access the do not call Registry and purge their records of any phone numbers listed there.

I love the Do Not Call Registry!  Finally the Fed’s got something right!  Be sure and put your numbers all on there so that you do not get bothered by telemarketers.  It’s very easy to do, it’s free and only takes a minute or two.  Just  go to DoNotCall.gov and t started today.



 
Posts Related to The Do Not Call List - How it works, what it does and why your phone number should be on the Do Not Call List!

 
 (702)318-1523 WTF Who is calling me? It is a scam trying to get my credit card info! 

// I received phone calls from (702)318-1523 every day over the past week. Generally the phone rings and then goes to the message machine. The ...
 
 Freecycle Review–what it is and why you can never get the good stuff! 

// Freecycle, on the surface looks to be a valuable and worthy website and resource, but when you try and use it you see something ...
 
 Best Buy Complaint–Employees that convince consumers to buy crap products from the lack of knowledge 

// This week I had my computer completely crash and didn&apos;t want to spend the money nor the time to fix the hard drive ...
 
 Great websites that our readers absolutely love and you need to check out! 

// From time to time here at ReportYourComplaint.com we find or get notified about great websites that provide wonderful services or information from our readers. ...
 
 Boost Mobile prepaid cellphone service review and complaint–damn telemarketing calls keep using up my minutes! 

// I recently had take a job as a cashier at Wal-Mart because I lost my previous job due to the bad recession. I need ...
 
 
 Tags: do not call list , DoNotCall.gov , harrassment , Helpful , helpful information , honest review , How to , Interesting , national do not call registry , recommended , stop telemarketers , telemarketers , telemarketing , The Federal Do Not Call Registry , website 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
