<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003450" url="http://lifestyle.ezine9.com/top-10-typical-foods-in-the-united-states-77367e43b3d.html" time="2012-07-12-19:36" support="1" score="0.0008852546668923262" bingtitle="Top 10 typical foods in the United States" webtitle="Top 10 typical foods in the United States">
			<query id="000019" bing-rank="136"/>
	<description>Popular condiments such as tomato, pico de gallo, sour ... Chicago-style hot dogs can be seen in every fast-food restaurant ... With all of our conveniences-cars, cell phones ...</description>
	<body>
		You are here : Lifestyle &gt; Cuisine &gt;
Top 10 typical foods in the United States
 
Top 10 typical foods in the United States
 Add to Favourite By: Louis Brown | Sep 4, 2010 | 591 words | 1806 views Ranking: ( 0 time(s) ) 
 Email | Print | 0 Comment(s) |     Font size 
 
 Fastfoods such as hamburgers, apple pie or potato chips are popular foods in the United States. In this article, you will have chances to discover top 10 typical foods in this country. If you travel to America some day, why not try eating the following dishes?

 


New England clam chowder is a must-eat dish when you travel to Boston. It is often served in restaurants on Fridays in order to provide a seafood option for people who abstain from meat every Friday. Among many types of clam chowders, Massachuset one is the most special. It is traditionally made with bacon, onion, potatoes, flour and clams.

 


 

 You can eat clam chowder with spices and soaked biscuits 

 


Shoofly pie is a fluffy molasses pie. Lemon juice is usually added to the bottom layer and buttermilk to the topping, which makes the pie more delicious. It is best to be served for breakfast.

 


 

 Shoofly pie may get its name because the molasses attracts flies that must be &quot;shooed&quot; away 

 

 

 


 Po-boys is a sandwich comprising fried meat or seafood inside. The traditional dish is served hot and includes fried shrimp and oysters. Besides, catfish, roast beef, hot sausage and French fries can be used to replace for traditional ingredients.

 


 

 This dish is served at any American restaurant 

 


The next thing that makes America great is not meat, cake or bread. It is Chili peppers used as both food and medicine. The American do not like chilli foods as much as Korean and Chinese, but peppers are essential ingredients in their dishes. Surprisingly, green chile seems to be hotter than red one.

 


 

 Chili peppers may be green or red 

 


The production of Olympia oysters developed considerably in the 1890s, but then fell off in the early 20th century. Small oysters used to disappear; therefore oyster farmers had to import Pacific and Eastern oysters to replace them. Among various oysters, Olympia oysters are the best ones.

 


 

 Olympias are still being harvested in small quantity 

 


 Fajitas can be found in most restaurants along with an interesting slogan:“Beef, beef, and more beef”. Beef is an integral ingredient which makes Fajitas great. However, chicken, pork and shrimp are good alternatives. Popular condiments such as tomato, pico de gallo, sour cream, lettuce and cheese are shredded.

 


 

 In restaurants, meat is usually cooked with onions and bell peppers 

 


San Francisco sourdough plays a particular importance in baking rye-based breads. Sourdough starter is made with flour and water refreshed for 3 or more days. The use of a sour starter for bread can be seen in both San Francisco and Europe.

 


 

 Baguette is made from organic San Francisco sourdough 

 


Pastrami was originated from Turkey and introduced to the United States in a wave of Jewish immigration. Pastrami is usually made from beef seasoned with a mix of spices including garlic, coriander, black pepper, paprika, cloves, allspice, and mustard seed. Then it is smoked and steamed until the meat is infused.

 


 

 In New York, pastrami is sliced and served along with rye bread. 

 


 Smithfield ham was originated from the town of Smithfield in Isle of in Virginia, the U.S.A. You can smell ham whether it is well-cooked or not. Of course, cooked ham slides have better taste while normal ham seems to be fatty.

 


 

 Smithfield ham is among foods that make America great 

 

 
Chicago-style hot dogs originating from the city of Chicago, Illinois has the unique combination of condiments. The hot dog is commonly topped with yellow mustard, chopped onions, sweet pickle relish and tomato slices.

 


 

 Chicago-style hot dogs can be seen in every fast-food restaurant in the United States 

 

 

 

 Related links: 

 Useful foods for beautiful skin 

 The worst foods for your teeth 

 Reasons for anti-soft drinks 
 Author Description : 
Louis Brown lives in California, where he enjoys writing articles on a variety of subjects, especially lifestyle. By trade, he is a user interface designer.
 Share this story with friends: 
 Facebook Twitter Google yahoo Del.icio.us Stumbleupon Technorati 
 
 Related Articles New Articles 
 
Top 10 typical foods in the United States
 
United States Regional Cuisine
 Publisher: The USA is often referred to as a melting pot - but when it comes to regional cuisine throughout the United States, nothing could be further from the truth. From New England to San Francisco, from Dallas to New York, there are regional specialties that are inextricably associated with a city, a state - even a neighborhood - foods and cuisines that are so much a part of the culture of one little area of the nation that just the mention of one brings a thought of the other. 
Meditation in the United States
 Publisher: Jane Michael Meditation in the U.S. started in the late nineteen sixties and became more popular in the seventies. It was part of the hippy movement or at least that movement embraced it. One of the icons of that time in music The Beatles got into meditation and some of the eastern... 
Trends In Headboards In The United States
 Publisher: Ben Weissman Fashion and design trends change all the time, with more and more commercial applications and ideas presented to the consumer. Designers play to the fickleness of consumers as well, especially those in the United States, who tend to have a penchant for instant gratification. One of the more popular areas... 
The Elderly in the United States
 Publisher: Josanne Anthony With all of our conveniences-cars, cell phones, computers, microwaves, and so many other things that we all have to make our lives easier - we are busier than ever, and constantly moving on the fast track of life. As connected as we are through computers, cell phones, texting, fax machines, etc., we seem to be more disconnected than ever. 
The 10 Fullest Foods
 Publisher: Kadence Buchanan Let&apos;s begin by stating that there are no &quot;good&quot; or &quot;bad&quot; foods. No food exist that can make you thinner or fatter because you simply decided to try it. But what is true is that there are certain types of foods that have to be consumed in larger quantities due to their low concentration of fat and because they are rich of nutritional substances, in comparison to those that contain higher percentage of fats and low percentage of nutritional substances. 
Tea Drinking In The United States
 Publisher: Marcus Stout Traditionally, the marketplace for loose leaf tea drinkers in the United States has been limited. 
Tea Drinking In The United States
 Publisher: Marcus Stout Traditionally, the marketplace for loose leaf tea drinkers in the United States has been limited Although loose leaf tea was extremely popular in colonial times, the consumption of loose leaf tea gradually changed and recently the American market for tea has been generally confined to iced tea and tea in bags... 
Turkey Consumputions In The United States
 Publisher: Jasper Sayer The consumption of turkeys in the U.S. has escalated through the years. It&apos;s no longer eaten primarily at Thanksgiving and Christmas, but throughout the year. The process of mass-producing turkeys for human consumption is as barbaric, if not more so, than the process of mass-producing chickens. 
Beautiful Garden Centers in the United States
 Publisher: Christa Kowalczyk Garden centers are known to be retail firms, which sell products and plants related to the different garden needs. A garden center is also considered as a primary business. It caters to the general public and is open in showcasing its display and facilities for plants and gardens. The items one... 
The Grapefruit Fad Diets In United States
 Publisher: Judy Sommer More than two decades ago, people who hunted to misplace import relied on the most admired diet at that time called the grapefruit diet. It is said to give the dieters around 800 calories or fewer if you ate tons and tons of grapefruit, whispered to be fat burning and partner it with eggs for protein, dry toast Cuisine Indian Cuisine - A Glance at North Indian Cuisine Best Countries To Enjoy Delicious Foods Foods Named After People Best Dishes in Different States of America Hugest Bibimbap in China&apos;s Jilin Province Top 10 typical foods in the United States Quality kitchen knives: A basic set Enhance Your Business With Promotional Travel Mugs South African&apos;s specialities History of ketchup Food&amp;Beverage Do You Know The Tips for Making Chicken Tortilla Soup Do You Know How to Make An Easy Cream of Potato Soup 20 foods that reduce stress and depression Berkeley Restaurant Guide will be incomplete without Indian Food Hubs Agar agar powder online Carboxy Methyl Cellulose exporter in China Find history of Acesulfame-K Looking For Bodybuilding Supplements in Ireland 5 Lesser-known Benefits of Drinking Do You Know What&apos;s the Best Way For Cooking Brown Rice Related searches: New England clam chowder Pastrami Comments Add new Comment Who like this article Do Chuong Foods You Should Avoid Eating Before Bed Tips To Prevent Snoring Top Safety Tips for Holiday Travelers 20 foods that reduce stress Karlie Kloss in Dolce&amp;Gabbana Bikini Model Kate Upton Flaunts Hot Curves Angry Justin Bieber Attacks Cameraman Chris Brown’s Girlfriend 2012: Karrueche Tran Taylor Lautner and Ex-Girlfriend Sara Hicks Sports Illustrated Swimsuit 2012 models How to Choose the Right Glasses for Your Face Shape Bieber and his little brother Microsoft Surface price&amp;release round-up Top 10 Best Headphones 2012 Lea Michele Shows Some Major Cleavage Best Dressed At 2012 Kids&apos; Choice Awards Kristen Stewart glams up for press duties Best 24-Inch Monitors 2012 Irina Shayk in XTi Shoe Ad LG Optimus Slider Send email to friend about articles : Top 10 typical foods in the... Sender: (required) Your Friend Email: (required) Subject: Message :   Here is an interesting page about Top 10 typical foods in the United States at EzineSeeker. Hope that you find it helpful as well.   Login Please enter email and Password to login into the system. Email: Password:   Remember me on this Computer   Forget your password, please click here or register . Use your Facebook account to login to Ezineseeker : Login Please enter email and Password to login into the system. Email: Password:   Remember me on this Computer     Forget your password, please click here or register . Use your Facebook account to login to Ezineseeker : Send email to friend about articles : Top 10 typical foods in the... Your Friend Email: (required) Subject: Message :   Here is an interesting page about Top 10 typical foods in the United States at EzineSeeker. Hope that you find it helpful as well.   Login Please enter email and Password to login into the system. Email: Password:   Remember me on this Computer     Forget your password, please click here or register . Use your Facebook account to login to Ezineseeker : Ezine Articles Submission - Massive Exposure for Quality Article Welcome, Guest!  Log In | Create Account All Articles 
 All Articles Business Education Entertainment Health Jobs Lifestyle Society Technology Travel Vehicle 
 Submit Articles 
 Home Top Authors Top Articles Community My Profile Groups 
 Need help: Editorial Guidelines Submit articles FAQ Become Member Contact us Popular topics: : Travel Self Improvement Computer Public Relation Online Promotion Ezine9 site: Sitemap Publish Article RSS Top articles Top authors More information: Terms&amp;conditions Privacy Policy Advertise with us Partner with us About us
	</body>
</document>
