<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003076" url="http://ask.metafilter.com/tags/industry" time="2012-07-12-19:11" support="4" score="0.00419208646767896" bingtitle="Posts tagged with industry | Ask MetaFilter" webtitle="Posts tagged with industry | Ask MetaFilter">
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000592" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>Someone has an idea to put to use ... of BPA that rub off of sales receipts ... optimally broken out by fast food, restaurant and if possible restaurant bar by credit card type ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main content 
 MetaFilter AskMeFi Projects Music Jobs Podcast IRL MetaTalk 
 
 Home FAQ Archives Tags Popular Best Of Random 


 Login New User 
 
 
84 posts tagged with industry. ( View popular tags )
 Displaying 1 through 50 of 84. Subscribe: 
 Related tags: 
 music + (9)
 money + (6)
 job + (6)
 FILM + (6)
 resolved + (6)
 Economics + (5)
 career + (5)
 academia + (5)
 work + (4)
 research + (4)
 business + (4)
 employment + (4)


 Users that often use this tag: 
 Anonymous (5)
 vincentm (3)
 InterestedInKnowing (2)
 Kraftmatic Adjusta... (2)
 amusem (2)
 FlamingBore (2)
 I recently read an article that contained a quote from someone in the movie industry about how it isn&apos;t currently worthwhile, or a priority, to make movies for a female audience/from a female perspective/ something along those lines. I have tried to find the associated article, but searching&quot;movie industry women sexism&quot;isn&apos;t very successful. I think I may have read the article at Jezebel. I may have even found it here. But I totally can&apos;t find it now. Help!
 posted by windykites on Jun 10, 2012 - 4 answers 
 job hunting filter: in biotech job market, what exactly an&quot;industry experience&quot;gives you and sets you apart from others who has no such experience [ more inside ] 
 posted by akomom on Jun 2, 2012 - 8 answers 
 How do I break into the service industry (i.e. host, server, barback) without any (or very little) experience? [ more inside ] 
 posted by patientpatient on May 10, 2012 - 8 answers 
 Who are the big players that control the majority of the market in US industries? [ more inside ] 
 posted by 7life on May 3, 2012 - 16 answers 
 I&apos;m seeing someone who&apos;s relatively new to networking in regards to the music industry. What are some red flags he should be watching out for when it comes to meeting people and handling contacts? Most importantly, how do I make sure I don&apos;t step out of bounds if I recognize someone has an ulterior motive? Thanks.
 posted by InterestedInKnowing on Apr 29, 2012 - 4 answers 
 Recording an album, and trying to strike a deal with the sound engineer / producer so we don&apos;t go broke. Are we signing in to a good deal or a bad deal? [ more inside ] 
 posted by klausman on Apr 14, 2012 - 10 answers 
 How do I deal with working in an industry/for people whose values don&apos;t match mine? [ more inside ] 
 posted by nubianinthedesert on Feb 27, 2012 - 36 answers 
 Let&apos;s assume Susan G. Komen has found an all-encompassing cure for [breast] cancer. Who owns the rights to the patent? [ more inside ] 
 posted by aca.int on Feb 4, 2012 - 8 answers 
 How can I learn more about the fake watch industry? [ more inside ] 
 posted by Admira on Nov 18, 2011 - 3 answers 
 I&apos;m in a band, and we&apos;re being courted by a fairly senior guy in the music industry. He&apos;s suggesting that rather than signing ourselves away to a major, we fund the first 18 months (so album recording, tour, publicity etc) we get funding from venture capitalists. Does anyone have any experience with this, or have any links for further reading on this? The music industry can be an unforgiving environment, and I want to know as much as possible independently to our potential manager...
 posted by anonymous on Aug 18, 2011 - 13 answers 
 What are the best resources (books, journals, blogs, etc) for becoming highly knowledgeable about the natural gas industry? [ more inside ] 
 posted by narcotizingdysfunction on Aug 12, 2011 - 3 answers 
 Can you help me find some free or modestly-priced online reports on the state of the publishing, recorded music, film + photo agencies / picture archives industries in the EU? [ more inside ] 
 posted by anonymous on Jul 25, 2011 - 3 answers 
 Does anyone have a source for a nice big image of the logo for the Moscow Engineering Physics Institute? There&apos;s a vector version floating around, but I&apos;d much prefer a large version of the original.
 posted by nicolas léonard sadi carnot on Jul 13, 2011 - 3 answers 
 Looking for outstanding examples of animations and videos that explain a difficult-to-understand concept or topic. Not KhanAcademy-type, but rather interactive Flash works or videos with 3D animation. [ more inside ] 
 posted by Kraftmatic Adjustable Cheese on Jul 9, 2011 - 12 answers 
 Someone has an idea to put to use an existing industrial machine that would expand its capabilities and reach other markets. At the moment there are 3 companies that manufacture this machine that he&apos;d like to approach. [ more inside ] 
 posted by watercarrier on Jul 6, 2011 - 6 answers 
 I&apos;d like to find some reasonably current information on the technical and quality challenges in industrial applications of fibre and OPSL lasers. [ more inside ] 
 posted by Jakey on May 4, 2011 - 2 answers 
 How can I learn a large amount about a topic in a few days? [ more inside ] 
 posted by Kraftmatic Adjustable Cheese on Apr 10, 2011 - 12 answers 
 One of my college professors from the TV department wants to come out to LA and learn more about the overall entertainment industry to update his knowledge. Are there any fellowships to help him do it? [ more inside ] 
 posted by rileyray3000 on Mar 25, 2011 - 4 answers 
 How does a biotech postdoc simultaneously explore academic and industry job opportunities? [ more inside ] 
 posted by anonymous on Jan 31, 2011 - 4 answers 
 Phthalates, VOCs, BPA in plastic and cans, the list goes on. I changed my habits in an attempt to avoid all those things. Now it&apos;s high amounts of BPA that rub off of sales receipts. Any advice that could help me chill out? I&apos;m exhausted. [ more inside ] 
 posted by allisonrae on Jan 1, 2011 - 17 answers 
 Please help a new Ph.D. know what to expect from a corporate recruiting interview in the sciences. [ more inside ] 
 posted by amelioration on Sep 23, 2010 - 10 answers 
 Is there an economic measure that describes what proportion of GDP is produced by firms of different sizes? [ more inside ] 
 posted by nowoutside on Sep 13, 2010 - 4 answers 
 I&apos;m doing reference vocals for a couple of team songwriters who have recently been signed under a music DJ who works for a major record label. The tracks are good, these guys know their pop music, however they have no money to offer me at the moment. The only things they can offer me is free studio time, access to their songwriters, some music tracks and connections in getting my music to the right people. When I get paid depends if their boss likes the vocals or if an artist picks up the song. Is this a common tactic among new songwriters when they cannot pay their vocalists? How can I make sure I&apos;m getting the best end of this deal or should I walk away?
 posted by InterestedInKnowing on Jul 7, 2010 - 2 answers 
 Been trying my best google-fu to no avail... so perhaps someone here might know where to point me.I am trying to determine the number of credit card transaction count and dollars annually that are used in the food industry, optimally broken out by fast food, restaurant and if possible restaurant bar by credit card type by year. Knowing this info for other countries would be helpful too. thanks so much for any help you can provide. smiles to all.
 posted by wildpetals on May 27, 2010 - 2 answers 
 Looking for articles and essays concerning the early days of the phonograph and radio--especially the cultural impact. [ more inside ] 
 posted by captainsohler on Feb 21, 2010 - 5 answers 
 So, celebrity gossip is everywhere and lots of $$$ is forked out for images of famous babies, etcetera... BUT how much money does the gossip industry MAKE? [ more inside ] 
 posted by Elle Vator on Dec 11, 2009 - 5 answers 
 I&apos;m looking for non-traditional collaboration models between academia and industry (any field) or between companies/consortiums. Any pointers? [ more inside ] 
 posted by gadha on Nov 30, 2009 - 7 answers 
 Applying to enter a math PhD program after working in industry. Question about recommendations. [ more inside ] 
 posted by lakshmi_mefi on Nov 23, 2009 - 9 answers 
 What kind of small toys or devices click when you rotate them forwards and backwards? Seeking mechanism or design... [ more inside ] 
 posted by pallen123 on Nov 21, 2009 - 13 answers 
 You are a paid writer/screenwriter/columnist/blogger. What can you tell me about how to best break into this profession? [ more inside ] 
 posted by the NATURAL on Oct 12, 2009 - 13 answers 
 What proportion of leather comes from animals whose other parts are ultimately consumed by humans for food? What proportion of leather-bearing food animals&apos; skins are ultimately made into leather? How would i find out? [ more inside ] 
 posted by dkg on Oct 9, 2009 - 6 answers 
 Do you know of any industry specific public online forums where insiders discuss common problems or share helpful tips? [ more inside ] 
 posted by Diddly on Sep 9, 2009 - 12 answers 
 Do video game industry non-compete agreements typically prevent their employees from working on and releasing small games in their own time? I&apos;m thinking of all employees, including developers, testers, designers, managers, and artists.
 posted by ignignokt on Jul 9, 2009 - 9 answers 
 I&apos;m a full-time film editor and occasional composer in Vancouver, about to move to Toronto. My main work has been TV movies and short films. Because I don&apos;t have a job lined up there, I&apos;ll need to network. I also enjoy collaborating, and would love to make some new acquaintances -- I don&apos;t know many people in TO. Can anyone think of resources, groups, or organizations in Toronto that might help me achieve these goals? [ more inside ] 
 posted by gonna get a dog on Jun 16, 2009 - 3 answers 
 I want a PhD in Mathematics, but I do not want to stay in academia. Is it worth it? [ more inside ] 
 posted by alligatorman on Jun 14, 2009 - 11 answers 
 Are there more car salespeople than automobile manufacturing people in the United States? [ more inside ] 
 posted by cinemafiend on Jun 1, 2009 - 5 answers 
 How does American Apparel make money? [ more inside ] 
 posted by abirae on May 27, 2009 - 10 answers 
 Looking for examples of creative, modern industrial architecture. [ more inside ] 
 posted by lou on Mar 28, 2009 - 9 answers 
 With the current financial crisis highlighting corruption within the banking and auto industries, I&apos;m starting to wonder about other industries that might be a little below the radar. What industries are generally corrupt? [ more inside ] 
 posted by roxegirl on Mar 3, 2009 - 26 answers 
 How to crack into the nonprofit sector? [ more inside ] 
 posted by cranberrymonger on Nov 30, 2008 - 14 answers 
 CareerFilter: I will be finishing my BS in Computer Science in 2-3 years. What industries will likely offer the best earnings potential and interesting work to a software engineer, and how do I improve my attractiveness as a potential hire to those industries? [ more inside ] 
 posted by [user was fined for this post] on Nov 24, 2008 - 6 answers 
 Wanting to leave academia after astrophysics PhD (oscillations in atmospheres of rotating starts, planets and discs). Need some feedback, tags, hints, keywords, that I should search in google and some suggestions of where my skills (look in the extended explanation) would be appreciated. [ more inside ] 
 posted by gradstu1980 on Nov 9, 2008 - 11 answers 
 Talented people making high quality goods (belts, wooden objects, pens, misc leather items , clothes, manuscript books, etc) at reasonable prices. [ more inside ] 
 posted by dance on Oct 20, 2008 - 11 answers 
 &quot;In order to feasibly produce, say, transparent adhesive tape, integrated circuits or sugar-free soft drinks, you need such-and-such materials and such-and-such equipment, which in turn depend on other things, all the way down to ores and fuel and such. So if you want to build your very own set of night vision goggles from scratch, here&apos;s everything you need access to in order to get started&quot;Has anyone compiled, for the public to see, anything resembling a real-life &apos;tech-tree&apos;, akin to what&apos;s found in computer games such as Civilization? [ more inside ] 
 posted by Anything on Oct 19, 2008 - 6 answers 
 I&apos;m about to begin work at a medical device company (as a paralegal) and would like an introductory book on the subject. I&apos;ve scoured Amazon, but haven&apos;t found anything that&apos;s a general overview, with chapters on history, business climate, FDA and regulatory issues, litigation -- just a smattering of everything, with perhaps emphasis on legal / regulatory. Most books are more specialized. Or are there websites or white papers along these lines? Recommendations, please!
 posted by nancoix on Aug 1, 2008 - 2 answers 
 AskMe Reference Desk: Pre-industrial production and trade of leather and leather goods - how did it work? [ more inside ] 
 posted by CKmtl on Jul 6, 2008 - 5 answers 
 how does a newcomer break into the nashville music industry? and how long does it usually take a newbie songwriter to be taken seriously?
 posted by locoindio on Jun 2, 2008 - 9 answers 
 People often say:&quot;The best way to make a small fortune in [insert industry here] is to start with a large one&quot;Who first came up with this joke, and what industry was the joke originally about?
 posted by Kevin A on May 16, 2008 - 16 answers 
 What do pornographers know that we don&apos;t? Namely, how to convince people to have sex on camera for not much money? [ more inside ] 
 posted by penciltopper on Apr 28, 2008 - 39 answers 
 How do financial dominatrices make their money? [ more inside ] 
 posted by divabat on Apr 23, 2008 - 9 answers 
 Page: 
 
 1 2 
 
 Features 
- Login 
- New User 
 Links 
- Home 
- Search 
- Archives 
- Tags 
- About 
- MeFi Wiki 
 Sites 
- MetaFilter 
- AskMeFi 
- Projects 
- Music 
- Jobs 
- IRL 
- MetaTalk ©1999-2012 MetaFilter Network Inc. 
All posts are©their original authors. 

 FAQ | Contact | *
	</body>
</document>
