<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003702" url="http://www.kvoa.com/news/mexican-fast-food-restaurant-in-hot-water/" time="2012-07-12-19:51" support="1" score="0.0005623955389445107" bingtitle="Mexican fast-food restaurant in hot water | KVOA.com | Tucson, Arizona" webtitle="Mexican fast-food restaurant in hot water | KVOA.com | Tucson, Arizona">
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>Pay it Forward; Sports. Sports News; High School Sports ... Mexican fast-food restaurant in hot water. Posted: Mar 22, 2012 9:00 ... Plus, the soda gun cups holder had a slimey growth ...</description>
	<body>
		Member Center

 Create Account Log In 
 
 KVOA.com 
 
 
 
 Sponsored by 
 
 Home 
 Create Account Log In Contact Us TV Listings 
 News 
 Local Arizona National Decision 2012 Kristis Kids Investigators CrimeTrackers News 4 @ 4 Let&apos;s Make a Meal News 4 Cooks News Links Online Poll Pay it Forward 
 Sports 
 Sports News High School Sports Arizona Wildcats Olympic Zone NBC Sports 
 Weather 
 Monsoon Storm Alert Interactive Map 7-Day Forecast Day Planner Todays Almanac Current Conditions Southeast Highs Southeast Lows Weather IQ 
 Video 
 Local News Sports News 4 at 4 Crime Trackers Kristi&apos;s Kids The Investigators Kitchen Cops NBC News Video 
 Health 
 TucsonHealth101.com Kitchen Cops Hittin&apos; the Trails 4 You Buddy Check 4 Biggest Loser Tucson 
 Traffic 
 TRAFFIC Text Alerts Traffic News Gas Buddy Tucson Traffic LIVE Incident Map LIVE Tucson Traffic Cameras 2 Wheelin&apos; in Tucson 
 Contests 
 Lifesaver Coloring Contest Lifesaver Essay Contests Half OFFers Register to Win Mug Mondays 
 About Us 
 Jobs and Careers Contact Us Meet Our Staff Contributors KVOA on Facebook @KVOA on Twitter Mobile Apps Text Alerts Community Calendar 
 Half OFFers 
 KVOA Half OFFers home KVOA Half OFFers on Twitter KVOA Half OFFers on Facebook 
 On TV 
 TV Listings Watch NBC Shows Online 
 Galleries 
 UA Sports Our Viewers On the Spot Hittin the Trails Arizona Critters Beautiful Arizona Weather News Tips Monsoon 2012 All Galleries 
 
 
 The Main Stream 

 Mexican fast-food restaurant in hot water 

Posted: Mar 22, 2012 9:00 PM
 Updated: Mar 23, 2012 8:37 AM 
 
 
 
 Rating: 
 
 0.0 (0 votes) 
TUCSON - Los Beto&apos;s on W. Ajo Way received five critical violations. A cook was rolling burritos with his bare hands. Raw shrimp was stored above ready-to-eat chili beef, and there was not hot water in the facility.

Los Beto&apos;s on W. Ajo Way is operating on a &quot;Provisional&quot; license.

Chili&apos;s on Broadway received two critical violations. Several foods were not cooked to the correct temperature. Plus, the soda gun cups holder had a slimey growth on it. Chili&apos;s on Broadway received a &quot;Good&quot; rating.

Bella Vita Pizzeria on Ina passed its re-inspection.

Waffle House on Grant, Pappoules at the Foothills Mall and Mamma Llama&apos;s on Craycroft all received an &quot;Excellent&quot; rating.


 
 Comments 
 
 
 
KVOA.com is Social!

 
 
 
 Click here to submit a news tip to News 4 Tucson! 
 
 
 Most Popular 
 
 Viewed 
 
DON&apos;T MISS THESE!
 
 HALF-OFFERS 

Why Pay Full Price for the Things You Want?
 
 KRISTI&apos;S KIDS LIFESAVER 2012 

Help save lives this summer!
 
 NEWS 4 TUCSON ON FACEBOOK 

Become a Facebook Fan!
 
 @KVOA ON TWITTER 

Follow us!
 
 BECOME A MEMBER 

Sign up on KVOA.com for newsletters, exclusive deals, and more!
 
 KVOA.COM LATEST CONTESTS 

Win! Win! Win!
 
 KVOA MOBILE APPS 

Get news, weather and more on your smartphone and tablet!
 
 TEXT ALERTS 

Get texts for news, traffic, deals and more!
 
 KRISTI&apos;S KIDS 

Stories and videos with Kristi&apos;s Kids
 
 NEWS 4 TUCSON @ 4 

What&apos;s happening on News 4 @ 4
 
 ADVERTISE WITH KVOA.COM 

Let us help grow your business
 
 COMMUNITY CALENDAR 

What&apos;s happening?
 
 KVOA PROGRAM SCHEDULE 

What&apos;s on KVOA and when!
 
 CONTACT US 

Contact info for our department heads
 
 MEET US! 

KVOA&apos;s on air personalities!
 
 KVOA CAREERS 

Work at News 4 Tucson
 
 RSS FEEDS 

Complete feeds of all KVOA.com stories
 
 SUBMIT NEWS TIP 

Click here to submit a news tip to us!
 
 Local News 
 
 
 &apos;Hiring Our Heroes&apos; job fair is is today 
 
 Local artists create outdoor gallery downtown Play Video 
 
 Prices at the Pump 7/12 Play Video 
 
 Cone Zone 7/12: Oro Valley, Downtown, Benson Play Video 
 
 Sierra Vista speed enforcement campaign Play Video 
 
 AZ ranks 3rd in total cases of unidentified remains Play Video 
 
 Late night boy scout rescue in remote area Play Video 
 
 
All content©2001 - 2012 KVOA.com - Tucson, AZ . All Rights Reserved.
For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
 Search Local.com: Popular Searches | Powered by Local.com Apartments in Tucson | Attorneys in Tucson | Auto Dealers in Tucson | Auto Parts in Tucson | Auto Repair in Tucson | Beauty Salons in Tucson | Car Rental in Tucson | Dentists in Tucson | Doctors in Tucson | Flowers in Tucson | Hotels in Tucson | Insurance in Tucson | Loans in Tucson | Mortgages in Tucson | Movers in Tucson | Pizza in Tucson | Realtors in Tucson | Restaurants in Tucson | Storage in Tucson | Tax Preparation in Tucson | Travel in Tucson | Featured | More...
	</body>
</document>
