<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003953" url="http://www.startupbizhub.com/start-your-own-homemade-preserves-and-pickle-business.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="1" score="0.0015492623378807403" bingtitle="Start Your Own Homemade Preserves and Pickle Business" webtitle="Start Your Own Homemade Preserves and Pickle Business">
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>This article will give you the necessary background that you’d need in order to get ... and family who love my food ... Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant; Starting ...</description>
	<body>
		News   Franchise 
 129   
Start Your Own Homemade Preserves and Pickle Business


 Perhaps you love to eat preserves and pickles, and would like to make money out of the things that you love. Now that youve made the decision, you are now asking yourself? How do I start my own homemade preserves and pickle business? 

This article will give you the necessary background that youd need in order to get going with your planned business.

 

In reality, getting into your own homemade preserves and pickle business is not that tough. All you need to know are the materials and the processes that you would be doing when you finally get into your business.

Materials for Starting a Homemade Preserves Business

To start a homemade preserves business, you would need lots of fruits. If you notice in commercial stores, fruits are preserved and bottled. The results of processing homemade fruit preserves are the jams, jellies and marmalades that you eat together with your bread.

With this mind, you need a good source of fruits. You could either choose to grow your own fruits, or you can get yourself a good supplier. Remember, since you are starting a business, you need a constant supply of fruits because youd be getting a lot of orders from your clients. It would do you no good to run out of supplies in the midst of a large order, wouldnt it?

If you plan to produce confits and curds as well, then you would also need a good supply of eggs and butter. Butter is easily and commercially available and, if you have money, you can grow poultry for your egg supply. This can also double as another business because you can sell off the extra eggs. You would also need honey for your confits as well.

Materials for Starting a Pickle Business

Pickles are generally vegetables that are subjected to brining. This means vegetables are subjected to fermentation by being soaked in a salt solution. This could also mean that vegetables are marinated and then stored in vinegar, although other acid solutions may be utilized. Pickles are processed in order to produce a pH feature of less than 4.6. This is because necrobacteria are killed in such an acidity level.

Pickling had its roots as a preservation technique, especially for sailors, but nowadays it has evolved into a business opportunity. Many people particularly enjoy the taste and flavors of pickled vegetable; hence it has risen in demand. Although few people know it, the bacteria in pickles are able to introduce Vitamin B into the pickle and improving their nutritious value. In other words, pickles are a healthy and delicious food that people can consume.

There are a variety of vegetables that you can gather for pickling. It would depend on your audience. In the North American and Canadian markets, for example, cucumbers are the dominant vegetables. However, you can still make money selling pickled vegetables that are popular in other nations as the United States has a high cultural diversity.



 &lt;&lt; Freelance Web Developing Business     Starting Home Sewing and Embroidery Business  &gt;&gt; 

129 Responses to &quot;Start Your Own Homemade Preserves and Pickle Business&quot;.
 1. nick on 7/28/2008 i still like to get info on how, like recipe or storage, or buying equipment 2. chandan kumar shrivastava on 2/9/2009 12:22:00 AM i want a report of pickle business. 3. Darlene on 3/18/2009 5:47:02 PM What is the average cost to make lets say a jar of strawberry jelly. I know it depends on the season, so if you could give me the worse case and the best case figures i would appreciate it very much. 4. mona nibber on 5/8/2009 3:15:31 AM i am from Amritsar and i am a house wife. i have no idea to start pickle business but i am very much interested to start this business. how much i need to invest? should i join the classes to prepare the pickle for home business. please suggest me. in short send me the a b c of this business. 5. Kath on 6/16/2009 6:59:01 PM Hi, Please could you send me the details of the business that you have, a detailed report of a previous venture would be helpful.

Thanks 6. A.Gauthama on 9/1/2009 2:40:46 AM I am interested to know about pickle business. Please guide me. 7. upendra joshi on 11/5/2009 2:16:12 AM to learn more about pickles contact us-03931276999,09391021222 8. Pramod on 12/28/2009 7:05:19 AM Hi, I would like to start the pickle business. But just a trading and not a production. Could you please guide me the risk and the funds required in this? Thanks, -Pramod 9. sue mercer on 2/6/2010 12:40:17 AM I would like some information on how to sell my homemade produce at farmer markets on the weekend and selling homemade produce gift baskets on line any help would be good, thanks sue. I live in seaford south australia 10. Anil Thomas on 2/23/2010 5:40:46 AM Hi, My mom is home maker, very good at Pickle preparation. We have tested with many people and everybody liked it. you can keep it for minimum six months. I am planning to start as business, can anybody help me what is prospects, how do i start etc., Looking forward a good suggestion. Thanks, Anil 11. kulvinder on 3/24/2010 1:33:19 PM indian pickles of mango, chillies, lemon, sweet sauces etc in bangkok 12. moni on 5/9/2010 2:56:39 AM Hi All, i am planning to start a pickle business in kerala. Can any body guide me?....Expecting ur co operation plz...Moni 13. priti on 5/24/2010 6:47:33 AM will you please inform me about &apos;various option for home based food productions&apos; gulbarga karanatka 14. afsal ashraf on 6/26/2010 6:00:17 AM please guide me with the investment and requirements to start this business 15. Nidheeshmon A J on 6/29/2010 3:29:32 AM i would like to start a pickle business in indian pickle like pickles of mango, chillies, lemon, sweet sauces etc. pls inform the formalities which i have to done b4 start the business. thanks and regards, Nidheesh 16. vishwanath sagavkar on 7/1/2010 4:27:03 AM I am thinking about to start my own pickle buisness, I wanted to complete guidance about pickle&amp;spices manufacturing guidance. 17. Matt M on 7/24/2010 12:04:34 AM St. Paul, MN. I have a killer recipe for pickles that people rave about and would like to start a business. Any help would be grateful. 18. Sue Darmody on 7/26/2010 12:22:03 AM I would like to start a small business making pickles and preserves and selling them in Sydney, NSW. How can I determine shelf life of these products and also what are the labeling requirements? 19. ushachandra on 7/27/2010 2:53:51 AM can u please tell how can i start pickle business through online...Hyderabad, Andhrapradesh, India 20. salma on 8/15/2010 5:23:55 PM I&apos;m interested in information about packaging cut fresh fruits and vegetables---getting them prepared for local market sale, home and office deliveries and in future supplying to stores. Getting the ABC of the whole process would be of much help. Thanks I live in Boston Ma. salsemasalema@yahoo.com 21. punit on 8/27/2010 9:32:33 AM Hi i m from mumbai my mom makes the best lemon pickles .which is the right place to sell it? 22. M.R.BIJU on 8/27/2010 10:37:32 AM hi, i am very interested to start a pickle business i want to know about the source of lemon, mangoes, ginger etc in low cost in all season .what is the main risk of this business ? and how we get international market. please give me your valuable advice 23. Jenson on 8/29/2010 3:16:17 PM Hi i m from kerala, Now working in dubai, I wish to start one pickle business for Export purpose. Kindly advise me how i start a small scale industry in kerala and any govmnt organization will help me for train how will sore this stuff and how will pack and all. Also were i will get machinery for packing and all? Please give me u r advice:jenson_expocok@yahoo.com 24. aditya on 9/2/2010 9:36:35 AM i live in sikar rajasthan and i want to start my own pickles business please assist me. 25. santhosh on 9/8/2010 7:27:59 AM hai, i am from chennai, advise me a b c of to start pickle business 26. rathi on 9/13/2010 1:15:44 AM Hi i am from chennai . i know how to make lemon, mango, gooseberry, garlic and ginger pickles . would like to start a buisness . can u pls give me the assistance . Thanks and regards 27. M.Ayyappan on 9/24/2010 9:58:40 AM I wish to export pickles from Cochin to Dubai can u please give me an idea about the procedures to export and the Shops at Dubai who require Kerala Pickles and their contact details etc. We are in Cochin and now doing Pickle business locally 28. amit kumar gupta on 9/26/2010 12:39:45 AM hi i want to start my pickle buisness. pls guide me how to register this buisness and what type of licenses required to do this buisness. 29. Anoop Bajpai on 11/30/2010 10:36:49 AM hi i m anoop bajpai. i want to start a home scale unit of good quality of different types of north indian pickles&amp;preserves. kindly guide me what types of machines&amp;equipments are required to prepare&amp;packaging. 30. fatemeh on 1/6/2011 8:42:58 AM Hi all.I am from kelachay in Iran.like to know how can i sell homemade jar and pickle? please give me some advice.thank you 31. shalinasen on 1/9/2011 1:12:44 PM hi.pls guide me to register non-veg home-made pickle business and what all licenses i have to have to do this business.kindly guide me also to what types of machines are required to preparation and packaging.and also about preservatives used in non-veg fish pickles.am from kerala. 32. harikumar on 1/12/2011 5:19:06 AM i would like to start pickle business at home.pl.guide me.what are all the things i have to do.what license required. how to get it. how to preserve veg. and non.veg pickles and how to pack it.and also jams.what will be the investment.from where i will get finance.i am from nilgiris. 33. sripriya on 1/12/2011 7:03:16 AM I am a house wife. I wanted to start pickle business. But I Don&apos;t know how much I invest my pickle business? then how will I get my customer? How will I talk customer initially? please help me. Answer me through my mail. Thanking U. 34. Kam on 1/12/2011 12:07:51 PM I am in USA. Want to start online direct to consumer business for specialty pickles from different countries. Do I need FDA involvement? what are my liabilities and responsibilities, how do I find correct jars and designer bottles, labels economically, do I need a permit or a certified preparation place, etc. Thanks. 35. Kellybee on 1/12/2011 2:40:57 PM Irvine, CA 92618. Hi, I would like to start a pickle business and chills. I have develop my recipes without any preservatives and it is delicious. My family and friends have taste test my pickles, pickle chills, and they love it. I want to have my own business and hope one day my products will end up in the supermarkets. Thank you for your help. 36. FatBottomedGirl on 1/13/2011 6:38:55 PM Seal Beach, CA. Like Kellybee, I too would like to start a business selling my original peach chutney and spiced peach butter. I have spent the past few years perfecting recipes for natural cooked-fruit products; friends and family who love my food encourage me now to take the next step to market my products. My products are all-natural with no preservatives and little sugar. Kellybee, can we start a dialog and share info? We both have the same goal selling our delicious products. lacuisiniere@yahoo.com 37. jeri lesch on 2/3/2011 7:39:12 PM I would like to start a pickle business in Marina Ca. I need step by step guidance. like start up cost.Licenses etc where to find jars, lables, bar codes. thank Jeri 38. Sugumar on 2/10/2011 1:28:58 AM Hi, i&apos;m from coimbatore, tamil nadu. We have prepare all type of pickles and i wish to export my pickles. so please guide me to export and how to get finance. 39. jaybest on 2/10/2011 8:06:06 AM Hi, I am Jim from California USA. Sugumar, I am interested in importing your pickled items from tamil nadu. Kindly reply as I will go ahead with the formalities and customs. 40. Gregory Mitchell on 2/21/2011 11:46:44 PM Hi, Will becoming out of hospital soon, no longer able to practice as a Chiropractor. Want to start a small pickle/preserve biz. I have my Master Food Preserver ticket and a library of 200+ books of techniques and recipes from the 1800&apos;s to present day. People LOVE my products, but I have only made small batch stuff so far. No IDEA of market demands, costs, etc. I could use some good old, all-around Dutch Uncle advice. Love to chat with y&apos;all...BE LUCKY !!! Gregory Mitchell- nlpmp.gm@gmail,com 818-428-7851 18375 Ventura Blvd. #289 Tarzana CA 91356 USA 41. usha Narasimhan on 3/5/2011 6:47:03 AM i am usha housewife from bangalore. i would like to know the preservative (names) which should be added for making pickles. please name the preservatives . i am eager to start pickle business. Thank you 42. Raghunath on 3/5/2011 11:10:36 PM @usha Narasimhan, normally in homemade pickles salt, oil and spices are the main preservatives but in commercial pickles citric acid and sodium benzoate is found. Let me know if you need more help. 
Raghunath Natarajan
Startup Biz Hub - Advisor (Staff)
 43. Nitu Shekhawat on 3/12/2011 2:32:04 AM Hi, I Want To Start My Pickle Business. Also I Want To Sell My Pickle By Ebay.com. May You Please Suggest The Procedure. 44. Mountainmiester on 3/14/2011 12:48:26 PM Unfortunately, I see nothing here about the business of starting a pickling business. Do I need a commercial kitchen? What is the processes legally to begin a food company? Do I need special insurance? Do I have to register anything with the FDA? 45. James on 3/15/2011 7:38:48 AM @Mountainmiester, you can get away with a regular kitchen but that should have few things that are required by FDA. Here is a list of things required by FDA for food business. 
Jestin James
Startup Biz Hub - Senior Advisor (Staff)
 46. sam mathew on 4/5/2011 3:07:44 PM hi i&apos;m into pickle business our specialty is prawns pickle,tuna,squid,searfish. production capacity is 60,000 bottles per month. currently exporting to australia,dubai. i want to expand my business to usa ,canada.uk..if any body interested to import my products i shall send samples to your desired destination..pls contact at chefmathewsam@yahoo.co.in..our production facility is usda approved etc 47. Bhavik Shah on 4/25/2011 1:38:44 PM Hi... we want to starting the business of pickle, we have started at small scale at home but now i want to give the huge interest in to this business so give us idea for my mom&apos;s dream of their large business. i am from India, Gujarat. Thanks... 48. rajib kumar sahu on 4/29/2011 3:28:19 AM hi my self rajiv i want to the pickle business and marketing information of new delhi in india . so give as idea .my dream their largest business. rajiv, berhampur, orissa. 49. Johny Mathew on 5/24/2011 1:44:47 PM Dear Sir, I like to start an pickle business. what is the legal procedure for it and where shall i get license for it in Banagalore north. Regards, Johny. 50. benjamin kalyanapu on 5/26/2011 12:51:20 AM hello i am benjamin kalyanapu from Ballarsha , maharashtra , india.
we already running pickles business from 15 years but we don&apos;t have any brand name or standardized product we dont have any packaging standards. we sell it door to door in the cities by roaming. please help me to get standerdised and tell me how can i get my brand name registered, food license and tell me the all process of setting up a business legally . 51. rahul on 5/27/2011 3:46:18 AM HI I AM RAHUL FROM ASSAM. I WANT TO START A PICKLE BUSINESS. I HAVE THE REQUIRED MANPOWER BUT I AM AFRAID OF MARKETING SEGMENT. SO PLS ANYONE SUGGEST ME. PLS...... 52. Jaba Mukherjee on 5/30/2011 1:26:01 AM I am a Home Maker in kokata... want to start a business with my friend.. my friend can make a nice prickle and other things how can i market it can some one help me? 53. Pooja BHasin on 6/3/2011 5:06:39 AM HI , I want to start Pickle business . I dont know how and where to place my products in the market. The focused market is Noida and Meerut. Please suggest . Regards, Pooja 54. DEEPA P on 6/6/2011 1:02:22 AM I WANT TO START A PICKLE MANUFACTURING UNIT.I AM STAYING IN KOLLAM.CAN U SUGGEST ME ABOUT THE MARKETING AND ALSO PLS SUGGEST ME THE INITIAL FORMALITIES FOR STARTING THE UNIT.I CAN INVEST ONLY 25000/-. 55. pushpaveni on 6/6/2011 1:41:10 AM I am a home maker doing catering business. pls guide me how to register the business and what type of license required to do this business.pls tell me how to preserve, pack and how much investment i need for starting this business. can u suggest from where i wl get finance.i am staying in kollam. 56. Deepak lamsal on 6/8/2011 12:42:55 PM dear sir, I want to start of pickle business, but i don&apos;t know processing of pickle make so give us your idea for me and also send machine or plant picture. I am from Nepal,Butwal 57. MOHD FAIZAN on 6/16/2011 10:18:54 AM dear sir i am living in delhi india. i am going to start pickle business and i have mango pickle recipe but want more recipe and i want to know about registration process and also know how to i get approval from health department i have only 20000 in my hand pls tell me the formality on urgent basis this request 58. NARAYANA RAO on 6/20/2011 4:04:28 AM Dear i want to establish non-veg pickle industry...plzz tell how to establish industry and what is required, how to registration, how to processing, how to packing, what is the present marketing procedural initial investment 20lakhs. 59. mohinish kumar on 6/20/2011 11:57:25 PM dear sir i want to start my own business of pickle .plzz help me to start my own business and guide me fully as possible .i need to help you sir .country India, state Bihar, city Patna. 60. B.Prasad on 6/22/2011 5:41:07 AM Dear sir, I had an food license but i had no money and i don&apos;t know how to start and develop business.we are requesting you to please give us guidelines to start business and also for the bank process for initial investment. 61. Jennifer McGraw on 7/14/2011 12:46:37 PM Hi i am very excited to start up a pickled string-bean company i want to work for myself please could you send me some information and all the facts i should know that would be very much appreciated. I live in Sackville N.B Canada my address is 1599 Route 16, Baie Verte N.B, E4M 2J1 62. Cecilia Viteri on 7/19/2011 5:12:33 AM Sir, I am about to begin a small business in Ecuador. What are the sanitary requirements for the kitchen? Thanks. 63. raman on 7/27/2011 7:05:32 AM hi, my mom makes the best lemon pickles and everyone appreciate her talent whether family,friends,no preservative is used,good for health&amp;demanded esp.in hilly areas b&apos;coz many people take from her when they go to greater heights of mountains.i personally want that my mom&apos;s hard-work achieve success by starting her business.please guide me all the procedures step by step like-license,packing,orders etc.waiting FOR YOUR RESPONSE -EMAIL rn3012@gmail.com 64. rajesh sharma. on 7/31/2011 1:19:56 AM i want to start a little pickle factory, plz help us. Rajesh 09721494074. 65. Vijaylakshmi on 8/1/2011 12:23:15 PM We are about to start a small scale business in tomato pickle(home made)Please contact us. mob(07259729909) 66. Rahul on 8/3/2011 7:46:17 AM I want to start my own pickle business in kolkata please assist me. 67. Abu hammad on 8/6/2011 7:27:28 AM Hi i am abu hammad from chennai south india we are manufacturing excellent quality of beef and meat 100% HALAL pickles which can be used for six to 24 months so pls feel free to call for marketing and importing or mail us mzmqasmi@yahoo.co.in note only whole sale
 for locals 68. Thangamani on 8/21/2011 8:01:14 AM I want pickle business so give me details..so pls replay me.
Karur, tamilnadu, india.... 69. Anupam on 9/3/2011 5:08:46 AM Please send me the details of the pickle business to how to do the marketing of the business. Ghaziabad UP, Thanks Anupam 70. jeri Dee&apos;s on 9/3/2011 10:13:08 PM I would like to start my own pickle business. I have been making them for about 20 years, and everyone loves them. I have send them to friends
from the east coast to the west coast.and they say to put them on the market. I need some information on how to market them and to get a distributor. 71. prem kumar on 9/13/2011 12:51:44 AM i am planning to start the pickles business. I want to know about the packing and storage method of pickles business. 72. venkat on 9/13/2011 8:54:08 AM I want to process all south Indian pickles in Vizianagaram Andhra Pradesh and sell the same in Andhra Pradesh&amp;Delhi or All India. What all licenses are required for manufacturing and trading this product at different locations. 73. thonta on 9/14/2011 3:35:22 AM i process all type of south Indian pickles in hkarnataka, bangalore and sell the same in Andhra Pradesh&amp;Delhi or All India. What all licenses are required for manufacturing and trading this product to overseas. 74. satheesh on 9/15/2011 11:39:28 AM I would like to start the pickle business in south part of kanyakumari, what is the process of start the business and where is available in the machines, and training institute in tamilnadu and kerala states. 75. Danish on 10/9/2011 4:42:49 AM I want to start pickle business. I would like to know about the packaging, storage method and also the various other methods and process of pickle business. 76. Ryan on 10/13/2011 2:23:16 AM chicago illinois. Please send me more detailed info as to the standard operating procedures for specialty pickel, relish, tampinad, gremalotta&apos;s. Thank you. 77. aley on 10/25/2011 1:10:23 PM please help me to start the pickle business. I need a good kerala recipe for mango, lemon and ambazhanga(june plum)pickles and canning and storing of pickles. please explain the process.I live in florida, usa 78. bob on 10/28/2011 12:54:42 PM Hi i want to start a pickle business in mumbai on a commercial basis.Please let me know in detail about the business plan and investment required for pickle business 79. shakeel on 11/1/2011 2:58:39 AM i want to start pickle business please send me complete recipe of pickle and how i store pickle long time.i am in pakistan. 80. V L Swaminaathan on 11/4/2011 11:59:11 AM I would like to start pickle export. what are the procedures for export
V L Swaminaathan 81. Darshan on 11/8/2011 3:49:14 PM I want to sell or export my home made pickles, souses, muraba, in local or international ,guide me right place to sell, GHAZIABAD
 Uttar pradesh, India 82. Angulique Hollamby on 11/15/2011 2:59:32 PM I want to export my home pickles, local or international. please guide me to the right people, I am from South Africa. 83. mahesh on 11/17/2011 3:22:13 AM Hi i am looking if it possible to give any packing products to do in home its self i am very interesting to do this type jobs pls u have option give to me i am ready for this. Mahesh - 9845766324 84. thulok on 11/17/2011 10:06:58 AM I want to start making pickles and jam from home in Kathmandu Nepal. 85. nalini on 11/18/2011 1:42:21 AM Hi i&apos;m delhi based homemaker and want to start my own business. I&apos;m good at paintings&amp;love preparing food. What should i start with, pls guide. 86. Shivaram on 11/21/2011 1:48:45 AM I would like to start a business in kerala, and I can market all over kerala as well. I have my own commercial vehicle to distribute the product all over kerala. Advise me what business I can start, or is there any manufacture required a Dealer to market their in Kerala? Shivaram, Calicut, Kerala, India 87. abdul on 11/30/2011 3:03:52 AM Hi i want to start a pickle business in Assam on a commercial basis. what is the process of start the business and where is available in the machines.Please let me know in detail about the business plan and investment required for pickle business. What all licenses are required for manufacturing and trading this product at different locations 88. nageswararao on 11/30/2011 10:20:45 AM i am indian, would like to start a home made pickle business online global wide with different delicious mouth watering verities of veg and non veg items. please let me know how much quantity of sodium benzoate as food preservative which accept all the nations. I am sure, my oath is continuing in charity and will enhance my charity activity with my profits. 89. prity saikia on 12/6/2011 7:46:33 AM we supply world hottest chilli paste, chutney. This chilli placed guineas records for hotness only grows Assam,Nagaland.Anyone want to deal can call 919678838660&amp;mail pritysaikia@yahoo.in 90. MaryLee Salvatore on 12/13/2011 11:45:32 PM I would like to market pickles, french dressing, and barbecue sauce in Pahokee and/or Gainesville, Florida. How do I get started? 91. Mrs. Damayanti M on 1/5/2012 1:07:03 AM HI, I am very much interested in starting a small scale business to support women by proving them with jobs. i want to start pickle, jams&amp;masala. Can anybody help me with the process&amp;rule&amp;regulation of fda&amp;the total minimum investment required for the same. we will be working from mumbai. pls contact me on 9987213367 or email me on damu79@gmail.com 92. Prashanth Acharya on 1/7/2012 2:40:25 AM I am currently in Dubai , I would like to settle in India. Please guide me in starting pickle business in Karnataka. Best Regards, Prashanth 93. rakesh on 1/8/2012 3:16:56 AM i am from dubai, i want to do business in kerala, can u advise me some good ideas. rakeshdxb84@yahoo.com 94. ZAFAR ALI on 1/16/2012 11:13:14 AM I want to start a home based pickle manufacturing business.Can you please give the guidance of manufacturing process,cost required,machines required for packaging and how to sale it in market. 95. m.pushpamala on 1/17/2012 3:17:37 AM we are in vellore.i have plan to start own business to start pickle business. can u give more information about that 96. Naheedparveen on 1/21/2012 5:39:23 AM i am from nashik I am making very testing pickles and many people like it can you help me to find a company that provide me ingredients for pickles and also export my pickle 97. susanta on 1/28/2012 10:48:43 AM who will help me for pickle marketing&amp;storage, where can i found raw material ,pls tell me. 98. Punchok on 1/29/2012 12:06:16 AM I want to produce home made jam in Ladakh for which I need bottle and leveling ,where can I find such supplier in Delhi 99. sahera on 1/29/2012 9:06:50 AM i want to take training in preparation of non-veg pickles. would you please give full information of the training centers. 100. nirmala bhatia on 1/31/2012 12:56:20 AM I am making very testing pickles and many people like it can you help me to find a company that provide me ingredients for pickles .I want to start a home based pickle manufacturing business.Can you please give the guidance of manufacturing process,cost required,machines required for packaging and how to sale it in market. rule&amp;regulation of fda&amp;the total minimum investment required for the same.i want to take training in preparation of veg&amp;non-veg pickles. would you please give full information of the training centers. we will be working from bangalore, karnataka,india also want to export pickle. 101. kunal trived on 2/12/2012 4:44:39 AM I want to do start non veg pickles business in gujarat so i want to know about all machines and legal document .plz give me valuable details 102. vishwanatha.N on 2/15/2012 12:30:03 PM Dear sir: In my native growing lot of mangoes(Srinivaspur), So I am interested to start a small unit of Pickle and Mango juice Factory, Will u please guide me, and How much I need to invest. please guide me soon. 103. Bev Jacob on 2/15/2012 9:54:16 PM Hi. I am a home maker and would like to start a business of making &apos;HOME MADE PICKLES&apos;. I would like to know how to *register non-veg home-made pickle business, and what *sort of licenses has to be obtained to run this business. Please guide me as to what *types of machines are required for packaging. I would like to know what preservatives used in non-veg pickles like fish and beef. 104. akshada pradhan on 2/18/2012 3:52:16 AM i want to start non veg home made pickle manufacturing in Jalgaon. please guide me how i can start this business and what is the requirements for the business. 105. Jakie Lyn G.Sawit on 2/18/2012 7:22:47 AM hi...i want to start home made pickles business. pls.guide me and all the important matter to start a pickle business 106. Thakkar Jayendra K. on 2/20/2012 3:29:05 AM we have complete range in Pickle Masala. We would like to appoint dealer net work for business expansion. Pl. feel free to call on 09879518777 for further action. Regards, Thakkar Jayendra K. 107. leena mahadevia on 2/21/2012 2:17:34 AM want to start a home based pickle/pizza puree etc food business. need to know the scope and how to start. it will be small and premium product. thanks pls advise. 108. mohan banstola on 2/21/2012 10:59:04 PM hi Anil Thomas&amp;Jaba Mukherjee, pl contact me i will help to sale of pickle mohanbchs@yahoo.co.in 109. SANTOSH KUMAR on 2/24/2012 1:46:13 AM Sir, I want to start small pickle business in Delhi, kindly give me suggestions and if there any legal formalities to be completed. Also give me the preservatives to be used to increase the shelf life of the pickles. Please give me your advise. Santosh Kumar 110. vijaya on 2/29/2012 12:59:37 PM i want to start my own pickle business at hyderabad. kindly help me. 111. Arun on 3/2/2012 5:16:57 AM Hi every one.. i am in india, i can do online business from worldwide. if any one wants to market their own products from place to place you can contact us...arun2448@gmail.com 112. Shoopy on 3/6/2012 9:29:11 PM Hello, I&apos;m from canada and would like to start my own dog food mass production company...can i do this from home?? on evenings and weekends?? do i need a kitchen or cook out back over a fire cause its just for dogs right? I have a full time job but am looking for some extra cash...thanks for your help! 113. padma on 3/13/2012 2:16:00 PM i want to start my own south indian pickle business in nagpur please help me 114. praveen on 3/16/2012 10:37:56 AM i know making banana jam jack fruit, vegetable jam strawberry jam apple jam and non veg fish pickle and mutton pickle halal product kindly help how much need for setup a business for export purpose only like know thank regards, praveen 115. laskhmi on 3/26/2012 9:24:56 AM i want to know if sodium benozate available in Dubai for retail for food preservative 116. Mehroo Billimoria on 4/6/2012 5:41:37 AM I am a good typist. I have computer at home. So, I would like to go for typing work at home. How to get business at home. Please suggest some ideas. Thanks Mehroo 117. santhoshi on 4/23/2012 2:26:51 AM sir i am hydrabad i want start a small business of tomato sauce. how to get equipments and how to get business at home please suggest some ideas. Thank you sir 118. Salai ramasamy on 4/23/2012 3:56:30 PM I am from chennai. I own a webstore that includes homemade pickles and grounded masalas. Do i need any kind of government certifications to sell the products to the foreign customers? My mail id: gongurapickle@gmail.com 119. sai lakshmi on 5/15/2012 2:50:10 AM sir, i want to send our home made pickle to our relatives 
staying in America please give the correct procedure to send without spoilage and give the correct address of exporters thank you 120. Sunita on 5/18/2012 12:40:58 AM I have presently 2000kg of garlic in cold storage but at this point some of it is getting discolored, i would like to chop and bottle this for sale in the supermarket, but i don&apos;t know the measurement of the citric acid and sodium benozate to be used for the preparation of 1 kg. Can u help...........? Sunita 121. Sam on 6/3/2012 10:21:08 AM Hi, i want to start a pickle business. We produce oil free pickle. I already have around 20 000 prepared bottles of pickles. I want to find a market in europe. Any idea how to start? 122. M.RADHAKRISHNARAJU on 6/5/2012 2:03:24 AM Sir, I would like to start the veg&amp;non-veg. pickles business.
Please give me the guide lines to start the business and suggest me the marketing sources. Thanking you, M.RADHAKRISHNAAJU 123. Vish Kroutz on 6/9/2012 6:30:42 AM I would like to start my pickle business in Brisbane, Queensland Australia. My focus is organic mixed vegetables and lemon pickles. I would like information on how to reach overseas markets-either Europe or Dubai. Many thanks Vish 124. mrs. satya on 6/12/2012 11:36:36 PM ours is an rehabilitation unit for the physically challenged ladies. recently we have started to sell home made ready to eat item. now i want to keep them in the hyper markets for sale. do i need any type of certificate? how to i get it? 125. Cannon on 6/25/2012 3:11:38 PM I am in Neptune Beach, Florida USA. I would like to know what licenses that I need to start selling my pickles. Do I need FDA approval? How do I go about the labeling and bottling my pickles to sell to stores and sandwich shops in Florida? Right now I am making and selling them from my home. Any advice would really be helpful, thanks. 126. NEENA H SINGH on 7/3/2012 12:51:44 PM i am living in Punjab ( India) very close to Chandigarh. I would like advice on how to start selling pickles from home. What permissions do I need ? Also advise on bottling- labeling and preserving the shelf life of my product. Give me all the helpful hints. 127. Priya J on 7/4/2012 8:37:09 AM Hi I want to start a catering/ or food stall or corporate houses in kolkata (india) in salt lake area. Please advise how to go about with the plan. Thanks Priya 128. Jyoti Prabhat Duarah on 7/11/2012 9:52:10 AM I need a project report on small scale fish pickle processing unit 129. sapanasubba on 7/12/2012 2:41:44 AM dear sir/madam,
i aslo want to start this kind of small business but i want to know that what will be the term and condition? how can i export out of nepal? what should i have to do with the government? how can i build up the relation with the customers? etc...in fact i really don&apos;t know about all this..m totally blank..can u answer me? 
 Name: 
 Email: 
 Comment: 
 Write your business location to help you better. Exp: City, State, Country 
 ( All the above fields are required. ) 
 

 Sign up for Newsletter 
Restaurant Business

 How to Start an Indian Restaurant Business Juice and Smoothie Bar Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant Starting a Hostel Business Startup Sushi Restaurant 

Mobile Business Ideas

 How to Start Mobile Catering How to Start Your Own Charter Fishing Business How to Start a Mobile Spa Business Mobile Detailing Business Startup Kit How to Start Mobile Notary Business 

Farming Business Ideas

 How to Start a Poultry Farm Starting Chicken Farm Business Starting a Dairy Farm Business How to Start a Fish Farming Business Start a Rabbit Farm 

Service Business Ideas

 Starting a Recruitment Agency How to Start a Courier Business Starting Your Own Money Lending Business Starting Your Own Guest House Business Starting Your Own Computer Training Center 
 
 Advice for Small Business Business Insurance Information Business Marketing and Advertising Entrepreneur Business Idea Farming Business Ideas Financing a Small Business Free Business Ideas Home Based Business Opportunity 
 Work at Home Business Ideas 
 Ideas for Small Business Instructor Guides Internet Business Ideas Professional Career Opportunities Repair Business Opportunity Restaurant Business Opportunities Retail Store Ideas Rural Business Opportunities Service Business Ideas Shop Business Ideas Small Business Articles Small Business Opportunities Small Manufacturing Business Starting Rental Business Startup Company Ideas Store Business Opportunities Tips for Buying and Selling Unique Business Opportunities Wholesale Business Opportunities 

Small Business Ideas

 How to Start a Towing Business How to Start a Trucking Business Starting a Taxi Business How to Start a Movie Theater How to Start a Shoe Business 

Small Business Articles

 How to Start a Gas Station How Much Does it Cost to Charter a Private Jet Starting a Night Club How Do You Calculate The Mark Up Price 

Home Based Business

 Starting a Home Health Agency How to Start a Home Baking Business Starting a Funeral Home Business Ideas for Home Based Business Starting a Woodworking Business 

Shop Business Ideas

 Starting a Pawn Shop Business How to Start a Meat Shop How to Start a Donut Shop How to Open a Sandwich Shop How to Start Auto Body Shop 

Store Business Opportunities

 Starting a Grocery Store Business Starting a Fashion Clothing Store How to Open a Liquor Store How to Start a Beauty Supply Store How to Start a Drug Store Business 

Startup Company Ideas

 How to Start a Tour Company How to Start a Security Company Start a Cosmetics Company How to Start a Skateboard Company Starting Your Own Repossession Company 
 Copyright©2007 - 2012 StartupBizHub.com. All Rights Reserved.
 About Us | Privacy | Contact Us 
 Site Map
	</body>
</document>
