<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003213" url="http://www.yelp.com/topic/chicago-my-cup-is-made-of-corn" time="2012-07-12-19:20" support="1" score="0.0009788074112139608" bingtitle="My Cup is Made of Corn ... | Chicago | Yelp" webtitle="My Cup is Made of Corn ... | Chicago | Yelp">
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>It&apos;s a plastic cup and I was eating some ice from it and read the side: This cup is made ... some fast food restaurant i was at had corn silverware. it was kinda cool, it ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk Events 

 Member Search 
   
Talk Chicago

 New York San Jose Los Angeles Chicago Palo Alto Oakland More Cities» 
 Search New Conversation 
 All Conversations A moment ago Local Questions&amp;Answers 24 minutes ago Events 20 hours ago Food 22 hours ago Shopping&amp;Products 33 minutes ago Travel 5 hours ago Relationships&amp;Dating 7/8/2012 Humor&amp;Offbeat 44 minutes ago Entertainment&amp;Pop Culture 2 hours ago Sports 50 minutes ago News&amp;Politics 7 minutes ago Family&amp;Parenting 18 hours ago Yelper Shout-Outs 7/10/2012 Site Questions&amp;Updates 15 hours ago Other A moment ago 

Recent Conversations

 You can keep your hair (sort of) but you&apos;ll never want sex again 
 A moment ago Dirt on Romney 
 7 minutes ago Weight loss 
 24 minutes ago Dollar Shave Club? 
 33 minutes ago 50 Shades of Grey 
 38 minutes ago Ultimate Stripper Playlist 
 44 minutes ago Dry Ice Shipping 
 44 minutes ago Bored this weekend, come watch some sailing. 
 50 minutes ago How to handle bad business? 
 One hour ago Doggies and parks near Willowbrook 
 One hour ago bye bye! Roll Your Own cigarette stores 
 One hour ago Taste of chicago 
 2 hours ago Music streaming services 
 2 hours ago Where the %$#@&amp;is Jesse Jackson Jr.? 
 2 hours ago Keep one - Drop one, part deux 
 2 hours ago Stupid labels.  WTF. 
 2 hours ago I&apos;m comin&apos; to CHICAGO&amp;this chick is HUNGRY! Top 5 MUST EATS?! 
 3 hours ago What are you listening to right now? 
 3 hours ago Where Do You Buy K Cups? 
 4 hours ago New York City in September 
 5 hours ago See All Conversations 
 
My Cup is Made of Corn ...

Category: Other 
 Page Bottom↓ Get email updates about this conversation 
 Elite &apos;12 212 friends 274 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Chaviva &quot;Dietarily Challenged&quot; G. says:
Seriously. It&apos;s a plastic cup and I was eating some ice from it and read the side:

This cup is made from corn,
environmentally sustainable,
and 100% compostable.
Greenware

This reminds me of course of an article I read in UTNE (I think it was UTNE) the other day about how CORN is the reason America is fat. Corn syrup, etc. etc. That corn is what has made America bad.

Discuss.
 
 
 542 friends 1019 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Carolynne M. says:
Well, if you gain weight in the near future, you can blame the cup.
 1/15/2008 Deanna M. says:
Corn plastic is totally awesome.  Though it takes forever to compost.
 
 31 friends 92 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Barry J. says:
corn nuts are awesome. You could carve a shot glass out of that pozole sized kernel.
 1/15/2008 brennan s. says:
You can make plastics out of corn and soy instead of petroleum.

The UTNE article was probably about High Fructose Corn Syrup.  Uh oh, flag?  j/k

A few facts about HFCS

1) It&apos;s price is artificial.  The US government through US Dept of Agriculture price supports helps
to keep the street price of HFCS below that of sugar.  This is marketed as a way to keep &quot;American farming competitive&quot;.  It&apos;s really about making corn more abundant in the United States because it is easier to grow, more difficult to spoil, and can be refined in as many products as petroleum.
2) HFCS, in excessive or regular quantities, is problematic for the long term health of the individual.  Sugar is better for the body.  HFCS is a cheap substitute sweetener used instead of sugar.  Almost every food product you can buy has some sort of sweetening agent in it.
3) Corn prices trade higher and higher almost every day because the market rush is on.  Many speculators think corn is the best crop that will emerge as the renewable replacement resource for petroleum.
 
 Elite &apos;12 288 friends 841 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Dane K. says:
some fast food restaurant i was at had corn silverware. it was kinda cool, it felt like really really high density foam kinda... you could bend it if you really wanted to, but otherwise it was rigid.

i *think* it was at the very unexciting Maui Tacos in maui. hrm.
 
 Elite &apos;12 168 friends 161 reviews 
 1/15/2008 George R. says:
The book &quot;The Omnivore&apos;s Dilemma&quot; tells extensively about corn production in this country and its overabundance... partially fueled by government subsidies. It notes that corn is everywhere and is in everything we eat in some form or another.
 
 31 friends 92 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Barry J. says:
what&apos;s weird is when it&apos;s undigested in your stool. what&apos;s up with that.
 
 Elite &apos;12 373 friends 553 reviews 
 1/15/2008 John &quot;Lighten Up, Francis&quot; B. says:
&quot;The Omnivore&apos;s Dilemma&quot; made me want to blow my head off with an ear of corn. The first section is about how all of us -- including (especially?) the farmers who grow it -- have been screwed by the government, agribusiness, and (oddly) the military over corn. I knew some of this, but dag.
 
 31 friends 92 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Barry J. says:
so omnivores can actually eat other omnivores, right? Is that the dilemma?
 
 Elite &apos;12 373 friends 553 reviews 
 1/15/2008 John &quot;Lighten Up, Francis&quot; B. says:
Decisions, decisions. Human flesh or stovetop stuffing.
 
 Elite &apos;12 219 friends 509 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Rocky &quot;youtube.com/rockybarragan&quot; B. says:
Rich sells moldable shoe inserts on the side...well the packages that the inserts come in are made of corn. I keep asking him if we could put in the microwave and make popcorn...I just get a look. :|
 1/15/2008 

This Yelper&apos;s account has been closed.
 
 98 friends 191 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Linda &quot;Fluorescent Adolescent&quot; P. says:
I&apos;m hungry for some corn right now.  I do have some Jays Corn Puffs so I&apos;ll go eat that right now :P.
 1/15/2008 

This Yelper&apos;s account has been closed.
 
 487 friends 12 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Astronomer Joe &quot;&quot;Father of the modern day Apocolypse&amp;Pie&quot;&quot; G. says:
At the Adler, we were presented with Adler cups made from corn.

One of our astronomers washed his in his dishwasher....melted into a heap.

Store that in your corn hole.

Welcoming our Corn Loving Overlords Joe
 
 412 friends 463 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Amaliya &quot;Hate the deed, not the breed&quot; L. says:
My Mil is allergic to corn, so she can&apos;t even eat canned goods because the linings are made out of corn.
 
 98 friends 191 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Linda &quot;Fluorescent Adolescent&quot; P. says:
But Daniel!  I must...have...corn!!!
 
 169 friends 164 reviews 
 1/15/2008 Sam &quot;I always bump my own threads&quot; K. says:
hfcs isn&apos;t so bad . . .

 http://www.nytimes.com/2… 
 
 98 friends 191 reviews 
 1/16/2008 Linda &quot;Fluorescent Adolescent&quot; P. says:
This thread is corn-y!

OK...Someone had to say it.
 1/16/2008 Lara S. says:
John, I have been trying to get through &quot;The Omnivore&apos;s Dilemma&quot; for about two months now!  I&apos;m just starting the foraging part.  Anyway, I hated the corn part... over-detailed&amp;over-whelming, which just made me apathetic.  Sigh.
I loved the Polyface Farms part though, and would love to visit the happy poop-pickin&apos; chickens someday though!
 1/16/2008 Deanna M. says:
I&apos;m not an omnivore, but that sounds like a really good book.  I&apos;ll have to add it to my to-read list...
 
 Elite &apos;12 288 friends 841 reviews 
 1/16/2008 Dane K. says:
it&apos;s been sitting on my bookshelf ready to read for a year now i think... maybe one day!

brian&apos;s cousin and husband lent it to us.  they both can talk for 4 hours solid about the book, and the problems w/ corn subsidies in america...
 1/16/2008 Andy F. says:
i love corn
 
 81 friends 120 reviews 
 1/16/2008 Robert &quot;token Canadian&quot; F. says:
I had no idea plastics could be made from corn and soy.  My immediate question is, how much corn/soy does it take compared to petroleum.  If they can&apos;t get algae or switchgrass ethanol nailed down before crushing oil price spikes, we may be picking between fuel or food when you consider how corn is involved in damn near everything we eat.
 
 Elite &apos;12 288 friends 841 reviews 
 1/16/2008 Dane K. says:
well that&apos;s one of the issues, which it seems you&apos;re hitting the nail on the head w/ your other comments. :)

many things can be made from corn, but it&apos;s inefficient.  the only reason it&apos;s done though is because farmers get corn subsidies that make it cost efficient for them to do so, so basically the government is paying for an inefficient process. and ethanol is the same way, ethanol is a good idea but compared to other crops really inefficient and it&apos;s not a winning proposition in the long term.  ...also at the expense of the government paying for these things, many other things are effected as well.  corn prices have gone up, which in turn has raised meat prices drastically....

one good outcome to the whole corn issue is HFCS prices... they&apos;re going up.  and now people are looking for alternatives to it, which of course was a cheap alternative to sugar ... maybe real sugar products will make a comeback, who knows
 
 Get email updates about this conversation 
 Flag conversation as inappropriate 
 
 Page Top↑ 

 This conversation is older than 2 months and has been closed to new posts. 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Chicago Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
