<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003658" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/359695" time="2012-07-12-19:49" support="1" score="0.0006276322331448298" bingtitle="Of all the fast-food chains ... who makes the best ice cream ..." webtitle="Of all the fast-food chains ... who makes the best ice cream shakes? - Chains - Chowhound">
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Coco&apos;s, Bob&apos;s Big Boy...While chain (sit down...order...wait for food...dine in ... This is in the Jack in the Box shake mix: Ice Cream Milk, Cream, Sucrose, Skim Milk ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; Chains Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
Of all the fast-food chains ... who makes the best ice cream shakes?
 
My gold star goes to Carl&apos;s Jr.

I crave their Vanilla Shake even when it&apos;s a chilly 45 degrees outside, but lately I&apos;ve warmed up to their mint chip.

Be warned, however, the strawberry is sort, um, how do I put this, ahem, um ... the strawberry is disgusting.

Do you have a favorite?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Jan 12, 2007 06:04 PM 
Updated on Nov 15, 2011

 108 Replies 
 
 
Coco&apos;s
Bobs Big Boy
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By calabasas_trafalgar on Jan 12, 2007 07:29 PM 
 re: calabasas_trafalgar 
Coco&apos;s, Bob&apos;s Big Boy...While chain (sit down...order...wait for food...dine in) restaurants, I don&apos;t think these are considered as &apos;fast food chains&apos;.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By crt on Dec 26, 2007 05:34 AM 

 
 
Burgerville (seasonal shakes)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By amopdx on Jan 12, 2007 07:30 PM 
 re: amopdx 
..and it isn&apos;t EVEN CLOSE!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Xericx on Jan 15, 2007 12:52 AM 

 re: amopdx 
Totally agree.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By bards4 on Nov 10, 2011 10:03 AM 

 
 
Dairy Queen brazier or Steak and Shake.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Kelli2006 on Jan 12, 2007 11:25 PM 

 
steak&amp;shake. No contest.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By revsharkie on Jan 13, 2007 01:08 AM 
 re: revsharkie 
Agreed. Steak&amp;Shake
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By theflytyr on Jan 13, 2007 02:24 AM 
 re: theflytyr 
Chalk up another Steak and Shake. My son was a&quot;shake guy&quot;for them and they definitely use real ice cream.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By coney with everything on Sep 14, 2007 05:38 AM 
 re: coney with everything 
Yup. But DQ is a close second.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Pylon on Sep 15, 2007 04:53 AM 

 
 
 
 
Chick-Fil-A, Cheeburger Cheeburger
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Janet from Richmond on Jan 13, 2007 12:25 PM 
 re: Janet from Richmond 
Cheeburger for sure - and they make malteds, which nobody else seems to do, and which I prefer.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By sivyaleah on Jan 13, 2007 02:59 PM 
 re: sivyaleah 
You can get malts at steak&amp;shake. I do every time.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By revsharkie on Jan 13, 2007 08:05 PM 
 re: revsharkie 
I live in the Northeast, there are none of them in this area, or NJ or NY anyway. I&apos;ve never even heard of it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By sivyaleah on Jan 13, 2007 11:50 PM 
 re: sivyaleah 
try Friendly&apos;s Fribble with whipped cream.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By othervoice on Jan 24, 2007 10:38 AM 
 re: othervoice 
I miss friendly&apos;s! they are the best.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By SRosie on Jan 27, 2007 04:05 PM 


 
 re: revsharkie 
Steak&amp;Shake is a Midwestern thing -- none at all on the East Coast.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Das Ubergeek on Jan 14, 2007 01:57 PM 
 re: Das Ubergeek 
that&apos;s unfortunate. (The nearest one to us here is about five hours away. We only get there a couple or three times a year.)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By revsharkie on Jan 14, 2007 06:29 PM 

 re: Das Ubergeek 
They have them in the South, too.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By alliebear on Jan 14, 2007 09:48 PM 

 re: Das Ubergeek 
I live in Miami and we have Steak&amp;Shake. They also have them in Tampa.
Love their white chocolate shake (seasonal).
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By lov2trav on Jan 24, 2007 10:25 AM 

 re: Das Ubergeek 
Actually - I was in Florida in March&amp;they&apos;re there; however, I didn&apos;t feature it....
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By JayVaBeach on Sep 13, 2007 05:39 PM 

 re: Das Ubergeek 
Not exactly true...we live on the East Coast of Central Florida&amp;have one here.

Agree that they make the best chain shake. My favorite is the Dark Chocolate.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By cavandre on Sep 26, 2007 09:24 AM 

 
 
 
 re: Janet from Richmond 
Technically, Chick-Fil-A shakes aren&apos;t ice cream shakes. From their web site (and yes, it&apos;s iceDream, not ice cream):

Icedream (whole milk, sugar, nonfat dry milk, cream, corn syrup, natural and artificial flavors [artificial compounds, vanilla flavoring], dried whole eggs, cornstarch, mono and diglycerides [from soybean oil], disodium phosphate, cellulose gum, carrageenan, sodium phosphate, guar gum, sodium citrate, annatto and caramel colors, artificial color [Yellow 5&amp;6]), milkshake base (whole milk, sugar, cream, whey powder (milk), nonfat dry milk, artificial flavor, disodium phosphate, mono and diglycerides [from soybean oil], tetrasodium pyrophosphate, guar gum, cellulose gum, carrageenan),
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Loren3 on Jan 16, 2007 03:18 PM 

 re: Janet from Richmond 
I will second Cheeburger Cheeburger simply because you can request any kind of shake under the sun. I&apos;ve had a chocolate cherry cheesecake shake that was amazing.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By CurlieGlamourGirlie on Nov 15, 2011 09:23 AM 

 
 
Those Carl&apos;s Jr.&quot;Hand-Scooped&quot;things? They scoop them and put them in cups, then leave the cups, uncovered, in the freezer. It can be a couple of days before they&apos;ll get used. Just so you know.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Das Ubergeek on Jan 13, 2007 12:41 PM 

 
I used to absolutely love the chocolate shakes from Rax Roast Beef but they long ago closed in this area. Do they still exist at all?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Velma on Jan 13, 2007 02:17 PM 
 re: Velma 
I used to like Rax too there closed here in Washington too.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By billjriv on Jan 18, 2007 07:55 PM 
 re: billjriv 
Missouri too. Haven&apos;t thought about them in a while. Now I&apos;ll be sad all day. :P
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Pylon on Sep 15, 2007 04:51 AM 

 
 re: Velma 
I loved the Rax jamoca shake. They are gone from Florida I believe. Arby&apos;s has a good jamocha as well. But Steak and Shake is my favorite.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By juli5122 on Nov 10, 2011 10:11 AM 

 
 
The Jamocha shake at Arbys is delicious.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By swissgirl on Jan 13, 2007 06:59 PM 

 
From my childhood, McD&apos;s special Shamrock shake (mint) that they would only have during the month of March. I don&apos;t think they do it anymore, but boy did I love those things growing up.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Jacey on Jan 14, 2007 12:28 AM 
 re: Jacey 
Yum! Shamrock Shakes were my favorite! I wonder if they did retire them...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sra. Swanky on Jan 14, 2007 03:12 PM 
 re: Sra. Swanky 
Not as of last year. I think they brought them back out of demand.

The shamrock shake is the only shake I like at McDonald&apos;s. Their shakes otherwise seem too gluey to me.

Out of the big boys, I like Jack in the Box best with Burger King next.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Jan 15, 2007 04:32 PM 
 re: rworange 
Thanks, orange - good to know. They don&apos;t really have anything posted that advertises the Shamrock Shake - I&apos;ll remember to ask for it in March now that I know they didn&apos;t put it in the&quot;flavor graveyard!&quot;
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sra. Swanky on Jan 19, 2007 09:50 PM 

 
 
 re: Jacey 
Ask them to mix half shamrock w/half chocolate. It&apos;s like drinking a Grasshopper cookie. Mm.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By nicoleberry83 on Jan 19, 2007 07:12 PM 
 re: nicoleberry83 
Now THAT sounds like a shake!! Thanks, nicoleberry - I gotta try it!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sra. Swanky on Jan 19, 2007 09:52 PM 

 
 
 
Vanilla shake at Whataburger. Thick and creamy
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Pampatz on Jan 14, 2007 08:27 PM 

 
Is In&apos;n Out an Ice Cream shake?

Love their chocolate....
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By jbyoga on Jan 14, 2007 08:32 PM 
 re: jbyoga 
Had one yesterday, I&apos;d have to agree.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By SRosie on Jan 27, 2007 04:06 PM 

 
 
The now defunct gelateria i worked at in grad school. but I guess that doesn&apos;t count.

Braum&apos;s. I don&apos;t know how popular they are outside of texas, but they make great ice cream, then mix whatever flavor you want into a shake. Malted available. Plus they have the best available dairy in a mini-store. No one ever believes their skim is actually skim.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By amkirkland on Jan 14, 2007 10:07 PM 
 re: amkirkland 
Braum&apos;s home base is in Oklahoma, maybe Tulsa. They&apos;re awful good. Haven&apos;t made it to Iowa yet. My folks buy all their milk&amp;eggs there.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By revsharkie on Jan 15, 2007 02:05 AM 
 re: revsharkie 
I miss them from my years in Texas and they have made it to Southern Missouri so they just need to come two hundred miles north!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Velma on Jan 15, 2007 02:11 AM 

 re: revsharkie 
They are actually based in Oklahoma City, and, yes, they do make the best shakes. They make the best a lot of things. Too bad there aren&apos;t more of them around. Braum&apos;s is one of those places I visit any time I go back home to Oklahoma.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Velvet Elvis on Sep 13, 2007 07:18 PM 

 
 
 
I&apos;d second Bob&apos;s Big Boy, but I&apos;ve never seen one outside of SoCal (there were a couple in the SF bay area, but they closed). In-n-Out has pretty good shakes, but sadly remains tethered to CA. It&apos;s not *quite* fast food, but here in FL I&apos;d recommend Steak&amp;Shake.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By aynrandgirl on Jan 15, 2007 03:05 AM 

 
Chick-Fil-A recently started doing shakes...I LOVE the oreo:)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By lbmsw on Jan 15, 2007 02:44 PM 

 
I like steak and shake.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By swsidejim on Jan 15, 2007 04:37 PM 

 
Steak and Shake, and Sonic. Sonic&apos;s Cream Pie shakes were a pregnancy staple for me. :-P
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Covert Ops on Jan 15, 2007 05:16 PM 

 
I&apos;m witht he burgerville they have a pumkin shake that will nock your socks off even in the winter.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By mlukewow on Jan 15, 2007 05:20 PM 

 
Hands down (and I&apos;m shocked no one has mentioned this yet): Jack in the Box Oreo Cookie shake. OMG...AMAZING!!! I&apos;m not even a huge shake fan and this just blows me away. Thick, creamy and just the right ratio of ice cream to cookie.

As a side note, I was really excited to try Carl Jr.&apos;s&quot;hand scooped shakes.&quot;What a disappointment. So watery and icey tasting.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Newkie on Jan 16, 2007 03:46 AM 
 re: Newkie 
This is in the Jack in the Box shake mix:
Ice Cream Milk, Cream, Sucrose, Skim Milk, Corn Syrup, Whey, Stabilizer (Sodium Caseinate, Cellulose Gum, Mono and Diglycerides, Disodium Phosphate, Soy Protein Concentrate, Carrageenan, Guar Gum, Sodium Citrate, Polysorbate 65, Dextrose), Natural and Artificial Vanilla, Annatto Extract (color). Contains Milk, Soy
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Loren3 on Jan 16, 2007 03:20 PM 
 re: Loren3 
Chick-fil-A all the way. Loren, you should change your handle to Debbie Downer.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Oh Robin on Sep 14, 2007 04:34 PM 

 re: Loren3 
I don&apos;t care what is in them - Jack In The Box has the best shakes. I don&apos;t have much of a sweet tooth, but when my DH gets one from there I practically wrestle him for it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By danhole on Sep 30, 2007 12:08 PM 

 
 
 
Mel&apos;s, partly because it&apos;s hard to find a blackberry shake anywhere, and they make a good one.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Pei on Jan 16, 2007 07:21 AM 

 
burgerville. right now its chocolate hazlenut. most of the shakes are seasonal, made from local ingredients. very very very very good:) IMPO
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By shanda013 on Jan 18, 2007 10:51 PM 

 
Shamrock shake, Every march.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By chezlamere on Jan 18, 2007 10:54 PM 

 
While this is not a&quot;fast food&quot;chain, it is a chain of ice cream stores ... Handel&apos;s Homemade Ice Cream&amp;Yogurt ( www.handelsicecream.com ).

Handel&apos;s was named in the top 10 best ice creams in the world in a book from National Geographic that ranked a wide range of things. I concur.

Everything they do with their ice cream, including their shakes, is incredible.

- - -

Patrick
Your Basic Food Groupie
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By basicfoodgroupie on Jan 19, 2007 09:54 PM 

 
I&apos;m a malt gal mostly (extra malt, please) and when possible, I like butterscotch malts (extra malt, please) but I do drink other kinds of malts from time to time and even shakes.

My latest favorite is Culver&apos;s. Yum!
Based in WI with shops in WI, MI, ND, SD, MN, IL, IA, MO, TX, CO, NE, WY, KY, TN, OH, KS

Also like:

Steak &apos;n Shake
Based in Indianapolis with shops in IN, OH, PA, MI, KY, TN, NC, SC, AL, GA, FL, MS, AR, OK, TX, KS, MO, IL, IA

Sonic (but not all Sonics are equal, not by any means!)
I like their malts/shakes less than Culver&apos;s and Steak &apos;n Shake but given my choice, I&apos;d much rather have Sonic&apos;s fruit smoothies than their malts or shakes.
Based in Oklahoma City with shops pretty much across the USA

Arctic Circle
I never miss one when traveling to Idaho every year or so. Fabulous seasonal concoctions including amazing egg nog and pumpkin versions.
Based in UT with shops in UT, ID, WY, MT, NE, OR, WA, CA

Here in Kansas City, I used to love malts and shakes from the mini-chain Winstead&apos;s but they&apos;ve not been good now for probably a dozen years or so. Just rank was&quot;quite ordinary or below&quot;since then.

I&apos;d love to find a great source for blackberry shakes/malts in my area or where I travel! Had a few way back when and loved &apos;em.

.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By KCJ on Jan 21, 2007 06:05 PM 
 re: KCJ 
&quot;Arctic Circle
I never miss one when traveling to Idaho every year or so. Fabulous seasonal concoctions including amazing egg nog and pumpkin versions.
Based in UT with shops in UT, ID, WY, MT, NE, OR, WA, CA&quot;

i love their fry sauce they&apos;re only in rural areas/small towns. When i visit my bf&apos;s family in&quot;smalltown&quot;, OR i always stop by the artic circle and pick up a jar of the fry sauce.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By amopdx on Jan 22, 2007 09:43 PM 
 re: amopdx 
Yes, I like Arctic Circle&apos;s Fry Sauce, too, but I find Fry Sauce to be pretty common all over Idaho. Don&apos;t know about other states in that region.

For those who don&apos;t know, Fry Sauce is basically a mayo and ketchup blend for dipping -- what else? -- your french fries! Very tasty and addicting, too. :)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By KCJ on Jan 23, 2007 02:16 AM 

 
 re: KCJ 
&quot;Sonic (but not all Sonics are equal, not by any means!)
I like their malts/shakes less than Culver&apos;s and Steak &apos;n Shake but given my choice, I&apos;d much rather have Sonic&apos;s fruit smoothies than their malts or shakes.
Based in Oklahoma City with shops pretty much across the USA&quot;

The northeast needs Sonic! They torture us with their commercials, but the closest one to NYC is about 70 miles, and there are none further north than the Jersey shore. *crying*
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By irishnyc on Dec 26, 2007 08:37 AM 

 
 
Not sure if this qualifies as &apos;fast food&apos; because you do sit down and food is brought to you, but I love the shakes at Red Robin!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By gingerbread girl on Jan 21, 2007 09:04 PM 

 
Interesting OP. The question pre-suppopses that all of you have tried the shakes in a respectable number or sample of fast food chains.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sam Fujisaka on Jan 23, 2007 03:42 AM 
 re: Sam Fujisaka 
Perhaps the title is a bit misleading, but I really did not intend the original post to presume (or require) sometime to have tried ALL shakes, or even a representative sample of such things.

Just sort of curious of the places that people have tried, which ones they like best ...

Although if someone has tried the shakes at ALL fast-food joints, do please speak up! :-)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Jan 23, 2007 11:20 AM 
 re: ipsedixit 
I&apos;m kinda partial to Fuddrucker&apos;s right now.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By calabasas_trafalgar on Oct 5, 2007 03:33 PM 

 
 
 
Jack in the Box!!!
their seasonal shakes- pumpkin pie esp are great- thick and creamy!!!

isn&apos;t anyone else answering from the WEST coast?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By msmd310 on Jan 23, 2007 08:15 PM 
 re: msmd310 
I was just in San Diego for the first time and loved the blackberry shake at Jack in the Box! They were great, I wished I had the time to try the Oreo one. I loved IN N OUT Burger but thought their shakes were too thick!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By callitasicit on Sep 15, 2007 09:41 PM 
 re: callitasicit 
the Blackberry shakes at JITB are the best! I&apos;m sure they&apos;re going to go away soon an be replaced by the pumpkin and then the egg nog(also delish!) as they were originally advertised as a seasonal flavor when they first came out at the beginning of summer. I don&apos;t indulge in these often and can&apos;t finish a whole one but darn...are they are a tasty treat!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ziggylu on Sep 16, 2007 07:34 PM 

 
 
 
That&apos;s easy - nothing beats a lickshake at Lick&apos;s!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By spades on Jan 23, 2007 08:22 PM 
 re: spades 
Licks in my opinion is average at best.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By callitasicit on Sep 15, 2007 09:42 PM 

 
 
Not exactly fast food (more like a &apos;50s diner), but the milkshakes at the Johnny Rocket&apos;s chain here in Los Angeles are truly outstanding. Seriously, I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve had a better shake in town.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Arthur on Jan 27, 2007 03:48 PM 

 
Culver&apos;s in the midwest - they use Frozen Custard - it is to die for -
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By weinstein5 on Jan 28, 2007 03:03 AM 
 re: weinstein5 
I second Culver&apos;s. Delicious. Sorry I can&apos;t say the same for the rest of their food...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By optimal forager on Sep 16, 2007 03:06 PM 

 
 
there is a chain here in NC called cookout that makes the best shakes. love there caramel cheesecake milkshake. pretty much every single one i tried has always been great.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By vttp926 on Sep 13, 2007 06:20 PM 
 re: vttp926 
I was just thinking about a cookout milkshake! The line is always insane, cars backed up everywhere in line for a burger and shake. So good, so many flavors! In the summer, July-August I think it is, they have a watermelon milkshake that is awesome. It doesn&apos;t get too watery, which I was worried about, and it has real watermelon pieces in it! Worth trying if you are in North Carolina and a shake lover!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By B_Moody on Nov 4, 2011 01:51 PM 
 re: B_Moody 
There is now a Cookout in RIchmond, VA and the shakes are fabulous.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Janet from Richmond on Nov 4, 2011 01:59 PM 

 
 
 
Chik-fil-a. Without question.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By runningwithtweezers on Sep 13, 2007 07:23 PM 

 
I&apos;m with ipsedixit when it comes to the shakes at Carl&apos;s.

My fave is the orange creamsicle job, though mint chip is quite fine.

I never have strawberry shakes, and hardly do strawberry anything, so no disgust factor for me.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By GroovinGourmet on Sep 14, 2007 05:55 AM 
 re: GroovinGourmet 
Burgerville, within 70 mile radius of Portland:
Seasonal shakes - blackberry, hazelnut, strawberry, pumpkin - all locally sourced, as are many of their other items!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Leonardo on Sep 15, 2007 10:05 PM 

 
 
Just a mention of two other possiblities, which are decent enough.

Wendy&apos;s for their Chocolate Frosty, which may or may not be considered to technically be an ice cream shake, but is subjectively tasty.

El Pollo Loco/Foster&apos;s Freeze for their shakes and malts.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By PommeDeGuerre on Sep 16, 2007 02:46 PM 
 re: PommeDeGuerre 
My favorite chain&quot;shake&quot;(though like you, I&apos;m not sure it counts!) is Wendy&apos;s frosty too.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ForFoodsSake on Nov 5, 2011 08:02 AM 
 re: ForFoodsSake 
Yeah, I like the chocolate frosty too. Don&apos;t like the vanilla.

Wendy&apos;s is now doing shakes. The summer berry shake was very good. The fall caramel was ok, but a bit too sweet for me.

Currently Sonic is making a really, really good pumpkin shake. It is super thick. The whipped cream is thick. A nice addition is a sprinkling of pumpkin crust crumbs on top of the whipped cream.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Nov 5, 2011 12:40 PM 

 
 
 
I&apos;m a little surprised by this, but my favorite is McDonald&apos;s. I love the chocolate, and DH loves the eggnog one in December. Chick-fil-a and Steak&amp;Shake are bland by comparison, even the mint choc at CFA is bland to me. Second favorite is Arby&apos;s mocha shake.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By starbucksbrew on Sep 17, 2007 02:42 PM 

 
Lic&apos;s Banana Shake. Yum.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ArikaDawn on Sep 18, 2007 01:16 PM 
 re: ArikaDawn 
Okay the only LIc&apos;s I have ever seen is i Vincennes, IN...where did you find one?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By pickychicky1979 on Sep 18, 2007 06:12 PM 
 re: pickychicky1979 
There are 3 in Evansville, IN where I grew up.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ArikaDawn on Sep 19, 2007 04:08 AM 
 re: ArikaDawn 
Oh yea, and at least one in Newburgh, IN.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ArikaDawn on Sep 19, 2007 04:11 AM 

 
 
 
 
Hmmm, old thread but I&apos;ll add Johnny Rocket&apos;s, with the vanilla malt being my favorite.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Rubee on Sep 18, 2007 06:21 PM 

 
Red Robin
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By steakrules85 on Sep 18, 2007 08:58 PM 

 
I really like Wendy&apos;s Chocolate Frostys (and now I like their Frosty Floats!)

But Dairy Queen also makes a great Oreo Blizzard...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Chew on That on Sep 19, 2007 10:23 AM 

 
Steak and Shake! And if you are not in the mood for a big one ask for a kid&apos;s size. Perfect! I love the Mocha!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Jolie on Sep 24, 2007 09:51 AM 

 
Johnny Rockets. They seem sort of fast food chainy to me. Great shakes.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By slacker on Sep 24, 2007 02:40 PM 

 
It&apos;s frozen custard, but Culvers is easily the best of the best,love the butterscotch, and the eggnog ...or was it the pumpkin pie, during the holidays...good stuff!, Steak n Shake makes a good shake,as does Sonic,and Dairy Queen,Braum&apos;s is a cut above most,and although it is an ice cream shop, the hot fudge shake at Bruster&apos;s is obscenely good....and i wonder how i got fat...LOL!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By jword2001 on Sep 24, 2007 08:29 PM 

 
Jack in the Box- Blackberry!, Oreo!, Pumpkin!, Mint!- thick, thick, and delicious
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By natalie.warner on Oct 1, 2007 11:23 AM 
 re: natalie.warner 
Don&apos;t get my thinking about. I live in Canada and it&apos;s so hard to find a good milkshake here. No Jack in the Box or Culvers!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By callitasicit on Oct 1, 2007 04:02 PM 

 
 
I like Checkers Choc. shake...with 2 apple pies to keep me honest....
BK&apos;s shakes aren&apos;t too bad.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By BoboBx on Oct 24, 2007 03:12 AM 

 
I just had one of Steak and Shakes Fruit and Frozen Yogurt Milkshakes and can honestly say I have been craving them since.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By sunkissedbabe43 on Oct 26, 2007 10:52 PM 

 
Another vote for Steak and Shake here. Never had them on the East Coast, but tried them after moving to the Midwest (IA, then IN). I really crave them and have been in the drive-thru line getting one for dinner (they are filling!) while its been snowing bucketsful. I do, however, have a real soft spot in my heart for the Arby&apos;s Jamocha shake.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By nofunlatte on Oct 27, 2007 05:22 PM 

 
Hardee&apos;s has the best whipped cream on a milkshake - tastes like frosting!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By starbucksbrew on Oct 28, 2007 06:22 PM 

 
Next time you&apos;re in Canada, try the chocolate shake (it&apos;s new) at Harvey&apos;s, which is a Canadian burger chain. It&apos;s to DIE for. Made with dark chocolate ice cream.... mmmm

Definitely missing the Shamrock shakes as well!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By thenurse on Nov 5, 2007 12:25 PM 

 
I happen to love Steak and Shake. They have a seasonal flavor...Vanilla w/ toffee crunch is outstanding, imho. I also like Chic-Fil-A. But at Steak and Shake I can order a kids size and it is the right amount. But at Chick-Fil-A they only size they have is huge. even if I try and no drink it all I do and then end up feeling sick.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Jolie on Dec 25, 2007 07:11 AM 

 
Out here on the West Coast (So Cal to be exact) I happen to think that Arby&apos;s makes the best shakes. They&apos;re usually limited offer (&apos;speciality flavors) deals though.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By crt on Dec 26, 2007 05:28 AM 

 
fast food

In N Out, Carl&apos;s Jr and Sonic would be my choices.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rasputina on Nov 4, 2011 03:27 PM 

 
Culvers. Damn it&apos;s good to live in Wisconsin.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Olliegator on Nov 4, 2011 08:53 PM 

 
Fatburger&apos;s Maui Banana Shake is the only one on my list.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By mucho gordo on Nov 5, 2011 05:58 PM 

 
Steak and Shake
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By HoosierFoodie on Nov 7, 2011 11:45 AM 
 re: HoosierFoodie 
Not really fast food, but yeah their shakes are great.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By aynrandgirl on Nov 7, 2011 01:38 PM 

 
 
Shake Shack makes the best shakes that I have had. Had a Black&amp;White malted the other day and I am still thinking about it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By CDouglas on Nov 8, 2011 07:22 AM 
 re: CDouglas 
I had a caramel one not too long ago and I&apos;m still dreaming about it. Somehow Sonic&apos;s pumpkin pie shake isn&apos;t scratching the itch!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By CurlieGlamourGirlie on Nov 15, 2011 09:22 AM 

 
 
 «Back to the Chains Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 Trader Joe&apos;s Yea/Nay Thread - 4th quarter 2011 [OLD] (423 replies) 1 Trader Joe&apos;s Yea/Nay Thread - 2nd quarter 2012 [OLD] (482 replies) 2 Admit it... There&apos;s Some Dishes at Chain Restaurants You Like (329 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 34 

 Interesting article to share... 

16 minutes ago
 
 43 

 Trader Joe&apos;s Yea/Nay Thread... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 9 

 Has KFC&apos;s chicken pot pie changed... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 478 

 Your disappointing purchases... 

about 3 hours ago
 
 7 

 Sheetz Eats 

about 8 hours ago
 
Wednesday, July 11, 2012
 
 11 

 Been a while - Outback 

about 11 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 4th of July Dessert Recipes See All 39 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana » Supertaster Daily: Whole Grain Beefaroni 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Blue Cheese and Chive Compound Butter 
 
 »Blogs » Quirky in Queens: Panorama of My Silence-Heart Café » All&apos;Angolo: Tasty Italian Pasta in LA&apos;s Koreatown » Should Lamb Have a Strong Taste? » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County 
 
 »Discussion » I will not be eating or drinking at Searsucker, Burlap, Gingham, Herringbone, Gabardine » Four Day NYC trip coming from Bay Area with kids » Adventurous kids and forbidden foods? » Let&apos;s talk soft serve » Advice for London (UK) family visiting Pismo / SB / Ventura? » Acme Bread ...... Couronne. 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;Of all the fast-food chains ... who makes the best ice cream shakes?&quot;
	</body>
</document>
