<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003371" url="http://minnesota.cbslocal.com/top-lists/best-vietnamese-in-the-twin-cities/" time="2012-07-12-19:31" support="1" score="0.0016863596262445054" bingtitle="Best Vietnamese In The Twin Cities « CBS Minnesota" webtitle="Best Vietnamese In The Twin CitiesCBS Minnesota">
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>Not many places in the country can boast a ... the best of the best pho…no need for any condiments ... for…great food, good service…not a fast food restaurant…</description>
	<body>
		86° Buy Tickets Health More Channels Buy Tickets Health Contests TV Schedule Radio Schedule 
 Daily Deals 49% off at Breath Appeal Buy Team Gear Reebok NFL Equipment Minnesota Vikings #12 Percy Harvin Purple Replica Football Jersey Events Owl City 
 Facebook Twitter Follow Us 
 Home News Sports Best of Events Watch + Listen Weather Traffic Places Your Home Deals Autos 
 
 Best Of Home Arts&amp;Culture Shopping&amp;Style Food&amp;Drink Nightlife&amp;Music Family&amp;Pets Travel&amp;Outdoors 
 
 
 Lunch Break: How&apos;d You Get That Job: Twins Organist | Wedding Survival Guide | Openly Gay Celebrities 
Best Of Home
 
Best Vietnamese In The Twin Cities

November 9, 2010 2:42 PM
 Share this View Comments More Activity Facebook Activity What&apos;s this? Add to Timeline - What&apos;s This Click &quot;Add to Timeline&quot; to publish
what you read to Facebook See what your friends have read
on CBS Local sites Use &quot;Remove&quot; or &quot;Turn off&quot; to
disable at any time 
credit: www.pho79mpls.com
 Not many places in the country can boast a collection of Vietnamese restaurants like that of the Twin Cities. Minnesotans have both awesome hole-in-the-walls and excellent bistros. Listed below are the Twin Cities’top Vietnamese restaurants, which can satisfy cravings for bahn mi (Vietnamese baguette sandwich), pho (noodle soup) or spring rolls. And if you’ve never had Vietnamese food, I’d highly recommend stopping by one of the littler shops for lunch on a whim. Vietnamese food, when compared to other Asian cuisines, is lighter and built of a sundry framework of flavors—mixing mint and jalapeno, for instance—to create dishes that are delicious and often healthy.The list is in no particular order.
 
credit: www.jasmine26.net
 
Jasmine Deli and Jasmine 26

2532 Nicollet Ave. S.
Minneapolis, MN 55404
(612) 870-3800
 Directory | Website 

I was introduced to Vietnamese food at Jasmine Deli. It’s run by the uber-friendly Truong family and is an excellent place to drop in with a friend to grab a mock duck bahn mi, a noodle salad and a Vietnamese iced coffee (drip-brewed dark roast coffee mixed with sweetened condensed milk). It’s both affordable and satisfying.

Jasmine 26 is Jasmine Deli’s up-scale sister shop with a liquor license. Run by the same family, 26 whips up spiked bubble teas at the bar and a more refined version of Vietnamese than that found at the Deli.
 
Stir fry noodles Thai style at Quang. (credit: quangrestaurant.com)
 
Quang Restaurant

2719 Nicollet Ave. S.
Minneapolis, MN 55408
(612) 870-4739
 Directory | Website 

Known for its huge, steaming bowls of pho, this family run Eat Street shop offers a tasty oasis for those fed up of winter.
 
credit: facebook.com
 
Saigon

704 University Ave. W.
St. Paul, MN 55104
(651) 225-8751
 Directory | Website 

Winner of CityPages’2010 Best Vietnamese , Saigon has amazing bahn mi for $3.50 a sandwich. You can’t afford to miss it.
 
credit: www.pho79mpls.com
 
Pho 79

2529 Nicollet Ave. S.
Minneapolis, MN 55404
(612) 871-4602
 Directory | Website 

Another Eat Street shop, Pho 79 is authentic and affordable. It has a weekday lunch buffet and offers its famous pho Monday through Sunday.
 
credit: www.ngonbistro.com
 
Ngon Vietnamese Bistro

799 University Ave.
St. Paul, MN 55104
(651) 222-3301
 Directory | Website 

Ngon (pronounced“Nong”) is visually outstanding when compared with other Vietnamese restaurants in the Twin Cities. It specializes in fusion cuisine, mixing Vietnamese style and inventiveness with local ingredients. They serve craft beers and organic wines. Note Ngon down under Date Night Ideas.
 
 Jonathon Sharp is an intern with WCCO.com. Share this View Comments More Activity Facebook Activity What&apos;s this? Add to Timeline - What&apos;s This Click &quot;Add to Timeline&quot; to publish
what you read to Facebook See what your friends have read
on CBS Local sites Use &quot;Remove&quot; or &quot;Turn off&quot; to
disable at any time 
 Stephen Huot 
The pho at Ngon is beautiful…
 Kare11 
You’ve spelled banh mi wrong.
 Dan in BP 
Thanh Vi in Brooklyn Park serve nice banh mi and pho and has very friendly servers too-this based on about a dozen visits!
 Hmong home mad PHO 
Naw, i would say that, home made pho is the best. it test much better then those at these place. lol…and yes, no roaches and mice at home.lol.. Priceless Some of these place are not clean.
 Tharen 
The Vina in Highland is my absolute favorite, a wonderful hot n spicy chicken, and Ho Bien on Lexington and University is my favorite for Pho.
 Kaylee 
Check out Cam Ranh Bay restaurant in Burnsville. They have the best egg rolls, Pho, and Banh Xeo (Rice Pancake) in town.
 Newsman 
Vietnam House in Brooklyn Park (Brooklyn BLVD and Broadway) makes a wicked bowl of Pho’. By far the best Pho I have tested in the Twin Cities.
 EMH 
There’s a family owned place called the Pink Flower that is very good. They are in Mounds View.
 TT 
Vina’s in Highland Park is the best!!
 Michele 
I love Vina’s. I’m not an expert of Vietnamese food, by any means, although I love it. But that’s where I learned to love Pho.
 Sara 
I think you missed the mark. We believe that Que Nha at 849 University Ave in St. Paul is far and away better than the ones you mentioned. Try it!!
 Jenn 
I agree! and they serve the pho in multiple sizes so you dont have to eat the BIG BOWL! YUM!!
 Trie chau fan 
No way!! Trie chau on University Avenue has the best of the best pho…no need for any condiments if u don’t feel like it or don’t know how to mix it up good….
 huh? 
I AGREE with you! I love Trie chau too!!
 Daisy 
Agreed! We stopped in there for lunch today and were so very pleasantly surprised. The food was fresh, delicious, and perfectly presented. I can’t wait to go back again to try more of their authentic dishes. Friendly staff, fast service, good value for your money…what more could you ask for?? Yummm!
 Jonny Wong 
Reply to Hmong Home.. how many Hmong ppl live in Minnesota and how many restaurant they open? That speak much about Hmong food.
 Lee 
Zen Asia in White Bear Lake is also good.
 Myra 
awesome food at Que Viet Village House in NE Mpls!!
 JJJ000 
How could you leave Lotus off this list? That’s just wrong….
 Bensongirl 
Check out On’s Kitchen Thai Cuisine on University, just west of Snelling…worth braving the light rail construction for…great food, good service…not a fast food restaurant…
 Linda 
The hot&amp;spicy chicken and eggrolls at Vina are my favs and a must everytime I go there!!!! Wish they weren’t so far away from Blaine…..but worth the trip!
 Linda 
Don’t forget Bambu in Maplewood. Best Pho soup!
 Dee 
So share the recipe!!
 Poor Service 
I’ve been here several times and the service was poor each time. They are quick to get the sale but even quicker to get you out. Also, they have food and sanitation issues and I’ve seen the health inspector visit them on more than one occasion.
 Bobby Hidalgo 
QUE VIET, JOHNSON ST, MINNAPOLIS
HAS THE BEST EGGROLL AND WONTON SOUP IN THE TWIN CITIES. TRY IT.
 O 
I like wok the dog !
 Tom 
From HCMC (Saigon) to Hanoi the food might be listed the same……but so many different flavors, and so darned GOOD!! Viet Nam is worth trip for those looking for a little adventure. The cuisine alone is worth the trip.
 maia moua 
My response is to Johnny Wong,obviously you’ve never been to The Hmong Village in Saint Paul. Hmong restaurants and all, except located in one location.. I believe this strategy is wiser than a bunch of restaurants all competing against one another and selling the obvious same dishes yet they’re springing up all over Minnesota. Its the same cooks with the same recipe monopolizing all the vietnamese eateries. By the way, the cooks at these eateries are mostly spanish folks.. Take a peek into the kitchen@ your fav place next time. I have no problem with this but I don’t believe its authentic. Call me old fashioned HMONG, but I and the folks@ Hmong Village do all our cooking. Now that’s real authenticity. And by the way, there are plenty of Good Hmong citizens here in Minnesota. Among us there are Doctors,Dentists, business owners etc.So do yourself a favor Wong, and instead of belittleing Hmong people like me because I don’t open a joint down the street like my cousin, perhaps you should suggest to your cousins about consolidating these dime a dozen restaurants with poor service and low quality food into one large enterprise.. That’s all in a nut shell.
 Laura 
Que Viet Village House, Brooklyn Park has the best Egg Rolls I have ever had. Dont want any others after you have had thiers.
 Parker 
Their eggrolls are like burritos and they’re good
 Emily 
The Pink Flower on County Road 10 is very good. It’s a family-owned place and they have awesome spring rolls.
 Susan 
Ant’s. very good.
 
 blog comments powered by Disqus 
Filed Under

 Best of Food&amp;Drink 

Related Tags

 Best Vietnamese Jasmine Deli and Jasmine 26 Ngon Vietnamese Bistro Pho 79 Quang Restaurant Saigon Twin Cities 
 Listen Live! 
Video News
 11 A.M. Weather Update More Videos 
Latest Galleries
 Previous Next Rhythmic Circus Performs At... California Car Meetup: Bob’s... Amazing Cloud Formations July 4 Severe Weather Storms Hit Northern Minnesota Busted: Best Celebrity DUI... Car Crashes Into Blaine Home,... Amelia Santaniello On &apos;The... Weird&amp;Interesting... Route 66: Views From The... Twin Cities Pride Parade In... River&apos;s Edge Music Festival... Heavy Rain Causes Floods,... Goin&apos; To The Lake: The... June 19 Severe Weather Fourth Of July Fireworks 
 Page 0 Page 1 Page 2 Page 3 
 
Follow CBS Minnesota
 Follow @WCCO 
 The Buzz From WCCO Radio 

 Jordan Goodman Talks Money On WCCO Morning News The J Rob Intensive Wresting Camp. Is It For You? John Williams Video Smack Down For 7-12 The Heavy Table With James Norton John Williams Video Smack Down For 7-11 
 
Meet WCCO-TV’s Anchors
 
TV Schedule

 Full Program Grid 7:00 PM The Big Bang Theory 7:31 PM The Big Bang Theory 8:00 PM Big Brother 14 9:00 PM Person of Interest 10:00 PM WCCO 4 News at Ten 10:35 PM Late Show with David Letterman 11:37 PM The Late Late Show with Craig Ferguson 
 Take Our Poll 
 Notable 2012 Deaths 
 
 Download CBS YourDay 
 
 Openly Gay Celebs 
 
 Gay Pride Parade 
 
 News 
 Local Business Consumer Crime Politics Entertainment Health Blogs 
 Weather 
 Live Radar Severe Weather School Closings On The Spot Weather Blog 
 Sports 
 Vikings Twins Timberwolves Wild Gophers High School Sports Rally 
 Best of 
 Arts&amp;Culture Family&amp;Pets Food&amp;Drink Nightlife&amp;Music Shopping&amp;Style Travel&amp;Outdoors 
 Watch + Listen 
 Video Library Audio on Demand Seen On WCCO-TV Heard On WCCO-AM 
 Other 
 Traffic Traffic Cams Local Offers Directory Events 
 Contact Us 
 WCCO-TV 830 WCCO 
 Corporate 
 About Us Advertise Business Development Contact Us Mobile Connect 
 
 
MINN. Business Listings

 Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Shopping Professional Services Search Listings 
 
 Privacy Policy Terms of Use EEO Reports Deals 
 Powered by WordPress.com VIP Facebook Twitter RSS Other CBS Local Cities ‣ 
 CBS Atlanta CBS Baltimore CBS Boston CBS Charlotte CBS Chicago CBS Cleveland CBS Connecticut CBS Dallas CBS Denver CBS Detroit CBS Houston CBS Las Vegas CBS Los Angeles CBS Miami CBS Minnesota CBS New York CBS Philadelphia CBS Pittsburgh CBS Riverside CBS Sacramento CBS San Francisco CBS Seattle CBS St. Louis CBS Tampa CBS Washington 
 
 ©2012 CBS Local Media, a division of CBS Radio Inc. All rights reserved. 
 Buy Tickets Health More Channels Buy Tickets Health Contests TV Schedule Radio Schedule 
 Daily Deals 49% off at Breath Appeal Buy Team Gear Reebok NFL Equipment Minnesota Vikings #12 Percy Harvin Purple Replica Football Jersey Events Owl City 
 Follow Us Facebook Twitter 
Select a Live Stream
 
News, Sports and Talk Radio
 
 Click to listen to 830 WCCO 
 
Music Radio
 
 Click to listen to KZJK-FM Click to listen to WLTE-FM Click to listen to Last.fm Click to listen to radio.com Click to listen to MP3.com
	</body>
</document>
