<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003300" url="http://www.move.com/apartmentsforrent-detail/175-n-feldner-road_orange_ca_92868_C708687" time="2012-07-12-19:26" support="1" score="0.0022705889811577683" bingtitle="Apartments for Rent at STRADA APARTMENTS - 175 N. Feldner Road ..." webtitle="Apartments for Rent at STRADA APARTMENTS, 175 N. Feldner Road, Orange, CA, 92868 - Move.com Rentals">
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="151"/>
	<description>Near 5, 57,and 22 Freeways; Near Entertainment; Near ... New Counter Tops; Patio/Balcony; Patio/balcony(select apts) ... Personal Check, Company Check, Money Order</description>
	<body>
		It looks like Javascript is disabled in your browser. Move requires Javascript to be enabled in order to use our site.
 Please follow these instructions to enable Javascript. 
 {&quot;ct&quot;: &quot;Orange&quot;, &quot;lid&quot;: &quot;708687&quot;, &quot;mid&quot;: &quot;&quot;, &quot;sn&quot;: &quot;175 N. Feldner Road&quot;} 
Visit our sites:

 Realtor.com 
 Home Finance Moving Home&amp;Garden 
 Move New Homes Seniorhousingnet Moving.com 
 
 Already have an account? Sign In 

 My Home Search Properties Learning Center 
 Feedback Apartment Rentals Home California Orange Orange Apartments for rent 175 N. Feldner Road Share Send To Friend Print Save Property Facebook Twitter LinkedIn Digg MySpace Delicious Technorati Google Reddit Close 
STRADA APARTMENTS
 175 N. Feldner Road, Orange, CA 92868 Map 

 
Photo of 
 
 See Floor Plans Features Details Neighborhood Info Driving Directions School Info 

 View All Photos           
 
Property Information
 
 Special Offer 1 
 
Move In Specials!

CALL FOR THIS WEEKS PRICING SPECIALS!!
 Disclaimer 
The owner of or advertiser for this listing arranged for its posting on Move.com and is solely responsible for all offers, claims and other listing content.
 
CALL FOR THIS WEEKS PRICING SPECIALS!!COME HOME to garden style apartment homes in the heart of the beautiful city of ORANGE!!! Upgraded with brushed nickel fixtures, custom paint with accent walls, and more nestled in magnificently designed landscape with lots of trees that brings the tranquil park feeling home.
Our community offers 2 SPARKLING POOLS, SPA, 24-HOUR smart card LAUNDRY CENTERS, Community BBQs with trellis, and fitness center. We are only MINUTES from the METROLINK station, major freeways, UCI Medical Center, St. Joseph Hospital, CHOC, MAIN PLACE MALL,Orange Circle, Block of Orange, Chapman University, Angel Stadium and Disneyland Resort. The added convenience of next door grocery shopping at the newly remodeled Ralphs Supermarket is all yours. Friendly on-site management that assures prompt attention to your needs. STRADA Apartment Homes, where your convenience is our business.*Subect to availability/O.A.C.

130 Units
Call for Availability: (888)403-1137 
 

 
 Contact Property 

For immediate assistance, call:
 (888)403-1137 
 
Make an appointment or ask a question.
 First Name Last Name Your Email Address Phone Move-in Date Questions or Comments Request Moving Quote 
 
 
STRADA APARTMENTS
 - Bed, Bath Name Email Address Phone Number Unit Needed By Questions or Comments Request Moving Quote 
 Privacy Policy 
 
Thank you!
Your request has been successfully sent.
 Close 
Could not send the Lead, please try again!
 Close 
Floor Plans for STRADA APARTMENTS
 Deposit:   

 
 Floor Plan Bed Bath Sqft. Rent From Availability Studio 
Call us: (888)403-1137 
 
Studio
 Studio 1 450 $975 + Check Availability 1 Bedroom 
Call us: (888)403-1137 
 
 One Bedroom 
 1 1 606 $1,150 + Check Availability 
One Bedroom
 1 1 707 $1,175 + Check Availability 2 Bedrooms 
Call us: (888)403-1137 
 
 Two Bedroom 
 2 1 801 $1,350 + Check Availability 
Two Bedroom
 2 2 881 $1,450 + Check Availability 
Two Bedroom
 2 2 901 $1,475 + Check Availability 
 
Features
 
Community Features
 Cats and Dogs (30lbs) Breed Restrictions Apply. 
 BBQ/Picnic Area Cats Allowed Cats and Dogs Welcome Close to Public Transportation Covered Parking Fitness Center Garage Gated Entrance/Controlled Access Laundry Facility Multiple Pets Near 5, 57,and 22 Freeways Near Entertainment 

 Near Restraunts Near Shopping On-Site Management Pet Friendly Pool Small Dogs Allowed Spa/Hot Tub/Sauna Standard Cable 
Unit Features
 
 Air Conditioning Ceiling Fan Custom Paint Dishwasher Disposal Full Kitchen Garage Garages, Carport or Uncovered Gas Cooking and Heating Hardwood Flooring(select apts) Hardwood Floors 

 High Speed Internet Available Mirrored Closet Doors New Counter Tops Patio/Balcony Patio/balcony(select apts) Walk-In Closets 
Details
 
 Lease Terms 4 to 13 months pending availability Utilities Included Call Accepted forms of rental payment Personal Check, Company Check, Money Order 
 
 Neighborhood Info Driving Directions School Info 
 
STRADA APARTMENTS
 (888)403-1137 
 
Office Hours:

 Mon-Fri: 9:00AM - 6:00PM Sat: 10:00AM - 6:00PM Sun: 
 
 Advertisement 
 
Find a Mover
 Move Date   Move From (Zip Code) Move To (Zip Code) Move Size Select a Size Studio 1 Bedroom 2 Bedrooms 2-3 Bedrooms 3 Bedrooms 4 Bedrooms 5 Bedrooms Get a Moving Quote 
 Advertisement 
 
Real Estate Resources
 
Finances:

 Find Rental Insurance In Your Area Get Mortgage Prequalified Online 

Move:

 Rent a Truck Free Storage Quotes Moving Checklists 

Settle In:

 Set Up Your Utilities Learn More About Your Community Get Decorating Tips 
 If you want all the details for 175 N. Feldner Road, you have come to the right place. Find information about the individual units, STRADA APARTMENTS (the rental community), and the neighborhood and local amenities. Information via varied mediums so you can get a good idea of what life is like at 175 N. Feldner Road, at least the best short a visit. There are also plenty of features on Move.com that make searching for rentals and learning about your options easy.

The information here is for the apartment for rent at 175 N. Feldner Road. But regardless of the search you conduct, Move.com is here to make your search easier. Related Interests 
 Search Apartments For Rent US Apartment Search Apartment search tips View More Related Interests 
 
 Moving tips and checklists Renting with pets Roommate rules Apartment inspection checklist 
 Corporate: Bookmark this Site | Site Map | Help | Sign In | About Move | Contact Us | Link to Us | Investor Relations | Media Room | Careers | Advertise with Us | Privacy Policy | Ad Choices | Terms of Use Operated by Move, Inc.: Move.com® | Homes by REALTOR.com® | Real Estate News Blog by REALTOR.com® | Real Estate Trends Blog | Movers - Moving.com 
 Senior Housing | TOP PRODUCER® | HomeInsight.com | New Homes | Apartments for Rent | Property Values © Move, Inc. All rights reserved. Equal Housing Opportunity .
 This information is provided by Move.com Formatted for easy printing so you can take this with you. Remember to say you found it on Move.com. This information has been secured from sources we believe to be reliable, but we make no representatives or warranties, expressed or implied, as to the accuracy of the information. You must verify the information and bear all risk for accuracies. SIGN UP Email Address Password Remember me Forgot my password Sign In 
 Don&apos;t have an account? Signing up is easy!

 Customize and store your unique Local Likes View your submitted leads Save your searches Save favorite properties 
 Create Account Email Address Password Confirm Password Gender Female Male I&apos;d rather not say Year of Birth e.g. 1965 Why are we asking? Keep me informed about MOVE.com®and REALTOR.com®products and updates to my saved searches and listings Sign Up 
 Already have an account?
 Sign In 
 Privacy Policy | Terms of Use 
We will not share your personal information without your permission.
 
You can access your saved listings and searches from any computer by signing into Move.com with your email address. Please ensure it is correct.


 Close Email incorrect? 
Please enter your email address below. We will send a new password to you.
 Email Address Submit 
We&apos;ve sent an email to
  from
 &quot;MOVE.com®Password Assistance&quot;. 

If you don&apos;t see this message it may have been 
 mistakenly flagged as spam and placed in your 
 Spam folder. Please add customerservice@move.com to your 
 safe sender list.

Follow the instructions in this email to reset your password.

 Back to Sign In 
 Current Password Forgot my password New Password Confirm Password Save Search Name Save     Cancel 
 Please try signing in again. 
 Select user type before the customization
 
Registered User

I already have an account.
Please sign me in and load my Local Likes.
 
New User

I am a new user and I would like to use this feature.
 Send to Friend Let your friends know about this property My Name My Email Address Send To Multiple email addresses should be separated by a comma or semi-colon. Message Send me a copy of this message Send Email Thanks! Your message is on the way. Close 
We will never share your personal information. Privacy Policy 
 
 
Please provide more information below for your moving quote.
 Move Size (approx) Select a Size Studio 1 Bedroom 2 Bedrooms 2-3 Bedrooms 3 Bedrooms 4 Bedrooms 5 Bedrooms Moving From Moving To Move Date (approx) Name Email Address Phone Number 
 Get a Moving
 Quote No, thanks Need a moving quote? Yes No, thanks 
Thanks! Your message is on the way.

A real estate professional will contact you soon.
 Moving?    We can help with that too! No, thanks 
 Sorry! We did not find movers that match your request. We’re always
 adding movers, so please try again later. For truck rentals, select “Just need to
 rent a truck?” or “No, thanks” to skip.
 
 Sorry! For in-state moves, we offer quotes from Full Service movers
 only. Please change the Move Type to Full Service or select “No, thanks” to skip.
 
This service is provided by Move, Inc. and is not affiliated with the real estate
 professionals associated with this property.
 
What are your 

Your Local Likes are simply the things that are important to you about where you
 want to live. Customize your Local Likes list to see changes to the map.
 Please wait...
	</body>
</document>
