<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003439" url="http://car-insurance-for-teenagers.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:35" support="4" score="0.0023183044665527975" bingtitle="Car Insurance For Teenagers - Inexpensive, Cheap, Affordable ..." webtitle="Car Insurance For Teenagers - Inexpensive, Cheap, Affordable, Information">
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="222"/>
	<description>Car ... to pay their own expenses, so unless he picks up some more hours at the local grocery store or fast food restaurant, you could be stuck footing a hefty bill.</description>
	<body>
		Car Insurance for Teenagers 
 
 Home Types of Insurance Coverage Compare Insurance Providers 
 
Tips to Paying Less
 How to Lower your Premium:
 Formal Driver&apos;s Education Classes Good student discount Clean Driving Record A Shared Family Vehicle 
 
Compare Insurance Quotes
 
Auto payments are different everywhere you look:


 Military Insurance Companies Comprehensive Plans Liability Only Plans Risky Vehicle Surcharges 
 
Auto Insurance Info for New Drivers

Finding car insurance for teenagers can be a frustrating process. You will likely find that an insurance policy to cover your 16 year old son is in excess of what your entire family is paying already. Teenagers can rarely afford to pay their own expenses, so unless he picks up some more hours at the local grocery store or fast food restaurant, you could be stuck footing a hefty bill. 

However, there are steps that you can take to minimize the cost of your young adult&apos;s insurance payments.

 GET A FREE QUOTE NOW Zip Code: 
 


 Quick Auto Insurance 


 Taking a driver&apos;s education class can lower your premiums. If the insurance company feels that your child is a professionally trained driver, they will classify them as less risky. If they can differentiate between a teenager who has and has not taken a drivers education course, they can make separate rates for each person.
 Good grades can mean less money out of your pocket. Statistically, students with high marks in school get in less accidents. We could spend all day theorizing why this is, but there are some obvious factors here. Good students spend more time studying, and less time driving. Students with straight As are less likely to go out drunk driving, and are more likely to obey traffic laws.
 A clean driving record is very important in getting affordable insurance quotes. 
This may seem obvious, but it is critical that your child has a good driving record. Any speeding tickets, traffic violations, driving under the influence, or even a minor in possession can raise insurance rates for your teenager significantly.
 Let your son or daughter share the family car before getting their own. 
Having fewer cars on your family car insurance policy, can significantly improve the impact that your teenagers addition to the policy will have. If your family&apos;s new driver gets his own car to begin with, your insurance quote will reflect that.



Check this great informational site out if you are looking to rent a manual transmission car for an inexpensive vacation.












 Designed by Standard Fire Insurance Front Door Enterprises 2007
	</body>
</document>
