<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003095" url="http://fastfood.einnews.com/country/spain" time="2012-07-12-19:13" support="1" score="0.0008063975765246023" bingtitle="Spain Fast Food News - Fast Food News Today" webtitle="Spain Fast Food News - Fast Food News Today">
			<query id="000172" bing-rank="87"/>
	<description>The eight-seat restaurant … ... Miami’s Cuban Guys fast food restaurant offers traditional ... ... You will be able to choose which days you want to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday Jul 12, 2012 Fast Food News Today A service for Global Professionals 
 Change your billing and/or user information Extend your subscription period Re-activate an expired account Manage your Email Alerts Add additional users to your account Manage your additional user account(s) Retrieve a lost password Get an invoice for your subscription Cancel your account by sending us an email through the feedback form 
 
 News by Topic News by Country 
 Tools 
 Publications Submit News Members About Contact 
 
Spain Fast Food News

Latest Spain News
 from
 Fast Food News Today.
 Southern Europe &gt;Spain
 | Spain
 Topics 
 Get by: Email or RSS 
 
 
 Costa Rica: 21 Firms Seek 1,200 Employees 
 12 Jul 13:58 GMT 
 …are bilingual (English and Spanish ) personal, and fast food restaurant employees. Finally, there… 
 
 My Media World: Karl Heasman 
 11 Jul 14:17 GMT 
 …Sky media sales conference in Spain . It was going extremely well…such as train stations and fast food restaurants. The one thing I… 
 
 Across the U.S., expanding menus and improved food 
 9 Jul 06:57 GMT 
 …offer creative restaurants serving interesting food . In short, I think…stop for fast food , making every effort to eat only real food …we found Cafe Madriz, a Spanish restaurant with a level…believe, that the interest in food that has spread throughout… 
 
 Kick your junk food habit to beat depression 
 1 Jul 18:56 GMT 
 …in Spain . They found that people who eat a lot of fast food and junk food are 37 percent more…, fruits and vegetables. Depression, Diet, Fast food , Health, Mediterranean 
 
 Food Flashes: July 1-7 
 1 Jul 08:27 GMT 
 Open   Cha Cha&apos;s Bar and Grill is open at 14436 Old Bandera Road in Helotes. It has two other family owned locations at 2026 Babcock Road and 5616 Bandera Road.   Coming Zoës Kitchen is opening at 999 E. Basse Road, Suite 125, in Lincoln Heights. It… 
 
 Four Amazingly Simple Ways to Save Money at the Fast Food Drive Through Window 
 27 Jun 07:19 GMT 
 …The Dollar Menu-aires. Now more fast food restaurants have value menus…self-control when you order fast food . Sources:&quot;McDonald&apos;…Weight at Waffle House Fast Food Review: Chick-Fil-A&apos;s…Atlanta Published by L. Spain I enjoy sharing my… 
 
 Going to Summerfest? Check out Milwaukee’s food scene 
 27 Jun 02:26 GMT 
 …County, and that includes food processors and supermarkets. German…, according to Nancy Stohs, food editor of the Journal-Sentinel.…Most serve burgers and other fast food — such as Leon’s,…sandwich it calls a “ Spanish hamburger” — but rich, high-butterfat,… 
 
 Best American Food Trends Part 2 
 19 Jun 12:18 GMT 
 …piece on the 8 Best Food Trends by covering the first…down restaurants, plus an expansive food hall with taqueria, gourmet burgers…. Small Plates: For centuries the Spanish , Greek and Chinese have known…the mercy of places like KFC , and the latter is far… 
 
 Stocks down on Spain worries 
 12 Jun 07:32 GMT 
 …$100 billion euro bailout indebted Spain had received earlier this…Europe with bailout in Spain and continuation of issues…to $2.11. Australian food ingredient maker Goodman Fielder…Brands, the operator behind fast food chains KFC and Pizza Hutt, rose… 
 
 US close: Spain set to grab bull by the horns 
 8 Jun 23:42 GMT 
 …to dance to a Spanish beat, and on Friday…as speculation mounted that Spain may formally request emergency…coal mining operations in Kentucky. Fast food firm McDonald&apos;s…Yum Brands, which operates the KFC and Pizza Hut restaurant chains, also… 
 
 US stocks score solid gains on Spain rescue hopes 
 8 Jun 21:53 GMT 
 US stocks score solid gains on Spain rescue hopes Posted: 09 June 2012 0515 hrs NEW YORK: Wall Street closed solidly in the black Friday as investors showed a bit more confidence ahead of a weekend that could see a rescue emerge for Spain and its ailing… 
 
 Stocks Rise Amid Hopes Over Spain Rescue 
 8 Jun 17:30 GMT 
 Stocks added to modest gains Friday, following news that Spain is expected to ask for help for its troubled banks soon, according to an ECB official. Spain will&quot;formulate a request for aid exclusively for banks recapitalization,&quot;according to… 
 
 Stock Futures Point Lower; McDonald&apos;s Slumps 
 8 Jun 14:12 GMT 
 …;s (MCD) 3% drop. The fast food leviathan reported a 3.3…. producer prices. News reports said Spain planned to request financial support… 
 
 ITGOW: Why I Added McDonald&apos;s To My DRiP 
 5 Jun 10:21 GMT 
 This article focuses on McDonald&apos;s (MCD) and is the 2nd in my series, ITGOW: Investments To Grow Old With. I believe that McDonald&apos;s fits at least 2 of the investment themes that I outlined in my article introducing the series and has recently… 
 
 10 Weight Control Commandments for Fast Food 
 25 May 02:48 GMT 
 …menu entrees from all these fast food chains and found that…of Spain . According to a recent survey by the Technomic food …the mood for fast food , here are my 10 fast food commandments to to…you 100 calories. The average fast food appetizer has 813 calories… 
 
 The 10 Fast Food Commandments 
 24 May 23:08 GMT 
 …of fast food options trying to lure you in. But is the food …in 4 Americans visits a fast food restaurant. McDonald’s alone…of Spain . According to a recent survey by the Technomic food …you 100 calories. The average fast food appetizer has 813 calories… 
 
 McDonald&apos;s: Big changes afoot; kids&apos; marketing proposal fails 
 24 May 16:36 GMT 
 McDonald&apos;s executives discussed growth initiatives, including restaurant revamps and menu optimization, at the annual shareholders meeting. (Charles Rex Arbogast / AP Photo / May 24, 2012) By Tiffany Hsu May 24, 2012, 9:02 a.m. McDonald’s Corp. is… 
 
 How Mexican fast food got rolling 
 8 May 21:07 GMT 
 …living scholar of Mexican-American fast food . And preferably, you will… Taco Bell website, Bell is cited as the creator of the&quot; fast food …back to before the Spanish conquest: no carnitas, no…of what constitutes Mexican-American food has never been more… 
 
 Fast Food, Boxed Baked Goods Tied To Depression Signals 
 12 Apr 19:22 GMT 
 …baked goods and fast food . Performed by researchers at Spain ’s University…diets and moods. “The more fast food you consume, the greater…the findings, according to Food Navigator, saying that it’…for the consumption of other food items,” states the report.… 
 
 Fast Food, Commercial Baked Goods Tied To Depression 
 12 Apr 17:57 GMT 
 …baked goods and fast food . Performed by researchers at Spain ’s University…diets and moods. “The more fast food you consume, the greater…the findings, according to Food Navigator, saying that it’…for the consumption of other food items,” states the report.… 
 
 Spanish study links eating fast food with depression 
 2 Apr 08:20 GMT 
 …University of Granada, in Spain , shows eating fast food is linked to a…study found that consumers of fast food , compared to those who eat…participants who eat the most fast food and commercial baked goods are… 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 Next Follow @EIN_News NEW French Alps Avalanche Kills 9---Latest News Updates from EIN News Press Releases 
 Latest See All Submit a Release 

Reach our readers and post your press release.

 Pretzelmaker® Kicks Off Summer With the Exclusive Pretzel Dog and ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Dunkin&apos; Brands Group, Inc. to Announce Second Quarter Fiscal Year 2012 ... [12 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Domino&apos;s Pizza® Brings Mobile Ordering App to Amazon&apos;s Kindle Fire [11 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Don&apos;t Call Him Junior: Son of Baconator Joins Wendy&apos;s Hamburger Lineup [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Pizza and Garlic Bread Together At Last: Pizza Hut Introduces Garlic ... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Lombardi Family Concepts Chooses GiftCardLab.com To Provide Company-... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire The Dunkin&apos; Donuts&amp;Baskin-Robbins Community Foundation Awards $127,... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Caribou Coffee Names Leigh Anne Snider Senior Vice President of Retail ... [10 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Central Coast McDonald&apos;s® Will Send One Lucky Customer to See Local ... [09 Jul 2012] PR Newswire Caribou Coffee Partners with Jungle Jim&apos;s International Market to Open ... [09 Jul 2012] PR Newswire 
 Learn more about advertising opportunities Today&apos;s Photos 
 huffingtonpost.com
 Farm Bill Lasting Five Years Approved By House Committee motherjones.com
 5 Surprising Ingredients Allowed in Organic Food 
 OP/ED 
 Latest See All Submit 

 The Great LIBOR Robbery And The Corruption of Major Markets Sorkin&apos;s Fictional&quot;Newsroom&quot;Gets It Right, As CNN, Fox And Others Get It Wrong Romney&apos;s 1 Per Cent Class Parties in Utah; What will The Uninvited Do? 
 Conferences 
 Latest See All Submit 
 GCSE-Food&amp;Health Protection Conference - Toronto Canada 
 Featuring:
 - Consumer Protection - Championing Effective Solutions
 - ... 
 3rd Juice, Nectar&amp;Soft Drinks Summit 2012 
 Magenta Global in cooperation with the Turkish Fruit Juice Industry Association (MEYED) is ... 
 
 International Conference on QA , QC&amp;Validation 
 OMICS Group cordially invites all the participants across the globe to attend the ... 
 Marketplace 
 Latest See All Post a Listing 

 Accounting Services 
Accounting, Tax&amp;Payroll Services. Enjoy your business, leave the paperwork to us. We are certified accountants.
 Press Release Distribution 
Get your press release seen by business and industry professionals and at all corners of the web for $79 or less
 Global Technology Forum 
Business strategies for the digital age. Free website from the Economist Intelligence Unit.
 
 
 FAST FOOD NEWS TODAY BACK TO TOP 

 Account Info: 
 My Account Subscriber Billing Info Member Center 
 Change your billing and/or user information Extend your subscription period Re-activate an expired account Manage your Email Alerts Add additional users to your account Manage your additional user account(s) Retrieve a lost password Get an invoice for your subscription Cancel your account by sending us an email through the feedback form 
 
 Create an Account: 
 Sign up for a Free Trial Register for an Account 
 Help&amp;Information Center: 
 Help Contact Us 
 Submit 
 Submit Press Releases Submit Marketplace Listing Submit a Conference Reserve Ad Space 
 About 
 About Fast Food News Today Members List User Agreement Privacy Policy Copyright Policy 
 Navigate: 
 Site Map Home Fast Food News by Topic Fast Food News by Country Fast Food News by US State Fast Food Press Releases Fast Food Press Releases by 24-7 
 Tools and Formats: 
 Email Alerts RSS Feeds 
 
 EIN News Home About EIN News 
Founded in 1995, EIN News is an international leader in real-time news tracking and digital information services. Our systems continuously scan the web, indexing news from thousands of worldwide sources. The data is then filtered and organized into news streams. The process is supervised by a team of professional news editors.

We are news professionals and technologists dedicated to producing the fastest and most comprehensive news streams on the planet. We are committed to providing our members with the highest quality software tools and resources available.

 EIN News is a division of Internet Product Development Group Inc. 
To reach us send an email or call +1 202 657 5158.
 EIN Presswire EIN Marketplace EIN Events and Conferences Newsfeed Maker Inbox Robot IPD Group EIN Twitter EIN Facebook 
 
 ©1995-2012 IPD Group, Inc. All Right Reserved. +
 Fast Food News Today
 = Unlimited access to real-time news Create your EIN News account now. EDITOR&apos;S PICKS 
Founded in 1995, EIN News is an international leader in real-time news tracking and digital information services. Our systems continuously scan the web, indexing news from thousands of worldwide sources. The data is then filtered and organized into news streams. The process is supervised by a team of professional news editors.

We are news professionals and technologists dedicated to producing the fastest and most comprehensive news streams on the planet. We are committed to providing our members with the highest quality software tools and resources available.

 EIN News is a division of Internet Product Development Group Inc. 

Main office: 1025 Connecticut Ave. NW, Suite 1000, Washington, DC 20036
To reach us send an email or call +1 202 657 5158.
 About 
 About Fast Food News Today Aimed at business leaders and global professionals worldwide, Fast Food News Today is a media monitoring service provided by EIN News.

 About EIN News Established in 1995, EIN News began by supplying business professionals and individuals with relevant and interesting news products. It has grown to become the largest digital news provider in Europe.

 Member List See the partial member list and join a community of professionals from private industry, institutions, and governments that rely on EIN as a critical source for research, breaking news and media services.
 
 EIN Presswire A platform to publish your press or news releases online and be read by thousands of decision-makers, leading journalists and industry professionals who rely on EIN News as an indispensable source of breaking news. Your release will also immediately appear in the Google database and stream out to our content partners, Facebook and Twitter.
 
ALL NEWS PUBLICATIONS

 EIN News provides breaking news coverage on the following topics:
	</body>
</document>
