<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003595" url="http://www.bizben.com/business-for-sale/fast-food-restaurant-for-sale-orange-county-california-ca-144631.php" time="2012-07-12-19:45" support="1" score="0.0008660570360831463" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Opportunity For Sale, Orange County ..." webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Opportunity For Sale, Orange County, California, CA | BizBen">
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="58"/>
	<description>More Fast Food Restaurant Businesses For Sale On BizBen.com ... Alternate Phone: 562-228-3477: DRE Number: None Given ... Now Offers Business Buyers FREE Franchise Selection ...</description>
	<body>
		New Listings All Listings Blog News Events Articles Buyer Programs Advertiser Login      Power User Login The #1 Website to Find Businesses for Sale in California Successfully Selling California
Businesses Online Since 1994!

Over 200 New Listings Daily! Businesses Sold This Month: 1,371 
Businesses Sold So Far This Year: 7,259 
 
Selling A Business?
Advertise On BizBen 

 
 Home Find Businesses for Sale 
 Search By Category Search By County Search By Keyword Advanced Search New Businesses For Sale Businesses For Sale By Owner New Business Opportunities 
 Advertise On BizBen 
 Individual Ads Multi Ad Advertising Resource Advertising Banner Advertising Franchise/Opportunity Advertising Advertising Testimonials Advertising Phone Consultations Advertiser Login 
 Franchises 
 New Franchise Opportunities Franchise Resale Opportunities Franchise Tips&amp;News 
 Business Brokers 
 Find A Broker Or Agent Broker&amp;Agent News Broker&amp;Agent Advertising Signup Broker&amp;Agent Advertising Login 
 Business Resources 
 All Business Resources BizBen Blog Articles BizBen Talk Radio News&amp;Tips Events Valuation Sold Stats Buying Book Selling Book 
 About BizBen 
 About&amp;Contact BizBen Site Map Email Alerts&amp;Reports FAQ&apos;s RSS Feeds Advertiser Login Power User Login 
 
 
 Home  &gt;&gt; Search Listings By: Category , Advanced Search  &gt;&gt; 144631 Save This Listing     View Saved Info&amp;Pages - 0     View Saved Listings - 0 
 
Fast Food Restaurant For Sale - Orange County, California
 
 
 
 Ad/Listing Information
 Contact Information   
 Status: Available Location: Orange County County: Orange City: None Given 
 
 Contact Broker:  James Kim, MBA Primary Phone:  213-384-0400 Alternate Phone:  562-228-3477 DRE Number:  None Given 
 
 Email Address:  Email Advertiser Date Started:  6/4/12 Date Last Revised:   6/4/12 BizBen Ad #:  144631 
  
  Financial Information Detailed Information   
 Price:    $350,000 Down:    $350,000 Revenue:    $600,000 Adj. Net:    $150,000 
 
 Relocatable:    No Home Based:    No Real Estate Included:    No Bkr To Bkr Coop:    No 
 
 Franchise:    No For Sale By Owner:    No Asset Sale:    No Lifestyle:    No 
 
 
 

 
Description Of This Orange County Fast Food Restaurant Business For Sale:
 Store Size Is 1,800 Sf, Rent Is 2,671.34+842.40. Lease Is Remained 2+5. Surrounded By Industrial Area. Call James Kim, MBA (Broker) at 213-384-0400 or 562-228-3477  (Please Mention You Saw This Ad On BizBen)
 About This Fast Food Restaurant Business Opportunity For Sale in Orange County. 

 

 
 Email This Listing Printer-Friendly Page 
 

 
 
 Your Browser Does Not Support Inline Frames. 


Fast Food Restaurant For Sale And Orange County Region Related Links:
 All Fast Food Restaurants For Sale - Quick Service Restaurants For Sale 
 
 See All Related Business For Sale Listings 
 
 All Restaurants for Sale&amp;Food Related Businesses For Sale 
 
 Orange County Business Opportunity Listings, Businesses For Sale, Franchises For Sale 
 
 Orange County Area Business Opportunity Listings, Businesses For Sale, Franchises For Sale 
 
 All James Kim, MBA Listings For Sale 
 
 Looking For A Specific Type Of Business (Location) For Sale? Place A Business Wanted To Buy Request On BizBen 
 
 Sell A Fast Food Restaurant Or Orange County Business, Place An Ad On BizBen Today 
 

 
Orange County Regional News&amp;Tips For Buying And Selling Businesses
 
 First-Time Business Buyers - What You Need To Know - Advise From Broker Ash Rasaei 
Making the transition from worker bee to small business owner involves a great deal of time, effort, money, and personal commitment. It is not a decision to be made hastily nor taken lightly. Ash Rasaei (310-622-8777) a Los Angeles area business broker discusses what first time buyers should know before buying a small business.
 


 Midas Franchise Has Franchise Resales Available In California - More Locations Just Announced 
Midas Franchise has listed numerous franchise resales on BizBen recently. Go to all Midas Franchise for sale - and see the most current list of franchise resales now available to California business buyers. No auto repair experience required. For more information you can also phone Barbara Korus at Midas at 877-890-5874 - check out the Midas list of California franchise resales before phoning her.
 


 CPA Willard Michlin Explores Why Business Buyers Get Into Trouble With Due Diligence Issues 
Willard Michlin - CPA, CFE chats about why you can do a large portion of the due diligence yourself, depending on your background, but you should never try to do it solely on your own. In this BizBen Blog he explores ways business buyers get themselves into trouble. Read his latest BizBen blog posting on due-diligence issues for business buyers - read this blog post before you buy a business!
 


 Selling Your Note After You Sell Your Business - Article By Lee Petsas, Business Broker 
One option of for owners selling a business is to take back a note - assist in the business purchase by financing the transaction. Lee Petsas, a business broker in Orange County explains this strategy and how it can help sell a business and get the deal done. Go to this article at Selling Your Note After You Sell Your Business and get the facts about seller carry note financing.
 

 
Orange County Regional Upcoming Events
 
 Southern California Laundry Seminar - How To Buy A Laundromat Workshop Schedule 
Looking to buy a Southern California card or coin laundromat? PWS Laundry is presenting their next Los Angeles, Southern California seminar Thursdays: May 17th, June 21st, July 19th. For details go to  How To Buy A Southern California Laundromat Seminar - To RSVP call 323-721-8832.
 


 Workshop Schedule: Build Wealth And Secure Your Future by Buying And Selling Businesses 
Build wealth and secure your future by learning how to buy and sell businesses at Global Perspective’s upcoming workshops located in the business district of Century City (Los Angeles County). The workshops are informative step-by-step instructional courses designed to give you the knowledge, material and structure needed to financially change your life. For more info call 888-222-8920 or go to workshop for buyers and sellers for upcoming schedule, workshop outline,&amp;RSVP instructions.
 

 
Orange County Regional Businesses Wanted To Buy
 
 Buyers Seek San Francisco Breakfast Restaurant (Or Restaurant That Can Be Converted) 
We are looking for a small San Francisco restaurant that can be opened as a breakfast restaurant. The restaurant can provide 25 to 40 seats, dish washing machine, a small storage, hood, grill, refrigerator space, a restroom. Any location in San Francisco that considered as a good area for a breakfast business, such as area is around by hotels, downtown, financial district. The price range we are looking for is $80,000 to $100,000. We all have been working in restaurants as server and chef in thai restaurants and breakfast restaurant for 6 to 10 years. Expected-income per day ( included expenses) should be about $1,000 to $1,500. For details about these buyers - their contact information, etc. log into your BizBen Account.
 


 Buyer Seeks Orange County Business To Puchase - Up To $150K Available For Down Payment 
 I am a retired insurance agent with Allstate insurance co. I owned an agency for 43 years. I would like to supplement my income with an active business outside of the insurance industry due to a noncompete clause. The down payment would be a max of $150,000. I live in Orange County. And this is where i feel the need to purchase. I would like to supplement my income by $5,000 per month. For more information regarding this business buyer log into your BizBen Account.
 


 Motivated Business Buyer Seeks Home Health Care Agency Or Health Care Service 
Buyer seeks home health care agency with an annual adjusted net income of $180K+. Ideally the business should be located in Southern California, but will purchase outside of Southern California if the right deal presents itself. Buyer has high credit score and is looking to purchase a business immediately, and has been pre-qualified for SBA financing. Contact buyer direct. For buyer contact info and details, log into your BizBen Account.
 


 Business Buyer Seeks Financial Advisory Company In LA County (Or Can Be Relocated) 
Buyer looking to buy a financial advisory businesss in the Los Angeles County Area or one that can be relocated to his area. Buyer has $150K for a down payment (cash), has approximately $150 in available home equity, and is looking for a financial advisory business priced between $500K and $700K. Has direct work experience in this industry and has been SBA Pre-Qualified for financing. Buyer seeks to acquire this type of business immediately. Please log into your BizBen Account to see more info about this buyer and their contact information.
 

 
More Orange County Information For Buying&amp;Selling Orange County Businesses


 Orange County Resources - Services Needed When Buying/Selling A Business Orange County Business Brokers - Brokers&amp;Agents That Service Orange County Orange County New Franchise Opportunities - New Start-Up Franchises Available Orange County Franchise Resales - Established Franchise Resales For Sale Orange County New Business Opportunities - Opportunities, Licensing Ventures 

 
 Close 
Fast Food Restaurant Business Opportunity For Sale, Orange County, California, CA | BizBen

 
 Email This Info To An Associate Or Friend required fields   
 Your Name: Your Email: To Name: To Email: Subject Comments:
 Enter any questions or comments in this field. HTML tags will be deleted.   Send myself a copy/email as well   
  or Cancel 
 
 
     Email     Print 
 Let BizBen expert advisors
provide the support you
need to successfully buy or
sell a California business.
 Let us help you create a
custom strategy: 
 Advertising&amp;
Selling A Business 

 Searching&amp;
Buying A Business 

 Business Network
Solutions 
 
 
 Need Assistance?
888-212-4747
866-270-6278
 
 
 
 Send an email
to BizBen.com 
   
 
 
 Questions? Check
out our FAQs . 
 
Sell Your
Small Business
 
BizBen connects you with thousands of buyers who use BizBen exclusively when looking to buy a business in California.
 
 
 
 
New Listings

Sign up for new listings via email.
Subscribe now!
	</body>
</document>
