<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003122" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Algoma/The-Captains-Table-Restaurant" time="2012-07-12-19:14" support="1" score="0.002050935497910963" bingtitle="The Captains Table Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant Algoma, WI" webtitle="The Captains Table Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant  Algoma, WI">
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>The Captains Table Restaurant a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 133 N Water St in Algoma, WI. ... clerk Matthew Bacon went to a Fulton restaurant and had drinks ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
The Captains Table
Restaurant

 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(920) 487-5304

 
 WI &gt; Algoma &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim The Captains Table Restaurant listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by The Captains Table Restaurant to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About The Captains Table Restaurant
 The Captains Table Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located at 133 N Water St in Algoma, WI . The Captains Table Restaurant has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, American, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for The Captains Table Restaurant
 
 
 
All Reviews for The Captains Table Restaurant


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about The Captains Table Restaurant:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
The Captains Table Restaurant News
 Call Sheet #171: New Convention Center for New York?, Digital Marketing Tips, Marshmallows Are In Lillie&apos;s Q will become a Mexican restaurant ... news from BizBash.com. BD Staffing – Events&amp;Catering has been around in New York City for nearly a decade. BD Staffing provides only the most seasoned, top-notch hospitality staff, including captains ... Go! Bars&amp;Clubs calendar: Jan. 6-12 Captain&apos;s Table — Four ... Erie Hotel&amp;Restaurant — Friends of Mine, 1 Jersey Ave., Port Jervis, 9 p.m. Jan. 6, no cover. Also: Emish, 9 p.m. Jan. 7. 856-6325. www.theeriehotel.com. The Falcon — New Zion Trio, 1348 Route 9W, Marlboro ... New Year&apos;s weekend events ROK Vegas: featuring Captains of Industry, tickets start at $125 and include open bar 9 p.m.-midnight; table ... Mermaid Restaurant&amp;Lounge and Shady Grove Lounge, 9:30 p.m.-12:30 a.m. at 3333 Blue Diamond Road (263-7777). Grand Ballroom: New Year&apos;s ... Oswego County&apos;s 11 Most Read Stories of 2011 After the meeting, Williams and deputy clerk Matthew Bacon went to a Fulton restaurant and had drinks ... including construction of the Captain’s Quarters, in Oswego; and a hodge podge of new businesses moved into Canal Commons, also in ... Go! Bars&amp;Clubs calendar: Dec. 30-Jan. 5 Also: New Year&apos;s Eve party with Cloudnyne, 10 p.m. Dec. 31. Also: Karaoke, 9:30 p.m. Jan. 4. 567-9429. Captain&apos;s Table — In the Pocket ... Erhardt&apos;s Waterfront Restaurant — Abbey Road, 205 County Route 507, Hawley, Pa., 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing New York City Restaurants | OpenTable Find Hot New Restaurants Near You! Earn Free Meals Faster - 1,000-Point Tables; Michelin Guide 2012 NY Star Recipients; Find New York Area Private Dining Venues Travel - Guides and Deals for Hotels, Restaurants and Vacations ... Expert travel advice for destinations around the world from The New York Times, including hotel, restaurant, and vacation tips and deals. New York Restaurants and Recipes - NYC Dining and Chefs - New York ... A weekly guide to the New York restaurant scene -- from restaurant openings to reviews to recipes. Search more than 3500 restaurants by cuisine, price, neighborhood ... New York Magazine -- NYC Guide to Restaurants, Fashion, Nightlife ... Daily coverage of New York&apos;s restaurants, nightlife, shopping, fashion, politics, and culture. NYMag.com is the online counterpart to New York Magazine. Restaurant Week in New York City - Official Information About NYC ... New York Eats The City offers everything from cheap meal on the fly to an elegant experience at one of the world&apos;s most famous restaurants. Must-Try Sandwiches 
Related Video
	</body>
</document>
