<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003659" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/in-n-out-burger-never-out-7090.html" time="2012-07-12-19:49" support="1" score="0.0018896338622365837" bingtitle="In-N-Out Burger is Never In and Out - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com" webtitle="In-N-Out Burger is Never In and Out - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>I think they should change their name to avoid ... After 23 minutes had transgressed, my food arrived ... Sometimes you simply must stop at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
In-N-Out Burger is Never In and Out
 SMB , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Sep 9, 2005 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food In-n-out Burger In-n-out Burger 
 Flag Close Post a comment In-N-Out Burger is never in and out. The lines are so long. I think they should change their name to avoid being sued for false advertising.
My last visit to the In-N-Out hamburger stand was just like any other. I waited in line. I ordered my burger and fries, and then I waited... and waited... and waited. Eighteen minutes went by before I had the nerve to let them know that I didn&apos;t appreciate being misled. Waiting 18 minutes for fast food is not In-N-Out.

After 23 minutes had transgressed, my food arrived hot and savory. Afterall, that&apos;s why people go to In-N-Out. They have the best fast food burgers on the market. Their fries come from fresh potatoes and are diced on site. There is a reason the wait is so long. It&apos;s because the food is good and affordably priced. I love going there!

What I don&apos;t like is waiting 23 minutes for a hamburger at an In-N-Out fast food joint. That&apos;s just bad advertising, and the chain is lucky they haven&apos;t encountered a lawsuit so far for false advertising. It might be time to modify.

Modifying is a serious business for the Snyder family, owners of the In-N-Out hamburger chain. They&apos;ve had the same menu for over 50 years. They&apos;ve always been privately owned and they have never franchised any units. Their principles have taken them to the top of the fast food business and I applaud them for it. In-N-Out salaries are very competitive, the service is always outstanding, and the 50&apos;s style is a refreshing blast from the past. The problem is that the amount of business they do could seriously turn them into the joke of the game.

If I know the Synders, I know that they are a tough family and willing to endure a little cornballing, but this is the founding principle. It&apos;s the name! They have to protect it&apos;s integrity.

How they go about protecting it is beyond my estimation. The attack is light hearted, a mere crack in an otherwise cemented foundation, but all that crack needs to become one giant hole is somebody who doesn&apos;t take it so lightly; somebody who sees it as an opportunity to capitalize beyond a point of fascination. I prey for In-N-Out. I don&apos;t want to see some no good scoundrel squeeze them because their business is so good and they don&apos;t know how to market it!
 
Published by SMB 

@  View profile 
 
 What Kind of Fast Food Tonight? Ever notice that the fast food places used to have really good food in the beginning Fast Food Calories: Where to Find Them This article helps you find fast food calorie information in your area and compare meals Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Sometimes you simply must stop at a fast food restaurant. But you don&apos;t have to ruin your diet! There are a few healthy options at most fast food joints. Eat Fast Food and Still Be Healthy There are ways to still enjoy the occasional helping of fast food while still eating healthily. Fast Food Failures What if someone put together a list of all the really bad fast food restaurants? What if that someone was me? 
 
 Burger King Versus In-and-Out Burger Restaurant Review: IN-N-OUT Burger Review and History of In-N-Out Burger In-N-Out VS. McDonald&apos;s A Review of In-N-Out Burgers in Rohnert Park, California Restaurant Review: In-N-Out - the Cult of the Hamburger Fast Food is Everywhere in CA 
 
 
 
 Takeaways 
 
 In-N-Out is never in and out In-N-Out has the best In-N-Out&apos;s founding principle, their name, could come back to haunt them for false advertising 
 
2 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Jones&apos;n for In-and-Out 7/10/2007 
Service and quality are fantastic! It&apos;s whining, master degree, educated yuppie morons like you that always find something to complain about. So what if you have to wait once in a while. Perhaps you should count your blessings because you live in a free country that has a fantastic business like In-and-Out.
 GabbaDj 4/1/2007 
You must be a Jew. Only Jews complain like you do.
 
 Displaying Comments 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
