<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003548" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080318230739AASY4kf" time="2012-07-12-19:41" support="2" score="0.002549121834576771" bingtitle="Umm condoms, help please? - Yahoo!7 Answers" webtitle="Umm condoms, help please? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>I think most drugstores have a good selection. Do ... If you don&apos;t want to be seen by the cashier ... place else you can think of besides a fast food restaurant. 3 ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Pregnancy&amp;Parenting &gt; Teen&amp;Preteen &gt; Resolved Question 
 hani ♥ Member since: 04 February 2008 Total points: 244 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Umm condoms, help please?
 OKay me and my boyfriend are going to have sex. Hes 15 and im 14, now dont bother to be like oh your too young bah blah blah we are sweethearts and we love eachother. It was both our decision. Where can i buy condoms and how much? will they let me buy them&gt; 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by bailezra Member since: 22 February 2008 Total points: 35,983 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Yes, you can buy condoms.

But if you are really intent on having sex, might I recommend that the two of you pay a visit to Planned Parenthood for a consultation before you do anything? They can educate you about the different forms of birth control that are available, teach you how to use condoms properly, and teach you how to take responsibility for your own body. They usually have free condoms, as well.

I do think that 14 is too young, but I doubt anything anyone says here will convince you of that, even the pregnant 14 year-olds. So if you are determined to have sex with your boyfriend, please make sure you are on reliable birth control and that you know how to use it. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 40% 2 Votes 
 10 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Umm condoms, help pl… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (21)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Robert P Member since: 05 March 2008 Total points: 1,390 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 considoring your white trash there prolly to expensive so dont bother. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 15 people rated this as good 
 by C N Member since: 24 February 2008 Total points: 19,767 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yeah you can buy them at any drug store or walmart, kmart, etc... usually near the pharmacy(right in front of the pharmacy counter,,, cause they get stolen so much) you can also go to the health department and get a bagfull for free, if youre in the US. If you buy them, expect to pay about a buck apiece. usually in packs of 3 or 12. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by penis_bl... Member since: 16 September 2007 Total points: 2,601 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 dependsing on where you live.. but they are usually available in a supermarket, drugstore,roadhouse/servo, or even in public toilets.

an here in AUS they cost about $8 for a pack of 12, but this varies.

goodluck!

xx 
Source(s):
 experience 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Janneth *19yr.old mommy&amp;wife* Member since: 20 May 2007 Total points: 1,394 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You can get them at pretty much every store. The times I&apos;ve bought condoms I think they were like $ 4 for a pack of three. The important thing is that you are being safe. If you feel uncomfortable at a store you can also go to a family planning clinic and they&apos;ll give them to you for free. Hope this helps=) 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Jordan&amp;sarah Member since: 18 August 2007 Total points: 171 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You can get them at wal-mart. I dont really know how much they are but i know they are not to high. 
Source(s):
 Mother of 2! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by manda Member since: 20 June 2006 Total points: 1,508 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Are you ready to have a child? I volunteer at a clinic for teen mothers and the one thing i hear from every single person is that they thought they were in love and then they guy ran off after they had sex, and now i know you&apos;re thinking yeath that was them but we are truly in love. Thats exactly what they thought. This is a big thing you can only give up your virginity once. Why not wait until your married? Give that specail gift to your husband. Please reconsider! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 6 people rated this as good 
 by sizesmit... Member since: 26 December 2007 Total points: 17,536 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Hello,
As a mother I&apos;d give the talk but, I want you to be protected, and commend you for using birth control methods. Please realize that sometimes they don&apos;t work, and you should also seek another form of birth control.

Yes, you can buy them at any pharmacy or department store. At the pharmacy department, they will sell them to you, be discreet about it, and they will be wrapped in a white bag which will hide them a little better so not to advertise. Also, you can go to the health office, which will provide you with free ones, and they will also provide spermicide free.

If you are really in a hurry, simply take some quarters into most convenience store restrooms, where they sell them in vending machines. Make sure you get one that is for pregnancy and disease protection, as they also sell some that are designed funny for pleasure, like a french tickler, but those are more prone to break, and are not as good.

Prices: at Walmart, around 7-18 dollars/box
Department of Health-discreet&amp;free
convenience store-$ .75-$1.00 in quarters

Be careful, and remember that just because you use a condom doesn&apos;t mean you won&apos;t get pregnant nor does it mean you won&apos;t catch an STD. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Elizabeth S Member since: 03 January 2008 Total points: 2,131 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yeah you can buy them at any drug store or walmart, kmart, etc... usually near the pharmacy(right in front of the pharmacy counter,,, cause they get stolen so much) you can also go to the health department and get a bagfull for free, 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Alex&apos;s mommy Member since: 13 March 2008 Total points: 1,648 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You love each other?
I don&apos;t think that word is even available for your age to say,
love is a BIG word, and life is LONG.
use it wisely,

just because he wants in your pants doesn&apos;t mean its love sweetheart.


PS, if i was your mother i would SUE each and everyone of these people telling a FOURTEEN YEAR OLD where to buy condoms. 
Source(s):
 ps, you cant just buy condoms. If you look your age, its a no go. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by jimmbobb Member since: 06 February 2008 Total points: 6,946 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 . That&apos;s a Very mature, Responsible attitude! Good.
I do NOT recommend the truck stop vending machines. You don&apos;t know how old or cheap the rubbers are.
I think most drugstores have a good selection. Do NOT get the 24-pac for $10&apos;cause they ARE cheap and will leak.
Some large grocery stores have them. ALWAYS check the&apos;Expiration Date&apos;. If the cashier gives you Any trouble, just say you want to speak to the Manager, NOW. The rubbers are for your sister, maybe.
Check the sites below&gt;&gt;&gt; 
Source(s):
 http://www.condomdepot.com/reviews/best-… , http://www.slate.com/id/2114132/ , 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Keith Member since: 11 February 2008 Total points: 1,421 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 better hope that condom don&apos;t break and you get knocked up. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by MeL Member since: 11 March 2008 Total points: 4,244 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Y DO U NEED TO HAVE SEX TO BE IN LOVE. YOUR ONLI 14 IT MITE NOT EVEN LAST 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 5 people rated this as good 
 by Roger Z Member since: 07 February 2008 Total points: 318 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 If you don&apos;t want to be seen by the cashier...just order them online if you&apos;re allowed to have a debit card or send an online check...however, go to a town where no one knows you and buy condoms there, therefore no suspecting people can catch you lol 
Source(s):
 www.trojan.com 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by mCfLyRcKmYeArDrUmS =] Member since: 17 January 2008 Total points: 3,475 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Theres no age limit on buying condoms but you can get them in pub toilets (for a more discreet purchase) and from chemists. i think if you go to a clinic and tell them your gonna have sex then they&apos;ll give you free condoms, both femi and male. =] 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by alien Member since: 20 February 2008 Total points: 2,765 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 you can get them from your doctor for free and you don&apos;t have to tell your parents about it. go with a friend or together. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by helene Member since: 27 July 2007 Total points: 125,559 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 Okay, you&apos;re not only going to give him sex, you&apos;re going to buy and pay for the condoms too? What is HE going to do, other than get off?

HE can buy them in any drugstore, convenience store, gas station, etc. It&apos;s the least he can do.

. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Robert O Member since: 14 January 2008 Total points: 3,151 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You can buy them anywhere. At a Target store, gas station, Walmart, and just about any place else you can think of besides a fast food restaurant. 3 pack for 4 dollars. Have fun and enjoy 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by dylandud... Member since: 09 January 2007 Total points: 801 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yah i highly doubt there gonna let a 14 year old walk into a shop and buy condoms, and u 2 just teenagers, your minds our clouded, the word love is just blinding u ur probably not gonna be together anyway,

PS, if i was your mother i would SUE each and everyone of these people telling a FOURTEEN YEAR OLD where to buy condoms.&lt;---- ahahaha thats a funny comment.

and just because both of you are excited about it and say yes doesnt mean its the right thing, and no, they will not let u buy them. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by thapinkd... Member since: 29 February 2008 Total points: 185 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yes you can buy condoms, and you should .. but if you don&apos;t even know basic information like where to buy them, (at any store Duh) .. keep those stank legs closed 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by me. Yeah. =] Member since: 27 February 2008 Total points: 1,561 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Most grocery store and gas stations sell them, but I&apos;m not sure how much, i think its under 5 dollars though, and some hospitals give them away for free. There is no age limit to purchasing condoms, you could buy them if you were 2. They can&apos;t deny you the right to protect yourself. Good Luck! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Pauly W Member since: 15 February 2006 Total points: 68,593 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You are way too young to have sex, whether you use comdoms or not. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Teen&amp;Preteen 

 All this money I&apos;m paying for college it better be worth it? Whats the next step? mom conversation gone wrong? What are the engineers called that design trains and their transportation? Help please I&apos;m 16 and my mom died ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 
 Adoption Baby Names Newborn&amp;Baby Other - Pregnancy&amp;Parenting Parenting Pregnancy Primary Schooler Teen&amp;Preteen Toddler&amp;Preschooler Trying to Conceive 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Jonathan R 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
