<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003048" url="http://studentoffortune.com/question/909466/Chapter-1-END-OF-CHAPTER-AND-APPENDIX-QUEDSTIONS" time="2012-07-12-19:09" support="3" score="0.014221183142468133" bingtitle="Chapter 1 END-OF-CHAPTER AND APPENDIX QUEDSTIONS ..." webtitle="Chapter 1 END-OF-CHAPTER AND APPENDIX QUEDSTIONS - StudentOfFortune.com">
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="113"/>
	<description>$10.00 Chapter 1 END-OF-CHAPTER AND APPENDIX ... rather than the customers) observed at a fast-food restaurant. ... Rearrange these data into a meaningful order and ...</description>
	<body>
		Question 
 $10.00 Chapter 1 END-OF-CHAPTER AND APPENDIX QUEDSTIONS 
 ISBN: 9780073365 
 Book Title: College Accounting Student Edition Chapters 1-24 
 Book Author: John Price, M. David Haddock, Michael Farina,
 Found in Business : General-Business 
 Chapter 1 , # 0
 Posted by : intelligentsia 
 Rating ( 3 ): A- 
 Questions Asked: 0
 Tutorials Posted: 140,
 Blog Posts:  1,
Earned: $376.07     Q: 
 1-1“Buy 2, get 1 free.”Explain why the“1 free”is free to the buyer but not to society. 

 1-2 What is meant by the term“utility”and how does it relate to the economic perspective? 

 1-3 Cite three examples of recent decisions that you made in which you, at least implicitly, weighed marginal costs and marginal benefits. 

 1-4 ( Key Question ) Use the economic perspective to explain why someone who is normally a light eater at a standard restaurant may become somewhat of a glutton at a buffet-style restaurant which charges a single price for all you can eat. 

 1-5 What is the scientific method and how does it relate to theoretical economics? What is the difference between a hypothesis and an economic law or principle? 

 1-6 Why is it significant that economics is not a laboratory science? What problems may be involved in deriving and applying economic principles? 

 1-7 Explain the following statements: 

 a.“Good economic policy requires good economic theory.” 

 b.“Generalization and abstraction are nearly synonymous.” 

 c.“Facts serve to sort out good and bad hypotheses.” 

 d.“The other things equal assumption helps isolate key economic relationships.” 

 1-8 ( Key Question ) Explain in detail the interrelationships between economic facts, theory, and policy. Critically evaluate this statement:“The trouble with economic theory is that it is not practical. It is detached from the real world.” 

 1-9 To what extent do you accept the eight economic goals stated and described in this chapter? What priorities would you assign to them? 

 1-10 ( Key Question ) Indicate whether each of the following statements applies to microeconomics or macroeconomics: 

 1-11 ( Key Question ) Identify each of the following as either a positive or a normative statement: 

 1-12 ( Key Question ) Explain and give an illustration of (a) the fallacy of composition; and (b) the“after this, therefore because of this”fallacy. Why are cause-and-effect relationships difficult to isolate in the social sciences? 

 1-13 Suppose studies show that students who study more hours receive higher grades. Does this relationship guarantee that any particular student who studies longer will get higher grades? 

 1-14 Studies indicate that married men on average earn more income than unmarried men of the same age. Why must we be cautious in concluding that marriage is the cause and higher income is the effect ? 

 1-15 ( Last Word ) Use the economic perspective to explain the behavior of the workers (rather than the customers) observed at a fast-food restaurant. Why are these workers there, rather than, say cruising around in their cars? Why do they work so diligently? Why do so many of them quit these jobs once they have graduated high school? 

Chapter 1 - Appendix

1-1 Briefly explain the use of graphs as a way to present economic relationships. What is an inverse relationship? How does it graph? What is a direct relationship? How does it graph? Graph and explain the relationships you would expect to find between (a) the number of inches of rainfall per month and the sale of umbrellas, (b) the amount of tuition and the level of enrollment at a university, and (c) the popularity of a music artist and the price of her concert tickets. 

 1-2 ( Key Question ) Indicate how each of the following might affect the data shown in Table 2 and Figure 2 of this appendix: 

 1-3 ( Key Question ) The following table contains data on the relationship between saving and income. Rearrange these data into a meaningful order and graph them on the accompanying grid. What is the slope of the line? The vertical intercept? Interpret the meaning of both the slope and the intercept. Write the equation which represents this line. What would you predict saving to be at the $12,500 level of income? 

 1-4 Construct a table from the following data shown on the accompanying graph. Which is the dependent variable and which the independent variable? Summarize the data in equation form. 

 1-5 Suppose that when the interest rate is 16 percent, businesses find it unprofitable to invest in machinery and equipment. However, when the interest rate is 14 percent, $5 billion worth of investment is profitable. At 12 percent interest, a total of $10 billion of investment is profitable. Similarly, total investment increases by $5 billion for each successive 2-percentage point decline in the interest rate. Describe the relevant relationship between the interest rate and investment in words, in a table, graphically, and as an equation. Put the interest rate on the vertical axis and investment on the horizontal axis, and in your equation use the form i = a + bI, where i is the interest rate, a is the vertical intercept, b is the slope of the line (which is negative), and I is the level of investment. Comment on the advantages and disadvantages of the verbal, tabular, graphic, and equation forms of description. 

 1-6 Suppose that C = a + bY , where C = consumption, a = consumption at zero income, b = slope, and Y = income. 

 a. Are C and Y positively related or are they negatively related? 

 b. If graphed, would the curve for this equation slope upward or downward? 

 c. Are the variables C and Y inversely related or directly related? 

 d. What is the value of C if a =10, b =.50, and Y = 200? 

 e. What is the value of Y if C = 100, a = 10, and b = .25? 

 1-7 ( Key Question ) The accompanying graph shows curve XX and tangents at points A , B , and C . Calculate the slope of the curve at these three points. 

 1-8 In the accompanying graph, is the slope of curve AA ’positive or negative? Does the slope increase or decrease as we move along the curve from A to A ’? Answer the same two questions for curve BB ’. 

 
 

 
 

 
 
   
     
     
     
     Tutorial   $10.00 Chapter 1 END-OF-CHAPTER AND APPENDIX QUEDSTIONS
 This tutorial hasn&apos;t been purchased yet. Posted on Feb. 26, 2011 at 09:55:16AM 
 A: Preview: ... ached ...

 The full tutorial is about 5 words long plus attachments . 
 
 Attachments: 
 Lecture Notes 1.doc (111K)  ( Preview ) 
 

     
   
 Home 
   
 Get Tutoring 
   
 Get Paid 
 
   
 
 Home 
 | 
 Blog 
 | 
 Fees 
 | 
 FAQ 
 
 
 
 Ask a Question 
 | 
 How Does This Work? 
 | 
 Recent Tutorials 
 | 
 Topics 
 
 
 
 Upload a Tutorial 
 | 
 See Recent Questions 
 | 
 Browse Questions 
 | 
 Affiliate Program 
 
       Blog | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Press | Frequently Asked Questions | Contact Us | Affiliates | Sitemap | About Us 
 Cheap Textbooks | Chegg Coupon 
Copyright©Student Of Fortune, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
