<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003447" url="http://www.imaginecountertops.ca/OurProducts/DuPontCorian/tabid/1011/Default.aspx" time="2012-07-12-19:36" support="1" score="0.002412518001711745" bingtitle="DuPont Corian - Imagine Countertops &gt; Home" webtitle="DuPont Corian">
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Largest Selection in the Valley ... lots of banks and trust companies, most fast food restaurant ... can be easily removed and all joints in the counters ...</description>
	<body>
		Our Products » DuPont Corian Login   |   
 Largest Selection in the Valley 
 


 IMAGINE COUNTERTOPS Inc. 

 675 Willow Park Road 

 Kelowna, British Columbia, V1X 5H9 

 Phone: 250-765-1677 

 Fax: 250-765-1877 

 Email: Info@imaginecountertops.ca 

 www.imaginecountertops.ca 
          Visit Our Photo Gallery 
 
 
 
 
        
 
 Solid Surface Countertops 
 Corian®, which was developed by DuPont™ over 40 years ago is the original solid surface material. With over 120 colours Corian is easily the leading solid surface product on the market today. As a  DuPont certified fabricator/installer (CFI) as well as a DuPont certified Corian &quot;Warranty Centre&quot;, we have been fabricating Corian for over 20 years. 

 Corian® can be a good fit for both residential and commercial projects. We have installed Corian® in many commercial projects in British Columbia such as the Kelowna International Airport, Williams Lake Library (Williams Lake, BC), McGill Library (Burnaby, BC), Surrey Sportsplex (Surrey, BC), Orchard Park Mall (Kelowna, BC), many different dental and medical facilities, many condo projects, lots of banks and trust companies, most fast food restaurant chains, to name just a few. 

 Corian® countertops by DuPont™ are a non-porous alternative to granite. The nature of Corian® allows us to be the most creative with this product compared to quartz, granite, or laminate materials. Corian® has the ability to be cut, routed, drilled, sculpted, bent, sand blasted, or worked like a fine wood. Corian® requires no sealing, is heat resistant, easy to clean, and impenetrable by mold, mildew and bacteria. Scratches and stains in the counters can be easily removed and all joints in the counters appear virtually seamless. 

 Because it is 100% non-porous Corian® is ideally suited for both health care and food preparation areas. It has an NSF (National Sanitation Foundation) 5.1 certification as a safe material for these environments. 

 Corian® is the hands down leader in the solid surface industry. Many products have tried to copy it but none have succeeded. Corian® is a blend of natural minerals and acrylic resin. It was invented by DuPont™ during the 1970s. Ideal for hundreds of uses Corian® is most widely used for food service applications and other places where sanitation is critical. Mold, mildew, bacteria, salmonella, and staining aren&apos;t an issue with Corian® . Corian® is widely used in the health care industry, again for its hygienic properties.

The acceptance of Corian® has literally exploded in the past dozen years. Many customers are replacing kitchen countertops which originally were made of laminates such as Formica®, Arborite®, or Wilsonart® for example. These tops may have chipped or simply worn over the years. While it is difficult to damage or harm Corian® it is also easily repaired.

We feel the main advantages to Corian® is that it is non-porous (hygienic) and seamless in appearance. And with its large variety of colours and patterns to choose from there is bound to be a colour for any decorating taste.

One of the other big advantages of using Corian® is its array of integral sinks, both for kitchens, vanities, or bars. There are over 30 sinks and styles to choose from. The sinks also come with the DuPont™ Corian® 10 year residential warranty.

Besides countertops, there are many other applications for Corian® , including window sills, table tops, cabinet doors, fireplace fascia&apos;s, patio tables, shower stalls, and tub surrounds. These are just some of the more common applications. Corian® can be shaped into just about any configuration and is possibly the most versatile countertop material on the market. You are only limited by your imagination. Coloured inlays, integral drainboards, hot rod trivets, a large variety of edge profiles and backsplash options are all available. We can even include a logo right in the surface. Corian® can also be thermoformed, meaning that we can heat it in one of our two ovens and shape it to your needs. 

Visit http://www.corian.com/ for more information.

 

 Corian® &quot;Care&amp; Maintenance&quot;: 

The following is meant to be a simple overview. For more details on Corian® care or other items, visit http://www.corian.com/ .

In most cases warm water and soap or an ammonia based cleaner is all that is required. Rinse and wipe completely dry, otherwise a film might form on the surface if water is left to dry on the countertop. This film will dull the look of the countertop making the finish appear blotchy and uneven. See &quot;General Cleaning&quot; below.

 General Cleaning: Use soapy water, ammonia based cleaner (not window cleaner), rinse and wipe completely dry. Solid surface cleaners, such as Clean EnCounters® or Countertop Magic® will also work well. These are usually available at your local hardware stores.

 Preventing Hard Water Marks: Rinse and wipe completely dry after cleaning. Clean up spills before they dry.

 Disinfecting: Occasionally, wipe surface with diluted household bleach (1 part water/1 part bleach). Rinse top thoroughly with water and wipe completely dry.

 Corian® Sinks&amp;Lavatories: Follow procedures above or use Soft Scrub® and a green Scotch-Brite® pad to remove residue. Rub the green Scotch-Brite® pad over entire sink to blend in finish. Note: Do Not use Scotch-Brite® on the countertop surface. It may dull your finish, which may then have to be re-sanded to bring your finish back.

To disinfect your sink, fill your sink 1/4 full with diluted household bleach (1 part water/1 part bleach). Be sure to get some of the solution into the overflow opening to disinfect. Let the solution stay in the sink for 15 minutes; then wash sides and bottom as solution drains. Rinse out the sink with water. Caution: Avoid getting the bleach solution in your eyes or bare skin. Always follow the bleach manufacturer&apos;s safety instructions when working with bleach. 

To enhance the gloss level on semi-gloss and high-gloss finishes, use a countertop polish such as Countertop Magic®, Hope&apos;s Countertop Polish® or Enhance Countertop Polish®.

 Preventing Heat Damage 

While Corian® is heat resistant, as with all countertop materials, it is important to minimize direct heat exposure to protect your surface and investment.

 Do Not Place Hot Pots, Pans, etc. Directly On any Countertop Surface. Use common sense. Always use heat trivets or hot pads when placing hot objects on any surface . Always use a trivet under portable heat generating appliances such as a toaster oven. Allow cookware to cool before placing it into a Corian® sink.



 Preventing Other Damage 

 In most cases Corian® can be repaired if damaged. Be sure to follow these guidelines to help you prevent any permanent damage to your Corian®.

 Avoid getting strong chemicals, such as paint removers, oven cleaners, etc., on your Corian® countertop. If a spill does occur, promptly flush the surface with water to fully rinse off the chemical. Do not cut directly on Corian® countertops. Use a cutting board. Frequent cutting directly on a Corian® countertop is not recommended, although scratches from occasional cutting can be renewed or repaired. Like most materials, darker colours of Corian® will show wear easier than lighter colours. We do not generally recommend dark colours of Corian® for high use areas. If you require more information or advice on this please contact us. 

 

 Advantages of DuPont Corian®: 

 Well over 100 colours and patterns to choose from. Non-porous and therefore 100% hygienic. NSF (National Sanitation Foundation) 5.1 Certification for food preparation areas. Never needs sealing. Corian® seams are inconspicuous, if not invisible, unlike quartz and natural stones. Corian® allows for the most creativity with such options as Integral sinks, integral backsplashes,&amp;inlays. Unlike quartz and natural stones Corian® can easily be repaired if damaged. Scratches or other marks are easily removed. Consistent colour throughout the material so no need to select a specific slab as in natural stones. Corian® offers a 10 year manufacturer’s warranty. Corian® can add to the value ($) of your home and is therefore a great investment. 
          Corian Color Samples 
     

 
 
 New Colors  (7 Photos) 
 
 
 Beiges  (12 Photos) 
 
 
 Extra Darks  (9 Photos) 
 
 
 Naturals  (14 Photos) 
 
 
 Extra Lights  (13 Photos) 
 
 
 Warms  (12 Photos) 
 
 
 Yellow Greens  (8 Photos) 
 
 
 Private Collection  (8 Photos) 
 
 
 Greens  (8 Photos) 
 
 
 Blues  (13 Photos) 
 
 
 Grays  (9 Photos) 
 
 
 Brights  (5 Photos) 
 
          
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Copyright (c) 2012 Imagine Countertops 
 Privacy Statement | Terms Of Use
	</body>
</document>
