<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003444" url="http://www.mentalfloss.com/blogs/archives/40638" time="2012-07-12-19:35" support="1" score="0.0014052699030338877" bingtitle="Friday Happy Hour: Design Your Own Theme Restaurant - Mental Floss" webtitle="Friday Happy Hour: Design Your Own Theme Restaurant - Mental Floss">
			<query id="001071" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>- Collecting Grateful Dead bootlegs - Pictures of ... Japanese and Thai food, but the only utensils ... I’d either open a fast-food restaurant that only serves ...</description>
	<body>
		SUBSCRIBE &gt; 
 GIFT SUBSCRIPTIONS &gt; 
 DIGITAL SUBSCRIPTIONS &gt; 
 subscriber services &gt; Friday Happy Hour: Design Your Own Theme Restaurant 
 by Jason English - November 13, 2009 - 11:24 AM 
 Every Friday, I post a series of unrelated questions meant to spark conversation in the comments. Answer one, answer all, respond to someone else’s reply, whatever you want. Very casual. On to this week’s topics of discussion… 

 1. Congratulations! You’ve inherited a large sum of money from a distant relative you didn’t know existed. One catch, though—you must use a portion of your fortune to launch a chain of theme restaurants. (Your relative was a little out there.) What would your restaurant’s theme be? (You can pick a time in history, an obscure hobby, a different professional wrestling commentator, etc.)

(We’ll send a free mental_floss t-shirt to the most creative budding restaurateur.)

 2. Based on my (non-scientific) study, 96% of internet discussion revolves around hating things. (You’d be surprised how many YouTube videos there are featuring people blowing up Elmo dolls.) To provide a tiny bit of counterbalance, tell us about something you really like. Or several things. I’ll go first: this old apple farm called Wightman Farms in Morristown, New Jersey, Ivan Maisel’s college football podcast, and Ida Pearle’s customer service. (She designs prints for kids’rooms; ours arrived with a broken frame, and she has gone well above and way beyond to make it up to us.)

 3. Colleges are known for offbeat courses (See:“Goldberg’s Canon: Makin’Whoopi”), but occasionally I’ll hear stories about a high school teacher who just happened to have an expertise in something you wouldn’t normally teach high school kids, like soap opera history or running a haberdashery. What’s the weirdest class your high school offered? 

 4. I’ve mentioned before that one of my dream freelance jobs is running a pet-naming consultantcy. No progress on that front to date. So even though we’ve probably covered this topic before, what’s the strangest pet name you’ve ever heard? 

 [See all the previous Friday Happy Hour transcripts.] 
   comments Email This Post Share on Twitter Share on Facebook «Previous Post   -   Next Post» Click here to get a Risk-Free issue of mental_floss magazine PRIVACY POLICY 
 10 Lines From Napoleon’s Love Letters That Sound Like Crazy Texts 

 11 Product Names That Mean Unfortunate Things in Other Languages 

 11 Obscure Regional Phrases That Describe Excessive Heat 

 17 Famous Literary Characters Almost Named Something Else 

 A Brief History of the Wife Carrying World Championships 
 
 subscribe   /   give a gift   /   subscriber services   /   back issues   /   terms of service   /   about   /   contact us   /   write for us   /   ad info   /   press   /   privacy policy   /   rss   /  
 
©2012 Mental Floss Inc. All Rights Reserved. Mental Floss is a registered trademark owned by Felix Dennis. mentalfloss.com is a trademark owned by Felix Dennis.

Disclaimer: All submissions made to mental_floss become the property of Mental Floss Inc and may be used without further permission by the submitter and without compensation to the submitter. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not submit anything to mental_floss.
	</body>
</document>
