<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003874" url="http://www.wvgazette.com/News/PhilKabler/201111050142" time="2012-07-12-20:02" support="3" score="0.0033550986598670906" bingtitle="Statehouse Beat: Public safety concerns about East End work ..." webtitle="Statehouse Beat: Public safety concerns about East End work release center overblown- Phil Kabler - 
The Charleston Gazette - West Virginia News and Sports -">
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>If you eat at a fast-food restaurant or attend a catered event in ... have attended nearly 500 ball games at Power Park ... Credit Card Consolidation; Chicago Cubs Tickets; Reglan</description>
	<body>
		- HOMES | JOBS | CARS | CLASSIFIEDS | COUPONS | TV WEEKLY   GET CONNECTED 
 Home News Opinion Sports Life A&amp;E; Outdoors Blogs Multimedia Obituaries Celebrations 

 Contact us Search archives Page Reprints Getting Into Print Weather Our History Privacy Statement RSS Feeds Advertising Webcams »More blue AP Video News Politics Gazette Charities Business Police Blotter Watchdog News Columnists Putnam County Public records Special Reports Weird News Corrections Advisories »More blue Editorials Dawn Miller James A. Haught Robert J. Byers Op-Ed Commentaries Letters Readers voice »More blue WVU Marshall Prep Sports Sports Columnists Mountaineer Gameday That&apos;s racin&apos; Corrections Inside Marshall Sports blog Gazette Relays »More blue People Food&amp;Dining Gardening Fashion Home Travel Columns On the Town »More blue The Gazz Events Calendar Art Books Film Music Reviews Stage TV Video Games Fun&amp;Games TV Weekly Corrections FlipSide Blogs »More blue Hunting&amp;Fishing Recreation Columns John McCoy Woods and Waters blog Scott Shalaway »More blue Beers To You Coal Tattoo Inside Marshall Sports Karin Fuller Mountain Word Plugged In Pop Cult Squawk Box Sustained Outrage Wine Boy Woods and Waters WV Film »More blue NDN Video West Virginia Uncovered »More blue Read obituaries Place an obituary »More blue »More blue 
     
 This page requires javaScript to be fully functional. Please turn on your browser&apos;s scripting, or install a broswer with javaScript support. 
 
 This page requires javaScript to be fully functional. Please turn on your browser&apos;s scripting, or install a broswer with javaScript support. 
 Phil Kabler Share print | comments | email | letter to editor |
 size Tweet Pin It Send me a copy Your E-mail address: Recipient&apos;s E-Mail Address: Personal Message (Optional):
	</body>
</document>
