<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003339" url="http://samanthagowing.wordpress.com/2011/08/13/food-trends-for-2012/" time="2012-07-12-19:28" support="7" score="0.0278793495364198" bingtitle="Food Trends for 2012 « Samantha Gowing" webtitle="Food Trends for 2012Samantha Gowing">
			<query id="000063" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000091" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000088" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>Just like the “mini me”-omenon for fast food, restaurant menus need to dispense ... some raw space or services to allow for “pop up” restaurants or food ...</description>
	<body>
		Gidday Master Recipes Shop Stories Saminars Contact 
 
 Samantha Gowing 

~ Chef. Mentor. Writer. Speaker.
 Search: 
Food Trends for 2012

 13 Saturday Aug 2011 
 
Posted by Samantha Gowing in Food Trends , Intuition , Restaurants , Sustainability , Wellness 

 ≈ 1 Comment 
 Top Tip: How to use Food as Medicine 
 In 2012, look out for: 

 1. Artisan Foods 

Leave the discounting to the supermarkets – fresh food retailers in 2011 will benefit by focussing on the growth in high quality home cooking spurred by the many TV shows. Carrying artisan, locally crafted products with unique flavour profiles is a sure fire way to gain customer loyalty and increase visitation.

 2. The“Celebrity Grower” 

What happens when we run out of celebrity chefs? Time to roll out the celebrity supplier! Centres that quickly grasp and action this trend through using celebrity food producers for promotions and infotainment in Centre will quickly lead the pack as the preferred fresh food destination.

 3. Food Channel Knowledge 

Consumer demand for information on each product from paddock to plate will continue, and fresh food retailers need to understand and be able to answer questions on the food miles, sustainability, ingredients and organic status of their products in order to appeal to the new consumer.

 4.“Mini Size Me!” 

Super sizing is just so yesterday! Is it due to the GFC, the changing demographic as Gen Y becomes the most prolific fast food consumer group or are we all just too damn busy to stop and eat? Whatever, it is imperative that every fast food menu has a component of mini versions of the most popular products, available for an extended period of time (instead of just lunchtime), to capitalise on the new 24/7 demands of shoppers. Sales uplifts of 10-20% have been achieved by retailers implementing this strategy, as rather than the consumer“trading down”from a regular to a“mini”size, more customers are being attracted across a larger day part!

 5. Less Salt, More Flavour 

Demands for healthier foods will continue and the key to success here is to look for menu lines that are a flavour variation on core lines (vertical expansion) rather than looking for horizontal menu expansion. Emerging opportunities for niche cuisines (as long as they have great vertical depth) with at least 50 menu lines are beginning to show potential to survive and thrive in larger food courts.

 6. Is There An App For That? 

Menus, on line ordering, group discount coupons, real time marketing, fan bases. Savvy fast food retailers will offer multi channels for communicating and marketing to their fan base and it needs to happen YESTERDAY!

 7. The Rise Of The C-Store 

Expect to see competition from other retail outlets such as convenience stores, chemists etc as they start to wise up to the demand for impulse fast foods. We expect to see strong brand development of“snack foods”such as sandwiches, drinks, pastries and coffees in these non-traditional food outlets.

 8. GastroPubs/Niche Dining 

We love pubs and we love our food. Fantastic new entertainment precincts will incorporate major GastroPubs as anchors, while the restaurants will become smaller and more niche in offer. A final addition will be to provide common“green space”areas designed to connect the community through socialising, gardening and interactive play. What I know about pubs 

 9. Grazing 

Just like the“mini me”-omenon for fast food, restaurant menus need to dispense with the old“entree, main course, dessert”format and head for shared plates and casual dining options within their offer to capitalise on the growing purchasing power of Gen Y and their propensity to socialise in larger groups, under more“public”formats.

 10. Pop Up/Mobile Slow Food 

Entertainment Precincts of the future will require an ability to“refresh”their offer on a sporadic basis to meet the needs of the attention span limited younger generation. Integrating some raw space or services to allow for“pop up”restaurants or food experiences will avoid stagnation and boredom as the quest for the“newest”and“tailored”offers continues to grow.

 11. Surf Spa Food
 Consumer demand for more robust spa cuisine created a niche an inch wide and a mile deep as more and more people (mostly women) want to learn to surf, do yoga, eat well and be pampered. Visit Surf Spa Food 
 
 
Share this:
 
 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Post navigation
 ←Previous post Next post→ 
 1 thought on“Food Trends for 2012”

 
 Steven Taylor said: 

 November 1, 2011 at 10:42 pm 
 
I am taking a BA in Culinary Arts in Ireland and have to put together an essay on food trends into 2012, I agree with what you are saying here but I am finding it very difficult to find research material backing it up, can you direct me towards something please

 Reply 


 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
♣Free Healing Foods DVD
 
♣Twitter
 Follow @samanthagowing 
♣Categories

 About Samantha Ayurveda Bali Bitter Sweet Sour Bones Byron Bay Cancer Candida Chinese Medicine Collingwood Craving Fans Dennis Gowing Digestion Enzymes Food Trends Grace Darling Hotel Health Trends Inflammation Intuition Japan Kevin Dennis Malaysia Marketing Melbourne Cup Mentoring Myths New York Organics Palm oil Probiotics Quinoa Recipes Restaurants Sri Lanka Stress Surf Spa Food Surfing Sustainability Testimonials Uncategorized Vegetarianism Wellness Yoga Zanzibar 
 
♣Archives

 June 2012 March 2012 December 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 October 2010 September 2010 April 2010 March 2010 November 2009 October 2009 November 2008 May 2008 November 2006 October 2005 July 2005 August 2004 July 2004 May 2004 April 2003 February 2003 August 2002 July 2002 February 2002 September 2001 June 2001 January 2001 May 2000 March 2000 November 1998 December 1971 November 1969 November 1964 
 
Twitter
 Follow @samanthagowing 
Links

 Bitter Sweet Sour Food Health Wealth 
 
 Subscribe to our Tribe 
 
Join 10 other followers

 

 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Chateau by Ignacio Ricci .
 Follow 
 Follow“Samantha Gowing” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
