<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003603" url="http://www.maloneyvision.com/why/patients.html" time="2012-07-12-19:46" support="8" score="0.02013411053619491" bingtitle="Maloney Vision Institute | Maloney Vision Correction | Maloney ..." webtitle="Maloney Vision Institute | Maloney Vision Correction | Maloney Lasik | Lasik Maloney">
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000842" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000838" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000815" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000833" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000843" bing-rank="25"/>
	<description>Bill Auberlen Champion Race Car ... way home, I stopped at a fast-food restaurant and I could already read the menu board. ... and I also decided to pay the ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Procedures | Why Choose MVI | Meet Our Doctors | Testimonials | Video Library | Affordability | Contact Us 
 
 
 
 
 WHY
CHOOSE MVI? 
 
 Reasons to choose MVI 
 
 What should I look for in a LASIK surgeon? 
 
 Meet our patients 
 
 Video Library 
 
 Newspaper and magazine articles 
 
 Press Releases 
   
 Looking for a doctor near you? 
 Follow@LasikLosAngeles 
 
 
 Meet our Patients What our Patients Say 
 



 Lindsey Vonn 
World Champion Downhill Skier
 

I decided to have LASIK because I noticed that it was becoming more difficult to see the gates and judge the terrain as I was skiing. After doing a ton of research and consulting with my team of doctors, one name kept coming up, and that was Dr. Maloney. I can&apos;t believe how crisp and clear everything is, I&apos;m so excited!

   watch video read more 
 

 Rick Yune 
 Actor 

&quot;Having perfect vision is imperative to my career. The high intensity stunts, precise martial arts training, split-second fight choreography and long hours on set push my eyes to their limits. Many of my closest friends and colleagues have chosen Dr. Maloney and I now know why. If you want the best possible vision for not only yourself but also your loved ones, Dr. Maloney is the one I trust.&quot;
 

 Kim Kardashian 
 Entrepreneur, Actress , Model 

When it came time for Kim Kardashian&apos;s LASIK with Dr. Maloney she decided to let the Keeping Up With the Kardashians camera crew and her sisters come along to watch it all. Check it out !

&quot;The next day I woke up and I could see so clearly. I can see better than I ever have before. I am just loving everything that&apos;s going on right now.&quot;
 

 Angie Akers 
 Professional Beach Volleyball Player
 www.angieakers.com 

&quot;For too long I was bothered by poor vision. I am so excited to finally have taken the plunge and have my eyes fixed. I waited until I found the very best surgeon. In my sport, great vision is essential to success. I no longer have to wear bothersome contact lenses and worry about sand getting caught underneath them. The dry and irritating contact lenses are now a thing of the past! Thank you Dr. Maloney!&quot;
 


 Henry Winkler 
 Actor 

&quot;When I came to the office I literally could not see out of my right eye. After surgery I couldn&apos;t believe I was able to read so clearly without my glasses. It is like a whole new world. If I had to choose one word to describe the experience, it would be &quot;gratitude&quot;. The one thing you&apos;re struck by is a sense of confidence of the staff. There is a sense of professionalism, but there is a sense of warmth, calm and gentleness.

See what Henry Winkler has to say abouthis Cataract and Lens Surgery.
 

 Dennis Quaid 
 Actor 

&quot;I decided to have LASIK because I was tired of looking for my glasses all the time. I&apos;d go out to restaurants, I can&apos;t read the menu. I&apos;d lie down in bed to read and have to get up to go in the other room to get my glasses. I even had five pairs of reading glasses and couldn&apos;t find one of them. I would recommend going to Dr. Maloney to anyone. It&apos;s painless, really easy, quick, and it will change your life for the better.&quot;

See what Dennis Quaid has to say about Dr. Maloney and his LASIK procedure.
 

 Kristin Cavallari 
 Actress 

Laguna Beach and The Hills star Kristin Cavallari documented her whole LASIK experience from consult to comprehensive exam to surgery and post-op visits afterward (and everything in-between too). If you want a first-hand look at what happens when you come to Maloney Vision Institute, check out her video diary .

&quot;It&apos;s completely changed my life. I have better than 20/20 vision!&quot;
 

 Cindy Crawford 
 Model, Actress 

&quot;I’d been considering corrective vision surgery since I’d heard
 about the procedure, but of course, I was very nervous about it. I heard
 about Dr. Maloney from my agent, who had his vision corrected with great results.
 I got up my courage and scheduled an appointment. They were very patient and
 explained all my options. The procedure was painless and I can see so much
 clearer now. It’s great to wake up in the middle of the night and watch
 television without my glasses, and, best of all, I can drive without glasses
 or contacts.

I would recommend it to anyone!&quot;

 Cindy Crawford talks about her LASIK procedure at the Maloney Vision Institute.
 

 William Shatner 
 Actor 

&quot;I decided after much contemplation to have the LASIK operation. In this city, there are opportunities to choose several doctors. I talked to several people, including optometrists, and the consensus, I don&apos;t think there was a dissenting voice, as to the finest doctor in the city for this kind of procedure was Dr. Robert Maloney.&quot;

See what William Shatner has to say about Dr. Maloney and his LASIK procedure.
 

 Drew Carey 
 Host, The Price is Right 

&quot;I was tired of wearing glasses. I had just been scuba diving on vacation
 and couldn&apos;t wear my glasses with the scuba gear. I was getting
 tired of being denied all this stuff, when I knew that the surgery
 was safe, and had friends that were raving about it.

I thought what am I waiting for? It&apos;s great. The results are amazing!&quot;

See what Drew Carey has to say about Dr. Maloney and his LASIK procedure.
 

 Henry Simmons 
 Actor 

&quot;Dr. Maloney was suggested to me through a friend. When I visited him he was very professional and very thorough. He just has this calming presence and any hesitation and fear going in was quickly diminished upon meeting him. He explains things so thoroughly it seems like you&apos;re the doctor. You understand exactly what&apos;s going on and the more knowledge you have, the less fear you have. And that&apos;s what he did.&quot;

See what Henry Simmons has to say about Dr. Maloney and his LASIK procedure.
 

 Michael Bolton 
 Singer, Songwriter 

&quot;It is just life-altering. The day after the procedure I had to ask Dr. Maloney if it was my imagination that the green looked greener, the blue looked bluer. Everything looked more vivid. Everything was brighter.&quot;

See what Michael Bolton has to say about Dr. Maloney and his LASIK procedure.
 

 &quot;Coach&quot; K. Tracy Roberts PGA 
Author, Play REAL Golf 
 www.PlayREALGolf.com 

&quot;Thank you Dr. Maloney! You and your gracious staff have completely changed my life. After a quick and painless procedure, I am completely free of the glasses I had been wearing for almost four decades–the last 10 years with trifocals. All facets of my personal and professional life have improved, and I am amazed each day by what your procedure has allowed to come into focus. Whether I am competing in professional golf tournaments, teaching golf using computer technology or simply enjoying the beauty of golf courses, not only is my vision clear, but colors are more vivid. Who knew something so quick and easy could make this big of an impact on my life?&quot;
 

 Bill Auberlen 
 Champion Race Car Driver 

&quot;When I went in to see Dr. Maloney my vision was 20/25. I was looking for the unfair advantage. He improved my vision to 20/15. Now I can see anything, anywhere, anytime. It&apos;s so much easier to do your job when you&apos;re not concentrating on what you can&apos;t see.&quot;
 

 Barry Manilow 
 Entertainer, Singer, Songwriter 

&quot;I was nervous before the procedure, but I wouldn&apos;t be again.
 It was quick, painless and simple. The staff made me feel totally
 at ease.

On the afternoon of the procedure, I had a costume fitting and
 two meetings with musicians. On the following two days, I had
 two photo sessions. It never even slowed me down.

I can wholeheartedly recommend LASIK for anyone who wants to throw
 away their glasses or contact lenses.&quot;
 
&quot;As a surgical ophthalmologist, I depend on essentially flawless
 visual acuity to perform microscopic eye surgery. The LASIK procedure
 Dr. Maloney performed on me has made a phenomenal difference in my
 life. I actually feel younger, more athletic and even more energetic.&quot;

 JillAnne McCarty, MD, PhD 
 LASIK Surgeon 
 Ventura, CA 
 
&quot;Without my glasses, I couldn&apos;t read the big &apos;E&apos; on the eye
 chart. After LASIK, I drove an Indy car around Texas Motor Speedway
 to an average speed of 204.7mph without glasses or contacts. It&apos;s
 a miracle!&quot;

 Mac Demere 
 Senior Road Test Editor 
 Motor Trend Magazine 
 
&quot;As an optometrist, I knew all the possible complications that
 could occur. Needless to say, I was a little nervous about having
 LASIK, but when I met Dr. Maloney, I was impressed.

The procedure itself was painless. I was in and out of his Westwood
 office in an hour. On the way home, I stopped at a fast-food restaurant
 and I could already read the menu board. One month after the surgery,
 my vision is 20/20 in each eye. I am thrilled.&quot;

 Shelly Fukunaga, OD 
 Eye Doctor 
 Southern California 
 

 Kenny G 
 Musician 

&quot;WOW!!! I can&apos;t thank you enough for what you have brought
 to my life. Your expertise has allowed me to be a lot more comfortable
 every day of my life from now on! Thanks for being so nice and so
 caring. Your entire staff was just a pleasure to be around. They
 made me feel very at ease with everything.&quot;

Hear what Kenny G has to say about his LASIK surgery.
 
&quot;Having the CK procedure was quick and painless. I am no longer
 inconvenienced by always reaching for the correct pair of glasses.
 Now I can read road signs much sooner than I could have before.
 I also participate in both golf and tennis and the improvement in
 my vision has become most noticeable.&quot;

 Pamela Larson 
 Human Resources Manager 
 
&quot;I found in Dr. Maloney an excellent combination of knowledge,
 experience and surgical skills. I am glad that I chose him for
 surgery. He is an outstanding physician, a gifited surgeon and a
 great human being.&quot;

 Sujal Shah 
 LASIK Surgeon 
 Bombay, India 
 
&quot;After living with astigmatism and strong nearsightedness for so
 long, my corrected vision is a dream come true! My confidence in
 selecting the LASIK procedure was strengthened by the professionalism
 and expertise exhibitied by everyone at the Maloney Vision Institute
 before, during and following the procedure. For those of you who
 are deciding on whether or not to have corrective eye surgery, I
 can tell you that I looked long and hard for just the right place
 to entrust my eyes. I found it here.&quot;

 Carol M. Lucas 
 Communications Center Manager 
 
&quot;When it was time for me to have LASIK, I felt that I should have
 it done only by someone who was world-renowned, so I came to Dr.
 Maloney. After wearing &apos;coke bottle&apos; glasses since the fifth grade,
 I am now correction-free.&quot;

 Francis Di Paolo, MD 
 LASIK Surgeon 
 Washington, D.C. 
 
&quot;Many thanks for my vision. My only disappointment with my new
 vision is that after eighteen years of marriage, I discovered that
 my husband looks nothing like Mel Gibson!&quot;

 Michele Devita 
 Librarian 
 

 Al Yankovic 
 Entertainer 

&quot;The operation was quick and completely painless. It was like science
 fiction. One moment I had 20/1000 vision, the next I could see perfectly.
 Now, not only can I see the alarm clock the moment I wake up in
 the morning, but I finally get to see what I look like in the shower.
 (Thanks I guess.) I also have excellent peripheral vision now, something
 I never had with glasses.

Of course, without my glasses, hardly anyone recognizes me anymore,
 so you&apos;ve pretty much killed my career. But, hey, I wouldn&apos;t hold
 that against you. Thanks again!&quot;
 
The procedure went so well, I was playing cards with friends the same afternoon I had cataract surgery. I had to call my dermatologist the next day as I saw things on my skin I had never seen before. Amazing what great eyesight can do.
Oh, and after the surgery, my husband looked so much older!

 -Marian P 
October 2010 
 
I had nothing but an excellent experience at Maloney Vision Institute. A well-trained staff and the handout information and articles were very helpful in getting me prepared for my surgery. I am very happy I made the decision to let Dr. Maloney perform my cataract surgery. I am looking forward to have the other eye done.

 -Gary C. 
September 2011 
 
I have been remiss in not letting you know how very wonderful my experience was with your office when I had my two cataract surgeries. I now have 20/20 vision in one eye (right) and 20/40 in the left eye (probably because of the asymmetric astigmatism in the left eye). The evaluation was extensive and thorough; I think my eyes were measured in ways they had never been before.

The surgery center was as pleasant and efficient as surgery centers can be. The anesthesiologists were very competent -- in fact, I hardly remember the surgery at all!

Again, thanks ever so much. After wearing glasses for over 50 years, I still reach for them in the mornings -- until I realize I can see quite well.

 -Mariam C., MD 
December 2009 
 
I had the cataract surgery done about 2 years ago. Everything went great during the procedure and through the healing process as well. The surgery was quick; the healing process was also quick. The best part was being able to see all the little details I had been missing my whole life.

 -Vanessa M. 
November 2009 
 
I&apos;ve had both my cataract surgeries done through your office and in both cases I was impressed and delighted by the quality of care I received at every step of the procedure. Your staff was thorough, provided answers to all my questions and gave me written materials that helped me understand the procedure. Follow-up calls and visits were prompt and thorough, and I found that every member of your staff with whom I had any interaction was both professionally competent and personally helpful. As you may recall, my first contact with your office was when my wife had her LASIK procedure several years earlier, and I was so impressed with her results and the attention given to her care that I never even considered going anywhere else when it came to having my cataracts removed. The results have been life-altering; I only rarely need reading glasses, and my life -- at least as far as vision goes -- has returned to the unencumbered state of my youth. As you might guess, I would recommend you -- and have recommended you -- enthusiastically to anyone considering cataract or LASIK procedures.

As regards the post-op healing process, the only part that was even remotely onerous was the application of eye drops, because I had never had to use them before. That said, in a couple of days, I had mastered it, and it was not a big deal at all. I followed your clearly-defined instructions to the letter, and have had complete success.

When it comes to health care professionals, both from the perspective of care and outcome, I consider MVI to be the Rolls-Royce standard by which all others should be judged.

 -Thane T. 
September 2011 
 
My experience with Dr Maloney&apos;s office was a terrific experience and the results were better than I expected. I had both eyes done and now for the first time in 50 years, I am not wearing glasses. The follow up after my cataract surgery was excellent.

 -Gary G. 
February 2010 
 
Thank you for providing me with the finest medical care experience I have ever received. When I made the decision to have laser surgery I asked my eye specialist Ronald Goldstein from All Eye Care in West Lake Village, &quot;If you could travel anywhere in the world Doc, who is the one person you would go to for laser surgery?&quot; Dr. Maloney was his highest recommendation. As a movie and TV composer who spends upwards of sixteen hours a day starring at monitors while writing music for film I am amazed at the incredible sharpness and clarity of my new vision, and forever grateful for this new gift of improved sight.

The staff at Maloney Vision Institute was very professional and Dr. Maloney&apos;s attentiveness and attention to detail are simply the best.

 -David W. 
September 2011 
 
My cataract surgery was done in 2009 over the course of 7 months simply because I could not make up my mind whether I wanted both eyes the same or one long and one short. I ended up going with the long and short decision, and I also decided to pay the extra for the higher grade lenses with the wider range. The results were far better than I expected.

I no longer need glasses for anything, not even reading. My eyes now can adjust thru the ranges of vision smoothly so that I see perfectly while doing projects or repairs around the house or working with my computer or cell phone. My long range vision is the best it has ever been. I have great night vision and I no longer have the flaring halo around lights at night.

The operation itself was a very easy and took very little time. The amount of medication for the procedure was perfect. I felt no pain or anxiety during the entire time. The staff was very friendly and professional. I was totally satisfied with this experience.

The healing was easier and quicker then when I had the Lasik procedure years ago. I had very little to no pain to speak of. I did take a while to get used to both eyes working together, but once they synchronized, I was amazed at how well I was able to see. I highly recommend paying the extra for the hi grade lenses, even though they were not covered by my insurance and were out of pocket for me, they were well worth the additional cost.

My vision is excellent, and the care and attention given at Maloney Vision were superior.

 -Rick H. 
September 2010 
 
Dear Dr. Maloney and Staff,

My father was the inspiration for us seeking the BEST Physician who we could trust with one of greatest gifts God has given us -our eyes. Unfortunately, my father was on an HMO Health Plan and his request to see an eye specialist was delayed and caused him his eye sight in one eye. Dad&apos;s brother also lost his vision when he was in his late 70&apos;s. So you can see why we were very concerned about my eye sight and could we trust a doctor.

Of course, we did much research on selecting a Doctor. Even though the expense was above the other Doctors, we felt very confident that Dr. Maloney would be able to correct my complicated vision.

Dr. Maloney was the most kind and knowledgeable eye surgeon that we have met. We felt comfortable in his response to our nervous questions.

The day of surgery to remove the cataract was nervous for us. However, there was no pain and an awful lot to gain. It was amazing to be able to see so crystal clear and resume all my daily activities. I wake up daily and should thank God daily for Dr. Maloney&apos;s assistance in providing me with clear vision. No more headaches after I wake up in the morning.

I did have a slight clouding in the lens capsule after the cataract removal, but Dr. Maloney adjusted my vision with the laser which was painless and improved the vision.

The appointment desk staff are always so pleasant and accommodating. When you arrive for appointments a patient is greeted warmly and the scheduling is outstanding.

We would strongly recommend Dr. Maloney for complicated and normal cataract procedures. 
God bless you Dr. Maloney.

Sincerely,
Mitzie Parker
 
After having both eyes done, a whole new world appeared. I now have perfect distance vision without glasses and just use reading glasses. I had pretty much stopped reading for entertainment but it&apos;s a delight once again.

As to the surgery and &quot;recovery&quot; - it&apos;s as if it never happened. No pain of any kind. Awake from surgery and read the signs across the room. When I arrived at home I put on reading glasses and read the box scores in the paper!!!

My daughter had laser surgery years ago with Dr. Maloney and when I told her of my impending need for cataract surgery she said &quot;Go to Dr. Maloney and make sure HE does the surgery.&quot; That was best advice ever. Dr. Maloney is the leader in the field and very comforting throughout the experience.

An easier, more rewarding experience could not be imagined. Thanks Doc for giving me my eyes back!!!

 -Larry H.
 January 2011 
 
The cataract procedure I had a couple of years ago was the easiest medical procedure I have had done. The recovery time was basically zero. As soon as I came out of the surgery center, I could read the street signs which were blurry before. I had no pain or discomfort either during the procedure or afterwards. The first night I had to wear the protective plastic cover over my eye which was no big deal. Eye drops afterwards were easy to handle. I trust Dr. Maloney with my eyes since he did a lasik procedure on both of my eyes over 10 years ago which was a success. When it is time to do my second eye, I will definitely have Dr. Maloney do the procedure.

 -Eeva T.
 December 2009 
 
When people ask about my cataract procedure, I tell them that my experience from the beginning to the end was exceptional. I also advise them to look no further if they were to have any vision corrective procedures. Every staff member and doctors are to be commended for their professionalism and just plain good &quot;people skills&quot;. The Maloney Vision Institute is clearly (in my eyes) the benchmark in the industry. I usually don&apos;t take the time to endorse any products or service but because my experience was so positive, I feel an obligation to express my thanks

P.S. - My only complaint is that my golf game has not gotten any better. As a matter of fact, I now clearly see all of my bad shots!

 -Ron N.
 April 2011 
 
I had a prism situation left eye; and, short vision in my right. I was having quadruple vision of tail lights at night, and, even with glasses, I did not feel comfortable driving.

Dr. Maloney gave me mono-vision without glasses. I&apos;m now seeing 20/15 for distance and can read the smallest print on the hand eye chart, so I do not need reading glasses. It doesn&apos;t get any better.

Maloney Vision Institute made me feel most comfortable about considering a cataract procedure and being able to perform. This was accomplished by 3 examination and procedure recommendations, two with excellent technicians and the third with Dr. Maloney, a doctor with the best resume I have ever seen. More impressive, he&apos;s the guy that has patents on 4 surgical machines that other doctors use to do the procedure. What more could you ask for?

Please, please give my contact information to any prospective patient. I&apos;m happy to help Dr. Maloney bring such joy and satisfaction to other people as he did for me.

 -Pete J. 
 April 2010 
 CONFIDENCE 
 
 
 
 
 Home | Meet Dr. Maloney (Video) | Are You A Good Candidate? | How To Choose A LASIK Surgeon | Why Choose Us? | Meet our Patients | In the News | Conductive Keratoplasty (CK) | CustomVue | IntraLase®Blade-Free LASIK | LASEK&amp;PRK | LASIK | Monovision Correction | Conductive Keratoplasty | Cataract Removal Crystalens | Multi-focal Lenses | The Visian ICL™ | Cataract Surgery&amp;Refractive Lens Surgery 
 Extreme Makeover | Focus On Independence | Cataract&amp;Lens Surgery Testimonial | Reality LASIK Videos | Kristin And Dr. Maloney On Inside Edition | Reality LASIK With Kristin Cavallari | Testimonials | Video Library | Newspaper And Magazine Articles | Press Releases | Meet Dr. Maloney | Meet Dr. Eghbali Meet Dr. Diehl | Find A Doctor | Directory | We&apos;re Easy To Reach | Map&amp;Directions | Career At MVI | Coming From Out Of Town? Forms | Clinical Updates | Nomograms | Newsletter | Resources | Glossary | iLASIK | Options | Patient Education | Crystalens HD | Affordability 

 COPYRIGHT 2008 MALONEY VISION INSTITUTE. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED. 

 Resources project 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
 
 facebook Hide bar X
	</body>
</document>
