<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003158" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/What_is_the_best_fast_food_restaurant" time="2012-07-12-19:17" support="2" score="0.003415774021159706" bingtitle="What is the best fast food restaurant - The Q&amp;A wiki" webtitle="What is the best fast food restaurantWhat is the best fast food restaurant">
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>Where is the best fast food restaurant? Panera if you are looking for a healthier option. ... Round Table Pizza Coupons; Restopolitan.com Coupons; Shop The Shows Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; Food&amp;Cooking &gt; Restaurants and Dining Establishments &gt; What is the best fast food restaurant? 
What is the best fast food restaurant?
 In: Restaurants and Dining Establishments [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: Burger King, how can you not LOVE the whopper. Double whopper omg! Triple whopper Geez.

My personal favorite is Burger King but Fazoli&apos;s and Arby&apos;s are really good as well.


i think wendys to me is better and so is chic-fil-a 

 First answer by ID2560434178 . Last edit by Pobble123 . Contributor trust : 0 
 [ recommend contributor recommended ]. Question popularity : 2 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Can you answer these Restaurants and Dining Establishments questions?
 
 What are the restaurants on offer at the gourmet society? Answer it! What is the most expensive restaurant in Beirut? Answer it! What do people call waitress? Answer it! What are the types of restaurant according to concept? Answer it! Is there agency in Cyprus to send to Canada for working? Answer it! 
 
Relevant answers:
 
 The BEST fast food or restaurant slogans? 
 People with a taste for life...! 
 What is the best colour for a fast food restaurant ? 
 orange is the best color 
 What fast food restaurant has the best fries? 
 macdonalds 
 What is in fast food restaurant food ? 
 It is helpful to understand what the government allows in feed or to be used in conventional production: Dairy cows - antibiotics, pig&amp;chicken byproducts, hormones (for growth), pesticides,... 
 The most fast food restaurants ? 
 i believe mcdonalds does 
 
 
Related ads:
 

 
Shopping for Restaurants and Dining Establishments deals?

Find Coupons and Promo Codes on Coupons by Answers.com

 Sequel Naturals Coupons Restopolitan.com Coupons Round Table Pizza Coupons Shop The Shows Coupons 
 FIND MORE COUPONS AND PROMO CODES Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 Why would the antifreeze be in the oil? In: Antifreeze and Engine Coolant Answer it! What the definition that fits this word pathway? In: Definitions and Word Differences Answer it! Is clothes being ironed a chemical or physical change? In: Chemistry Answer it! Can we locate pump below the pipe rack? In: Science Answer it! » more 
Featured guides
 
 Current Price Of Gold Per Ounce Gatorade Coupons Online How to Trade Commodities Osteoporosis Treatments Side Effects Herbal Essences Coupons Online 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
