<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003203" url="http://www.chineseop.com/others/I-need-a-name-for-my-new-fast-food-business-please-help-i-will-be-opening-in-4-w.html" time="2012-07-12-19:20" support="1" score="0.0019089170086876116" bingtitle="I need a name for my new fast food business please help.i will be ..." webtitle="I need a name for my new fast food business please help.i will be opening in 4 w-About Food&amp;Health">
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>Just what the world needs, another artery clogging, kid yourself fast food restaurant. ... What do you do when you want to pick up a brownie but know you should have a fru</description>
	<body>
		Home | Sitemap | RSS Feed | Bookmak Us Catalogue Home Cooking Recipes General Cooking Dining Out Entertaining Cuisine Non-Alcoholic Drinks Health Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Beer wine 
 

 Related Resources 
 You are: Home &gt; Others &gt; 

I need a name for my new fast food business please help.i will be opening in 4 w
 Views:    Font: [ Large Medium Small ] 
 Here are some friends with simlar question as we.And I have this question for many days,anyone help us?
Kitty said: Yes. I need a name for my new fast food business please help.i will be opening in 4 w -I try seach this on internet but no results found.Maybe this is a stupid question.
Mike said: oh,no,you are wrong.I have found as below for this question( I need a name for my new fast food business please help.i will be opening in 4 w ),it will help you,my kids.
 my menu will be n dips,fish n chips.

Answer:
What about :
Kebabra&apos;s ,
The River Side Cafe
Diner City
Sasta&apos;s
Strand Cafe
Grab n Go
Food 4 U Acme Eats Snappy Snacks ??
Food to Go ? big bites u need to catch the food first.dead or alive blue water.10 second food Acne Factory?
Fat Vats?
Cholesterol R&apos;Us?
Heart Disease on a Stick? Well what&apos;s your style or atmosphere in your establishment?

That could help you find a name.

This reminds me of a story about the famous Orville Redenbacher when he first got into the business of selling popcorn.

After he began cornering the market, he went to a firm to help figure out a brand name for his product so that people could easily remember the name to his product. After a few weeks, the firm told Redenbacher to use his name as the brand. A name that cost $2000 to be suggested to be put on a box that was given to him by his parents for free.

Something to think about. Good luck. Good Food To Go Fully loaded Arteries Cholesterol King

McHeartattack dip into kevins plaice Cardiac Cave? Defibrilator Palace? Cholesterol Haven? Just what the world needs, another artery clogging, kid yourself fast food restaurant. Ever think of serving salads? Fresh Vegetables? Fresh Fruit? Best of luck in your venture, but please consider some healthy options-those of us who like to eat good foods simply cannot get them in fast food places Gut Busters You need something that rolls easily off the tongue. Imagine business people talking about where to go for lunch and saying&quot;Do you want to go to Joe&apos;s, or that new place whose name I can&apos;t remember?&quot;.

Don&apos;t try to use your name in the name of the business. Because if you fail, people will have that name associated with you. A safe bet is to use the name of your town/city. The Townsville Take-Away. Or The Townsville Deli, something like that. Downtown Grill. Keep it short. Enough for people to be able to abbreviate it in conversation.

Good luck! I miss the good ol&apos;days of having my place. There&apos;s no way I can suggest a name for your restaurant (or any other type of business) without knowing anything about you, the town you live in, what type of clientele you&apos;re catering to, etc etc etc. Remember that whatever you name the place, you&apos;re going to be stuck with it. Also (this goes without saying), you have to beware of copyright issues. Even if your last name is (for example) McDonald, you&apos;d have a really hard time not getting sued if your called your restaurant&quot;McDonald&apos;s&quot;.

Speaking of last names, have you considered using your own actual last name (or a permutation of it)? Or, perhaps you have someone in your family history (a grandmother, great aunt, etc) who has a first name that lends itself well? For example, Nonna Yolanda (&quot;grandma Yolanda&quot;in Italian) is named after my grandmother. We do serve Italian food, but not exclusively. i&apos;m not sure about the name for your shop but here&apos;s a slogin for you to put on your shop window and on your menu&apos;s. YOU&apos;VE TRIED THE REST NOW TRY THE BEST. Fast&apos;n Fine
QuickBites
Yum Inna&apos;Tum (hey, that&apos;s good)
Snack KaBobs Have you done any market research in your area?

There is a move towards healthier eating in most places, so maybe you should have some healthy choices of food too. Also if you are going to cook the food healthily.....e.g. Cook in olive oil instead of vegetable oil, use granary bread, etc, then choose a name which reflects this, and make sure you let people know when you market the business.
&quot;tasty and healthy&quot;?

Don&apos;t forget to check that the name has not already been registered for another business BEFORE you get the sign painted and the menus printed. Otherwise you will have to scrap the lot and start all over again! &apos;Scrummy Yummys&apos;
&apos;The Tasty Bite&apos; Hello i had the idea of opening just what you are doing but have not got the money to do it ,what i was going to call mine was
THE WRAP SHACK Think of the person you most despise. That way, if it doesn&apos;t work out, you save your reputation! YAAY! Culinary factory
divine factory McRonalds
Burger Ring
KFB
Pizza But
Dominics Pizza &quot;Not The Irish Fry&quot; Ulster Options
Ulster Eats
Derry Delights
Derry Fine Dining (a play on Very Fine Dining)
Foyle Foods
Foods by the Foyle

Best of luck - Let us know how you get on. I&apos;ll look out for your premises the next time I visit Derry city (I live in the south of Ireland). Burger Me!!! or The Whole Plate Full How about&quot;Sizzling Sizzlers&quot;if it is near higway then&quot;HighWay Convenio&quot; 


 
 Read this: All the information of cooking and health post by website user,chineseop.com not guarantee
correctness,It&apos;s Non-profit and only for informational purposes. 
PRE: I need a new messy/punky/hippy hairstyle?  NEXT: I need a lot of Energy before I play drums - what&apos;s the best thing to drink/eat 

Related Question about Food and Health
 Can I find gouda cheese in Saint Thomas, Dominica, Barbados, St. Lucia or Antigu 
I would like to buy gouda cheese for a friend. Im going in a cruise to the islan...
 What is/are your favorite kinds of cereals? 
My favorite kind of cereals include Honey Nut Cherrios, Frosted Flakes, and Capt...
 Whats your favourite ice cream or lolly ices .? 
Answer: Hey, no one answered your question so i thought id pop in here so you wo...
 Meat-eaters, which meats do you feel squeamish about eating--frog,rabbit,shrimp, 
I am physically averse to eating any animals but beef, chicken, and duck. I was ...
 I&apos;m not eating chocolate right now...what are some easy, yummy sweet treats I ca 
Answer: Carmel...or hard candies, like butterscoth uuummmmmm Eat nuts or pecans....
 Is there a difference between a mocha frappe and a mocha freeze? 
Answers: They both taste the same. Frappe is Starbucks. Freeze is from Baskin Ro...
 I like uk!!i&apos;m italian and i&apos;d like to know some of your specilities!!!thank u? 
i hope to have written all right Answer: We have some great specialities, unfort...
 Pretzel Discovery? 
Who discovered the pretzel and in what year? Answer: The pretzel wasnt discovere...
 

Popular Question about Food and Health
 Where Can I Buy Warheads Candy In Minneapolis?!? HARD QUESYTION PLS ONLT PROs? What do you do when you want to pick up a brownie but know you should have a fru Everyone who has fruit loops in their house, please do me a favor? Everyone who has froot loops in their house, please do me a favor? Who Do You Want to Win the -? IS Guy Fieri a -? What&apos;s your fav.fruit???? 
 
 About | Contact | Sitemap | Top 
©2007 - 2008 chineseop.com Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
