<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003964" url="http://ww1.webanswers.com/food-drink/dining-out/what-is-the-fastest-fast-food-restaurant-8ea0d6" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="5" score="0.014148257105335885" bingtitle="What is the fastest fast food restaurant? - WebAnswers.com" webtitle="What is the fastest fast food restaurant? - WebAnswers.com">
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>What is the fastest fast food restaurant ... You could go through the drive through and order your meal at the ... Tell me which fast food restaurant is your favorite.</description>
	<body>
		Welcome New User! ( Create Account | Sign In ) 
 Answer Questions and Earn Money! Join Us 
 How WebAnswers Works | Become an Expert | FAQs | Advanced Search | Leaderboards | Earn Money Maximize 
 Start earning today! 
 
 You are here: Home   Categories   Food&amp;Drink   Dining Out   What is the fastest fast food restaurant? 
     What restaurant chain makes the most money? Restaurant profits, fast food profitable restaurants, fast casual restaurant franchises usa What is your favorite fast food restaurant? Whoever answers this first with the one im thinking gets awarded.remember one fast food restaurant... Restaurant name I want open a fast food restaurant (like mcdonalds) in washington, i need a name of restaurant... What is the best fast food restaurant? What is your opinion on which fast food restaurant is the best? for me, i would have to say... Is there a traditional family mexican restaurant (not fast food ) by 11375? Is there a traditional family mexican restaurant (not fast food ) within 1 mile of the zip... Click here to ask a question about anything! 

 
 Get paid for participating 
 Ask questions - It&apos;s FREE Get answers within minutes. Fun, fast and easy. Share your opinions with our community. Earn money for answering. See how. 
This Question has not been awarded yet.

 Post your answer now! 
 Find more related questions to What is the fastest fast food restaurant? Question 
Submitted 850 days ago...
 
 MudPie316 

New User (1)
 
What is the fastest fast food restaurant?


 Share | Abuse |   Answers Answer 1 / 8 - Submitted 361 days ago... 
 
 SlipFallGuy 

Brain (7,059)
 
I recall living near a McDonald&apos;s in New Mexico where the owner really had things well organized. You could go through the drive through and order your meal at the speaker and they were handing it out the window by the time you got there. They even advertised that your meal was free if you didn&apos;t have it in your hands within 30 seconds from ordering. I suppose the food was prepared well ahead of the crowd, but I don&apos;t recall anything that felt or tasted like it had been sitting around for long. I used to eat there a lot when I lived there.
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 2 / 8 - Submitted 360 days ago... 
 
 zeecook 

Beginner (35)
 
If you are in the Kingsport, TN area, stop on by the Pal&apos;s. They have the fastest. You order on one side of the building and drive around to the other side and pay and food is right there ready for you. There is NO inside seating and you will know it when you see the Pal&apos;s. It is a blue building with a BIG hot dog, fries and drink on it. Yeap, that is Pal&apos;s.
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 3 / 8 - Submitted 360 days ago... 
 
 marellen822 

Beginner (33)
 
I live in Northern Californa and I would say the fastest is a Taco Bell down the street from me. I usually take the drive thru and I&apos;m in and out like a shot.
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 4 / 8 - Submitted 359 days ago... 
 
 deeny111 

Authority (205)
 
The fastest is the most unhealthy and can cause you heart disease and indigestion, followed by a high blood pressure and a heart attack.

Examples:
Burger King, Hardee&apos;s, Carl&apos;s JR, KFC, Wendy&apos;s, Jack in the Box, Arby&apos;s, Yum Brands: which include Pizza Hut, Taco Bell, and Long John silver.

Stay healthy, Stay away from Fast Food ; )
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 5 / 8 - Submitted 359 days ago... 
 
 kitkatb23 

Beginner (21)
 
Mcdonald&apos;s is the fastest because with so many chains they&apos;ve got the system down pack however if you would like to factor in accuracy. I would have to say Burger King is the fastly accurate I&apos;ve never brought home a bag that didn&apos;t have everything in which I order. About 25% of the time I go to McDonald&apos;s it is never right.
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 6 / 8 - Submitted 359 days ago... 
 
 PallasAthena 

Brain (7,457)
 
Fast food is already so fast, if it got any faster the poor little drones who work there would be pelting you with food as soon as you opened the door.
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 7 / 8 - Submitted 358 days ago... 
 
 evasmomma 

New User (9)
 
I think tht the fastest place to eat is mcdonalds and the best part is u can now eat healthy on the go they have salads wrapas parfet lots of items even healthy options for kida :)
 Share | Link | Abuse     Answer 8 / 8 - Submitted 352 days ago... 
 
 usmak45 

Beginner (22)
 
The Fastest food restaurant is the KFC.
 Share | Link | Abuse         
 Answer This Question Now 
 
What is the fastest fast food restaurant?

If your Answer is chosen as the “accepted” answer, you will earn ongoing royalties on this thread.
Simply type your Answer in the box below and post your answer.
 Learn more about how WebAnswers.com works 
 Add picture 
 

 Email Subscriptions 

 Author adds clarification

 All new responses Related Questions Healthy Fast Food? 

What is the healthiest fast food restaurant choice?
 Open | Category: Dining Out | 9 Replies Tasty Fast Food? 

What&apos;s the tastiest fast food restaurant choice?
 Open | Category: Dining Out | 20 Replies What fast food restaurant has the best food? 

Tell me which fast food restaurant is your favorite.
 Awarded to: Bruzzbuzz | Category: Dining Out | 17 Replies What is your favorite fast food restaurant? 

Which fast food restaurant do you like the most?
 Open | Category: Dining Out | 8 Replies What is your favorite fast food? 

What is your favorite fast food restaurant and what meal or food item?
 Awarded to: DarkStar1158 | Category: Food&amp;Drink | 9 Replies   Overview | FAQs | Contact Us | Member Agreement | Privacy Policy | Site Map | Partners 

 * NEW Referral Program | Link to this page Copyright©WebAnswers 2012. All rights reserved. X 

 Close this window
	</body>
</document>
