<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003071" url="http://www.highstreetcentral.com/mysterys.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:11" support="1" score="0.0007008963150719666" bingtitle="The Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club ©" webtitle="The Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club">
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>Whenever you visit a major fast food restaurant or ... or just pop out for a drink. Fees ... with an e-mail address we can get the information to you immediately on receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		THE HIGHSTREETCENTRAL SHOPPING DIRECTORY © 
 All the information you can handle... 
 
 
 
The Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club USA © 
 
 
Mystery Shoppers Always Needed
 
 &quot;For months I&apos;ve been tracking down ways to become a Mystery Shopper.
You have given me the best information so far.&quot; C.L. 

Please click here to go to the Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club UK © 
Please click here to go to the Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club Canada © 
 Mystery Shopping , or Secret Shopping as it is sometimes known, is well established and a very large part of the Market Research Industry. It is a service used by the top retail outlets, leading entertainment / leisure organizations and banks.
 
Whenever you visit a major fast food restaurant or well known retail chain, have you ever wondered how they manage to maintain a consistent high level of service no matter how many branches they have and regardless of where they are in the world?
It is not left to chance. They all use mystery shoppers to pose as diners or buyers to evaluate the service at ground level. Thousands of ordinary people get paid to go shopping, eat out in a restaurant or just pop out for a drink. Fees per visit vary between
companies, but are usually between about $12.00 and $35.00. And of course expenses are paid - yes that really does mean that your food and drink is paid for as well.
 
You would choose which assignments are most suitable for you and work for one or more mystery shopping companies on a casual basis. Generally you would be paid a set amount per visit plus travel, parking and phone expenses. Travel expenses usually consist of an allowance of around 35 cents per mile. You would visit bars, supermarkets, steak houses and fast food restaurants to check out the service and fill in a simple questionnaire. This information is used to improve standards. Thousands of visits take place across the country daily.
Examples of some Restaurant / Bar questions for Secret Shoppers:

 Was the exterior clean and tidy?
 Was the interior clean and tidy?
 Did the staff member who served you make eye contact?
 Were you greeted?
 Were you served in a friendly manner?
 Were you served within two minutes of entry?
 Were you offered ice with your drink, if appropriate?
 Were you offered starters, side items, desserts or coffee?
 Was your food served within 15 minutes?
 Was your table cleared within five minutes of completion?
 Was the music appropriate for the type of venue?



Join the Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club
The Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club is over 9 years old and has over 5000 satisfied members. For a one time membership fee of $20.00, we will provide you with the contact details of dozens of US Mystery Shopping companies and the simple instructions needed to get you started.
All you have to do is to give them a call and ask for an application form - most companies will respond. Register with as many companies as possible for best results. It may be over a month, though often sooner, before you receive your first assignment, but it is worth the wait. We will also send you details of how to become an on-line Mystery Shopper, testing websites for good customer service from the comfort of your own home!
Why do we charge $20 for this service?
Your payment covers all our administrative, organizational and website costs - it also entitles you to lifetime membership of the Mystery Shopping Club (no annual fees) and access to our Mystery Shopping helpdesk. Also, if you find that one of the companies is not recruiting presently, please let us know and we will send you another company&apos;s information as soon as it becomes available. This list is added to regularly and all updates are supplied to club members free of charge on request. Free e-mail support is also included and there are absolutely no further charges...
Payment choice 1
 
Please click here to pay by credit card . (Please note that the next batch of memberships will be sent out within 10 working days.) 

Payment choice 2
If you would prefer to pay by check, please write your name and home address on a piece of paper marked &quot;Mystery Shopping&quot;, enclose a check for $20.00 (payable to High Street Central) and send to:
THE MYSTERY SHOPPING CLUB,
GREEN VIEW,
BROOK END ROAD NORTH,
CHELMSFORD,
ESSEX
CM2 6NW UK
If you supply us with an e-mail address we can get the information to you immediately on receipt of your check. Don&apos;t forget to bookmark us for future reference. Please right click here now to add to favorites.
Note: Although we are based in the UK, we have been operating very successfully within the US Mystery Shopping field for over 6 years now. In fact, the majority of our club members are US residents.
 
 Journalists please click here for a look at the life of a Mystery Shopper.
 Please click here to read what Choices Magazine had to say after a visit to the Mystery Shopping Recruitment Club © 
 
 Click here to tell a friend 

 Please bookmark / add to favorites for future use. 
 
Please click here for The High Street Central Directory
 IMPORTANT INFORMATION Have you taken out a credit card, mortgage, secured loan, unsecured loan or hire purchase agreement in the last 10 years? If you have (or have had) a mortgage, loan or credit card with providers such as Abbey, Barclaycard, MBNA, Halifax, HSBC, HBOS, Lloyds, Natwest, RBS or in fact any other credit provider, you may be able to reclaim up to 15,000 if you were sold PPI insurance - in most cases even if you&apos;ve lost the paperwork.

Learn more about PPI Claims now! 
 
 ©highstreetcentral.com Keywords: shopping directory, shoping, directery
 Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | About Us and Contact Information | Safe Shopping | Home
	</body>
</document>
