<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003298" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/267410-Free-Juicy-Juice-Sippy-Cup" time="2012-07-12-19:26" support="2" score="0.0014912241713208505" bingtitle="Free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup - Welcome to Your Daily Freebies ..." webtitle="Free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup">
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>Register and receive a free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup: http://www.juicyjuice.com/Special-Offers/Default ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons; Military ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals Free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Results 1 to 4 of 4 
Thread: Free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 12-03-2009,  12:39 PM #1 jandmama 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Nov 2009 Posts 29 
Free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup
 Register and receive a free Juicy Juice Sippy Cup:

 http://www.juicyjuice.com/Special-Offers/Default.aspx Reply With Quote 12-03-2009,  06:15 PM #2 jodeci77 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Nov 2008 Location Springfield, IL Posts 128 
 
 I got this for my niece&amp;my mom swears it&apos;s the best sippie cup ever. 0 leaks! Reply With Quote 12-04-2009,  08:28 AM #3 astrosfan 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Aug 2007 Location Mississippi Posts 173 I got one for my son and LOVE IT!!! I&apos;m sending one to my niece now. Reply With Quote 12-05-2009,  01:23 PM #4 mousiez 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2007 Posts 102 
get one, everyone
 Last year the first strains of H1N1 hit our house, ALL of us were so sick we literally could not move.
And we live on a farm...and we still had to go and tend the animals.
not fun.
The ONE saving grace was having this sippy cup, because it could fall on the bed, and not spill....and it didn&apos;t give too much liquid at one time.
While it&apos;s available, everyone, get one for each of your family, you won&apos;t regret it! Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
