<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003326" url="http://www.coversurehyde.co.uk/veh_private_car.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:28" support="1" score="0.0010019915460429626" bingtitle="Coversure Hyde - Private Car Insurance" webtitle="Coversure Hyde - Private Car Insurance">
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="88"/>
	<description>Private Car Insurance. We will search through many of the leading UK car insurance companies, and a number of schemes ... Take Away &amp; Fast Food; Restaurant &amp; Cafe; Pub &amp; Wine Bar</description>
	<body>
		Information 
 Contact Us Claimsline Existing Customers About Us News&amp;Blog FAQ&apos;s 
 
 
 Vehicles 
 Courier&amp;Haulier Business Fleet HGV Van Taxi&amp;Private Hire Mini Bus&amp;Coach Business Car Driving Instructor Motor Trade Private Car Motorbike Breakdown Cover Theft Protection 
 Commercial 
 Liability Contractors All Risks Goods In Transit Plant Cover Office Business Property Wholesale Commercial Combined Tools&amp;Equipment 
 Retail 
 General Take Away&amp;Fast Food Restaurant&amp;Cafe Pub&amp;Wine Bar Beauty Trades Body Art Hotel&amp;Guesthouse Antiques Shop 
 Property 
 Our Products Commercial Let Residential Let Unoccupied Residential Home Home&amp;Contents Holiday Home 
 Other 
 Legal Travel Marine Surgeries Insurance Healthcare 
 
 
 Private Car Insurance 

We will search through many of the leading UK car insurance companies, and a number of schemes that are not available directly to the public or online,
in an effort to save you money.

Our experienced team will search and select a policy for you that best suits your needs.

We offer other options to suit you, such as:


&gt;legal cover
&gt;windscreen cover available
&gt;European cover available
&gt;flexible payment options
&gt;business use available
&gt;breakdown cover (including European cover) at greatly reduced rates
 
 quote now 

Recieve a personal and detailed quote from a team member

Quote Buster!

We will do our best to beat any quote you have recieved for the same policy
 
Unique Insurance packages For Your requirements

As one of the country&apos;s largest independently owned groups of insurance brokers, we have formed excellent relationships with many of the UK&apos;s leading insurance companies, so we can get the right cover at the right prices. We can tailor bespoke insurance polices which will give you complete cover.
 
 Business Car 
 
 Home&amp;Contents 
 
 Legal Fees Insurance 
 
Call FREE On
 
0800 358 1235
 
To Speak To An Advisor
 
 Vehicles 

 Courier&amp;Haulier Business Fleet HGV Van Taxi&amp;Private Hire Mini Bus&amp;Coach Business Car Driving Instructor Motor Trade Private Car Motorbike Breakdown Cover Theft Protection 
 
 Commercial 

 Liability Contractors All Risks Goods In Transit Plant Cover Office Business Property Wholesale Commercial Combined Tools&amp;Equipment 
 
 Retail 

 General Take Away&amp;Fast Food Restaurant&amp;Cafe Pub&amp;Wine Bar Beauty Trades Body Art Hotel&amp;Guesthouse Antiques Shop 
 
 Property 

 Our Products Commercial Let Residential Let Unoccupied Residential&amp;Nursing Home Home&amp;Contents Holiday Home 
 
 Other 

 Legal Travel Marine Surgeries Insurance Healthcare Products 
 
Information

 Home Contact Us Claimsline Existing Customers About Us News&amp;Blog FAQ&apos;s How To Find Us Privacy&amp;Security Terms&amp;Conditions Press Centre Job Vacancies 
 
Connect

 Linked In Facebook Twitter 
 
© Coversure Insurance Services (Hyde) 2011

Macci Ltd t/as Coversure Insurance Services (Hyde) is authorised and regulated by the Financial Services Authority. Ref: 307594.

Coversure Hyde offers Insurance Products to the Greater Manchester area covering towns including Failsworth, Stockport, Bredbury, Droylsden, Cheadle Hulme, Wilmslow, Hazel Grove, Stalybridge, Glossop, Skelton, Hackthorpe, Ashton under Lyne, Droylsden, Stalybridge, Denton, Glossop, Stockport, Wilmslow, and Hyde.
 
 Coversure Insurance Hyde 

118 Market Street, Hyde, Cheshire SK14 1EX

 Tel: 0800 358 1235
 Fax: 0161 366 7504
 Mobiles Call: 0161 222 7878
 E-mail: Hyde@coversure.co.uk

 Office: Monday – Friday: 9.00am – 5.30pm
 
Site By: Sum Studio
	</body>
</document>
