<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003322" url="http://www.mississauga.worldweb.com/RestaurantsBars/Indian/" time="2012-07-12-19:27" support="1" score="0.000766660441600295" bingtitle="Mississauga Indian Restaurants: Indian Restaurants in Mississauga ..." webtitle="Mississauga Indian Restaurants: Indian Restaurants in Mississauga, Ontario">
			<query id="000301" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>Enter the world of Indian cuisines, delicacies and ... cuisines are served up at this casual, modern restaurant ... to offering great deals on hotel, airline and car ...</description>
	<body>
		Mississauga Indian Global Search Local Search 
 Nearby Towns/Cities... ALL DESTINATIONS Ajax Aurora, ON Bolton, ON Bowmanville, ON Brampton Burlington Caledon, ON Georgina, ON Inglewood, ON King, ON Markham Milton Mississauga Nestleton, ON Newmarket, ON Oakville Oshawa Pickering Richmond Hill, ON Scugog, ON Stouffville, ON Thornhill, ON Toronto Vaughan, ON Whitby, ON Woodbridge, ON Plan Your Trip» 
 Stay Play Eat Shop See Go Review Map All 
 Add» Review | Business | Event | Photo WorldWeb.com » Canada » Ontario » Greater Toronto Area » Mississauga » Restaurants&amp;Bars » Indian 1:27 pm EDT 
 
Mississauga Indian
 •A WorldWeb.com Travel Guide to Indian in Mississauga , Ontario . Listings Map Reviews Write a Review Butter chicken, chana masala, naan bread and pakoras are some of the most popular Indian dishes often served at Mississauga, Ontario Indian restaurants. Check out our list below to find Indian buffets, Indian vegetarian restaurants, and different Indian regional cuisines in Mississauga by referring to reviews, descriptions and ratings. 
 Udipi Madras Cafe Udipi Madras Cafe is located on Enfield Place in Mississauga. The menu offers Indian vegetarian cuisine. A breakfast and lunch buffet are available on the weekends. Address: 265 Enfield Place | Mississauga, ON | L5B 3E2
 Telephone: 1 905 277-0010
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Sangam Indian Cuisine Enjoy tasty tandoori items, made from chicken, lamb or fish. Numerous vegetarian selections are available. Sangham has two locations in Mississauga and one in Toronto. Address: 3091 Hurontario St | Mississauga, ON
 Telephone: 1 905 277-5772
 Address: 6991 Millcreek Dr, Mississauga ON
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info The Shish Mahal Indian Cuisine Savory appetizers, clay oven specialties, vegetarian entrees, non-vegetarian dishes, signature basmati rice selections and roti are just a sample of the offerings available at this restaurant. Address: 3176 Ridgeway Dr., Unit 66. | Mississauga, ON | L5L 5S6
 Telephone: 1 905 820-7711
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Lorne Park Indian Cuisine&amp;Bar An upscale Indian restaurant and bar located in Clarkson, Mississauga at Erin Mills and QEW. Address: 1603 Clarkson Rd N | Mississauga, ON | L5J 2X1
 Telephone: 1 905 855-2400
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Saffron Touch Indian Sweets and Restaurant This dining and take-out restaurant serves the Mississauga area. Specializing in Tandoori dishes, authentic North Indian food is prepared by an experienced chef. Address: 1525 Bristol Road West | Mississauga, ON | L5M 4Z1
 Telephone: 1 905 369-0112
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Mango Rain Traditional Indian and Thai cuisines are served up at this casual, modern restaurant, which offers classics like tandoori chicken, satay, pad Thai and butter chicken. Take out services are also offered. Address: 1714 Lakeshore Road W. | Mississauga, ON | L5J 1J5
 Telephone: 1 905 919-1374
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Nirvana the Flavours of India Address: 35 Brunel Road | Mississauga, ON | L4Z3E8
 Telephone: 1 905 501-5500
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Shan-E-Darbar A menu of soups, vegetarian snacks, meat dishes, chicken specialties, seafood, basmati rice selections and Indian breads await patrons of this traditional Indian restaurant. Daily lunch and dinner buffets are also offered. Address: 2644 Islington Ave. | Toronto (Etobicoke), ON | M9W 2X5
 Telephone: 1 416 741-7406
 Address: 7166 Airport Rd. | Mississauga, ON
 Telephone: 1 905 678-7889
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Avani Asian Indian Bistro A posh and modern decor with menu highlights including signature Salmon Tikka, Tandoori Rack of Lamb, Lobster Masala and addictive Samosa Rolls. An executive lunch buffet where selections are brought to the table is offered daily in addition to a full a la carte menu. Address: 801 Matheson Blvd. W. | Mississauga, ON | L5C 4L6
 Telephone: 1 905 501-0021
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Amma Restaurant Enter the world of Indian cuisines, delicacies and specialties. Providing tasty food since 1983 in India and now in Canada and soon in the USA. Located close to Burmhamthore, Dundas Street, Queensway, QEW, Hurontario Street and Tomken. Address: #1195, Dundas Street E | Mississauga, ON | L4Y 2C5.
 Telephone: 1 905 897-2662
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Savikavi A family restaurant specializing in authentic Indian&amp;Chinese Cuisine. Address: 6400 Millcreek Drive | Mississauga, ON | L5N 3E7
 Telephone: 1 905 542-8613
 Address: 1098 Peter Robertson Blvd. #25, Brampton
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Zeerah Telephone: 1 905 569-7916
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Glass Bucket Restaurant Address: 4040 Creditview | Cooksville, ON | L5A2G9
 Telephone: 1 905 848-3454
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Trinidad Style Hot Roti and Doubles Address: 7205 Goreway Drive | Mississauga, ON | L4T2T9
 Telephone: 1 905 678-9201
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Bombay Bhel Address: 6435 Erin Mills Parkway | Mississauga, ON | L5N4H4
 Telephone: 1 905 858-6100
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Tikki Tikka Indian Bistro Address: 2057 Royal Windsor Dr | Mississauga, ON | L5J1K5
 Telephone: 1 905 823-2000
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Barb&apos;s Roti Shop Address: 1181 Lakeshore Road East | Mississauga, ON | L5E1G1
 Telephone: 1 905 278-4713
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Meenu&apos;s Kitchen - Take Out or Delivery The Pure taste of Homemade Indian Food -Fresh, Hygienic and Delicious available at reasonable prices. The most practial solution: One Dal and One Vegetable cooked fresh everyday. Very convenient for those who cannot cook at home. 
(Non-Vegetarian dishes also available) Telephone: 1 647 201-7874
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Tandoori Flame This establishment serves succulent south Asian cuisine. Address: 3050 Confederation Parkway, | Mississauga,, ON
 Telephone: 1 905 272-0808
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info New India Sweets&amp;Restaurant Address: 1201 Britannia Road West | Mississauga, ON | L5V1N2
 Telephone: 1 905 814-1730
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Sweet India Restaurant Address: 7126 Airport Road | Mississauga, ON | L4T2H1
 Telephone: 1 905 673-0041
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Bara&apos;s Hut Doubles&amp;Roti Address: 127 Dundas Street East | Mississauga, ON | L5A1W7
 Telephone: 1 905 281-9368
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Village of India Enjoy the fine flavours and aromas of this Indian restaurant. Known for the all-vegetarian and sweet menu items. Address: 1011 Eglinton Ave E | Mississauga, ON
 Telephone: 1 905 238-9219
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Spice Route This affordable kebab and curry tandoori restaurant offers freshly prepared dishes - feel welcome to have the spices adjusted to taste. When in Mississauga, give the Spice Route a try. Address: 6905 Millcreek Drive #1, | Mississauga,, ON
 Telephone: 1 905 593-9982
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info La Karma Address: 801 Matheson Blvd West | Cooksville, ON | L5A4A3
 Telephone: 1 905 502-1799
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Savana Restaurant&amp;Lounge Located in the Best Western airport hotel, this comfortable restaurant offers a menu of Indian and Continental cuisine. Savana serves breakfast, lunch and dinner. Address: 5825 Dixie Rd, Best Western Toronto Airport West | Mississauga, ON | L4W 4V7
 Telephone: 1 905 670-8180
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Sangam Indian Cuisine Inc Address: 5825 Dixie Road | Mississauga, ON | L4W4V7
 Telephone: 1 905 670-5588
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Bombay Bhel Restaurant Address: 5035 Hurontario Street | Mississauga, ON | L4Z3X7
 Telephone: 1 905 890-7955
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Wedding Photographer 
 Keepsake Photography 
 Candid, documentary-style photography for your special day! Serving Southern Ontario!
 Pro Photographer 
 Pixel Blur Photography 
 Wedding and lifestyle photographer serving the greater Toronto area!
 Luxury Transport 
 Yorkville Limousine 
 The Limousine service revolution has begun in the Greater Toronto Area!
 Fitness Centre/Pool 
 Staybridge Suites Toronto Mississauga 
 Book now to get the guaranteed lowest Internet room rate!
 Specialty Transport 
 A1 Toronto Limos 
 specializes in providing affordable luxury transportation!
 Book Your Vacation! 
 Hotels Flights Cars Hotel City
 
 Check-in
 Check-out
 
 Adults
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Children
 0 1 2 3 4 
 
 View Hotel Listings My Reservations | Cancel a Reservation Please enter a city or airport code of 3 to 25 characters. Please enter the age of each child. 
 Airports 
From
 
To
 
 
 Compare surrounding airports 
 Depart
 Return
 Exact 
+/- 3 
 Adults
 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 Children
 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 
 
 More Search Options
 One Way | Multiple Destinations 
 Car Rentals 
Pick up car at:
 At an airport Other locations 
 Airport Code
 Different Dropoff?
 Yes No 
 Drop off car at
 At an airport Other locations Airport Code
 
 
Pick-up Date
 
Drop-off Date
 
Car Type
 5 basic types Compact Pickup Truck Economy Full Size Intermediate Luxury Van Premium Standard Sport Utility Convertible Station Wagon Specialty 
 
 More search options 
 
 
 Mississauga Tourism Directory 

 Lodging Tours&amp;Activities Visitor Attractions Restaurants&amp;Bars Shopping Transportation Rental Services Wedding Planner Convention Planner Real Estate Events Business Index Reviews 
 Business Owners/Managers 
Do you manage a business in Mississauga? If so, please search our tourism directory to ensure your company information is up to date and accurate. If you don&apos;t find a listing, we invite you to add a complimentary listing . If you want to increase your exposure to the millions of people who come to WorldWeb.com each month to plan their trips and vacations, please refer
to our advertising information . 
 
 

WorldWeb.com provides comprehensive travel information for Vancouver and beyond. In addition to offering great deals on hotel, airline and car rental reservations, WorldWeb.com connects you directly to companies servicing the tourism industry.
 Contribute
 Write a Review Add a Listing Submit an Event Share Your Photos 
 About WorldWeb.com
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Contact Us Advertising Info 
 
   Canada USA United Kingdom Ireland Australia New Zealand Italy France Caribbean 
 ©1994-2012 World Web Technologies Inc. 
Mississauga Indian
	</body>
</document>
