<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003249" url="http://www.petromarket.net/gas-stations-convenience-stores-on-sale/looking-for-partner-operator" time="2012-07-12-19:23" support="1" score="0.00012728047484861024" bingtitle="Looking for partner - operator of Fast food restaurant ..." webtitle="Looking for partner - operator of Fast food restaurant.Petromarket - Gas Stations and Convenience Stores for sale">
			<query id="001467" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>Our company just bought a BP gas station with fast food restaurant on a premises. ... Tenant can cancel his lease and get his deposit back after end of trial ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content. | Skip to navigation 

 Site Map Accessibility Contact 
 Search Site only in current section Advanced Search… 
Sections
 
 Home On Sale Buyers Jobs Finance Equipment Members Glossary About 
 
Personal tools

 Log in Register 
 You
are here: Home → On Sale → Looking for partner - operator of Fast food restaurant. 
 Log in Login Name 
 Password 
 Cookies are not enabled. You must enable cookies before you
 can log in. Forgot your password? New user?   Info 
Document Actions

 Send this Print this 
 
Looking for partner - operator of Fast food restaurant.
 Editorial Rating: Average Rating: ( 37 votes ) Click to change your rating:   worthless bad average good great Our company just bought a BP gas station with fast food restaurant on a premises. The restaurant is closed right now. It is in a great shape and loaded with new equipment. It has 16’ grill, walking cooler and freezer, ovens, pizza ovens, salad bar, drive thru window and other equipment. We looking for experienced person who can operate or lease this restaurant. Chinese take outs or Philadelphia cheese steaks may be. 
 Price : FREE Details : 
Terms:

First 12 months is a trial period. Tenant can cancel his lease and get his deposit back after end of trial period.

Equipment deposit $20,000-$30,000 based on tenants credit history and restaurant management experience.

Lease 5 years + two five years options. Equipment deposit will be returned after end of first term.

The rent is:

1.       Months 1-3 the rent is $250/month

2.       Months 4-6 the rent is $500/month

3.       Months 6-18 the rent is $1,000/month

4.       Months 18-24 the rent is $1,500/month

5.       Months 25-48 the rent is $2,000/month

6.       Months 49-60 the rent is $2,200/month

7.       Months 61-120 the rent is $2,500/month

8.       Months 121-180 the rent is $3,000/month
 Store Sales : n/a Gas Sales (gallons) : n/a Rent : Negotiable Building : 1,200 sq ft Location Address : 8936 Frankstown rd City, State : Pittsburgh, PA ZIP : 15235 Type : Drive thru, fast food 

 Attached files 
 Floor plan by Sergei Gorlov   
 Looking for partner - operator of Fast food restaurant. 40.460829 -79.867552 
 All items created by seller in this section CITGO gas station and convenience store for sale in Philadelphia Want to buy a convenience store and Gas station? This is a great one - Citgo for sale in Philadelphia downtown. 15 years lease + 5 years option. Property for sale by owner for $1,600,000. Business for sale for $290,000 by landlord. Gasoline price is Rack+2c. 
Call Anna Maveela for details at 412-306-0269 x 2015. SOLD First year is trial. For sale or lease by owner. Minimum Investment. Will finance. Only $195,000 for everything!!! Gas station, Full size canopy, 4 MPD&apos;s, diesel, kerosene.
Store 900s.f. walking cooler. Five tanks - 3x 10,000 gallons single wall fiberglass for gasoline and 2x 4,000 catholically protected steel for Kerosene and Diesel. Everything is in good standing with PA DEP. To our best knowledge no evironmental problems.
As is. Property for sale or long term lease with option to buy.
Call Anna Maveela for details at 412-306-0269 x 2015.
Motivated seller. Sunoco A-plus in Pittsburgh Downtown - Great gas station with convenience store. Want to buy a convenience store? This is a great one - Sunoco A-plus for sale in Pittsburgh downtown.
For LEASE. For sale by owner. PROPERTY IS NOT FOR SALE.
Call Anna Maleeva (412)306-0269 x 2015 SOLD McMurray A-plus. 1,510,000 gallons in 2010. For sale by owner. Gas Sales - 1,510,000 gallons a year. Store Sales - $600,000 a year SOLD Gas station property for sale by owner - 215-888-8844 Boris Huge property
Great store 2,200 s.f.
4 MPD&apos;s
Full size canopy SOLD Sunoco in Cleveland, OH. $900,000/year store. 900,000 gallons. Only $90,000. Sunoco gas station and convenience store for sale. 5 minutes from Cleveland downtown. Great family business. For sale by owner. Lease 15 years. Beer and wine. Price $90,000 SOLD Looking for partner - operator of Fast food restaurant. Our company just bought a BP gas station with fast food restaurant on a premises. The restaurant is closed right now. It is in a great shape and loaded with new equipment. It has 16’ grill, walking cooler and freezer, ovens, pizza ovens, salad bar, drive thru window and other equipment. We looking for experienced person who can operate or lease this restaurant. Chinese take outs or Philadelphia cheese steaks may be. SOLD Cochran A-plus Gas station for Sale Sunoco A-plus. In great upscale neighborhood convenience store for sale.
You will love the area. Low cost of operation.
Not a state minimum on cigarettes. I am not a broker.
Call Sergei Gorlov 412-401-8290 SOLD Scottdale Sunoco Store Sales in 2005 - $1,020,000. 
Gasoline Sales in 2005 - 900,000 gallons. 
Scottdale, PA SOLD Braddock Shell Gas station with a kiosk 
 
 
 CITGO gas station and convenience store for sale in Philadelphia Dec 19, 2011 
 

 
 Sunoco A-plus in Pittsburgh Downtown - Great gas station with convenience store. Oct 05, 2011 
 

 
 GAS&amp;MART FOR SALE Jul 05, 2012 
 

 
 Owner Financing&amp;Available Immediately! Jun 28, 2012 
 

 
 Gilbarco Pumps Jun 16, 2012
	</body>
</document>
