<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003784" url="http://onlinebrandingsecretsexposed.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:56" support="1" score="0.0014813966454142423" bingtitle="Online Branding Secrets Exposed" webtitle="Online Branding Secrets
Exposed">
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>In your everyday life and mundane purchases, do you ever stop to think why your visit a particular fast food restaurant, drink a particular cola, prefer a particular ...</description>
	<body>
		“Leapfrog
Over All Your Competitors With These Simple Branding Secrets You Can
Apply Immediately!” 

 Discover
Simple Yet Powerful Techniques Successful Marketers Build Their
Businesses Upon...Then use These Techniques To Grow Your Own Business! 

 
 

 Date: 
 

 From
the Desktop of: Andre Niemand,CEO,MWL 

 Dear
Friend 

 In your everyday life and mundane
purchases, do you ever stop to think why your visit a particular fast
food restaurant, drink a particular cola, prefer a particular mobile
phone over all the multiple brands that exist in the market? 

 It&apos;s simple really. The unique selling
point of a particular product may be its branding. 

 The truth is that there are tons of
products or services in the market that are alike. 

 Cheeseburgers, soft drinks and cars
normally serve one or two functions yet because of branding, people may
perceive them to be unique, maybe even superior to other brands in the
market! 

 Some companies think that they can
pretty much get consumers to select them by simply dropping their
prices or being a jack of all trades. The problem is, most people would
have thought of that as a shortcut (read: lazy!) method of building a
business, when the truth is many smaller and unsuccessful businesses
normally resort to such a method without success. 

 So does building a brand mean you&apos;ll
have to spend heaps of cash on creating an out of this world tagline
and television commercials? 

 Of course not. You&apos;re an online
entrepreneur and there are tons of resources out there in the Internet
marketing world you can utilize to build your brand with ease.  

 You see, resources are not a problem
online. The biggest asset you will have to maximize, however, is the
thing between your ears–your brain. 

 There will be a fair bit of creativity,
some thinking and some research to do should you want to create a
powerful brand that breaks through the monotony of boring competitor
sites in the market, reaches out and grabs your prospect by the scruff
of the collar.  

 But it won&apos;t be tough, because thanks
to the many sites I&apos;ve created using a simple, effective style of
branding that anyone can easily utilize and build their own successful
brand like clock work! 

 Introducing:  
 
 Online
Branding Secrets  

 
 
 
 This
simple to execute, straight forward guide will reveal to you how you
can easily create a successful and powerful brand that your prospects
will recall as easily as McDonald&apos;s is associated with fast food and
Coke with soda! 

 You
will discover valuable chunks of branding advice such as:  
 
 
 
 
 The No.
1 mistake most marketers make in building a brand - DO NOT repeat this! 
 
 Some
proven, effective ways to creating a brand people will definitely
remember  
 
 One
important element to remember to have customers flocking back to you
time and again 
 
 How
choosing the right domain names can affect your branding for better or
worse!   
 
 Choosing
your logo and building your brand using the right words
without breaking a sweat! 
 
 Avoiding
bad first impressions of your brand and simple ways to do so! 
 
 Factors
to keep in mind when creating a successful webpage for your
business! 
 
 The
step-by step method of leveraging on your keywords for faster search
engine indexing   Maximizing
social media sites for faster brand exposure 
 
 And
much, much more! 

 Now if
you were to attend some &apos;guru&apos; &apos;s seminar or even an offline crash
course on marketing and branding it would probably set you back by a
few hundred dollars, probably even over a thousand!
Honestly, paying so much and only having 2-3 hours spent with that
expert seems like a waste of time and money!

Thank fully, I won&apos;t be doing that. I&apos;ve always believe in over
delivering so my customers trust me and look forward to dealing with me
again. 

Not to mention the fact that I look forward to our probable
relationship as customer and friend.
So after some consideration, I&apos;m offering this comprehensive, no B.S
guide to you for the low one time price of $ 27 . 

 In
fact, even after you&apos;ve gotten your hands on this guide, you can always
return it back if you feel it doesn&apos;t quite work out, thanks to the: 

  

 You
could walk away from this skeptical and invest huge amounts of cash to
do your branding. Sure it might have worked, but are you able to recoup
your losses through investment? And if you spent heaps on creating an
ineffective brand? Wouldn&apos;t that be a greater waste of time? 

 Online
Branding Secrets helps you create a successful brand without you
spending heaps of cash or time to do so...and you can start prospering
from your newfound business identity straightaway!
By the way, $27 is my introductory price but once I find too many
people using these solid traffic generation tactics the price will
increase. That&apos;s a given. 

 It&apos;s
time to seriously make your marketing job a whole lot easier by having
a recognized brand that sells by itself. Simply follow the link below,
and : 
 

 
 

 Are you
a visual learner? Do you find learning much easier when you are
literally shown how to do something? If you
do, you are not alone! 

 How
would you like to watch a series of videos, that show you exactly,
step-by-step, how to master the art of running branding campaigns in
just a few hours time? 

 See
here&apos;s the thing: I&apos;ve decided to convert the eBook to a complete video
training series. As I want to make sure I&apos;m able to deliver the utmost
quality to you, I spent close to one thousand dollars just to outsource
the video creation to a professional video producer.

 So
here&apos;s what you get: 

 You&apos;ll
Get Over 1 Hour Of Step-By-Step Videos
That Show You How -- Right Before Your Eyes! 

 

 The entire
video series
is presented using an easy step-by-step process that anyone can
follow.  
 
 
 
 This
awesome video training series will cut short your learning curve and
ensure you are able to pick up the skills with ease and skyrocket your
results! 

 In
fact, this online branding secrets video series is the most definitive
course to building a profitable brand for your business, even if you
have never been successful before!

So just click on the order button
below to brand yourself for just $27 . 

 The
difference between successful marketers and those who aren&apos;t is the
amount of action they take...so join the ranks of marketers earning
huge loads of massive profits online and... 
 
 


 Yours
Sincerely,

 

 

 


 Join
The Affiliate Program
	</body>
</document>
