<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003099" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/does-sonic-the-fast-food-restaurant-take-debit-cards" time="2012-07-12-19:13" support="11" score="0.03561560453957002" bingtitle="Does Sonic the fast food restaurant take debit cards? | ChaCha" webtitle="Does Sonic the fast food restaurant take debit cards? | ChaCha">
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000737" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>Does Sonic the fast food restaurant take debit cards? ... Every time you use a credit card, you actually are ... No, you cannot use any bank issued gift card ...</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
Does Sonic the fast food restaurant take debit cards? 

In: Business › Corporate Info › Debit Card 
 
Rate This Answer
 
Sonic, the fast food restaurant, does accept debit card s (use with pin) or debit cards used as credit (Visa or MC). Thanks! 
 Answered

 
 - 40 days ago at 12:24pm on Jun 02 2012 
Related Debit Card Questions

 
 What is the phone number for Ivy tech debit card customer service? 

Contact customer service at 866-629-5570.

in Business | 2 days ago via web 
 
 How do you get a debit card? 

To get a debit card you need to have a checking...

in Business | 8 days ago via sms text 
 
 How old do you have to get a debit card at city bank on your own? 

To obtain a checking account with a debit card,...

in Business | 25 days ago via sms text 
 
 Are there any interest fees associated with using a debit card? 

Debit cards do not accrue interest fees like cr...

in Business | 25 days ago via sms text 
 
 When was a debit card invented? 

Credit cards were first thrown down in 1951. Th...

in Business | 26 days ago via sms text 
 
 Can you use a debit card at mexican restaurants? 

Mexican restaurants such as Acapulco and El Tor...

in Business | 32 days ago via Android app 
 
 What is the hotline number for Mio pre paid debit cards? 

866-840-6461. ChaCha!

in Business | 39 days ago via sms text 
 
 What store can I find a $200 prepaid debit card? 

Prepaid $200 (and up) Mastercard debit cards ca...

in Business | 54 days ago via web 
 
 What does it mean when your debit card is captured? 

When a debit card is captured it means that a h...

in Business | 64 days ago via web 
 
 How old do you have to be to own a debit card? 

All you need is a state issued ID card and an a...

in Business | 69 days ago via Android app 
 
 Can a retail store go back on a debit card transaction? 

Please reword your question. Are you asking if ...

in Business | 144 days ago via sms text 
 
 How do you get negative money on a debit card? 

You get a negative balance when you buy somethi...

in Business | 164 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Week&apos;s Popular Questions for Debit Card 

 
 Can I use my ATM card as a debit card? 

A debit card is simply an ATM with a Visa or Ma...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 23 hr 2 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What the difference between debit and credit on a debit card? 

While they look alike, a debit card works more ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 19 hr 6 min ago via sms text 
 
 Do you need a bank account to have a debit card? 

Yes, you&apos;re subtracting money from your own ban...

in Corporate Info | 3 days ago via Android app 
 
 Does a walmart debit card work on the redbox for movies at the walmart store? 

Yes, as long as your debit card is charged with...

in Corporate Info | 2 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How does credit work on a debit and credit card? 

A debit card takes the form of a credit card, b...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 13 hr 19 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 Can you overdraft on a debit card? 

You should not be able to overdraft on a debit ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Can you cash visa debit gift cards at a bank for cash? 

Yeah baby, you can get cash! Use the ATM. ChaCha!

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 hr 11 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 Can you have a debit card when your 15? 

Yes, you can have a debit card when you are 15 ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 6 days ago via Android app 
 
 If your debit account is empty can you use your debit card as a credit card? 

If your bank account is empty you won&apos;t be a ab...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 6 days ago via web 
 
 Does In n Out accept debit cards? 

In&amp;Out Burgers website does not say if they a...

in Corporate Info | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Month&apos;s Popular Questions for Debit Card 

 
 What the difference between debit and credit on a debit card? 

While they look alike, a debit card works more ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 19 hr 6 min ago via sms text 
 
 Can I use my ATM card as a debit card? 

A debit card is simply an ATM with a Visa or Ma...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 23 hr 2 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 How old do you have to be to get a debit card? 

It varies from bank to bank. Generally, a paren...

in Law | 5 days ago via web 
 
 Can you use a debit card as a credit card? 

No, a debit card looks like a credit card, it w...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 12 hr 37 min ago via Android app 
 
 How old do you have to be to have a debit card? 

You have to be at least 18 years of age to have...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 16 hr 41 min ago via web 
 
 Do I need a pin number to use a Visa debit card? 

Debit cards usually use pin numbers so the mone...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 3 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 If your debit account is empty can you use your debit card as a credit card? 

If your bank account is empty you won&apos;t be a ab...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 6 days ago via web 
 
 Can you overdraft on a debit card? 

You should not be able to overdraft on a debit ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Does redbox take debit cards? 

Redbox credit/debit card readers are standardiz...

in Corporate Info | 4 days ago via sms text 
 
 Is Visa a credit card company or debit card company? 

Visa is a credit card processing company. They ...

in Corporate Info | 8 days ago via sms text 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Debit Card Galleries

 
 
 
 Fun Facts About Apple Inc. 
 Viewed 1344 times 
 
 
 
 Google Charged with Deceptive Ads 
 Viewed 28 times 
 
 
 
 The Impact of Brand Significance 
 
 
 
 Top 10 Celeb Endorsements 
 Viewed 112 times 
 
 
 
 Best Buy Closing Stores 
 Viewed 63 times 
 
 
 
 A 90s Kid&apos;s Christmas List 
 Viewed 1137793 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Debit Card Quizzes

 
 
 
 How Much Do You Really Know About Facebook? 
 Viewed 15061 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Know Company Slogans? 
 Viewed 16333 times 
 
 
 
 Is Your Boss a Jerk? 
 Viewed 2023 times 
 
 
 
 Can You Match the Insurance Company to its Slogan? 
 Viewed 5790 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Recognize That 90&apos;s Logo? 
 Viewed 8127 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Recognize These Famous Logos? 
 Viewed 583274 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
About Debit Card 
 
A debit card is a plastic card that enables the cardholder to withdraw money directly from their bank account or to make purchases which are charged directly to the bank account instead of charging on credit.

 More about Debit Card »
 
About Fast Food 
 
&apos;&apos;Fast food&apos;&apos; has become a regular part of people&apos;s vocabulary since the 1950&apos;s. The convenient, fast, and relatively cheap prices of fast food restaurants have made them some of the most popular stops for people on the move. Offering typical American foods like burgers, fries, and soft drinks, fast food restaurants have a definite American vibe and foothold.

 More about Fast Food »
 
Top Trends in Corporate Info 

 Bell Coupons» 
 
Top Trends in Business 

 Job Application» Savings» Rent» ATM» Resume» Brands» Visa» Work Permit» Bankruptcy» Interest Rate» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Hurt» Ford» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Business › Corporate Info › Debit Card 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
