<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003711" url="http://staugustine.com/news/business/2012-02-12/welcome-business-feb-12-2012" time="2012-07-12-19:52" support="1" score="0.0005978303482726836" bingtitle="Welcome Business: Feb. 12, 2012 | StAugustine.com" webtitle="Welcome Business: Feb. 12, 2012 | StAugustine.com">
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Parks; The Beaches; Wedding Guide; Maps &amp; Directions; De ... The Krystal Company, the iconic southern fast food restaurant ... Customers will receive a code on their receipt that ...</description>
	<body>
		Join Now!  |  Login 
 Forgot Password? Subscribe To The Paper Make StAugustine.com Your Homepage 
 Site Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! Search 
 
 Home News 
 St. Augustine Record Local News Local Videos Daily Jail Log Police Report Obituaries 
 Read Obituaries Submit Obituary 
 School News Business Florida News National News World News Archives St. Augustine History 
 The Nation&apos;s Oldest City Castillo de San Marcos Pedro Menendez Historic Churches Lightner Museum Henry Flagler Fort Matanzas Fort Mose Government House Bartram Trail Minorcans of St. Augustine 
 Archaeology Topic Public Employee Salaries Correction Request Form 
 Opinion Sports 
 High School High School Football High School Sports Topics Outdoors Recreation The Rant National Sports Surf Report Fishing With Capt. Sharky 
 Entertainment 
 Compass Surf The Drift Celebrity Slideshow Event Calendar Contests Arts Music Dining Puzzle Connection TV Listings Florida Lottery 
 Living 
 SA Deal Mall Wedding Guide Celebration Forms Health 
 Health Slideshow 
 Food 
 Recipes for Right Now Seasonal Themed Recipes 
 Celebrations 
 Read Celebrations Engagement Announcement Form Paid Wedding Announcement Form Free Wedding Announcement Form Anniversary Announcement Form Birth Announcement Form First Birthday Announcement Form 
 Best of St. Augustine Our Community Religion Seniors Garden Business Directory Local Clubs Subscribe to Record Hot Deals Video Tour of St. Johns County Specialty Publications 
 GUS! First Coast Community Journal Marsh Creek News Journal North Shores News Southern Comfort World Golf Village SJC Chamber Newsletter 
 
 Visitor&apos;s Guide 
 Lodging 
 Hotels&amp;Motels Bed&amp;Breakfasts Home&amp;Condo Rentals 
 Attractions Dining Shopping Spas&amp;Salons Outdoors 
 Explore Outdoors Golf Parks The Beaches 
 Wedding Guide Maps&amp;Directions 
 Resources 
 Advertise Manage My Subscriptions Subscribe to E-News&amp;Hot Deals Watch Local Video Buy Photos Contact Us About Us 
 StAugustine.com The St. Augustine Record Morris Communications Staff Directory 
 Business Directory Interact 
 Staff Blogs Community Blogs Create Blog Spotted Twitter Facebook 
 Archives Chamber of Commerce Council on Aging Lowest Gas Prices St. Johns County Offices Port,Waterway,Beach Commission Hurricane Guide 
 Classifieds 
 Place An Ad Garage Sales Merchandise Pets&amp;Animals Recreation Business&amp;Financial Legals 
 Legal Notices Legal Ads Online Fictitious Name Request Form Print Fictitious Name Request Form 2011 Delinquent Tax Listing 
 Service Directory 
 Jobs 
 Find A Job Post A Job Post A Resume 
 Autos 
 Drive Time Auto Classifieds 
 Homes 
 Find An Agent Homes For Sale Condos For Sale Land For Sale Commercial Property Homes/Apartments For Rent 
 
 Advertisement 
 86° Scattered clouds 
 MORE WEATHER Tides News / Business 
 
 
 Comment 
 Follow This Article 
Welcome Business: Feb. 12, 2012
 Posted:  February 12, 2012 - 1:01am Advertisement From staff Welcome Business: Feb. 12, 2012 February 17, 2012 4:38 PM EST Copyright 2012 St. Augustine Record. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 Salon Gallery 

Sayne Leonard opened Salon Gallery in December at 5575 A1A South, suite 111 in St. Augustine.

The salon provides technique cutting, styling, coloring, updos, Keratin treatment,perm, manicure, pedicure and facials.

Salon Gallery also carries hair care products.

The hours of operation are: 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. Tuesday; 10 to 5 p.m. Wednesday; 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. Thursday; 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Friday; and 9 a.m. to 4 p.m. on Saturday.

 

 Liberty Tax Service 

Liberty Tax Service opened a new office in St. Augustine. The new Liberty Tax is at 2790 U.S. 1 South and is open from 7 a.m. to 9 p.m. during tax season.

“We are excited to be expanding Liberty’s operations in St. Augustine,” said John Hewitt, CEO and Founder of Liberty Tax Service. “We pledge quality computerized tax preparation and superb customer service to the people of St. Augustine.”

The office is owned and operated by Andrew and Kyra Broskie. The office will employ 5 to 10 experienced tax preparers, marketers, and other office staff for the tax season. “We have a terrific staff including a retired IRS agent” Broskie says.

 

 Krystal 

The Krystal Company, the iconic southern fast food restaurant chain known for its famous hot, small, square Krystal burgers will open a new restaurant in St. Augustine at 6 a.m. on Monday. The restaurant is at 2370 State Road 16 and is the second Krystal location in St. Augustine.

Krystal will mark the grand opening of the restaurant by offering a free Sackful of Krystals every week for a year for 30 lucky customers.

Customers will receive a code on their receipt that will allow them to go to www.Krystal.com for a chance to enter. Every day for the first month, one winner will be chosen to receive a Sackful (12 Krystals) every week for a year.

Krystal will to offer Wi-Fi free to their customers.
 
 Comment 
 Follow This Article 0 
 Spotted 
 
 Please Note: You may have disabled JavaScript and/or CSS. Although this news content will be accessible, certain functionality is unavailable.

 Skip to News 

 «back 

 next» 
 
 
 Taylor Branch Speaks at Accord Luncheon Accord Breakfast&amp;Tour with Taylor Branch June 2012 Take The Record Wimbledon My Gallery NASCAR Sprint Cup Series Romper Room with Miss Virginia Thomas Jefferson Dinner 
 Most Viewed 
 
 Motorcycle crash victim remembered for humor, kindness   Three sexual offenders sentenced Tuesday   St. Augustine soldier&apos;s death at Fort Hood under investigation   
 
 Most Commented 
 
 Letter: Attacks on Obamacare are outright lies and half-truths   City to pay up for Picassos   Mother in abuse case drops battered spouse defense   
 
 Highest Rated 
 
 Mother in abuse case drops battered spouse defense   House District 17 candidates present agendas   12:30am Letter: Attacks on Obamacare are outright lies and half-truths   
 Advertisement Advertisement 
 Latest Updates 
 
 Viewed Commented Rated 
 
 Motorcycle crash victim remembered for humor, kindness   Three sexual offenders sentenced Tuesday   St. Augustine soldier&apos;s death at Fort Hood under investigation   
 
 Letter: Attacks on Obamacare are outright lies and half-truths   City to pay up for Picassos   Mother in abuse case drops battered spouse defense   
 
 Mother in abuse case drops battered spouse defense   House District 17 candidates present agendas   12:30am Letter: Attacks on Obamacare are outright lies and half-truths   
 
 Recent Comments 
 
 Negative comments abound! Mental Health Problems why? 
 Advertisement 
 Site Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! Search 
 
 Home Privacy Policy Advertise About Our Ads Contact Us Site Map Posting Rules Find St. Augustine Jobs Subscribe to Newsletter 
 
St. Augustine Record©2012. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
