<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003346" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?What-Are-Normal-Lipids-and-What-Can-Be-Done-to-Bring-Unhealthy-Lipid-Levels-Back-Into-a-Healthy-Range&amp;id=4703728" time="2012-07-12-19:29" support="3" score="0.002351391096147467" bingtitle="What Are Normal Lipids &amp; What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid ..." webtitle="What Are Normal LipidsWhat Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range">
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001169" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000277" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>... we gaze upon the dollar menu at our favorite fast food restaurant ... if allowed to go unchecked can lead to a number of ... If my test confirm that I don&apos;t have the normal ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Health and Fitness » Heart Disease Rob D. Hawkins 
 Diamond Author |   498 Articles 
 Joined: January 27, 2009 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
What Are Normal Lipids&amp;What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range

 By Rob D. Hawkins 
 
I believe most doctors will tell you that it is rare when a patient has a lipid profile done and normal lipids levels are found. Most of us are simply too busy to pay much attention to take the steps necessary to achieve and maintain normal lipids and quite honestly when we gaze upon the dollar menu at our favorite fast food restaurant it is probably not something we considered. But perhaps it should be!

Plain and simple lipids are blood fats that if allowed to go unchecked can lead to a number of very serious conditions including heart attack, stroke, and atherosclerosis. These tiny molecules are poorly soluble in water thus needing help in moving through the bloodstream and are paired with less water soluble lipoproteins.

There are five lipoproteins categories listed in order of density. They are: chylomicrons, very low density lipoproteins (VLDL), intermediate density lipoprotein (IDL), low density lipoprotein (LDL), and high density lipoprotein (HDL).

When evaluating normal lipids we will taking a look at total cholesterol, triglycerides, LDL, and HDL.

Each of these reading has a slightly different significance and importance. Generally normal lipids are 230 or less for cholesterol; 150 or less for triglycerides; 130 or less for LDL; and 50 or more for HDL.

These numbers should be adjusted by 15 percent or so if a person has any one of a number of coronary disease risk factors are present. This list includes obesity, smoking, inactivity, high blood pressure, diabetes or being borderline diabetic, and age (over 45 years old for men and over 55 years old women).

When reading your lipid profile you doctor may choose to evaluate whether normal lipids levels exists by viewing the results as ratios. For example the most common way lipid risk for hardening of the arteries (atherosclerosis) is evaluated is by comparing total cholesterol to HDL. This ratio should not exceed 4.5 to 1. Another common evaluation method used is comparing LDL (bad cholesterol) to HDL (good cholesterol).This ratio should not be more than 2.5 to 1.

 If my test confirm that I don&apos;t have the normal lipids reading I had hoped for what is the next step? 

There are a number of steps your doctor will likely suggest. They are a low saturated fat diet high in soluble fiber; daily exercise; weight management; smoking cessation; reducing stress; and depending on the physician possibly a glass of red wine nightly.

It is worth mentioning that in order to lower both cholesterol and triglycerides a moderate amount of polyunsaturated fat may be required. The most healthful source of polyunsaturated fat is cold water fatty fish such as salmon and tuna.

If the above steps are not successful in achieving normal lipid levels then one of a number of cholesterol/blood fat reducing medications may be prescribed such as statin medications or prescription strength niacin.

 Can supplements help? 

Most current research supports this idea. Some of the best examples include certain B vitamins (B6,B12,folic acid); omega 3 fish oil high in DHA/EPA; and natural cholesterol reduction supplements containing phytosterols or policosanol.
 
Rob D. Hawkins is an enthusiastic advocate for the use of safe and effective high quality alternitive health products and natural living, with over 10 years experience in the field. Learn more about natural remedies and natural health at Purchase Remedies.com 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Rob_D._Hawkins 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Health and Fitness: Heart-Disease 
 Rob D. Hawkins 
 Email Address: Subscribe Heart Disease Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Maintain Normal Cholesterol Level the Natural Way Maintaining Healthy Lipids Serum Cholesterol Levels Is Essential To Protect You From Heart Disease Maintain Normal Cholesterol Levels As If Your Life Depended On It Normal Range of Cholesterol Levels - Understanding the LDL-HDL Ratio Maintain Normal Triglyceride Levels for A Healthier Life A Lipids Diet Can Help Protect You Against Clogged And Blocked Arteries As Well As Heart Disease How To Manage Serum Lipids Cholesterol To Successfully Protect Yourself Against Heart Disease A Blood Lipids Test Will Provide Invaluable Information About The Risk For Heart And Artery Disease What Are The Ideal Cholesterol Levels For Men? The What, Why, and How of a Normal Cholesterol Range Fully Explained and How You Can Achieve It 
 
Recent Articles

 Heart Health: Which Fats Are Good for the Heart? Are Eggs In Your Diet Plan To Lower Cholesterol? Can Drinking Soda Increase Your Cholesterol Levels? Heart Healthy Diet - Foods To Prevent Heart Disease The Link Between Triglycerides and High Cholesterol Cardiovascular Translational Research Enhances the Patient Care Eating Mangoes Can Help Lower Triglycerides and Improve Heart Health Five Foods That Lower Cholesterol Fast How Certain Diets Lower Cholesterol Levels More Effectively Are You Taking Care of Your Heart? 
 
Submitted On July 20, 2010. Viewed 311 times. Word count: 518.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Hawkins, Rob D. &quot;What Are Normal Lipids&amp;What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range.&quot; What Are Normal Lipids&amp;What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range .
 20 Jul. 2010 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?What-­Are-­Normal-­Lipids-­and-­What-­Can-­Be-­Done-­to-­Bring-­Unhealthy-­Lipid-­Levels-­Back-­Into-­a-­Healthy-­Range&amp;id=4703728 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Hawkins, R. D. (2010, July 20). What Are Normal Lipids&amp;What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?What-­Are-­Normal-­Lipids-­and-­What-­Can-­Be-­Done-­to-­Bring-­Unhealthy-­Lipid-­Levels-­Back-­Into-­a-­Healthy-­Range&amp;id=4703728 Chicago Style Citation: 
Hawkins, Rob D. &quot;What Are Normal Lipids&amp;What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range.&quot; What Are Normal Lipids&amp;What Can Be Done to Bring Unhealthy Lipid Levels Back Into a Healthy Range EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?What-­Are-­Normal-­Lipids-­and-­What-­Can-­Be-­Done-­to-­Bring-­Unhealthy-­Lipid-­Levels-­Back-­Into-­a-­Healthy-­Range&amp;id=4703728 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
