<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003165" url="http://www.bignerds.com/papers/4424/Why-You-Not-Eat-Fast-Food/" time="2012-07-12-19:18" support="11" score="0.029104295497159604" bingtitle="Free Why You Should Not Eat At Fast Food Restaurants Term Paper ..." webtitle="Free Why You Should Not Eat at Fast Food Restaurants Term Paper | Poolgirl666">
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000875" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>Make fast food meals a treat and not a convenience 2. Avoid requesting larger sizes ... If you eat a Big Mac twice a week that’s $12.00, at the end of the month it will be ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Essay and Coursework Database 
 Saved Login Join 

 »  Order a Custom Essay »  Submit an Essay 
 
 Home Page » Politics 
 
Why You Should Not Eat at Fast Food Restaurants
 
Related Essays
 Advantages And disAdvantages Of EAting At Fast... ADVANTAGES AND DISADVANTAGES OF EATING AT FAST-FOOD RESTAURANTS
Life is moving at a very fast pace in today&apos;s world. Everyone is striving hard to compete with The Cause And Effect Of Fast Food Restaurants Rydell, S., Harnack, L., Oakes, J., Story, M., Jeffery, R.,&amp;French, S. (2008). Why Eat at Fast-Food Restaurants: Reported Reasons among Frequent Consumers. Journal Fast Food Restaurants And Our Eating Habits to get easily acquainted with luxury and laziness. This is where the concept of fast food restaurants figures. In a country like India where the cost of living is 
 Stats 
 
 Submitted by: poolgirl666 Date Added: 10 / 19 / 2008 Category: Politics Words | Pages: 476 | 2 Views: 3686 
 
 Save Essay Flag Essay 

 Similar Essays 
 
 Why You Should Not EAt At Fast Food Restaurants Why Fast Foods Aren&apos;t Healthy Report Of Fast Food Market Critically Examine The Development Of The... Fast Food Summary Paper Customer Prefernces On Fast Food Outlets Fast Food Fast Food Fast Food Consumption In America Sueing Fast Food 
 
Why You Should Not Eat at Fast Food Restaurants
 View Full Essay 
Why you should not eat at fast food restaurants

INTRODUCTION
How many of you eat fast food more than three times a week? Do you eat it because it tastes good? Do you eat it because it’s cheap or because it’s fast and convenient? Do you know where they get it from, or how they cook it or what they use to cook it? On the other hand, not all fast food joints are bad for you; the most important thing to keep in mind is to know what you are eating and making smart decisions. Do you ever wonder how clean the kitchen is or the cooking conditions that take place? There are three types of fast food dangers; Illness, obesity and fast food financial danger.
BODY
I. Illnesses caused by fast foods (M. Mayntz)
A. Food Poisoning
1. Food poisoning is one of today’s most visible fast food scares.
2. Food poisoning comes from two main causes
a. Unsanitary cooking conditions
b. Improperly cooked food


II. Obesity from eating too much fast food (Dateline)
A. Obesity is a growing concern that affects all age groups but is more effective on people who eat fast food meals several times a week.
B. Making smart choices
1. Drink water instead of soda
2. Choose healthier side items
3. Opt for small portions or split the meal
4. Skip heavy condiments such as mayo or ketchup
 C. Supersize Me is
III. Fast food financial dangers
A. Many people don’t realize the fast food financial danger that can quickly take over their wallet.
B. The average cost for a single person can range up the 5-7 dollars; however these costs can quickly escalate when eating at these fast food restaurants multiple times a week.
1. Make fast food meals a treat and not a convenience
2. Avoid requesting larger sizes that add more to the bill
3. Use coupons and special deals to enjoy your treat at a lower cost
C. If you eat a Big Mac twice a week that’s $12.00, at the end of the month it will be $48.00 and at the end of the year it come out to be around $576.00. 



Conclusion...
 
Sign Up for a Free Account to View this Essay. Sign Up Now. It&apos;s Free! 
 Enter keyword: 
©2012 BigNerds.com

 Help Contact Us Terms of Service Privacy Policy Copyright Information Advertise With Us
	</body>
</document>
