<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003956" url="http://www.spokanefitnesscoach.com/spokane-wpblog/2009/12/10/eating-healthy-in-spokane-person-time-eat-out/" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="1" score="0.001390866850416705" bingtitle="Eating Healthy in Spokane for the Person who only has Time to Eat ..." webtitle="Eating Healthy in Spokane for the Person who only has Time to Eat Out. | Spokane Fitness Secrets">
			<query id="000871" bing-rank="162"/>
	<description>... to know that in Spokane you can eat out and still have a healthy meal. ... Although eating at a fast food restaurant is for the most ... Next on the line would be a grilled ...</description>
	<body>
		Eating Healthy in Spokane for the Person who only has Time to Eat Out.
 Thursday, December 10th, 2009 
 Eating Out in Spokane can be done in a healthy manner. 

 In Spokane there are several people who are so busy with work, working out, and life that the best way for them to get something to eat is to eat out in the closest restaurant. Eating out can pose a problem if you want to keep that unwanted fat off. There are so many great tasting foods on that menu that are not so great for your figure. In this article I will give you some ideas on what to eat when you do eat out. This information is all based on assuming that you work out on a regular basis. If you do not, this article is not for you. If are not working out on a regularly basis and would like to start on a great workout click here . 

 
 

 How to Eat Out Fast Food Style 

 

 




It is a relief to know that in Spokane you can eat out and still have a healthy meal. Let’s start with the fast food chains that are notorious for adding the unwanted inches. Although eating at a fast food restaurant is for the most part a big “no no” and if you have a personal trainer he or she would probably make you pay in your next workout for eating there. But if you do the best thing you can order is a grilled chicken salad of some kind. Next on the line would be a grilled chicken sandwich with no mayo. And absolutely NO French Fries! If you must have fries, be sure to run 10 miles afterwards to burn those fat calories. Sandwich shops are pretty safe as long as you stay away from a lot of cheese and mayo.



 How to Eat Out Restaurant Style 

 

Spokane has some great restaurants for eating out at. Eating out at a sit down restaurant can be a lot better than fast food. For the most part a good sit down restaurant will have a healthy category on their menu. Ordering from this category is pretty safe and for the most is a healthy meal that includes vegetables, protein, etc. Also ordering a grilled chicken salad of some kind will work as well. One of the main problems with out at a sit down restaurant is the portion size you get. The portions are usually big which can really pack on the calories. So a good practice is to ask for a to-go box as your order so when your meal comes out place half of it in that to-go box. This helps you not eat the whole thing unconsciously. Also we tend to forget that our drinks have calories too. So it is important to stay away from soda or high sugar drinks. If you have an alcoholic beverage, be sure to keep it at one or two. I know that is hard to do after a hard day at work but doing this will help keep the calories down. For more help on a great eating plan click here .




 Related posts: 

 What’s for Dinner Spokane? Healthy Eating For Those On The Run. Here it is, the age old question plagued by busy people everywhere, “What’s for dinner Spokane?”   This week you... Spokane Fast Food: Is a healthy kids meal an option? If you think that ordering a Spokane Fast Food kids meal might save you on calories, fat and salt because... Healthy Eating from Spokane Farmer’s Markets Summer is wrapping up but it’s not too late to take advantage of the Spokane  Farmer’s Markets that make their... 5 tips to save when eating healthy Often times people think eating healthy is expensive, although in the long run a cheap diet of junk food will... Three Good Habits for You Spokane, #3 Healthy Spokane Food Part 3 of 3 Good Habit #3 is Healthy Spokane Food Even with the good habits I have started, I... Spokane eating and more eating (how to recover)… I hope you had a great Christmas and time with your family. I sure did. Lots of fun and lots... Packing a Healthy Spokane School Lunch Packing a healthy Spokane school lunch for your child can be tricky.  Many of us have picky eaters, kids who... 

 
 Go To Spokane Fitness Coach Home Page... 



 
 


 Find out how you too can get in Amazing Shape... 

 





 
 
 
Spokane Fitness Secrets Navigation 
 Home | Free Consultation | Ultimate Body DVD | Free Resources | Blog | Success Stories | FAQ | Contact 

 Spokane Personal Training Programs 
 Fitness Spokane WA Main | Spokane Personal Training Website | Super Shape Personal Training Spokane WA | Spokane Personal Trainer Advantages | The Best Personal Trainers In Spokane WA | Personal Trainers Spokane WA Progression | Guaranteed Spokane Personal Trainer Success 

 Other Helpful SpokaneFitnessCoach.com Pages 
 Secrets Of Health Clubs Spokane WA | Spokane Gyms Directory | How To Pick Out Of Spokane Fitness Centers | The Truth About Super Supplements Spokane | Nutrition Spokane Resources | Nutritionist Spokane Listings | Fitness Spokane WA Tips Blog | Fitness Marketing
	</body>
</document>
