<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003914" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/10/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343.html" time="2012-07-12-20:05" support="1" score="0.0010948685380048938" bingtitle="Best Fast Food Chains: Major Survey Says Chick-Fil-A, Panera ..." webtitle="Best Fast Food Chains: Major Survey Says Chick-Fil-A, Panera, Chipotle Are America&apos;s Favorites">
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>It&apos;s pretty easy to say which fast food chain is the biggest. By number of restaurants? ... Mitt Romney&apos;s Vice Presidential Pick: Signs Point To ...</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 Fast Food E. Coli Food Food Informants 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 42k Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k GOP Votes To Repeal Obamacare Again 21k Brewer&apos;s Anti-Gay Benefits Stance Prompts Protest Resignation 4k House GOP&apos;s Obamacare Repeal Efforts Reportedly Cost Nearly $50 Million 6k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Entertainment 
 Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 1k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 47 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 14 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 Business 
 WATCH: Evidence Ex-Wall Street Trader May Have Taken Cyanide 2k Paul Krugman Slams Times Colleague, CNBC 3k Here Are The 16 Banks Under Investigation Over The Libor Scandal 369 Evander Holyfield&apos;s Unable To Avoid Foreclosure On $14 Million Mansion 693 Missing Banker: I &apos;Hurt The People I Was Trying To Help&apos; 432 
 Like 34k   Go to Business More in Business 
 Small Business Money 
 You might also like 
 World Tech Media Culture Sports Weird News Crime 
 Media 
 Katie Couric Speaks Out About Ann Curry&apos;s &apos;Today&apos; Ouster 403 Gallup: Confidence In TV News At New Low 4k Anderson Cooper&apos;s Coming Out Was Planned For Months 256 WATCH: Soledad O&apos;Brien Cringes At Biden&apos;s Sex Joke 338 WATCH: Greg Gutfeld Freaks Out 1k 
 Like 46k   Go to Media More in Media 
 Eat The Press Calderone: The Backstory 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment TV Comedy Arts Books Religion Moviefone 
 Kitchen Daily 
 Beat The Heat With 15 No-Cook Meals 12 Ways To Turn Your Ugly Pie Into A Showstopper 40 Kitchen Trick: Preserve Fresh Herbs In Frozen Olive Oil Food Debate: Does Ketchup Belong On Hot Dogs? 225 Rise And Shine: 10 Mouth-Watering Eggs Benedicts 
 Like 37k   Go to Kitchen Daily More in Kitchen Daily 
 Recipes Baking Breakfast Chefs and Experts Entertaining Healthy Eating Dinner Tonight Easter Kitchen Daily Videos 
 You might also like 
 Food 
 Travel 
 PHOTOS: Guess Who Has The Worst Traffic? 433 Concordia Captain Makes Shocking Revelations 941 Boo: Now The World&apos;s Cutest Airline Spokesman 60 70-Year-Old Minister Takes 7000th Coaster Ride 53 Theme Park Sued For Barring Amputees From Coaster 78 
 Like 24k   Go to Travel More in Travel 
 Travel Video Destinations Themed Guides TSA Airlines 
 You might also like 
 Food Culture World GPS for the Soul Kitchen Daily 
 Green 
 PHOTOS: Adorable Baby Elephant Saved By Mother 359 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 238 Waldo Canyon Fire Fully Contained 97 Young Man Mysteriously Found Dead Inside Tiger Den 79 A &apos;Snow Monster&apos; In Mount Rainier Creek 268 
 Like 104k   Go to Green More in Green 
 Energy Climate Change Animals Green Tech Green Holiday 
 You might also like 
 Politics Food World Science Healthy Living 
 Tech 
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately 897 The Mildly Fabulous Story Of The First Photo Posted To The Internet 207 Is The U.S. Government Planning To Secret Super-Scanners? 515 WATCH: Conservative Group Calls For Boycott Of Google 1k 11 Things You Should Never Do On OkCupid 242 
 Like 54k   Go to Tech More in Tech 
 Best of TED Social Media 
 You might also like 
 Small Business Green Science New York San Francisco TechCrunch Engadget Joystiq 
 Comedy 
 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh 790 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 14 15 Dogs Receiving The Best News Ever 33 Seth Meyers Will NOT Make Big Move 118 
 Like 105k   Go to Comedy More in Comedy 
 Funny Videos Comedy Club Political Humor Original Videos Crossing The Line 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment Weird News College Arts Culture 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 Food 
 Recipes Chefs Restaurants Desserts Cocktails Wine Beer 
 
 HuffPost Social Reading Some error occurred 
 Login with Facebook to see what your friends are reading Enable Social Reading i 
 
 Settings 
 Read Share Settings Share everything I read Share only things safe for work Dont share what I&apos;m reading 
 
 Read Share History Learn More 
 
 
Best Fast Food Chains: Major Survey Says Chick-Fil-A, Panera, Chipotle Are America&apos;s Favorites
 
 First Posted: 02/10/2012 12:21 pm   Updated: 02/14/2012 5:53 pm 
 
share this story
 Follow   Fast Food ,   Video , Panera Bread , Best Fast Food Chains , Chick-Fil-a , Chipotle , Fast Food Chain Survey , Fast Food Industry , Favorite Fast Food Chains , Food News 

It&apos;s pretty easy to say which fast food chain is the biggest. By number of restaurants? Subway . By total revenue? McDonald&apos;s .

Deciding which is the best is tougher. It&apos;s an inherently subjective process. And there&apos;s nothing in the restaurant chain world to things like the National Book Awards, Grammy&apos;s or Westminster Best-In-Show to place stamps of approval on especially delicious fries from a drive-thru.

All we have are surveys. In September, Zagat released its ranking of fast food chains , determining that Five Guys was the most popular in the country. A comprehensive survey from research firm MarketForce, released in August, came up with the same result . Together, they gave Five Guys plenty of reason to be smug.

Industry research firm Sandelman and Assoc. just released the results of a huge new survey on fast food , based on the responses of 100,000 diners, far more than either Zagat or MarketForce. The final rankings are based on the responses of people who actually visited the restaurants in question in the three months before taking the survey. The survey ranked restaurants by the number of diners who said their experience had been &quot;excellent.&quot;

Five Guys, though it does well, is not the winner. Neither is In-N-Out, another perennial contender in these types of surveys. (Though it&apos;s worth noting that, as a commenter points out, the final results weren&apos;t so far off from the Zagat rankings by rating , rather than popularity.) Click through below to find out who is, among chains with at least 500 outposts:


 10. Whataburger 1  of 12 FIRST SLIDE PREVIOUS SLIDE NEXT SLIDESHOW Whataburger has been in the fast food business since 1950, as long as almost anyone out there. But perhaps because they&apos;ve been modest in their expansion strategy, focusing on the South, they&apos;ve done a pretty good job maintaining high quality, with 45% of survey respondents saying they had an excellent time in their last experience at the chain. READ WHOLE POST Denny&apos;s &apos;Tour Of America&apos; Menu Features Regional Favorites (PHOTOS) Fast Food Workers Of Reddit Tell You What Not To Eat Oscar Mayer To Eliminate Gestation Crates By 2022 8 Super Expensive Bucket List Wines 8 Of Our Favorite Restaurants, Bars And Cafes From Television History (VIDEO) Bongiovi Pasta Sauces Taste Test: They&apos;re Halfway There (Sorry, We Couldn&apos;t Resist) PLAY FULLSCREEN ZOOM SHARE THIS SLIDE  Whataburger has been in the fast food business since 1950, as long as almost anyone out there. But perhaps because they&apos;ve been modest in their expansion strategy, focusing on the South, they&apos;ve done a pretty good job maintaining high quality, with 45% of survey respondents saying they had an excellent time in their last experience at the chain. MORE SLIDESHOWS NEXT &gt;   |   &lt; PREV Denny&apos;s &apos;Tour Of America&apos; Menu Features Regional Favorites (PHOTOS) Fast Food Workers Of Reddit Tell You What Not To Eat Oscar Mayer To Eliminate Gestation Crates By 2022 8 Super Expensive Bucket List Wines 8 Of Our Favorite Restaurants, Bars And Cafes From Television History (VIDEO) Bongiovi Pasta Sauces Taste Test: They&apos;re Halfway There (Sorry, We Couldn&apos;t Resist) RATE IT!   |   VOTE Not My Thing Love It! CURRENT TOP 5 PICK YOUR OWN TOP 5 USERS WHO VOTED NEW! CREATE YOUR OWN SLIDESHOW 10. Whataburger   1  / 12 SHARE THIS SLIDE Whataburger has been in the fast food business since 1950, as long as almost anyone out there. But perhaps because they&apos;ve been modest in their expansion strategy, focusing on the South, they&apos;ve done a pretty good job maintaining high quality, with 45% of survey respondents saying they had an excellent time in their last experience at the chain. ADVERTISEMENT CURRENT TOP 5 SLIDES RATE THIS PHOTO VOTE Not My Thing Love It! USERS WHO VOTED ON THIS SLIDE SLIDESHOW THUMBNAILS 


 CORRECTION: This article originally contained several typos. The company that released the survey is called Sandelman and Assoc., not Sandleman and Associates. Survey respondents were required to have dined at the restaurant in question within the last three months, not the last six months. And we failed to mention that slideshow above includes only chains with at least 500 outposts; the full results include several chains with high ratings but fewer than 500 locations. 
 FOLLOW 
 HUFFPOST FOOD ON Facebook: Like 17k Twitter:   Get Alerts CONTRIBUTE TO THIS STORY 
 Send Corrections Send us a Link Contact us 

 Send a Tip Send Photos/Videos Comment 
 
 
 Fast Food Video 
 It&apos;s pretty easy to say which fast food chain is the biggest. By number of restaurants? Subway. By total revenue? McDonald&apos;s. 

Deciding which is the best is tougher. It&apos;s an inherently subjective p... It&apos;s pretty easy to say which fast food chain is the biggest. By number of restaurants? Subway. By total revenue? McDonald&apos;s. 

Deciding which is the best is tougher. It&apos;s an inherently subjective p...   Loading... TOP LINKS ON THIS TOPIC 1 of 5 
 Best fast-food chains in the world 
 
 WOOOOHOOOO Chefette made the list of Best Fast Food Chains in the World! 
 
 Proud to be Pinoy: Jollibee named one of the best fast-food chains in the world #fb #in 
 
 Best Fast Food Chains: Major Survey Reveals Chick-Fil-A, Panera, Chipotle As America&apos;s Favorites: It&apos;s pretty ea... 
 
 Best and Worst Fast Food Kids&apos; Meals | Healthy Living - Yahoo! Shine 
 
 10 Best Japanese Fast Food Chains - Japan Talk 
 
 Publix Top-Rated in Customer Experience 
 
 Top 10 Best Fast Food Resturant Chains 
 
 Best Online Colleges: 8 Delicious Fast Food Items You Won&apos;t Find in ...: Many of our fast food chains in America... 
 
 10 Best Japanese Fast Food Chains - Japan Talk | The asian food gazette. | Scoop.it 
 
 Off The Fast Food Diet lvY: .WQm 
 
 Off The Fast Food Diet URj: .hML 
 
 Jollibee&apos;s Success Through Their Expansions Qzv: .ZxD 
 
 Free Range Chicken? How About Free Range Employees? | Fistful of Talent 
 
 The Restaurant Development Summit: An Overview on Vimeo 
 Around the Web: 

 Fast Food Survey | Zagat 

 The best and the worst fast food restaurants review | Open Travel Info 

 America&apos;s Top 10 Healthiest Fast Food Restaurants - Eating - Health ... 

 Top Fast Food Restaurants - Chef Reviews of Best Fast Food ... 

 Top 16 Awesome Fast Food Restaurants 

 The Top 13 Fast Food Chains | The Top 13 | www.thetop13.com 

 Best Fast-Food Chains? &apos;Consumer Reports&apos; Readers Weigh In ... 

 Filed by Joe Satran  |  
 More in Food... 

 Obesity in Asia: American Fast Food Changing... Marion Cunningham Dead: Home Cooking Guru, Dies... $3,100 Pie Auctioned In Missouri Might Be... Coca-Cola Addiction: UK Teen Zoe Cross Hospitalized...     
 Comments 411 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 
Previewing Your Comment.
This comment has not yet been posted You have exceeded your word limit by   words. Please click the &quot;Edit&quot; button and shorten your comment.

 Post Comment Edit Cancel 

You can post to us this information Contact us Click here to leave a comment.

HuffPost High School welcomes a lively, thoughtful debate in the comment section. Keep in mind that the articles here are penned by young authors, so please keep criticism respectful, and help us to keep this a safe and supportive place for writers of all ages to contribute. Post Comment Preview Comment To reply to a Comment: Click &quot;Reply&quot; at the bottom of the comment; after being approved your comment will appear directly underneath the comment you replied to. Post Comment Preview Comment To reply to a Comment: Click &quot;Reply&quot; at the bottom of the comment; after being approved your comment will appear directly underneath the comment you replied to. 
 Share your Comment: 
 Post to Facebook. Post to Blogger. Post to Twitter. Post to WordPress. Post to TypePad. Post to Tumblr. Post to Yahoo! 
 Blogger login: Blogger password: Select blog:   refresh list Remember me: 
 
 Wordpress host: Wordpress login: Wordpress password: Remember me: 
 
 TypePad host: TypePad login: TypePad password: Select blog:   refresh list Remember me: 
 
 Tumblr login: Tumblr password: Remember me: 
 Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Recency  |  Popularity Page:  1   2   3   4   5   Next ›   Last »  (11 total) HUFFPOST SUPER USER Sean Hobbins insert witticism 28 Fans 11:34 AM on 02/27/2012 I wish Whataburger would spread. They make a far superior fast food burger than anyone except Five Guys and In-N-Out Sean_Hobbins: I wish Whataburger would spread. They make a far superior http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Sean_Hobbins/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_137507130.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Joe Bob Jones 1 Fans 02:55 AM on 02/26/2012 Chick-Fil-A. Not allowed. Grounded. Bigoted, and publicly so, they can go suck on their fil-a. Joe_Bob_Jones: Chick-Fil-A. Not allowed. Grounded. Bigoted, and publicly so, they can http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Joe_Bob_Jones/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_137281368.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 rbjllj 2 Fans 12:08 PM on 02/16/2012 People need to learn personal accountabi­lity of what they eat or drink for that matter.

People are all too willing to slam the fast food industry for making people fat. But yet they might not consider their cappucinos, latte&apos;s, sodas, and other high calorie or high sugar drinks.

People need to educate themselves of what calories they are having. If a restaurant doesn&apos;t disclose it, then don&apos;t eat there.

Starbucks has quite a few calorie disasters in a cup. Put it this way, would you eat a cupcake or a big mac on the go? But yet some of the cals are equal to that and some are even more than that for the over priced, sugar and calorie laden cappucinos, frappucinos, and lattes. rbjllj: People need to learn personal accountabiÂ­lity of what they eat http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/rbjllj/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135281498.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 zest 784 Fans 11:30 AM on 02/15/2012 Chick-fil-a is number one in sales and number one is discriminating against hiring gays, atheists, and any religious denomination except baptist. zest: Chick-fil-a is number one in sales and number one is http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/zest/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135064202.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER flyinghigh0905 26 Fans   10:05 AM on 02/15/2012 I can&apos;t bring myself to eat Chipotle. This is because of a South Park episode, where Billy Mayes advertises for a product called Chipotle-Away, designed to clean the blood out of a chipotle eater&apos;s underwear after eating Chipotle. I&apos;m sure it&apos;s just Parker and Stone poking fun, but I just can&apos;t do it. flyinghigh0905: I can&apos;t bring myself to eat Chipotle. This is because http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/flyinghigh0905/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135047569.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER PrairieGayCompanion Everything red will be blue again. 981 Fans   09:55 PM on 02/13/2012 I have only eaten at Five Guys once and it was the most greasy, disgusting thing I&apos;ve ever tried to eat, and I&apos;ve had lots of things in my mouth. PrairieGayCompanion: I have only eaten at Five Guys once and it http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PrairieGayCompanion/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134784064.html History  | Permalink  | Share it hemiram 12 Fans 02:21 AM on 02/15/2012 180 degrees from my only visit. It was great and I have to fight the urge to go back every time I&apos;m near the place. Awesome! hemiram: 180 degrees from my only visit. It was great and http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/hemiram/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135013167.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER nychaseter Socialism for the rich and Capitalism for the poor 191 Fans   11:08 AM on 02/25/2012 Their burgers are ok. If I can&apos;t order a burger how I want it (temperature cooked), a place won&apos;t make the list; well done isn&apos;t gonna cut it with me. As far as chain restaurant&apos;s go, no one does a better burger than Ted&apos;s Montana Grill. They&apos;re ot those hard, dense, factory-pressed burgers. The meat is flavorful, always juicy, crumbly, light patties. Five Guys are ok, but they&apos;re strictly fast food quality. nychaseter: Their burgers are ok. If I can&apos;t order a burger http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/nychaseter/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_137145283.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER grailknight is happily godless 181 Fans 09:12 PM on 02/13/2012 Zaxby&apos;s chicken fingers? Silly, chickens don&apos;t have fingers! grailknight: Zaxby&apos;s chicken fingers? Silly, chickens don&apos;t have fingers! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/grailknight/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134777522.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Food Review 101 Web-Site 1 Fans 08:23 PM on 02/13/2012 Chipotle all the way Food_Review_101_Web-Site: Chipotle all the way http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Food_Review_101_Web-Site/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134769678.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER makebofapay 764 Fans 06:08 PM on 02/13/2012 No wonder we have an epidemic of diabetes and obesity in this country. If you want to be healthy and stay healthy don&apos;t eat in any of these places--ever. Learn to cook healthy foods yourself. It&apos;s NOT hard! Maybe some day someone will come up with a chain restaurant that is truly healthy and delicious. Until then, figure out how to get and stay healthy. There is a ton of information everywhere on how to do this. makebofapay: No wonder we have an epidemic of diabetes and obesity http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/makebofapay/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134745357.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER flyinghigh0905 26 Fans   10:01 AM on 02/15/2012 You should contact corporate instead. flyinghigh0905: You should contact corporate instead. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/flyinghigh0905/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135046837.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER flyinghigh0905 26 Fans   10:02 AM on 02/15/2012 haha oopsy wrong post. flyinghigh0905: haha oopsy wrong post. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/flyinghigh0905/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135047096.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER gumbygirl That&apos;s Princess Smarty-Pants to you, buster! 28 Fans 05:58 PM on 02/13/2012 I got the worst case of food poisoning once from Panera&apos;s mushroom soup. When I was able to drag myself out of the bathroom for a minute I called them to let them know. I was treated to a nasty, expletive laced rant from their manager for my trouble. Needless to say, I haven&apos;t been back since. gumbygirl: I got the worst case of food poisoning once from http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/gumbygirl/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134743210.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER flyinghigh0905 26 Fans   10:02 AM on 02/15/2012 Oops I meant to write down here... that you should call corporate. flyinghigh0905: Oops I meant to write down here... that you should http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/flyinghigh0905/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_135047057.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 OutAtFirst Believe it! You don&apos;t know how to text and drive 572 Fans 05:24 PM on 02/13/2012 Chick-fil-A uses way too much salt. After I eat there I spend the rest of the afternoon looking for drinking fountains. OutAtFirst: Chick-fil-A uses way too much salt. After I eat there http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/OutAtFirst/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134735986.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 baxtron tek phlarpt 296 Fans 01:41 PM on 02/13/2012 couldn&apos;t baxtron: couldn&apos;t http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/baxtron/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134684466.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST COMMUNITY MODERATOR BuckyJamesDio This monkey&apos;s going to Heaven. 843 Fans 05:40 PM on 02/13/2012 Apparently. BuckyJamesDio: Apparently. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/BuckyJamesDio/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134739423.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 baxtron tek phlarpt 296 Fans 01:40 PM on 02/13/2012 Unable to order Jimmy John&apos;s in downtown St. Paul. The potheads working there had the music blaring so loud, I could hear myself think. And I&apos;m under the age of 40. baxtron: Unable to order Jimmy John&apos;s in downtown St. Paul. The http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/baxtron/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134684401.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER DavidMG OWS Senior Citizen 364 Fans   01:57 PM on 02/12/2012 You&apos;ll find 28oo healthy eateries throughout the US in &quot;Healthy Highways.&quot; DavidMG: You&apos;ll find 28oo healthy eateries throughout the US in&quot;Healthy http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/DavidMG/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134526768.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER exilist 45 Fans 01:13 PM on 02/12/2012 Wienerschnitzel! exilist: Wienerschnitzel! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/exilist/best-fast-food-chains_n_1268343_134519868.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
     Page:  1   2   3   4   5   Next ›   Last »  (11 total) new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost i8Qz06fBrewk88y62oY44E4%2BS3qwa%2BYV0tg%2B0VQGaPukWXz8TJR%2BPZ86DflztAzNPrbRiXZxawxQQsl3l2a4abEdyH7Tgt%2Fn 0mkc7VOLHyLE7zMt3PKHFn%2FncBBtYsHFioCP6w87o4QvSV9HVQrUq6e5XQ66X02Q9%2Fb%2BnzHs2mXnTWCyTNNH9Eu%2BVQQvBt5f 1 of 2 Excedrin Recall: When Is The Migraine Medicine Coming Back? 
 Like 156 WATCH: Cookie Monster Sings &apos;Share It Maybe&apos; 
 Like 5k The Unlikely Celeb Katie Holmes Turned To For Divorce Advice? 
 Like 6 17 Ways To Be A Good Daughter 
 Like 1k Is Sex Better Without An Orgasm? 
 Like 123 18 Signs You&apos;re About To Cheat 
 Like 92 Can Oral Sex Cure Morning Sickness? 
 Like 125 Will Vera Wang&apos;s Brand Survive Her Split? 
 Like 10 Love Can Grow Out Of Casual Sex, Says Study 
 Like 369 Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of HuffPost Food Group 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
