<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003197" url="http://www.vegsource.com/news/2011/02/former-mcdonalds-executives-to-start-healthy-fast-food-chain.html" time="2012-07-12-19:20" support="3" score="0.004153241782521189" bingtitle="Former McDonald&apos;s executives to start healthy fast-food chain ..." webtitle="Former McDonald&apos;s executives to start healthy fast-food chain - Vegsource.com">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>Of course, if the food doesn&apos;t taste good, nobody will ... Receive email notification of further comments. ... Caldwell Esselstyn Jr. MD &amp; Dean Ornish MD Explain Bill...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, July 12, 2012
 
 
 
 
 Home Store Discuss Food Video Health Green Celebs World Lifestyle Animals Homeschool 
 
Food
   
Former McDonald&apos;s executives to start healthy fast-food chain
 
02/14/11


 

 
 Read More: fast food , mcdonald&apos;s , tal ronnen , vegan 
 
 
 
 Get VegSource Alerts
 
First Name
 
Email
 
 Share This Page With a Friend 
 
 Print This Page 
 
 Comments 
 
Email This Story to a Friend
 Your friend&apos;s email address: 
 Your email address: 
 Message (optional): 
 
I&apos;ve often mentioned the possibility of some celebrity opening up a fast-food chain with options for vegan and vegetarians, but it looks like it will take a former McDonald&apos;s executive to make it a reality.

Founder Stephen Sidwell and CEO Mike Roberts recently announced plans to launch LYFE (&quot;Love Your Food Everyday&quot;) Kitchen, a transformational, socially responsible &quot;lyfestyle&quot; brand that will open in Palo Alto, Calif., this summer.

Roberts, who previously oversaw more than 31,000 McDonald&apos;s restaurants in 118 countries, resigned as president and chief operating officer of the fast-food empire in 2006. He was approached by Sidwell, an investment banker, and the two agreed that the time was ripe for a healthy fast-food option.

Of course, if the food doesn&apos;t taste good, nobody will buy it—no matter how well it&apos;s branded. To complete that part of the puzzle, Roberts and Sidwell turned to Chef Art Smith, former personal chef to Oprah Winfrey and a two-time James Beard Foundation Award winner. They also brought on Chef Tal Ronnen, regarded as one of the most groundbreaking vegan and vegetarian chefs.

&quot;With two celebrated, taste-making chefs and a talented team of leaders and advisers, we believe LYFE Kitchen is a response to one of America&apos;s most significant, unmet needs: the consumer&apos;s demand for delicious, affordable food that is good for you,&quot; said Roberts. &quot;We also plan to become a part of the Palo Alto community and begin giving back right away.&quot;

According to the release, no item on the menu will contain more than 600 calories, with each featuring responsibly sourced ingredients from local farms and &quot;sustainable whenever possible.&quot;
 
 Read the whole story here .

 
 

 


FACEBOOK COMMENTS:
 
 
4 Comments | Leave a comment 
 
Very cool!
 Posted by: VeganMarr | February 15, 2011 12:24 AM | Reply Score: 0 ( 0 votes cast) 
Good luck to them. We avoid fast food places like the plague - it&apos;s a waste of money. Given that the past 30 years has been based upon credit and debt the entire collection of big box retailers and fast food joints that we see around us will crumble into history. The 60&apos;s and 70&apos;s should be the new normal - something more sustainable instead of people living wayyyyy beyond their means.
It&apos;s about time people got real jobs doing real work. One can&apos;t build an economy by borrowing and spending. The fact that it ran 30 years is amazing - but just look at the parabolic rise in debt. It&apos;s a freekin&apos; joke right now with some trumpeting the falling consumer debt levels - well it&apos;s because they&apos;re defaulting on mortgages and loosing their bubble ATM-homes. Meanwhile the trade defecit continues - while exporting real jobs to make money to pay off the debt.... The depression has barely begun.

Good move - wrong time!
 Posted by: Eric | February 16, 2011 3:54 AM | Reply Score: -1 ( 1 votes cast) 
This says it all-
 http://www.mcdonaldsindia.net/about/faq.htm 
 Posted by: jay | February 22, 2011 5:53 AM | Reply Score: -1 ( 1 votes cast) 
Very cool site.
Thanks for sharing this...

Regards, Johny

 Posted by: johnycreg142 | June 2, 2011 10:14 AM | Reply Score: 0 ( 0 votes cast) 
Leave a comment
 Name Email Address URL Remember personal info? Comments
 (You may use HTML tags for style) Receive email notification of further comments. 

 
Most Popular Articles This Month
 
 

 This is what Chicken McNuggets look like -- Seriously! 

This photo below has been extensively passed around...
 6137 views 
   
 

 Low Carb Book Authors -- ARE FAT! (VIDEO) 

Low carb diet proponents are making a killing...
 5258 views 
   
 

 China Study author Colin Campbell slaps down critic 

Editor&apos;s Note: There has recently been a flurry...
 2960 views 
   
 

 The Paleo Diet Is Uncivilized (And Unhealthy and Untrue) 

Low-carbohydrate (low-carb) diets are fueling the destruction of...
 2597 views 
   
 

 How to Win An Argument With a Meat-Eater 

The Hunger Argument The Environmental Argument The...
 2518 views 
   
 

 Michelle Pfeiffer goes vegan (VIDEO) 

Caldwell Esselstyn Jr MD has had a major...
 2398 views 
   
 

 The Comparative Anatomy of Eating 

Humans are most often described as &quot;omnivores.&quot; This...
 2041 views 
   
 

 Dr. Esselstyn on Sanjay Gupta&apos;s CNN Special (VIDEO) 

Dr. Esselstyn&apos;s appearance on CNN&apos;s special, &quot;The Last...
 1752 views 
   
 

 Native Foods Vegan Cafe -- Boulder Colorado Opens! (VIDEO) 

SCROLL DOWN TO WATCH VIDEO Team VegSource recently...
 1514 views 
   
 

 The Truth About the Weston Price Foundation 

We&apos;ve previously run an expose on the...
 1368 views 
   
 

 Caldwell Esselstyn Jr. MD&amp;Dean Ornish MD Explain Bill... 

On Friday, September 24, CNN&apos;s Wolf Blitzer interviewed...
 1103 views 
   
 

 Beyond Meat -- It&apos;s cheaper, healthier and tastes better than... 

It&apos;s called Beyond Meat, and it&apos;s made from...
 1037 views 
   
 

 Jeff Novick&apos;s FAST FOOD - Burgers&amp;Fries - It&apos;s... 

This is the DVD you&apos;ve been waiting for!...
 1021 views 
   
 

 A Fast Way to Health -- Water-only Fasting 

Fasting to achieve physical and psychological health benefits...
 843 views 
   
 

 Definitive New Book - The Starch Solution (VIDEO) 

This website probably wouldn&apos;t exist if it weren&apos;t...
 811 views 
 
 
 
 Get VegSource Alerts
 
 First Name

 Email
 
 Send A Tip 
 
 Make VegSource Your Home 
 

 
 Home Store Discuss Food Video Health Green Celebs World Lifestyle Animals Homeschool 
 
Copyright©2012 VegSource Interactive, Inc. Reproduction of material from any VegSource pages without written permission is strictly prohibited.
VEGSOURCE®is registered in the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office as a trademark of Mostly Magic Productons, Inc.

 About us | Advertise | Login | Make VegSource your Home Page | RSS&amp;XML | Contact Us | Privacy | Policies | Site Credits | Powered by Movable Type
	</body>
</document>
