<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003579" url="http://www.dallasobserver.com/2009-05-07/restaurants/williams-chicken-for-when-you-want-it-fast-and-done-right/" time="2012-07-12-19:44" support="3" score="0.004806455912026763" bingtitle="Williams Chicken, For When You Want it Fast and Done Right - Page ..." webtitle="Williams Chicken, For When You Want it Fast and Done Right - Page 1 - Dining - Dallas - Dallas Observer">
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>... Lane 972-437-1716 Minutes I waited for my food: 5 ... Williams Chicken is calling out all you other fast food restaurant ... More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink ...</description>
	<body>
		Dining 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Unfair Park Schutze Ask a Mexican Buzz Archives Search Dallas Observer Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Dallas People Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Crave Dallas People Music Home DC9 at Night Dallas People Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home City of Ate Taste of the Town Menus Happy Hours Deals Best Of Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Crave Arts Home Mixmaster Theater Dallas People Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Dallas People Film Festivals Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2011 2010 2009 2008 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Taste of the Town Jersey Boys Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Career Fair Great Expectations DFW 
Top

dining

Stories
 
 
Blogs

 The 10 Sexiest Actors in DFW 

By Elaine Liner
 
Blogs

 A Plan for Fair Park: Bulldoze It 

By Jim Schutze
 
Slideshow

 10 Awesome Summer Foods in Dallas 

By Staff
 
Blogs

 An Englishman Reviews the BBQ of Hard Eight 

By Gavin Cleaver
 
Features

 The Dallas Observer People Issue 

By Staff
 
Blogs

 The Bitching-About-Texas-Weather Drinking Game 

By Alice Laussade
 
Blogs

 Ten Minutes in Heaven With Chef Curtis 

By foodbitch
 
Features

 Farmers Branch Spent Millions to Keep Out Mexicans. 

By Brantley Hargrove
 
   
 Pin It 
 
Williams Chicken, For When You Want it Fast and Done Right


 A A A Comments By Alice Laussade Thursday, May 7 2009 
If there&apos;s one thing you can get fast in Dallas, it&apos;s food (if there are two things, they&apos;re food and meth. Three? Food, meth and laser hair removal). And when it comes to fast food, boy, have we got options.
 
Location Info
 
Map
 
 William&apos;s Fried Chicken 

 9359 Forest Lane 
 Dallas , TX 75243-6256 
Category: Restaurant &gt; American 

Region: Garland&amp;Vicinity 

 
 0 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Details
 Williams Chicken
9359 Forest Lane
972-437-1716


Minutes I waited for my food: 5

Seconds I waited to snarf it down once it passed from their window into my car: 0 
Related Content
 
 What Some Locals Want in a &quot;Complete Street.&quot; (Hint: More Lights, Trees and Buried Utilities.) February 23, 2012 Drink $5 Margaritas All Over Dallas Tonight to Prepare for This Weekend&apos;s Margarita Meltdown May 24, 2012 Carl&apos;s Jr. Scientists Finally Shaped Ice Cream into a Burger. What Took So Long, Guys? May 18, 2012 The Margarita Meltdown Returns to Oak Cliff in May. Book Your Taxi Now. April 19, 2012 Lisa Garza Dishes Retro Comfort at Sissy&apos;s Southern Kitchen&amp;Bar February 28, 2012 
 
More About
 
 Restaurants and Food Services Fast Food Restaurants Miley Cyrus Eating Out Foods 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
 Me: Hey Dallas, I know this is a crazy question, and I&apos;m just throwing this out there, but do we really need to have two Sonics on Forest within, like, three blocks of each other? 

 Dallas: We totes do, bra. 

 Me: Dallas, you are such a fuckin&apos; douche. 

 Dallas: That&apos;s what she said. Heh. Meet you at Ghostbar lates? 

 Me: (shoots Dallas in face) 

As you approach Forest and Abrams, there are more fast food restaurants than there are giant teeth in Miley Cyrus &apos; honkin&apos; grill. Dallas is trying its hardest to get you to sell out at lunchtime, offering every chain meal deal you can think of. And then, in the middle of it all, there&apos;s Williams Chicken . Located right next door to a Church&apos;s Chicken as if to say, &quot;Yeah, I would be scared to be situated right next to another tasty-ass chicken place—lucky for me that shit you serve is naaasty.&quot; Williams Chicken is calling out all you other fast food restaurant bitches, &quot;Hold me back, Whataburger. Hold me back. You know I&apos;ll cut a bitch.&quot; Now&apos;s when I hold Williams Chicken&apos;s earrings and rings so she can whoop National Fast Food Chain&apos;s lardy ass.

I got a Coke, two good-sized pieces of dark meat, coleslaw (three cheers for big chunky pieces that look like they were made fresh and hand-cut), corn fritters (little fried cornballs. Uh, yum), a dinner roll and a giant jalapeño all for a little more than five bucks. Added bonus, Williams Chicken is smart: They know the only cash I ever carry is the see-a-penny-pick-it-up kind, so unlike a lot of local mom-and-pop drive-throughs, they take plastic.

I wouldn&apos;t say that it was the best fried chicken I&apos;ve had in Dallas ( Henderson &apos;s and Big Mama&apos;s out-taste this for sure), but it was nice and juicy and fresh, and the pieces were way bigger than the ones you get from KFC —plus you don&apos;t have to go to a damned KFC (the white suit thing is too 1990s-coke-dealer for me).
 Check out this week&apos;s featured ad for Restaurants 
 Spiral Diner 

 View Ad View Website 
 More Ads &gt;&gt; 
Get the Dining Newsletter
 
The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
 
 
 Email
to Friend Write to
Editor Print
Article 
   

 Please enable JavaScript to leave a comment.   
Now Trending


 
 Bad News: Goghee To Go Taco is Closing. Awesome News: They&apos;re Reopening BIGGER! 12 Questions for Chef Angelo Sosa A Cheap Lunch at the Zodiac? It&apos;s a Gas. 
 More Dining Stories &gt; 
Observer on Facebook
 
Slide shows » 

 100 Favorite Dishes in Dallas: 100-60 10 Awesome Summer Foods in Dallas The Best Fried Chicken in Dallas More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
Best of Dallas
 
2011 - Food&amp;Drink

 Best Reason to Wait Out the Rapture in Plano 
 Holy Grail Pub Best I&apos;ll-Be-Smart-When-I&apos;m-Dead Dish 
 Holy Grail Pub 
 More Food&amp;Drink Awards &gt; About Us | Media Kit | Work for Dallas Observer | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Dallas Observer Advertising | National Online Advertising | Mobile | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Site Problems? | RSS | Site Map Dallas Observer®is a registered trademark of Village Voice Media Holdings, LLC ©2012 Dallas Observer, LP, All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
