<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003788" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100912152036AAWWlAT" time="2012-07-12-19:56" support="2" score="0.0008126415743934105" bingtitle="Isn&apos;t it ironic how eurotrash complain about Americans so much ..." webtitle="Isnt it ironic how eurotrash complain about Americans so much? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000384" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001042" bing-rank="29"/>
	<description>His patent for a “waste paper receptacle” to offer an improved method of ... 1912 Fast food restaurant A fast food restaurant, sometimes known as a quick ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Society&amp;Culture &gt; Other - Society&amp;Culture &gt; Resolved Question 
 ikurbsto... Member since: September 11, 2010 Total points: 114 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Isn&apos;t it ironic how eurotrash complain about Americans so much?
 Especially on he internet? Don&apos;t they realize how incredibly ironic they are being? 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 I love how eurotrash are quick to judge Americans, yet they are the ones who depend on us and wouldn&apos;t be able to last one day without American technology! Oh sweet sweet irony! 
 2 years ago 
 @duh: Wrong again! Most vaccines and technological innovations were actually produced by America. Let&apos;s see how well you&apos;d fair without.

Global Positioning System
DNA computing
Bose–Einstein condensate
Screenless hammer mill
Xtracycle
Nanoimprint lithography
Scroll wheel
JavaScript
Flash programming
Low plasticity burnishing
Bait car
Digital video recorder
PageRank
Virtual globe
Torino scale
Phase-change incubator
Microwave Anisotropy Probe
Self-balancing personal transporter


Artificial liver
SERF
Fermionic condensate
HPV vaccine
Three-dimensional model rendering
Shingles vaccine
Nanowire battery
Bionic contact lens 
 2 years ago 
 And these are only post-1993! 
 2 years ago 
 @duff: Wrong again! The first general purpose computer was actually ENIAC and was developed by the United States. Also:

1890 Stop sign


The stop sign design currently used in English-speaking countries, as well as in most European countries
A stop sign is a traffic sign, usually erected at road junctions such as a four-way intersection, that instructs drivers to stop and then to proceed only if the way ahead is clear. The idea of placing stop signs at road junctions was first conceived in 1890 when William Phelps Eno of Saugatuck, Connecticut proposed and devised the first set of traffic laws in an article published in Rider and Driver. However, the first use of stop signs did not appear until 1915 when officials in Detroit, Michigan installed a stop sign with black letters on a white background. Throughout the years and with many alterations made to the stop sign, the current version with white block-lettering on a red background that is used in the United States as well as emulate 
 2 years ago 
 1890 Tabulating machine
The tabulating machine is an electrical device designed to assist in summarizing information and, later, accounting. The results of a tabulation are electrically coupled with a sorter while displayed on clock-like dials. The concept of automated data processing had been born. In 1890, Herman Hollerith invented the mechanical tabulating machine, a design used during the 1890 Census which stored and processed demographic and statistical information on punched cards.[19][20] 
 2 years ago 
 1890 Babcock test
The Babcock test was the first inexpensive and practical test which were used to determine the fat content of milk. Invented by Stephen Moulton Babcock in 1890, the test was developed to prevent dishonest farmers who could, until the 1890s, water down their milk or remove some cream before selling it to the factories because milk was paid by volume.[21] 
 2 years ago 
 1890 Smoke detector
• A smoke detector is a device that detects smoke and issues a signal. Most smoke detectors work either by optical detection or by physical process, but some of them use both detection methods to increase sensitivity to smoke. Smoke detectors are usually powered by battery while some are connected directly to power mains, often having a battery as a power supply backup in case the mains power fails. The first automatic electric fire alarm was co-invented in 1890 by Francis Robbins Upton and Fernando J. Dibble. Upton and Dibble were issued U.S. patent #436,961. Upton was an associate of Thomas Alva Edison, although there is no evidence that Edison contributed to this invention.[22] 
 2 years ago 
 1890 Jackhammer
• A jackhammer, also known as a pneumatic hammer, is a portable percussive drill powered by compressed air. It is used to drill rock and break up concrete pavement, among other applications. It jabs with its bit, not rotating it. In 1890, Charles Brady King of Detroit, Michigan invented the jackhammer, later being exhibited at the 1893 World&apos;s Columbian Exposition in Chicago. On January 28, 1894, a patent was issued.[23]
1891 Ferris wheel


The first Ferris wheel at the 1893 World&apos;s Columbian Exposition in Chicago
The Ferris wheel is a non-building structure, consisting of an upright wheel with passenger gondolas attached to the rim. Opened on June 21, 1893 at the Chicago World&apos;s Fair, the Ferris wheel was invented two years earlier by the Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania bridge-builder George Washington Gale Ferris in 1891.[24] 
 2 years ago 
 1891 Crown cork
The crown cork, the first form of a bottle cap, was invented in 1891 by William Painter of Baltimore, Maryland.[25]
1891 Dow process
The Dow process is the electrolytic method of bromine extraction from brine, and was Herbert Henry Dow&apos;s second revolutionary process for generating bromine commercially in 1891.[26] 
 2 years ago 
 1891 Gas-operated reloading
Gas-operation is a system of operation used to provide energy to operate autoloading firearms. In gas-operation, a portion of high pressure gas from the cartridge being fired is used to power a mechanism to extract the spent case and chamber a new cartridge. Energy from the gas is harnessed through either a port in the barrel or trap at the muzzle. This high-pressure gas impinges on a surface such as a piston head to provide motion for unlocking of the action, extraction of the spent case, ejection, cocking of the hammer or striker, chambering of a fresh cartridge, and locking of the action. John Moses Browning, a well known designer of lever action firearms, filed his first patent for an automatic firearm that harnessed expanding propellant gas to operate the mechanism in 1891.[27] 
 2 years ago 
 1891 Schrader valve
• A Schrader valve consists of a hollow cylindrical metal tube, typically brass, with the exterior end threaded. The interior end takes a variety of forms depending on its application. In the center of the exterior end is a metal pin pointing along the axis of the tube; the pin&apos;s end is flush with the end of the valve body. Generally, all Schrader valves are used on tires. They have threads and bodies of a single standard size at the exterior end, so caps and tools generally are universal for the valves on all automobile and bicycle pneumatic tires. Also, pressure valves can be used on Schrader valves in place of caps in order to measure the pressure of pneumatic tires. In 1891, George Schrader, the son of German-American immigrant August Schrader, invented the Schrader valve. A patent was issued on April 11, 1893.[28] 
 2 years ago 
 1891 Tesla coil
• A Tesla coil is a type of resonant transformer circuit invented by Nikola Tesla around 1891. Nikola Tesla used these coils to conduct innovative experiments in electrical lighting, phosphorescence, x-ray generation, high frequency alternating current phenomena, electrotherapy, and the transmission of electrical energy without wires for point-to-point telecommunications, broadcasting, and the transmission of electrical power.[29]
1891 Traveler&apos;s check
• A traveler&apos;s check is a preprinted, fixed-amount check designed to allow the person signing it to make an unconditional payment to someone else as a result of having paid the issuer for that privilege. Traveler&apos;s checks were invented by Marcellus F. Berry at American Express in 1891.[30]
1891 Zipper
• The zipper is a popular device for temporarily joining two edges of fabric. Whitcomb L. Judson was an American engineer from Chicago, Illinois, who invented the metal zipper device with locking teeth in 1891.[31] 
 2 years ago 
 1892 Dimmer
• Dimmers are devices used to vary the brightness of a light. By decreasing or increasing the RMS voltage and hence the mean power to the lamp it is possible to vary the intensity of the light output. Although variable-voltage devices are used for various purposes, the term dimmer is generally reserved for those intended to control lighting. Dimmers are popularly used in venues such as movie theatres, stages, dining rooms, restaurants, and auditoriums where the need or absence of light during activities requires constant change. The dimmer was invented in 1892 by Granville Woods.[32] 
 2 years ago 
 1892 Tractor


An Oliver 60 Row Crop, circa 1944
A tractor is a vehicle specifically designed to deliver a high tractive effort at slow speeds, for the purposes of hauling a trailer or machinery used in agriculture or construction. The term is used to describe the distinctive farm vehicle. Agricultural implements may be towed behind or mounted on the tractor, and the tractor may also provide a source of power if the implement is mechanized. In 1892, John Froelich invented and built the first gasoline/petrol-powered tractor in Clayton County, Iowa.[33][34][35] 
 2 years ago 
 1893 Silicon carbide
Silicon carbide, or carborundum, is a compound of silicon and carbon bonded together to form ceramics, but it also occurs in nature as the extremely rare mineral moissanite. The material was manufactured by Edward Goodrich Acheson around 1893.[36]
1893 Spectroheliograph
The spectroheliograph is an instrument used in astronomy that captures a photographic image of the Sun at a single wavelength of light, a monochromatic image. The spectroheliograph was invented in 1893 by George Ellery Hale and independently later by Henri Alexandre Deslandres in 1894.[37] 
 2 years ago 
 1893 Radio

Timeline of Tesla/Marconi dispute
Radio uses electromagnetic waves to send signals. The frequencies are below those of visible light. Information is carried by systematically changing some property of the radiated waves such as amplitude, frequency, or phase. Nikola Tesla is regarded by most, as well as the United States Supreme Court who in 1943 (with Justices Rutledge and Frankfurter dissenting) overturned Guglielmo Marconi&apos;s infringement on Tesla&apos;s #645,576 patent,[38][39] to be the original inventor of effective radio transmissions and many of the patents concerning radio such as reliable radio frequencies, Tesla&apos;s system of four circuits in resonance which showed the aerial connection with the ground as the essential element of wireless telegraphy, and effective transmission of long-distance signals. The supreme court&apos;s decision considered Marconi&apos;s claim that he had no knowledge of Tesla&apos;s work to be false since Tesla himself had already published his invention of a 
 2 years ago 
 1894 Mousetrap
• A mousetrap is a specialized type of animal trap designed primarily to catch mice. However, it may also trap other small animals. Mousetraps are usually set in an indoor location where there is a suspected infestation of rodents. The first mouse trap was invented by William C. Hooker of Abingdon, Illinois, exactly three years before James Henry Atkinson developed a prototype called the&quot;Little Nipper&quot;, who Atkinson himself probably saw the Hooker trap in shops or in advertisements, thus copying it as the basis for his own model.[41] Hooker received US patent #528671 for his invention, the mousetrap, in 1894.[42][43] 
 2 years ago 
 1895 Volleyball


Three volleyball players performing a block
Volleyball is an Olympic sport in which two teams of 6 active players are separated by a net. Each team tries to score points against one another by grounding a ball on the other team&apos;s court under organized rules. William G. Morgan invented the sport first known as&quot;Mintonnette&quot;in 1895 while studying at a YMCA in Holyoke, Massachusetts. It was later re-named volleyball by Alfred S. Halstead.[44]
1896 Comic book
A comic book is a magazine or book of narrative artwork and, virtually always, dialog and descriptive prose with humorous or action-oriented content. The first known proto-comic-book magazine was&quot;The Yellow Kid in McFadden&apos;s Flats&quot;, published by the G. W. Dillingham Company in 1896. Cartoonist Richard F. Outcault created the first illustrations.[45] 
 2 years ago 
 1897 Cotton candy
Cotton candy is a soft confection made from sugar that is heated and spun into slim threads that look like a mass of cotton. It was co-invented in 1897 by William Morrison and John C. Wharton, candy-makers from Nashville, Tennessee.[46]
1897 Charcoal briquette
• A charcoal briquette, or briquet is a block of flammable charcoal matter which is used as fuel to start and maintain a fire, mainly used for food preparation over an open fire or a barbecue. Charcoal briquettes are made by using a process which consists of compressing charcoal, typically made from sawdust and other wood by-products, with a binder and other additives. The binder is usually starch. Some charcoal briquettes may also include brown coal, mineral carbon, borax, sodium nitrate, limestone, raw sawdust, and other additives like paraffin or petroleum solvents to aid in ignition. The design of the charcoal briquette was invented and patented by Ellsworth B. A. Zwoyer in 1897.[47] 
 2 years ago 
 1898 Remote control
• A remote control is an electronic device used to operate any machine, such as a television, remotely. Many of these remotes communicate to their respective devices through infrared signals and radio control. In Madison Square Garden, at the Electrical Exhibition, Nikola Tesla gave the first demonstration of a boat propelling in water, controlled by his remote control which he designed using radio signals. Tesla received a patent for his invention in 1898.[48] 
 2 years ago 
 1898 Semi-automatic shot gun
• A semi-automatic, or self-loading shot gun is a firearm that requires only a trigger pull for each round that is fired, unlike a single-action revolver, a pump-action firearm, a bolt-action firearm, or a lever-action firearm, which all require the shooter to chamber each successive round manually. In 1898, John Moses Browning invented the first semi-sutomatic shot gun, later patenting it in 1900. Naming it the Auto-5, Browning&apos;s semi-automatic relied on long recoil operation. This design remained the dominant form in semi-automatic shotguns for approximately 50 years, being widely used and the preferred weapon of choice among soldiers fighting in World War One. Production of the Auto-5 ceased in 1999.[49]
1898 Flashlight
• A flashlight is a portable electric spotlight which emits light from a small incandescent lightbulb, or from one or more light-emitting diodes. The flashlight was invented in 1898 by Joshua Lionel Cowen in New York City.[50] 
 2 years ago 
 1898 Synthetic bristled hairbrush
A hairbrush is a small brush with rigid bristles used in hair care for brushing, styling, and detangling human hair, or for brushing a domestic animal&apos;s fur. Although not the first to invent a hairbrush, Lyda Newman was granted a patent in 1898 for the first hairbrush incorporating synthetic bristles as prior hairbrushes were made with boar’s hair.[51]
1898 Vertical filing cabinet
• A filing cabinet is a piece of office furniture usually used to store paper documents in file folders. In the most simple sense, it is an enclosure for drawers in which items are stored. A vertical file cabinet has drawers that extend from the short side (typically 15 inches) of the cabinet. The vertical filing cabinet was invented by Edwin G. Seibels in 1898, thus revolutionizing efficient record-keeping and archiving by creating space for offices, schools, and businesses.[52]
1898 Installer bit
• Installer bits are a type of twist drill bit for use with a hand-portable po 
 2 years ago 
 1898 Sousaphone
The sousaphone, sometimes referred to as a marching tuba, is a wearable tuba descended from the hélicon. It was designed such that it fits around the body of the wearer and so it can be easily played while being worn. The sousaphone is named after John Philip Sousa but was invented by C. G. Conn in 1898.[54]
1900 Duckpin bowling
• Duckpin bowling is a variation of bowling that uses balls which are significantly smaller than those used in ten-pin bowling, weighing 1–2 kilograms (2–4 pounds) each, which are devoid of finger holes. The pins are correspondingly shorter and lighter than their ten-pin equivalents. Hence, when the pins are knocked down, they resemble a&quot;flock of flying ducks&quot;. While the rules remained almost identical to those of the Ten-pin game, one rule change was made: A bowler is allowed to use three bowls on each turn. Strikes would still be strikes and spares still spares, but when all pins were knocked down on the third ball, it counts as a score of te 
 2 years ago 
 1900 Carbide lamp
Carbide lamps, also known as acetylene gas lamps, are simple lamps that produce and burn acetylene which is created by the reaction of calcium carbide with water. The first carbide lamp was invented and patented in New York City on August 28, 1900 by Frederick Baldwin.[57]
1900 Thumbtack
A thumbtack is a short nail or pin with a large, slightly rounded head made of metal which is used to fasten documents to a background for public display and which can easily be inserted or removed by hand. The thumbtack was invented by Edwin Moore around 1900, the year in which he founded the Moore Push-Pin Company.[58]
1901 Key punch
• A keypunch is a device for manually entering data into punched cards by precisely punching holes at locations designated by the keys struck by the operator. Early keypunches were manual devices. Later keypunches were mechanized, often resembling a small desk, with a keyboard similar to a typewriter, and with hoppers for blank cards and stackers for 
 2 years ago 
 1901 Mercury-vapor lamp
A mercury-vapor lamp is a gas discharge lamp which uses mercury in an excited state to produce light. The arc discharge is generally confined to a small fused quartz arc tube mounted within a larger borosilicate glass bulb. The outer bulb may be clear or coated with a phosphor. In either case, the outer bulb provides thermal insulation, protection from ultraviolet radiation, and a convenient mounting for the fused quartz arc tube. In 1901, Peter Cooper Hewitt invented and patented the mercury-vapor lamp.[60]
1901 Assembly line production

1913 Ford Model T assembly line production.
Used globally around the world, an assembly line is a manufacturing process in which interchangeable parts are added to a product in a sequential manner in order to create a finished product more quickly than with older methods. This type of manufacturing greatly reduces the amount of time taken to assemble a product,thus reducing production, material, and labor costs so that an af 
 2 years ago 
 1902 Postage meter
• A postage meter is a mechanical device used to create and apply physical evidence of postage, or franking, to mailed matter. Postage meters are regulated by a country&apos;s postal authority; for example, in the United States, the United States Postal Service specifies the rules for the creation, support, and use of postage meters. A postage meter imprints an amount of postage, functioning as a postage stamp, a cancellation and a dated postmark all in one. The postage meter was invented by Chicago inventor Arthur Pitney, receiving a patent for the invention on October 14, 1902.[64]
1902 Teddy bear
• A teddy bear is a stuffed toy bear. They are usually stuffed with soft cotton and have smooth and soft fur. It is an enduring form of a stuffed animal that has become a collector&apos;s item. The first teddy bear was invented in 1902 by Morris Michtom, owner of a Brooklyn toy store, who was inspired by Clifford Berryman&apos;s political cartoon&quot;Drawing the Line in Mississippi&quot;that d 
 2 years ago 
 1902 Mercury arc valve
• A mercury arc valve is a type of electrical rectifier which converts alternating current into direct current. Rectifiers of this type were used in electric motor power supplies for industry, in electric railways, streetcars, and diesel-electric locomotives. They also found use in static inverter stations and as rectifiers for high-voltage direct current power transmission. Mercury arc rectifiers were invented by Peter Cooper Hewitt in 1902.[67]
1902 Air conditioning

Air conditioning units outside a classroom building
Air conditioning is the cooling and de-humidification of indoor air for thermal comfort. Using a system of coils as a solution to cool and remove moisture from muggy air in a printing plant that was wrinkling magazine pages, Willis Carrier invented and manufactured the world&apos;s first mechanical air conditioning unit in 1902.[68] By increasing industrial production in the summer months, air conditioning revolutionized American life. The introductio 
 2 years ago 
 1903 Offset printing press
Offset printing is a commonly used printing technique where the inked image is transferred from a plate to a rubber blanket, then to the printing surface. Ira Washington Rubel invented the first offset printing press in 1903.[70]
1903 Crayons
• A crayon is a stick of colored wax, charcoal, chalk, or other materials used for writing and drawing. Crayons were invented by Edwin Binney and Harold Smith, who owned a paint company in New York City. As inexpensive art supplies, Binney and Smith invented the modern-day crayon by combining paraffin wax with pigments. After great success of marketing them to consumers, they became known by the brand name of Crayola.[71] 
 2 years ago 
 1903 Airplane


The Wright Flyer II flying almost four circles over Huffman Prairie, about 2 and 3/4 miles in 5 minutes and 4 seconds on November 9, 1904.
A fixed-wing aircraft, or airplane, is a heavier-than-air craft whose lift is generated by air pressure differential between the upper and lower wing surfaces. The Wright brothers, Wilbur and Orville Wright of Dayton, Ohio, made the first powered and sustained airplane flights under 
 2 years ago 
 control of the pilot in the Wright Flyer I on December 17, 1903 in Kitty Hawk, North Carolina.[72] In the two years afterward, they developed their flying machine into the world&apos;s first practical fixed-wing aircraft. By October 1905, the Wright Flyer III was capable and proven to circle in the air 30 times in 39 minutes for a total distance of 24.5 miles.[73] The brothers&apos;fundamental breakthrough was their invention of&quot;three-axis control,&quot;which enabled the pilot to steer the aircraft effectively and to maintain its equilibrium. This required method has become standard on all fixed-wing aircraft. From the beginning of their aeronautical work, the Wright brothers focused on unlocking the secrets of control to conquer&quot;the flying problem,&quot;rather than on developing more powerful engines as some other experimenters did. Charles Edward Taylor built the first aircraft engine and was a vital 
 2 years ago 
 contributor of mechanical aspects in the building and maintaining of early Wright engines and airplanes.[74] Although there were many earlier attempts at heavier-than-air powered flight, some of which achieved successful short hops,[75] and disputed earlier claims of sustained flight,[76] the Wright brothers are officially credited by the Fédération Aéronautique Internationale, the international record-setting body for aeronautics and astronautics, as achieving&quot;the first sustained and controlled heavier-than-air powered flight&quot;.[77] In addition, U.S. patent number #821393 for the airplane, was filed by Orville Wright on March 23, 1903 and was issued in May 1906.[78] 
 2 years ago 
 1903 Windshield wipers


A windshield wiper with motorized arm
The windshield wiper is a bladed device used to wipe rain and dirt from a windshield. The windshield wiper was invented by Mary Anderson in 1903 to help streetcars operate safely in the rain. In 1905, Anderson patented her invention, which allowed the car operator to control the external, swinging arm wipers from within the car. [79]
1903 Wood&apos;s glass
Wood&apos;s glass is a light filter used in communications during World War I. An&quot;invisible radiation&quot;technique which worked both in infrared daylight communication and ultraviolet night communications, it does not transmit visible light, leaving the&apos;invisible radiation&apos;as a signal beam. Wood&apos;s glass was invented by Robert Williams Wood in 1903.[80] 
 2 years ago 
 1903 Wood&apos;s lamp
A Wood&apos;s lamp is a diagnostic tool used in dermatology which shines ultraviolet light onto the skin of the patient; a technician then observes any subsequent fluorescence. Though the technique for producing a source of ultraviolet light was devised by Robert Williams Wood in 1903 using&quot;Wood&apos;s glass&quot;, not until 1925 was the technique used in dermatology by Margarot and Deveze for the detection of fungal infection of hair.[81]
1904 Automatic transmission
An automatic transmission is an automobile gearbox that changes gear ratios automatically as the vehicle moves, freeing the driver from having to shift gears manually. Modern automatic transmissions trace their origins to an early&quot;horseless carriage&quot;gearbox that was developed in 1904 by the Sturtevant brothers of Boston, Massachusetts.[82] 
 2 years ago 
 1904 AC power plugs and sockets
• An electric plug is a male electrical connector with contact prongs to connect mechanically and electrically to slots in the matching female socket. Wall sockets, are female electrical connectors that have slots or holes which accept and deliver current to the prongs of inserted plugs. Sockets are designed to accept only matching plugs and reject all others. The original two blade electrical plug and socket were invented by Harvey Hubbell and patented in 1904.[83] The three-prong plug was invented by Philip F. Labre in 1928.[84] 
 2 years ago 
 1904 Dragline excavator
• Dragline excavation systems are heavy equipment used in civil engineering and surface mining. In civil engineering the smaller types are used for road and port construction. The larger types are used in strip-mining operations to move overburden above coal, and for tar-sand mining. A dragline bucket system consists of a large bucket which is suspended from a boom, a large truss-like structure, with wire ropes. The bucket is manoeuvred by means of a number of ropes and chains. The hoist rope, powered by large diesel or electric motors, supports the bucket and hoist-coupler assembly from the boom. The dragrope is used to draw the bucket assembly horizontally. By skillful manoeuvre of the hoist and the dragropes the bucket is controlled for various operations. The dragline excavator was invented in 1904 by John W. Page.[85] 
 2 years ago 
 1905 Architectural acoustics
• Architectural acoustics is the science of controlling sound within buildings. The first application of architectural acoustics was in the design of opera houses and then concert halls. It was developed by Wallace Clement Sabine from 1895 to 1905.[86]
1905 Fly swatter
• A flyswatter is a hand-held device for swatting flies and other insects. Samuel Crumbine, a member of the Kansas board of health, wanted to raise public awareness of the threat of flies. He was inspired by a chant at a Topeka softball game:&quot;swat the ball&quot;. In a health bulletin published soon afterwards, he exhorted Kansans to&quot;swat the fly&quot;. In response, a schoolteacher named Frank H. Rose created the&quot;fly bat&quot;, a device consisting of a yardstick attached to a piece of screen. Crumbine invented the device now commonly known as the fly swatter.[87] 
 2 years ago 
 1905 Ice pop
• An ice pop, also commercially known as a popsicle, is a frozen water-based dessert on a stick. It is made by freezing a colored, flavored liquid around a stick. Once the liquid freezes solid, the stick can be used as a handle to hold the ice pop. The ice pop was invented by 11-year-old Frank Epperson in 1905. Living in San Francisco, California, Epperson had left a fruit drink out overnight, with a stirrer in it, thus making it freeze. In 1923, Epperson got a patent on his&quot;frozen ice on a stick&quot;. Epperson also invented the twin ice pop, with two sticks so it could be shared by two children. The most famous brand name associated with the ice pop is Popsicle.[88] 
 2 years ago 
 1906 Audion tube
• The Audion is an electronic amplifier device and was the forerunner of the triode, in which the current from the filament to the plate was controlled by a third element, the grid. A small amount of power applied to the grid could control a larger current from the filament to the plate, allowing the Audion to both detect radio signals and to provide amplification. The Audion tube was invented by Lee De Forest in 1906.[89] 
 2 years ago 
 1907 Electrostatic precipitator
• An electrostatic precipitator (ESP), or electrostatic air cleaner is a particulate collection device that removes particles from a flowing gas (such as air) using the force of an induced electrostatic charge. Electrostatic precipitators are highly efficient filtration devices that minimally impede the flow of gases through the device, and can easily remove fine particulate matter such as dust and smoke from the air stream. In 1907, the California physicist Frederick G. Cottrell invented and received a patent for the electrostatic precipitator.[90] 
 2 years ago 
 1907 Paper towel
• A paper towel has the same purposes as conventional towels such as drying hands, wiping windows, dusting, cleaning up spills. However, paper towels can only be used once after they blot wet surfaces. A school teacher in Ashland, Ohio, named Kurt Klier, gave students individual paper squares, so that the single towel in the bathroom would not be infected with germs. When Arthur Scott, head of the Scott Paper Company heard about it, he decided to try and sell a load of paper that had been made too thick to use as toilet paper.[91]
1908 Electric washing machine
• A washing machine, or washer, is a machine designed to clean laundry, such as clothing, towels and sheets. The Thor was the first electric-powered washing machine. Introduced in 1908, the electric washing machine was invented by Alva J. Fisher. A patent was issued on August 9, 1910.[92] 
 2 years ago 
 1908 Electric mixer
• An electric mixer is a kitchen appliance used for whipping, beating, and folding food ingredients. It typically consists of a handle mounted over a large enclosure containing the motor, which drives one or two beaters. The beaters are immersed in the food to be mixed. The first electric mixer was invented by Herbert Johnston in 1908 and sold by the KitchenAid division of the Hobart Manufacturing Company.[93] 
 2 years ago 
 1909 Skee ball
• Skee ball is a common game found in arcades and one of the first redemption games. Skee ball is similar to bowling except it is played on an inclined lane and the player aims to get the ball to fall into a hole rather than knock down pins. The object of the game is to collect as many points as possible by rolling balls up an incline and into the designated point value holes. Skee ball was invented and patented in 1909 by J.D. Estes of Philadelphia.[94] 
 2 years ago 
 1909 Paper shredder
• Paper shredders are used to cut paper into chad, typically either strips or fine particles. Government organizations, businesses, and private individuals use shredders to destroy private, confidential, or otherwise sensitive documents. The first paper shredder is credited to prolific inventor Abbot Augustus Low of Horseshoe, New York. His patent for a “waste paper receptacle” to offer an improved method of disposing of waste paper received a U.S. patent on August 31, 1909.[95] 
 2 years ago 
 1909 Suppressor
• A suppressor or silencer is a device either attached to or part of the barrel of a firearm to reduce the amount of noise and flash generated by firing the weapon. It generally takes the form of a cylindrically-shaped metal tube with various internal mechanisms to reduce the sound of firing by slowing the escaping propellant gas, and sometimes by reducing the velocity of the bullet. Hiram Percy Maxim, the son of famous machine gun inventor Hiram Stevens Maxim, is credited with inventing the suppressor in 1909.[96] 
 2 years ago 
 1909 Muffler
• A muffler is a device for reducing the amount of noise emitted by a machine. On internal combustion engines, the engine exhaust blows out through the muffler. The internal combustion engine muffler was invented in parallel with the firearm suppressor by Hiram Percy Maxim in 1909.[97]
1909 Gin rummy
• Gin rummy, or Gin for short, is a simple and popular two-player card game with a standard 52-card pack. The objective of Gin Rummy is to score more points than your opponent improving one&apos;s hand by forming melds and eliminating deadwood. Gin rummy was invented by Elwood T. Baker and his son, C. Graham Baker in 1909.[98] 
 2 years ago 
 1910 Headset
• A headset is a headphone combined with a microphone. Headsets provide the equivalent functionality of a telephone handset with hands-free operation. They are used in call centers and by people in telephone-intensive jobs. The first-ever headset was invented in 1910, by a Stanford University student named Nathaniel Baldwin.[99]
1911 Binder clip


A single, large sized binder clip
A binder clip, or a banker&apos;s clip or foldback clip, is a simple device for binding sheets of paper together. It leaves the paper intact and can be removed quickly and easily unlike the staple. The binder clip was invented in 1911 by Washington D.C. resident Louis E. Baltzley who was motivated by a desire to help his father, Edwin, a prolific writer and inventor, keep manuscripts in order. The original design was modified five times, but the essential mechanism has never changed.[100] 
 2 years ago 
 1911 Flying boat
A flying boat is a specialized form of aircraft that is designed to take off from and land on water, using its fuselage as a floating hull. Such aircraft are sometimes stabilized on water by underwing floats or by wing-like projections from the fuselage. It is the use of the fuselage to provide the main buoyancy of the aircraft which distinguishes flying boats from floatplanes, which use one or more floats attached below the fuselage or the wings to keep the fuselage clear of the water. In 1911, American aviation pioneer Glenn Curtiss invented the two-seat&quot;Flying Fish&quot;, a large craft that became classified as a flying boat because the hull sat in the water.[101] 
 2 years ago 
 1911 Automobile self starter
An automobile self-starter is an electric motor that initiates rotational motion in an internal combustion engine before it can power itself, therefore eliminating the hand crank used to start engines. In 1911, Charles F. Kettering invented the automobile self-starter while working at National Cash Register and then sold them for installation on cars at the Cadillac company. There had been many attempts at producing an electric starter before, but none of them were successful. Most designs at that time called for the use of an electric motor attached to the engine&apos;s flywheel. However, in order to fit in the car&apos;s engine compartment, the device would have to be small, and therefore it would be unable to produce a sufficient enough amount of torque.[102][103] 
 2 years ago 
 1911 Road surface marking


Dead Man&apos;s Curve along the Marquette–Negaunee Road in Michigan shown in 1917 with the first hand-painted centerline
A road surface marking is any kind of device or material that is used on a road surface in order to convey official information for drivers and pedestrians. Edward N. Hines originated the concept of painting a line down the center of a road to separate traffic in opposing directions. They were first used in Wayne County, Michigan in 1911.[104] 
 2 years ago 
 1912 Autopilot
An autopilot is a mechanical, electrical, or hydraulic system used to guide a vehicle without assistance from a human being. Most people understand an autopilot to refer specifically to aircraft, but self-steering gear for ships, boats, space craft and missiles is sometimes also called by this term. The first aircraft autopilot was invented by Lawrence Sperry in 1912. Sperry demonstrated it in 1914, and proved the credibility of the invention by flying the aircraft with his hands away from the controls and visible to onlookers.[105] 
 2 years ago 
 1912 Fast food restaurant
A fast food restaurant, sometimes known as a quick service restaurant or QSR, is a specific type of restaurant characterized both by its fast food cuisine and by minimal table service. Food served in fast food restaurants typically caters to a&quot;meat-sweet diet&quot;and is offered from a limited menu. Cooked in bulk and kept hot, it is finished and packaged to order, usually available ready to take away, though seating may be provided. The history of fast food can be traced to New York City on July 7, 1912 with the opening of a fast food restaurant by Joseph Horn and Frank Hardart called the Automat.[106] 
 2 years ago 
 1912 Electric blanket
• An electric blanket is a blanket with an integrated electrical heating device usually placed above the top bed sheet. The first electric blanket was invented in 1912 by American physician Sidney I. Russell.[107]
1912 Electric traffic light


Traffic lights in Spain
The traffic light, also known as traffic signal, is a signaling device positioned at a road intersection, pedestrian crossing, or other location. Its purpose is to indicate, using a series of colors, the correct moment to stop, drive, ride or walk, using a universal color code. The color of the traffic lights representing stop and go are likely derived from those used to identify port (red) and starboard (green) in maritime rules governing right of way, where the vessel on the left must stop for the one crossing on the right. In Salt Lake City, Utah, policeman Lester Wire invented the first red-green electric traffic lights.[108] 
 2 years ago 
 1914 Regenerative circuit
The regenerative circuit allows an electronic signal to be amplified many times by the same vacuum tube or other active component such as a field effect transistor. A regenerative circuit is often an AM detector, converting the RF signal on the antenna to an audio waveform. Their use of positive feedback greatly increases both the selectivity and sensitivity of a simple receiver. Positive feedback builds up the input signal to very high levels. Edwin Armstrong, invented and patented the regenerative circuit while he was a junior in college, in 1914.[109]
1914 Traffic cone
• Traffic cones, also called toddlers, road cones, safety cones, construction cones, pylons, or Witches&apos;Hats, are usually cone-shaped markers that are placed on roads or sidewalks to temporarily redirect traffic in a safe manner. Traffic cones were invented in 1914 by Charles P. Rudabaker.[110] 
 2 years ago 
 1914 Fortune cookie
• A fortune cookie is a crisp cookie usually made from flour, sugar, vanilla, and oil with a&quot;fortune&quot;wrapped inside. A&quot;fortune&quot;is a piece of paper with words of faux wisdom or a vague prophecy. In the United States, it is usually served with Chinese food in Chinese restaurants as a dessert. The message inside may also include a list of lucky numbers and a Chinese phrase with translation. Contrary to belief, the fortune cookie associated as a Chinese invention is a fallacy. In 1914, the Japanese-American named Makoto Hagiwara of the Japanese Tea Garden in San Francisco, California introduced the fortune cookie and is thus recognized as its inventor.[111] 
 2 years ago 
 And I haven&apos;t even scratched the surface yet. Trust me, you&apos;re better off eating your crumpets, because you have no chance against me. 
 2 years ago 
 by Piece Chance Member since: July 01, 2007 Total points: 35,015 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 I think the word you&apos;re looking for is pathetic, not ironic. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: I think you&apos;re right. 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (3)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by UlsterLo... Member since: September 02, 2010 Total points: 2,523 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 is&apos;nt it ironic how you called us trash during a question about us talking trash about you? only one i can see trashing anyone is you trashing us. plus you seem to be forgetting most of the best inventions, real life changing inventions, were invented by british men. britain does not need america whatsoever, we are just an allie and fight on your side. nothing else. how about The first programmable computer British was invented in Manchester university, This computer still works and is actually faster than the PC/laptop you are now using.1948 The first computer with a stored programme and memory- nicknamed&apos;baby&apos;- was developed at Manchester University,UK

Anemometer - Robert Hooke British inventor

Disc Brakes - Frederick William Lanchester British inventor

Cordite - Sir James Dewar, Sir Frederick Abel

Electromagnet - William Sturgeon, British Scientist

Fax Machine - Alexander Bain British Inventor

Holography - Dennis Gábor British Inventor

Optical Computer Bristol University UK Sept 2009

Internal Combustion Engine - Samuel Brown, British Engineer and Inventor

Geostationary satellite feasibility was another British first, A C Clarke who died recently

Jet Engine British (Whittle)

Radio (Underlying Principles) - James Clerk Maxwell Very famous British scientist

Thermos - Sir James Dewar, British inventor

Evolution theory Darwin British

Vacuum Cleaner - Hubert Cecil Booth, British Inventor (Not Hoover)

Body scanner British

Internet BRITISH,(Tim Berners -Lee)

Radar British WW2

Train first train self propelled British (Stephenson)

Steam Engine British 3 British
Inventors: Thomas Savery, Thomas Newcomen, James Watt

1803 John Dalton&apos;s atomic theory was the forerunner of all modern medicine. Manchester UK

1805 The first gas street lighting illuminated part of Chapel Street in Salford, along with the Philips and Lee factory.Manchester UK

1880 The first mechanically powered submarine was launched to the designs of eccentric Hulme curate, the Reverend George Garrett.Manchester UK

George Stephenson Rocket Steam Engone

Robert Stephenson , First Box Girder Bridge

Propelling pencil . Sampson Mordan.UK associate of Michael Faraday
 http://www.gracesguide.co.uk/wiki/S._Mor… 

Scramjet semi orbital jet engine British

First Powered flight. John Stringfellow Attercliffe, Sheffield, England

Cat Eyes British Percy Shaw

Float Glass and self cleaning glass, Pilkington UK

First successful two-stroke engine was invented by Sir Dougald Clerk.British

Periodic Table British
British chemist, John Newlands

The&quot;Seismometer&quot;British James Forbes

Englishmen, Sir Henry Bessemer (1813-1898) invented the first process for mass-producing steel
Spinning Jenny - James Hargreaves
Modern Seismograph
John Milne was the English seismologist and geologist who invented the first modern seismograph and promoted the building of seismological stations. In 1880, Sir James Alfred Ewing, Thomas Gray and John Milne, all British scientists working in Japan, began to study earthquakes. They founded the Seismological Society of Japan and the society funded the invention of seismographs. Milne invented the horizontal pendulum seismograph in 1880.
Sir Isaac Newton ( British ) was the inventor of the Universal Law of Gravity
Michael Faraday (British 1791 - 1867) invented both the electrical generator and the electric motor,
John Logie Baird (1888 - 1946) is immortalised for his invention of Television (1926) but also worked on early developments in radar and fibre optics (1924/5).
Hovercraft British Sir Christopher Cockerell (1910 - 1999) - 1959
Linear induction motor - Eric Laithwite (British 1921-1997) - early 1960s
Pedal cycle ....Kirkpatrick MacMillan- British -invented the pedal cycle 1839
Penicillin--Alexander Fleming - 1928
Holography 1947...Dennis Gabon -- British
Torpedo http://www.weymouthdiving.co.uk/torpedoe… 
DNA Profiling.Prof Sir Alec Jeffreys,The inventor of DNA finger printing was named as the Great Briton of 2006 at a ceremony at London&apos;s Guildhall.

Harrier Jump Jet, one of my British invented favourites ,I met one of the designers, he lived over the road to me

1919 Ernest Rutherford discovered how to split the atom at Manchester University UK .

2009......James Dyson has launched a bladeless fan

2009 Cancer Genome Sequence break through British scientists Dec 2009

The above is not a complete list by any means and represents a fraction of British inventions 
Source(s):
 d&apos;uh 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Clíodhna Member since: August 10, 2010 Total points: 102 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 After living in America for a few years, no, it is not so strange. Some or most might not have experienced the reason they talk trash, so that&apos;s a tad off, but those who have, like my own self, it is very clear the things that deserve that talking. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Rainbow Warrior Member since: August 03, 2010 Total points: 1,194 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I&apos;m American, though I don&apos;t live there anymore. 
Source(s):
 Trashtalker about Americans, and their cesspool culture. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Society&amp;Culture 

 What&apos;s wrong with this generation? I&apos;m gonna ask this guy whether her likes me or not. Any ideas, tips or warnings? Ideas please!!!! Is this a good plot?? What do I do ??? I am not interested in anything this world has to offer ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Society&amp;Culture 
 Community Service Cultures&amp;Groups Etiquette Holidays Languages Mythology&amp;Folklore Other - Society&amp;Culture Religion&amp;Spirituality Royalty 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
