<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004721" url="http://www.fastfoodfacts.info/" time="2012-07-12-21:13" support="35" score="0.19314835468591515" bingtitle="Fast Food Facts | Calories, Fat and other nutritional information." webtitle="Fast Food Facts | Calories, Fat and other nutritional information.">
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000905" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000306" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000007" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000463" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001502" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000597" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001478" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000893" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000622" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000307" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="67"/>
	<description>an up-to-date searchable database of nutritional information on Fast Food Restaurant menu items. Over 2,600 items in the database from 27 restaurants.</description>
	<body>
		Search  
 
  Facts in Print  
 
  Fast Food News  
 
  Bookstore  
 
  Diet Info  
 
  Trivia  
 
  Press  
 
  About  
 
  Contact  
 
 Enter your search terms 
 Submit search form 
 
 
    
 Fast Food Facts is your source for the most up-to-date nutritional information on your favorite fast food for dieting and weight control; sugar levels for diabetics; carbs (carbohydrate) for low-carb dieters; and health&amp;nutrition class projects for students and teachers. 
 Recent Features:  Taco Bell Test Kitchen 
 Jamba Juice Test Kitchen Fast Food Facts
 Database Facts 

2,600 menu items
27 Restaurants
926,388 calories
40,440g of fat 
 
 Search Fast Food Facts:  Enter your search terms Submit search form 
 
 Fast Food Nutrition
Search by Restaurant Fast Food Nutrition
Search by Food Category Fast Food Nutrition
Search for a specific item Pick a restaurant: Arby&apos;s Boston Market Burger King Carl&apos;s Jr. Chick-Fil-A Church&apos;s Chicken Dairy Queen Dunkin&apos; Donuts Hardee&apos;s Jack in the Box KFC Krispy Kreme Long John Silver&apos;s McDonald&apos;s Panera Bread Co. Sonic Drive-In Starbucks Steak &apos;N Shake Subway Taco Bell Wendy&apos;s Whataburger 
 and include: All Menu Items All Sandwiches Beverages Breads Breakfast Burgers Chicken Chicken Sandwich Condiments Desserts Donuts, Bagels, Muffins Entrees Fish Fish Sandwich French Fries Individual Components Non-Burger Sandwiches Salads Salad Dressings&amp;Toppings Sandwiches Shakes, Slushes, etc. Side Dishes Tacos&amp;Wraps 
 and sort by: Alphabetical Calories Calories from Fat Grams of Fat Saturated Fat Cholesterol Sodium Carbohydrates Fiber Sugars Protein (optional) 
 least to most most to least (optional) 
 Help? Pick a Category All Sandwiches Beverages Breads Breakfast Burgers Chicken Chicken Sandwich Condiments Desserts Donuts, Bagels, Muffins Entrees Fish Fish Sandwich French Fries Individual Components Non-Burger Sandwiches Salads Salad Dressings&amp;Toppings Sandwiches Shakes, Slushes, etc. Side Dishes Tacos&amp;Wraps 
 and sort by: Alphabetical Calories Calories from Fat Grams of Fat Saturated Fat Cholesterol Sodium Carbohydrates Fiber Sugars Protein (optional) 
 least to most most to least (optional) 
 Help? Select a Restaurant Arby&apos;s Boston Market Burger King Carl&apos;s Jr. Chick-Fil-A Church&apos;s Chicken Dairy Queen Dunkin&apos; Donuts Hardee&apos;s Jack in the Box KFC Krispy Kreme Long John Silver&apos;s McDonald&apos;s Panera Bread Co. Sonic Drive-In Starbucks Steak &apos;N Shake Subway Taco Bell Wendy&apos;s Whataburger 

Enter all or part of an item&apos;s name:
 
 Help? 

 Fast Food News 

 
 
Fast Food Facts Special Reports:

 McRib Deconstructed ◊ SNL Taco Town ◊ Fast Food Nation: The Movie 
 High Fructose Corn Syrup (HFCS) ◊ The McRules 
 Since 1999!
Fast Food Facts is celebrating 10 years
of serving you complete fast food nutrition facts!
 
 
 

 

 Fast Food Facts ©1999-2009 , Ken Kuhl , All Rights Reserved.
 Terms of Use ¦ Advertising info ¦ Privacy policy 
All trademarks/servicemarks referenced on this site are properties of their respective owners.
Fast Food Facts is not affiliated with any restaurant.
 

 
 Fast Food Facts site stats:
 Restaurants included in database: Arbys, Boston Market, Burger King, Carls Jr., Chick-Fil-A, Churchs Chicken, Dairy Queen, Domino&apos;s Pizza, Dunkin&apos; Donuts, Hardee&apos;s, Jack in the Box, KFC, Krispy Kreme, Little Caesar&apos;s Pizza, Long John Silvers, McDonalds, Panera Bread Co., Papa John&apos;s Pizza, Pizza Hut, Sbarro, Sonic Drive-In, Starbucks, Steak &apos;N Shake, Subway, Taco Bell, Wendy&apos;s, Whataburger. Nutrtional data included: total calories, calories from fat, fat grams, saturated fat, trans fat, cholesterol, sodium, carbohydrates, dietary fiber, sugar, and protein. All items listed here: Fast Food Facts Menu Items Special diet information : Exercise, nutrition, diet, special diet, diabetes diet, low-carb, low carb diet also included. For sale: The Fast Food Facts Book , nutrition information in book form, nutrition information on Fast Food Restaurants in book form.
	</body>
</document>
