<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004214" url="http://wn.com/Wumbo" time="2012-07-12-20:27" support="1" score="0.0006699725028411081" bingtitle="Wumbo - World News" webtitle="Wumbo">
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure, however. Therefore, though we strive to use commercially acceptable ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, 12 July 2012 upload Login Edit 
 go to the top About WN Contact Feedback Privacy Policy ©2012 World News Inc., all Rights Reserved 
 Wumbo Tweet sms this page email this page 
 Videos Images Wiki Related Video Details Twitter Collage Bing Shopping 
 
 SpongeBob SquarePants (season 3) Asshole 

 Related News Top Headlines 

 wumbo 

 wumbo 

 Related Sites People Places Video Suggestions 

 WN Shopping Ebay Publications 
 
 

 Open Collage in a new Window Email the Collage 
 Loading... 
 Sorry your browser does not support IFRAME Loading suggestions ... 
 Alec Baldwin Andrew Overtoom Animation Band Geeks Best Day Ever Betrayal Bikini Bottom Brittle (food) C. H. Greenblatt C.H. Greenblatt Carlos Alazraqui Christmas Who? Chum Bucket Clubhouse Cockroach Continuity error Cremation Dan Povenmire Dani Michaeli David Hasselhoff Dee Bradley Baker Derek Drymon Dream Dunces and Dragons DVD Earth Erik Wiese Ernest Borgnine Excavator Fools in April Frank Weiss Frozen Face-Off Gary the Snail Gasoline Ghoul Fools Glacier Green Eggs and Ham Headstone Herman Melville Hospital Humour Jaws (film) Jay Lender Jeffrey Tambor Just One Bite Krusty Krab Leapfrog Lord of the Flies Luke Brookshier Magic 8-Ball Mark O&apos;Hare Mattress Merriwether Williams Midlife crisis Mirror Moby-Dick Money Moon Mr. Krabs Mr. Lawrence NASA Neil Ross Nickelodeon Nicktoons Padded cell Panty raid Paramedic Paranoia Party Pooper Pants Patrick Star Paul Tibbitt Pest of the West Phaseolus lunatus Portal Animation Portal Nickelodeon Portal Television Pranks a Lot Region 1 Region 2 Region 4 Rocko&apos;s Modern Life Rodney Bingenheimer Rough Draft Studios Safe Sailor Mouth Saliva Sam Henderson Sand Sandy Cheeks Sandy&apos;s Rocket Scallop Scarlett Johansson Seahorse Sean Dempsey September 11 attacks Sherm Cohen Sidekick Snare drum SpongeBob (season 9) Square dancing Squidward Tentacles Stephen Hillenburg Steve Nesbit Steven Banks Steven Spielberg STS-51-L Texas Tim Conway Tim Hill Tom Kenny Tom King (writer) Tom Yasumi Tomato United States Vincent Waller Walt Dohrn Water WhoBob WhatPants? Wikipedia Cleanup Wood Your Shoe&apos;s Untied YouTube 
 

 
 Bikini Bottom 
 http://wn.com/Bikini_Bottom NASA 
The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA, ) is an Executive Branch agency of the United States government, responsible for the nation&apos;s civilian space program and aeronautics and aerospace research. Since February 2006, NASA&apos;s self-described mission statement is to &quot;pioneer the future in space exploration, scientific discovery and aeronautics research.&quot;
 http://wn.com/NASA Texas 
Texas () is the second-largest U.S. state by both area and population, and the largest state in the contiguous United States.
 http://wn.com/Texas United States 
The United States of America (also referred to as the United States, the U.S., the USA, or America) is a federal constitutional republic comprising fifty states and a federal district. The country is situated mostly in central North America, where its forty-eight contiguous states and Washington, D.C., the capital district, lie between the Pacific and Atlantic Oceans, bordered by Canada to the north and Mexico to the south. The state of Alaska is in the northwest of the continent, with Canada to the east and Russia to the west across the Bering Strait. The state of Hawaii is an archipelago in the mid-Pacific. The country also possesses several territories in the Caribbean and Pacific.
 http://wn.com/United_States 




 
 Aaron Springer 
Aaron Springer is a modern animator and storyboard artist. Springer is best known as a storyboard artist for American animated series SpongeBob SquarePants , &apos;&apos;Dexter&apos;s Laboratory , and Samurai Jack. He also directed several of these episodes. Recently, Springer created and co-directed the pilot episode for Korgoth of Barbaria in collaboration with Genndy Tartakovsky. Springer also was the voice of the animated character Laughing Bubble in The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie&apos;&apos; (2004).
 http://wn.com/Aaron_Springer Andrew Overtoom 
Writer/director Andrew Overtoom is an Animation Director on SpongeBob SquarePants . He also wrote, directed and filmed My Life with Morrissey , an independent feature film shot on 16mm about an obsessed fan who meets her demise after meeting her rock star idol.
 http://wn.com/Andrew_Overtoom C. H. Greenblatt 
Carl H. Greenblatt (born June 17, 1972) is an American cartoon writer and storyboard artist. He has worked on the hit TV series SpongeBob SquarePants , and on the Cartoon Network&apos;s series The Grim Adventures of Billy&amp;Mandy and Evil Con Carne .
 http://wn.com/C_H_Greenblatt C.H. Greenblatt 
 http://wn.com/CH_Greenblatt Carlos Alazraqui 
Carlos Jaime Alazraqui (born July 20, 1962) is an American actor, stand-up comedian, impressionist and voice actor. He is best known for his role as Deputy James Garcia on the Comedy Central series Reno 911! . His voice-over work includes the role of Bobbi Fabulous on Phineas and Ferb, Denzel Q. Crocker and Juandissimo Magnifico on The Fairly OddParents! , Rocko on &apos;&apos;Rocko&apos;s Modern Life , Lazlo in Camp Lazlo , as Jonathan Weed on Family Guy&apos;&apos; and currently does the voice of Felix the Cat.
 http://wn.com/Carlos_Alazraqui Dan Povenmire 
Daniel Kingsley Povenmire (; born September 18, 1963) is an American television director, writer, producer, storyboard artist, and actor associated with several animated television series, best known as the co-creator of the Disney animated series Phineas and Ferb in which he also voices the show&apos;s villain, Heinz Doofenshmirtz. Povenmire grew up in Mobile, Alabama, where he was a talented art student who spent summers outdoors and making movies. Povenmire attended the University of South Alabama before deciding to pursue a film career and transferring to the University of Southern California School of Cinematic Arts.
 http://wn.com/Dan_Povenmire Dani Michaeli 
 http://wn.com/Dani_Michaeli Dee Bradley Baker 
Dee Bradley Baker (born August 31, 1962) is an American actor and voice actor. He is best known for his voice-work on Phineas and Ferb , SpongeBob SquarePants , Adventure Time with Finn and Jake , American Dad! , Ben 10 , , Halo , Gears of War , and &apos;&apos;Regular Show.
 http://wn.com/Dee_Bradley_Baker Derek Drymon 
Derek Drymon (born 1968) is an American writer and storyboard artist. He has worked on numerous animated cartoon productions of the 1990s and 2000s, best known for his work on &apos;&apos;Rocko&apos;s Modern Life and SpongeBob SquarePants&apos;&apos;.
 http://wn.com/Derek_Drymon Erik Wiese 
Erik Wiese (aka Eric Eldritch) is a storyboard artist and writer who has worked on the animated series SpongeBob SquarePants for four seasons, beginning with his character development and design for the pilot &quot;Help Wanted.&quot; After this he became the Co-Creator of the series The Mighty B! , where he directs all of the episodes.
 http://wn.com/Erik_Wiese Frank Weiss 
Frank Weiss (born July 25, 1944 in Cardston, Alberta) is a retired Canadian racecar driver. He competed in the USAC and CART Championship Car series.
 http://wn.com/Frank_Weiss Herman Melville 
Herman Melville (August 1, 1819–September 28, 1891) was an American novelist, short story writer, essayist, and poet, whose work is often classified as part of the genre of dark romanticism. He is best known for his novel Moby-Dick and the posthumous novella Billy Budd .
 http://wn.com/Herman_Melville Jay Lender 
Jay Lender(14 June, 1969, New Haven, Connecticut) is a writer and director on the hit TV series SpongeBob SquarePants . The episodes he made include:
 http://wn.com/Jay_Lender Luke Brookshier 
 http://wn.com/Luke_Brookshier Mark O&apos;Hare 
&apos;&apos;&apos;Mark O&apos;Hare&apos; is an American cartoonist who created the comic strip Citizen Dog&apos;&apos;.
 http://wn.com/Mark_O&apos;Hare Mr. Krabs 
Eugene H. Krabs is a fictional character on the television cartoon series SpongeBob SquarePants . He is voiced by Clancy Brown. The character is seen in most episodes of the show, as well as in movies, video games, and other media based on the series. Additionally, he has been featured on countless toys, games, dolls, and other popular merchandise items.
 http://wn.com/Mr_Krabs Mr. Lawrence 
 http://wn.com/Mr_Lawrence Neil Ross 
Neilson &quot;Neil&quot; Ross (born 31 December 1944) is an English voice actor and announcer, born in London, England and now resident and working in Los Angeles, in the United States. He has provided voices for (mainly minor characters) in many American cartoons, particularly those based on Hasbro products and Marvel Comics, and numerous video games. Ross has also provided voice roles (such as radio announcers) for many movies, including Back to the Future II , Babe , Quiz Show , and Being John Malkovich .
 http://wn.com/Neil_Ross Paul Tibbitt 
Paul Tibbitt is a prolific cartoon writer and storyboard artist on the TV series SpongeBob SquarePants . He is currently the Co-Executive Producer of the show. He is the voice of Mama Krabs, Doodlebob and Potty the Parrot. He studied in the Character Animation program at the California Institute of the Arts.
 http://wn.com/Paul_Tibbitt Stephen Hillenburg 
Stephen McDannell Hillenburg (born August 21, 1961) is an American animator, writer, producer, actor, voice actor, and director best known for creating the animated series SpongeBob SquarePants . He currently owns his own production company, United Plankton Pictures. He has also written for Mother Goose and Grimm and &apos;&apos;Rocko&apos;s Modern Life&apos;&apos;.
 http://wn.com/Stephen_Hillenburg Steve Nesbit 
Steven Roberto Nesbit (Steve Nesbit) was born on 13 February 1936 in Auckland, New Zealand. He was educated at St Peter&apos;s College. He is a former rugby union footballer who played for the All Blacks. He played in in the position of First five-eighth. He played 11 matches for the All Blacks in 1960, including 10 tests.
 http://wn.com/Steve_Nesbit Steven Banks 
Steven Banks (born November 27) is an American musician, comedian, actor, mime and writer of television, plays, books and cartoons, including SpongeBob SquarePants .
 http://wn.com/Steven_Banks Steven Spielberg 
Steven Allan Spielberg, (born December 18, 1946) is an American film director, screenwriter, film producer and video game designer. In a career spanning six decades, Spielberg&apos;s films have covered many themes and genres. Spielberg&apos;s early science-fiction and adventure films were seen as an archetype of modern Hollywood blockbuster filmmaking. In later years, his films began addressing such issues as the Holocaust, slavery, war and terrorism. He is considered one of the most influential filmmakers in the history of cinema. He is also one of the founders of DreamWorks.
 http://wn.com/Steven_Spielberg Tim Conway 
Thomas Daniel &quot;Tim&quot; Conway (born December 15, 1933) is an American comedian and actor, primarily known for his roles in sitcoms, films and television. Conway is best-known for his role as the inept second-in-command officer, Ensign Charles Parker, to Lt. Commander Quinton McHale (played by Ernest Borgnine), in the popular 1960s WWII sitcom &apos;&apos;McHale&apos;s Navy , and for co-starring alongside Carol Burnett on The Carol Burnett Show&apos;&apos;.
 http://wn.com/Tim_Conway Tim Hill 
Tim Hill is one of the most &quot;well known infamous&quot; cartoon workers of the 90&apos;s and 2000&apos;s. He began his career in 1993 as a writer and storyboard artist for &apos;&apos;Rocko&apos;s Modern Life , he also created the very popular Kablam! skit, Action League Now! . He has been active as an episode writer for SpongeBob SquarePants&apos;&apos; since 1999, and continues to do that to this day and in Matthew&apos;s World.
 http://wn.com/Tim_Hill Tom Kenny 
Thomas James &quot;Tom&quot; Kenny (born July 13, 1962) is an American actor, voice actor and comedian, best known as the voice of SpongeBob SquarePants in the television series of the same name, as well as Gary the Snail and the French narrator based on Jacques Cousteau. He is also the narrator of Cartoon Network&apos;s The Powerpuff Girls . Aside from voice acting, Kenny starred in the short-lived Fox sketch show The Edge , and was a cast member of the HBO sketch comedy program Mr. Show , where he worked with Jill Talley, whom he subsequently married. He currently voices the Ice King in the Cartoon Network animated series Adventure Time with Finn and Jake , and voices additional characters on Scooby-Doo! Mystery Incorporated , another Cartoon Network show. As of 2007, he has also hosted the show Funday Night at the Movies on TCM, which encourages children to watch old movies. He was born in Syracuse, New York.
 http://wn.com/Tom_Kenny Tom King (writer) 
Tom King is an American television writer and story board artist best known for his work on the animated children&apos;s shows The Ren and Stimpy Show , SpongeBob SquarePants , Camp Lazlo , Chowder and The Fairly OddParents . He also worked on Fanboy and Chum Chum, also being the Head Writer of NBC Daytime&apos;s Another World , ABC Daytime&apos;s Loving , &apos;&apos;Ryan&apos;s Hope (with Millee Taggert) and a breakdown writer on One Life to Live&apos;&apos;.
 http://wn.com/Tom_King_(writer) Tom Yasumi 
Tom Yasumi is an animation director best known for his work on &apos;&apos;Rocko&apos;s Modern Life and SpongeBob SquarePants&apos;&apos;.
 http://wn.com/Tom_Yasumi Walt Dohrn 
Walter &quot;Walt&quot; Dohrn is an American voice actor, screenwriter, animator, television director and comedian. He voices the villainous Rumpelstiltskin in Shrek Forever After .
 http://wn.com/Walt_Dohrn 




 
Make changes yourself !
 LOGIN to EDIT and SAVE this page. 
 Send this Playlist by SMS Email this Page 
 I wumbo&apos;d you a song 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:54 Published: 22 Dec 2010 Updated: 11 Jul 2012 
Author: estemshorn extended version - www.youtube.com DOWNLOAD THE FREE MP3 - www.mediafire.com www.facebook.com Thanks to everyone who has watched this video so far. Please keep sending it to people! Once this reaches ~4000 views and gets to my most viewed video, i&apos;ll release the extended version 2/28 - 3000 views! The background music is&quot;A song that is so miserable that even i can admit its suckage&quot;by The Instru-mentals (the song is a reference to this lol - www.fretsonfire.net ) If this gets taken down, I&apos;m gonna fly to the viacom headquarters and fucking slap every single person in the general vicinity as hard as fucking possible because viacom is faggots and sucks ass and doesn&apos;t understand what fair fucking use is of course, no copyright infringement intended olo http://wn.com/I_wumbo&apos;d_you_a_song 
 Wumbo Dubstep 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:03 Published: 09 Jun 2011 Updated: 11 Jul 2012 
Author: survivor672 PATRIC STAR IS DANK... made on Audacity 1.3 beta and fl studio. Be sure to RATE and SUBSCRIBE and check us out on facebook at: www.facebook.com http://wn.com/Wumbo_Dubstep 
 psych-- boom boom booom... muffins.... 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:19 Published: 04 Sep 2009 Updated: 21 May 2012 
Author: oxlauren18xo favorite thing that has ever crossed his lips. .... that&apos;s incredible i know i made it up just now no i was talking about the detective thing that too. http://wn.com/psych-_boom_boom_booom_muffins 
 I wumbo&apos;d you a song (extended) 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:29 Published: 12 Mar 2011 Updated: 11 Jul 2012 
Author: estemshorn Free Download: www.mediafire.com www.facebook.com Thanks to everyone who watched the original video, all ~4000 of you. Also thanks to the people who told me to make this longer. Thanks to Viacom too, for not being a total prick and taking it down this time. The background music is&quot;A song that is so miserable that even i can admit its suckage&quot;by The Instru-mentals (the song is a reference to this lol - www.fretsonfire.net ) If this gets taken down, I&apos;m gonna fly to the viacom headquarters and fucking slap every single person in the general vicinity as hard as fucking possible because viacom is faggots and sucks ass and doesn&apos;t understand what fair fucking use is of course, no copyright infringement intended olo http://wn.com/I_wumbo&apos;d_you_a_song_extended 
 WuMbO 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:30 Published: 11 Dec 2011 Updated: 10 Jul 2012 
Author: Sypher782 WhY ArE We uNdEr tHe mOtHeRfUcKiNg oCeAn? Karkat: ambitiousBard http://wn.com/WuMbO 
 I wumbo&apos;d you a memorial video (RIP Ernest Borgnine) 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:12 Published: 09 Jul 2012 Updated: 11 Jul 2012 
Author: estemshorn In memory of Ernest Borgnine (1917-2012) I wumbo&apos;d you a song is my #1 video on youtube. Combined, the original and the extended version make up half of my overall view count. nearly 50000 views. Ernest voiced Mermaid Man. And if you didn&apos;t know, the whole Wumbo scene was from the episode Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy IV. Without him, wumbo probably never wouldn&apos;t have happened, therefore I wouldn&apos;t have been able to commit copyright infrigement and make my most-viewed video evar. Not to mention I love spongebob and the Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy episodes were some of my favorites. The song is a depressing remix of&quot;I wumbo&apos;d you a song&quot;. Performed by me (Original song by The Instru-mentals) on my delicious midi keyboard. Go watch the original&quot;I wumbo&apos;d you a song&quot;video here: www.youtube.com http://wn.com/I_wumbo&apos;d_you_a_memorial_video_RIP_Ernest_Borgnine 
 spongebob wumbo 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:31 Published: 27 Feb 2007 Updated: 09 Jul 2012 
Author: holyschnike duhh http://wn.com/spongebob_wumbo 
 SBSP - Wumbo Sparta Remix (Sparta Duel vs. Jario943) 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:26 Published: 24 Jul 2011 Updated: 03 Jul 2012 
Author: Sliacen Round 1 vs. Jario943 First time ever sparta dueling...I&apos;m not sure if I&apos;m doing this correctly. Whatever...what matters is that I tried my best. Copyright belongs to Viacom and stuff. http://wn.com/SBSP_Wumbo_Sparta_Remix_Sparta_Duel_vs_Jario943 
 RuneScape SANTA HAT LURE - #Wumbo [--110m+ L00TATIONS--] 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:41 Published: 02 May 2012 Updated: 05 Jul 2012 
Author: itzToaster Stay tuned until the end for his live reaction :p Now recruiting for my new clan, Wumbo. The cost is 75m to get in, we lure every day. Skype is not required but it&apos;s helpful. Inbox me for an application if you&apos;re interested in joining. Song: Huey Mack - Popular http://wn.com/RuneScape_SANTA_HAT_LURE_Wumbo_--110m+_L00TATIONS--_ 
 -Rares Lured- RuneScape Clan Wars Lure Vid 5 [Wumbo] - 500m+ Lured [Red&amp;Purple Portal] Toaster 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 4:27 Published: 26 May 2012 Updated: 07 Jul 2012 
Author: itzToaster Pictures used in this video gyazo.com gyazo.com gyazo.com Clan Members&apos;YouTube&apos;s www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com If you wish to join wumbo, inbox me on YouTube. There&apos;s a 75m entry fee, which gets you in the cc and all of our methods. 1st Song - www.youtube.com 2nd Song - www.youtube.com http://wn.com/-Rares_Lured_RuneScape_Clan_Wars_Lure_Vid_5_Wumbo_500m+_Lured_Red_Purple_Portal_Toaster 
 RuneScape - #Wumbo 130m Lure - Blue H&apos;ween, Ags, Bandos 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:02 Published: 24 May 2012 Updated: 04 Jul 2012 
Author: itzToaster Want to join #Wumbo? Inbox me on YouTube. Picture of us luring him in red - gyazo.com ________________________________________________________________________ Rwter Downed for Bank - youtu.be Lure Vid 4(Masks, Santas) - youtu.be Song - Skylar Grey Ft. Lupe Fiasco - Words I Never Said (Zoroaster Remix) http://wn.com/RuneScape_Wumbo_130m_Lure_Blue_H&apos;ween,_Ags,_Bandos 
 MMD-Wumbo (from spongebob) 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:23 Published: 26 Mar 2011 Updated: 06 Jul 2012 
Author: Mela475 boredom=spongebob :D(or Patrick at least) X3 CMON! YOU KNOW! I WUMBO YOU WUMBO HE SHE ME WUMBO~ WUMBOLOGY! THE STUDY OF WUMBO! IT&apos;S FIRST GRADE SPONGEBOB!(which was absent at the time) (Nothing but animating belongs to me. Models and audio belong to their rightful owners) -- Why so many views? -.-lll http://wn.com/MMD-Wumbo_from_spongebob 
 Flipnote Hatena - Wumbo is a word 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:27 Published: 17 Sep 2010 Updated: 10 Jul 2012 
Author: rbrsonicx credit to Guaps Check his stuff out at flipnote.hatena.com or his youtube: WiiYoshi14 www.youtube.com http://wn.com/Flipnote_Hatena_Wumbo_is_a_word 
 Patrick Star Explaining Wumbo 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:17 Published: 21 Oct 2011 Updated: 10 Jul 2012 
Author: OldSkoolgamerz Patrick&apos;s enriching and wisdom-filled lecture regarding the study of wumbo. http://wn.com/Patrick_Star_Explaining_Wumbo 
 RuneScape - #Wumbo - Green H&apos;ween Mask Lure ft. RagBrid [Toaster] 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:35 Published: 20 May 2012 Updated: 07 Jul 2012 
Author: itzToaster Santa Hat Lure - youtu.be RWter downed for bank - youtu.be Clan Wars Lure Vid 4 - youtu.be Song - www.youtube.com http://wn.com/RuneScape_Wumbo_Green_H&apos;ween_Mask_Lure_ft_RagBrid_Toaster_ 
 Stupid Starfish-Squidward&apos;s True Love and WUMBO 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:55 Published: 07 Jul 2010 Updated: 09 Jun 2012 
Author: Goldenretriever2009 Spongebob goes to Patrick for his wisdom on the Shrunken Squidward, but he seems to think Squid will fall in love with a Pickle...&quot;THEY LIKE EACHOTHER!!!&quot;Then Patrick gives Spongebob his words of wisdom...&quot;You got it set to M for Mini, when it should be set to W for WUMBO!!!&quot;To see full episode watch Spongebob Squarepants on Nickelodeon, it&apos;s a great and funny show! THE WUMBO MOMENT http://wn.com/Stupid_Starfish-Squidward&apos;s_True_Love_and_WUMBO 
 Wumbo Bomb 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:22 Published: 18 Jan 2010 Updated: 01 Jul 2012 
Author: Detholize Don&apos;t set it to&quot;W&quot;... http://wn.com/Wumbo_Bomb 
 RuneScape - Red H&apos;ween - LOL @ THAT LOOT [Wumbo] 180m Lure 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:52 Published: 11 Jun 2012 Updated: 07 Jul 2012 
Author: itzToaster LURE VID 5 - youtu.be LURE VID 4 - youtu.be -------- RARE LURES ------- Blue H&apos;ween - youtu.be Green H&apos;ween - youtu.be Green H&apos;ween - youtu.be Red H&apos;ween - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Song used - www.youtube.com http://wn.com/RuneScape_Red_H&apos;ween_LOL_@_THAT_LOOT_Wumbo_180m_Lure 
 Update: Wumbo stops Amnesia? Wumbo gets paid? 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:03 Published: 02 Nov 2011 Updated: 22 Jun 2012 
Author: WumboGaming Facebook fanpage for updates: www.facebook.com Royalty free music I used: Monokle Galun - Get At Will For those who dont have sound: Thanks so much everyone for subscribing and leaving me positive feedback! I will start making Amnesia videos again soon, I just wanted a break from it because I&apos;ve played it for 7 months straight every day, I wasnt getting as scared anymore as I used to http://wn.com/Update_Wumbo_stops_Amnesia?_Wumbo_gets_paid? 
 The Viridian City - W is for Wumbo 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 5:07 Published: 28 Jul 2009 Updated: 01 Jun 2012 
Author: fudgermonkey99 My friends band The Viridian City playing their original song W is for Wumbo. I just took some clips of a live show and put the song over it to provide a video to watch so you can see how they act live to persuade you to go to their shows. If you guys like this then check the band out at their myspace (www.myspace.com/theviridiancity) http://wn.com/The_Viridian_City_W_is_for_Wumbo 
 #4 Wumbo died horribly - Zombie Escape 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 6:12 Published: 04 Jun 2011 Updated: 02 Feb 2012 
Author: WumboGaming Always feel free to suggest any custom story I havent played yet :D http://wn.com/_4_Wumbo_died_horribly_Zombie_Escape 
 #3 Wumbo gets scared again - Followed by Death Chapter One 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 10:48 Published: 03 Apr 2012 Updated: 16 Jun 2012 
Author: WumboGaming Hit the like button if you enjoyed it, also dont forget to share it with your friends Facebook Fanpage: www.facebook.com http://wn.com/_3_Wumbo_gets_scared_again_Followed_by_Death_Chapter_One 
 Wumbo dies of laughter 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:57 Published: 10 Mar 2012 Updated: 13 Jun 2012 
Author: WumboGaming I hate my laugh, I sound like a hamster being tortured. http://wn.com/Wumbo_dies_of_laughter 
 
 Play next List all Videos Autoplay Autorepeat Shuffle Replay 
 

 
 Uploaded: Today This Week This Month Anytime 

 Sort by: Relevance Date Popular Rating 
 
 
 Sign up 
 I have an account, login 1:54 I wumbo&apos;d you a song extended version - www.youtube.com DOWNLOAD THE FREE MP3 - www.mediafire.com www.facebook.... published: 22 Dec 2010 author: estemshorn I wumbo&apos;d you a song extended version - www.youtube.com DOWNLOAD THE FREE MP3 - www.mediafire.com www.facebook.com Thanks to everyone who has watched this video so far. Please keep sending it to people! Once this reaches ~4000 views and gets to my most viewed video, i&apos;ll release the extended version 2/28 - 3000 views! The background music is&quot;A song that is so miserable that even i can admit its suckage&quot;by The Instru-mentals (the song is a reference to this lol - www.fretsonfire.net ) If this gets taken down, I&apos;m gonna fly to the viacom headquarters and fucking slap every single person in the general vicinity as hard as fucking possible because viacom is faggots and sucks ass and doesn&apos;t understand what fair fucking use is of course, no copyright infringement intended olo 1:03 Wumbo Dubstep PATRIC STAR IS DANK... made on Audacity 1.3 beta and fl studio. Be sure to RATE and SUBSCR... published: 09 Jun 2011 author: survivor672 Wumbo Dubstep PATRIC STAR IS DANK... made on Audacity 1.3 beta and fl studio. Be sure to RATE and SUBSCRIBE and check us out on facebook at: www.facebook.com 0:19 psych-- boom boom booom... muffins.... favorite thing that has ever crossed his lips. .... that&apos;s incredible i know i made it... published: 04 Sep 2009 author: oxlauren18xo psych-- boom boom booom... muffins.... favorite thing that has ever crossed his lips. .... that&apos;s incredible i know i made it up just now no i was talking about the detective thing that too. 2:29 I wumbo&apos;d you a song (extended) Free Download: www.mediafire.com www.facebook.com Thanks to everyone who watched the origi... published: 12 Mar 2011 author: estemshorn I wumbo&apos;d you a song (extended) Free Download: www.mediafire.com www.facebook.com Thanks to everyone who watched the original video, all ~4000 of you. Also thanks to the people who told me to make this longer. Thanks to Viacom too, for not being a total prick and taking it down this time. The background music is&quot;A song that is so miserable that even i can admit its suckage&quot;by The Instru-mentals (the song is a reference to this lol - www.fretsonfire.net ) If this gets taken down, I&apos;m gonna fly to the viacom headquarters and fucking slap every single person in the general vicinity as hard as fucking possible because viacom is faggots and sucks ass and doesn&apos;t understand what fair fucking use is of course, no copyright infringement intended olo 0:30 WuMbO WhY ArE We uNdEr tHe mOtHeRfUcKiNg oCeAn? Karkat: ambitiousBard... published: 11 Dec 2011 author: Sypher782 WuMbO WhY ArE We uNdEr tHe mOtHeRfUcKiNg oCeAn? Karkat: ambitiousBard 2:12 I wumbo&apos;d you a memorial video (RIP Ernest Borgnine) In memory of Ernest Borgnine (1917-2012) I wumbo&apos;d you a song is my #1 video on youtub... published: 09 Jul 2012 author: estemshorn I wumbo&apos;d you a memorial video (RIP Ernest Borgnine) In memory of Ernest Borgnine (1917-2012) I wumbo&apos;d you a song is my #1 video on youtube. Combined, the original and the extended version make up half of my overall view count. nearly 50000 views. Ernest voiced Mermaid Man. And if you didn&apos;t know, the whole Wumbo scene was from the episode Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy IV. Without him, wumbo probably never wouldn&apos;t have happened, therefore I wouldn&apos;t have been able to commit copyright infrigement and make my most-viewed video evar. Not to mention I love spongebob and the Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy episodes were some of my favorites. The song is a depressing remix of&quot;I wumbo&apos;d you a song&quot;. Performed by me (Original song by The Instru-mentals) on my delicious midi keyboard. Go watch the original&quot;I wumbo&apos;d you a song&quot;video here: www.youtube.com 0:31 spongebob wumbo duhh... published: 27 Feb 2007 author: holyschnike spongebob wumbo duhh 2:26 SBSP - Wumbo Sparta Remix (Sparta Duel vs. Jario943) Round 1 vs. Jario943 First time ever sparta dueling...I&apos;m not sure if I&apos;m doing th... published: 24 Jul 2011 author: Sliacen SBSP - Wumbo Sparta Remix (Sparta Duel vs. Jario943) Round 1 vs. Jario943 First time ever sparta dueling...I&apos;m not sure if I&apos;m doing this correctly. Whatever...what matters is that I tried my best. Copyright belongs to Viacom and stuff. 2:41 RuneScape SANTA HAT LURE - #Wumbo [--110m+ L00TATIONS--] Stay tuned until the end for his live reaction :p Now recruiting for my new clan, Wumbo. T... published: 02 May 2012 author: itzToaster RuneScape SANTA HAT LURE - #Wumbo [--110m+ L00TATIONS--] Stay tuned until the end for his live reaction :p Now recruiting for my new clan, Wumbo. The cost is 75m to get in, we lure every day. Skype is not required but it&apos;s helpful. Inbox me for an application if you&apos;re interested in joining. Song: Huey Mack - Popular 4:27 -Rares Lured- RuneScape Clan Wars Lure Vid 5 [Wumbo] - 500m+ Lured [Red&amp;Purple Portal] Toaster Pictures used in this video gyazo.com gyazo.com gyazo.com Clan Members&apos;YouTube&apos;s ... published: 26 May 2012 author: itzToaster -Rares Lured- RuneScape Clan Wars Lure Vid 5 [Wumbo] - 500m+ Lured [Red&amp;Purple Portal] Toaster Pictures used in this video gyazo.com gyazo.com gyazo.com Clan Members&apos;YouTube&apos;s www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com www.youtube.com If you wish to join wumbo, inbox me on YouTube. There&apos;s a 75m entry fee, which gets you in the cc and all of our methods. 1st Song - www.youtube.com 2nd Song - www.youtube.com 1:02 RuneScape - #Wumbo 130m Lure - Blue H&apos;ween, Ags, Bandos Want to join #Wumbo? Inbox me on YouTube. Picture of us luring him in red - gyazo.com ____... published: 24 May 2012 author: itzToaster RuneScape - #Wumbo 130m Lure - Blue H&apos;ween, Ags, Bandos Want to join #Wumbo? Inbox me on YouTube. Picture of us luring him in red - gyazo.com ________________________________________________________________________ Rwter Downed for Bank - youtu.be Lure Vid 4(Masks, Santas) - youtu.be Song - Skylar Grey Ft. Lupe Fiasco - Words I Never Said (Zoroaster Remix) 0:23 MMD-Wumbo (from spongebob) boredom=spongebob :D(or Patrick at least) X3 CMON! YOU KNOW! I WUMBO YOU WUMBO HE SHE ME W... published: 26 Mar 2011 author: Mela475 MMD-Wumbo (from spongebob) boredom=spongebob :D(or Patrick at least) X3 CMON! YOU KNOW! I WUMBO YOU WUMBO HE SHE ME WUMBO~ WUMBOLOGY! THE STUDY OF WUMBO! IT&apos;S FIRST GRADE SPONGEBOB!(which was absent at the time) (Nothing but animating belongs to me. Models and audio belong to their rightful owners) -- Why so many views? -.-lll 0:27 Flipnote Hatena - Wumbo is a word credit to Guaps Check his stuff out at flipnote.hatena.com or his youtube: WiiYoshi14 www.... published: 17 Sep 2010 author: rbrsonicx Flipnote Hatena - Wumbo is a word credit to Guaps Check his stuff out at flipnote.hatena.com or his youtube: WiiYoshi14 www.youtube.com 0:17 Patrick Star Explaining Wumbo Patrick&apos;s enriching and wisdom-filled lecture regarding the study of wumbo.... published: 21 Oct 2011 author: OldSkoolgamerz Patrick Star Explaining Wumbo Patrick&apos;s enriching and wisdom-filled lecture regarding the study of wumbo. 1:35 RuneScape - #Wumbo - Green H&apos;ween Mask Lure ft. RagBrid [Toaster] Santa Hat Lure - youtu.be RWter downed for bank - youtu.be Clan Wars Lure Vid 4 - youtu.be... published: 20 May 2012 author: itzToaster RuneScape - #Wumbo - Green H&apos;ween Mask Lure ft. RagBrid [Toaster] Santa Hat Lure - youtu.be RWter downed for bank - youtu.be Clan Wars Lure Vid 4 - youtu.be Song - www.youtube.com 0:55 Stupid Starfish-Squidward&apos;s True Love and WUMBO Spongebob goes to Patrick for his wisdom on the Shrunken Squidward, but he seems to think ... published: 07 Jul 2010 author: Goldenretriever2009 Stupid Starfish-Squidward&apos;s True Love and WUMBO Spongebob goes to Patrick for his wisdom on the Shrunken Squidward, but he seems to think Squid will fall in love with a Pickle...&quot;THEY LIKE EACHOTHER!!!&quot;Then Patrick gives Spongebob his words of wisdom...&quot;You got it set to M for Mini, when it should be set to W for WUMBO!!!&quot;To see full episode watch Spongebob Squarepants on Nickelodeon, it&apos;s a great and funny show! THE WUMBO MOMENT 0:22 Wumbo Bomb Don&apos;t set it to&quot;W&quot;...... published: 18 Jan 2010 author: Detholize Wumbo Bomb Don&apos;t set it to&quot;W&quot;... 1:52 RuneScape - Red H&apos;ween - LOL @ THAT LOOT [Wumbo] 180m Lure LURE VID 5 - youtu.be LURE VID 4 - youtu.be -------- RARE LURES ------- Blue H&apos;ween - ... published: 11 Jun 2012 author: itzToaster RuneScape - Red H&apos;ween - LOL @ THAT LOOT [Wumbo] 180m Lure LURE VID 5 - youtu.be LURE VID 4 - youtu.be -------- RARE LURES ------- Blue H&apos;ween - youtu.be Green H&apos;ween - youtu.be Green H&apos;ween - youtu.be Red H&apos;ween - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Song used - www.youtube.com 2:03 Update: Wumbo stops Amnesia? Wumbo gets paid? Facebook fanpage for updates: www.facebook.com Royalty free music I used: Monokle Galun - ... published: 02 Nov 2011 author: WumboGaming Update: Wumbo stops Amnesia? Wumbo gets paid? Facebook fanpage for updates: www.facebook.com Royalty free music I used: Monokle Galun - Get At Will For those who dont have sound: Thanks so much everyone for subscribing and leaving me positive feedback! I will start making Amnesia videos again soon, I just wanted a break from it because I&apos;ve played it for 7 months straight every day, I wasnt getting as scared anymore as I used to 5:07 The Viridian City - W is for Wumbo My friends band The Viridian City playing their original song W is for Wumbo. I just took ... published: 28 Jul 2009 author: fudgermonkey99 The Viridian City - W is for Wumbo My friends band The Viridian City playing their original song W is for Wumbo. I just took some clips of a live show and put the song over it to provide a video to watch so you can see how they act live to persuade you to go to their shows. If you guys like this then check the band out at their myspace (www.myspace.com/theviridiancity) 6:12 #4 Wumbo died horribly - Zombie Escape Always feel free to suggest any custom story I havent played yet :D... published: 04 Jun 2011 author: WumboGaming #4 Wumbo died horribly - Zombie Escape Always feel free to suggest any custom story I havent played yet :D 10:48 #3 Wumbo gets scared again - Followed by Death Chapter One Hit the like button if you enjoyed it, also dont forget to share it with your friends Face... published: 03 Apr 2012 author: WumboGaming #3 Wumbo gets scared again - Followed by Death Chapter One Hit the like button if you enjoyed it, also dont forget to share it with your friends Facebook Fanpage: www.facebook.com show more results remove add to playlist &lt;%= durationStr %&gt; &lt;%= title %&gt; &lt;%= tooltipContentBody %&gt; &lt;%= title %&gt; ... &lt;%= durationStr %&gt; &lt;%= tooltipContentBody %&gt; 

 
 This article has multiple issues . Please help improve it or discuss these issues on the talk page . 
 It does not cite any references or sources . Please help improve it by adding citations to reliable sources . Tagged since April 2011. It describes a work or element of fiction in a primarily in-universe style that may require cleanup . Tagged since April 2011. It may contain original research . Tagged since April 2011. 
 

 SpongeBob SquarePants Season 3 200px 
 SpongeBob SquarePants , Season 3 Country of origin United States Broadcast Original channel Nickelodeon Original run October 5, 2001 – October 11, 2004 Home video release DVD release Region 1 September 27, 2005 Region 2 December 3, 2007 Season chronology 
 ←  Previous 
 Season 2 Next  →
 Season 4 
 

 Season three of the animated television series SpongeBob SquarePants aired 37 episodes on Nickelodeon from October 5, 2001 with &quot; The Bully &quot; and &quot; Just One Bite &quot; to October 11, 2004 with &quot; SpongeBob Meets the Strangler &quot; and &quot; Pranks a Lot &quot;. The show was put on hiatus during 2003. Episodes aired every few months after that date until October 11, 2004 which it ended. The show was put on hiatus again, however, and Season 4 would not begin until 6 May 2005. Like previous seasons, season three consists of 20 episodes. Season 3 was released on DVD in region 1 on September 27, 2005; region 4 on November 8, 2007 and region 2 on December 3, 2007. Season 3 was the last season with Stephen Hillenburg as the showrunner - he left after the movie . After his departure, Paul Tibbitt became the new showrunner which varies on the series animation and humour .
 
 
Contents
 
 1 Episodes 2 The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie 3 References 
 
 
 Episodes [link] 

 Episode Number Title Directed by Written by Original air date 41a &quot;The Algae&apos;s Always Greener&quot; Frank Weiss Aaron Springer 
 C.H. Greenblatt 
 Merriwether Williams March 22, 2002 Plankton wants Mr. Krabs&apos; secret formula, so he uses a machine to help him switch lives with the delusional crab, to see what it is like. Plankton gets so close to getting the Krabby Patty, but he is challenged by all the things Mr. Krabs has to face, such as SpongeBob’s weekly performance review, Squidward&apos;s hatred against working with SpongeBob, Pearl wanting a bigger allowance, Squidward&apos;s awful performance, and invasions from his rival (who is now a naked Mr. Krabs), and the horrid &quot;Victory Screech&quot; that the staff and customers of the Krusty Krab emit after a failed invasion by the rival. Eventually, all of these disturbances cause a deeply bothered Plankton to switch back to his life. In the end, he&apos;s happy again.  41b &quot;SpongeGuard on Duty&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Mark O&apos;Hare March 22, 2002 SpongeBob volunteers for life guard duty at Goo Lagoon when Larry the Lobster mistakes ice cream on SpongeBob&apos;s nose for sun block (man sauce), the official sign of a Goo Lagoon lifeguard. When Larry swims to save a stranded and drowning swimmer, SpongeBob begins to struggle with the fact that he cannot swim, and thus, cannot save lives (not even his own). When Larry leaves SpongeBob in charge, the sponge tries to prevent disaster by closing off the beachfront, offering everyone free ice cream, and invoking the one-hour waiting period after eating. Then Patrick shows up misunderstanding things and running into the water, and SpongeBob must save his pal. But he fails (because of Patrick), and Larry rescues them both. He then gives them swimming lessons.  42a &quot;Club SpongeBob&quot; Andrew Overtoom Walt Dohrn 
 Mark O&apos;Hare March 12, 2002 
SpongeBob and Patrick form a club, and become trapped in a clubhouse that hardly has any room. When SpongeBob states that the cephalopod wouldn&apos;t fit in, Squidward becomes offended and decides to try to join anyway. Despite SpongeBob and Patrick&apos;s pleas to stay out, Squidward squeezes himself into their tiny clubhouse. As it turns out, Patrick was speaking literally when he said Squidward wouldn&apos;t fit in, to which SpongeBob adds that they have been stuck in the clubhouse for 3 days. While trying to climb out, Squidward causes the clubhouse to land in a tropical forest in the middle of nowhere. While he seeks for a way out, SpongeBob and Patrick take the advice of their &quot;Magic Conch Shell&quot; (a parody of the magic conch from Lord of the Flies and the popular Magic 8-Ball ), which tells them to do &quot;nothing&quot; and wait, a method that surprisingly works to their advantage. Meanwhile, Squidward does not share his companions&apos; belief in the supposed powers of the shell. When supplies fall from the sky,(from a plane) Squidward keeps asking the magic conch if he can have something to eat though the magic conch keeps replying with &quot;No&quot;. The last time that he asks, he gets really angry (though it&apos;s not known if at this point, he would have to smash it on the ground). Eventually, a potential rescuer arrives, but he is also a Magic Conch Shell&apos;s club member (much to Squidward&apos;s dismay). The conch tells them to do &quot;nothing&quot; again and sit down. Squidward then decides to surrender and sit down with the three.
Note: There is a continuity error in this episode. When squidward was asking the magic conch shell for food it showed spongebob&apos;s hand holding the conch when it was squidward holding it.  42b &quot;My Pretty Seahorse&quot; Tom Yasumi Kent Osborne
 Paul Tibbitt March 12, 2002 
SpongeBob finds a lost Seahorse near his house one day and decides to adopt it. He names her &quot;Mystery&quot;. When SpongeBob brings Mystery to work one day, Mr. Krabs orders him to get rid of her. The sponge decides to hide Mystery inside the restaurant, only to see that it&apos;s quite difficult to cook food and keep a wild animal from being seen at the same time, since Mystery keeps escaping and eating everything in sight, including one of the customers and all the money in the restaurant&apos;s safe .

One Time appearance: Mystery the Seahorse 
This may be Mystery&apos;s only appearance in the TV series but you can ride her in the Game Boy version of Battle for Bikini Bottom.  43a &quot;The Bully&quot; Frank Weiss Aaron Springer 
 C.H. Greenblatt 
 Merriwether Williams October 5, 2001 
SpongeBob is terrified when a new student named Flats comes to his boating school and says he wants to kick SpongeBob&apos;s butt. After being stalked by Flats all day, Flats catches up with him and gets ready to kick his butt, although, every time he strikes SpongeBob the blows are absorbed by SpongeBob&apos;s sponge-material body. Flats continues to punch SpongeBob all day and night. The next day, at school, Flats runs out of energy and passes out. Mrs. Puff enters the classroom and gasps at the sight of Flats lying on the floor and SpongeBob standing beside him with his fist raised. Thinking SpongeBob has beat up Flats for no reason, she says she&apos;s going to kick SpongeBob&apos;s butt.

Third appearance of Boating Students and Flatts

Note: Though it may seem so, this is not Flats&apos;s first appearance. His debut was in fact in the season 1 episode &quot; Sandy&apos;s Rocket &quot;. When SpongeBob and Patrick believe they are on the Moon (when in reality they are still in Bikini Bottom, Earth ), and wrongly assume that the Bikini Bottomites are untrustworthy aliens that are disguised as the citizens of Bikini Bottom, SpongeBob hides behind the door in Flats&apos;s bathroom mirror and traps him using a net gun. Flats made a second appearance in the episode &quot; Texas &quot;, when Sandy realizes that her real home is in Bikini Bottom, not Texas SpongeBob and Patrick throw a party for Sandy at the Krusty Krab and SpongeBob shows her square dancing (Flats dancing with a purple box).

Twice during the episode, SpongeBob runs in fear from Flats, and inadvertently points to a old fish when he says Flats is gonna kick his butt. The citizens of Bikini Bottom, led by Harold, are angry at this, and beat up the old fish.
There is a deleted scene in this episode. One of the things SpongeBob does while being beaten up by Flats is playing leapfrog with Patrick.  43b &quot;Just One Bite&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Merriwether Williams October 5, 2001 
When SpongeBob learns that Squidward has never had a Krabby Patty, it becomes his obsession to get his co-worker to take just one bite, believing that it is the reason why he is &quot;always so miserable&quot;. When Squidward finally does, he hates it; at least that&apos;s what he tells SpongeBob. In front of SpongeBob, Squidward throws the Krabby Patty to the ground, stamps on it twice, hits it with a block of wood and then slams a headstone down on it. After SpongeBob goes away, Squidward digs the Krabby Patty out and swallows what remains of it, including some excess sand . He then tries to get a Krabby Patty from SpongeBob, telling him a customer ordered it. When no one claims the patty, Squidward tells SpongeBob to leave it at the counter, but SpongeBob eats it instead. Squidward attempts to eat one out of the garbage but SpongeBob intervenes and &quot; cremates it&quot;. That night, Squidward dreams of meeting a Krabby Patty, falling in love with it, marrying it, having children with it, growing old with it and dying with it. Afterwards, he goes to the Krusty Krab and sneaks into the patty vault inside the Krusty Krab. Squidward unexpectedly sees SpongeBob come in and SpongeBob realises that Squidward does likes Krabby Patties. Squidward admits this and eats dozens of the Krabby Patties in the vault. SpongeBob tries to warn Squidward that eating too many patties at once will cause him to explode, but it&apos;s already too late. He is taken away to the hospital with his head separated from the remains of his body and the paramedic who is there in the ambulance with Squidward tells him &quot;Yeah, I remember my first Krabby Patty.&quot;

Note: This episode is a parody of the book Green Eggs and Ham with SpongeBob as &quot;Sam I am&quot; and Squidward as the grumpy unnamed character who claims to dislike green eggs and ham before admitting liking them after trying them.

There is a deleted scene in this episode. In the original episode, when Squidward enters the Krusty Krab at night after his dream, he runs up against the door, looks into the restaurant and says &quot;There it is! Unguarded! All I have to do is...&quot;, However, he then realizes breaking in is too easy and then notices a bucket of an unseen substance on top of the door. He thinks it is just water , so he kicks the door open and the bucket falls on the ground, causing the substance in the bucket to spill. Squidward walks inside the Krusty Krab and notices that the bucket did not contain water, but gasoline . A robotic arm then appears behind Squidward and drops a lit match into the gasoline puddle and Squidward screams as the Krusty Krab goes up in flames, burning him badly as well. Squidward runs into the kitchen, thinking that his pain is over, but is thwarted by another bucket of gasoline, which causes the same scenario as before. He then sees the Patty Vault and walks over to it, no longer blackened from the fire. This entire scene was later cut out, resulting in Squidward walking up to the Patty Vault without even entering the Krusty Krab. No explanation has ever been given for this, but it may be either because the scene was thought to be too violent or to ensure young children were not encouraged to play with fire, also the fact that the episode aired so close to the September 11 attacks it was believed to be considered inappropriate to air explosions and fire during the aftermath of the attack. The deleted scene can be watched via YouTube .

When the uncut version of this episode used to air The Bully used to air first but airing of the edited version has this in reverse.
There is a continuity error as well. Though Squidward claims to have never eaten a Krabby Patty, this is actually false. In &quot; Your Shoe&apos;s Untied &quot;, which aired the previous season, SpongeBob constantly trips over his untied shoelaces and accidentally launches hundreds of Krabby Patties directly into Squidward&apos;s mouth and down his throat, causing Squidward to grow to enormous size. However, Squidward never had any intention to eat them, which probably explains his denial.  44a &quot;Nasty Patty&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
 Kaz 
 Mark O&apos;Hare March 1, 2002 A health inspector comes to the Krusty Krab. Mr. Krabs and Spongebob has given the inspector a big meal. After the health inspector finish all the food, he asked for a Krabby Patty so he can pass the inspection. After Mr. Krabs and Spongebob saw the news about a man who disguised as the health inspector so he can have &quot;free food&quot;. Spongebob and Mr. Krabs thought that the heath inspector is the &quot;imposter&quot;, so they make a nasty patty and give it to the health inspector because they think he&apos;s a fake inspector. After he faints from eating the patty, SpongeBob and Krabs think they killed him (when what actually happened was that a fly got stuck in the inspector&apos;s throat). They are panicking, but still they cannot give up, so they went to bury the health inspector&apos;s body. However, when Spongebob threw a big rock out of the way, the health inspector woke up and says &quot;Where am I?&quot; and got hit by a big rock that Spongebob threw. When the cops came to fake an arrest with them, Mr. Krabs and Spongebob thought they were gonna get arrested for killing the health inspector, but Mr. Krabs said &quot;What will be the charges?&quot; and the cops said &quot;For not being in the Krusty Krab to whip us up for some delicious Krabby Patty.&quot; After the health inspector slided down the mountain to Spongebob&apos;s foot, they shrieked and Spongebob put him in the trunk and knocked out the inspector again, without seeing him, while Mr. Krabs kept the cops busy. When they got to the Krusty Krab, Spongebob tries to put the inspector&apos;s body in the freezer, but the back door to the freezer is locked, he put the body in his hat. When the cops are about to leave, the officer says &quot;I want a soda,&quot; then Mr. Krabs gave her a soda, but when she wanted ice, Mr. Krabs tried to tell her that there is no ice. The officer said &quot;It seems like you two committed a murder,&quot; Mr. Krabs, finally confesses and when they open the freezer door, it&apos;s nothing but melted ice. After the officer said &quot;Is this some kind of a joke?&quot; and Mr. Krabs say yes. The officer must have thought that he turned into a zombie and walked out and laughed. Meanwhile, after the health inspector walked in, yawning the kitchen, Spongebob screamed &quot;Ahhh!!! It&apos;s a zombie!!!&quot; The officers hit the inspector on the head, and then when he got up he said that the Krusty Krab has passed the inspection. After the inspector crawled out of the kitchen, the door shut on the inspector&apos;s head.  44b &quot;Idiot Box&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams March 1, 2002 
SpongeBob and Patrick order a giant Television set just so that they can play in the box. They let Squidward have the TV, but when Squidward tells them their idea to play in the box is stupid, SpongeBob and Patrick deny this saying that imagination is better than Television. Squidward when he begins to leave begins to hear sound effects from the box as SpongeBob and Patrick play their &quot;Imagination&quot; games. Squidward asks them how is noise being made, but they deny being aware of this. They add that it is caused by &quot;Imagination.&quot; Squidward begins to suspect later that they are using a tape recorder instead of their imaginations and so he comes into the box to find out what the sounds are caused by, but when he, Patrick, and SponeBob imagine &quot;Robot-Pirate Island&quot; the sounds are not heard. Squidward still believes that there is a tape recorder or anything that makes sound and so he sneaks into the box at night and imagines himself as a race car driver and he hears the sounds, but a garbage truck confuses the box to be garbage and it takes it to the dump with Squidward inside. In an epilogue, SpongeBob and Patrick go outside the next day to find their box gone, and so they decide to go to visit Squidward instead.

During the liftoff sounds, NASA commentator Steve Nesbit can be heard during the &quot;ascent&quot;.
The commentary of the launch was of the fatal STS-51-L Challenger mission.  45a &quot;Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy IV&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Merriwether Williams January 21, 2002 When Mermaid Man accidentally leaves his belt behind as he and Barnacle Boy leave the Krusty Krab, SpongeBob picks it up and proceeds to test it out with a barrel of pickles. Amazed at what it does, he shrinks the kitchen props. As he serves Krabby Patties to cockroaches , Squidward discovers the belt. Surprised that Mermaid Man lent it to SpongeBob, he picks up the phone and threatens to tell on him. SpongeBob is concerned that Mermaid Man will be mad, so he shrinks Squidward in order to stop him. Squidward grows angry and demands him to unshrink him this instant or he is gonna be in very big trouble. SpongeBob agrees and tries to, but unfortunately, he doesn&apos;t know how to, so he runs over to Patrick&apos;s house, where Pat thinks Squidward is an action figure. After being told by SpongeBob to stop playing with it, Pat advises him to turn the M on the belt upside-down to make a W for &quot;Wumbo&quot; and SpongeBob proceeds to fire away, but he accidentally shrinks Patrick. SpongeBob quickly panics and shrinks everybody in Bikini Bottom, including Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy. It is quickly discovered that the shrink ray&apos;s effects are irreversible, so the Bikini Bottomites climb into SpongeBob&apos;s body through his pores and begin to attack him on the inside; before they can do any real damage, SpongeBob atones for his mistakes by shrinking the city of Bikini Bottom and himself, allowing everyone to live out their lives peacefully. However, Plankton soon arrives back from his vacation to find a city his size which however accomplishes his dream to be taller to crush his enemies.  45b &quot;Doing Time&quot; Frank Weiss Aaron Springer 
 C.H. Greenblatt 
 Merriwether Williams January 21, 2002 
Spongebob has begun yet another reckless driving rampage during his driver&apos;s test, which ends plunging off a cliff. When the car nose-dives into a tanker truck full of fruit juice, which floods out an entire nursing home, Mrs. Puff is arrested on the spot and thrown in prison. Spongebob tries every will to help Mrs. Puff escape from prison, yet every time he appears, Mrs. Puff refuses to deal because she enjoys prison, especially because Spongebob isn&apos;t around. Continuous attempts by SpongeBob and Patrick to get Mrs. Puff out of jail get her in trouble with the prison wardens, and eventually, she is locked up in a straight jacket, and placed in padded celled -solitary confinement. To Mrs. Puff&apos;s dismay, the walls are made of &quot;sponge,&quot; and Spongebob&apos;s maniacally-laughing face ends up appearing on the walls, floor, and ceiling. Mrs. Puff begins screaming, only to wake up from a dream. It turns out she and Spongebob are still plunging off a cliff, this time ending in the same outcome as before, only this time Spongebob gets arrested. Mrs. Puff then begins to relax, only to appear in shackles and a prison outfit. She wakes up screaming again, and is still sitting in the boatmobile going off a cliff. Now an uninviting inmate from the first dream is driving, and she wakes up screaming again. Spongebob still happens to be driving off a cliff. Mrs. Puff groans, &quot;Oh, forget it.&quot;
 Note: Almost all of the episode is a dream.  46a &quot;Snowball Effect&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams February 22, 2002 
A snowstorm hits Bikini Bottom, thanks to a glacier that settled above the city. For SpongeBob and Patrick, this means snowball fights. An attempt to recruit Squidward is unsuccessful, as he finds such an activity to be immature, until the prospect of his neighbors injuring each other entices him. But pretty soon, Squidward goes overboard with the whole thing . Eventually, SpongeBob and Patrick decide to go inside, but Squidward thinks they&apos;re still outside and playing (partly because of a tree that is dropping snow on him, which he thinks is SpongeBob and Patrick still throwing snowballs at him).

Running Gag: Spongebob and Patrick throwing snowballs in Squidward&apos;s house which puts out Squidward&apos;s fire
in his fireplace  46b &quot;One Krab&apos;s Trash&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
 Kaz 
 Mark O&apos;Hare February 22, 2002 
Mr. Krabs sells some junk. He sold a toilet plunger to Patrick, but when he said that it looks like the toilet plunger he threw out last Tuesday, Mr. Krabs flips the bottom part over and says that it&apos;s a 17th century soup ladle. Mr. Krabs sells it for $5, but when Patrick says &quot;I only got seven,&quot; and Mr. Krabs takes the offer, he calls himself a smart shopper. Among the other junk there was a novelty soda-drink hat, which SpongeBob purchases. When Mr. Krabs finds that the hat is rare, and worth a million dollars, he tries everything he can to get it back. Eventually, he pretends to be the &quot;Ghost of Soda-drink Hats&quot; by hooking a badly drawn ghost to a fishing rod and sticking it through spongebob&apos;s houses window, and tells SpongeBob that the hat once belonged to a now-deceased person named &quot; Smitty Werbenjaegermanjenson &quot;. He tells SpongeBob that if he doesn&apos;t place the hat in Smithy&apos;s grave, he&apos;ll be cursed. So, a frightened SpongeBob decides to fulfill the command, though he apparently placed it in the grave of &quot;Smitty Werbenjaegermanjanson &quot;. Mr. Krabs defiles his grave and takes the hat, only for Smitty Werbenmanjanson to rise from the dead in the form of an animated skeleton, and asks Mr. Krabs to give him the hat back. Mr. Krabs refuses, so Smitty summons the &quot;army of the living dead&quot; to kill Mr. Krabs and take the hat back. But Mr. Krabs defeats them all, and leaves the graveyard. He then tries to sell the hat, only to learn it is it is now considered worthless, since a warehouse full of them was recently discovered. Then, SpongeBob passes by with his new hat, which claps with hands on it, and it is worth even more money — a billion dollars. Mr. Krabs then cries. Squidward is passing by and mocks Mr. Krabs by saying &quot;What a baby!&quot; a verse which Mr. Krabs said by watching Squidward dig up a grave of his &quot;Own Wishes, Hopes and Dreams&quot;.
Guests: Gary Carter III  47a &quot;As Seen on TV&quot; Frank Weiss Aaron Springer 
 C.H. Greenblatt 
 Merriwether Williams March 8, 2002 The Krusty Krab makes a low-budget TV commercial, starring Mr. Krabs, Squidward, and Pearl. SpongeBob is in it, too, but only the very top of his head can be seen from the dining area, and only his chest is seen on a close-up of a Krabby Patty. When he heads to work the next morning, SpongeBob is completely convinced that his few seconds on TV would make him a star to many, even though his face was never seen, and the inflation of his ego gets in the way of his kitchen duties.  47b &quot;Can You Spare a Dime?&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Merriwether Williams March 8, 2002 
Mr. Krabs loses his lucky first dime. Because he kept in in the register for luck, he accuses Squidward of stealing it, being the cashier. An argument ensues, and Squidward quits, setting out to fulfill his fantasies. However, SpongeBob finds Squidward on the street, living in a box and begging for change. Although Spongebob is oblivious as to what happened to him, Squidward convinces Spongebob that he lost everything in the wake of quitting his job, going as far as eating his own artwork since nobody would buy it. SpongeBob lets him move in to his house, but Squidward quickly takes over. After &quot;months&quot; of being Squidward&apos;s slave, SpongeBob tries to convince Mr. Krabs to hire Squidward back. Mr. Krabs refuses because he still believes that Squidward stole his dime. SpongeBob explodes in rage and strangles Mr. Krabs, finding out the dime (a giant ring-shaped boulder) was in his pocket. Mr. Krabs then agrees to re-hire Squidward, but then accuses him of placing the dime in his pocket.

Note: There is a continuity error in this episode. When SpongeBob shows Squidward some possible jobs in a newspaper, Squidward says he is allergic to newsprint. However, in several future episodes, Squidward is shown reading a newspaper and is not getting affected by it. It is possible that Squidward faked the allergies so he didn&apos;t have to see the jobs.  48a &quot;No Weenies Allowed&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams March 15, 2002 SpongeBob wants to get into the Salty Spittoon, the toughest club in Bikini Bottom. Sandy proves her worth and gains admission. Spongebob attempts to join as well, but the bouncer says he is a &quot;weenie&quot; (weakling) and suggests going to a restaurant called &quot;Weenie Hut Jr.&apos;s.&quot; SpongeBob is in denial, saying he is tough enough to get in but ends up at Weenie Hut Jr.&apos;s and meets two real &quot;weenies&quot; once he&apos;s in there. He then tries to get into the Salty Spittoon numerous times, only to end up at Weenie Hut Jr.&apos;s once again. He then finds Patrick at Weenie Hut Jr.&apos;s, and convinces Patrick to fake a fight with him so he can get into the Salty Spittoon. At first, their act proves unconvincing, but when SpongeBob calls Patrick &quot;Tubby&quot;, an angered Patrick punches SpongeBob. However, SpongeBob reminds Patrick that he was supposed to let him win, so Patrick agrees. He then puts on an act by beating himself senseless without his own appendages. SpongeBob seems to be the victor, so he is granted permission to enter. The next thing SpongeBob knows, he is in an ambulance on the way to a hospital with Sandy, finding out he injured himself by slipping on an ice cube. At the hospital, the doctor says he has gone to the wrong hospital (because SpongeBob described his injuries as &quot;boo boos&quot;) and tells him to go to a hospital called &quot;Weenie Hut General&quot;. SpongeBob then goes into denial once again.  48b &quot;Squilliam Returns&quot; Sean Dempsey Sam Henderson 
 Jay Lender 
Kent Osborne March 15, 2002 
Squidward is on his lunch break and he spots his arch-rival from high school, Squilliam Fancyson, who is very wealthy and succeeded in everything Squidward failed at since high school. Squidward says he owns a five star restaurant and it has great food. After successfully asking Mr. Krabs if he can run the restaurant for one night, Squidward makes Mr. Krabs the cook, SpongeBob the waiter, and Patrick the coat-check. But once everybody proves to be completely inept, Squidward prepares to confess the truth to Squilliam. However, when Squilliam arrives, SpongeBob is the best waiter ever because he (literally) emptied his mind of everything except fine dining and breathing. Squilliam loves the restaurant and asks for SpongeBob&apos;s name. But SpongeBob does not remember his name, and in a mental breakdown, he ruins the Krusty Krab, revealing it is normally a fast-food restaurant. Squidward then admits he is really a cashier, and owns no restaurant. Squilliam tells him he&apos;s also a cashier who&apos;s not in the upper-class, but soon reveals it was actually a lie. Squilliam and his friends leave, leaving Squidward humiliated.

This episode is a flashback as though Squidward and Squilliam have not met before in the series, even though Squilliam appeared in the Season 2 episode Band Geeks .
Guests: Dee Bradley Baker as Squilliam Fancyson  49a &quot;Krab Borg&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Mark O&apos;Hare March 29, 2002 
SpongeBob watches a scary robot movie and thinks everything is a robot, even Gary. The next day, SpongeBob thinks Mr. Krabs is a robot and tells Squidward that robots have glowing red eyes, pinchers for hands and ran on batteries. seconds after, Mr.Krabs comes out after accidentally spilling salt on his eyes causing them to glow red and has a pincher in his hand to fish an egg out of a pot and batteries in his pocket from his radio. Spongebob and Squidward soon believe that robots have conquered the world, and they team up to overpower and question the &quot;robot&quot; and find out what he did with the &quot;real&quot; Mr. Krabs, oblivious to the fact that the Mr. Krabs they see is not a robot, and is no fake. The interrogation involves torturing him (like slapping him and destroying many of his valuables) in an attempt to &quot;find out&quot; about the location of the &quot;real&quot; Mr. Krabs. When they find out Mr. Krabs isn&apos;t a robot (and is the genuine Mr. Krabs), SpongeBob recalls that the ending of the movie revealed the events of the movie was just their imagination. He then runs away, leaving Squidward out to dry.
Guests: Rodney Bingenheimer as The DJ  49b &quot;Rock-a-Bye Bivalve&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Mark O&apos;Hare March 29, 2002 
Patrick and SpongeBob are outside one day and find an abandoned baby scallop , the undersea equivalent of birds. Since its parents are nowhere to be found, they decide to raise it, and additionally act as the parents of the scallop; SpongeBob is the &quot;mother&quot; while Patrick is the &quot;father&quot;. However, things quickly grow out of hand as SpongeBob ends up as the sole caretaker of the scallop, while Patrick goes to &quot;work.&quot; Spongebob grows suspicious of Patrick&apos;s rare appearances during the daytime, revealing the amount of diapers he has had to change (e.g., an excavator organizing a pile outside his house). Even though Patrick apologizes, he continues on with his routine the next morning. After returning from &quot;work,&quot; Spongebob confronts Patrick about his late evening schedules, which causes Patrick to be overwhelmed and go back to &quot;work,&quot; which is revealed to be just lounging at his residence. This fuels a heated argument between the two, instantly broken up when the scallop is perched on Spongebob&apos;s window. The two apologize and prepare to catch the scallop, but never happens now that it is revealed that it can fly. Spongebob and Patrick wave to the scallop as it flies away.

Note:This is the most controversial episode of SpongeBob, mostly because its so-called &quot;references to homosexuality.&quot; One scene during the episode has Spongebob and Patrick appear to get in bed together, only to reveal that Patrick is actually sleeping under the mattress similar to how he sleeps under his rock. Also, at the end Patrick says to Spongebob &quot;let&apos;s have another.&quot;. But this is popular because of the scene where SpongeBob ties a rubber band around him and says &quot;I am a happy sponge!&quot;
One Time appearance: Junior  50a &quot;Wet Painters&quot; Frank Weiss C.H. Greenblatt 
 Kaz 
 Mark O&apos;Hare May 10, 2002 
Patrick and SpongeBob are hired to paint Mr. Krabs&apos; house, but are told that it is permanent paint, threatening to amputate their butts and mount them over his fireplace if they get even one drop on anything but his walls. After they finish painting, chaos ensues when they get a tiny drop of paint on Mr. Krabs&apos; first dollar. SpongeBob desperately tries to remove the paint from the dollar, but only ends up spreading it all over. When Mr. Krabs comes back, he licks the paint off and reveals the paint is saliva -soluble. When Mr. Krabs informs them that his previous warning was just to mess with them, SpongeBob and Patrick get angry and storm off. Mr. Krabs laughs at his charade so hard that spittle gets scattered all over the walls and ruins the paint job.
Best Day Ever Rank: 92  50b &quot;Krusty Krab Training Video&quot; Frank Weiss Aaron Springer 
 C.H. Greenblatt 
Kent Osborne May 10, 2002 
A training narration of the Krusty Krab, demonstrating what work is like and how it takes place at the Krusty Krab. The entire episode is formatted like a sort of an employee training video, and features an anxious SpongeBob waiting to make a Krabby Patty. However, when he finally learns the recipe, the video abruptly ends before it&apos;s revealed to keep it secret.

Guests: Steve Keleha
Note: The Klasky Csupo Robot (a.k.a. SSF) logo was accidentally used in the closing logo flaw during split-screen credits, but was fixed in 2006.  51 &quot;Party Pooper Pants&quot; Andrew Overtoom
Walt Dohrn (song sequence) Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Mark O&apos;Hare May 17, 2002 
SpongeBob gets a plan-your-own-party kit and decides to plan a party and invite everyone he knows even though a lot of people don&apos;t know him. He panics when the first guest is 30 seconds late but eventually everyone arrives. When he leaves to the coat room thinking the party is out of control while everyone is just having fun and he breaks it up and tries to read comics in an organized and boring fashion. After he is locked out accidentally the police throw him in jail for busting into his own house but when he returns Patrick tells him that it was a best party ever.
Note: Nickeldeon promoted this episode as &quot;SpongeBob&apos;s House Party&quot;.  52a &quot;Chocolate with Nuts&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
 Kaz 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams June 1, 2002 
After accidentally getting Squidward&apos;s &quot;Fancy Living Digest&quot; in the mail, SpongeBob and Patrick want to live fancy too. They decide they will get rich by selling candy bars. People keep turning them down so they lie about the candy. People start to buy the candy, but at the last house they go to, a con man tricks them out of everything they earned up to that point. When they feel all hope is lost, a chocolate maniac catches them and wants to purchase all their chocolate. With all the money they have they decide to rent out the local fancy restaurant, aptly named &apos;Fancy!&apos;.
This episode is very well known for the chocolate maniac&apos;s exclamation, &quot;CHOCOLATE!&quot;  52b &quot;Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy V&quot; C.H. Greenblatt 
 Kaz 
 Merriwether Williams June 1, 2002 
Barnacle Boy is sick of being treated like an actual boy by Mermaid Man (and everyone else), so he decides to become evil and teams up with the Dirty Bubble and Manray. Barnacle Man (as he is now called) and his gang, known as E.V.I.L. ( E very V illain I s L emons), go around town doing evil. SpongeBob, Squidward, Patrick, Sandy, and Mermaid Man team up to get Barnacle Boy back. Everybody but Mermaidman fails to do so. Barnacle Boy tells Mermaid Man that there are just 3 things that he wants. He wants to be treated like a real superhero (and not just Mermaid Man&apos;s sidekick ), to be called &quot;Barnacle Man&quot; (although, he is still called Barnacle Boy in later episodes), and to get an adult-sized Krabby Patty, which Mermaid Man agrees to. Barnacle Man goes back to the good side, and his friendship with Mermaid Man is restored.

Guests: Ernest Borgnine as Mermaid Man, and Tim Conway as Barnacle Boy
Note: Another name for this episode is &quot;Superfriends&quot;.  53a &quot;New Student Starfish&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Mark O&apos;Hare September 20, 2002 
Patrick tells SpongeBob that he is bored whenever he spends the day at boating school, so SpongeBob lets the starfish tag along. Unfortunately, this only leads to trouble, as Patrick&apos;s antics during class get SpongeBob sent to the back of the classroom, and costs him one of his &quot;good noodle stars.&quot; SpongeBob&apos;s anger leads to a lame excuse for a fight in the hallway between he and Patrick, getting them sent to detention after school.
Note: The nickname of Mrs. Puff &quot;big fat meanie&quot; is based off a name-calling phrase &quot;big fat liar&quot;.  53b &quot;Clams&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Mark O&apos;Hare September 20, 2002 
Mr. Krabs earns his millionth dollar, and rewards SpongeBob and Squidward by taking them clam fishing for the weekend (though Squidward doesn&apos;t like this reward). A major problem soon arises, as Mr. Krabs loses his millionth dollar when a giant clam snatches it away (due to SpongeBob accidentally hooking it while fishing). The mishap sends him over the edge, as he forces SpongeBob and Squidward to find the dollar, telling them they can&apos;t leave until it&apos;s found. To show he&apos;s serious, he tosses all of their food overboard, leaving only one sandwich (a parody of Herman Melville &apos;s classic, Moby-Dick ). When they try to sneak away, Mr. Krabs goes completely insane and uses the two as live bait. But, as the clam is about to eat them, he seizes the opportunity to get his dollar, causing him to get eaten. When the two think he&apos;s gone for good, he reappears with the dollar but he traded his entire body except for his head and left arm for it.
This episode spoofs Steven Spielberg &apos;s film Jaws .  54 &quot;Ugh (SpongeBob B.C.)&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne March 5, 2004 
Prehistoric ancestors of SpongeBob, Patrick and Squidward — SpongeGar, Patar, and Squog (respectively), discover fire after a lightning bolt strikes a piece of wood and sets it ablaze. After realizing that food can be cooked over the fire, the three have a feast with their surroundings as the food. After their feast, the three cannot decide on who would keep the fire at their house for the night, and fight over it. But rain puts the fire out. After SpongeGar and Patar apologize to Squog for their arguments, just as he prepares to hit SpongeGar and Patar over the head, Squog gets struck by lightning, and gets set ablaze.

Meanwhile, in a prehistoric home, Potty the Parrot and Patchy the Pirate argue over which era is better, the future or the past; Potty prefers the future, and Patchy prefers the past. Eventually, though, Potty unites a futuristic robot and a prehistoric caveman together, and they sing a song. And despite Patchy soon becoming interested in the future too, Potty gives him a T-Rex, which bites him.
Nickelodeon promoted this episode as &quot;SpongeBob B.C.&quot;  55a &quot;The Great Snail Race&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
Joe Liss January 29, 2003 
SpongeBob and Patrick discover that Squidward has ordered a female purebred racing snail named Snellie (voiced by Tom Kenny ), whom he plans to enter in Bikini Bottom&apos;s most famous snail race. SpongeBob decides to enter Gary in the race, when Squidward brags that Snellie is better than Gary, despite being scoffed at by Squidward because Gary is a mutt. Patrick also decides to enter a rock that he confuses with a snail named &quot;Rocky&quot; (despite being told continuously by other characters that Rocky is a rock). SpongeBob and Patrick enter the snail and rock in the race anyway, but SpongeBob trains Gary roughly and nonstop, resulting in Gary falling apart in an ironic fashion (his insides basically are pieces of machinery). However, just as Snellie is about to cross the finish line, she turns back to comfort Gary, and the two snails fall in love. However, at the end of the episode, one question remains: who won the race? It was revealed that Rocky somehow won the race.

And also, the music in the background of the title of the episode is the same music that is in The Spongebob SquarePants Movie. The song is called, &quot;Now That We&apos;re Men&quot;.


The running gag is that Squidward&apos;s family name is mispronounced as &quot;Tennisballs&quot;, &quot;Tentpoles&quot;, and &quot;Tortellini&quot; despite that Squidward repeatedly tells them his name is &quot;Squidward Tentacles&quot;
There was a deleted scene in which Sandy gets arrested for kicking Spongebob&apos;s butt.  55b &quot;Mid-Life Crustacean&quot; Frank Weiss C.H. Greenblatt 
 Kaz 
 Mark O&apos;Hare January 29, 2003 Mr. Krabs has hit his midlife crisis , so he decides to tag along with SpongeBob and Patrick when they have a night in the town, hoping that he will feel young and wild again. However, Mr. Krabs quickly finds that SpongeBob and Patrick&apos;s idea of a wild night is anything but wild, or even cool They go on a panty raid to go look for girls underwear only to find out that is Mrs. Krabs house and Mr. Krabs gets grounded for the rest of the night SpongeBob comes back to apologize for what happened and Mr. Krabs forgives him on his race car bed.  56a &quot;Born Again Krabs&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams October 4, 2003 
One night during closing, SpongeBob finds an old, moldy Krabby Patty under the grill. Mr. Krabs forbids him to make another one until the moldy Krabby Patty is sold, causing the restaurant to go for weeks without customers. When the penny-pinching crab takes a bite from the patty, he ends up in the hospital with a potentially fatal case of food poisoning. Mr. Krabs makes a deal with the Flying Dutchman that he can keep his soul if he promises to never be cheap again, a deal he&apos;s good at upholding for a while. But when Mr. Krabs loses all of his money, and finds out that the he is awake, he finds the deal too hard to uphold, and becomes cheap again. When the Flying Dutchman arrives, SpongeBob puts himself before Mr. Krabs, hoping that Mr. Krabs will prove himself to be not cheap. But instead, Mr. Krabs carelessly gives him to the Flying Dutchman in exchange for 62 cents. Squidward scolds Mr. Krabs for selling out the only person who stood up for him, and Mr. Krabs begins to regret having sold SpongeBob. The Flying Dutchman returns SpongeBob, but not because of Mr. Krabs&apos; regret for selling SpongeBob, but because SpongeBob being deemed by the Dutchman as &quot;a fate worse than death&quot; because he talked up a storm after just 30 seconds.
When the Flying Dutchman returns to his residence, he answers a call. But it turns out to be from SpongeBob, who again chatters and annoys him.  56b &quot;I Had an Accident&quot; Frank Weiss C.H. Greenblatt 
 Kaz 
 Merriwether Williams October 4, 2003 
SpongeBob shatters his rear end in a sand-boarding injury. In order to avoid the &quot;Iron Butt,&quot; he commits himself to stay indoors for the rest of his life, leaving Sandy and Patrick to try to convince him that the outdoors aren&apos;t always so dangerous.

After several attempts to lure Spongebob outside, Sandy and Patrick try to traumatize him by having Patrick dress up in a gorilla suit and threaten Sandy. Spongebob still isn&apos;t convinced, knowing Patrick wore the suit the previous Halloween. However, Patrick, not in a gorilla suit, walks onto the scene, greeting Sandy, yet confuses her why there are two Patricks on the scene. Patrick says he is in the gorilla suit, which reveals that the other Patrick is revealed to be an actual gorilla (in actuality, a human in a gorilla suit). Spongebob is finally convinced to leave his house (after the &quot;gorilla&quot; throws Patrick and Sandy into a sack and beats them up), allowing him to come outside to attempt to save Sandy and Patrick. However, SpongeBob is ripped in half by the gorilla, but is still able to express his newfound fear of gorillas, with Sandy and Patrick expressing the same fears. SpongeBob then says out loud, &quot;What&apos;s a gorilla doing underwater in the first place?&quot;. The gorilla then says, &quot;Well, you see, it&apos;s funny because... GEORGE! THEY&apos;RE ONTO US!&quot; He then hitches a ride on a man in a zebra suit, and they gallop into the sunset.

Note: Another name for this episode is &quot;Safety Freak SpongeBob&quot;.
Note: This is the only SpongeBob episode that is revealed, at the end, to have been watched on a TV by a family. They then turn the TV off.  57a &quot;Krabby Land&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Mark O&apos;Hare April 3, 2004 It&apos;s summer in Bikini Bottom, and that means the kids are out of school. For Mr. Krabs, their temporary freedom means more profit for him (even he raises the price of cheapest Krabby Patty meal, &quot;Kiddie Meal&quot;, into most expensive in menu). To attract them, he sets up a playground consisting of rusty, poorly-constructed, and dangerous equipment, with a promise to the kids that they would get to meet Krabby the Clown before the day&apos;s end. However, he soon finds out that the kids probably shouldn&apos;t be underestimated. At the end, the kids were having fun and a kid was tossing money , but after Mr. Krabs betrayed the kids (he promised that Krabby The Clown would be at the Krusty Krab, but after he told them that he was here, he put on a frozen tomato on his nose and dressed as a clown, children were upset), they tortured him with lima beans .  57b &quot;The Camping Episode&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Merriwether Williams April 3, 2004 
SpongeBob and Patrick go camping one night, which excites their neighbor Squidward, who hopes that the two will get lost in the woods and never come back. However, Squidward soon learns that SpongeBob and Patrick&apos;s chosen campsite was ten feet outside SpongeBob&apos;s pineapple. The two get Squidward to join them in camping after Squidward is convinced that SpongeBob and Patrick think that he is weak for not going camping in the first place. But Squidward is forced to endure the camping rituals of SpongeBob and Patrick, such as roasting marshmallows and singing campfire songs, resulting in SpongeBob&apos;s musical number &quot;The Campfire Song Song&quot;. In return, Squidward decides to play his clarinet. Spongebob suddenly averts Squidward from playing (after shooting a marshmallow in his throat via his clarinet, nearly choking him in the process) since it is said to attract a &quot;sea-bear.&quot; Squidward doubts them at first, believing sea-bears are hoaxes, but SpongeBob and Patrick present him with a tabloid newspaper front page entitled &quot;Sea Bears and Fairy Tales are Real&quot;. After learning the doings that can attract sea bears, Squidward attempts to prove they are untrue by performing those actions. However, Squidward eventually does attract a sea bear, and gets mauled in the process. While this happens, Spongebob and Patrick are huddled inside a circle drawn on the ground said to deter sea-bears. After being brutally assaulted by the sea-bear multiple times, Squidward squeezes inside the two&apos;s safe circle, causing the sea-bear to retreat. However, the episode ends just as Squidward learns about sea rhinoceroses and that the only protection is wearing Anti-Sea-Rhionosares under garments...

Note: At first the title of this episode was &quot;Squidward Goes Camping&quot;.
Note: The date in the episode is 25 May.  58a &quot;Missing Identity&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams January 19, 2004 
On a rainy day in a diner, SpongeBob recounts a recent tale in which he loses his nametag:

Mr. Krabs is to do a surprise uniform inspection, with the consequence of the least prepared employee getting &quot;the boot&quot; (which is literally, a large stinky boot that must be worn for the rest of the workday). SpongeBob recruits Patrick to help him retrace his steps to find his nametag, but quickly learns that this method isn&apos;t perhaps the best one, and that Patrick isn&apos;t much help at all. After searching in a dumpster, he finds out he was wearing his shirt backwards, and when he puts his shirt on the right way, he discovers that his nametag was on all along. However, because he was in a dumpster, SpongeBob smells awful, so Mr. Krabs boots him out of the Krusty Krab.
Note: You may slightly notice the missing nametag in shortcut by witnessing Spongebob&apos;s lack of backtracking which he changes his clothes.  58b &quot;Plankton&apos;s Army&quot; Sean Dempsey Jay Lender 
 Sam Henderson 
 Merriwether Williams January 19, 2004 
Mr. Krabs tells his employees that today is the 25th anniversary of Plankton&apos;s first attempt at stealing the Krabby Patty&apos;s secret formula. Plankton, meanwhile, tries to hire henchmen to help him steal it, but he&apos;s too small. He has another idea: he&apos;ll hire as many of his relatives as possible to help him steal it. They invade the Krusty Krab, and trap Squidward and Mr. Krabs in a toilet. (SpongeBob was cleaning out the men&apos;s room, and that&apos;s why he is only seen in the beginning and end of this episode) Plankton does a Snare Drum roll and reads what seems to be the secret formula, and it says that plankton are part of the recipe. This scares off Plankton and his relatives (except for one of them, who is illiterate and whom Mr. Krabs commands to &quot;Get out of here!&quot;). After the Plankton family flees from the Krusty Krab, Mr. Krabs points out that the recipe that the Planktons read is a fake, says that he&apos;s sure Plankton will eventually realize that it&apos;s a fake and attempt to go after the real formula, but says he hid the real formula in a place that nobody will ever find. But when Squidward correctly guesses the hiding place (at Mr. Krabs&apos; home, under his mattress ), Mr. Krabs hurriedly attempts to find a new hiding place for the real formula.
Note: Nickelodeon branded this episode as &quot;Plankton&apos;s Revenge&quot;.  59 &quot; The Sponge Who Could Fly (a.k.a. The Lost Episode)&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams March 21, 2003 Main article: The Sponge Who Could Fly 
In the live action section, Patchy intends on presenting a lost episode of SpongeBob SquarePants; however, he has lost it. He then uses a treasure map to find it which leads him to a playground where a video tape is buried. When Patchy starts the video it initially only shows SpongeBob walk cycles which upsets Patchy that he starts getting rid of all his SpongeBob merchandise and runs away. However, Potty informs the tape is still on because the real episode is playing next. Happy again, Patchy returns home and replaces all his stuff.

The animated section begins and SpongeBob wishes he could fly with the jellyfish. He constructs several flying machines, all of which fail to fly for very long. In his attempts, he uses a biplane, bat wings, a garden chair with balloons, and a giant kite pulled by a bicycle driven by Patrick. After attempting to fly but failing, he is called &quot;The Birdman of Bikini Bottom&quot; and is ridiculed. Depressed, he finally finds out a way to fly: inflatable pants. Now that he can fly, though, the other citizens of Bikini Bottom take advantage of him, and when he finally refuses he is left alone in jellyfish fields with his pants taken away. SpongeBob decides that flying is not for him. But the jellyfish take him flying across the sky to cheer him up. When they drop him off at his home, Patrick asks him if he wants to &quot;fly&quot; over to a pizza joint, to which he declines to. Patrick just replies, &quot;suit yourself&quot; and literally flies off, leaving SpongeBob in absolute shock.

After the episode, in another live action section, Patchy decides to play it again. Not knowing a thing about technology, he accidentally wrecks the tape so it can&apos;t be seen again. outside, the narrator talks about Patchy&apos;s day and then you can see a Spongebob constellation.
Note: Nickelodeon promoted this episode as &quot;SpongeBob: The Lost Episode&quot;  60a &quot;SpongeBob Meets the Strangler&quot; Tom Yasumi Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 C.H. Greenblatt 
 Merriwether Williams October 11, 2004 
SpongeBob tattles on the &quot;Tattle-tale Strangler&quot;, a criminal who promises to strangle anyone who reports on him and his crimes. He escapes the police&apos;s clutches and wants to go after SpongeBob for tattling on him. SpongeBob wants a bodyguard to help protect him from the Tattle-tale Strangler. He asks a lot of people, but they are all too scared of the Tattle-tale Strangler. Then just when he was going to leave town, someone claims to be offering help. The man is the Tattle-tale Strangler wearing a fake mustache. SpongeBob doesn&apos;t know this though, and allows him to become his bodyguard. The strangler is trying to get him alone so he can strangle him without getting caught. But every time he tries to strangle him, SpongeBob is either talking to him, doing something, or he is with another person(s).

After a while, the strangler gives up and tries to run away from SpongeBob. He ends up confessing and staying in jail. He is glad that he is away from the &quot;yellow idiot&quot; (SpongeBob), but is then surprised to see Patrick (who turned himself in because of a lie that the Tattle-tale Strangler told to the extremely gullible starfish, making him think he is the Tattle-tale Strangler) as a cell-mate. Patrick says to the Tattle-tale Strangler, &quot;Hey Mac. What are you in for?&quot;.
One Time appearance: The Strangler  60b &quot;Pranks a Lot&quot; Andrew Overtoom Paul Tibbitt 
Kent Osborne
 Merriwether Williams October 11, 2004 
In the original series finale, SpongeBob goes to the &quot;Palace of Pranks&quot; with Patrick and says he got his Gag Seanut Brittle Can (a spoof of peanut brittle ) from there saying it&apos;s a gag. Patrick assumes that there is really Brittle inside and opens it only to discover it was a prank.
They go inside and purchase &quot;Invisible Paint&quot;, a can of spray-paint that can turn things invisible. SpongeBob and Patrick intend to use it to spray a park bench, and then sit on it, making it look like they are floating (and so the people around them will be amazed by this as a result). Remembering a warning that the paint stains clothes, the two completely strip down to their birthday suits, then fight over who should spray the bench, leading them to spray each other until they&apos;re completely invisible, and also end up accidentally spraying it onto their clothes. So, SpongeBob and Patrick decide to go around tricking people into thinking they&apos;re ghosts. At first, it works, as they scare everyone in town, including Mr. Krabs, who initially claimed that he couldn&apos;t be scared. But Mr. Krabs eventually finds out (by throwing water at them, as he was trying to put out a lit match that they were going to use to burn a dollar bill as part of their plan of torturing him), and gets back at SpongeBob and Patrick when he makes a show called &quot;Live Nude Pranksters&quot;, which show SpongeBob and Patrick&apos;s nudity to the customers of the Krusty Krab. SpongeBob, ashamed, concludes the episode be saying to Patrick that they should have bought a whoopie cushion.  

 [ edit ] The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie 
 Main article: The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie 
 The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie was released in the United States on November 19, 2004. In addition to the base cast, it was voiced by Alec Baldwin (Dennis), Jeffrey Tambor (King Neptune), Scarlett Johansson (Princess Mindy), Carlos Alazraqui (King Neptune&apos;s squire), Neil Ross (Cyclops), and David Hasselhoff (David Hasselhoff). It was written by Stephen Hillenburg , Derek Drymon , Tim Hill , Kent Osborne, Aaron Springer , and Paul Tibbitt . It was directed by Stephen Hillenburg and Mark Osborne 

In the film, Squidward becomes manager of the Krusty Krab 2, leaving SpongeBob depressed as he feels that he should have been chosen instead. Plankton steals King Neptune&apos;s crown, sells it to a person in Shell City, and frames Mr. Krabs. King Neptune freezes Mr. Krabs until SpongeBob and Patrick come back with his crown in 6 days (thanks to Patrick). Meanwhile, Plankton controls Bikini Bottom, now Planktopolis. SpongeBob and Patrick face many obstacles including two motormouths, thugs, monsters, an abyss, Dennis (a person sent by Plankton to destroy SpongeBob and Patrick), a diver, a heat lamp, and Plankton&apos;s minions. In the end, SpongeBob becomes the manager of the Krusty Krab 2.

 References [link] 
 
 
 
 v t e 
 SpongeBob SquarePants Seasons 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
 Notable episodes 
 &quot; Help Wanted &quot; &quot; Fools in April &quot; &quot; Christmas Who? &quot; &quot; Party Pooper Pants &quot; &quot; Sailor Mouth &quot; &quot; Graveyard Shift &quot; &quot; The Sponge Who Could Fly &quot; &quot; Ugh &quot; &quot; Have You Seen This Snail? &quot; &quot; Dunces and Dragons &quot; &quot; Friend or Foe? &quot; &quot; Best Day Ever &quot; &quot; Atlantis SquarePantis &quot; &quot; Pest of the West &quot; &quot; What Ever Happened to SpongeBob? &quot; &quot; Truth or Square &quot; &quot; To SquarePants or Not to SquarePants &quot; &quot; SpongeBob vs. The Big One &quot; &quot; SpongeBob&apos;s Last Stand &quot; &quot; The Clash of Triton &quot; &quot; The Great Patty Caper &quot; &quot; Frozen Face-Off &quot; &quot; Ghoul Fools &quot; &quot; A SquarePants Family Vacation &quot; 
 Films 
 Theatrical films 
 The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie (2004) The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie 2 (2014) 
 TV movies 
 Atlantis SquarePantis (2007) Square Roots: The Story of SpongeBob SquarePants (2009) Truth or Square (2009) 
 
 Miniseries 
 Legends of Bikini Bottom SpongeBob&apos;s Runaway Roadtrip 
 Characters 
 SpongeBob Patrick Squidward Mr. Krabs Sandy Plankton Gary 
 Amusement rides 
 Bikini Bottom Bus Tour Krusty Krab Order Up Rock Bottom Plunge SpongeBob SquarePants 4-D SpongeBob&apos;s Splash Bash Jimmy Neutron&apos;s Nicktoon Blast 
 Places 
 Bikini Bottom Krusty Krab Chum Bucket 
 People 
 Stephen Hillenburg Steven Banks Luke Brookshier Sherm Cohen Walt Dohrn Derek Drymon C.H. Greenblatt Sam Henderson Tim Hill Tom King Mr. Lawrence Jay Lender Dani Michaeli Mike Mitchell Mark O&apos;Hare Andrew Overtoom Dan Povenmire Aaron Springer Paul Tibbitt Vincent Waller Erik Wiese Merriwether Williams Tom Yasumi 
 Related articles 
 Merchandise Characters Episodes Rocko&apos;s Modern Life Spongiforma squarepantsii Rough Draft Studios Nicktoons SpongeBob SquarePants Movie 300 
 
 Book Category Animation portal / Television portal / Nickelodeon portal WikiProject 
 
 
 
 http://wn.com/SpongeBob_SquarePants_(season_3) 

Related pages:

 http://ru.wn.com/Третий сезон мультсериала «Губка Боб Квадратные Штаны» 



This page contains text from Wikipedia, the Free Encyclopedia - http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SpongeBob_SquarePants_(season_3) 

This article is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License , which means that you can copy and modify it as long as the entire work (including additions) remains under this license. 

 This article is about the insult. For other uses, see Asshole (disambiguation) . 
The word asshole , a variant of arsehole , which is still prevalent in British and Australian English , is a vulgar to describe the anus , often pejoratively used to refer to people.

 
Contents
 
 1 History 2 Semantics 3 Political usage 4 See also 5 References 
 

 History [link] 

The word arse in English derives from the Germanic root *arsaz, which originated from the Proto-Indo-European root *ors — meaning buttocks or backside . [ 1 ] The combined form arsehole is first attested from 1500 in its literal use to refer to the anus . The metaphorical use of the word to refer to the worst place in a region, e.g. , &quot;the arsehole of the world&quot;) is first attested in print in 1865; the use to refer to a contemptible person is first attested in 1933. [ 2 ] In the ninth chapter of his 1945 autobiography, Black Boy , Richard Wright quotes a snippet of verse that uses the term: &quot;All these white folks dressed so fine / Their ass-holes smell just like mine ...&quot;. Its first appearance as an insult term in a newspaper indexed by Google News is in 1965. [ 3 ] As with other vulgarities, these uses of the word may have been common in oral speech for some time before their first print appearances. By the 1970s, Hustler magazine featured people they did not like as &quot;Asshole of the Month.&quot; [ 4 ] In 1972, Jonathan Richman&apos;s Modern Lovers recorded his song &quot; Pablo Picasso ,&quot; which includes the line &quot;Pablo Picasso was never called an asshole.&quot;

Until the early 1990s, the word was considered one of a number of words that could not be uttered on commercial television in the United States. Comedian Andrew Dice Clay caused a major shock when he uttered the word during a televised MTV awards show in 1989. [ 5 ] However, there were PG-13 and R rated films in the 1980s that featured use of the word, such as the R-rated The Terminator (1984), the PG-13-rated National Lampoon&apos;s Christmas Vacation (1989), and the PG-rated Back to the Future (1985). By 1994, however, vulgarity had become more acceptable, and the word was featured in dialog on the long-running television series NYPD Blue , though it has yet to become anything close to commonplace on network TV. In some broadcast edits (such as the syndication airings of South Park ), the word is partially bleeped out — ironically, as &quot;assh—&quot;, with the profane half of the word intact.

 Semantics [link] 

The word is mainly used as a vulgarity , generally to describe people who are viewed as stupid or incompetent or detestable. [ 6 ] 

This word or its literal translation is found in colloquial speech in a number of cultures (in both English and other languages ). [ 7 ] This is because it describes an organ of elimination that is considered a taboo region (since it belongs to the intimate parts ) of the body in many societies . [ 8 ] 

The English word ass (meaning donkey , a cognate of its zoological name Equus asinus ) may also be used as a term of contempt, referring to a silly or stupid person. In the United States, and, to a lesser degree, in Canada, the words arse and ass have become synonymous; however, in the rest of the English-speaking world, ass still only refers to the donkey, rather than the arse ( buttocks ). It is worth noting that speakers of some varieties of English &quot;drop their Rs&quot; before consonants, leading to a pronunciation of arse that is quite similar to ass . [ 9 ] 

 Political usage [link] 

In 2000, during a Labor Day event, then candidate George W. Bush made an off-hand remark to his running mate, Dick Cheney , that New York Times reporter Adam Clymer was a &quot;major league asshole.&quot; The gaffe was caught on microphone and led to a political advertisement chiding Bush for &quot;using expletives ... in front of a crowd of families,&quot; produced for Democratic opponent Al Gore . [ 10 ] 

In February 2004, American media reported that during a rally of supporters, Venezuelan President Hugo Chavez called Bush &quot;an asshole&quot; for believing his aides in supporting a coup against Chavez in 2002 . [ 11 ] The word in the original Spanish was &quot; pendejo &quot;, and in news coverage the word was widely, though incorrectly, translated as &quot;asshole&quot;; the meaning of the word varies substantially in Latin America, and in Venezuela its meaning is closer to &quot;fool&quot;. [ 12 ] The following year, in September, Nightline host Ted Koppel said to Chavez on national television, &quot;I&apos;m going to perhaps shock you a little, but these are your words. You called President Bush an asshole,&quot; to which Chavez replied, &quot;I&apos;ve said various things about him. I don&apos;t know if I actually used that word.&quot; [ 13 ] 

 See also [link] 

 Arse The No Asshole Rule Sexual Slang Profanity 

 References [link] 
 
 ^ Calvert Watkins, American Heritage Dictionary of Indo-European Roots revised second edition, p. 60 ^ Lighter, J.: Historical Dictionary of American Slang , Random House , 1994. ^ &quot;A refreshing radicalism.&quot; Lerner, Michael, The Harvard Crimson , May 28, 1965. Google Search done August 6, 2008. ^ &quot;Out like Flynt.&quot; Time , April 9, 1979. Retrieved August 6, 2008. ^ MTV Video Music Awards | 1989 ^ &quot;Asshole&quot; . Webster&apos;s Online Dictionary . http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/asshole . Retrieved 2011-05-30 .   ^ &quot;Asshole In Other Language Than English&quot; . Organisasi.Org Community And Library Online . http://en.organisasi.org/translation/asshole-in-other-languages . Retrieved 2011-05-30 .   ^ Napoli, Donna Jo; Hoeksema, Jack. The grammatical versatility of taboo terms . 33 .   ^ Ass/Arse Online Encyclopedia ^ &quot;A &quot;major league asshole&quot;&quot; . Salon.com . 09-04-2000 . http://archive.salon.com/politics/feature/2000/09/04/cuss_word/ .   ^ &quot;Chavez Calls Bush &apos;Asshole&apos; as Foes Fight Troops&quot; . Washington Post . February 29, 2004 . http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/articles/A17578-2004Feb29.html .   ^ Venezuelanalysis.com , 2 August 2005, Memo to Time and Reuters: Chávez Did Not Call Bush an &quot;Asshole&quot; ^ &quot;Transcript: Hugo Chavez Interview&quot; . Nightline . 09-16-2005 . http://abcnews.go.com/print?id=1134098 .   
 
 
 
 v t e 
 Sexual slang General 
 Anilingus Banjee Bara Bareback Baseball metaphors for sex Blue balls Born-again virgin Bottom (BDSM) Camel toe Circle jerk Cock tease Cunt Deep-throating Dick Dirty Sanchez Dogging Donkey punch Douche Dyke Fag hag Felching Fruit Fuck Gay-for-pay Girlfriend experience Glory hole Hogging Lipstick lesbian Mama-san Mammary intercourse Mandarin Chinese profanity Mile high club Moose knuckle Nookie Pearl necklace Pegging Pussy Queen Quickie Mat Rusty trombone Saddlebacking Serosorting Shemale Slut Snowballing Soggy biscuit Switch Tea bag Top Top, bottom and versatile Troll Turkey slap Voulez-vous coucher avec moi? Wanker Whale tail 
 LGBT-specific 
 Bear Beard Bi-curious Breeder Bugchasing Chicken Chickenhawk Chub Daddy Down-low Party and play Soft butch Swish Trade Twink U-Haul lesbian 
 In pornography 
 Ass to mouth Bukkake Centerfold Clothed female, naked male (CFNM) Clothed male, naked female (CMNF) Creampie Cum shot Deep-throating Downblouse Facial Felching Fluffer Gang bang Golden Age of Porn Insert MILF Money shot Paysite Point-of-view Stunt cock Upskirt 
 
 Sexual slur Human sexuality Sexology Terminology of homosexuality 
 
 
 
 http://wn.com/Asshole 



This page contains text from Wikipedia, the Free Encyclopedia - http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asshole 

This article is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License , which means that you can copy and modify it as long as the entire work (including additions) remains under this license. 

 1:35 RuneScape - #Wumbo - Green H&apos;ween Mask Lure ft. RagBrid [Toaster] itzToaster RuneScape - #Wumbo - Green H&apos;ween Mask Lure ft. RagBrid [Toaster] Santa Hat Lure - youtu.be RWter downed for bank - youtu.be Clan Wars Lure Vid 4 - youtu.be Song - www.youtube.com 0:55 Stupid Starfish-Squidward&apos;s True Love and WUMBO Goldenretriever2009 Stupid Starfish-Squidward&apos;s True Love and WUMBO Spongebob goes to Patrick for his wisdom on the Shrunken Squidward, but he seems to think Squid will fall in love with a Pickle...&quot;THEY LIKE EACHOTHER!!!&quot;Then Patrick gives Spongebob his words of wisdom...&quot;You got it set to M for Mini, when it should be set to W for WUMBO!!!&quot;To see full episode watch Spongebob Squarepants on Nickelodeon, it&apos;s a great and funny show! THE WUMBO MOMENT 0:22 Wumbo Bomb Detholize Wumbo Bomb Don&apos;t set it to&quot;W&quot;... 1:52 RuneScape - Red H&apos;ween - LOL @ THAT LOOT [Wumbo] 180m Lure itzToaster RuneScape - Red H&apos;ween - LOL @ THAT LOOT [Wumbo] 180m Lure LURE VID 5 - youtu.be LURE VID 4 - youtu.be -------- RARE LURES ------- Blue H&apos;ween - youtu.be Green H&apos;ween - youtu.be Green H&apos;ween - youtu.be Red H&apos;ween - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Santa Hat - youtu.be Song used - www.youtube.com 2:03 Update: Wumbo stops Amnesia? Wumbo gets paid? WumboGaming Update: Wumbo stops Amnesia? Wumbo gets paid? Facebook fanpage for updates: www.facebook.com Royalty free music I used: Monokle Galun - Get At Will For those who dont have sound: Thanks so much everyone for subscribing and leaving me positive feedback! I will start making Amnesia videos again soon, I just wanted a break from it because I&apos;ve played it for 7 months straight every day, I wasnt getting as scared anymore as I used to 5:07 The Viridian City - W is for Wumbo fudgermonkey99 The Viridian City - W is for Wumbo My friends band The Viridian City playing their original song W is for Wumbo. I just took some clips of a live show and put the song over it to provide a video to watch so you can see how they act live to persuade you to go to their shows. If you guys like this then check the band out at their myspace (www.myspace.com/theviridiancity) show more add to playlist clear 
 Youtube Vimeo Dailymotion Yahoo Blip 
 






 
The World News (WN) Network, has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to user privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for wn.com, as well as e-mail newsletters.

1. Personal Information Collection and Use

We do not collect personally identifiable information about you, except when you provide it to us. For example, if you submit an inquiry to us or sign up for our newsletter, you may be asked to provide certain information such as your contact details (name, e-mail address, mailing address, etc.).

When you submit your personally identifiable information through wn.com, you are giving your consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you would prefer that we not collect any personally identifiable information from you, please do not provide us with any such information. We will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent, except as otherwise disclosed in this Privacy Policy.

Except as otherwise disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we will use the information you provide us only for the purpose of responding to your inquiry or in connection with the service for which you provided such information. We may forward your contact information and inquiry to our affiliates and other divisions of our company that we feel can best address your inquiry or provide you with the requested service. We may also use the information you provide in aggregate form for internal business purposes, such as generating statistics and developing marketing plans. We may share or transfer such non-personally identifiable information with or to our affiliates, licensees, agents and partners.

We may retain other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Such third parties may be provided with access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but may not use such information for any other purpose.

In addition, we may disclose any information, including personally identifiable information, we deem necessary, in our sole discretion, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal proceeding or governmental request.

2. E-mail addresses

We do not want you to receive unwanted e-mail from us. We try to make it easy to opt-out of any service you have asked to receive. If you sign-up to our e-mail newsletters we do not sell, exchange or give your e-mail address to a third party.

E-mail addresses are collected via the wn.com web site. Users have to physically opt-in to receive the wn.com newsletter and a verification e-mail is sent. wn.com is clearly and conspicuously named at the point of
collection.
If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by e-mailing us at michaelw(at)wn.com

The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during registration and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100 percent secure, however. Therefore, though we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If we decide to change our e-mail practices, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we think appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

If we make material changes to our e-mail practices, we will notify you here, by e-mail, and by means of a notice on our home page.

3. Third Party Advertisers

The advertising banners and other forms of advertising appearing on this Web site are sometimes delivered to you, on our behalf, by a third party. In the course of serving advertisements to this site, the third party may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. For more information on cookies, you can visit www.cookiecentral.com.

4. Business Transfers

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell certain aspects of our entities or assets. In such transactions, user information, including personally identifiable information, generally is one of the transferred business assets, and by submitting your personal information on Wn.com you agree that your data may be transferred to such parties in these circumstances.
	</body>
</document>
