<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004122" url="http://www.notquitenigella.com/2011/11/06/butch-foods-camperdown/" time="2012-07-12-20:22" support="1" score="0.00031142957253189847" bingtitle="Butch Foods, Camperdown @ Not Quite Nigella" webtitle="Butch Foods, Camperdown @ Not Quite Nigella">
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>... foods such as pies and lasagnes but there is always a healthy home made option instead of the workers finding sustenance at a fast food restaurant. ... to receive ... seat ...</description>
	<body>
		« Win A Copy of Heston Blumenthal At Home Or Fantastical Feasts! | The Pantry, Manly » 
Butch Foods, Camperdown
 November 6th, 2011 by Not Quite Nigella 
 Tweet Pin It 
 
 

What’s in a name? When Queen Viv and I drove past Butch Foods one afternoon we were taken by the look , a homespun inviting look but also a name. As someone that was really supposed to be called Selina but never was (and I think it suits me better) I know what a name can do to you. So  earmarked for a visit in my notepad I noted the first of that day’s good omens: a miracle park outside (1 hour yes but because we were sitting in the window I could lookout for parking inspectors) .

 

 

 Belgian hot chocolate $4.50 

Formerly a family run takeaway business for 20 years the building was built around 1886 and was infested with termites which necessitated a gutting and rebuilding using sustainable and recycled materials and equipment. The service is friendly from the young guy behind the counter who is very sweet and enthusiastic. We order a“hot chocolate with sticky marshmallows”(just regular marshmallows, I thought Sticky was a new brand!). And a chai latte which is so spiced Queen Viv’s eyebrows shoot up and her eyes pop. The hot chocolate is good although it tastes more of cocoa than chocolate. It comes in a sizable mug and try as I might I can’t finish it.

 

 Clayton’s Jaffles $4.50 

I’m delighted to see a jaffle on the  menu as a homespun touch.  They’re not made in those nifty jaffle makers that seal the ends rather it is done more as a toasted sandwich in a sandwich press. And although we ordered a ham and cheese one a cheese and tomato one arrives. Nevertheless it is quite good and with just the right amount of butter, enough to give it flavour but not enough to grease the fingers.

 

 Pork and beans pie $7 

 

A pie is next and there was a choice of pork and beans, Moroccan chicken, Thai vegetable curry and beef goulash. Queen Viv likes the sound of the pork and beans and it is based in a rich tomato and capsicum sauce with a lot of cannellini beans, moreso than the pork which I don’t get much of. The pastry is buttery and it’s a good size and comes with a few spinach leaves and a slice of tomato. We note that all of the cake, pies and foods are made on the premises and you can also buy free range eggs as well as take home frozen meals.

 

 Green eggs and ham $11.90 

Our last choice is mine, a green eggs and ham number with pesto and feta scrambled eggs, wilted spinach with ham on a slice of multigrain bread. I quite like this, the eggs are flavoured well and are natural mates with the ham although Queen Vic is less taken with the multigrain bread underneath it.

 

 Lamington $3 and Chocolate and peanut butter drop cookie gluten free $1.50 

It’s dessert time and even though we’ve eaten quite a bit for lunch we try one of their homemade lamingtons covered in toasted coconut flakes which is a cute portion size. The owner comes over and tells us that she has given us a smaller slice as she heard us say that we were quite full and as such it is only $3 which is a thoughtful gesture. A bite sized gluten free cookie is chosen out of curiosity. It has a nice crumbly, short texture and copious amounts of chocolate chips although I don’t taste much in the way of peanut butter.

 

And what about the name Butch? Well apart from their 20 year business selling dog food and dog treats it has nothing to do with the Butch name. Butch was apparently so that workers during the day could feel comfortable coming in. As such they make man pleasing foods such as pies and lasagnes but there is always a healthy home made option instead of the workers finding sustenance at a fast food restaurant.

So tell me Dear Reader, do you like your name? And were you ever supposed to be called something else?

 Butch Foods 

103 Church Street, Camperdown, NSW
Tel: +61 (02) 9557 3155

 

If you enjoyed this post, why not share it with your friends?

 

 Print Page 
 
Related Posts

 Deus cafe at Deusexmachina, Camperdown St Jude, Redfern Cornersmith, Marrickville Armchair Collective, Mona Vale Hawthorn, Mosman A Birthday Dinner For Two Under the Velvet Canopy! Moose General Store&amp;Cafe, Redfern Love Grub, Alexandria 
 Posted in Cafe&amp;Casual Eating , Eating , Restaurants by cuisine , Sydney - Inner West 
Subscribe to Not Quite Nigella

Subscribe to Not Quite Nigella to receive daily updates via email. Just enter your email address and press Subscribe.
 
 
 « Win A Copy of Heston Blumenthal At Home Or Fantastical Feasts! | The Pantry, Manly » 
45 Comments | Add your own 

 1. Kimberley | November 6th, 2011 at 7:36 am | # 
I like my name! hehe im drooling thinking about that pie!!!!!!! 
 2. ck | November 6th, 2011 at 8:04 am | # 
As soon as I saw the name Butch, I thought,‘sounds like dog food’, so I laughed when I got to the end! I really like how you don’t just cover the high end of the foodie market, but always have something for everyone.
 3. Miss Kimbers | November 6th, 2011 at 8:24 am | # 
My dad wanted to call my sister and me after Dr Who assistants!

The eggs look good:)
 4. Heidi | November 6th, 2011 at 8:26 am | # 
Selina…I think you could pull anything off, but I do love Lorraine. Sounds so french I always loved my name, but was going to be olivia at one point. I think Heidi suits me far better.
Heidi xo
 5. The Food Mentalist | November 6th, 2011 at 8:36 am | # 
I like the name of this place. I can really see you as a Selina actually. I was supposed to be called Naomi but got Erin instead 
 6. gummi baby | November 6th, 2011 at 8:42 am | # 
I like my name too and I love their interpretation of Green Eggs and Ham! I’d give it a go myself if I could eat eggs again. I loved the fact that they used multigrain bread, it may not be palatable to the unitiated but once you’ve eaten it for a while (and there are some very nice ones around), I find it hard to go back to white bread on a regular basis. Great find!:D
 7. YaYa | November 6th, 2011 at 9:02 am | # 
haha, when I read the headline I thought it was a butcher shop you were going to review!It’s good to see food served up that’s not too fancified for a change, that lamington looks fantastic!
 8. Lea | November 6th, 2011 at 9:27 am | # 
This is very very weird! While making beds and doing the usual tidy up this morning, I was enjoying having dome uninterrupted thinking time as darling hubby has taken the cherubs out for the day. For some unknown reason whilst putting fresh sheets on our bed I found myself thinking about you and that your name was not what I thought it would be. (I had been a reader for a while before I realised your true name). So to read (less than a hour later) that you could have been a Selina, spins me out!
 9. Amanda | November 6th, 2011 at 10:11 am | # 
I hated my name as I was growing up, but have settled into it now–I’ve had a long time to get used to it!
 10. EHA | November 6th, 2011 at 10:13 am | # 
Not too much to say about the food: pleasant enough stopover, I guess ! Yes, in spite of the fact that 80% of people I meet mispronounce mine initially, I love it ! Both Mom and Dad actually wanted a girl and had picked the N European name‘Mai’should their wishes eventuate. Then I was born on a midsummer evening as the sun was going down and Dad first saw me in my Mom’s arms at last light–well,‘Eha’does mean‘last light of the day’in Estonian and Dad just had to name me that: am SO glad!! The opposite:‘dawn’is‘Koidu’in the language and both are v popular girls’names !
 11. Kelley | November 6th, 2011 at 10:28 am | # 
Considering I don’t like tomato I wouldn’t have been as forgiving with the sandwich.

But then again I have my cranky pants on today.

They belong to Stacey and while I don’t particularly like my name I am glad my parents went with that rather than Stacey.
 12. Janannyjam. | November 6th, 2011 at 10:37 am | # 
Have never liked my name,Janice Lorraine,so called myself Jan or Janny,when Mum called me JANICE!!!Iknew thatI was in big trouble!
Enjoy NQN,you are my daily eat with my eyes treat,keep up the good work.
 13. Ann | November 6th, 2011 at 10:48 am | # 
You do try ALL sorts of places, don’t you? Sorry, but I think it looks a bit ordinary!
I agree, Selina does suit you.
My name is boring and even my mum thinks so!
 14. Hotly Spiced | November 6th, 2011 at 10:54 am | # 
The prices seem very reasonable and a parking space in Camperdown can only be described in one word–miracle. No complaints about my name except that at my Christening the minister mis-heard my name so I was actually christened with a different name. It’s hard to tell who’s the real me!
 15. Lucy @ Lucy eats | November 6th, 2011 at 10:58 am | # 
Doesn’t look very butch at all! My parents let me choose my name when we came to NZ (but I don’t remember doing so haha).

The food looks real cute and the lamington looks delicious
 16. Three-Cookies | November 6th, 2011 at 11:40 am | # 
Interesting, macho sounding name with pink plastic stools outside:) At least the name attracts attention and customers. Butch is a brand of dog food rolls sold in NZ.
 17. Chris | November 6th, 2011 at 11:56 am | # 
My mother said she and my Dad thought about naming me Veronica or Victoria because I had a tiny‘V’birthmark/scar on my forehead when I was born. But I’m happier with Chris (Christine) that I was named.
 18. Victoria Challalncin | November 6th, 2011 at 12:48 pm | # 
A fun post. I’ve never of a jaffle before, but like the looks of it. And that pie is positively calling to me. As for names…I go from Victoria to Vicki and back again simply because I live in Mexico. Either is fine!
 19. Elly | November 6th, 2011 at 1:22 pm | # 
not so keen on my name. Have never met anyone whose name is spelled and said the same way as mine. P.S my name is Elena Pronounced e as in egg, le as in let, na as nah!
 20. InTolerant Chef | November 6th, 2011 at 1:22 pm | # 
I like the name, and I like how they give blokes an‘out’, it’s like making my dad quiche- he hates it, but he sure loves egg and bacon pie I guess my name’s OK, but I suppose we all yearn to be a bit exotic!
 21. KT | November 6th, 2011 at 1:58 pm | # 
I love Butch Foods. I used to go there often when I was based at RPA. I miss it!
 22. msihua | November 6th, 2011 at 2:04 pm | # 
Hmmm what’s in a name? It’s hard with an Asian name and I grew up trying to be different…but I guess mine is pretty unique and I’ve grown to love it now 
 23. Hannah | November 6th, 2011 at 2:13 pm | # 
But…. but…a jaffle has to have the crispy sealed edges! At least the lamington looks amazing 
 24. Mary | November 6th, 2011 at 2:26 pm | # 
I do love a good jaffle! I was going to be called Patrick if I came out a boy. A bit strange, given it is now my partner’s name.
 25. My Inner Chick | November 6th, 2011 at 4:21 pm | # 
OOOO—-Belgian hot chocolate!! Are those marshmallows on the plate?
Lorraine, I’d like some green eggs and ham…Yes! Yes! Sam I am! Xxx
 26. cakelaw | November 6th, 2011 at 7:44 pm | # 
I like the name–it’s rather cool. I’d love some green eggs and ham just so that Icoud say“Sam I Am”.
 27. Merryn | November 6th, 2011 at 8:57 pm | # 
Oh, those green eggs and ham right out of Dr Seuss! That is a name. I was to be called Jennifer Susan but somehow mother had her way and called me Merryn–a name she read in a book when she was 16–some 14 years earlier. THE most forgettable name in the world! How I would have loved to have been called Susan whilst growing up through those awkward teenage years. Luckily, one does grow into one’s name A Great‘Butch’story Lorraine x
 28. Not Quite Nigella | November 6th, 2011 at 9:42 pm | # 
Hi Kimberley-Hehe that’s great! It was quite tasty! 

Hi ck-Haha yes that’s very true isn’t it?? Thanks ck! 

Hi Miss Kimbers-oh really? Did your mother stop him? 

Hi Heidi-Aww you are too sweet Heidi! And you know Heidi was my favourite book when I was young-I wanted to be Heidi! x

Hi The Food Mentalist-I know, me too, I really think that I suit it! Both Naomi and Erin are nice names! 

Hi gummi baby-Thanks, yes hte green eggs and ham were delicious! True, I think this was more a regular multigrain sandwich loaf which she didn’t really go for 

Hi YaYa-Now wouldn’t that be a great name for a butcher’s shop!? 

Hi Lea-Wow that is very weird indeed! I always think that my name although I like it, doesn’t really suit me!

Hi Amanda-Oh really? Hehe that’s true, I always thought that people that hated their names had unusual names! 

Hi EHA-How do you pronounce it properly? Just in case! What a lovely meaning! I didn’t know that was what it meant!

Hi Kelley-HHehe cranky pants would have come out for that tomato? Yes Kelley suits you more than Stacey I think!

Hi Janannyjam-Haha yes when they use that name with a stern tone, well you know you’re in trouble! Thank you so much! 

Hi Ann-Yes i try all sorts of places I’ve always felt more Selina! Oh really? She didn’t get to choose?

Hi Hotly Spiced-Ha yes indeed re parking! Oh really? how unusual! Is that binding at all?

Hi Lucy-Haha yes no pin ups on the wall! Oh that’s cute being able to choose your own!

Hi Three-Cookies-Haha something for everyone? Haha really?

Hi Chris-Oh wow, that sounds like Harry potter (sort of?!) which is very cool indeed 

Hi Victoria-I love proper jaffles! Yes it’s good when the shortening is nice and you don’t mindit. I’m not fond of the shortening for Lorraine aka Loz! 

Hi Elly-Oh right, I think that’s how I would have pronounced it. Do people pronounce it another way? 

Hi InTolerant Chef-Hehe yes gotta feed the blokes huh! LOL that is very funny re the quiche! I certainly do! 

Hi KT-Oh right, yes the location is right nearby!

Hi msihua-Yes exactly! I used to want the name Jane!

Hi Hannah -I know! I love jaffles! 

Hi Mary-Aren’t they great? Oh that’s a bit strange isn’t it! so they ended up with a son in law with that name!

Hi Kim-Yep sure are! Haha then you shall have them xxx

Hi cakelaw -Hehe yes it’s very important to say that when you get them! 

Hi Merryn-Oh you don’t like it? I think it is quite unique! Yes that’s true, I hope I’ve grown into mine Thank you! x
 29. Bianca @ T.C.C | November 6th, 2011 at 10:11 pm | # 
That pie looks squashed! Surely you are fooling us all and there was really no filling? Haha!
 30. Ladybugfunk | November 6th, 2011 at 10:16 pm | # 
Hi Lorraine, I must admit I would have been disappointed if I got a toastie after expecting a jaffle…It’s rather sacred. I was almost called Ana so am very happy with Lydia which definitely suits me 
 31. Naomi | November 6th, 2011 at 10:24 pm | # 
I never used to like my name growing up, wanted to be called something cute like Becky haha
But now I like it, it’s not too common. And seeing I didn’t have a name until a week after I was born there were no other options 
 32. Phunk | November 6th, 2011 at 10:51 pm | # 
That lamington looks delicious with the toasted coconut, it never occurred to me you could improve on a lamington but there you go!
I was named many years before I was even thought of so was never going to be anything but 
 33. Debra Kolkka | November 6th, 2011 at 11:07 pm | # 
I was named after Debbie Reynolds–I was born around the time of the Tammy movies. I quite like it now, but wasn’t all that keen when I was younger. Strangely, I resembled Debbie Reynolds a bit when I was young.
 34. Mi Vida en un Dulce | November 7th, 2011 at 1:52 am | # 
The food looks delicius, I just finished my breakfast and I’m hungry again. Excelent meal for a Sunday eh?
I like my name, it’s my Mom’s also. As far as I know, my grandfather was reading a book about Pompeya where is a young lady called Nydia…that’s the origin of my mother’s name, so mine.
 35. Anna Johnston | November 7th, 2011 at 7:00 am | # 
Green Eggs and Ham looks so good. Mmmm.
I was always supposed to be called Anna, however some thought should have perhaps gone into this, I hate being called a goanna…Not funny…At all!
 36. Amber | November 7th, 2011 at 11:32 am | # 
I have a thing against cafes/restaurants using square, supermarket style bread when good bread is so easily accessible! (you can imagine then that I was delighted at breakfast yesterday when we were served doorstop sized pieces of beautifully toasted sourdough!)

Apparently my dad thought it would be funny to call me Holly. I would then have been“Holly Day”. Oh dear…thank goodness he didn’t get away with that one!
 37. Kay | November 7th, 2011 at 12:31 pm | # 
Butch was my coffee place when I worked at RPA I never ever had a bad coffee there.
 38. Nic@diningwithastud | November 7th, 2011 at 12:34 pm | # 
Lol I wasnt supposed to be called something else but if I was a boy I would be Nathan. Coincidently, my godson was named Nathan 
 39. Claire @ CKCreations | November 7th, 2011 at 12:35 pm | # 
Well it’s definitely a catchy name.

I like my name but I was meant to be Anna or Elizabeth. Mum and dad said I didn’t look like either of those so I was randomly named Claire (middle name Elizabeth).

When dad rang to tell my grandma her response was‘well you might change it.’I guess she didn’t like it!
 40. Food Wine Sleep | November 7th, 2011 at 2:23 pm | # 
Ah c’mon was trying to keep this place quiet!! I normally pop in here for a quiet Sat. morning coffee after dropping my daughter off at local tennis lessons…boo hoo probably won’t get a seat next week….
 41. mykitchenstories.com | November 7th, 2011 at 5:03 pm | # 
I was reading this with my sister who thought it might be a lesbian hangout!………I think Ill give it a miss for now, rather go to Luxe or Pie tin
 42. Bubble and Sweet | November 7th, 2011 at 9:59 pm | # 
Really the name Butch kept the workers feeling comfortable coming in ?? I’m happy with my name I kept teasing my husband that I was going to call child #3 Buffy if it was a girl, luckily turned out to be a boy 
 43. Sophie | November 7th, 2011 at 11:20 pm | # 
Jaffles are one of my homely faves. This one looks good! 
 44. Nami | November 8th, 2011 at 4:42 pm | # 
I like my name but it’s hard for people to remember after I moved here.. that’s one problem…Hm, I always make ham&amp;cheese but cheese and tomato is a good change huh. I should try that for my kids. 
 45. Mygutter Guard | January 10th, 2012 at 5:51 pm | # 
Now I’m hungry ahahah…
this is good 
 

Post a Comment
 Your email is never published nor shared. Required fields are marked * Name * Email * Website Comment 
 

 
 
 
 
 
Receive daily updates via email. Just enter your email address and press Subscribe.
 
 
 Search Not Quite Nigella
 Click here to search using maps 
 

 About Me Advertising/Sponsorship Wallpaper Wednesdays Media&amp;Awards Sponsors What is NQN up to now? NQN on Facebook RSS 
 
Thanks to our sponsors.


 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Eating in Sydney
 Sydney - CBD and inner city 
 Sydney - East 
 Sydney - Inner West 
 Sydney - North 
 Sydney - Northern Beaches 
 Sydney - South 
 Sydney - West 
 Cheap Thrills $20 or under pp 
 
Aust Eating&amp;Travel
 Blue Mountains 
 Canberra and Surrounds 
 Central Coast NSW. 
 Hunter Valley 
 Mudgee 
 Norfolk Island Eating&amp;Travel 
 Orange 
 Queensland 
 South Australia 
 Snowy Mountains 
 South Coast of NSW 
 Tasmania 
 Victoria 
 Western Australia 
 
New Zealand Eating&amp;Travel
 New Zealand 
 North Island 
 South Island 
 
Asia Eating&amp;Travel
 Hong Kong 
 Bali Eating&amp;Travel 
 Singapore 
 Tokyo Eating&amp;Travel 
 Vietnam Eating&amp;Travel 
 
USA Eating&amp;Travel
 U.S.A. 
 
Canada Eating&amp;Travel
 Canada Eating&amp;Travel 
 Edmonton Eating&amp;Travel 
 Montreal Eating&amp;Travel 
 Quebec Eating&amp;Travel 
 Vancouver Eating&amp;Travel 
 Jasper Eating&amp;Travel 
 
UK Eating&amp;Travel
 London Eating&amp;Travel 
 
Europe Eating&amp;Travel
 Austria Eating&amp;Travel 
 Finland Eating&amp;Travel 
 Paris Eating&amp;Travel 
 
Middle East Eating&amp;Travel
 Middle East Eating&amp;Travel 
 
Cooking&amp;Recipes
 Basics Made From Scratch 
 Biscuits and Cookies 
 Breads 
 Breakfast recipes 
 Cakes 
 Cakes - Easy 
 Cocktail Party Food 
 Cupcakes 
 Dinner recipes 
 Easy peasy 
 Gluten Free 
 Healthy 
 Holidays 
 Ice Creams 
 Jams and Spreads 
 Lunch recipes 
 Macarons 
 Other Sweet Things 
 Perfect Picnic Food 
 Pies quiches&amp;tarts 
 Soups 
 Vegetarian Friendly Mains 
 
And More
 Afternoon and High Tea 
 Book Reviews 
 Celebrity Chefs&amp;Interviews 
 Competitions 
 Cooking Classes 
 Food Festivals 
 Hatted&amp;Michelin restaurants 
 Kid friendly 
 Markets 
 NQN&apos;s most memorable moments and meals 
 Patisseries and Bakeries 
 Special Events 
 Special Features 
 Specialty Shopping 
 The Unusual 
 Wallpapers 
 Walking&amp;Eating Tours 
 
Restaurants by Cuisine
 African 
 American 
 Breakfast&amp;Brunch 
 Buffets 
 Cafe&amp;Casual Eating 
 Chinese 
 Chocolatiers 
 English 
 French 
 German&amp;Austrian 
 Greek 
 Hamburgers 
 Indian 
 Indonesian 
 Italian 
 Japanese 
 Jewish and Kosher 
 Korean 
 Lebanese 
 Mexican 
 Middle Eastern 
 Modern Australian 
 Other Asian 
 Other European 
 Portuguese 
 Seafood 
 Singaporean&amp;Malaysian 
 South American 
 Spanish 
 Steak 
 Swedish 
 Swiss 
 Takeaway&amp;Fast Food 
 Thai 
 Turkish 
 Vegetarian friendly 
 Vietnamese 
 Wine Bars 
 With a view 
 
Themes
 Christmas 
 Easter 
 Halloween 
 Romantic 
 
Most recent posts

 Flowerbombs, Flaming Cocktails&amp;Secret Foodies! Carrot Cake Muesli Bars Izakaya Den, Melbourne How To Cook The Perfect Steak! Cara&amp;Co, Sydney The Light in Antibes, France Win 1 of 8 Copies of High Season by Jim Hearn! St Jude, Redfern Hot‘N Cheesy Chorizo Dip The Farm at Cape Kidnappers, New Zealand 5 Minute Self Saucing Banana Butterscotch Pudding 4Fourteen, Surry Hills Exploring Kangaroo Island, South Australia Win a $170 Voucher For A Christmas in July Dinner With Trippas White! Chinese Bourbon Chicken 
 Search Not Quite Nigella
 Sitemap 

 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 2.5 Australia License .
 
 
 ©2012 all rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
