<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004634" url="http://www.instrumentalistmagazine.com/index_old.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:08" support="5" score="0.021104527497891944" bingtitle="Piano Explorer Main" webtitle="Piano Explorer Main">
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>... is less than the cost of a meal at a fast food restaurant. ... especially in this difficult economy. Pay an invoice online: ... outside the U.S. must be paid by credit card.</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 Kids 
 Composer
Schedule 
 Subscribe 
 Teacher&apos;s Guides 
 Contact Us 
  


 

 

 
 This website is supplemental material for subscribers of the student
magazine, 
Clavier&apos;s Piano Explorer. It includes additional information for students , including
links to music mentioned in the issue and quizzes, as well as suggestions for teachers .
  
 
 Renew Now for Fall: Many subscriptions expire over the summer or in
September. Order now for next year, so your students receive their magazines
on time and without interruption. Even if you do not
know how many students you will have in the fall you can order now. Just place your order for the number of copies you think you will need,
and then add a few extras. In September adjust your order number and pay only
for the final amount. (We are happy to send a few extra copies in September so
new students do not have to wait several weeks for their magazines.)

You can add additional students to your group order throughout the year and
only pay for the magazines you receive. (Check your mailing label for
expiration date.) Renew now and don&apos;t miss an issue. (see below for more information)
 
 Order at our Online
Store 
Email: [email protected] 
Call 888-446-6888 

 

 July 2012 - Student Page 

 Composition Contest Winners 

 May 2012 Student Page 

 Kids Corner - with honorable mention pieces from 2012 Contest 

 July
Teacher&apos;s Guide 

 Past Issues 

Click on the picture or date to learn more about the articles in July

 
  
 
 
 Order online: click here or call 888-446-6888 or email us at [email protected] 

Most teachers pass on the low cost of Piano Explorer as
a material&apos;s fee. At only $6 per student (group subscriptions) for a full year
of great magazines, this is less than the cost of a meal at a fast food
restaurant. As always we work to keep our costs and thus the price of the
magazine as low as possible, especially in this difficult economy.

 Pay an invoice online: click here 
 

 
 
 Subscription Rates 
 
 
 Group Rate (5 or more copies ): 
 $6 per person/year (10 issues/ year) 
 Regular Rate: 
 $12 per person (1 year) 
 
 For delivery outside the U.S.
(due to increased delivery costs) 
 Canada: regular rate-$26, group rate-$12 per person
 Other Foreign rates: regular-$34, groups-$17 per person
 All subscriptions sent outside the U.S. must be paid by credit card. 

 To Order Piano Explorer 

 Online store for renewals/new subscriptions
 Pay an Invoice 

 or contact us by email:
 Subscriptions/address changes 
 Editorial
questions/comments 

 200 Northfield Road, Northfield,
Illinois 60093
Toll free
(888)446-6888, Fax (847)446-6263 

 Copyright 2012 Piano Explorer Co., All
rights reserved.
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
	</body>
</document>
