<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004944" url="http://seeyarealsoon.com/parkguides/magickingdom/" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="1" score="0.0014381593517250977" bingtitle="The Magic Kingdom | &quot;See Ya Real Soon!&quot;" webtitle="The Magic Kingdom |See Ya Real Soon!">
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>Casey’s Corner (Counter Service) A baseball themed fast-food restaurant, it ... back into the park, though. Columbia Harbor House (Counter Service ... Spin the car around ...</description>
	<body>
		&quot;See Ya Real Soon!&quot; Skip to content 
 Home Podcast Park Guides About Me Links 
 
The Magic Kingdom
 
 

Walt Disney World’s first (and most popular) theme park, the Magic Kingdom, is home to everyone’s childhood fantasies come to life.  Separated into six unique, highly-immersive“lands,”the park is laid out in an easy-to-navigate hub-and-spoke design.  With the iconic“Partners”statue of Walt Disney and Mickey Mouse standing proudly in the center, in front of the breathtaking Cinderella Castle, the lands branch off in different directions.  View an up-to-date map here. 

 EVENTS: Most nights,“ Wishes”Nighttime Spectacular fireworks show lights up the sky.  Several parades make their way through the park each day, including the“ Celebrate a Dream Come True ”parade, and“ Move it, Shake it, Celebrate it !”After dark, the widely popular“ Main Street Electrical Parade ”dazzles guests.  There is a traditional flag-lowering ceremony in the Town Square each day.

Many seperate-admission parties are scheduled for select nights throughout the year, encorouging guests to dress up and enjoy the park at limited capacity.  Most of the park’s most popular attractions are open, and special fireworks shows, parades, dance parties, character meets, and many other special events happen throughout the night.  These parties include Disney’s Pirate and Princess Party , Mickey’s Not-So-Scary Halloween Party , and Mickey’s Very Mery Christmas Party .

 

 The entrance and exit to the Magic Kingdom is down Main Street, USA.  This is my personal favorite of all the“lands”, even though it boasts no rides and very little attractions.  Main Street, USA is themed after Walt Disney’s childhood hometowns of Kansas City and Marceline, Missouri, around the turn of the last century.  Read all about the details here . 

 MAIN STREET, USA ATTRACTIONS: 

 The Walt Disney World Railroad Take a ride on one of three authentic steam engines.  The track loops the entire park, and includes a stop at the Frontierland Station, and soon a stop at the new Storybook Circus area of the refurbished Fantasyland. The Harmony Barber Shop A real working barbershop, they specialize in children’s first haircuts.  Poke in just to get a look at the antique furnishings, or get your little one spruced up with colored hair gel and a sprinkling of“Pixie Dust.” Town Square Theater Next door to Tony’s Town Square Restaurant, the Theater occupies the former Main Street Exposition Hall.  Inside, you can meet with your favorite Disney Princesses, or even go backstage to shake hands with Mickey Mouse himself, before his big magic act.  While waiting in line, guests are entertained by“magical”interactive posters. Main Street Transportation At special times throughout the day, you can catch a one-way trip from Main Street’s Town Square to the“hub”in front of  Cinderella Castle.  You can ride an old-fashioned jitney, a fire engine, an omnibus, a horseless carriage, or even a horse-drawn trolley. Sorcerers of the Magic Kingdom Main Street’s latest addition is a fun-for-all-ages“alternative reality”interactive game.  Located in the Main Street Fire Station in the Town Square (Engine Company 71, named after the year the park opened), Sorcerers of the Magic Kingdom has Merlin recruiting apprentices to help stop Disney villians from taking over the park.  Players recieve special collectible cards, and must search the park for clues and specially activate hidden portals to thwart the villians.  The game is free with park admission, but I would only recommend it for those who have previously visited the Magic Kingdom, otherwise you may miss everything else the park has to offer! 

 MAIN STREET, USA SHOPPING: 

 The Main Street Emporium The largest (and best themed) gift shop in the Magic Kingdom, the Emporium is home to just about any kind of souvenir you could want. Main Street Athletic Club Sports-themed Disney merchandise Main Street Cinema Disney Clothiers Uptown Jewelers Crystal Arts The Chapeau Get your personalized Mickey ears here Main Street Confectionary The smell of baking chocolate chip cookies is pumped out in front, luring people in sweet-tooth-first.  Delicious baked goods, candy, and those huge better-than-homemade rice crispy treats. Main Street Gallery 

 MAIN STREET, USA DINING: 

 Tony’s Town Square Restaurant (Table Service) A charming Italian eatery located at the park’s entrance, Tony’s is modeled after the romantic restaurant from Lady and the Tramp (you can even see the happy couple enjoying spaghetti in the moonlit alleyway; and be sure to look for their pawprints in the cement out front).  My personal experience has been hit or miss; I find it a bit pricey for what you get, but it’s a nice retreat from the hustle and bustle of the park. The Plaza Restaurant (Table Service) Typical but decent fare; mainly burgers, sandwiches, soups and salads.  Worth checking out if just for the desserts though! Casey’s Corner (Counter Service) A baseball themed fast-food restaurant, it’s fun to grab a bite then sit outside to watch the honky-tonk piano player effortlessly turn classic Disney songs into bouncy ragtime tunes.  They’re supposedly known for great hot dogs, but they’re more accurately standard at best. Main Street Confectionary (Bakery) Crystal Palace (Character Dining) Be sure to make reservations for a fun dining experience with Winnie the Pooh and friends.  Breakfast tends to be the best meal here. Plaza Ice Cream Parlor 

 

 

 When most people think of Disney theme parks, they tend to think of Fantasyland.  Through the center walkway of Cinderella Castle, Fantasyland is currently themed to be a quaint medieval castle village, straight out of a fairytale.  Major changes are underway however, and the land will be doubling in size over the next few years.  While construction may temporarily disrupt some of the ambiance to the area (though Disney finds ways to make it as least-intrustive as possible), by 2013 the landscape of Fantasyland will be better than ever before (read about the changes here ). 

 UPDATE: The Storybook Circus area will be the first phase of the new Fantasyland to open, scheduled for May 2012.  Attractions will include the Great Goofini’s Barnstormer (a kiddie-coaster), two Dumbo the Flying Elephant rides, a play area, train depot, and more.

 FANTASYLAND ATTRACTIONS: 

 Prince Charming’s Regal Carousel Look for the horse with the golden ribbon on its tail–that’s Cinderella’s. Dumbo the Flying Elephant Perhaps the most iconic of all Disney rides, the Fantasyland expansion includes plans for a whole Dumbo’s Circus-themed area, including two flying elephant rides.  Expect the transition in May 2012. it’s a small world A great attraction to cool off, soak up history from the 1964 World’s Fair, and get the most annoying song ever written stuck in your head. Peter Pan’s Flight Geared toward little ones, but it’s a ride I never miss.  My favorite part is flying over the London skyline… Snow White’s Scary Adventures This classic dark ride will run for the last time in late May, 2012.  The area will be made into a Disney Princess meet-and-greet location.  A brand new Snow White attraction, the Seven Dwarves’Mine Train, will be built nearby. Mad Tea Party Take a spin in the classic oversized tea cups. Mickey’s PhilharMagic THE BEST 3D show on Disney property, this musical romp follows Donald Duck as he inadvertently crashes through some of Disney’s most famous movie scenes.  Shown on the world’s largest seamless projection screen.  Some more trivia:  All of the Donald’s audio was lifted from classic Disney animated shorts, so the attraction is posthomously voiced by the great Clarence“Ducky”Nash. The Many Adventures of Winnie the Pooh I may still be bitter about this attraction because it replaced Mr. Toad’s Wild Ride, but after you get over the resentment, it’s actually a really fun experience.  I guess. Crane your neck and keep an eye out for the hidden shout-outs to Mr. Toad and his friends. 

 FANTASYLAND SHOPPING: 

 Bibbidi Bobbidi Boutique Found inside Cinderella Castle, this wildly popular salon for children 3 and up offers hair-styling, shimmering makeup, nails, and even full princess costumes.  Photo packages are also available.  Boys can be made into knights with a hair-styling plus their very own sword and shield.  (A second location at Downtown Disney offers the same services, plus a Hannah Montana package).  Reservations are STRONGLY suggested, call 1-407-WDW-STYLE. Fantasy Faire Mickey’s PhilharMagic gift shop. Kodak Kiosk Pooh’s Thotful Shop Pooh-themed merchandise Seven Dwarves Mine Snow White and the Seven Dwarves souvenirs Sir Mickey’s Adult clothing and Disney merchandise Tinker Bell’s Treasures Children’s toys, costumes, and accessories 

 FANTASYLAND DINING: 

 Cinderella’s Royal Table (Character Dining) Dine like royalty high in the dining hall of Cinderella Castle.  Offering panoramic views of Fantasyland, this is the ultimate must-do for any fan of the classic fairy tales.  Disney Princesses mingle as you eat, and even Cinderella herself is on hand to greet guests as they arrive.  Be sure to reserve early, this one fills up fast. Pinnochio Village Hause (Counter Service) Standard quick-service fare, offering tables that overlook the loading dock for“it’s a small world.” Mrs. Pott’s Cupboard (Snacks) The Enchanted Grove (Juice/Coffee Stand)  The coffee is NesCafe.  Don’t bother.  Slushies available too, but opt for a Dole Whip in Adventureland instead, trust me. 

 

 

 Liberty Square is the smallest of all the lands, and it’s very easy to walk right past it on the way to Frontierland or Adventureland.  With buildings themed after colonial America, there’s plenty of out-of-the-way treasures to discover.  Outside of the Hall of Presidents is an actual replica of the Liberty Bell, one of 50 made for the bicentennial celebration in 1976.  Every state received one, but Pennsylvania already had the original, so Disney inherited the copy. 

 The Liberty Tree, the largest (real) tree in the Magic Kingdom, holds thirteen lanterns, representing the thirteen original colonies.  A wooden pillory is popular for photo-ops, and some of the most unique shopping is available here. 

 LIBERTY SQUARE ATTRACTIONS: 


 Hall of Presidents A show featuring great speeches from U.S. Presidents.  Not the best attraction for kids (or adults) with attention problems, but the amount of detail is fascinating for history buffs.  FDR is wearing FDR’s ACTUAL leg braces, a detail the audience never even sees, but that’s how much care Imagineers took in crafting this attraction.  Special permission was received from the White House to use the Presidential Seal in the lobby.  Check out the latest addition, what I like to call“Robama”, voiced by our current commander-in-chief himself. 


 The Haunted Mansion My absolute favorite of any Disney attraction.  999 happy haunts come out to socialize at the Haunted Mansion, hidden back among the Gracey family graveyard.  Cutting edge technology mix with classic theatrical illusions to create a spooky, silly ride through the manor.  Read all about the chillingly detailed backstory here: Part I Part II Liberty Square Riverboat The Liberty Belle is an authentic paddle-wheel riverboat, sauntering down the Rivers of America several times a day.  A nice, relaxing trip around Tom Sawyer Island, the only thing missing is a high-stakes poker game. 

 LIBERTY SQUARE SHOPPING: 

 Yankee Trader Kitchenware. Liberty Square Portrait Gallery Have your silhouette drawn by an artist.  Perfect for ugly people! Heritage House Colonial American-themed gifts and souvenirs. Ye Olde Christmas Shoppe Beat the Florida-in-August heat by ducking in this shop for a taste of the holidays.  Outside it looks like several different buildings, but they’re all connected inside. 

 LIBERTY SQUARE DINING: 


 Liberty Tree Tavern ( Table Service) Serving a broad menu at lunch and family-style fare at dinner,  Liberty Tree Tavern has quite possible the best food in the Magic Kingdom.  You’ll leave with that feeling you get after Thanksgiving dinner.  Kindly leave your pants buttoned while heading back into the park, though. 


 Columbia Harbor House (Counter Service) Coming from New England, I can testify that this quick-service spot is authentic in almost every way, from the ambience of an old colonial seaside home, to the clam chowder.  The fish and chips are certainly not worthy of the Massachusetts seal of approval, but it’s a nice break from the usual burgers and hot dogs.  Chicken fingers are available too.  This one is my usual choice for counter service in the Magic Kingdom. Sleepy Hollow Snacks You’ll lose your head over the baked goods here! 

 

 

 For the cowboy in all of us, Frontierland offers some of the best attractions in the park.  spontaneous hoedowns break out with Woody and other Disney favorites. 

 FRONTIERLAND ATTRACTIONS: 

 Splash Mountain Themed after the Disney live-action/animated Song of the South, this flume ride may include cute bunnies and singing critters, but it has one“hare”-raising drop! Big Thunder Mountain Railroad It’s the wildest ride in the wilderness!  A runaway mine train is the basis for this coaster.  In late afternoon, the grease on the tracks is at its hottest; that makes for one fast ride.  Closed for refurbishment the first half of 2012 in order to install a new track system. Frontierland Shootin’Arcade A classic shooting gallery game. Tom Sawyer Island Accessable by raft, Tom Sawyer Island is a nice retreat away from the rest of the park.  Explore caves, hideouts, an old mill, and even a fort.  (TRIVIA:  The fort is named Fort Clemens, in honor of Samuel Clemens, aka Mark Twain.  It offers the best view of Big Thunder Mesa.  Inside the mill, a bird’s nest is built precariously on a rotating gear, spared from being crushed due to a missing cog:  this is a scene from the Disney Silly Symphony short“The Old Mill,”the first cartoon to use multi-plane technology.  The creaks and groans of the mill are to the tune of“Down by the Old Mill Stream,”the song used in that short.  Also, there are six paintbrushed hidden around the island every day.  Bring one back the cast member on the raft, and you may just get a reward!) Country Bear Jamboree A cute animatronic show.  Featuring 20 twangin’, pluckin’, and croonin’bears, in the style of a grand old hoedown. 
 FRONTIERLAND SHOPPING: 
 Frontier Mercantile Unique western-themed gifts. Briar Patch Splash Mountain and Winnie the Pooh merchandise. Prarie Outpost and Supply Trail Creek Hat Shop Splash Court Splash Mountain souvenirs 

 FRONTIERLAND DINING: 

 Pecos Bill’s Tall Tale Inn&amp;Cafe (Counter Service) Fresh sandwiches, wraps, salads, and burgers. Golden Oak Outpost Chicken and flatbread sandwiches 

 

 Deep inside all of us, there is a yearn for adventure.  Whether it’s sailing the high seas with a crew of rough pirates, discovering new territories deep in the heart of the darkest jungle, or catching a flying carpet to a far away land, Adventureland has something for the explorer in everyone.  Also, it’s home to the Dole Whip Float. 

 ADVENTURELAND ATTRACTIONS: 


 Pirates of the Caribbean A true Disney classic.  Take a boat ride through the town of Tortuga to witness a pillaging in progress.  Keep an eye out for Captain Jack Sparrow, who’s after the town’s treasure stash.  A perfect ride after a nice cold Dole Whip float. Jungle Cruise The ride itself is not very impressive; it’s the cast members that make it.  Your tour guide’s schtick is SOOO very delightfully corny, you’ll be rolling your eyes and groaning after every line.  A serene boat ride (the boats are modeled after“The African Queen”) through the world’s deepest jungles features animatronic wildlife and a boatful of puns.  Try a Dole Whip float afterwards. Walt Disney’s Enchanted Tiki Room An old school classic!  Nothing overly-exciting or flashy about this one (since they reverted it back to the original format in August 2011).  But a nice, pleasant little show, and a GREAT place to take a seat and cool off for fifteen minutes.  Between Dole Whip floats. The Magic Carpets of Aladdin In my opinion, the most ill-fitting, badly-themed attraction in all of Walt Disney World.  Up to four riders can share a carpet in this Dumbo-type ride, which has cartoonish, carnival-like design elements, sticking out like a sore thumb in the middle of Adventureland.  It’s like a turkey leg in the middle of your Dole Whip float. Swiss Family Treehouse You may just walk right by this attraction.  Just a basic walk-through (actually more of a“walk-up”) based on the tree house from the classic Disney film.  A nice off-the-beaten path attraction, but if you’re crunched for time, don’t feel bad about skipping it.  Go across the path for a Dole Whip float instead. 


 ADVENTUERLAND SHOPPING: 


 House of Treasure Booty fitting for a pirate Pirate’s Bazaar Agrabah Bazaar Clothing, costumes, and Aladdin merchandise Island Supply 


 ADVENTURELAND DINING: 

 Aloha Isle If you’re ever in Walt Disney World and find yourself wondering if all of the airfare, hotel fare, park tickets, dining plan, and countless other expenses were really worth it, stop at the Aloha Isle and get yourself a Dole Whip float.  You’ll then realize it was worth coming just for this treat.  Pineapple or Vanilla flavored non-dairy soft serve floats on top of fresh pineapple juice.  If you do anything on your Disney vacation, get a Grand Marnier slushie at the France pavillion in Epcot.  If you do anything else, make it a Dole Whip float.  I think they might have other stuff too, but if you order anything other than the Dole Whip float, I will find you and make you exchange it.  Seriously, get a Dole Whip float. Sunshine Tree Terrace They sell snacks here, but it doesn’t matter.  Go get a Dole Whip Float. Tortuga Tavern Are you even listening to me?  Don’t worry about the burgers and sandwiches available (seasonally) at this former home of El Pirata y El Perico Restaurante.  DOLE.  WHIP.  FLOAT.  GO.  NOW. 

 

 Okay, before we continue, did you remember to get a Dole Whip float in Adventureland?  I hope so, because it’s a long walk back across the park.  And you have to get one. 

 Anyway… 

 Tomorrowland is an ever-changing vision of a futuristic city.  It has a convention center, power supply company, and even its own transit system.  The best land to visit after dark. 

 TOMORROWLAND ATTRACTIONS: 


 Space Mountain The world’s first indoor roller coaster.  The world’s first in-the-dark roller coaster.  And the world’s first computer-operated rollercoaster.  A fun ride through space, the best part is you can’t see where the next turn, dip, or climb is.  An all-new interactive queue makes the hefty wait times actually bearable. The Tomorrowland Transit Authority Peoplemover Perhaps the lamest ride in all of Walt Disney World, it also happens to be one of my favorites.  The TTA is a must-do for many vacationers, although it offers no thrills, no scares, no excitement.  But that’s the charm of it.  A winding, overhead  loop around Tomorrowland, you’ll find yourself cool and relaxed during a hot, busy day of running from ride to ride.  Also the only way to see Walt Disney’s original model for EPCOT. Stitch’s Great Escape! An immersive show with all kinds of effects, this attraction straps you in helplessly while Stitch (from Disney’s Lilo and Stitch) escapes and runs amok.  A HUGE disappointment to those who loved Alien Encounter, the show’s scarier previous version.  Better suited for smaller kids than the original, however.  Little ones get a kick out of the mischievous furball seemingly burping in their face and bouncing around the room. Buzz Lightyear’s Space Ranger Spin Highly entertaining, two people can fit per ride vehicle.  You are each given a laser blaster, and the vehicle is equipped with a joystick.  As guests travel through the dark ride, you must shoot targets to rack up points.  Spin the car around; targets often appear on all sides.  At the end, a winner from your car is declared, and I must admit to having an undefeated record of losing. Astro Orbitor Precariously high over Tomorrowland, these miniature rocket shuttles offer some of the best views of the park.  If you don’t get too dizzy, that is. Monsters, Inc. Laugh Floor Comedy Club This inventive interactive show finds the gang from the Disney/Pixar hit trying to power Monstropolis with laughs.  What better way than converting the former“Scare Floor”into a comedy club?  Animated monster comics on stage interact in real time with actual audience members in a hilarious use of technology. Carousel of Progress Steeped in Disney history, this attraction, though no longer popular, holds a special place in many people’s hearts.  Debuting at the GE pavilion in the 1964 New York World’s Fair, it’s a trip through time, showing how far mankind has come with technology.  WARNING:  The classic Sherman Brother’s ditty“It’s a Great Big Beautiful Tomorrow”will be stuck in your head until you ride“it’s a small world”again. (TRIVIA:“Uncle Orville”is voiced by legendary Looney Tunes voice actor Mel Blanc, and the mannequin of Orville, with his tub, has a double–on Big Thunder Mountain Railroad) Tomorrowland Speedway Go-karts on a track.  Fun for kids.’nuff said. Tomorrowland Video Arcade For the children who must have their video game fix EVEN THOUGH THEY’RE IN DISNEY WORLD FOR CRYING OUT LOUD!  WOULDN’T YOU RATHER BE ON SPACE MOUNTAIN?!? 


 TOMORROWLAND SHOPPING: 


 Merchant of Venus Mickey’s Star Traders Racing Specialties Tomorrowland Video Arcade 


 TOMORROWLAND DINING: 


 Cosmic Ray’s Starlight Cafe (Counter Service) Order from the Starlight Soup-Salad-Sandwiches section, the Cosmic Chicken section, or the Blast-off Burgers Section (Complete with toppings bar).  The food is typical of everywhere else in Disney, mostly the same stuff, but everything is pretty decent.  Trying to cut back?  Sit for a spell in the lounge area featuring piano-playing alien animatronic Sonny Eclipse.  The music is so bad you’ll lose your appetite. 


 

 The Lunching Pad Snacks, beverages, and the ever-present turkey legs. Tomorrowland Terrace Noodle Station When it’s open (which isn’t very often), this counter service is a delightful, delicious little area.  On the outer cusp of Tommorowland, almost in the Plaza area of Main Street, USA, the outdoor seating offers a perfect view of Cinderella Castle. Auntie Gravity’s Galactic Goodies Ice cream and other treats. 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
One Response to The Magic Kingdom 

 Grumpymickey 6 March, 2012 at 9:00 AM 
From reading your section on Adventureland I see you either really like Dole Whips, work for the Dole company or have a pineapple farm! Either way I look forward to confirming your strong endorsement of this treat. It has to be great, after all I love pineapple and ice cream!
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 &quot;See Ya Real Soon!&quot; ·News and notes from the World of Disney…And Beyond! Blog at WordPress.com .·Theme: Pilcrow by Automattic . Follow 
 Follow“&quot;See Ya Real Soon!&quot;” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 83 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
