<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004639" url="http://www.merchantcircle.com/business/The.Dinner.Station.Highland.Village.TX.972-966-6300" time="2012-07-12-21:08" support="5" score="0.008975313577378677" bingtitle="The Dinner Station, Highland Village TX 75077" webtitle="The Dinner Station, Highland Village TX 75077">
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>... dinner - stop by the grocery store (takes too long) or swing into the nearby fast food restaurant ... time will fly by AND you will leave ... I found out when I picked up my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Loading... Autos Home&amp;Garden Real Estate Health&amp;Beauty Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining All Join Now Login Help Dashboard Sign Out Autos Business to Business Community Education Electronics Entertainment and Arts Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Professional Services Real Estate Recreation Retail Shopping Travel&amp;Lodging Find A Merchant Find A Deal Get Advice 
Find
 Merchants Deals Advice 
In or Around
 I&apos;m Insured I&apos;m Uninsured National  TX  Highland Village  75077 
 Food&amp;Dining | Catering Services | Restaurants 
 
 Info Map Blog Products Offers Newsletter 
 View gallery page 
 The Dinner Station 
 
           
 ( 1 ) review Write a Review 2920 Justin Rd., Suite 550 , Highland Village , TX 75077 972-966-6300 www.thedinnerstation.com 
Member since January 2010
 Hours: See our online calender of events or call to schedule your meal prep time. Payment: Credit Cards, Cash Neighborhood: Lewisville We also service the Flower Mound area. Book Appointment Get Directions Connect to Merchant Report Abuse Follow Follow 
Write A Review

Write a review about this merchant!
 
Write A Review

Write a review about this merchant!
 
About The Dinner Station
 
Categories: Food&amp;Dining | Catering Services | Restaurants | American Restaurants | Specialty Food Stores 


The Dinner Station offers a fun environment for preparing delicious meals made with quality ingredients tailored to your family&apos;s dining tastes. We also offer pre-assembled meal packages for pickup.


Opening The Dinner Station was our way of bringing the convenience and fellowship of preparing meals back to busy parents and working people here in our community. At The Dinner Station we have created a fun environment for preparing delicious meals made with quality ingredients tailored to your family&apos;s tastes (your family likes it spicy, add more spice; your little one will not eat mushrooms, leave them out and add extra carrots instead; got the idea?).


We left no detail out in creating a lovely &quot;kitchen&quot; at The Dinner Station - complete with kitchen cabinets, large kitchen islands for workstations, enough refrigeration for all of our customers, and windows to let in the light. The walls are painted in cheerful shades of red, yellow and blue.
Great tasting, quality food is important to us and we knew it would be important to you too. We have spent countless hours perfecting our recipes in our own kitchens. All of the dishes were tested by our own families and friends so that we were sure that you would want to serve these meals to your families. All of the food is purchased through one of Dallas&apos; oldest and most prestigious food suppliers in order to ensure the quality of products you would expect when feeding family and friends.


Do you want to know the best part?
No more last minute calls on the way home from work trying to decide what to have for dinner - stop by the grocery store (takes too long) or swing into the nearby fast food restaurant (unhealthy and expensive)? We have done the hard and time consuming parts for you - menu planning, grocery shopping, slicing, dicing, and clean-up! All you have to do is sign-up and then come to their kitchen empty-handed. In about 2 hours, you will leave with 8, 12, or 16 full- or half-sized meals that are ready for you to cook when you need them. When you walk in the door, you will be minutes away from a delicious meal that the whole family will love.


We hope you enjoy The Dinner Station and find it an invaluable resource to you and your family. We want this to be a place where you can come and have fun with your friends or come make new ones and at the same time have the benefit of meals ready-to-cook for your family without a hassle.


We welcome your feedback. Please let us know how you like us or if you have any comments, questions, concerns, or suggestions!


Meal assembly – How it works: Select your meal prep time; Choose a dining package from our flexible monthly menu choices; Grab an apron and move from station to station following our mouth-watering recipes; Take the meals home


Freezer ready assembled meals: Monthly menus available to plan one or more weeknight dinners for your family or a convenient, unique dining experience for any special occasion.


Economical and convenient dining: We provide the groceries, the recipes and the kitchen – you save time and get delicious, nutritious meals for about the same as you would spend at the store – and far less than dining in a restaurant.


Private Parties: For groups of 12 or more (limit 20), you can have the place all to yourselves! BYOB


Wedding or Baby Showers with us benefit everyone: Get a group together to prepare a month&apos;s worth of meals for the new bride or mother - and the guests leave with meals for their families too!


Girls’ Night Out: Grab some of your closest girlfriends and head on over for some fun! We guarantee that the time will fly by AND you will leave with a month&apos;s worth of meals for you and your family. BYOB


Date Night can be more than just another movie: Get a sitter, grab your spouse, and head straight to The Dinner Station! You and your spouse will have fun building meals together and mingling with other couples. BYOB


Corporate Events to build teamwork or just do something different: Looking for a new team event? Talk about balancing work and family - this is the answer!


Entertaining Guests does not have to be an all day affair: Make your life easier by selecting meals from our monthly menu that your guests are sure to love. Hosting a party with 12 guests? Select 2 - 3 of any of the delicious dishes and leave the work to us!


Out of Town Guests do not have to eat sandwiches everyday: Expecting company? Come stock up on easy to cook meals that everyone is sure to love.


Holiday Meals do not have to be a so much work: Join us at the holidays for special meal packages designed to make feeding your family less work for you. Watch the calendar for these special events.


Vacation Meals that taste just like you never left home: Heading to a beach house, lake cabin, etc.? Fill your ice chest with our delicious dishes and take them with you.


Additional perks of The Dinner Station: Gift Certificates, Rewards Points, We’ll store the prepared meals for you for weekly pickup



Tags: meal , assembly , – , how , it , works , select , your , prep , time ,
 Sponsored Links 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed 
 0.0 Self Opportunity 972-317-2138 Highland Village, TX, 75077 0.0 General Nutrition Center 972-966-1787 Highland Village, TX, 75077 0.0 Tequila&apos;s Sports Bar&amp;Grill 972-317-4171 Highland Village, TX, 75077 0.0 TEE, INC 214-912-0523 Highland Village, TX, 75077 
Related Businesses
 
Write a review about The Dinner Station
   Rate:
           
 Review I would recommend The Dinner Station to my Facebook Friends 
 

 
 
Reviews about The Dinner Station
 Sort by:  Most Helpful | Highest Rated | Most Recent The Dinner Station 2 
Might as well buy boxed from the freezer section
 
The one good thing about these meals is that they&apos;re convenient. Everything else is terrible. The food quality is poor. Most of the meals taste like they&apos;re loaded with chemicals and preservatives (they are!). 
I called our local Dinner Station before ordering and asked the manager if any of their ingredients were organic. He said no. Ok, I can deal with that for the sake of convenience. It&apos;s better than going the fast-food route. I asked if they were full of chemicals and preservatives. He said &quot;No, everything is made in-house&quot;. Wow! I guess I should have verified! I thought that meant everything was home-made. I specifically asked him about the &quot;cream base&quot;. I found out when I picked up my food that it comes out of a package. I&apos;m giving them 2 stars for convenience. But I wish I would have saved my money and bought some &quot;healthier&quot; convenience food. I won&apos;t buy from there again.
 By Rachel on October 04, 2010 at 05:28 PM The Dinner Station 2.0000000000000000 out of 5 1 1 
Browse By Category 
 Banquet Rooms Beverages Candy&amp;Sweets Catering Services Grocery Stores Meats Organic Foods Produce Retailers Restaurants Specialty Food Stores Beverage&amp;Drinks Food&amp;Produce Wholesale view more 
Get in touch with The Dinner Station
 Get in touch with The Dinner Station (20 Characters Min, 140 Characters Max) Ask Me See my entire network 
14 In My Network
 See all my Neighbors 
My Neighbors
 
Related Businesses
 
Sponsored Links
 
Other Local Businesses 
 
Follow Us
 MerchantCircle on Facebook Twitter @merchantcircle MerchantCircle Blog Home | About Us | Blog | Forums | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Support | Answers | Advertise with Us | Developers | Expert Articles Our Partners: Ask Answers  |  Life 123  |  Citysearch  |  Insider Pages  |  Urbanspoon MerchantCircle is a Reply! Inc. property. Other Reply! sites include: Bloglines | iMotors | Contractors.com | EducationHub ©2012 Reply! Inc. All Rights Reserved. CLOSE
	</body>
</document>
