<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004241" url="http://www.restaurantdesignaz.com/" time="2012-07-12-20:28" support="8" score="0.01904812311150585" bingtitle="Restaurant Design - All about restaurant design tips" webtitle="Restaurant Design - All  about restaurant design tips">
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000307" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="70"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Interior Design ... In order to get the best feel you need to ... How to pick a name for a restaurant? Ready to name your new ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Design 
 All about restaurant 
 Home About 
 
 8 Restaurant Design Tips: Sometimes Great Food and Service Just Aren’t Enough 
 February 7th, 2011 1 comment 
Sometimes great food and great service just aren’t enough.
So what’s the missing link? Restaurant design that works.
Restaurateurs contemplating a new design or renovation should consider eight tips for design:
 
 1) Develop a vision. “First of all, restaurants must create a setting that speaks to the customer,”says Alexander. He helps restaurateurs develop a vision of what the restaurant is about. Is it casual or formal? Upscale, mid-scale or budget? Who are the target customers? What kind of ambience is desired? Do the price points match the setting? The locale? Does the design and construction budget match the client’s expectations? 2) Design for functionality. “The kitchen and the bar must work together, period. Everything else follows,”he says. Can servers move easily? Do traffic patterns ease congestion for staff and customers? Can drinks be served quickly? Is the kitchen designed to professional specifications and culinary requirements?“Don’t forget—a happy chef is a good chef,”says Alexander. 3) Maximize the vision. Alexander creates visual cues through the use of materials, textures, color and seating and tabletop accessories such as dishes, silver and glassware. The vision must enhance the guest experience and guarantee that decorative elements work in harmony. Is there synergy between the visual elements and every aspect of the guest experience? Do design elements reflect the intended ambience and customer expectations? 4) Design to define space. Large spaces can be parceled into smaller, more intimate ones through, for example, the use of screens, booths and banquettes. Large airy spaces can benefit from grand architectural elements such as columns and visual elements like fireplaces. Mirrors can be wonderful design tools, too, Alexander says, because they expand the sense of space and eliminate emptiness. Besides, he adds,“they’re wonderful for people-watching.” 5) Capitalize on color. Color has a vast psychological influence, according to Alexander. Used skillfully, color conveys ambiance and attitude and provides an ideal backdrop for culinary offerings. For example, spicy foods may be best enjoyed amid rich, bright colorful rooms done up in red, yellow and orange. Think definition: dramatic shades of black, gray or mauve spell sophistication while a backdrop of neutral pastels might enhance a more mainstream menu offering. 6) Don’t neglect acoustics. Nothing spoils a dining experience more than bad acoustics. Use materials, textures and shapes that create a pleasurable sound environment. Effective use of draperies, carpeting and acoustical and ceiling tiles can go a long way toward eliminating unwanted sound effects. 7) See the light. A favorite application of lighting is its use to dramatize focal points. A piece of artwork, an unusually textured wall or the dining tables themselves – all can be illuminated for effect. Tabletops bathed in pools of light in a semi-dark room, for example, create a sense of intimate space in which the diner’s attention can focus on plate presentation. Brightly lit spaces with high ceilings convey a sense of energy and vitality while a cozier feel can be achieved with low ambient lighting supplied by wall sconces or lamps. Use ceilings to enhance design. Well-designed ceilings act as a background, pulling together the room’s lighting, color and texture. They can define space in an otherwise open room. Ceiling height can modulate a room’s sense of openness or intimacy while elaborate ceiling design provides a rich visual experience that enhances the design theme. 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: 
 Choosing The Best Interior Design Firm 
 February 5th, 2011 No comments 
cafe interior design
 
Interior design is an upcoming field that finds application in many places. Every new company that is set up, every new business or office that is started will definitely want to hire an interior designer to make their office space aesthetically pleasing and attractive. Today, it has become common for every new restaurant or office to have a particular style – some are serious and somber, while others are flashy and bright. Depending on the nature of the office or restaurant, an appropriate theme can be chosen for that space.

When it comes to choosing the right decor and theme for a building’s interiors, there is nobody who can do a better job than an interior designer. There are different interior designers who specialize in different types of interiors – for example, there are special restaurant designer when it comes to restaurant design. Restaurant interior design is by far the most sought after, as people pay a lot of attention to the aesthetics of the places where they come to eat. Interior design for restaurants can be quite tricky, because the furniture and wall colors have to go well with each other. The furniture must also be elegant and comfortable at the same time. Similarly, there are dozens of other factors that must be taken into consideration while designing the interiors for a restaurant.

To find the best interior design, a small advertisement posted on the internet will do. The best of interior design firms are always on the lookout for newer and newer clients, and will immediately respond to your advertisement. A simple Google search for best restaurant designer and related search keywords will also bring up thousands of results, most of which will be links to the websites of some leading interior designer. From here, it becomes easy – after getting quotations from all the designers for the job, you can make a deal with the most cost-effective designer who can give you the interiors you want.
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: 
 How to Interior Design a 4-Star Restaurant 
 December 17th, 2010 No comments 
 Consult with the owner. Your design should start with his vision. For example, the three restaurants owned by Chef Emeril Lagasse in New Orleans all exude some aspect of his famous over-the-top style: the blond wood and iron accents of Emeril’s New Orleans exemplifies the bold Creole flavors of his New Orleans style. Lagasse’s Nola Restaurant, in the heart of the French Quarter, features a building stripped to the essentials. Lagasse’s Delmonico’s features Victorian touches, such as chandeliers and elegant formal spaces. Consider understatement if the food is over-the-top. The Fat Duck, Heston Blumenthal’s wild, experimental restaurant in Bray, Berkshire, UK, with its snail porridge and bacon and egg ice cream, boasts the unassuming facade of an English country inn. Carry the theme throughout the furnishings. If the restaurant features a steakhouse theme, join paneling of reclaimed barn boards such Long Leaf Lumber uses, or consider Colonial designs in lighting, such as those by Authentic Designs (see Resources below). Modern dried flower arrangements in warm colors extending into the red can balance against light blue table service and cream- or butter-colored French doors. Finish off your design with furnishings that provide visual interest for the diner. In addition to commissioned pieces and estate sale finds, The Museum Store Company supplies reproductions of museum artifacts to commercial clients. 

 
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: restaurant design 
 Restaurant Interior Design Tips 
 December 8th, 2010 1 comment 
 

Interior Design

One of the things that we really enjoy when we get to eat outside of our homes and eat in a restaurant is the ambiance, besides the food that they are offering. Ambiance really plays a big part when it comes to making you enjoy your dining experience and for some, it determines if they will be returning to the restaurant or not.

Here are some great tips that you can take note of for a great design if you are one of those people who are thinking of opening up a restaurant. These tips play a big part in design and are proven to be very effective when it comes to creating a great ambiance where people will keep coming back for more of what your restaurant can offer.

One of the best restaurants interior design tips that you should first take note of is knowing and understanding your target market. Just by determining what your customers are demanding, you can instantly create a design in your mind that will suit best suit their lifestyle. Are you going for the young urban professionals who wear a coat and tie most of the time that will require your restaurant interior design to be more flashy and elegant? Or are you going for the market of kids who enjoy having quick fixes for their tummies but will like play rooms or arcades at the same time?

Getting a feedback from your target customers will clearly help you in formulating the best design in your mind. Chances are, once that you have finally determined what they want and once you have implemented all those elements in your restaurant, the higher the chances that they will, time and time again, visit your place and spread the word that yours is one of the greatest restaurants that they have been in. ( Source By: ArticlesBase )

Click for more restaurant interior design information
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: Restaurant Interior Design 
 Interior Design Temporary Restaurant by Tribe Studio Architects 
 December 7th, 2010 No comments 
 
 Restaurant known as place for serving food and drink and today an owner didn’t concern about menu but also thinking about how a costumer enjoy life and eat in restaurant. by designing and decorating restaurant more comfortable and enjoyable make a costumer endure and stand inside for long time like what done with this temporary restaurant exhibited Eat Green Design festival in Sydney, Australia. a unique and contemporary interior temporary restaurant created by Tribe Studio Architects lets we watch his detail description about temporary restaurant in Sydney below: 

 This project explores the conversion of a vast museum space into a pop-up restaurant. 40 guests are seated at one linear table, where they are served and lectured on all things sustainable. The intention of the design is to engage in the sustainability dialogue whilst creating a playful, festive and whimsical space. The idea of suspended plywood spirals at varying lengths reduces the intimidating grandeur of the hall to create an intimate and inviting space, throwing a warm glow and interesting shadows onto the table. The design incorporates the insertion of a low ceiling and lighting installation, to create a sense of warmth and intimacy in the enormous space using sustainably produced materials, low VOC paints and compact fluorescent light fittings. The installation was created from 2400×1200 sheets of 6mm BB grade hoop pine plywood, laser-cut and painted. The plywood panels are fixed to a fine steel frame and suspended on rigging. The steel frame is inset from the edge, allowing an elevation reading that reveals the sharp thinness of the ply. The use of the laser-cut tapering spiral involved extensive prototyping to achieve the right thickness of plywood verse a proportioned spiral to allow for drops under gravity. The spirals create an inverted mountainous topography and give a three-dimensionality to the piece. The detailing intent was sustainably focused, with a simple expression of the material’s inherent natural qualities. By fabricating the panels offsite, we reduce the energy embodied in transportation. Laser-cutting and minimal use of material allows for the panels to be transported flat. After being dismantled the ceiling installation was designed to be broken down into modules for wall art, trivets, Christmas trees and table lamps. As it happened, the entire installation was bought by a restaurant and will have a second life. 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

Click for more restaurant design ideas information

Resources: http://www.greatfu.com/ 
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: restaurant design ideas 
 Fast Food Restaurant Interior Design 
 December 6th, 2010 8 comments 
This unique sustainability fast food restaurant interior design concept is located in Hamburg’s city centre German. Designed by Ippolito Fleitz group, this sustainability restaurant concept pervades the entire technical restaurant equipment – from energy-efficient kitchen technology, to the team uniform made from FAIRTRADE-certified materials, to economical hand dryers in the toilets. The designer manage to translate the principle of sustainability into an overriding architectural concept.

The restaurant space is divided into two main zones: the dining area and the service area. On entering the restaurant, the customer first encounters the narrow end of this box. It is painted a strong shade of violet – WakuWaku’s corporate colour – thereby creating a powerful upbeat and strong brand staging. Two digital menu boards suspended from the ceiling display the current menu and images of the food on offer in alternation.

The design of the service unit signalises urbanity and speed, both trademarks of WakuWaku. The colourful, lacquered surfaces form a dynamic contrast to the expanses of stainless steel and the service counter, with its natural white, ceramic, mosaic tile surround. The intricate nature of the mosaic also represents the care and attention invested in preparing the fresh products.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

Click for more restaurant interior design information
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: Restaurant Interior Design 
 How Paint Enhance Your Restaurant Design 
 December 2nd, 2010 No comments 
 

We all know that color can affect our mood for better or worse, some colors can agitate and excite, while others can bring about a sense of calm and relaxation.

It is because of this very phenomenon, that using color strategically in restaurant design can significantly enhance—or even detract from—the restaurant patrons dining experience.

Keeping this in mind is crucial when you are planning on renovating your existing restaurant or if you happen to be preparing a new one for grand opening, choose the wrong colors and you can be sending unintended signals to your diners.

Fortunately, interior designers—and those that specifically work in the restaurant design world—know this and can help you choose a color palette that will not only set your patrons at ease, but will leave them refreshed and with the desire to return, perhaps next time with friends.

They will have no idea that the color has helped affix this idea in their head, but you should never underestimate the power of color as it relates to the moods of people.

For instance, one of the most common colors chosen for a restaurant is red, this is because it is associated with energy and desire; conversely, blue is almost never used in a restaurant because it gives people pause and brings about a reflexive mood.

However, a good designer will know which colors to compliment each other with and can enhance detail through accent colors and decor.

You can find out more about restaurant design here.
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: restaurant design 
 How to Create Great Restaurant Design 
 December 1st, 2010 No comments 
 

Ok so I figured today I’d talk about great restaurant design , and how to determine what you are striving to achieve. Sure you can go by personal preference, but creating the ambiance is one of the most important elements in the success from the restaurant. Ambiance really plays a big part when it comes to making you enjoy your dining experience and for some, it determines if they will be returning to the restaurant or not.

Here are some tips for a great design if you are one of those people who are thinking of opening up a restaurant. These tips play a big part in design and are proven to be very effective when it comes to creating a great ambiance where people will keep coming back for more of what your restaurant can offer.

One of the best restaurants interior design tips that you should first take note of is knowing and understanding your target market. Just by determining what your customers are demanding, you can instantly create a design in your mind that will suit best suit their lifestyle. Are you going for the young urban professionals who wear a coat and tie most of the time that will require your restaurant interior design to be more flashy and elegant? Or are you going for the market of kids who enjoy having quick fixes for their tummies but will like play rooms or arcades at the same time?

Getting feedback from your target customers will clearly help you in formulating the best design in your mind. Chances are, once that you have finally determined what they want and once you have implemented all those elements in your restaurant, the higher the chances that they will, time and time again, visit your place and spread the word that yours is one of the greatest restaurants that they have been in.

Resource:

http://restaurantfurnitureblog.com/restaurantfurniture/restaurant-furniture-layout-design/how-to-create-great-restaurant-design/10/08/2010/
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: restaurant design 
 Great Restaurant Interior Design Ideas 
 November 30th, 2010 No comments 
 

Few people realize the importance of designing the interior of their business premises, however the interior of the business can determine how successful the business is. This becomes more obvious when you look at the design of restaurants. When people enter a restaurant the very first thing that they will notice is the decor.

Most restaurants with the exception of McDonalds and other fast food joints create a very warm and inviting environment which makes people feel warm and comfortable. The decor is only part of the ambience, which is also created by the smell and the quality of the service provided.

The ambience of the restaurant can make or break any restaurant, even if the food is prepared very carefully it can taste horrible if the interior design of the restaurant is not very nice. Many restaurants try to make their interior design suit everyone, however this isn’t possible. These people should only really be trying to please their desired customer base. If you appeal to a certain type of customer then hopefully your client base will continue to grow.

The interior design of the restaurant should be in line with the expectations of their customers. For example a 1950′s diner theme will never work in a Chinese Restaurant. It might draw in the punters to start off with because it’s a novelty, however this will soon wear off and people will soon start to question the mismatch of designs. If you have a Chinese restaurant then you should decorate it and make it feel as Chinese as possible.

In order to get the best feel you need to hire professional decorators, this will make it possible to decorate the restaurant properly so that you are able to draw in the customers. Eating out should be an experience, by designing your restaurant carefully you can add to this experience. Neutral designs for restaurants are boring and won’t add to the excitement, this could ultimately drive your customers away.

Separate the Kitchen

Many people have a very large room with a kitchen, which they plan to use as a restaurant. However a large un-separated space for a restaurant isn’t really a very good idea. People eat out for an experience, they want to eat in a nicely designed environment. Eating in a wide open space doesn’t really cut it for many people! You should separate the space into separate areas, separating the dining room from the reception is vital. This can be accomplished using a wall or even a simple curtain.

Lots of people neglect the importance of interior restaurant design, when their restaurant fails to succeed they don’t understand why. You should invest the time required to make your restaurant look beautiful, and then you will be able to watch your business grow from strength to strength.

Resource: http://ezinearticles.com/?Great-Restaurant-Interior-Design-Ideas&amp;id=1602748
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: restaurant design Tags: restaurant design idea 
 Restaurant Name: Ideas and Suggestions 
 November 29th, 2010 No comments 
How to pick a name for a restaurant?

 
Ready to name your new restaurant? It would be a good idea to spend some time thinking about it before you commit thousands of dollars to naming your establishment, because once named a restaurant cannot be very easily renamed. It is costly and you might lose existing customers. There are several approaches to naming a restaurant. If you believe that you have an approach that is radically different, please share, in exchage for having your restaurant’s name featured prominently on this webpage. And I am not just talking theme restaurants here!

 
Naming a restaurant after the location

The great advantage of naming your eatery after the specific location is that people can easily find it. Davis Sq. Pizza, anyone? Of course, if you ever plan to establish a franchise this may or may not work. A more generic name may be better in this case. In fact, you can choose a name that represents a remote location. Like a Texas Barbecue in Minnesota or Oregon. Location names are very easy to remember, and you can always throw in something that would better define your restaurant, the type of cousin, the theme etc. 
Theme restaurant’s name

Theme restaurants tend to have more colorful and exotic names. Often these are one of a kind establishments. You can certainly try to reflect the menu of a themed restaurant in its menu, but it would almost make it appealing to less people. The attraction of a themed restaurant is not its menu, but its design and atmosphere . People may come to your restaurant from 50 miles away just to see a dinosaur skeleton or what have you. Chances are if all they want is a good meal, they can find a restaurant nearby. It is sad, but I must admit that there are some themed restaurants with mediocre and overprices food. Still, they do pretty well. No names will be named here 
Make your name your restaurant’s name

You’ve seen them. Bob’s pizza, Tom’s pancakes, Jack and Gill’s etc. Not extremely innovative, if you ask me. Names like these reflect the price range more than anything else. Probably something on the cheap side, don’t you think? You can kick it up a notch by adding some foreign charm, though. Chez Henri? But this name has other problems. 
Using your menu for inspiration

If you have one item that you feel is particularly strong, go ahead and feature it in the name. But seriously, is it all that easy to build a restaurant around a single recipe? What’s worse, people may end up associating your restaurant with only one menu item. I have heard from numerous people that they never ate at The Cheesecake Factory because they don’t like cheesecakes. This restaurant happens to have one of the most extensive (albeit eclectic) menus around! 
Totally random names that“sound good”

Blue Moon? Silent Garden? Seven stars? I am not a big fan of names that tell you nothing about the place itself. Don’t get too poetic with your restaurant’s name. It will probably cost you. 
Names to avoid

Always make sure that the name you are thinking of is not trademarked. Also, be careful when you use slang, local dialects, and especially foreign words. People must be able to pronounce your restaurant’s name! Not everybody knows enough French to pronounce Chez Henri. Also, something that sounds totally benign in one language can be extremely offensive in another one. The use of foreign words in one case when you just may want to contact a professional to check things out for you, 
A safe and meaningful way to name a restaurant

Unless you want to have a modern sounding name, there is a great way to research restaurant names. Get some old guide books or telephone books from the area that you want to use for inspiration. Look at the names of restaurants from the past. Like anything? Make sure nobody is using the name already, and you are all set. This is especially great if you want to name an Italian or French restaurant. 
 
                   
 Get Shareaholic Categories: Uncategorized Tags: restaurant name Older Entries RSS 
 Google Youdao Xian Guo Zhua Xia My Yahoo! newsgator Bloglines iNezha 
 
Recent Posts

 8 Restaurant Design Tips: Sometimes Great Food and Service Just Aren’t Enough Choosing The Best Interior Design Firm How to Interior Design a 4-Star Restaurant Restaurant Interior Design Tips Interior Design Temporary Restaurant by Tribe Studio Architects 
 
Archives

 February 2011 December 2010 November 2010 
 
Blogroll

 restaurant design firm 
 
Tags
 Italian restaurant design Kitchen Planning menu design restaurant design restaurant design idea restaurant design ideas Restaurant Interior Design Restaurant Lighting Design restaurant name Top Copyright©2010-2011 Restaurant Design
Restaurant Topic: Foldable Bar Stools | kitchen step stools
	</body>
</document>
