<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004916" url="http://www.superstock.com/stock-photography/Fast_food" time="2012-07-12-21:26" support="14" score="0.03991471155163789" bingtitle="Fast_food Stock Photography Images From SuperStock" webtitle="Fast_food Stock Photography Images From SuperStock">
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000792" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="001341" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>In fast-food restaurant, portrait boy eating a hamburger, french ... a fast-food employee gives a customer her order ... Tupical Highway Exit Sign Advertising Fast Food ...</description>
	<body>
		United States  is your country.  For advanced features, please Sign in or Register Rights Managed Royalty Free Midstock Subscription Fine Art Vintage Travel Curated Help Contact Us Promotions Lightbox 

 
 Advanced Search 
 Search within results Rights-Managed Royalty-Free Mid-Stock CDs Only 
 
Image Type:
 Photos, Art&amp;Illustration Photos Only Art&amp;Illustration Only 
Collection:
 All Collections Contemporary Vintage Fine Art Travel 
Orientation:
 Horizontal Vertical 
Color Space:
 B&amp;W Color 
Display images per page:
 50 per page 100 per page 150 per page 200 per page 
 
 We are unable to process your request. Click here for error message. If problem persists, please contact our help desk: 800.828.4545 
 helpdesk@superstock.com close Detailed error message not available 
 
 Search Results Loading .... Go to page: 
 11,363 images for FAST_FOOD Enable Rollover Sort By: Newest Relevance Page 1 of 114 
 17729812 1566-928285 New York University students and their supporters protest at NYU over the donations that the fast food chain Chick-Fil-A give... New York University students and their supporters protest at NYU over the donations that the fast food chain Chick-Fil-A gives to anti-gay groups The restaurant chain uses its WinShape Foundation to donate to groups opposed to legalizing gay marriage and. New York University students and their supporters protest at NYU over the donations that the fast food chain Chick-Fil-A gives to anti-gay groups The restaurant chain uses its WinShape Foundation to donate to groups opposed to legalizing gay ma
 17930389 4286R-1270 A packet of typical fast-food restaurant french fried potatoes or chips. 17873434 1848-586685 Fast Food street restaurant, Paris, France, Europe, PublicGround. Fast Food street restaurant, Paris, France, Europe, PublicG... Fast Food street restaurant, Paris, France, Europe, PublicGround. Fast Food street restaurant, Paris, France, Europe, PublicGround
 18333820 1829-50338 Young couple kissing at fast food restaurant 18093044 4292-94770 Turkey, Istanbul, Doener Kebab fast food stand 18345774 1829-63263 Young Woman Carrying Fast Food 17943403 1840-29664 Brighton, Fast Food Eating 16406323 1566-741242 Beijing (China): fast-foods in front of the train station 17408813 4252-18853 Man fast food 18365251 1830-60773 Boys Drinking Soda and Eating Fast Food 17529418 1899-55020 Indian Fast Food, Samosas Pan-Asian Latin Appetizers And Contrast With Tart Chimichurri Served In Dish 18297250 1569R-9075119 Boy eating hamburger in fast food restaurant with his parents 18107554 4292-123584 Teenage boy eating at fast food 17930606 4286R-1587 Scotch Pie, or mutton pie, a favourite Scottish &apos;fast food&apos;, found throughout the Lowlands and beyond. 18334312 1829-50973 Fast Food on Disposable Plates 17389449 1606-154954 France, Paris, Quartier Latin, fast food restaurants, people, 18363927 1829-85140 Fast food / Calories stacking up 16702900 1597-143926 LA, Los Angeles, California, southern California, CA, America, American, US, USA, United States, Randy´s Donuts, Donut, Donut... LA, Los Angeles, California, southern California, CA, America, American, US, USA, United States, Randy´s Donuts, Donut, Donuts, Doughnut, Doughnuts, Food, Junk Food, Fast Food, Drive Thru, Drive Through, Restaurant, Day, Outdoors, Outside, Crazy, Fun, Fun. LA, Los Angeles, California, southern California, CA, America, American, US, USA, United States, Randy´s Donuts, Donut, Donuts, Doughnut, Doughnuts, Food, Junk Food, Fast Food, Drive Thru, Drive Through, Restaurant, Day, Outdoors, Outside, Cra
 16671630 1597-142124 pedestrian, pedestrians, walkway, sidewalk, walk, walking, Avenida Central, Central Avenue, avenue, flag, flags, internationa... pedestrian, pedestrians, walkway, sidewalk, walk, walking, Avenida Central, Central Avenue, avenue, flag, flags, international, KFC, Kentucky Fried Chicken, fast food, food, chicken, exterior, architecture, front, facade, outside, outdoor, outdoors, day,. pedestrian, pedestrians, walkway, sidewalk, walk, walking, Avenida Central, Central Avenue, avenue, flag, flags, international, KFC, Kentucky Fried Chicken, fast food, food, chicken, exterior, architecture, front, facade, outside, outdoor, outd
 17894217 1566-986918 Closed empty fast food style building in Falmouth, Cape Cod, Massachusetts USA 18362278 1829-83224 Couple Eating Fast Food in Limousine 17452685 4273-9553 Fast Food, Club Sandwich With Salad And Tomato 18093043 4292-94769 Turkey, Istanbul, Vendor in a Doener Kebab fast food stand 17620503 1597-148626 Asia, China, Hong Kong, Mong Kok, Chinese Food, Asian Food, Street Food, Fast Food. Asia, China, Hong Kong, Mong Kok, Chinese... Asia, China, Hong Kong, Mong Kok, Chinese Food, Asian Food, Street Food, Fast Food. Asia, China, Hong Kong, Mong Kok, Chinese Food, Asian Food, Street Food, Fast Food
 17663710 1597-152431 Woman, blond, food, eating, meal, break, park, Fast Food, healthy, muesli, cereals,. Woman, blond, food, eating, meal, break,... Woman, blond, food, eating, meal, break, park, Fast Food, healthy, muesli, cereals,. Woman, blond, food, eating, meal, break, park, Fast Food, healthy, muesli, cereals,
 16675923 1566-836333 Greek Cuisine Tyropita Cheese Pie, Fast Food Cafe, Chania, Crete, Greece 14667929 1566-587420 Arroyo de la Miel Malaga Province Costa del Sol Spain Dusk street shot with Burger King fast food restaurant 12123373 1792-48970 United States, Georgia, Atlanta, fast-food restaurant 15909306 1589R-138509 Chinese friends eating fast food together 17658086 1566-904135 Stall selling fast food on funfair in Cheshire UK 16475739 1566-810674 stir fried noodle with slice omlette Pad mee, thai fast food , food court , bangkok 17744847 1566-932801 In a fast food, Gaborone, Botswana 14574264 3153-715603 Varsity is the largest drive_in fast_food in America. Atlanta, Georgia, U.S.A. 17754954 1566-943359 Seoul (South Korea): Burger King fast-food in the Myeong-dong shopping district 14842582 4187-21430 Danish Fast Food Hot Dogs 15214702 1829-45157 Boy with Fast Food Meal at Table 16713881 1795R-48958 Close up of fast food 17409945 4252-18849 Man fast food 15200818 4107-70762 Fast-food french fries 15733544 1566-656856 Burger King fast food 16353520 4052-37243 US fast food, hamburger 15987166 1899-25846 Chow stalls on a city street. Chow stalls vie for trade, selling fast food to passing customers on a city side street. Wan Ch... Chow stalls on a city street. Chow stalls vie for trade, selling fast food to passing customers on a city side street. Wan Chai, Hong Kong, People&apos;s Republic of China, July 1960. Wan Chai, Hong Kong, China, People&apos;s Republic of, Eastern Asia, Asia.
 18096807 4292-104562 Italy, chef making industrial pizza 18074274 4292-76851 French fries and ketchup 18383322 1829-87180 Decorated Vintage Car on Route 66 17730436 1566-928395 New York University students and their supporters protest at NYU over the donations that the fast food chain Chick-Fil-A give... New York University students and their supporters protest at NYU over the donations that the fast food chain Chick-Fil-A gives to anti-gay groups The restaurant chain uses its WinShape Foundation to donate to groups opposed to legalizing gay marriage and. New York University students and their supporters protest at NYU over the donations that the fast food chain Chick-Fil-A gives to anti-gay groups The restaurant chain uses its WinShape Foundation to donate to groups opposed to legalizing gay ma
 16467215 1566-802148 FAST FOOD, CLUB SANDWICH WITH SALAD AND TOMATO 15176054 1608-407 India, Uttar Pradesh, Agra Indian girl eating western style fast food whilst studying 17074800 4269-19374 Fast food. 15194000 4107-82032 Man Eating Fast Food 18345792 1829-63283 Young Woman Eating Hamburger 17674738 1597-154425 Inhabitant of Hamburg, Hamburger, chips, fries, Coca Cola, white, background, Junkfood, Fast Food. Inhabitant of Hamburg, Ham... Inhabitant of Hamburg, Hamburger, chips, fries, Coca Cola, white, background, Junkfood, Fast Food. Inhabitant of Hamburg, Hamburger, chips, fries, Coca Cola, white, background, Junkfood, Fast Food
 15029830 4168-3205 Russia, Moscow, Fast Food Restaurant, Doner Kebab 18063508 4292-62903 Pizza leftovers 18055628 4292-60613 Pizza 18102723 4292-122381 Dubai, United Arab Emirates, Mall of the Emirates, fast food restaurant 18252791 4286-55019 Customer and employee at Kentucky Fried Chicken restaurant in Sofia, Bulgaria. 17295379 4272-3904 Fast food, Hong Kong style, on the streets of Kowloon in the Mong Kok district, Hong Kong. 17079229 4269-22939 Fast food. 18304267 1830-42116 Friends at the Mall 17782016 1566-964875 Fast food restaurant. Barcelona. Catalonia. Spain. 17451493 4273-9551 Fast Food, Club Sandwich With Salad And Tomato 16380102 1566-715015 Georgia, Atlanta, ATL, Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport, concession, business, fast food, snack, Krystal Hamb... Georgia, Atlanta, ATL, Hartsfield-Jackson Atlanta International Airport, concession, business, fast food, snack, Krystal Hamburger, counter, menu, man, woman, cashier, ordering,
 12056031 4062-3966 Girls eating chips/fast food in Cardiff city centre at night, Wales, UK, 2002 14595466 3153-755877 europe, spain, catalonia, barcelona, fast food on the rambla 17389375 1606-155359 Japan, Kansai, Nara, Japanese McDonald&apos;s restaurant, 17684013 1532R-59017 Nasi goreng in a take away box 17756151 1566-944263 Japan, Tokyo, Shinjuku, Burger King, fast food, restaurant, business, student, 12813747 1841-31083 young woman r person in the twenties eating fast food for Hamburg food 20-25 25-30 years car 18233050 4286-31368 Still life of several hot dogs in buns with mustard. 18102855 4292-122513 USA, New York City, Manhattan, McDonald&apos;s fast food 12340385 4107-36042 Three children in a fast food restaurant 15215621 1829-46441 Young Woman with Fast Food 12602630 1829-25944 Young couple in a fast food-restaurant. 17689056 1532R-62103 Curried sausage with ketchup 18290173 1841-116737 Young couple eating pizza. Young couple eating pizza 17631190 1589R-153014 Lunch tray with food remains 17685992 1532R-62202 Fruit salad in plastic container to take away 13711501 1850-27629 Usa, California, Los Angeles, Hamburger Fast Food Sign 18214735 4273-17971 Ham Sandwich with Tomato and Salad 17928065 4286R-2247 An aubergine, parmesan cheese and tomato bake ready for the oven - a quick and delicious way of using eggplants 17685923 1532R-62102 Curried sausage with chips and ketchup 16786282 1566-862592 Greek Cuisine Fast Food Kalitsounia, Cheese and Spinach Pies in a Bakery Take Away Box 12523124 1815R-62601 Figurine made from fast food 12893382 1841-56657 soccer world cup 2006 national dish national flag fast food Japan Sushi stick 17907644 4285-14451 ONE TOASTED HAM AND CHEESE SANDWICH WITH SALAD LEAVES 17447951 4273-5731 Sausage And French Fries Against White Background 18147268 1773R-75686 Woman with icecream and cellphone 17621168 1802R-134028 Burger 17685779 1532R-61892 Turkey Sandwich on Sesame Seed Roll with American Cheese, Tomato, Onion and Pickle; Chips 18201559 1660R-59353 French fries and hamburger, studio shot 12797088 1841-25839 woman eating Hamburger, French Frise, fast food, not healthy 12343333 4107-41556 Woman at Fast Food Stand 18093800 4292-96819 Hamburgers, potato chips and coca cola glass on dish shaped as human face 18265723 4286-69566 woman sales thai food on market in 17320554 4272-32601 Fast food Turkish style, a mackerel seller on the waterfront at Eminonu, Istanbul Asia 18257025 4286-59899 Family at a breakfast table 18205465 1660R-63092 Two hands reaching for last slice of pizza 17886244 1773R-52729 Woman with fast food and vegetables 17453140 4273-6650 Pizza With Tomato, Cheese, Ham And Olives 
 Loading .... Page 1 of 114 
 Back to top Go to page: 
 
 Follow us on: Home | Website Terms | Privacy Policy | Licensing | Social Media Sharing | Popular Image Searches | Photo of the Day 
©2012 SuperStock. All Rights Reserved .
	</body>
</document>
