<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004114" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/52716422/SMEDA-Fast-Food-Restaurant" time="2012-07-12-20:21" support="50" score="0.09375472555405681" bingtitle="SMEDA Fast Food Restaurant - Scribd" webtitle="SMEDA Fast Food Restaurant">
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001027" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>... advance and kept warm, or reheated to order. Many fast-food ... The cashier will only be responsible for ... PREF-11/December, 2006/ FAST FOOD RESTAURANT Cost ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Pre-Feasibility Study F F A A S S T T F F O O O O D D R R E E S S T T A A U U R R A A N N T T Small and Medium Enterprise Developme nt Authority Government of Pakistan www.smeda.org.pk HEAD OFFICE Waheed Trade Complex, 1 st Floor , 36-Commercial Zone, Phase III, Sector XX, Khayaban-e-Iqbal, DHA Lahore Tel: (042) 111-111-456, Fax: (042) 5896619, 5899756 helpdesk@smeda.org.pk REGIONAL OFFICE PUNJAB REGIONAL OFFICE SINDH REGIONAL OFFICE NWFP REGIONAL OFFICE BALOCHISTAN Waheed Trade Complex, 1 st Floor, 36-Commercial Zone, Phase III, Sector XX, Khayaban-e-Iqbal, DHA Lahore. Tel: (042) 111-111-4 56 Fax: (042) 5896619, 5899756 helpdesk@smeda.org.pk 5 TH Floor, Bahria Complex II, M.T. Khan Road, Karachi. Tel: (021) 111-111-4 56 Fax: (021) 5610572 helpdesk-khi@smeda.org.pk Ground Floor State Life Building The Mall, Peshawar. Tel: (091) 9213046-47 Fax: (091) 286908 Helpdesk-pew@smeda.org.pk Bungalow No. 15-A Chaman Housing Scheme Airport Road, Quetta. Tel: (081) 831623, 831702 Fax: (081) 831922 helpdesk-qta@smeda.org.pk December, 2006   Pre-Feasibility Study Fast Food Restaurant PREF-11/December, 2006/ DISCLAIMER The purpose and scope of this information memorandum is to introduce the subject matter and provide a general idea and information on the said area. All the material included in this document is based on data/information gathered from various sources and is based on certain assumptions. Although, due care and diligence has been taken to compile this document, the contained information may vary due to any change in any of the concerned factors, and the actual results may differ substantially from the presented information. SMEDA does not assume any liability for any financial or other loss resulting from this memorandum in consequence of undertaking this activity. Therefore, the content of this memorandum should not be relied upon for making any decision, investment or otherwise. The prospective user of this memorandum is encouraged to carry out his/her own due diligence and gather any information he/she considers necessary for making an informed decision. The content of the information memorandum does not bind SMEDA in any legal or other form. DOCUMENT CONTROL Do cu m en t No . PR EF -1 1 R e v i s i o n 1 P r ep a r e d b y S M E D A - S i n dh Ap pr ove d by Pr ov in ci al Chi ef – Sin dh I s s u e D a t e D e c e m b e r , 2 0 0 6 I s s u e d b y L i b r a r y O f f i c e r   Pre-Feasibility Study Fast Food Restaurant PREF-11/December, 2006/ 1 1 P P R R O O J J E E C C T T P P R R O O F F I I L L E E 1 1 . . 1 1 P P u u r r p p o o s s e e o o f f t t h h e e D D o o c c u u m m e e n n t t s s This document is developed to provide the entrepreneur with potential investment opportunity in setting up and operating a medium sized fast food restaurant offering a variety of food items to the general public. This pre-feasibility gives an insight into various aspects of planning, setting up and operating a fast food restaurant for the general populace. The document is designed to provide relevant details (including technical) to facilitate the entrepreneur in making the decision by providing various technological as well as business alternatives. The document also allows flexibility to change various project parameters to suit the needs o f the entrepreneur. 1 1 . . 2 2 P P r r o o j j e e c c t t B B r r i i e e f f Fast food is food which is prepared and served quickly at outlets called fast-food restaurants. It is a multi-billion dollar industry which continues to grow rapidly in many countries. A fast-food restaurant is a restaurant characterized both by food which is supplied quickly after ordering, and by minimal service. The food in these restaurants is often cooked in bulk in advance and kept warm, or reheated to order. Many fast-food restaurants are part of restaurant chains or franchise operations, and standardized foodstuffs are shipped to each restaurant from central locations. There are also simpler fast-food outlets, such as stands or kiosks, which may or may not provide shelter or chairs for customers. Because the capital requirements to start a fast-food restaurant are relatively small, particularly in areas with non-existent or medium income population, small individually-owned fast-food restaurants have become common throughout Pakistan. Generally restaurants, where the customers sit down and have their food orders brought to them, are also considered fast food. 1 1 . . 3 3 O O p p p p o o r r t t u u n n i i t t y y R R a a t t i i o o n n a a l l e e The Fast Food Restaurant Market is a growing industry in Pakistan relying heavily on the changing lifestyle patterns, population growth of the target age group and the related increase in employment of women. With today&apos;s hectic lifestyles, time-saving products are increasingly in demand the most obvious being the fast food. The rate of growth in consumer expenditures on fast food has led most other segments of the food-away-from- home market for much of the last one decade. Demand for convenience has driven expenditures where people want quick and convenient meals; they do not want to spend a lot of time preparing meals, traveling to pick up meals, or waiting for meals in restaurants. As a result, consumers rely on fast food. Knowing this, fast food providers are coming up with new ways to market their products that save time for consumers. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
SMEDA Fast Food Restaurant
 Download or Print 439 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 04/10/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
