<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004936" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Over-the-Years-Our-Diets-Changed&amp;id=5970169" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="1" score="0.0013071896580091854" bingtitle="Over the Years Our Diets Changed - EzineArticles Submission ..." webtitle="Over the Years Our Diets Changed">
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>If you look into the window of a fast food restaurant on any given ... we used to enjoy as we sat down to the dinner table ... of vegetarian lasagna with garlic bread and a glass ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Health and Fitness » Nutrition Leslie M Collins 
 Basic Author |   7 Articles 
 Joined: February 21, 2011 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Over the Years Our Diets Changed

 By Leslie M Collins 
 
Many Americans, especially young Americans think that a perfect diet consists of two all beef patties, tomato, lettuce and cheese all on a sesame seed bun is the perfect diet for breakfast, lunch and dinner. Oh yes, don&apos;t forget the sugary 16 ounces of soda that are now super sized for one low price, all to wash down the patties.

Americans have gotten used to the fast food craze. If you look into the window of a fast food restaurant on any given morning or night, you will see young people, senior citizens, families, single people, children and adults alike all piled into a fast food restaurant. I ask, what has happened to our eating habits? Must we eat fast food? What happened to the home cooked meats, fruits, vegetables and desserts that we used to enjoy as we sat down to the dinner table in the kitchen with our families at our sides. Each person, at the table, enjoying a homemade meal topped off with ice cream or a slice of fruit. Has this gone by the wayside like many of the other things of yesteryear that are now just memories?

Our diets have changed to the two all beef patties with a sliver of tomato and a half of jar of mayo. What happened to the two glasses of water we used to drink? This too has become a twenty-four ounce of flavored soda, unfortunately. Diets are no longer an important issue to people because they are always on the run. This is one of the reasons why we are so fat. Instead of compromising our health with fast food, we need to take a look at the abundance of foods that we have here in America. We need to slow down and enjoy it.

With nutrition supposedly being of the utmost importance, we need to start acting like it. We need to consider breakfast as our most important meal of the day and use it to refuel with fresh fruits and grains as we go off on our busy day. We need to pack a lunch for our mid day meal. Probably, Grandma&apos;s homemade stew with a slice of cornbread and a fruit for dessert. Oh yes, don&apos;t forget your thermos of water. Many of us forget that water is life-sustaining and always manage to trade it in for flavored sodas. Our bodies need healthy food for nutrients and fresh water to sustain us. So I say to you, what is in your perfect diet? Could it be two &quot;all beef&quot; patties, mayo, cheese, lettuce on an &quot;all wheat&quot; bun and a sixteen ounce soda or a plate of vegetarian lasagna with garlic bread and a glass of red wine?

Stop stuffing your face with the beef patties and sodas and start on the road to a more healthy and nutritious diet. One that is right for you. A diet that includes nature&apos;s fruits and vegetables.
 
Information just like this will help you become fit http://rightdietplan.com/articles/the-right-diet-plan Also discover the perfect diet program http://rightdietplan.com/articles/secrets-to-lose-weight 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Leslie_M_Collins 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Health and Fitness: Nutrition 
 Leslie M Collins 
 Email Address: Subscribe Nutrition Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 How to Burn Excess Belly Fat and Get Perfect Abs The Pet Food Ingredient Game Ten Secrets to Frustration, Weight Loss and Yo-Yo Dieting! Weight Loss Myths Perpetuated By Multi-Billion Dollar Industries Proven Natural Weight Loss Remedy How to Lose Weight Sensibly 
 
Recent Articles

 Healing With Nutrition Sports Nutrition - The Day Before Competition Muscle Gain Nutrition With Unique Food Choices Game Day Nutrition - What Should Kids Eat? Vitamins and Minerals for Youth Athletes Abs of Steel - Here&apos;s a Quick Way If You Want to Work! 4 Week Focus on Weight Loss for Health The Stone Age Diet: Free of Gluten and Processed Foods Food Supplements - Boosting Your Nutritional Requirements Truth About Six Pack Abs Review 
 
Submitted On February 21, 2011. Viewed 16 times. Word count: 489.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Collins, Leslie M. &quot;Over the Years Our Diets Changed.&quot; Over the Years Our Diets Changed .
 21 Feb. 2011 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Over-­the-­Years-­Our-­Diets-­Changed&amp;id=5970169 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Collins, L. M. (2011, February 21). Over the Years Our Diets Changed .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Over-­the-­Years-­Our-­Diets-­Changed&amp;id=5970169 Chicago Style Citation: 
Collins, Leslie M. &quot;Over the Years Our Diets Changed.&quot; Over the Years Our Diets Changed EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Over-­the-­Years-­Our-­Diets-­Changed&amp;id=5970169 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
