<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004455" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20070727055034AAxvsUn" time="2012-07-12-20:53" support="10" score="0.012243345452968946" bingtitle="Red Robin--a sit-down restaurant or fast food restaurant? - Yahoo ..." webtitle="Red Robin--a sit-down restaurant or fast food restaurant? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>Red Robin--a sit-down restaurant or fast food restaurant? ... place where you go in and order at the counter ... Also they have a nice selection of adult beverages.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Other - Dining Out &gt; Resolved Question 
 117wstwd Member since: July 24, 2007 Total points: 2,365 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Red Robin--a sit-down restaurant or fast food restaurant?
 Is Red Robin a place where you go in and order at the counter and pick up your food at the counter, then take it to your seat, or are you seated by the hostess and have a waiter/waitress to take your order and bring your food? 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by AlloAllo Member since: July 07, 2006 Total points: 3,243 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 You are seated and they have wait-staff. It&apos;s a&quot;gourmet&quot;hamburger place! They do have good burgers. The best thing about them is the bottomless fries. You can keep asking and asking and they will bring you baskets of crisp, golden, yummy steak fries.

Oh, yeah...they have a bar, too. You could, of course, always get carry-out if you didn&apos;t want to eat in.

Thanks...now I might have to go there tonight for dinner! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Good answer 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (10)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by fugitive... Member since: May 02, 2007 Total points: 106 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 a little of both ur seated
and once u order u get
ur food pretty fast 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by nicole20... Member since: April 26, 2006 Total points: 744 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 it is a sit down restaurant but your food is usually served to you pretty quickly. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Mrs Apple Member since: May 05, 2006 Total points: 12,958 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It&apos;s a sit-down restaurant. You&apos;re greeted by a host/hostess who will take you to a table and you order from the waiter/waitress. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Thomas Member since: May 25, 2006 Total points: 6,576 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It is similar to places like Ruby Tuesdays, TGIFridays, and Chili&apos;s. I have to say, they have much better food though. The atmosphere at Red Robins is better too. I highly recommend going there to eat. The fries are really really good. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Dan S Member since: July 27, 2007 Total points: 3,238 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 its a sit down restaurant and have servers that scream over the little kids to take your order. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Alibaste... Member since: April 20, 2007 Total points: 820 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 At the place I went to in PA it was a sit down restaurant. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by the drizzle is a chick! Member since: July 03, 2007 Total points: 5,468 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 it&apos;s a great sit down place.. they have tons of different burgers, and chicken sandwiches that are amazingly good! my fave is the&quot;banzi burger&quot;it&apos;s marinated in teriaki seasoning, and has a grilled pinapple slice on it.. yummy! but they have other foods too, steaks, fish, pasta&apos;s.. i would reccomend it highly! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Latrese F Member since: June 27, 2007 Total points: 482 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Red Robin is a combination of a fast food and sit down resturant....
You sit down to eat your hambuger and bottomless fries or what ever else you like to order...
the food is in the same category of fast food, but a way better version...
they are quite tasty!! 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Maria W Member since: June 05, 2007 Total points: 1,378 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It&apos;s a sit-down restaurant with lots of different burgers and sandwiches. It&apos;s actually really good food. Also they have a nice selection of adult beverages. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by piratefa... Member since: July 23, 2007 Total points: 3,804 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Just started getting them in Western Pa. The 2 that I have been to have excellent service. It&apos;s a GREAT place to take kids! They have a reasonably priced menu and the decor is so interesting, lots of things to look at. And my son (the balloon freak) gets to choose a balloon from the dozens hanging from the ceiling as we leave. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Dining Out 

 Why do I get food poisoning from fast food places? My boss serves up old out of date food , what to do ? What do you usually get at Panera? Where to buy good cheesecake thats NOT from Cheesecake Factory? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Does Red Robin offer take out Do servers make more at high end restaurants or casual? This is my Red Robin question and warning to you not to go… how much does a server/waitress make at Red Robin in… What should we order at Red Robin? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
