<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004116" url="http://easyskinnylife.com/tag/skinny-picks/" time="2012-07-12-20:21" support="15" score="0.03742458942964328" bingtitle="Skinny Picks | Easy Skinny Life" webtitle="Skinny Picks | Easy Skinny Life">
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>After a glass of wine and a ton of coaxing, I walked into a fast food restaurant for ... could build anything!In looking around at the busy tables, I knew my order would ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content 
 Home About Kathy My Store Fanpage 
 
 Easy Skinny Life 
 Skip to content 
 Eating Rules Exercise Food Shopping Skinny Habits Recipes Restaurants 
 Reviews: Skinny Picks Survival Guide: Dining Out, Restaurants, Events, Family Gatherings 
 Skinny Observations Skinny Style 
 
Tag Archives: Skinny Picks 
 05 May 
 Eating Healthy at Bonefish Grill 
 What is healthy to eat Bonefish Grill?  First, the restaurant has the word “fish” in its name, so I knew there was hope.  (The Cheesecake Factory would cause me pause).  Of course, in any restaurant, even food that is healthy in its purest form can turn into a calorie and fat bomb depending on its preparation, additions of oil, butter, and sauces.Bonefish Grill does not offer calorie or nutritional information online for its entrees, so ask about the preparation.  All of the grilled white fish and shellfish options are ... Read More→ Restaurants , Reviews: Skinny Picks | 3 Comments 31 Aug 
 Healthy Eating at the Airport: Silver Diner 
 It&apos;s a week of impromptu Skinny Travels.  I packed a bag and grabbed a flight to New England this morning in order to celebrate the waning days of summer and taste some of the local favorite cuisine.First, I had to navigate my eating choices at the airport for an early breakfast.  My advice:  If you are in a hurry, grab a plain yogurt or refrigerated hard-boiled eggs and some fresh fruit.   However, if you have 10 to 15 minutes to spare, head directly to Silver ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks , Skinny Travels , Survival Guide: Dining Out, Restaurants, Events, Family Gatherings | 2 Comments 23 Aug 
 Skinny Picks: Eating Healthy at Chick-fil-A Fast Food Restaurant 
 The things I do for my loyal Easy Skinny Life readers!  After a glass of wine and a ton of coaxing, I walked into a fast food restaurant for the first time in ages to assess the healthiest options to eat at cult favorite Chick-fil-A, a fast food chain with a huge following.What&apos;s the healthiest entree item to eat at Chick-fil-A?Skinny Pick&apos;s Lesser of Evils:  Chargrilled Chicken Cool Wrap WITHOUT Ranch Dressing or Spicy DressingMulti-grain wrap with grilled chicken, lettuce, ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks | Comment 14 Aug 
 Skinny Travels: Eating Healthy at Greenman Juice Bar&amp;Bistro in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware 
 More Skinny Traveling!  Greenman Juice Bar&amp;Bistro is my favorite go-to place in Rehoboth Beach, Delaware to have an innovative and healthy meal at the beach.  Located just off the boardwalk, it is open for breakfast and lunch only.  I typically go for both!  Vegetarians will have a field day at this place, but carnivores are equally happy with its local meats.Skinny Pick for Breakfast:  Greenman Tofu ScrambleHash ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks , Skinny Travels | Comment 08 Aug 
 Skinny Sushi and Hidden Calories: Eating Healthy at Sushi Bars and Restaurants 
 Sushi isn&apos;t an everyday meal for me.  I know that healthy eaters around the world have consumed it forever, but it&apos;s not &quot;easy&quot; to determine calories, ingredients and portions unless you are skilled enough to prepare it yourself.  In fact, solving the mysteries of all of the sushi options, along with the varying ways chefs create them is quite exhausting.  I&apos;m lazy Skinny, so my meals are usually easy and fast to calculate.... Read More→ Eating Rules , Reviews: Skinny Picks | 2 Comments 03 Aug 
 Skinny Travels: Eating Healthy on the Ocean City Boardwalk 
 Along the East Coast, we have some fabulous boardwalks fronting the Atlantic Ocean, with the usual t-shirt shops, honky-tonk games and fun food.  Yet, the healthy meal choices are pretty limiting.On the boardwalk in Ocean City, Maryland, my family has shared the same tradition since I was a little girl.  We kick off our beach vacation with lunch at Tony’s Pizza with its famous oil-dripping gooey pizza, followed by a race down the boardwalk to Thrashers famous French fries, and a bonus stop to Dumser’s famous ice cream for the new generation ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks , Skinny Travels | 2 Comments 24 Jul 
 Skinny Review: Eating Healthy at Texas Roadhouse 
 Texas SteakhouseSkinny Pick:  6 oz Dallas Filet, ordered with:Two sides of Mixed Vegetables, no butter
Sweet Potato, ordered plain. It’s déjà vu all over again!  My visit with the relatives took me to yet another steakhouse, Texas Roadhouse, which was very similar to Outback Steakhouse.  After pouring over the menu and slabs of raw meat greeting me at the front entrance, it was obvious that the 6 oz filet mignon at about 500 calories or ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks | 1 Comment 15 Jul 
 Skinny Review: Healthy Eating at Bill Bateman’s Restaurant 
 Bill Bateman’s Restaurant, located Maryland and PennsylvaniaWhile this regional restaurant may be more known for its famous Buffalo wings, burgers and crab pretzels, it does offer some surprising Skinny Pick options in this loud and raucous neighborhood hangout.  Scanning the menu, I immediately noticed its Side Orders section offers a baked sweet potato and steamed broccoli.  Every day.  Heck, from that foundation of good vegetables, I could build anything!In looking around at the busy tables, I knew my order would stick out like a sore thumb ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks | Comment 13 Jul 
 Skinny Observations: The Mayor’s Lunch Pick at West End Grill 
 The Mayor&apos;s &quot;Skinny Pick&quot; for Lunch at West End Grill, Annapolis Maryland RestaurantMayor Josh Cohen of Annapolis, Maryland, is a very busy guy.  Read the papers.  It&apos;s one thing after another in Maryland&apos;s Capital City.  Yet, he&apos;s been reading the Easy Skinny Life blog and eating better these days.  This young Mayor needs as much energy and good nutrition as possible.Despite a very long council meeting and post-meetings last night, he started ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks , Skinny Observations | 1 Comment 06 Jul 
 Skinny Review: Eating Healthy at Outback Steakhouse 
 Outback SteakhouseSkinny Pick:  6 oz Victoria’s Filet, ordered with:One side of steamed broccoli, no butter
One extra side of mixed vegetables, no butter
Sweet potato, ordered plain. Surprised at my top Skinny Pick?  Hey, ... Read More→ Reviews: Skinny Picks | 3 Comments 02 Jul 
 Restaurant Reviews: My Top Skinny Picks 
 Reviews:  Skinny PicksIntroducing a new section up and running on this blog to provide my top, healthy and delicious pick at local and national restaurants!  Please post your favorite or your most challenging dining out places for consideration.Make most of your meals at home.  However, when you do dine out, your menu selections will help maintain an Easy Skinny Life or contribute to a hard, painful and unhealthy one.   The choice is an easy one to me! Reviews: Skinny Picks | 4 Comments 
 Subscribe to our Newsletter 
 
Categories

 Breakfast Recipes (7) Cardio Exercising Easy (1) Cocktail Recipes (2) Eating Rules (53) Exercise (5) Flexibility Training Easy (1) Food Shopping (19) Healing the Body, Anti-Inflammation, Anti-Aging Benefits (4) Healthy Super Foods (1) Lunch Recipes (17) Main Course Recipes (50) Recipes (64) Restaurants (3) Reviews: Skinny Picks (16) Side Dishes (6) Skin and Complexion Benefits (3) Skinny Habits (5) Skinny Observations (9) Skinny Style (3) Skinny Travels (6) Strength Training Easy (1) Superfood Spotlight of the Week (2) Survival Guide: Dining Out, Restaurants, Events, Family Gatherings (14) 
 
Recent Posts

 I Can’t Believe It’s Not Butter Spray. Don’t believe it! Naked Skinny Turkey Burger with Swiss Cheese Healthy Tuna Salad with Avocado, Goat Cheese and Beans One Pan Seared Tilapia, Broccoli and Red Skinned Potatoes Easy Skinny Grocery Shopping Rules to Live By Easy Skinny Steak Night Skinny Habits: Scales are the Solution, not the Problem! Skinny Halibut with Lemon Butter, Capers and Shallots Eating Healthy at Bonefish Grill It’s an Easy Skinny Life on Facebook Skinny Wild Salmon, Roasted Red Pepper, and Sweet Potato Salad Healthiest Sweeteners and Skinny Sweet Rules Skinny Superfood Avocado Indian Spiced Skinny Roasted Chickpeas and Vegetables Skinny Seafood Pasta and Vegetables Skinny Shrimp and Kiwi Salad Orchard Nuts: Eat Fat To Get Skinny Healthy Strawberry Avocado Salad with Stone Ground Mustard Garlic Dressing Herb-Crusted Pan Seared Basa Fish Eggs for a Skinny Life 
 
Search
 Search for: 
 
 
 
 © 2011 Easy Skinny Life - All Rights Reserved 
 
Warning: you are using an old version of
Internet Explorer. Please upgrade to IE 8 or later
for maximum site compatibility!
	</body>
</document>
