<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004975" url="http://tampabay.citysearch.com/profile/2710386/clearwater_fl/lenny_s_restaurant.html" time="2012-07-12-21:29" support="18" score="0.05339962160432184" bingtitle="Lenny&apos;s Restaurant - Clearwater, FL, 33765 - Citysearch" webtitle="Lenny&apos;s Restaurant - Clearwater, FL, 33765 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="146"/>
	<description>As hungry as you go in there, you may still find ... complain about the wait, head to a nearby fast food restaurant ... Pros: Extensive breakfast menu, cooked to order ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Tampa, FL Metro &gt; Clearwater &gt; Restaurants &gt; Lenny&apos;s Restaurant 
Lenny&apos;s Restaurant
 (727) 799-0402 
 21220 US Hwy 19 N , Clearwater , FL | Directions  
 33765 27.971001 -82.730100 View Website 
 Menu Share Save 
   Own this Business? Best of Citysearch Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 93 % 100 31 27 Votes Add a Photo Categories: Restaurants 
 View More 
 Payment Methods: MasterCard, Discover, Visa, American Express Restaurant Special Features: Brunch 
 View Less 
 Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (31) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Lenny&apos;s Restaurant 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Lenny&apos;s Restaurant
 Recommends AnnaElisabeth Joined 10 months ago 5.0 September 15, 2011 
 Lenny&apos;s Restaurant. Great food, atmosphere, and service.
 0 Heart Recommends PPHS84 Joined 2 years ago 5.0 September 23, 2010 
 BEST. I love Lenny&apos;s food !! Amazing relish tray with HOME MADE pickles!!! The best food in the Clearwater area. My entire family are regulars there! I wish I lived in Florida still so I could enjoy the food more regularly!!!! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend 10Reviews Joined 2 years ago 2.0 June 07, 2010 
 eat and leave. I have been going to lenny&apos;s since i lived in florida in 1990 Always experience the rush from the staff to get in and get out......and thats fine as I go there with that intention. Its not the place to go when you want to enjoy and relax.

Today the waitress was so rushed that when she got the order wrong she blamed me (I was ready to simply eat the food to make the waitress happy......however I just dont eat ham). The food she brought back was cold and .... :( not good at all. I was so disappointed. I could have opened a can of spagettios and had the same level of food.....bad unless your starving. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends waternwind Joined 3 years ago 5.0 November 23, 2009 
 5stars well deserved. It has all been said - Great Food - Good Service - Reasonable prices. I only wish they were open at 2 am for breakfast on the weekends.
 0 Heart Recommends LargoLaurie Joined 4 years ago 5.0 July 01, 2008 
 Philly/South Jersey memories and great food!. WARNING: Lenny&apos;s may be habit-forming! 

Great food at very good prices, served by a friendly staff in a place with personality... First, deciding what you&apos;re going to order is a challenge. The breakfast menu is extensive and intriguing, and as the servers walk by with hot high-piled plates for other diners, your eyes and nose will have you changing your mind a dozen times.

Second, you&apos;ll each too much. You&apos;ll start out with a danish basket, what many hotels and busy business people might call a&quot;continental breakfast.&quot;HA! At Lenny&apos;s this is just the&quot;Welcome, we&apos;re glad you&apos;re here&quot;intro to what&apos;s yet to come... the appetizer that helps keep you from chewing on the menu while decided what to order. As hungry as you go in there, you may still find yourself taking leftovers home after eating heartily.

Third, you&apos;ll become addicted. Whether a northeast transplant like me who enjoys a gastronomical trip down memory lane or someone who just likes a huge delicious breakfast served the way you want it, you&apos;ll go back again and again. Who else in the Tampa area knows how to serve up that scary Pennsylvania/South Jersey mystery meat scrapple extra crispy? Heck, what other area restaurant has even heard of scrapple? You&apos;ll make Lenny&apos;s a weekend family tradition. When a friend you haven&apos;t seen for a while suggests meeting somewhere for breakfast, you&apos;ll immediately think&quot;Lenny&apos;s.&quot;When you have family in town visiting, you&apos;ll consider Lenny&apos;s a must-do on their itinerary.

Lenny&apos;s can be pretty darn slammed, especially on weekends. Parking can be a challenge, and you&apos;ll probably have a wait. If you&apos;re not in a hurry, it&apos;s well worth the wait. Taking the family or a group of friends to this hometown favorite is an outing... an event... not just a place to grab food. If you&apos;re going to complain about the wait, head to a nearby fast food restaurant instead. It ain&apos;t the Ritz, but it&apos;s a heck of a lot more fun and filling! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 See more tips for Lenny&apos;s Restaurant 
 Write a Tip for Lenny&apos;s Restaurant 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 88 % Johnny&apos;s Italian Restau… 2907 State Rd 590 Ste 1 
 Clearwater, FL 
1.1 mi away 67 % Pattaya Thai Sushi Rest… 2794 Gulf To Bay Blvd 
 Clearwater, FL 
0.9 mi away Ruby Tuesdays 2710 Gulf To Bay Blvd 
 Clearwater, FL 
0.8 mi away 
 
Things to do near Lenny&apos;s Restaurant
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 Best of Citysearch 2009 Breakfast 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
