<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004050" url="http://krupsicecreammaker.org/best-krups-ice-cream-maker/rival-ice-cream-interesting-info/" time="2012-07-12-20:16" support="4" score="0.0061932109664782605" bingtitle="rival ice cream Interesting Info" webtitle="rival ice cream Interesting Info">
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000401" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>... with ice cream ... fast food restaurant chain Burger ... In order to appeal to as many demographic groups as possible and better compete with its fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Subscribe 
 
 Krups Ice Cream Maker 

Krups Ice Cream Makers
 
rival ice cream Interesting Info
 
If one has a good working knowledge of the physics involved in making ice cream, then every batch should come out great with this simple and basic machine.

The main thing to know is that SALT ADDED TO ICE ALWAYS RESULTS IN SUPER-COOLED WATER, approximately -15 degrees F., and super-cooled water will not freeze. However, the liquid inside the thin aluminum canister which is surrounded by the super-cooled water will begin to crystallize and freeze; It has no option but to do so under the laws of physics. The aluminum is a great conductor of heat, and all the heat from the liquid within it is pulled out into the salty super-cooled slush outside causing the salty slush to melt down even more. That’s a good sign, and that’s why you need to periodically add additional layers of ice and salt during the process!

Here’s the biggest trick to successful ice cream using this or any other machine. The liquid you want to turn into that sweet creamy treat needs to be around 40 degrees when you begin. In other words: refrigerator-cold. Doing so will shorten the processing time and assure good results with the least amount of ice and salt.

One other trick, which is high calorie/fat but it’s ice cream so hey, is to use as little milk as possible, instead using half and half and some heavy whipping cream. Milk produces ice milk not ice cream, and it has a sort of an ice-crystal texture…yuck. (Search for Alton Brown’s Chocolate Ice Cream recipe…it rocks)

I love my Rival $20 something dollar machine, and spending more on a fancy machine would be an unnecessary waste of money. It has 5 parts: a plastic bucket for the ice and salt, aluminum container for the cream, mixing paddle, lid and a motor unit. If it breaks, you end up with a bathroom size trash can and aluminum which can be recycled for cash!! It’s a green machine! Call Al Gore! 
 Brand NEW in Box Ice Cream Maker Rival Ice Cream Treate Shoppe Shop 
 
 US $47.99 
 Bid now | Buy it now | Add to watch list 
 History

Main article: History of Burger King

The predecessor to what is now the international fast food restaurant chain Burger King was founded in 1953 in Jacksonville, Florida as Insta-Burger King. The original founders and owners, Kieth J. Kramer and his wife’s uncle Matthew Burns, opened their first stores around a piece of equipment known as the Insta-Broiler. The Insta-Broiler oven proved so successful at cooking burgers, they required all of their franchises to carry the device. After the original company began to falter in 1959, it was purchased by the Miami, Florida franchisees James McLamore and David R. Edgerton who renamed the company Burger King. The duo ran the company as an independent entity for eight years, eventually expanding to over 250 location in the United States, when they sold it to the Pillsbury Company in 1967.

Under Pillsbury, the company underwent several attempts at reorganization or restructuring in the late 1970s and early 1980s. While these efforts were effective in the short term, many of them were eventually discarded resulting in Burger King falling into a fiscal slump that damaged financial performance of both Burger King and its parent. Poor operating performance and ineffectual leadership continued to bog the company down for many years, even after it was acquired in 1989 by the British alcoholic conglomerate Grand Metropolitan and its successor Diageo. Eventually, the institutional neglect of the brand by Diageo damaged the company to the point where major franchises were driven out of business and its total value was significantly decreased. Diageo eventually decided to divest itself of the money loosing chain and put the company up for sale in 2000.

In 2002, a troika of private equity firms led by TPG Capital, L.P with associates Bain Capital and Goldman Sachs Capital Partners agreed to purchase BK from Diageo for $1.5 billion (USD), with the sale becoming complete in December of that year. The new owners, through several new CEOs, have since moved to revitalize and reorganize the company, the first major move was to re-name the BK parent as Burger King Brands. The investment group initially planned to take BK public within the two years of the acquisition, however this action was delayed until 2006 due to several reasons. On 1 February 2006, it was announced that TPG planned to take Burger King public by issuing an Initial Public Offering (IPO). Between March 2004 and March 2009, the company experienced a score of consecutive profitable quarters that were credited with successfully re-energizing the company, however with the slowing of the economy during the financial crisis of 2007-2010 the company’s business has declined while its immediate competitions, McDonald’s, has grown.

Franchises

Main article: Burger King franchises

When Burger King Corporation began franchising in 1959, it relied on a regional franchising model where franchisees would purchase the right to open stores within a defined geographic region. These franchise agreements granted BKC very little oversight control over its franchisees and resulted in issues of product quality control, store image and design and operations procedures.

This model remained in place until 1978 when the company hired McDonald’s executive Donald N. Smith to help revamp the company. Smith initiated a restructuring of all future franchising agreements, disallowing new owners from living more than one hour from their restaurants, preventing corporations from owning franchises and prohibiting franchisees from operating other chains. This new policy effectively limited the size of franchisees and prevented larger franchises from challenging Burger King Corporation as Chart House had. Smith also sought to have BKC be the primary owner of new locations and rent or lease the restaurants to its franchises. This policy would allow the company to take over the operations of failing stores or evict those owners who would not conform to the company guidelines and policies. However, by 1988 BKC parent Pillsbury had relaxed many of Smith’s changes, scaled back on construction of new locations and stalling growth. Neglect of Burger King by new owner Grand Met, and its successor Diageo, further hurt the standing of the brand, causing yet more financial damage to BK franchises.

By 2001 and nearly eighteen years of stagnant growth, many of its franchises were in some sort of financial distress. The lack of growth severely impacted BKC’s largest franchise, the nearly 400 store AmeriKing; by 2001 the company, which until this point had been struggling under a nearly $300 million debt load and been shedding store across the US, was forced to enter Chapter 11 bankruptcy. The failure of AmeriKing deeply affected the value of the BKC, and put negotiations between Diaego and the TPC Capital-lead group on hold. The developments eventually forced Diaego to lower the total selling price of BKC by almost three quarters of a billion dollars. After the sale, newly appointed CEO Bradley Blum initiated a program to help the roughly 20% of its franchises, including its four largest, who were in financial distress, bankruptcy or had ceased operations altogether. Partnering with the California-based Trinity Capital, LLC, the company established the Franchisee Financial Restructuring Initiative, a program to address the financial issues facing BK’s financially distressed franchisees. The initiative was designed to assist franchisees in restructuring their businesses in order to meet financial obligations, focus on restaurant operational excellence, reinvest in their operations and return to profitability.

Individual owners also took advantage of the AmeriKing failure; one of BK’s regional owners, Miami-based Al Cabrera, purchased 130 stores located primarily in the Chicago and the upper mid-west region, from the failed company for a bargain basement price of $16 million, or approximately 88% of their original value. The new company, which started out as Core Value Partners and eventually became Heartland Foods, also purchased 120 additional stores from distressed owners and completely revamped them. The resulting purchases made Mr. Cabrerra BKB’s largest minority franchisee and Heartland one of BKH’s top franchises. By 2006, the company was valued at over $150 million, and was sold to New Yorkased GSO Capital Partners. Other purchasers included a three way group of NFL athletes Kevin Faulk, Marcus Allen and Michael Strahan who collectively purchased 17 stores in the cities of Norfolk and Richmond, Virginia; and Cincinnati-based franchisee Dave Devoy, who purchased 32 AmeriKing stores. After investing in new decor, equipment and staff retraining, many of the formerly failing stores have shown growth upwards of 20%.

Legal issues

Main article: Burger King legal issues

The Hoots’family Burger King restaurant in Mattoon, Illinois, one subject of major litigation by Burger King.

Burger King has been involved in several legal disputes and cases, as both plaintiff and defendant, in the years since its founding in 1954. Situations involving these many legal topics have affected almost every aspect of the company’s operations. Depending on the ownership and executive staff at the time of these incidents, the company’s responses to these challenges have ranged from a conciliatory dialog with its critics and litigants to a more aggressive opposition with questionable tactics and negative consequences. The company’s response to these various issues has drawn praise, scorn, and accusations of political appeasement from different parties over the years.

Controversies and disputes with groups such as People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals (PETA) over the welfare of animals, governmental and social agencies over health issues and compliance with nutritional labeling laws, and unions and trade groups over labor relations and laws. These situations have touched on legal and moral concepts such as animal rights, corporate responsibility, ethics, and social justice. While the majority of the disputes did not result in lawsuits, in many of the cases the situations raised legal questions, dealt with legal compliance, or resulted in legal remedies such as changes in contractual procedure or binding agreements between parties. The resolutions to these legal matters have often altered the way the company interacts and negotiates contracts with its suppliers and franchisees or how it does business with the public.

Further controversies have occurred during the company’s expansion in the Middle East. The opening of a Burger King location in the Israeli-occupied territories lead to a breach of contract dispute between Burger King and its Israeli franchise; the dispute eventually erupted into a geopolitical conflagration involving Muslim and Jewish groups on multiple continents over the application of and adherence to international law. The case eventually elicited reactions from the members of the 22-nation Arab League; the Islamic countries within the League made a joint threat to the company of legal sanctions including the revocation of Burger King’s business licenses within the member states’territories. A related issue involving members of the Islamic faith over the interpretation of the Muslim version of canon law, Shariah, regarding the promotional artwork on a dessert package in the United Kingdom raised issues of cultural sensitivity, and, with the former example, posed a larger question about the lengths that companies must go to insure the smooth operation of their businesses in the communities they serve.

A trademark dispute involving the owners of the identically named Burger King in Mattoon, Illinois led to a federal lawsuit; the case’s outcome helped define the scope of the Lanham act and trademark law in the United States. An existing trademark held by a shop of the same name in South Australia forced the company to change its name in Australia, while another state trademark in Texas forced the company to abandon its signature product, the Whopper, in several counties around San Antonio. Legal decisions from other suits have set contractual law precedents in regards to long-arm statutes, the limitations of franchise agreements, and ethical business practices; many of these decisions have helped define general business dealings that continue to shape the entire marketplace.

Charitable contributions and services

Burger King has two of its own in-house national charitable organizations and programs. One is the Have It Your Way Foundation, a U.S.-based non-profit, 501(c)(3) corporation with multiple focuses on hunger alleviation, disease prevention and community education through scholarship programs at colleges in the US. The other charitable organization is the McLamore Foundation, also a non-profit, 501(c)(3) corporation that provides scholarships to students in the US and its territories. Additionally, there is an optional literacy program that partners individual restaurants with community schools in the US.

In various regions across the United States, Burger King and its franchises have aligned themselves with several charitable organizations that support research and treatment of juvenile cancer. Each year these coalitions hold a fund raising drive called A Chance for Kids, in which Burger King restaurants sell lottery-style scratch cards for $1. Each card produces a winning prize that is usually a food or beverage product, but includes (rarer) items such as shopping sprees or trips. In the Northeast, BK has affiliated itself with the Major League Baseball team the Boston Red Sox and its charitable foundation, the Jimmy Fund. The group runs the contest in Boston. In the New York city area it operates the contest in association with the Burger King Children’s Charities of Metro New York and the New York Yankees. Funds raised in these areas go to support the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute located in Boston. In Nebraska, the company is affiliated with the Liz’s Legacy Cancer Fund BK Beat Cancer for Kids program at the UNMC Eppley Cancer Center at the University of Nebraska Medical Center in Omaha. In the Pittsburgh region it funded the establishment of the Burger King Cancer Caring Center, a support organization for the families and friends of cancer patients.

Products

Main article: Burger King products

The Whopper sandwich, Burger King’s signature product

When the company began, its menu consisted predominantly of hamburgers, French fries, soft drinks, and desserts. In 1957, BK added its signature item, the Whopper. This quarter pound hamburger was created by Burger King founders James McLamore and David Edgerton as a way to differentiate BK from other burger outlets at the time. The sandwich became famous enough that BK eventually adopted the motto“Home of the Whopper”.

One of Donald N. Smith’s first changes to the menu was the addition of the Burger King Specialty sandwich line in 1979, which significantly expanded the breadth of the BK menu with many non-hamburger sandwiches including new chicken and fish offerings. The new specialty sandwich line was one of the first attempts to target a specific demographic, in this case adults 18-34, members of which would be willing to spend more on a higher quality product. One of Smith’s other significant contribution to the menu was the addition of a breakfast product line, which until this time was not a market Burger King had entered. Besides the addition of the Croissan’Wich in 1983, the breakfast menu remained almost identical to the McDonald’s offerings until a menu revamp in 1985. This expansion introduced BK’s Am Express product line which added new products such as French toast sticks and Mini-muffins.

As the company expanded both inside and outside the US, it introduced localized versions of its products that conform to regional tastes and cultural or religious beliefs. International variations add ingredients such as teriyaki or beetroot and fried egg to the Whopper, beer in Germany, Italy and Spain, and halal or kosher products in the middle East and Israel. To generate additional sales, BK will occasionally introduce limited time offers (LTOs) that are versions of its core products or new products intended for either long or short term sales. Items such as the Texas Double Whopper and various sandwiches made with mushrooms and Swiss cheese have been rotated in and out of its menu for several years while products such as its 1993 offering, a Meatloaf Specialty Sandwich and limited table service along with special dinner platters, failed to generate interest and were discontinued.

A meal including small french fries, a Whopper, Jr., a drink, and packets of Heinz ketchup

In order to appeal to as many demographic groups as possible and better compete with its fast food restaurant competitor Wendy’s, Burger King added a multi-tiered value menu in 1993 with items priced at 99, $1.99 and $2.99 (USD). The project, called Operation Phoenix, was an attempt to add not only a value menu but a line of value meals. The tiered menu was replaced with a more standard value menu in 1998, while the value meals were separated into their own menu segment. This value menu featured seven products: Whopper Jr., 5 piece Chicken Tenders, a bacon cheeseburger, medium sized french fries, medium soft drink, medium onion rings and small shake. In 2002 and 2006, BK revamped its value menu adding and removing several different products such as chili and its Rodeo Cheeseburger. Many of these items have since been discontinued, modified or relegated to a regional menu option. To better appeal to a more adult palate and demographic, BK introduced several new products to its menu in 2003, including several new or revamped chicken products, a new salad line and its BK Joe brand of coffee. Some of the new products, including its Enormous Omelet Sandwich line and the BK Stacker line, brought negative attention due the large portion size, amounts of unhealthy fats and trans-fats. Many of these products feature higher quality ingredients like whole chicken breast, Angus beef, natural cheeses such as Cheddar and pepper jack. Again, not all these products, such as the BK Baguette line, have met corporate sales expectations.

Advertising

Main article: Burger King advertising

A Burger King advertisement on a bus stop in Seoul, South Korea.

Burger King has employed varied advertising programs, both successful and unsuccessful, since its foundation in 1954. During the 1970s, output included a memorable jingle, the inspiration for its current mascot the Burger King and several well known and parodied slogans such as Have it your way and It takes two hands to handle a Whopper. Burger King introduced the first attack ad in the fast food industry with the help of then unknown Sarah Michelle Gellar in 1981. The television spot, which claimed BK burgers were larger than competitor McDonald’s, so enraged executives at McDonald’s parent company, they sued all parties involved. Starting in the early 1980s and running through approximately 2001, BK engaged a series of ad agencies that produced many unsuccessful slogans and programs, including its biggest advertising flop Where’s Herb?.

Burger King was a pioneer in the advertising practice known as the product tie-in with a successful partnering with George Lucas’Lucasfilm, Ltd. to promote the 1977 film Star Wars in which BK sold a set of glasses featuring the main characters from the film. This promotion was one of the first in the fast food industry and set the pattern that continues to the present. BK’s early success in the field was overshadowed by a 1982 deal between McDonald’s and the Walt Disney Company to promote Disney’s animated films beginning in the mid 1980s and running through the early 1990s. In 1994 Disney switched from McDonald’s to Burger King, signing a ten film promotional contract which would include such top ten films as Aladdin (1992), Beauty and the Beast (1991), The Lion King (1994) and Toy Story (1995). A partnership in association rival ice cream with the Pokmon franchise at the height of its popularity in 1999 was one of the most successful in the industry, rivaled only by McDonald’s/Ty Beanie Babies cross-promotion in 19992000.

Shortly after the acquisition of Burger King by TPG Capital, L.P. in 2002, its newly hired CEO Bradley (Brad) Blum set about turning around fortunes of the company by initiating an overhaul its flailing advertising programs. One of the first moves by the company was to reinstate its famous Have it your way slogan as the corporate motto. BK handed the effort off to its new advertising agency, Miami-based Crispin Porter + Bogusky (abbreviated as CP+B). CP+B was known for having a hip, subversive tack when creating campaigns for its clients, exactly what BK was looking for. One of CP+B strategies was to revive the Burger King character used during BKs 1970s/1980s Burger King Kingdom children’s advertising campaign as a caricatured variation now simply called“the King”. The farcical nature of the Burger King centered advertisements inspired an internet meme where the King is photoshopped into unusual situations that are either comical or menacing, many times followed with the phrase Where is your God now?.

Additionally, CP+B created a series new characters like the Subservient Chicken and the faux nu metal band Coq Roq featured in a series of viral web-based advertisements on sites such as MySpace and various BK corporate pages to compliment the various television and print promotional campaigns. One of the more unique promotions that CP+B devised was the creation of a series of three advergames for the Xbox 360. Featuring company celebrity spokesman Brooke Burke, the games sold more than 2 million copies, placing them as one of the top selling games along with another Xbox 360 hit, Gears of War. These innovative ad campaigns, coupled with other new promotions and a series of new product introductions, drew considerable positive and negative attention to BK and helped TPG and its partners realize about $367 million in dividends.

Headquarters

Company headquarters in unincorporated Miami-Dade County, Florida

Burger King is headquartered in a nine-story office tower by Miami International Airport. Elaine Walker of the Miami Herald stated that the headquarters has a“Burger King”sign that drivers on Florida State Road 836“can’t miss.”In addition the chain planned to build a neon sign on the roof to advertise the brand to passengers landing at the airport. 130 employees began working at the Burger King headquarters on Monday July 8, 2002, with the remainder to move in phrases in August 2002. Prior to the moving to its current headquarters in 2002, Burger King had considered moving away from the Miami area; Miami-Dade County politicians and leaders lobbied against this, and Burger King stayed in the area.

The company’s previous headquarters were in a southern Dade County campus described by Walker as“sprawling”and“virtually hidden away.”The former headquarters were located in the Cutler census-designated place; since then the area incorporated into the Village of Palmetto Bay. The former Burger King headquarters as of 2007 houses rental offices for several companies.

By 2006 Burger King had announced that it planned to move its headquarters to a proposed office building in Coral Gables. By 2007 Burger King instead renewed the lease in its existing headquarters for 15 years. Burger King planned to consolidate employees working at an area near Miami International Airport and at a Dadeland Mall-area facility into the current headquarters by June of that year. Instead Bacardi USA leased the headquarter complex, a 15-story building.

International operations

Countries with Burger King restaurants

Key:

Red: Current BK countries

Orange: Former BK countries

Yellow: Hungry Jack’s countries

Burger King has a longstanding presence at U.S. Army and U.S. Air Force installations worldwide, dating back to the 1980s under a contract with Army and Air Force Exchange Service. Today, while other chains such as Taco Bell, Popeye’s, and Subway have a presence on military bases, virtually every major Army and Air Force installation hosts a BK restaurant.

Countries currently with Burger King locations

Afghanistan (Army and Air Force Exchange Service)

Andorra

Argentina

Austria

Australia (known as Hungry Jack’s)

Bangladesh

Bahamas

Bahrain

Bolivia

Brazil

Bulgaria

Canada

Colombia (Reentered March 2008)

Chile

Czech Republic

People’s Republic of China ()

Hong Kong ()

Costa Rica

Cyprus

Denmark

Dominican Republic

Ecuador

Egypt

El Salvador

Faroe Islands

Germany

Gibraltar

Guatemala

Guyana

Honduras

Hungary

India

Indonesia

Iraq (AAFES)

Ireland

Israel

Italy

Jamaica

Japan

Jordan

Kuwait

Lebanon

Malaysia

Malta

Mexico

Netherlands

Aruba

Netherlands Antilles

Curaao

Sint Maarten

New Zealand

Nicaragua

Norway

Oman

Panama

Paraguay

Peru

Philippines

Poland

Portugal (Franchised by Ibersol Group)

Romania

Russia (Franchised by Shokoladnitsa)

Moscow

Qatar

South Korea

Saudi Arabia ( )

Singapore

Spain

Saint Lucia

Sweden

Switzerland

Republic of China ()

Thailand

Trinidad and Tobago

Turkey

United Arab Emirates

United Kingdom

Cayman Islands

United States

Guam

Puerto Rico

Uruguay

Venezuela

Countries formerly with Burger King restaurants

Australia: Burger King branded restaurants operated 19972003 violating franchise agreements, sold and rebranded to Australian Burger King franchise Hungry Jack’s following legal action

Finland: Burger King operated in Helsinki for a short period in 1980s

France: Burger King decided to leave France in 1997 and closed their 39 French outlets in 1998

Greece: Burger King operated in Greece for a short period in the early 1990s

Ukraine: Burger King operated in Kiev for a short period in 2006.

United States Virgin Islands: Burger King left both St. Croix and St. Thomas in 1997

Iceland: Burger King has closed its doors on the 31st of December 2008. news link

See also

Florida portal

Companies portal

Food portal

Drink portal

Book:Burger King

Books are collections of articles which can be downloaded or ordered in print.

McDonald’s–Largest competitor in hamburger restaurants, third in fast food restaurants

Subway–Second largest competitor in fast food restaurants

Wendy’s–Third largest competitor in hamburger restaurants

Yum! Brands–Largest competitor in fast food restaurants

References

^ a b c Burger King Holdings (BKC) annual SEC income statement filing via Wikinvest

^ a b Burger King Holdings (BKC) annual SEC balance sheet filing via Wikinvest

^“Burger King Holdings Inc (BKC)”. Morningstar, Inc.. http://quote.morningstar.com/Quote/Quote.aspx?pgid=hetopquote&amp;ticker=BKC. Retrieved 2008-10-03.

^ a b BKC publication (October 2007).“BKC 2008 Annual Report”(PDF). Burger King Holdings. http://media.corporate-ir.net/media_files/irol/87/87140/BurgerKing_2008_AR_FINAL.pdf. Retrieved 2008-12-23.“11,550 Restaurants in 71 countries and territories”

^ Smith, Andrew F. (30 August 2006). Encyclopedia of junk food and fast food (1st ed.). Greenwood Publishing Group. pp. 2728. ISBN 0313335273. http://books.google.com/books?id=mYc4aw7tnekC&amp;pg=PA172&amp;lpg=PA172&amp;dq=In+1952,+Matthew+Burns+of+Long+Beach,+California,+invited+his+stepson,+Keith+G.+Cramer&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=pSgzQ49j8g&amp;sig=JDU82XU3jMgALQaPF1Kb9lQ7IIY&amp;hl=en&amp;ei=dAA2SvDyE5WJtgfXhNn4Dg&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;ct=result&amp;resnum=1. Retrieved 2009-06-14.

^ a b c John A. Jakle; Keith A. Sculle (27 March 2002). Fast Food (1st ed.). JHU Press. pp. 116119. ISBN 080186920X. http://books.google.com/books?id=0nYcgnWKWXgC&amp;printsec=frontcover. Retrieved 2009-06-15.

^ a b c Ester Reiter (March 1996). Making Fast Food: From the Frying Pan Into the Fryer, 2nd edition. McGill-Queen’s University Press. p. 64. ISBN 0773513876. http://books.google.com/books?id=oBj-sPpJDQcC&amp;pg=PA64&amp;lpg=PA64&amp;dq=donald+smith+burger+king&amp;source=web&amp;ots=FhXPdZvuKU&amp;sig=Oc4o4BHLk8esIyTgcjWHuSzdXKA&amp;hl=en. Retrieved 2008-04-06.“Burger King’s early franchising arrangements proved to be troublesome”

^ Siler, Julia Flynn (11 August 1988). The New York Times. http://www.nytimes.com/1988/08/11/business/business-people-deal-for-friendly-offers-official-chance-to-shine.html?pagewanted=1. Retrieved 25 January 2010.

^ a b c d FundingUniverse.com.“History of Burger King Corporation”. Answers.com. http://www.answers.com/topic/burger-king. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ Mark Trumbull (2006-11-13).“Are private buyouts good for the economy?”. Christian Science Monitor. http://www.csmonitor.com/2006/1113/p01s01-usec.html. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ Grace Wong (2006-05-12).“Burger King IPO set to fire up”. CNN Money. http://money.cnn.com/2006/05/12/markets/ipo/burger_king/index.htm. Retrieved 2007-09-30.

^ Julie Jargon (1 February 2010).“As Sales Drop, Burger King Draws Critics for Courting‘Super Fans”. Wall Street Journal. Yahoo.com. http://finance.yahoo.com/career-work/article/108728/burger-king-draws-critics. Retrieved 1 February 2010.

^ Eric N. Berg (1988-11-04).“Burger King’s Angry Franchises”. The New York Times. http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=940DE0DD1530F937A25752C1A96E948260&amp;sec=&amp;spon=&amp;pagewanted=print. Retrieved 2008-04-06.“The franchisees complain that, in recent years, the chain’s growth has come almost entirely from the franchisees, not from the corporation.”

^ a b Shelly Reese (2005-02-04).“It was broken, and new owner’s fixing it”. The Cincinnati Enquirer. http://www.boj.com/articles/franchise/burger_king_fixed.htm. Retrieved 2008-04-12.

^ Jo Napolitano (2002-12-22).“A Fighter for Burgers and Fries”. The New York Times. http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9C03E5D81E3DF931A15751C1A9649C8B63&amp;sec=&amp;spon=&amp;pagewanted=all. Retrieved 2008-04-06.“The AmeriKing bankruptcy has added uncertainty to the prospects for Burger King, which relies heavily on franchise owners of its restaurants.”

^ Phyllis Berman (2003-04-15).“Burger King’s Flame-Broiled Future”. Forbes Magazine. http://www.forbes.com/2003/04/15/cz_pb_0415burger.html. Retrieved 2006-04-06.“The all-cash deal was originally pegged at $2.2 billion but got negotiated down to just $1.5 billion.”

^ Elaine Walker (2002-01-03).“Burger King bolstering its many weak franchisees.”. Knight-Ridder. http://www.highbeam.com/doc/1G1-81297863.html. Retrieved 2008-04-06.

^ Burger King Holdings on Bison.com (2003-02-03).“Burger King Launches Franchisee Financial Restructuring Initiative”. Press release. http://www.bison.com/press_burgerking_02032003. Retrieved 2008-04-06.

^“BK franchisee-led group buys 131 AmeriKing units”. Nations Restaurant News. 2003-12-15. http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m3190/is_50_37/ai_111507745/. Retrieved 2008-04-12.

^“Major Burger King Franchisee To Sell 240 Restaurants”. The Miami Herald. 2006-12-17. http://franchise.business-opportunities.biz/2006/12/29/major-burger-king-franchisee-to-sell-240-restaurants/. Retrieved 2008-04-12.

^ Keith Reed (2007-08-17).“Faulk joins other black athletes to buy Burger King franchises”. The Boston Globe. http://www.boston.com/business/globe/articles/2007/08/17/faulk_joins_other_black_athletes_to_buy_burger_king_franchises/. Retrieved 2008-04-12.

^ Trish Hall (1991-08-08).“How Fat? Burger King to Post Answers”. The New York Times. http://query.nytimes.com/gst/fullpage.html?res=9D0CE6DA163CF93BA3575BC0A967958260&amp;scp=1&amp;sq=Burger Center for Science in the Public Interest&amp;st=cse. Retrieved 2008-05-30.“Executives of Burger King, based in Miami and owned by Grand Metropolitan P.L.C. of London, announced the plan yesterday after five months of discussion with New York [City]’s Consumer Affairs Commissioner, Mark Green.”

^ Amy Bennett Williams (2008-04-28).“Burger King gets farm workers petition; Daughter of Burger King VP says dad wrote anti-coalition postings”. The Fort Meyers News-Press. http://www.news-press.com/article/20080704/NEWS01/107040011/1014/business. Retrieved 2008-04-28.“At Senate hearings on farm conditions held by U.S. Sen. Bernie Sanders, I-Vt., earlier this month, Eric Schlosser, author of the best-selling“Fast Food Nation”, praised Yum! and McDonald’s for working with the coalition and urged Burger King to do the same.“The admirable behavior of these two industry giants makes the behavior of Burger King…seem completely unjustifiable.”&quot;

^ Amy Bennett Williams (2008-04-12).“Tomato pickers feeling spied on”. The Fort Meyers News-Press. http://www.news-press.com/article/20080704/NEWS01/107050001. Retrieved 2008-06-09.“In recent months, theye [the CIW and supporter Student/Farmworker Alliance] been vilified online and in e-mails that can be traced to the Miami headquarters of Burger King, a company that’s opposed the groups efforts.”

^ Elaine Walker (2008-05-18).“Burger King’s virtual missteps `a cautionary tale’”. The Miami Herald. http://bm.com/Newsroom/Lists/BMNews/DispForm.aspx?ID=3713&amp;nodename=B-M in the News&amp;subTitle=Burger King’s Virtual Missteps‘a Cautionary Tale’. Retrieved 2008-05-24.“The fast-food chain fired Grover and company spokesman Keva Silversmith last week for violating the company’s Code of Business Ethics and Conduct.”

^ Andrew Martin (2007-03-28).“Burger King Shifts Policy on Animals”. The New York Times. http://www.nytimes.com/2007/03/28/business/28burger.html. Retrieved 2008-03-09.“In what animal welfare advocates are describing as a“historic advance”, Burger King, the world’s second-largest hamburger chain, said yesterday that it would begin buying eggs and pork from suppliers that did not confine their animals in cages and crates.”

^ AP Wire (2007-03-28).“Burger King Offers Cage-Free Food.”. Fox News. http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,261903,00.html. Retrieved 2007-08-21.“”Suppliers will hopefully respond by producing more of these types of products”, [PETA spokesman Matt] Prescott said.”

^ James Joyner (2005-09-18).“Burger King Stops Selling Anti-Muslim Ice Cream”. Outside the Beltway. http://www.outsidethebeltway.com/archives/_burger_king_recalls_sacrilegious_desserts/. Retrieved 2008-06-04.“Burger King has stopped selling ice cream cones after a single idiot Muslim was offended by the shape of the swirl on the lid.”

^ Gale Group (2008-02-11).“PETA Praises Safeway for Adopting New Industry-Leading Animal Welfare Policies”. Business Wire. http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m0EIN/is_2008_Feb_11/ai_n24256165/. Retrieved 2008-03-09.“June 2001: Following PETA’s six-month“Murder King”campaign, Burger King agrees to adopt standards that are in some areas better than those adopted by McDonald’s.”

^ AP Wire (2007-05-17).“Burger King responds to trans-fat cooking oil suit”. CTV. http://www.ctv.ca/servlet/ArticleNews/story/CTVNews/20070517/burgerking_transfat_070517/20070517?hub=Health. Retrieved 2007-09-28.

^ a b Andrew Martin (2008-05-24).“Burger King Grants Raise to Pickers”. The New York Times. http://www.nytimes.com/2008/05/24/business/24farm.html?_r=1&amp;sq=Burger King Tomatoes&amp;st=nyt&amp;oref=slogin&amp;scp=1&amp;pagewanted=print. Retrieved 2008-05-24.“At a news conference on Capitol Hill, the hamburger chain, based in Miami, said it would pay tomato prices adequate to give workers a wage increase of 1.5 cents a pound.”

^ Julia Goldman (1999-09-01).“Dumping West Bank store puts Burger King in a pickle”. The Jewish News Weekly. Archived from the original on 2008-02-05. http://web.archive.org/web/20080205091033/http://www.jewishsf.com/content/2-0-/module/displaystory/story_id/11939/edition_id/230/format/html/displaystory.html. Retrieved 2007-10-01.“When the Burger King Corp. pulled its name from a franchise in the West Bank settlement of Ma’aleh Adumim on Thursday of last week, it claimed the reason was breach of contract.”

^ a b Israel Faxx news report (1999-08-30).“Jews Plan to Boycott Burger King.”. Israel Faxx. http://www.allbusiness.com/middle-east/israel/394208-1.html. Retrieved 2008-06-04.“The Zionist Organization of America is considering calling for a worldwide Jewish boycott against Burger King, to protest its surrender to Arab threats and the closure of its branch in Ma’aleh Adumim.”

^ a b Candice Williams (2007-07-07).“U.S. Muslims Call For Burger King Boycott.”. Israel Faxx. http://www.allbusiness.com/middle-east/israel/711850-1.html. Retrieved 2008-06-27.“A Washington-based Muslim group, American Muslims for Jerusalem, says it is calling on Muslims and Arabs to immediately boycott the fast food restaurant chain, Burger King, for a second time. In a news conference, the group says the Miami-based fast food…”

^ Megan Steintrager (2000-11-05).“Middle East Muddle”. Nations Restaurant News. http://www.allbusiness.com/retail-trade/eating-drinking-places/4284932-1.html. Retrieved 2008-06-24.“…and the Arab League has threatened to revoke contracts for 84 Burger Kings throughout the Middle East.”

^ John Innes (2005-09-07).“Burger King recalls’sacrilegious’desserts”. The Scotsman. http://news.scotsman.com/latestnews/Burger-King-recalls-sacrilegious-desserts.2662082.jp. Retrieved 2008-05-10.“The offending lid was spotted in a branch in Park Royal last week by business development manager Rashad Akhtar, 27, of High Wycombe.”

^ Edward Rothestien (2006-02-20).“History Illuminates the Rage of Muslims”. The New York Times. http://www.nytimes.com/2006/02/20/arts/20conn.html?scp=1&amp;sq=Burger+King+Islam+Ice+Cream&amp;st=nyt. Retrieved 2008-06-04.“Today’s Iconoclasts want to oppose all attempts to display forbidden images, whatever their provenance. And for a variety of reasons, many in the West readily defer. Last fall, for example, Burger King withdrew its ice cream from restaurants in Britain after receiving complaints from Muslims that the swirling illustration on the package resembled the name of Allah.”

^ John Jermaine (2003-11-20).“The burger king and queen of Mattoon”. The Illinois Times. http://www.illinoistimes.com/gyrobase/Content?oid=oid:2686. Retrieved 2007-09-26.

^ Restaurant Business News (2003-05-30).“Burger King Re-flags Australian Stores”. AllBusiness.com. http://www.allbusiness.com/retail-trade/eating-drinking-places/4275422-1.html. Retrieved 2007-09-29.“Hungry Jack’s was BK’s original franchisee in Australia, but the company could not use the Burger King name at the time because it was already trademarked.”

^ Rupert M. Barkoff (2005-01-25). Fundamentals of Franchising. American Bar Association. p. 23. ISBN 1590314093. http://books.google.com/books?id=eVmD3FAG3zgC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=Fundamentals+of+Franchising&amp;rview=1&amp;sig=ACfU3U2UKUN5gnUt4-cPAoDFwTLrGxClSA#PPR3,M1.

^“471 U.S. 462″. Findlaw. 1985-05-20. http://caselaw.lp.findlaw.com/scripts/getcase.pl?navby=CASE&amp;court=US&amp;vol=471&amp;page=462. Retrieved 2008-03-04.

^ Larry L. Teply; Ralph U. Whitten (2002). Cases, Text, and Problems on Civil Procedure. Denis F. McLaughlin. Wm. S. Hein Publishing. p. 244258. ISBN 0837737257. http://books.google.com/books?id=r7Psaabe_U8C&amp;pg=PA244&amp;lpg=PA244&amp;dq=Burger+King+v.+Rudzewicz&amp;source=web&amp;ots=gZD77z7Rok&amp;sig=RMA00heD0UxxajBgfKF8dzhh_zo&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;resnum=6&amp;ct=result#PPA245,M1.

^“the HIYW foundation”. Burger King Holdings. http://www.bk.com/companyinfo/community/hiywfoundation.aspx. Retrieved 2007-09-26.

^“the McLamore Foundation”. Burger King Holdings. http://www.bk.com/companyinfo/community/mclamore.aspx. Retrieved 2007-09-26.

^“Burger King A Chance for Kids”. The Jimmy Fund. 2007-07-01. http://www.jimmyfund.org/cor/special/burger/default.html. Retrieved 2007-09-28.

^“Burger King Children’s Charities of Metro New York to help Small Fries become Large Fries”. The Jimmy Fund. 2002-07-26. http://www.jimmyfund.org/abo/press/pressreleases/2002/072602b.asp. Retrieved 2008-03-29.

^“BK Beat Cancer for Kids”. University of Nebraska Medical Center. http://www.bkbeatcancerforkids.org/. Retrieved 2008-03-09.“The BK Beat Cancer for Kids Program was established through the generosity of Burger King Restaurants and is one of many outreach and fundraising programs benefiting Liz’s Legacy, the Fund to Advance Cancer Research at the UNMC Eppley Cancer Center.”

^“Burger King Cancer Caring Center”. http://www.cancercaring.org/aboutbkccc.html. Retrieved 2007-09-28.

^“the History of Burgers”. worldsgreatesthamburgers.com. http://www.worldsgreatesthamburgers.com/index/content/id/8. Retrieved 2008-03-28.“The Hungry Jacks“Aussie Burger”has tomato, lettuce, onion, cheese, bacon, beetroot, egg, ketchup and a meat patty.”

^“Prima-Agri to Produce Halal Beef for Regional Fast Food Chains”. The Halal Journal. 200-10-10. http://www.halaljournal.com/artman/publish_php/article_894.php. Retrieved 2007-10-01.

^ Zawya.com (2004-05-02).“Burger King UAE launches the king of all burgers across the UAE”. Press release. http://www.zawya.com/story.cfm/sidZAWYA20040802080316. Retrieved 2007-10-01.

^“The Kosher Whopper Boosts Burger Sales in Israel.”. AllBusinees.com. 2000-07-01. http://www.allbusiness.com/wholesale-trade/merchant-wholesalers-nondurable/621140-1.html. Retrieved 2007-10-01.

^ Glenn Collins (1997-08-28).“As Business Gets Lean, a Big King Dares Big Mac”. The New York Times. Archived from the original on 2007-10-30. http://web.archive.org/web/20071030031723/http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F50F14F83E550C7B8EDDA10894DF494D81. Retrieved 2007-08-21.

^“Burger King Debuts New 99‘Great Tastes’Menu”. Press release. 1998-03-17. http://www.prnewswire.com/cgi-bin/stories.pl?ACCT=104&amp;STORY=/www/story/3-16-98/435564&amp;EDATE=. Retrieved 2007-10-09.

^“Burger King promotes new menu”. South Florida Business Journal. 2002-09-12. http://www.bizjournals.com/southflorida/stories/2002/09/09/daily63.html. Retrieved 2007-10-09.

^ BKC publication (July 2007).“US Regional Menu Nutritional Brochure”(PDF). Burger King Holdings. http://www.bk.com/Nutrition/PDFs/regional_menu.pdf. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ Herb Weisbaum (2006-07-06).“Burger King Launches Line Of Jumbo High-Rise Burgers”. KOMO Radio (Seattle, WA). Archived from the original on 2008-02-06. http://web.archive.org/web/20080206123616/http://www.komoradio.com/news/archive/4191016.html. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ Bruce Horovitz (2005-05-03).“Burger King to offer whopper of a breakfast sandwich”. USA TODAY. http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2005-03-27-burger-king_x.htm. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ Heather Lalley (2005-09-06).“Word of the day: Meat’Normous”. The Spokesman Review (Spokane, WA). http://www.spokesmanreview.com/blogs/healthbeat/archive.asp?postID=761. Retrieved 2007-09-01.

^ The Gale Group (2004-08-04).“Chains beef up with Black Angus”. Nation’s Restaurant News. http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m3190/is_35_38/ai_n6189447/. Retrieved 2007-07-16.

^ Kevin Newcomb (2004-10-07).“Burger King’s Back With New Buzz”. ClickZ.com. http://www.clickz.com/3404771. Retrieved 2007-06-10.

^ a b Bruce Horovitz (2004-03-22).“Burger King zaps menu, image”. USA Today. http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2004-03-21-burgerking_x.htm. Retrieved 2007-09-26.

^ J. Jonathan Gabay (October 2006). Gabay’s Copywriters’Compendium. Butterworth-Heinemann. p. 582. ISBN 9780750683203. http://books.google.com/books?id=emVzMXpBUoIC&amp;pg=PT582&amp;lpg=PT582&amp;dq=two+hands+to+hold+a+whopper&amp;source=web&amp;ots=RhYRX3HvwD&amp;sig=asdTJpFqWxkBe6WAzr7Kw2DOl70&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;resnum=10&amp;ct=result. Retrieved 2008-12-04.

^ BKC publication (2007-03-12).“Marketing and Advertising History”. Burger King Holdings. http://www.bk.com/companyinfo/content/corporation/history.html. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ Shep Hyken (2006-05-26).“Customer service and more”. BlogSpot. http://shephyken.blogspot.com/2006/05/hold-pickles-hold-lettuce-special.html. Retrieved 2007-09-26.

^“Sarah Michelle Gellar”. NNDB.com. http://www.nndb.com/people/511/000023442/. Retrieved 2007-10-02.

^“Herb Comes Out of Hiding”. Time Magazine. 1986-02-03. http://www.time.com/time/magazine/printout/0,8816,960538,00.html. Retrieved 2004-10-24.

^ Mark Schoifet (1986-01-01).“Herb falls flat, but Wendy’s breaks another winner”. Nation’s Restaurant News. http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m3190/is_v20/ai_4083228/. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^“Burger King Corporation, Turnaround under Grand Met in the 1990s”. FundingUniverse.com. http://www.fundinguniverse.com/company-histories/Burger-King-Corporation-Company-History.html. Retrieved 2007-11-26.

^ Jason Kandel (1999-11-12).”“Kids swarm Burger King as Pokmon-mania strikes”. Los Angeles Daily News. http://www.thefreelibrary.com/KIDS+SWARM+BURGER+KING+AS+POKEMON-MANIA+STRIKES.(News)(Statistical…-a083629023″. Retrieved 2007-12-02.

^“Burger King Corporation Selects Crispin Porter + Bogusky As Lead Creative Advertising Agency”. HispanicBusiness.com. 2006-01-23. Archived from the original on 2008-01-21. http://web.archive.org/web/20080121215651/http://www.hispanicbusiness.com/news/newsbyid.asp?id=14482.

^“Burger King in MySpace campaign”. Mad.co.uk. 2006-05-13. http://www.mad.co.uk/Main/Home/Articles/be50c1fbeab44225a611af5edb1d4ae7/Burger-King-in-MySpace-campaign.html. Retrieved 2007-08-27.

^ Peter Delegge (2005-07-31).“Burger King Goes Tasteless”. MarketingToday.com. http://marketingtoday.blogspot.com/2005/07/burger-king-goes-tasteless.html. Retrieved 2007-08-25.

^ Robyn Tippins (2006-08-03).“Burger King’s Table Guests”. AllBusiness.com. http://www.allbusiness.com/marketing-advertising/advertising/3877633-1.html. Retrieved 2007-08-25.

^ Coola (2006-12-21).“More than 2 Million Games Sold Nationwide…”. XBox365.com. http://www.xbox365.com/news.cgi?id=GGHHHLHurH12210217. Retrieved 2007-10-27.

^“CP+B website, ://Work section.”. Crispin Porter + Bogusky. http://www.cpbgroup.com/. Retrieved 2007-10-24.

^ B.L. Ochman (2004-04-12).“Burger King Has Fun With Subservient Chicken Viral Campaign”. http://www.whatsnextblog.com/archives/2004/04/burger_king_has_fun_with_subse.asp. Retrieved 2007-08-25.

^ Evelyn Nussenbaum (2007-04-23).“Is Burger King Perverting Children?”. Madisdon Avenue*West. Archived from the original on 2007-10-29. http://web.archive.org/web/20071029201343/http://blogs.business2.com/madisonavenuewest/2007/04/is_burger_king_.html. Retrieved 2007-08-25.

^“We’re Listening”. Burger King. http://www.bk.com/companyinfo/content/contactus.html. Retrieved January 31, 2009.

^ a b Walker, Elaine. (July 9, 2002).“Burger King Begins Switch to New Headquarters in Miami.”. Miami Herald. http://www.accessmylibrary.com/coms2/summary_0286-8831811_ITM. Retrieved August 28, 2009.

^“Home Page”. Burger King. http://web.archive.org/web/19970415114954/http://www.burgerking.com/. Retrieved October 2, 2009.

^“Cutler CDP, Florida”. U.S. Census Bureau. http://factfinder.census.gov/servlet/MapItDrawServlet?geo_id=16000US1215962&amp;_bucket_id=50&amp;tree_id=420&amp;context=saff&amp;_lang=en&amp;_sse=on. Retrieved October 2, 2009.

^“About our village”. Village of Palmetto Bay. http://www.palmettobay-fl.gov/about.htm. Retrieved October 2, 2009.

^ a b“Bacardi U.S.A. to take over BK’s planned Coral Gables headquarters”. South Florida Business Journal. Tuesday. May 8, 2007. http://southflorida.bizjournals.com/southflorida/stories/2007/05/07/daily8.html#. Retrieved October 2, 2009.

^ Beaird, Daniel. (August 2006).“OFFICE MARKET UPDATE Vacancies drop as job growth remains steady.”. Southeast Real Estate Business. http://southeastrebusiness.com/articles/AUG06/cover2.html. Retrieved October 2, 2009.

External links

Wikimedia Commons has media related to: Burger King

Official site

Burger King News

How many calories does Burger King food have?

Yahoo! Burger King Corporation Company Profile at Yahoo! Finance

Burger King Corporation Company Profile at Hoovers.com

v  d  e

Burger King

History   Advertising  Advertising Programs   Franchises   Legal issues   Products

People

Brad Blum  Greg Brenneman  Norman E. Brinker   Jeff Campbell  John W. Chidsey  Jack Cowin  David Edgerton  James McLamore  Donald N. Smith

Product

list

Beef

Angus or Steakhouse burger  Big King  BK Stacker  Rodeo Cheeseburger  Whopper  BK XXL

Chicken

BK Chicken Fries  BK Chicken Tenders  Original Chicken  TenderCrisp  TenderGrill  BK Crown Jewels line  BK Baguette line  Chick’n Crisp

Other

BK Big Fish  BK Dinner Baskets   BK Veggie  Spicy Bean Burger  Croissan’Wich  Enormous Omelet

Advertising

programs

Campaigns

Coq Roq  The Subservient Chicken  Ugoff  The Burger King  The Whopperettes  The Whoppers  Where’s Herb?  BK Tee Vee  Burger King Kingdom  Sneak King  Big Bumpin’PocketBike Racer

Sponsorships

Burger King Stunners  Burger King Whoppers  Tony Stewart (NASCAR)

Related subjects

Burger Wars  Fast food advertising

Franchisees&amp;

related topics

Army and Air Force Exchange Service  AmRest  Beurger King Muslim  BK Whopper Bar  Burger King (Mattoon, Illinois)  Carrols Corporation  Simonds Farsons Cisk  Heartland Foods  Hungry Jack’s  Olayan Group  Wimpy

Legal

cases

Burger King Corporation v Hungry Jack’s  Burger King v. Rudzewicz  Burger King Pokmon container recall

Nutrition

USA (regional  product ingredients  low calorie data  low carb data  eating strategy data)  Australia (Hungry Jack’s)  Brazil  Canada  New Zealand

Annual revenue  $2.05 billion USD (2006)  Employees 340,000 (2005)  Stock symbol NYSE: BKC  Website burgerking.com

v  d  e

Fast food restaurant chains in the United States

Hamburger

A&amp;W  Arctic Circle  Big Boy  Burger King  Burgerville  Carl’s Jr.  Checkers/Rally’s  Cook Out  Culver’s  Fatburger  Five Guys  Hardee’s  In-N-Out Burger  Jack in the Box  Johnny Rockets  Krystal  Maid-Rite  McDonald’s  Nation’s Giant Hamburgers  Roy Rogers  Sonic Drive-In  Steak n Shake  Tommy’s  Wendy’s  Whataburger  White Castle  Winstead’s  Zippy’s

Pizza

Boston Pizza  CiCi’s Pizza  Domino’s  Donatos Pizza  Hungry Howie’s Pizza  Little Caesars  Mazzio’s  Papa Gino’s  Papa John’s  Peter Piper Pizza  Pizza Hut  Pizzeria Regina  Rocky Rococo  Round Table Pizza  Sal’s Pizza  Sbarro  Shakey’s Pizza

Chicken

Bojangles’Famous Chicken‘n Biscuits  Boston Market  Brown’s  Chick-fil-A  Chicken Express  Church’s Chicken  El Pollo Loco  Kentucky Fried Chicken  Pollo Tropical  Popeyes  Raising Cane’s  Zaxby’s

Asian-Pacific foods

Jollibee (Filipino)  L&amp;L Hawaiian Barbecue  Lee’s Sandwiches (Vietnamese)  Manchu Wok (Chinese)  Panda Express (Chinese)  Pick Up Stix (Chinese)  Sarku Japan (Japanese)  Yoshinoya (Japanese)

Ice cream

Baskin-Robbins  Ben&amp;Jerry’s  Braum’s  Brigham’s Ice Cream  Bruster’s  Carvel  Cold Stone Creamery  Culver’s  Dairy Queen  Dippin’Dots  Friendly’s  Fosters Freeze  Hagen-Dazs  Marble Slab Creamery  Newport Creamery  Tastee-Freez

Frozen yogurt

Pinkberry  Red Mango  TCBY  Yogen Frz

Sandwich

Arby’s  Blimpie  Cos  D’Angelo Sandwich Shops  Firehouse Subs  Hogi Yogi  Jason’s Deli  Jersey Mike’s Subs  Jimmy John’s  Kelly’s Roast Beef  Milio’s Sandwiches  Panera Bread  Potbelly Sandwich Works  Quiznos  Rax Roast Beef  Schlotzsky’s  Subway  Tropical Smoothie Cafe  Tubby’s  Which Wich?

Seafood

Arthur Treacher’s  Captain D’s  Ivar’s  Long John Silver’s

Hot dog

James Coney Island  Hot Dog on a Stick  Nathan’s Famous  Portillo’s  Wienerschnitzel

Mexican-style food

Baja Fresh  Boloco  Cafe Rio  California Tortilla  Chipotle Mexican Grill  Del Taco  Freebirds World Burrito  Mighty Taco  Moe’s Southwest Grill  Qdoba Mexican Grill  Rubio’s Fresh Mexican Grill  Taco Bell  Taco Bueno  Taco Cabana  Taco John’s  Taco Mayo  Taco Tico  Taco Time

Baked goods

Au Bon Pain  Auntie Anne’s  Bruegger’s  Cinnabon  Dunkin’Donuts  Einstein Bros. Bagels  Krispy Kreme  Mrs. Field’s Cookies  Pretzel Time  Shipley Do-Nuts  T.J. Cinnamons  Tim Hortons  Winchell’s Donuts

Beverages

Caribou Coffee  The Coffee Bean&amp;Tea Leaf  Coffee Beanery  Dunn Bros  Jamba Juice  Orange Julius  Peet’s Coffee&amp;Tea  Planet Smoothie  Seattle’s Best Coffee  Smoothie King  Starbucks  Tully’s Coffee   Biggby Coffee

Defunct

Burger Chef  Carrols  Druther’s  Gino’s Hamburgers  Naugles  Red Barn  Sandy’s

v  d  e

Food chains in the United Kingdom

Coffeehouse:

AMT Coffee  Caff Nero  Caff Ritazza  Coffee Republic  Costa Coffee  Gloria Jean’s Coffees  Starbucks

Fast food restaurants:

Bagel Nash  Baskin-Robbins  Burger King  Chicken Cottage  Dixy Chicken  Domino’s Pizza  Favorite Chicken  KFC  Krispy Kreme  Little Chef  McDonald’s  Millie’s Cookies  Papa John’s Pizza  Pizza Hut  Sbarro   Shakeaway  Spudulike  Wimpy  Yogen Frz

Casual dining:

Aberdeen Angus Steak Houses  Beefeater  Bella Italia  Brewers Fayre  Caf Rouge  Carluccio’s  Chiquito  Damon’s  Fine Burger Company  Frankie&amp;Benny’s  Gourmet Burger Kitchen  Hard Rock Cafe  Harry Ramsden’s  Harvester  Hooters  Hungry Horse  Loch Fyne  Nando’s  Outback Steakhouse  PizzaExpress  Planet Hollywood  Prezzo  Rainforest Cafe  Romano’s Macaroni Grill  Strada  Taybarns  T.G.I. Friday’s  Wagamama  YO! Sushi  Zizzi

Sandwich shops:

Bakers Oven  EAT.  Greggs  O’Briens  Pret A Manger  Quiznos  Sayers   Subway  Upper Crust

Pub chains:

All Bar One  Firkin Brewery  Scream Pubs  Slug and Lettuce  Walkabout  Wetherspoons  Yates’s

Former chains:

ABC  Arby’s  A&amp;W Restaurants  Berni Inn  Benjys  Blimpie  Chili’s  Dunkin’Donuts  Happy Eater  Long John Silver’s  Lyons Corner Houses  Pasta Hut  Popeye’s  Quick  Schlotzsky’s  Taco Bell  Wendy’s

v  d  e

Restaurant chains in Ireland

Fast-food restaurants

Abrakebabra  Apache Pizza  Burger King  Domino’s Pizza  Four Star Pizza  KFC  McDonald’s  Supermac’s  Wimpy

Casual dining restaurants

Captain America’s  Eddie Rocket’s  Hard Rock Cafe  Harry Ramsden’s  Metzo  Pizza Hut  Spur Steakhouse  T.G.I. Friday’s

Categories: Companies listed on the New York Stock Exchange | Burger King | Bain Capital companies | Companies based in Miami-Dade County, Florida | Companies established in 1954 | Fast food | Fast-food chains of Canada | Fast-food chains of the United States | Fast-food franchises | Fast-food hamburger restaurants | Multinational food companies | Restaurant chains in the United States | Texas Pacific Group companiesHidden categories: Wikipedia semi-protected pages 
 
 White Mountain F69204-X 4-Quart Electric Ice Cream Freezer 
 Rating: 
 USD $172.45 
 Order Now White Mountain F69206-X 6-Quart Electric Ice Cream Freezer 
 Rating: 
 USD $169.49 
 Order Now 

 Nestle Scholler relaunches Movenpick in bid to gain share on rival Langnese.(Ice Cream Scoops): An article from: Quick Frozen Foods International 
 Rating: 
 USD $5.95 
 Order Now The Ultimate Ice Cream Maker Recipes 
 Rating: 
 
 Order Now 

 Rival 8550-X 5-Quart Wooden Electric Ice Cream Maker 
 Rating: 
 USD $199.99 
 Order Now
	</body>
</document>
