<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004650" url="http://www.whec.com/news/stories/s2290640.shtml?cat=565" time="2012-07-12-21:09" support="1" score="0.00017840738860339287" bingtitle="New ketchup packets coming to a fast-food restaurant near you ..." webtitle="New ketchup packets coming to a fast-food restaurant near you
 | www.WHEC.com">
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>New ketchup packets coming to a fast-food restaurant near you ... Macedon Police: Man violates order of ... charged in deadly Grape Street fire expected in ...</description>
	<body>
		Mobile Weblinks Messenger Post RBJ What&apos;s on NBC MeTV Social Media Email Alerts Contact Red Cross 
 
 
 
 
 NEWS DECISION 2012 WEATHER CLOSINGS TRAFFIC SPORTS COMMUNITY ABOUT OLYMPICS EVENTS 
 
New ketchup packets coming to a fast-food restaurant near you

Posted at: 09/19/2011 2:30 PM

 A new kind of ketchup packet is coming to a fast-food restaurant near you.

The new Heinz&quot;Dip and Squeeze&quot;packets will begin replacing the traditional rectangular ketchup packets at Wendy’s, Chick-fil-A and Dairy Queen restaurants. McDonald&apos;s and Burger King are testing the packets.

Just as the name says, you can dip for fries or squeeze for extra ketchup on your burger.

The red, bottle-shaped packets hold three times as much ketchup as traditional packets.

For more Rochester, N.Y. news go to our website www.whec.com.

 Print Story 
 
 
Local News

 Greece Planning Board approves redevelopment at Greece Ridge Mall Man charged with shooting at Tonawanda Indian Reservation It must be some parade Police make an arrest in cold case murder from 1980 Mayor Richards declares heat emergency Friday Cocktails can prevent bone loss Senate committee to review nomination of Monroe County Court Judge Name of fallen marine can be displayed outside Hornell Post Office 
 

 
 
Site Index

 
 NEWS Local ROC City I-Team 10 National Health Tech Business Strange Video 
 
 DECISION 2012 Decision 2012 News Political Blog Candidates Ask Your Questions Social Media NBC Political Coverage RNC DNC 
 
 WEATHER Download Our iPhone App Current Temp Forecast Doppler Radar Severe Weather Closings Weather Cameras Air Quality Weather Photos 
 
 CLOSINGS Current Closings Get Alerts Road Conditions 
 
 TRAFFIC Live Traffic Gas Prices 911 Accident Report DOT Road Work DOT Traffic Map Airport Departures Airport Arrivals 
 
 SPORTS Local Sports High School Sports Scholar Athlete Sports Photos 2012 Summer Olympics Amerks Knighthawks Red Wings 
 
 COMMUNITY Events Do The Right Thing ESL Jefferson Awards Pet of the Week Senior Life 10 Country Mr. Food Red Cross 
 
 ABOUT About Us Advertising Children Jobs News Team Public File | EEO Closed Caption Privacy Policy Terms of Use
	</body>
</document>
