<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004216" url="http://imagebuilderscolorado.com/commercial.html" time="2012-07-12-20:27" support="1" score="0.001426317801558553" bingtitle="Image Builders - Denver, Colorado" webtitle="Image Builders - Denver, Colorado">
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>new reception areas and desk; new eating areas; new flat ... as well as an efficiently designed take-out counter. ... including the addition of a new entry and fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Denver Uptown is a development located within walking distance of downtown Denver. Retail shops comprise the first story of the four-square block urban development and 700 apartments occupy the upper stories. Image Builders completed multiple tenant improvement projects for retailers including a coffee shop, a wine store, a flower shop, a DVD shop, a dry cleaners, and a chiropractic clinic. These interior views of a gourmet coffee shop, illustrate elegant details such as stained concrete floors, open grid ceilings, dcor lighting and a gas fire place. The interior design demands impeccable workmanship which is a salient feature of Image Builders&apos; project completion. As with all of its projects, Image Builders worked hand-in-hand with the owners of Above the Rim Fine Wines to insure a creative and innovative interior design that maximizes tenant objectives such as customer traffic flow and product display and storage. 
This post tension concrete building features enclosed parking on the ground level, and 10 luxury condominiums on the six upper 
 floors. The post tension concrete structure allows for maximum interior space planning.

Eight of the units are 2250 sq. ft. each and the two penthouse units are 4500 sq. ft. with a rooftop garden and spa. 
 The security entry, fully sprinkled building with smoke and fire detection insures optimal owner safety. Country club finishes include bamboo floors, granite slab counter tops in the kitchens, stainless steel, gas appliances, 91/2 ft. ceilings, exquisite workmanship trim and finishes, and all ceramic tiled bathrooms. &quot;These are the finest built, loveliest luxury units in the City of Denver.&quot;

Christina Lammerman, Gerretson Realty 
 
Image Builders was selected as the exclusive contractor for the renovation of seven Marriott TownePlace Suites in the Denver and Colorado Springs metro area. 
 Image Builders assisted the owners in the revision of floor plans for existing Marriott Lobbies 
 in order to add Market Centers and new Business Centers to each of the existing hotels. 
 The renovations included:
 new reception areas and desk new eating areas new flat screen televisions new finishes from carpet to compact fluorescent lighting 
 
 
Studio, one and two bedroom units complete with kitchens and fireplaces are fully furnished for 
 the comfort of the business traveler. Image Builders&apos; expert workmanship turns an economical 
 environment into a luxurious experience.

This Marriott Residence Inn also features a swimming pool, exercise room and hospitality suite. 
This motel in central Colorado includes an indoor, Olympic-size swimming pool, spa, exercise 
 room and conference room. The expansive lobby area is of southwest design with a large 
 fireplace built of native river-rock. The exterior of the building is also wainscoted with 
 river-rock. 
Image Builders turned several office suites in a strip mall into this popular barbeque 
 restaurant in Metro Denver in a record 45 days. The restaurant features a large, festive 
 seating area as well as an efficiently designed take-out counter. ADA bathrooms were included 
 in the design. The kitchen features a Southern Pride &quot;real wood&quot; smoker which cooks/smokes 750 lbs of meat at 
 a time, a sophisticated &quot;balanced&quot; HVAC and exhaust system, walk in cooler and freezer, and all 
 other commercial kitchen appliances. The design utilized newer construction techniques that met 
 sanitary standards, but kept costs low. New ADA compliant bathrooms were included in the design 
 and construction. 
This modern, hip Wine Bar was previously a used bookstore. Image Builders worked hand in hand with the owners of the Paris on the Platte Coffee Shop to design and build the spacious Wine Bar. The cosmopolitan bar features a large selection of fine wines, a full bar and Mediterranean menu. 
This free standing, 6500 sq. ft. restaurant with 250 person occupancy contains a retail-curio 
 shop and a conference room. Its stainless commercial kitchen is of the optimal design to serve 
 the large seating capacity. 
 
Image Builders completed the total renovation of 37 stores. This fast-track project included 
 quarry tile floors, new interior dcor and layout, and ADA-compliant restrooms. 
Image Builders created a new, high-tech automotive center from an existing furniture store at 
 the end of a retail mall. The automotive center features 9 bays which required us to add 
 overhead doors into an existing solid masonary wall. 
Image Builders completed this total store renovation, including the addition of a new entry 
 and fast food restaurant, in record time. The store had sales increases even during the 
 renovation project because Image Builders crafted the construction schedule to meet the 
 client&apos;s retail demands. 
 
The Town of Alma (Elevation 10,578) Colorado, highest incorporated town in the United States, 
 chose Image Builders to perform the historical renovation of the Town&apos;s Community Church in 
 compliance with the strict parameters of the State of Colorado&apos;s Historical Society. The Town will use the renovated church as a community center. Image Builders performed a 
 complete renovation of the church while maintaining the historical integrity of the building. The renovations were completed within the confines of the original, historical floor plan and 
 included:
 underpinning of foundation strengthening of roof framing and tuck pointing of the church restoration of the original windows addition of new hydronic (in floor) heat system ADA compliant bathroom new and modern kitchen and new drywall and paint 
 
Working hand in hand with the District Board Members for the design of an office building that meets the changing needs of a municipal utility, Image Builders completed this 2000 sq ft modular office building for the Sanitation District in Fairplay, Colorado in record time. 
This 7 acre site includes 250 storage units, a two-bedroom manager&apos;s apartment with oversized 2-car garage, and rental office. 
 


 
 Unaxis Optics USA, Inc. - Golden, Colorado - Optics Testing Laboratory
The Daily Scoop - Denver, Colorado - Frozen Custard Shop
Juma&apos;s DVDs, Inc. - Denver, Colorado - Video Store
Blossoms, LLC - Denver, Colorado - Flower Shop
Just Brakes - Denver, Colorado - New automotive center
Jiffy Lube - San Jose, California - New automotive center
	</body>
</document>
