<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004086" url="http://www.dailyfinance.com/2010/06/24/as-sonic-earnings-stumble-drive-in-chain-turns-to-new-marketing/" time="2012-07-12-20:18" support="1" score="0.006911860255719567" bingtitle="As Sonic Earnings Stumble, Drive-In Chain Turns to New Marketing ..." webtitle="As Sonic Earnings Stumble, Drive-In Chain Turns to New Marketing Chief - DailyFinance">
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>... restaurants, where customers park in a booth, order ... is what separates Sonic from every other fast-food restaurant. ... Doritos tacos put sizzle in Taco Bell&apos;s US...</description>
	<body>
		AOL MAIL 
 You might also like:  AOL Jobs ,  AOL Real Estate  and  More 
 


 DailyFinance 
 Home Saving 
 Savings Experiment Consumer Ally Economizer Family Money College Finance Fantastic Freebies 
 Spending 
 Credit Cards Credit Reports Debt Retail Technology 
 Investing Planning 
 Power of Planning Retirement IRA Center Calculators Insurance Banking 
 Taxes 
 Tax Center Tax Tools&amp;Resources 
 Jobs 
 Search Jobs Get Career Advice 
 Real Estate 
 Homes for Sale Mortgages 
 Questions or Feedback ? 
 
As Sonic Earnings Stumble, Drive-In Chain Turns to New Marketing Chief
 By Nikolay Tsintsadze Posted 2:45PM 06/24/10 Posted under: Earnings Share Sonic ( SONC ) is one of America&apos;s few remaining chains of drive-in restaurants, where customers park in a booth, order through a speaker system, and then dine in the car after a carhop delivers the meal. As popular as this system has been in the past, Sonic is struggling to bring recession-weary customers back to its booths.

During its earnings call after the market closed on June 21, the company reported an underwhelming earnings figure of 18 cents a share for the third quarter. Wall Street analysts had estimated earnings between 19 and 21 cents a share. Worse, the profit figure included a one-time gain of three cents a share from a tax benefit.

Excluding the gain and other special items, Sonic&apos;s net income dropped 37.5% from a year earlier. Management cited the combination of debt reduction and disappointing same-store sales as the reason for the decline. (The transcript of the earnings call has more details.)
 
What Do These Numbers Mean for Investors? 

Lynne Collier, the managing director of Restaurant Research at Sterne Agee, sees this regression as a &quot;serious setback.&quot; She notes that investors were looking for this quarter to mark the turnaround for Sonic and a return to financial growth. The company was to use this period as a springboard for the next quarter, which is typically its strongest one. Now there is doubt as to whether sales can recover and Sonic can end its fiscal year on a good note.

Compounding the problem is Sonic&apos;s financial leverage. In an attempt to strengthen its balance sheet, the company has been paying off some of its debt. Usually, reducing liabilities is beneficial to a company, but it can be painful in the short run since cash used to pay off debt isn&apos;t available for other purposes such as expansion, or marketing.

Weakness in Sonic&apos;s current fourth quarter, which runs from June 1 to Aug. 31, implies that the coming colder months will see an even worse dip in activity at the start of the next fiscal year.

 Sonic&apos;s Business 

While the booth and drive-through system is part of the company&apos;s image, it makes for volatile sales. The setup depresses sales during the winter, as people are less likely to want to sit in their cars and eat in bad weather, especially as gasoline to run their heaters gets more expensive.

This isn&apos;t the only issue that Sonic must address. One of its historical selling points, original drinks, is being tested. Calling itself the &quot;Ultimate Drink Stop,&quot; Sonic has prided itself in having an unrivaled selection of exclusive drinks. Now, other players in the restaurant field are challenging this claim by rapidly expanding their drink offerings to compete with Sonic.

Most of the challenges that lie ahead of Sonic are endemic to the restaurant business. Competition is cutthroat, and with so many individual businesses fighting over customers, differentiation is difficult -- hence the need for a marketing recharge.

Analysts had complained that the company&apos;s marketing strategy was getting somewhat old. Sonic apparently agreed, announcing that Danielle Vona, a former PepsiCo ( PEP ) vice president, is the new chief marketing officer . She brings to the job a good record at PepsiCo for introducing and promoting new products, including the Propel and Sierra Mist brands plus juice and dairy products, during her 11 years with the company.

 Future Prospects

 If Vona is effective, sales volume should be able to recover from recent troubles. The booth and drive-through business model, in spite of its flaws, is what separates Sonic from every other fast-food restaurant. Retaining that separation and improving the brand&apos;s attractiveness can keep existing customers while bringing in new ones.
 
 Sonic has proven its ability to open new locations successfully, and there are countless possibilities for new franchises. In New Jersey, for instance, lines for newly opened Sonic restaurants can stretch for blocks and last past midnight.

The possibility of expansion of both franchises and profitability make Sonic an interesting company to investors, if only a fresh marketing campaign can bring in the customers.
 
From Our Partners:
 More Articles on AOL Real Estate Florida Law Enforcement Employees Paid To Get Drunk - AOL Jobs Beware Of Office Parties! Alcohol Affects You More At Work Than At A Bar - AOL Jobs 
More On DailyFinance:
 Why Your Organic Food Isn&apos;t as Organic as It Used to Be New McDonald&apos;s CEO&apos;s Grand Plan Involves a Lot of Chicken Why Gap Will Never Be Great Again 
 Tagged: drink , drinks , earnings , fast food , growth , marketing , pepsi , pepsico , Sonic , strategy 
 Share Getty Images 
 CLOSER TO A BAILOUT? FHA&apos;s Mortgage Delinquencies Soar - CNNMoney Dimon Faces Round Two Before Congress - FOXBusiness HEALTH CARE REFORM: 5 Investing Scenarios of Obamacare Ruling - InvestorPlace The Biggest Sign of a China Bubble - The Motley Fool THE FED&apos;S SUMMER SEQUEL: Operation Twist 2 - IBTimes How to Stomp Out Pesky Travel Fees - CBS MoneyWatch FedEx Earnings Don&apos;t Deliver - 24/7 Wall St. 
 
Add a Comment
 Sign in» Add a Comment Type your comment here *0 / 3000 Character Maximum Submit 
 manage My Portfolios


 Track Your Investments Here! 
See why so many people use the DailyFinance portfolio tool as the cornerstone of their investing strategy.
 Sign In or Register Now advertisement 
Most Popular Stories

 1 
 New McDonald&apos;s CEO&apos;s Grand Plan Involves a Lot of Chicken 
 2 
 Brides Say &apos;Yes&apos; to Selling Their Dress ... Before the Wedding! 
 3 
 The LIBOR Scandal Explained in One Simple Infographic 
 4 
 Get the Best Bargain on Perfect Pillows -- Savings Experiment 
 5 
 Ousted Duke Energy CEO Earns Up to $44.4 Million for a Few Hours Work 
 
 
DailyFinance Wire

 8 Things to Never Keep in Your Wallet 8 Signs Your Identity Has Been Compromised Listen Up, Ladies: Tips for Closing the Financial Gender Gap New Jobless Claims Fall Sharply to Four-Year Low Family Finds $3 Million Worth of Classic Baseball Cards in Grandpa&apos;s Attic China Slams the Brakes on GM&apos;s Accelerating Car Sales Obama&apos;s Tax Cut for the 1% (and Everyone Else, Too) 
 More DailyFinance Stories 
Newswire
 AP CNN 24/7 WallSt 
 China&apos;s economic slowdown painful despite... 4 questions for JPMorgan during Friday report All eyes on JPMorgan as banks report earnings Buffett says general economy slowing this... Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight... Global stocks slide on Fed minutes Fewer auto closings reduce US unemployment... More US homes facing foreclosure risk in June 
 
 Young dad, $15,000 in credit card debt 30-year mortgage rate falls to record 3.56% Why health care costs keep rising 700,000 homeowners no longer underwater New foreclosures jump 9% in second quarter $400,000 portfolio, too many holdings Homes lost for as little as $400 in back taxes 3 tuition bills, only $35,000 saved 
 More from CNNMoney 
 Gambling Revenues Continue to Fall in Nevada Can Activist Investors Fix Procter&amp;Gamble? Take A Poll!!! Groupon Shareholders Stuck Where They Are, CEO&amp;All Boeing Gets Order for 150 Planes from United Groupon, Zynga at Post-IPO Lows More Caution For Intel Earnings Today’s Market Winners and Losers Big Short Interest Changes in Cult&amp;Controversial Stocks (ALU, STD, BAC, BKS, DNDN, DMND, FSLR, GMCR, GRPN, HGSI, LNKD, NFLX, RSH, RIMM, SIRI) 
 More from 24/7 Wall St. 
Follow Us

 Facebook Twitter RSS To Go 
 
Compare Mortgage Rates
 Mortgage Rates by Zillow 
Headlines From DailyFinance Partners
 
 MORE CITIES GOING BROKE Stocks pressured by &apos;lack of confidence&apos; Wells Fargo in $175M unfair lending... 
 More CNNMoney.com 
 US domestic stocks beat multinationals Goldman recruits former Treasury spokesman US companies’ dash for cash heralds a painful freeze 
 More Financial Times 
 Bizarre Case of Failed Broker PFG... Fiscal Cliff Hitting Growth: &apos;Economy... How US Can Avert Fiscal Cliff: &apos;We&apos;ve... 
 More from CNBC.com 
 Tax Rules for Deducting Donations (The... Casino Vacations Without the Casino... Designer Donuts? Why Cheap Treats Are... 
 More at SmartMoney 
 Want an Energy Efficient Home? Start... My Repaired Car Has Lost Value. Can I... With Six Cards Already, Would Another... 
 More Fox Business 
 How to stop unwanted robocalls Consumer Reports Index: Americans... Who serves the best pancakes? 
 More from Consumer Reports 
 
 Female House GOP Staffers Make... Post 50s Expected To Outnumber Younger... &apos;The City Needs Breathing Room&apos; 
 More from Huffington Post 
 2012 Maryland Clean Energy Summit Don&apos;t Ban Coal for Electricity... Handling Big Data in the Energy... 
 More from AOL Energy 
 Wells Fargo to Pay $125 Million in Race... David Hoffman of Marin County, Calif.,... Kitchen Lighting: Ambient, Task and... 
 More from AOL Real Estate 
 What It&apos;s Really Like To Be A Tattoo... Top 10 Mistakes That Interns Make Hopeful Sign For Jobs: Unemployment... 
 More from AOL Jobs 
 DailyFinance 
Business News

 Main Autos Books Charity Columns Crime Food Green Media People Travel Jobs Real Estate 
 
Personal Finance

 Debt Insurance Credit College Finance Retirement Recalls Taxes 
 
Investing

 Portfolios Media Credit Stocks in the News ETF&apos;s Earnings 
 
Our Partners

 Tech News Small Business Real Estate 24/7 Wall St Autoblog 
 
 DailyFinance Sitemap | Terms of Service | Privacy Policy | Trademarks | HELP | Advertise With Us 

©Copyright 2012 AOL Inc. All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
