<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004231" url="http://www.allthingspos.com/citizen/" time="2012-07-12-20:28" support="1" score="0.0009684792797309" bingtitle="Citizen - POS Experts, Same Day Shipping and Low Prices!" webtitle="Citizen  - POS Experts, Same Day Shipping and Low Prices!">
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>Products · Barcode Scanners · Credit Card Swipers ... speed economy printer for bankcard, POS, fast food, restaurant ... mobile printing solution for portable receipt and ...</description>
	<body>
		Expert Advice: 1-800-326-0393  ·  Same Day Shipping  ·  Low Prices Cart    

 
 Products 
· Barcode Scanners 
· Credit Card Swipers 
· Cash Drawers 
· POS Software 
· POS Systems 
· POS Printers 
· POS Touchscreens 
  More» 

 Brands 

 Services 

 Solutions 

 

 Customer Service 
· Contact Us 
· Delivery Options 
· Printer Drivers 


 

 About Us 
 
 POS Hardware › Citizen 
 
Citizen

 Citizen is the leader in North America for providing specialty electronics including OEM mechanisms, OEM printers, POS printers, Kiosk printers, and LCD products. 
 
 Citizen 
 CT-S281 
 Drop-in paper loading 
The Citizen CT-S281 is the industry&apos;s most advanced two-inch thermal printer. Featuring a powerful one million cut rated auto-cutter that supports both full and partial cuts, hi-speed text and graphics, and two-dimensional barcode... Citizen 
 CT-S310 
 The CT-S310 is compatible with Microsoft Windows XP and Vista and it proves once again that it is Small on Size and Big on Value! 
The CT-S310 follows the multiple interface approach unique to the POS marketplace meaning customers can select between a parallel and a serial version. USB is always included as a standard feature. This turns the printer into a very safe investment... As low as 
 $186.60 Citizen 
 CT-S310II 
 Low power consumption 
The Citizen CT-S310II is a green step forward towards reducing negative impact on the environment and it is Energy Star qualified. The power supply is the most eficient at managing power consumption and is built-in to eliminate the &quot;brick&quot; and free... As low as 
 $246.90 Citizen 
 CT-S601 
 Compact design can be installed anywhere 
The Citizen CT-S601 is your Next Best Printing Solution for your receipt applications as it not only offers more features for less price than any other competitive model, but also it is fully compatible with previous Citizen models - making the... As low as 
 $229.50 Citizen 
 CT-S651 
 Compact front-exit design can be installed anywhere 
The Citizen CT-S651 is your Next Best Printing Solution for your receipt applications as it not only offers Front Exit and more features for less money, but also it is fully compatible with previous Citizen models and with competitive models including... As low as 
 $239.50 Citizen 
 CT-S801 
 Greater reliability delivers longer life&amp;lower maintenance costs 
The Citizen CT-S801 is the first in a new line of revolutionary &quot;Intelligent&quot; printers, featuring the industry&apos;s first POS printer with a back lit graphic LCD display that communicates with you. It is ideal for a variety of applications from... As low as 
 $344.80 Citizen 
 CT-S851 
 The world&apos;s fastest, most reliable, easiest to configure and customize POS printer. 
The Citizen CT-S851 represents the industry&apos;s first &quot;Front Exit&quot; and &quot;Intelligent&quot; POS printer with a back lit graphic LCD display, which includes an editor to customize display messages - a great value-add for end users. The CT-S851 is ideal... As low as 
 $265.10 Citizen 
 CT-S2000 
 It has the easy paper loading 
CT-S2000 thermal printer offers high speed printing with selectable paper widths up to 112 mm. CT-S2000 printer is ideal for printing applications that require larger amounts of data or information, including secure prescription printing. CT-S2000... Citizen 
 CT-S2000L 
The Citizen CT-S2000L printer offers the same high speed printing with selectable paper widths up to 82.5 mm as the CT-S2000, but also features the ability to print labels. CT-S2000L printer is ideal for printing applications that require larger... As low as 
 $293.20 Citizen 
 CT-S4000 
 Large capacity (102 mm) drop-in paper loading 
CT-S4000 Thermal Printer is a two-color, thermal printer capable of real-world speeds up to 220 mm/second and offers variety of advanced printer features including: Citizen&apos;s Spill-Shield design to prevent damage from moisture or foreign objects to... As low as 
 $437.30 Citizen 
 CT-S4000L 
The Citizen CT-S4000L printer offers the same high speed printing with selectable paper widths up to 112 mm as the CT-S4000, but also features the ability to print labels. The CT-S4000L is a two-color, thermal printer capable of real-world speeds up to... As low as 
 $191.90 Citizen 
 CBM-910II 
 Bit image graphics printing 
The Citizen CBM-910II is a compact, palm-sized dot-impact printer that provides users with unparalleled features within the impact printer class. It utilizes a plethora of applications from data-logging, coin-counting, instrumentation and measurement... As low as 
 $181.30 Citizen 
 CD-S500 
 Two-Color Printing 
The Citizen CD-S500 is a cost-effective, high-speed (5 lines per second) receipt printer that features drop-in paper loading in a compact and versatile design. With the CD-S500, business owners such as hospitality, restaurant, hotel or retail can... As low as 
 $219.10 Citizen 
 iDP-3550 
 High speed economy printer for bankcard, POS, fast food, restaurant and convenience store use. 
Designed for such applications as receipts, journals, kitchen, ticket, and credit/debit card transactions, the iDP-3550 series has a cash drawer kick out feature that can control two drawers. The iDP-3550 series also features a 6k-byte memory buffer,... As low as 
 $190.00 Citizen 
 PD-22 
 Ideal for a wide range of mobile printing requirements 
Whether you are printing receipts for customers, packing lists for products or messages sent to your telephone, the Citizen PD-22 two-inch printer is there for you. Weighing just over nine ounces, the PD-22 is one of the smallest and lightest... As low as 
 $623.00 Citizen 
 PD-24 
 Fast and quiet portable printing 
The Citizen PD-24 is a light weight, four-inch (112 mm) portable printer with features that make it ideal for a wide range of mobile printing application including field service, mobile diagnostics, route accounting, health care, law enforcement,... As low as 
 $210.10 Citizen 
 CMP-10 
The Citizen CMP-10 is a small, lightweight mobile receipt printer that brings functionality and convenience to any mobile environment. Printing at 50 mm/sec, the CMP-10 affords maximum wireless freedom through an infrared (IrDA) interface. Weighing... As low as 
 $219.60 Citizen 
 CMP-20 
 The ideal mobile printing solution for portable receipt and labeling needs. 
The Citizen CMP-20 two-inch portable printer is designed to be simple to use and easy to operate. This, combined with the durable, strong plastic case able to take the occasional knock, means the CMP-20 just keeps running and running. The CMP-20... As low as 
 $315.90 Citizen 
 CMP-30 
 Easy media loading with drop-in paper loading and paper out indicator 
The Citizen CMP-30 three-inch portable printer is designed to be simple to use and easy to operate. This, combined with the durable, strong plastic case able to take the occasional knock, means the CMP-30 just keeps running and running. The... As low as 
 $321.10 Citizen 
 CL-S400DT 
 Self-contained metal mechanism for durable operation 
The compact yet powerful CL-S400DT delivers a combination of reliability and high performance in the desktop thermal printer class. Featuring a small footprint and self-contained metal mechanism for durable operation, this versatile printer can handle... As low as 
 $260.40 Citizen 
 CL-S700 
 Direct thermal or thermal transfer printing 
The Citizen CL-S700 series is built with durability and ease of access in mind. Featuring a large, programmable front LCD control panel and a revolutionary Cross-Emulation control board that allows the printer to switch from Datamax to Zebra... As low as 
 $803.40 Citizen 
 CL-S700DT 
 Direct thermal printing 
The Citizen CL-S700DT is the direct thermal-only version of the CL-S700 printer. This series is built with durability and ease of access in mind. Featuring a large, programmable front LCD control panel and a revolutionary Cross-Emulation control board... Citizen 
 CLP-531 
 300 dpi resolution standard 
The Citizen CLP-531 direct thermal printer combines robust printing, 300 dpi resolution and superior price performance, ease of use and precision engineering. Citizen&apos;s unique metal Hi-Lift print mechanism allows for quick media loading while an... As low as 
 $203.70 Citizen 
 CLP-621 
 203 dpi resolution standard 
The powerful Citizen CLP-621 offers unparalleled versatility in the desktop thermal printer class. Printing in 203 dpi in both direct thermal and thermal transfer modes, the CLP-621 features a 360-meter ribbon for greater productivity and reduced... As low as 
 $313.00 Citizen 
 CLP-631 
 300 dpi resolution standard 
The powerful Citizen CLP-631 offers unparalleled versatility in the desktop thermal printer class. Printing in 300 dpi in both direct thermal and thermal transfer modes, the CLP-631 features a 360-meter ribbon for greater productivity and reduced... Citizen 
 CLP-7200 
 Internal 8-inch (200 mm) media capacity 
The Citizen CLP-7200 series offers superior price performance and ease of use with precision form, fit, and function. Increased processing speed ensures no delay in even the most complex label or tag application. Citizen&apos;s unique metal Hi-Lift... As low as 
 $75.20 Citizen 
 Receipt Paper 
Paper for Citizen receipt printers. Please note that not every type of receipt paper listed here will be compatible with every Citizen receipt printer we sell. Please call for full compatibility information. Citizen 
 Parts 
Products and parts from Citizen. Citizen 
 CT-S280 - Discontinued ,
 No direct replacement available. Contact us for comparable substitute.
 Citizen 
 CT-S300 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen CT-S310 
 Citizen 
 CLP-521 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen CL-S521 
 Citizen 
 CBM-231 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen CT-S300 
 Citizen 
 CBM-270 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen CT-S280 
 Citizen 
 CBM-1000 II - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen CT-S651 
 Citizen 
 iDP-3111 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen CBM-910II 
 Citizen 
 IDP-3240 - Discontinued ,
 No direct replacement available. Contact us for comparable substitute.
 Citizen 
 iDP-3400 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen iDP-3550 
 Citizen 
 iDP-3210 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen IDP-3240 
 Citizen 
 iDP-3535 - Discontinued ,
 Replaced by the Citizen iDP-3550 
 
 

 ©2011 All Things POS
	</body>
</document>
