<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004555" url="http://www.britevents.com/restaurants/cheshire/warrington/emerald-takeaway/21986/" time="2012-07-12-20:58" support="1" score="0.0006610925404532473" bingtitle="Emerald Takeaway Fast Food restaurant in Warrington, Cheshire" webtitle="Emerald Takeaway Fast Food restaurant in Warrington, Cheshire">
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>Fast Food restaurant (Warrington) - Emerald Takeaway ... menu, opening times, or to book a table at Emerald Takeaway restaurant, please phone our main telephone number on ...</description>
	<body>
		| | | Cheshire | x 
BritEvents.com | .
 REGISTER LOG IN 
Already a member? Sign in here:
 Email 
 Password 
    Home Page Search Tickets News Reviews Venues Hotels Videos Latest Add Event MY LOCATION:    LONDON Add an event Log in / register CURRENT LOCATION: London 
 SEARCH All types of event Business Car Boot Sales Exhibitions Film Gay&amp;Lesbian History&amp;Heritage Kids Lifestyle Literature Music Nightclub Events Religious Sport Strange&amp;Bizarre Theatre Visual Arts Any date ----------------------- Today Tomorrow Next weekend Next 7 days Next 31 days 
 Music Theatre Sport Attractions Heritage Visual Arts Exhibitions Car Boot Sales Nightclubs More Film Gay/Lesbian Lifestyle Literature Bizarre Religious/Spiritual Business Everything Else! Back COMEDY TICKETS 
 Alan Carr Bill Bailey Kevin Bridges Michael McIntyre Mrs Brown Sarah Millican See all Comedy tickets 
 CONCERT TICKETS 
 Coldplay Drake Lady Gaga Madonna Olly Murs The Stone Roses See all Concert tickets 
 FESTIVAL TICKETS 
 Bestival Download Festival Rock Ness Festival T in the Park V Festival Wireless Festival See all Festival tickets 
 SPORT TICKETS 
 British Open Chester Races Six Nations The Ashes Twenty 20 Cup Wimbledon See all Sport tickets 
 THEATRE TICKETS 
 Blood Brothers Les Miserables Phantom of the Opera War Horse We Will Rock You Wicked See all Theatre tickets 
 EAT OUT 
Emerald Takeaway
ADDRESS:
Loushers Lane
Warrington
Cheshire
WA4 2RD

PHONE:
 01925 230033 
 
 
 
Emerald Takeaway Restaurant

Loushers Lane, Warrington, Cheshire
 
Welcome to Emerald Takeaway Fast Food restaurant in Warrington, Cheshire. For information about our menu, opening times, or to book a table at Emerald Takeaway restaurant, please phone our main telephone number on 01925230033.




Check out our full list of restaurants in Warrington , or see a list of other restaurants that are close to Emerald Takeaway in Warrington below.
 
 

Restaurant Map


Use the map below to plan your journey to Emerald Takeaway by car or public transport.


 

Emerald Takeaway Reviews


Have you eaten at Emerald Takeaway ? Why not share your experience and add your review for Emerald Takeaway by filling in the comments box below:

 


What&apos;s on nearby

 


July 2012
 14 Oddsocks Julius Caesar Grappenhall Heys Walled Garden 


August 2012
 17 Miles Kane Parr Hall 24 Creamfields Daresbury Estate 25 Adam Ant Pyramid And Parr Hall 26 Creamfields Daresbury Estate 


September 2012
 18 New Balance English Half Marathon Victoria Park 20 Beating Berlusconi Pyramid And Parr Hall 23 The Park Royal Wedding Fayre Park Royal Hotel 30 Richard Street Pyramid And Parr Hall 


October 2012
 6 The Vagina Monologues Pyramid And Parr Hall 7 Halliwell Jones Stadium Wedding Fayre Halliwell Jones Stadium 9 Good Old Days Pyramid And Parr Hall 14 Britannia Daresbury Park Wedding Fayre Brittania Daresbury Park Hotel 25 Gaga A Tribute to Queen Pyramid And Parr Hall 31 Daniel Sloss Pyramid And Parr Hall 


November 2012
 10 Mark Watson Pyramid And Parr Hall 29 Steve Hughes Big Issues Pyramid And Parr Hall 


December 2012
 7 Rhydian Pyramid And Parr Hall 18 Kate Rusby at Christmas Pyramid And Parr Hall 


May 2013
 15 Micky Flanagan Warrington Parr Hall 


September 2013
 14 Jimmy Carr Warrington Parr Hall 


Other Nearby Restaurants

 The Dragon City 
Chinese restaurant - 549m away away
 Don Pino 
Italian restaurant - 688m away away
 Kelly&apos;s Chinese Restaurant 
Chinese restaurant - 728m away away
 Kelly&apos;s Chinese Restaurant 
Chinese restaurant - 728m away away
 Ideal Restaurant 
Chinese restaurant - 869m away away
 101 Restaurant&amp;Bar 
English restaurant - 918m away away
 Domino&apos;s Pizza 
Pizzeria restaurant - 918m away away
 Medipizza 
Pizzeria restaurant - 1003m away away
 T N T No 1 Chinese Restaurant 
Chinese restaurant - 1007m away away
 McDonalds 
American restaurant - 0.7 miles away
 FEATURE 8 free attractions in London 
It&apos;s renowned for being one of the most expensive cities in the world, but surprisingly there are plenty of things to do in London without having to dig deep into your pockets.
 FEATURE The Witchcraft Trials of Essex 
Essex is infamous with its involvement in the witchcraft trials that took place around 400 years ago. We look at case histories and the accusations that caused mass hysteria, showing the amazing stories behind the considerable loss of life.
 FEATURE Top 10 West End musicals 
You can&apos;t visit London without taking a trip down the West End to see some of the world&apos;s best musicals. There is such an astonishing array of musicals that it&apos;s difficult to choose which one to see. We give you a helping hand with a list of our own top ten musicals.
 FEATURE You and What Army band interview 
Telford-based electro-rock band You and What Army describe themselves as &quot;having unforgivingly catchy trance synths that soar over tectonic-plate-shatteringly heavy guitar riffs, dancefloor-destroyingly awesome basslines and lowrider-cruisingly phat beats, with the narrated apocalypse rapped, sung and screamed wildly into the fray.&quot; That&apos;s one massive claim, so BritEvents&apos; Lucy Middleton catches up with the four piece band to find out more about their epic sound.
 
Help if you&apos;re lost

 Register / Log In 
Register or log into your account to add events. About BritEvents 
Who we are, why we do it. And how much we love it! Privacy Policy 
How our privacy policy affects you. Contact Us 
Get in touch with us to tell us what we&apos;re doing right. Sitemap 
View our whole site map to all our major pages. Traffic Updates/News 
The latest traffic and travel news from our sister website. 
 
©BritEvents.com 2012 - 2013
 Emerald Takeaway Fast Food restaurant in Warrington, Cheshire
	</body>
</document>
