<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004234" url="http://forums.nasioc.com/forums/showthread.php?t=757940" time="2012-07-12-20:28" support="14" score="0.05880142842082767" bingtitle="#1 fast food restaurant in the world..... - NASIOC" webtitle="#1 fast food restaurant in the world...... - NASIOC">
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>#1 fast food restaurant in the world..... Alaskan Impreza Club Forum -- AKIC ... wendys, I always make sure to check for bugs and weird **** in my food when I order ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to the North American Subaru Impreza Owners Club Thursday July 12, 2012 
 
 Home Forums WikiNASIOC Products Store Modifications Upgrade Garage 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   NASIOC &gt; NASIOC Chapters &gt; Alaskan Impreza Club Forum -- AKIC #1 fast food restaurant in the world...... 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register Forum Rules iTrader FAQ Members List Calendar Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Google Forum Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 Welcome to NASIOC - The world&apos;s largest online community for Subaru enthusiasts! Welcome to the NASIOC.com Subaru forum .

You are currently viewing our forum as a guest, which gives you limited access to view most discussions and access our other features. By joining our community, free of charge , you will have access to post topics, communicate privately with other members (PM), respond to polls, upload content and access many other special features. Registration is free, fast and simple, so please join our community today! 

If you have any problems with the registration process or your account login, please contact us . * Registered users of the site do not see these ads. 
 

   Share Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
 04-23-2005, 09:45 PM  # 1 Konvict Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 45615 Join Date: Oct 2003 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Fairbanks, AK Vehicle: 
 2005 Ford Mustang
Redfire 
 #1 fast food restaurant in the world...... Aparently Discovery thinks the Wendy&apos;s in North Pole, AK is the #1 fast food restaurant in the world. 

 http://travel.discovery.com/fansites...fastfood1.html 

Mike * Registered users of the site do not see these ads.   
 
 Konvict View Public Profile Find More Posts by Konvict 
 
 04-23-2005, 10:58 PM  # 2 Damien3082 Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 68710 Join Date: Aug 2004 Location: Kent, WA Vehicle: 
 2005 Impreza WRX
Pearl Blue 
 Hell yeah. Wendy&apos;s is the bomb. Speaking of which, I&apos;m eating right now lol.   
 
 Damien3082 View Public Profile Find More Posts by Damien3082 
 
 04-24-2005, 02:09 AM  # 3 00Maddog Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 62410 Join Date: May 2004 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: land of awd Vehicle: 
 2004 ra&apos;d redrex in
8k w/ STI kit :) DASH 
 the lady that found a finger in her chili is in jail for making it up. Now they just need to find out who&apos;s finger it is. Wendy&apos;s actually checked all employees fingers to make sure nobody was missing any. I like wendys, especially the wild mountian burgers that are now gone.   
 
 00Maddog View Public Profile Find More Posts by 00Maddog 
 
 04-24-2005, 03:42 AM  # 4 Spitfyre02 Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 60463 Join Date: Apr 2004 Chapter/Region: South East Location: Valdosta GA Vehicle: 
 2002 WRX sedan
Black 
 *shudder* have they even visited that wendys, I always make sure to check for bugs and weird **** in my food when I order from there. lol   
 
 Spitfyre02 View Public Profile Find More Posts by Spitfyre02 
 
 04-24-2005, 07:01 PM  # 5 .RYAN Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 69463 Join Date: Aug 2004 Chapter/Region: NWIC Location: Wa Vehicle: 
 08 Daily - Legacy
 
 Wendys is by far the worst food I&apos;ve ever had.   
 
 .RYAN View Public Profile Visit .RYAN&apos;s homepage! Find More Posts by .RYAN 
 
 04-25-2005, 12:21 AM  # 6 TheShadow Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 62558 Join Date: May 2004 Chapter/Region: SCIC Location: GT909 Vehicle: 
 09 WRX
OBP 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by WRXSHAGGY Wendys is by far the worst food I&apos;ve ever had. 
 agreed, fries are awful there   
 
 TheShadow View Public Profile Find More Posts by TheShadow 
 
 04-25-2005, 12:28 AM  # 7 richy_21 Scooby Guru  
 Member#: 58670 Join Date: Apr 2004 Chapter/Region: MAIC Location: Behind the scope Vehicle: 
 2005 got muuuuu?
 
 ^^^ WHAT....i disagree   
 
 richy_21 View Public Profile Visit richy_21&apos;s homepage! Find More Posts by richy_21 
 
 04-25-2005, 12:44 AM  # 8 00Maddog Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 62410 Join Date: May 2004 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: land of awd Vehicle: 
 2004 ra&apos;d redrex in
8k w/ STI kit :) DASH 
 wendys rules, 11:00 at night, I can get a triple stack mmmm gf gets a salad with her spicy chicken. no place else can say that.   
 
 00Maddog View Public Profile Find More Posts by 00Maddog 
 
 04-25-2005, 01:15 AM  # 9 SparkysJDMSpeedWagon Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 52530 Join Date: Jan 2004 Chapter/Region: South East Location: Goldsboro, NC Vehicle: 
 2004 For Sale:
Silver 04 wagon w/18g 
 I must agree that the fries aren&apos;t the best, although my friends and I think that they are specially-formulated for dipping in Frosties. The burgers are some of the best ones I&apos;ve had in Alaska (since there isn&apos;t a Waddaburger or Jack in the Box up here).   
 
 SparkysJDMSpeedWagon View Public Profile Find More Posts by SparkysJDMSpeedWagon 
 
 04-25-2005, 01:47 AM  # 10 Spitfyre02 Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 60463 Join Date: Apr 2004 Chapter/Region: South East Location: Valdosta GA Vehicle: 
 2002 WRX sedan
Black 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by SparkysJDMSpeedWagon I must agree that the fries aren&apos;t the best, although my friends and I think that they are specially-formulated for dipping in Frosties. The burgers are some of the best ones I&apos;ve had in Alaska (since there isn&apos;t a Waddaburger or Jack in the Box up here). 
 
Oh man I havent had Jack in the Crack in so long, since I was in Tucson. The sourdough jack, mmmm greasy burger. Thats the only place I know where you can get Chinese, Mexican and american food all in the same place.

Nick   
 
 Spitfyre02 View Public Profile Find More Posts by Spitfyre02 
 
 04-25-2005, 02:27 AM  # 11 memo79 Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 70388 Join Date: Sep 2004 Location: Ft. Wainwright, AK Vehicle: 
 &apos;01 2.5RS
BRP 
 Did somebody say Whataburger??? mmmmmmmmmmmmmm   
 
 memo79 View Public Profile Find More Posts by memo79 
 
 04-25-2005, 03:53 AM  # 12 bert_WRX Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 27143 Join Date: Oct 2002 Location: Anchorage, AK/Burbank, CA uhh...In&amp;Out?   
 
 bert_WRX View Public Profile Find More Posts by bert_WRX 
 
 04-25-2005, 04:20 AM  # 13 AK_2002_WRX Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 10591 Join Date: Sep 2001 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: anch, ak Vehicle: 
 2004 Silverado SS
Victory Red 
 i&apos;ve never tried wendys in my life....lol...are their burgers pretty good? i&apos;ve been tryin to stay away from fast food...lol   
 
 AK_2002_WRX View Public Profile Find More Posts by AK_2002_WRX 
 
 04-25-2005, 04:24 AM  # 14 WRX8U82 Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 38080 Join Date: Jun 2003 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Anchorage, AK Quote: 
 Originally Posted by bert_WRX uhh...In&amp;Out? 
 I like In&amp;Out too...always eat there when I leave AK, but I don&apos;t like there fries either. Then wash it down with some Jamba Juice...What&apos;s your Jamba??? Mayn, I miss Cali!   
 
 WRX8U82 View Public Profile Find More Posts by WRX8U82 
 
 04-25-2005, 05:07 AM  # 15 JordyB Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 20328 Join Date: Jun 2002 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Boost: My Anti Drug Vehicle: 
 &apos;05 Forester XT
&apos;07 Legacy spec.B 
 I&amp;O rocks, had it my first time in Vegas when I was down there for SEMA a few years ago. Loved it!!!   
 
 JordyB View Public Profile Find More Posts by JordyB 
 
 04-25-2005, 03:08 PM  # 16 XR4Tim Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 73802 Join Date: Nov 2004 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Eagle River, AK Vehicle: 
 Fast rare cars...
Lots of them 
 Looks like Alaska has a lot going for it in the fast food industry. The Taco Bell on Old Seward is the busiest Taco Bell in the world, and now the North Pole Wendy&apos;s is the #1 fast food restaurant in the world. Crazy.   
 
 XR4Tim View Public Profile Visit XR4Tim&apos;s homepage! Find More Posts by XR4Tim 
 
 04-25-2005, 04:29 PM  # 17 .RYAN Scooby Newbie  
 Member#: 69463 Join Date: Aug 2004 Chapter/Region: NWIC Location: Wa Vehicle: 
 08 Daily - Legacy
 
 Alaska needs a Del Taco. Man I miss that so much. I eat there everyday when I go on leave.   
 
 .RYAN View Public Profile Visit .RYAN&apos;s homepage! Find More Posts by .RYAN 
 
 04-25-2005, 07:07 PM  # 18 WRXnFX Alaskan Mafia 
Moderator  
 Member#: 10398 Join Date: Sep 2001 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Corner of Easy and Lazy Quote: 
 Originally Posted by bert_WRX In&amp;Out? 
 Yup, I agree.

Winslow   
 
 WRXnFX View Public Profile Find More Posts by WRXnFX 
 
 04-25-2005, 08:36 PM  # 19 OrionAK Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 28019 Join Date: Oct 2002 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Alaska Vehicle: 
 2006 Forester XT
Crystal Grey Metallic 
 We ran Jack in the Box out of town YEARS ago. Back in the late 80&apos;s or early 90&apos;s when 50% of their food was made from poop, or so we were told.

We like our poop up here, even going so far as to sell it to tourists once we laquer it up, but we draw the line when our beef is cut with 50% people poop. And it&apos;s probably the lack of beef in the mix rather than the amount of poop that ticked us off. We likes our meat.   
 
 OrionAK View Public Profile Find More Posts by OrionAK 
 
 06-13-2009, 05:59 AM  # 20 menusnearu01 *** Banned ***  
 Member#: 213892 Join Date: Jun 2009 I have find the good restaurants in US from the following site..

 http://health.yahoo.com/experts/eatt...t-restaurants/ 

You can also refer this site.......

 Menus Nearu   
 
 menusnearu01 View Public Profile Find More Posts by menusnearu01 
 
 06-13-2009, 06:17 AM  # 21 Garandman Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 101117 Join Date: Nov 2005 Chapter/Region: NESIC Location: Boston Vehicle: 
 2009 WRX 5 door
Blue 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by 00Maddog the lady that found a finger in her chili is in jail for making it up. Now they just need to find out who&apos;s finger it is. Wendy&apos;s actually checked all employees fingers to make sure nobody was missing any. 
 It&apos;s in their employee handbook.   
 
 Garandman View Public Profile Find More Posts by Garandman 
 
 06-13-2009, 06:37 AM  # 22 02redwagone Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 87067 Join Date: May 2005 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Oregon Coast/AK Vehicle: 
 02 Old but tasty
SRP 
 Holy blast from the past. Wendy&apos;s FTW.   
 
 02redwagone View Public Profile Find More Posts by 02redwagone 
 
 06-13-2009, 07:34 AM  # 23 07_BluRex Scooby Specialist  
 Member#: 127922 Join Date: Oct 2006 Chapter/Region: AKIC Location: Home of Black Metal... Norway Vehicle: 
 2011 Puma Sneaks
Black with white stripez! 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by menusnearu01 I have find the good restaurants in US from the following site..

 http://health.yahoo.com/experts/eatt...t-restaurants/ 

You can also refer this site.......

 Menus Nearu 
 SPAMMMMMMMMM!!!!!!!! Kill it!   
 
 07_BluRex View Public Profile Find More Posts by 07_BluRex 
 
 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home NASIOC General   General Community   Newbies&amp;FAQs   Interior&amp;Exterior Modification   Car Care&amp;Detailing   Car Audio, Video&amp;Security   Motorsports     Autocross     Press Releases     Motorsports Specific Items For Sale   Proven Power Bragging   Member&apos;s Car Gallery   News&amp;Rumors     Non-Subaru News&amp;Rumors   Warranty Issues&amp;SOA Problems NASIOC Technical   Normally Aspirated Powertrain   Factory 2.0L Turbo Powertrain   Factory 2.5L Turbo Powertrain   Pre-2002 Factory Turbo Powertrain   Normally Aspirated with bolt-on Forced Induction Powertrain   Built Motor Discussion   Engine Management&amp;Tuning     AccessPort     UTEC     Commercial ECU Reflashes     Open Source Reflashes     Other Engine Management   Water/Methanol Injection, Nitrous&amp;Intercooler Cooling   Electrical&amp;Lighting   Transmission (AT/MT)&amp;Driveline   Brakes, Steering&amp;Suspension   Tire&amp;Wheel   Subaru Conversions   Custom Fabrication, Welding&amp;Tools   Service&amp;Maintenance   NASIOC Project Cars NASIOC Classifieds   Private &apos;For Sale&apos; Classifieds     Scammer Central     Engine/Power/Exhaust     Suspension/Brakes/Handling     Drivetrain     Wheels/Tires     Exterior/Styling     Interior/Dressup/Audio&amp;Security     Accessories&amp;Misc     Non-Subaru Stuff     Complete Car Part-Out     1993 - 2001 Impreza Specific Parts     Legacy Specific Parts     Motorsports Specific Items   Private &apos;Wanted&apos; Classifieds   Private Vehicle &apos;For Sale&apos; Classifieds   Vendor &apos;For Sale&apos; Classifieds     Engine/Power/Exhaust     Engine Management     Suspension/Brakes/Handling     Drivetrain     Wheels/Tires     Exterior/Styling     Interior/Dressup/Audio&amp;Security     Gauges&amp;Electronics     Accessories&amp;Misc     Car Care&amp;Detailing     Services     Vehicle Sales     Used, Open Box or Refurbished Items   Vendor Storefront Forums     Boomba Racing     Fred Beans Parts     IAG Performance     Import Image Racing     JDM Racing Motors     No Limit Motorsport     Perrin Performance     RavSpec   Vendor &apos;Group Buy&apos; Classifieds   Vendor &apos;General Sale&apos; Forum   Vendor &apos;One Day Sale&apos; Forum   Vendor Announcements NASIOC Reviews   Car Part Reviews   Vendor Reviews   Dealership Reviews NASIOC Chapters   Alaskan Impreza Club Forum -- AKIC   Bay Area Impreza Club Forum -- BAIC   Hawaii Impreza Club Forum -- HIIC   Mid Atlantic Impreza Club -- MAIC   Mid West Subaru Owners Club Forum -- MWSOC   New England Impreza Club Forum -- NESIC   North West Impreza Club Forum -- NWIC   Puerto Rico Impreza Club Forum -- PRSIC   Rocky Mountains Impreza Club Forum -- RMIC   Southern California Impreza Club Forum -- SCIC   South West Impreza Club Forum -- SWIC   Texas Impreza Club Forum -- TXIC   Vancouver Impreza Club Forum -- VIC NASIOC Regional Areas   Canada Region Forum     Western Canada     Eastern Canada   South East Region Forum   Tri-State Area Forum   International Forum NASIOC Subaru Models   Impreza Forum   Legacy Forum     Legacy Specific Parts For Sale   Forester Forum   Baja Forum   Outback Forum   Tribeca Forum   BRZ Forum   &apos;Old School&apos; Subaru Forum NASIOC Miscellaneous   Off-Topic     Political Playground     NASIOC Supporter Forum   Grassroots Motorsports Magazine Forum NASIOC Archives   NASIOC Archives     General Forum Archive     Technical Forum Archive     WRX Forum Archive     STi Forum Archive     SVX Forum Archive 
 


 Similar Threads Thread Thread Starter Forum Replies Last Post Name a nationwide chain of non-fast food restaurants you can&apos;t stand and why -=C=- Off-Topic 530 03-02-2012 02:11 PM Have you ever asked for grilled onions at fast food restaurants? nottheliving Off-Topic 48 07-18-2007 07:45 PM Santa Claus is rated the #1 richest man in the world, by Forbes [27] Off-Topic 10 09-29-2006 08:47 PM Friday&apos;s has turned into a sit down fast food restaurant. Johnny Knoxville Off-Topic 96 03-11-2005 01:15 AM 


 All times are GMT -4. The time now is 02:28 PM . 
 
 Contact Us - Forgot Password - Advertising - Archive - Privacy - Terms - Top 

 Powered by vBulletin®Version 3.7.0
Copyright©2000 - 2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
Powered by Searchlight ©2012 Axivo Inc. Copyright©1999 - 2011, North American Subaru Impreza Owners Club, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
