<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004219" url="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-504564_162-57405379-504564/hunger-games-hamburglar-hits-maine-mcdonalds-by-stealing-order-at-drive-thru-window/" time="2012-07-12-20:27" support="1" score="0.000524048850180206" bingtitle="Hunger Games: &quot;Hamburglar&quot; hits Maine McDonald&apos;s by stealing order ..." webtitle="Hunger Games: &quot;Hamburglar&quot; hits Maine McDonald&apos;s by stealing order at drive-thru window - Crossroads - CBS News">
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="146"/>
	<description>... Hamburglar&quot; hits Maine McDonald&apos;s by stealing order ... thief, found him in the parking lot of a rival fast food restaurant ... Health Care Bill: What&apos;s In It? Obama to heckler ...</description>
	<body>
		CBSNews.com | CBS Evening News | CBS This Morning | 48 Hours | 60 Minutes | Sunday Morning | Face the Nation | Up to the Minute 

 
 Log In | Register 

 Your Profile | Log Out 
 
 CBS News.com Politics 
 Video U.S. World Politics Entertainment HealthWatch MoneyWatch Tech Sports Photos Local 
 Atlanta Baltimore Boston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Hartford Houston Las Vegas Los Angeles Miami Minneapolis New York Philadelphia Pittsburgh Sacramento San Francisco Seattle St. Louis Tampa Washington 
 More 
 Popular Strange News Blogs Puzzles CBS News on Twitter Newsletters Podcasts Widgets CBS News Bios 
 

 Blogs: Political Hotsheet Crimesider Investigates HealthPop Celebrity Circuit Tech Talk More 
 The Feed What&apos;s Cooking WorldWatch EconWatch Author Talk Crossroads 
 Shows: 60 Overtime Hotsheet Live Radio Mobile 
 Scroll Left Scroll Right 
 Small Business 5 steps to building a stellar online reputation 1 of 9 CBS Evening News Officer: &quot;Tribal warfare&quot; on Chicago streets 2 of 9 Entertainment Bob Dylan, PBS dispute location of guitar 3 of 9 Political Hotsheet Why Romney welcomes the NAACP boos 4 of 9 CBS This Morning Rolling Stones still rockin&apos; at 50 5 of 9 U.S. Penn State probe condemns &quot;callous disregard&quot; 6 of 9 Video Shark jumps and snatches fish from couple 7 of 9 Gallery TV&apos;s most memorable moments 8 of 9 Feature 5 citizens who left the U.S. to avoid paying tax 9 of 9 
 March 28, 2012 8:37 AM 
 Print Text 
 
Hunger Games: &quot;Hamburglar&quot; hits Maine McDonald&apos;s by stealing order at drive-thru window
 By Barry Leibowitz Topics Daily Blotter 
&quot;Officer Big Mac,&quot;one of a series of characters in previous McDonald&apos;s ad campaigns
 (Credit:
Wikipedia) (CBS/AP) AUGUSTA, Maine - With a &quot;Hamburglar&quot; on the loose, maybe Officer Big Mac needs to get back on the case.


Police say a young man, seemingly inspired by the pattie-pilfering character once featured in McDonald&apos;s advertising campaigns, ran between a car and the takeout window at an Augusta restaurant Sunday night as an employee tried to hand a bag of food to a driver.



A witness flagged down an officer who was leaving a nearby convenience store.



Lt. Christopher Massey, acting on a description of the hungry thief, found him in the parking lot of a rival fast food restaurant diving into a McDonald&apos;s bag.



Massey tells the Kennebec Journal the suspect swore and ran into the woods. He was never caught.



Massey says the three young men who had their food stolen didn&apos;t know the &quot;hamburglar.&quot;



McDonald&apos;s replaced the stolen food, worth about $20.



 0 Add A Comment + Add a comment Subscribe to this comment thread by email SUBMIT Click here to add another comment. The posting of advertisements, profanity, or personal attacks is prohibited. By using this Web site you agree to accept our Terms of Service . Click here to read the Rules of Engagement . Comment reply 
 Subscribe to this comment thread by email Submit Cancel The posting of advertisements, profanity, or personal attacks is prohibited. By using this Web site you agree to accept our Terms of Service . Click here to read the Rules of Engagement . 
Report offensive content:

If you believe this comment is offensive or violates the CBSNews.com Terms of Use , you can report it below (this will not automatically remove the comment). Once reported, our staff will be notified and the comment will be reviewed.

 Select type of offense: 

 Offensive: Sexually explicit or offensive language

 Spam: Advertisements, commercial links, or repetitive posts

 Disruptive posting: Flaming or offending other users

 Illegal activities: Promote cracked software, or other illegal content

 Off-topic: Commentary unrelated to the storyline

 Comments (optional):
 Report Cancel 
E-mail this comment to a friend.

 E-mail this to: 
 
 Your e-mail address: 
 Send me a copy of this message
 Note: Your e-mail address is used only to let the recipient know who sent the e-mail and in case of transmission error. Neither your address nor the recipients&apos;s address will be used for any other purpose.

 Add your own personal message: (Optional)
 Hi, I found this user&apos;s comment on CBSNews.com and thought you might be interested in reading it. Send e-mail Cancel Popular Now in Politics 
 
 post 
 House passes health care repeal, again 
 post 
 Romney booed at NAACP 
 post 
 Chris Christie &quot;by the numbers&quot; 
 
 Why Romney welcomes the NAACP boos At NAACP, Biden booed -- for ending his speech More independent voters back health care repeal Rep. Jackson suffering from &quot;mood disorder&quot; Romney booed at NAACP Romney booed by NAACP crowd Romney&apos;s tenure at Bain questioned Romney to raise money with Cheney Romney&apos;s wealth an issue for 20 percent of voters House passes health care repeal, again Health Care Bill: What&apos;s In It? Top governors&apos; races to watch Debt has increased more under Obama than Bush Chris Christie &quot;by the numbers&quot; Dem Rep. Worries Guam Could &quot;Capsize&quot; Romney&apos;s undisclosed assets worth millions? 
 
Follow Crossroads

 RSS» Facebook» Twitter» 
 Most Popular on CBS News 
 Stories More» 

 01 Officer: &quot;Tribal warfare&quot; on Chicago streets 02 Newspaper: DOJ lawyer tried to stifle reporter 03 Why Romney welcomes the NAACP boos 04 Penn State probe condemns &quot;callous disregard&quot; 05 Outlaws motorcycle gang hit with mass arrests 
 
 Videos More» 

 01 Shark jumps and snatches fish from couple 02 7/11: Firsthand look at Chicago gang violence; TV&apos;s most memorable moments 03 Families in murder case brawl outside courtroom 
 
 35 Photos | View Gallery» 
 Stars at the ESPYs 12 Photos | View Gallery» 
 George Zimmerman crime scene photos 8 Photos | View Gallery» 
 Guinness World Records&apos; wackiest sports record holders 36 Photos | View Gallery» 
 Who will you see at Comic-Con 2012? 8 Photos | View Gallery» 
 Make-A-Wish recipient Zachary meets Hellboy 
 Scroll Left Scroll Right More» CBS This Morning now on iPad&amp;iPhone! GET THE FREE APP CBS News on Facebook CBS News 
Copyright©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. 
 CBSNews.com Site Map Video Site Map Mobile/WAP Site Help Contact Us CBS Bios Careers Internships Development Programs 

 Topics China United Nations Social Security North Korea Terrorism Capital Punishment Immigration Gay Marriage 

 Disaster in Japan Foreclosures Debt Crisis Massacre in Norway Election 2012 Marijuana Rupert Murdoch 9/11: Tragedy 

 Follow Us Facebook Twitter RSS Email Newsletters YouTube CBS Mobile 

 
 CBS This Morning iPad App 
 
Enjoy CBS This Morning all day long! Get instant access to original news stories, videos and interviews from Gayle King, Erica Hill and more.
 
 
 Visit other CBS Interactive sites: Select Site BNET CBS College Sports CBS Radio CBS.com CBSNews.com CBSSports.com CHOW CNET CNET Channel GameSpot International Last.fm MaxPreps Moblogic MP3.com mySimon NCAA Search.com TechRepublic The Insider TV.com UrbanBaby.com UWIRE Wallstrip ZDNet BNET CBS College Sports CBS Radio CBS.com CBSNews.com CBSSports.com CHOW CNET CNET Channel GameSpot International Last.fm MaxPreps Moblogic MP3.com mySimon NCAA Search.com TechRepublic The Insider TV.com UrbanBaby.com UWIRE Wallstrip ZDNet Privacy Policy Terms of Use Mobile User Agreement About CBS Advertise
	</body>
</document>
