<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004420" url="http://colleenscookbook.wordpress.com/2008/01/16/favorite-frozen-meals-michelinas-lean-gourmet/" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="1" score="0.0017785787629256314" bingtitle="Favorite Frozen Meals: Michelina’s Lean Gourmet « Colleen’s ..." webtitle="Favorite Frozen Meals: Michelinas Lean GourmetColleens Cookbook">
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>... to biodegrade than all those plastic trays ... in my own mind having worked once at a fast-food restaurant. ... offers advice on healthy eating, meal planning, and ...</description>
	<body>
		Colleen’s Cookbook 
 
 Home About Me Recipe Box 
 
Favorite Frozen Meals: Michelina’s Lean Gourmet

 January 16, 2008 at 10:31 am 8 comments 

 Visit Pennies&amp;Pounds for a revised and updated version of this Michelina’s Lean Gourmet article, along with more posts on weight loss and healthy eating on a budget ! 

Michelina’s may be at the low end of the frozen-food market, but you have to give them credit. That cardboard packaging may sometimes impart a little papery flavor to the food it holds, but it’s a highly efficient design, more likely to biodegrade than all those plastic trays and cellophane wrappers we toss out after our lunch breaks.

My mom used to stock the freezer with several of these (among others) for us kids to heat up on days we didn’t feel like a sandwich for lunch or had to fend for ourselves for dinner. Actually, these really were more likely lunch fare—for dinner, it was usually the stocks of Marie Callendar’s chicken pot pie and frozen entrées that would get tapped.

Marie Callendar’s frozen food takes way too much prep time for lunch (or, frankly, dinner) most of the time, in my opinion. Plus, some have nutritional stats that make you wonder why you’re not just picking up a to-go meal from Olive Garden.

Anyway, onward to the review.

Michelina’s Lean Gourmet

 Macaroni&amp;Cheese 

I realize the convenience factor is small here, as it’s not so difficult to whip up a box of mac and cheese and stuff it in Tupperware. However, when I was a kid and less familiar with the stove, this was definitely a freezer favorite. I don’t find any of the more expensive frozen mac and cheese dinners to be at all superior to my taste buds, so if I felt a desire to pack myself a plate for lunch, I bought this. The serving is definitely way small, but it’s only 270 calories.

I don’t remember most of the other meals listed on the Lean Gourmet home page—Albertson’s fails me again. Some look promising, such as this Vegetable Rice Pilaf that looks chock-full of colorful veggies, if the picture is to be believed.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Entry filed under: Grocery Goodies , Healthy Eating , Reviews . Tags: food , frozen foods , losing weight , shopping .
 
 Favorite Frozen Meals: Smart Ones Favorite Frozen Meals: Gardenburger 
 
8 Comments Add your own 

 
 1. donna  | September 24, 2008 at 4:10 am
 
i love the michelina meals better on price and taste
 Reply 
 2. donna  | September 24, 2008 at 4:11 am
 
thanks
 Reply 
 3. donna  | September 24, 2008 at 4:12 am
 
i love the lean gourmet pepper steak with rice
 Reply 
 4. donna  | September 24, 2008 at 4:13 am
 
south beach is too expensive and not at all tasteful like others
 Reply 
 5. donna  | September 24, 2008 at 4:15 am
 
also love the pizza and pasta michelinas has
 Reply 
 6. HermanTurnip  | February 25, 2009 at 9:24 am
 
My wife found a huge bug in one of Micheelina’s frozen meals. Details can be found here:

 http://terribleanalogies.com/2009/02/insect-found-in-dinner/ 

I’d advise everyone to avoid this product. The other half of this bug is still out there…
 Reply 
 
 7. Colleen  | February 25, 2009 at 7:44 pm
 
Never happened to me. Despite that, I’m still the sort of person who believes that if we let every gross-out food mistake get to us, we’d never eat anything for fear of its potential hair, bug, mold, or other icky content. The fact that everyone’s hands are covered in germs doesn’t generally stop me from reaching for the popcorn bowl, so why get worked up if I find a hair on my plate? It’s not made of uranium.

Say what you will of how it’s indicative of poor sanitary standards behind the scenes. Salmonella, like we’ve found in the peanut butter plant, is indicative of poor management, for sure. But other things…well, I allow for a lot of human error in my own mind having worked once at a fast-food restaurant. I never got sick from the food, and preparation conditions were no worse than any home kitchen, but I bet a lot of people would have been horrified to know what happened to their food before it hit their tray. For example, at the place I worked, the person in charge of cleaning the dishes–a hands-on job since we had no automatic dishwasher–was also the person in charge of serving drive-thru customers. Believe me, when you had to run to the front, take an order, and get food out the window in 90 seconds, you didn’t take time to wash the chemicals and filth off your hands.

I doubt I’ll convince anyone not to cringe at that idea here, but I offer my relaxed opinion anyway. To each his own!
 Reply 
 
 8. Sandy  | March 9, 2009 at 1:44 pm
 
Just wanted 2 say i love your lean meals&amp;how they have ww points on them. i just wish i could find them in more stores near me.
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 Trackback this post  |  Subscribe to the comments via RSS Feed 
 
 About The Cookbook 
 
Come for the recipes I’ve created, enjoyed, or discovered and the themed collections from my Recipe Box. Stay for the links to interesting food blogs and food-related articles, product reviews, and kitchen stories.

 Subscribe to my blog   

 Subscribe by e-mail 
 Search for: 
 My Other Sites 
 
 

 Pennies&amp;Pounds offers advice on healthy eating, meal planning, and weight loss. You&apos;ll find tips for making nutritious choices while staying within a reasonable budget as well as reviews of products and tools to aid a healthier lifestyle.

 

 Sharp Pencils provides helpful how-tos and inspiring activities that help kids excel at writing. Also, teachers will appreciate the printable activity sheets, daily journal prompts and vocabulary words, links to other literacy sites, and more!
 
 Categories 

 Around the Kitchen Book Looks Cookie Calendar Eating Grocery Goodies Healthy Eating Holidays Looks Tasty Recipe Box Recipe Roundup Recipes Reviews Tip File 
 
 Recent Posts 

 New Articles on Cooking, Meal Planning, and Healthy Living Cookie Calendar Lives! South Beach Living Pudding Cups Dinner at a Greek Diner Slowing Down, Speeding Up 
 
 Top Posts 

 Recipe Box Favorite Frozen Meals: South Beach Living (and More from Kraft) Cookie Calendar: Spicy Chocolate Cookies Easy Bean Patties Favorite Frozen Meals: Lean Cuisine 
 
 Tags 
 appetizers Asian bacon baking beans beef breakfast chicken Christmas comfort food cookies cooking dessert diet dinner dip eggs food From the Archives frozen foods gifts Halloween Healthy Eating Italian losing weight lunch Meal Makeover meal planning Mexican nutrition original recipe pantry pasta potatoes salad sandwich sauce sausage shopping Slovakia software soup Thanksgiving vegetables weight loss 
 Archives 

 July 2009 December 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 
 
 Recent Comments 

 Colleen on Cookie Calendar: Spicy Chocola… Anthony on Cookie Calendar: Spicy Chocola… Colleen on Favorite Frozen Meals: South B… ilva mcbrayer on Favorite Frozen Meals: South B… Minty M&amp;M Cookie… on Cookie Calendar: Minty Christm… 
 
 Looks Tasty 
 
 Blogroll 

 A Hamburger Today Back to the Table Beauty Eats Bite of the Best Cheap Eats Cooking for 2 Diner’s Journal Epi-Log Feeding Frenzy Fit Fare Hungry Girl Hungry Girl on Yahoo Just Bento Kalyn’s Kitchen MacGourmet.com NPR Food Serious Eats Simply Recipes Slashfood Snack Pack Supermarket Sampler Taquitos.net The Kitchen Sink The Pioneer Woman Cooks Well Yahoo Food Editor’s Picks 
 
 Recipe Sources 

 All Recipes America’s Test Kitchen AOL Food Campbell’s Kitchen Cook’s Country Cook’s Illustrated Epicurious Every Day with Rachael Ray Everyday Food Fine Cooking Food Network Food Network Canada Good Housekeeping Kraft Foods Martha Stewart Food NY Times Dining&amp;Wine Real Simple Top Secret Recipes Yahoo Food 
 
Theme: Blix by Sebastian Schmieg . Blog at WordPress.com .
 Follow 
 Follow“Colleen&apos;s Cookbook” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
