<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004078" url="http://archives.midweek.com/content/columns/onthemove_article/losing_pounds_like_a_biggest_loser/" time="2012-07-12-20:18" support="1" score="0.0061970601196330195" bingtitle="Losing Pounds Like A ‘Biggest Loser’ | On The Move | Midweek.com" webtitle="Losing Pounds Like ABiggest Loser| On The Move | Midweek.com">
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>Place A Classified Ad; Government Section; Hawaii ... “What I did with my food is very similar to what ... I would go to a fast food restaurant and order dinner for myself and my ...</description>
	<body>
		77°F mostly cloudy 
 
 
 MIDWEEK.COM | MIDWEEK KAUA&apos;I | JOBS | AUTOS | STAR CLASSIFIEDS   

 HOME MIDWEEK 
 Coverstory Feature Story Newsmaker 
 BUSINESS 
 Round Table Entrepreneurs Movers 
 CALENDAR 
 What&apos;s Up Ongoing 
 COMMUNITY 
 Central East West Windward Military Star News Focus on Oahu 
 EDITOR&apos;S DESK 
 Classics Column Letters Special 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 Games Scene@Night TV Listings Uncle Tom&apos;s Gabbin&apos; Video Xposure 
 EXPERT ADVICE 
 Doctor In The House Health&amp;Wellness Hot Tips 
 FASHION 
 Fashion Flash MWSpace SMART Style 
 FOOD 
 Broke Da Mout Food&amp;Beverage  Focus Heart-y Chef Sam Choy&apos;s Kitchen Table Talk Vino Sense 
 LIFESTYLE 
 Applause Click Chick Currents Good Neighbors Guest Column Hot Shots MidWeek Poll Moonlighting Old Friends Pa&apos;ina Pet Parade Proof Positive Susan&apos;s Page Mystery&apos;s Shopper The Wild Side The Young View What&apos;s Next 
 MOVIES 
 Hot Ticket Show Times 
 ART&amp;MUSIC 
 Art&amp;Stage Music Montage Musical Notes 
 POLITICS 
 A Conservative  Estimate Coffee Break Dick Adair Just Thoughts Mostly Politics Roy Chang The Right Price 
 SPORTS/FITNESS 
 Curran Events Hot Air Keeping Score On The Move 
 TRAVEL 
 Kimo&apos;s Vegas Tourism Matters 
 RESOURCES 
 Archive Advanced Search Contact info Help/FAQ Rack locator RSS/XML Feeds Sitemap Subscription Services 
 BOOKSTORE 
 Diana Helfand Don Chapman Jerry Coffee Jo McGarry Sam Choy Tom Moffatt 
 CLASSIFIED ADS 
 Place A Classified Ad Government Section Hawaii Real Estate Hawaii Rentals Hawaii Jobs Autos 
 


 MIDWEEK PARTNERS Del.icio.us 

 

 
 
 
 
 
 

 SPORTS/FITNESS &gt; On The Move 
Losing Pounds Like A‘Biggest Loser’
 By .(JavaScript must be enabled to view this email address) 
Friday - September 23, 2009
 E-mail this story | Print this page | Comments (0)| Archive | RSS | Share Del.icio.us 
 
 
 
 Alexis Mundis 
 
 
I’m so excited because the new season of The Biggest Loser has just started. And from just the very first episode I was already in tears. The stories of these contestants - what they’ve been through and are going through ... and their weight, OMG, their weight! I get so touched each season with their stories and achievements and I just can’t wait to witness a new group of contestants and their journey to weight loss.

East Oahu resident Alexis Mundis also loves The Biggest Loser , especially last season’s show featuring Kristin Steede and her mom Cathy Skell.

“When I watched her story last season, it was almost like watching myself on TV,”explains Mundis, 23.“I really was inspired to change my life.”

Soon after, she discovered that Steede had a blog and decided to write to her. They connected and Mundis eventually found other women with similar goals and together they formed a support group, calling themselves the Sisterhood of the Shrinking Pants.

 
 

Now, seven months later, Mundis has gone from weighing 426 pounds to 266, and is training for the Honolulu Marathon this December.

She also will get to meet, along with the rest of Hawaii, the woman who motivated her to lose the weight.

That’s right, Steede and Skell will both be here for three special events Sept. 24, 26 and 27.
 
 
 Biggest Loser Season 7 contestants Kristin Steede with mom Cathy Skell 
 
 
The Sept. 24 (Thursday) event takes place at the University of Hawaii’s Manoa Campus Center Ballroom. Registration starts at 6:30 p.m. and the presentation begins at 7 p.m. Cost is $15 per person.

“My mom and I will both talk about life before The Biggest Loser , life on ( The Biggest Loser ) ranch, what it was like working out with Jillian Michaels and Bob Harper, and also the lessons we’ve learned and what life is like now,”says Steede, who turns 30 while in Hawaii Sept. 28.“I think just hearing our journey is one of the most powerful events for people. We’ll also open it to questions and answers.”

Steede’s starting weight on The Biggest Loser was 360 pounds. When she was eliminated at week 16, she weighed 193 pounds. Now, she’s about 205 pounds.

She blames an addiction to food and lack of exercise for her weight, but with the help of The Biggest Loser , has realized the cause and triggers of this very bad habit.

“I was always this chubby little girl, and my parents divorced when I was 9 years old,”recalls Steede.“And for whatever reason, I took comfort in eating when my parents were going through that because I just got larger and larger ever since that age on up.

 


“What I did with my food is very similar to what my mom did with her alcohol bottles. (Skell struggled with alcoholism but celebrates more than 20 years of sobriety this year.) I would go to a fast food restaurant and order dinner for myself and my husband and order a double-cheese-burger to eat on my way home and take that wrapper and crumple it up and hide it in my purse or my console of my car and pretend it never happened.”

Steede admits that the hardest part about being home since The Biggest Loser is her temptation with food.

“It’s easy to say no to food when there’s cameras in your face, but now the cameras are gone and there’s no one holding you accountable except for yourself.”

The Sept. 26 event (Saturday) is a hike through a bamboo forest and rain forest to Manoa Falls. Cost is $25 per person. The hike starts at 9 a.m. and space is limited.

And for the final event on Sept. 27 (Sunday), Steede and Skell team up with Crossfit Oahu to give you a taste of what working out on The Biggest Loser was like. The class starts at 9 a.m. Cost is $45 per person.

For more information on any of these events or to register, email .(JavaScript must be enabled to view this email address) or call 920-268-1533.
 Books Written By MidWeek Columnist To Book Store &gt;&gt; 
 E-mail this story | Print this page | Comments (0)| Archive | RSS Comments (0)|


Most Recent Comment(s):
 
Posting a comment on MidWeek.com requires a free registration .
 
Username

 

Password

 

 Auto Login

 

 Forgot Password 
 
 

 Classified Ads Legal Notices Twitter Facebook 
 Advertising information 
 

 
 

 
 
 
 

 
 Hawaii Luxury
Magazine 

 Tiare Asia and Alex Bing were spotted at the Sugar Ray&apos;s Bar Lounge View more photos &gt;&gt; 
 


 
 Search Yellow Pages
 
 Popular Searches Apartments in Honolulu 
 Attorneys in Honolulu 
 Auto Dealers in Honolulu 
 Auto Parts in Honolulu 
 Auto Repair in Honolulu 
 Beauty Salons in Honolulu 
 Car Rental in Honolulu 
 Dentists in Honolulu 
 Doctors in Honolulu 
 Flowers in Honolulu 
 Hotels in Honolulu 
 Insurance in Honolulu 
 Loans in Honolulu 
 Mortgages in Honolulu 
 Movers in Honolulu 
 Pizza in Honolulu 
 Realtors in Honolulu 
 Restaurants in Honolulu 
 Storage in Honolulu 
 Tax Preparation in Honolulu 
 Travel in Honolulu 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com © MidWeek Printing, Inc. A Oahu Publications Company. All Rights Reserved.
 Terms under which this service is provided to you. Read our privacy guidelines. Contact us . 
 Your Print Ad Here!
	</body>
</document>
