<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004762" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/pepes-mexican-food-alhambra-2" time="2012-07-12-21:16" support="1" score="0.0007595367004069499" bingtitle="Pepe&apos;s Mexican Food - Alhambra - Alhambra, CA" webtitle="Pepe&apos;s Mexican Food - Alhambra - Alhambra, CA">
			<query id="000172" bing-rank="111"/>
	<description>Best Mexican fast food restaurant in town! Every thing is ... the price is reasonable- especially since you receive ... refills, kids meals, drive thru, and outside seats.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Pepe&apos;s Mexican Food
 157 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Mexican Mexican   [Edit] 
 511 W Valley Blvd 
 Alhambra , CA 91803 
Neighborhood: Alhambra
 (626) 289-8618 http://www.theoriginalpepes.com Announcement 
Now accepting all major credit cards!!
 1 of 44 Add Photos View All Photos Hours: 
Mon-Thu, Sun 6 am - 12 am

Fri-Sat 6 am - 2 am
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Street, Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Price Range: $ 
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: Free
 Good For: Lunch, Dinner
 Alcohol: No
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: No
 Caters: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 Dogs Allowed: Yes
 First to Review Robyn d L. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
 Reviews (157) About This Business 
 Yelp Sponsor 
 
 
157 reviews for Pepe&apos;s Mexican Food
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;Oh of course, we always get the Chili cheese fries .&quot; In 19 reviews &quot;I get them with carne asada and they are great.&quot; In 30 reviews &quot;Come check out the best breakfast burrito in town.&quot; In 12 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
157 reviews in English

 
Review from Christine L. 
 
 115 friends 35 reviews 

 Christine L. 
 
Montebello, CA
 7/9/2012 1 photo 
Love their taquitos. They drown it in awesome guacamole. Not the watery cut corners kind. Real guacamole. Which is what makes it awesome. Because other Mexican places sometimes get stingy with the guacamole to taquitos ratio. I pay attention to things like this so for their taquitos alone, it&apos;s worth going.

Other things to note:

-- Carne Asada burrito is good. But portion is big and I can never finish it.
-- They have a drive thru.
-- You can get your own squeeze bottle of chili.
-- It gets windy with their outdoor only seating so make sure you don&apos;t send your napkins flying around when at the table.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michael L. 
 
 20 friends 68 reviews 

 Michael L. 
 
San Gabriel, CA
 7/10/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
Came here with the girlfriend because we were craving some Mexican food. We ordered the Carne Asada burrito and Carne Asada fries.

The burrito was pretty dry, with little to no sauce at all. Completely flavorless.

The Carne Asada fries was under cooked.

Maybe we just had bad luck with the orders, but i&apos;ve definitely had MUCH better. I&apos;d rather recommend Alberto&apos;s if you want to get your fix of Mexican food.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (4) Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Miguel V. 
 
 1 friend 18 reviews 

 Miguel V. 
 
Whittier, CA
 7/2/2012 
Stopped by for lunch.  Wasn&apos;t too hungry so I ordered some a la carte taquitos.  They were great.  I have had food from the Pepe&apos;s in Downey and in Anaheim.  Both are great and so was the food at this establishment.  For food I give the place four stars, but the dining area leaves much to be desired.

The seating is outside, which I don&apos;t mind, but one of the inherent problems is that the drive thru for vehicles comes directly through the dining area splitting seating on both sides where cars pass.   There seemed to be this garbage smell, like raw sewage.  I had to move not to get a whiff of the ripe smell.  Pretty gross.

The food is great, but do yourself a favor and get the food to go.  The Mexican music was way too loud and I had to shout to place my order and get a refill.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tiffany P. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 130 friends 377 reviews 

 Tiffany P. 
 
Chino, CA
 7/2/2012 1 Check-in Here 
After getting off of graveyard shift, all I could think about was demolishing a breakfast burrito...  I ordered the chorizo, egg, and potato burrito with cheese.  That thing was massive!  Suffice to say, I only finished half of it.  It was freshly made and totally hit the spot.

I also remember Pepe&apos;s taquitos being bomb too, I&apos;ll have to get that next time around.

Friendly drive-thru service!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Robert R. 
 
 17 friends 112 reviews 

 Robert R. 
 
Sun City, CA
 6/28/2012 1 Check-in Here 
One of those great places you find in LA that is laid back and not expensive but serves great food.

Gets really busy during lunch, do yourself a favor and get there early to avoid the rush. There is limited parking in the rear and the back alley and the drive thru will make it difficult to get in and out of during busy times.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from andrew i. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 andrew i. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 7/5/2012 
Pepe&apos;s is one of the staples of Mexican food in the Alhambra area. It&apos;s actually the original location and has been around for over 20 years. I warn you, not everyone will be satisfied here because it depends on what you order! If you&apos;re a regular then you definitely know the scoop. As a kick starter, I&apos;ll recommend the taquitos or chili fries. It&apos;s definitely a good alternative to the hoards of asian restaurants which surround the area or from other mexican spots such as king taco. According to Yelp, they just started accepting credit cards which is a plus.

P.S.
Outdoor only seating but a drive thru is available!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Susan H. 
 
 4 friends 3 reviews 

 Susan H. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 5/20/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I&apos;ve only been here for breakfast, but I&apos;ve come about 3 times and it is really good for your most important meal of the day!

So some of the things I&apos;ve tried is the regular Breakfast Burrito, Pepe&apos;s Breakfast Burrito, Chili Rellenos Breakfast Quesadilla, and one of their breakfast fries item. They were all pretty good, but my favorites have come down to their normal Breakfast Burrito with bacon, and their Chili Rellenos Breakfast Quesadilla.

They&apos;re opened at 6am for breakfast, so you can catch breakfast even if you have work early in the morning! The breakfast burrito with bacon has a good combination of bacon, potatoes, cheese, and salsa wrapped in a very large tortilla to keep it from spilling out. So you don&apos;t get your hands dirty from eating it! The bacon was crispy and made a very good blend with the rest of the burrito. I&apos;ve also tried it with bacon and didn&apos;t enjoy it as much.

The Chili Rellenos Breakfast Quesadilla was delicious. It wasn&apos;t oily at all, which made it such a good breakfast item! It was crispy on the outside where the tortilla was fried, and n the inside had a very good amount of cheese with the chili.

Parking was simple and easy in the back of the building, and the servers were all really nice. They&apos;re not too stingy with their salsa too like a lot of other places are, so they will give you enough for you to accompany your meal. They have a very large variety of food on their menu and I&apos;m sure that you will be able to find something to your liking.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from johanna e. 
 
 13 friends 32 reviews 

 johanna e. 
 
Pasadena, CA
 6/22/2012 
The last time I ate here I found a piece of plastic (I think it was from some kind of wrapper) IN my burrito. Won&apos;t be coming back.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Invisible P. 
 
 3 friends 93 reviews 

 Invisible P. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 5/16/2012 
Was in the area early in the morning so my partner said we had to stop. Had a breakfast burrito. Very good...the green sauce was excellant as well. Will have to try an afternoon stop as well.
All the burritos in the moring looked good!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mister B. 
 
 0 friends 30 reviews 

 Mister B. 
 
Glendale, CA
 5/1/2012 
To all the naysayers who said this is not &quot;authentic Mexican&quot; food... get a life!

First of all this place has been here for almost 50 years, almost as long as me, so I think that makes it pretty authentic in my book.  In my opinion Pepe&apos;s has the best of the best when it comes to fast food Mexican that you are going to find anywhere. In fact, I would rather eat Pepe&apos;s sitting outside in the rain than eat at ANY Mexican full service resturaunt in the Los Angeles area; it&apos;s that good.  Pepe&apos;s has the very best taquitos and hard shell tacos, LOADED with fresh roasted beef, and covered with guacamole. I recommend the #8 taco plate to all first timers, and you&apos;ll see what I mean.

Pros:  they have been doing this for many years and they have it down

Cons: you may have to wait in line, and there may not be a place to sit and eat.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Layla A. 
 
 2 friends 5 reviews 

 Layla A. 
 
Monterey Park, CA
 6/26/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
BOMB ASS GREASY TACOS... love it
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Dori D. 
 
 66 friends 50 reviews 

 Dori D. 
 
San Diego, CA
 5/30/2012 
Wet Burrito!!!! GET IN MY BELLY!!!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from John N. 
 
 310 friends 848 reviews 

 John N. 
 
Manhattan, NY
 4/11/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
***************************3.5********************­***

I been craving mexican food forever since I been living in the east coast for the past 3 1/2 yrs. This is one of my first stop to go and I just love their breakfast here. I got a breakfast burrito and a chorizo, eggs, bean and rice plate which I love. Everything was fresh and cheap and delicious!!!

I can&apos;t wait to come back already!!!!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Pat B. 
 
 1 friend 6 reviews 

 Pat B. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 6/25/2012 
Love this place! I eat here once a week and almost always get the hard shell tacos. Wonderful crunch to them and filled with meat and cheese. Also, the breakfast burritos are a whole meal to themselves and served all day. Great for a non-morning person.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Willis W. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 70 friends 154 reviews 

 Willis W. 
 
San Gabriel, CA
 4/20/2012 3 Check-ins Here 
Parking: IN THE BACK. Very limited parking
Tip: They have drive through!

Got the breakfast burrito and the Pepe&apos;s Breakfast Burrito.
Breakfast burrito: Huge filled with egg, potatoes, and bacon. They don&apos;t skimp out on the bacon. Every single bit had chunks of bacon. Worth the money. I finished it and was full until dinner. Can definitely split between two meals.

Pepe&apos;s Breakfast burrito: Same thing as the regular burrito except there is avolcado and it is wet. Good god they put this monstrosity in a box covered with sauce. I had to split this to two and a half meals cause it is so huge. Definitely am coming back here to try some other stuff. But this is on the list of food to get here!

Workers are really nice and friendly! A place to get your mexican food cravings. They open as early as 6.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nikki A. 
 
 8 friends 13 reviews 

 Nikki A. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 5/9/2012 
Nothing short of amazing. Best Mexican food ever! I highly suggest Chili Cheese Fries, you will not be disappointed!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Shane S. 
 
 144 friends 206 reviews 

 Shane S. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 3/8/2012 
I used to miss 4th period taking extra long lunches from Alhambra High... just to get to  this place! It even has a drive thru!!  I love their tacos and taquitos with their homemade guacamole. all the burritos are just as good, but I usually get the carnitas, machaca, or the carne asada.
I really can&apos;t say enough about this place as I love it! The food is always made to order, and they always give you plenty of salsa! Homestyle fast food at its finest!
 
 Listed in: Mexican 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Pete C. 
 
 24 friends 328 reviews 

 Pete C. 
 
Reseda, CA
 3/21/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Carne asada fries were OK.

Bean and Cheese burrito was OK, but HUGE!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Neeek C. 
 
 31 friends 127 reviews 

 Neeek C. 
 
Covina, CA
 4/21/2012 
Best Chili Cheese Fries in town. Yes, better than The Hat. The only bad thing about this place is that it doesn&apos;t stay open late because it would be the perfect place to come after a night of drinking. But then again, I guess the restaurants on valley give this place quite of bit of competition in that area.

Anyways, probably one of the best mexican food places on town. Parking is kind of a hassle but they have a drive-thru and there is plenty of street parking around this place.

I recommend chili cheese fries, carne asada fries and the burritos here.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (2) Cool (3) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Sarah S. 
 
 181 friends 177 reviews 

 Sarah S. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 1/18/2012 2 photos 1 Check-in Here 
This is why I can&apos;t lose weight being surrounded by cheap good eats.
Apparently they have items off the menu but I&apos;m a newbie so I stuck with what looked yummy on the menu.

Tried a hard taco w/ guacamole (shredded beef)
chili cheese fries (good, but next time I&apos;ll add guacamole)
carne asada burrito (wet for $1 more) - one of the best burritos!

There&apos;s a drive thru, but was able to park on the street and order to-go.  Also, their exterior sign is damaged so there is no sign! It was easy to spot since it stuck out like a sore thumb on a street packed with Chinese eats.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (4) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Binh T. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 77 friends 176 reviews 

 Binh T. 
 
San Gabriel, CA
 1/7/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I really wanted to like this place, I really did.

Was craving for burritos today so yelped for some close by and got Pepe&apos;s. This place been around since the beginning of my lifetime and I always pass by the Rosemead one, so finally gave it a chance. Ordered the Carne Asada burrito with rice substitute instead of beans for $4.99 and Carne Asada fries for about $7. The burrito was dry. Rice, meat and a bit of salsa in it and that&apos;s it. No sauce or flavor. Didn&apos;t even finish my half of it because it was so bland. The Carne Asada fries was okay. I could tell some fries were not fully fried. There was very less guacamole and the guacamole had big chunks of avocado.

Two stars because it really was &quot;Meh. I&apos;ve experienced better.&quot;
 
 Listed in: Take Out 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (3) Cool (3) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Adam O. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 126 friends 88 reviews 

 Adam O. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 4/24/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
Pepe&apos;s is right on that cusp of being really good overall and being stuck in the mediocre West San Gabriel Valley Mexican Food category. The best thing there is definitely the carne asada nachos. You get a mountain of chips smothered in freshly grated cheese, beans, guacamole, salsa, and carne asada. The meat is always seasoned pretty well but there&apos;s a lot of nervey and chewy pieces in there which is kind of a bummer. Everything else is ok but will taste even better with a few beers!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Shelly T. 
 
 99 friends 22 reviews 

 Shelly T. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 2/19/2012 
carne asada fries are sooooo good (fatty and salty, just the way i like it).  A size small is filling enough. Lots of crinkle cut fries smothered in cheese, meat, guacamole. Definitely fulfilled my craving for fries.

people there are also friendly.

parking is available, and i think they may have a drive through kind of thing...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Elle D. 
 
 50 friends 34 reviews 

 Elle D. 
 
West Covina, CA
 1/9/2012 1 photo 
Aww, come on. I ordered carne asada guys, not some pork concoction with onions and bell peppers.

So yea, at least 1/3 of my carne asada nacho fries was PORK. Edible, but not what I wanted. There was a lot of sauce with the pork. I had no idea what it was.

Not coming back. I&apos;m making the extra drive to another Mexican joint, like King Taco off the 710.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Chris E. 
 
 13 friends 10 reviews 

 Chris E. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 3/5/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Coming from sd, I&apos;ve tried all types of mexican food, and paid for all types of mexican food as well.

They charge 3 bucks for 2 rolled tacos. TWO! I can get 10 for 5 bucks in SD... anyway...

Any way, each $1.50 rolled taco was smothered in guacomole, and had little to no taste. Ordered the breakfast burrito as well. It was ok, but my advice is to get it without beans.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mrs G. 
 
 4 friends 41 reviews 

 Mrs G. 
 
Upland, CA
 3/28/2012 
So I&apos;ve never been to a Pepe&apos;s. I grew up in Covina my whole life have never eaten at the one on Azusa just because the location never appealed to me and I&apos;ve never heard of this place. My cousin took me to this one in  Alhambra. This is my 3rd favorite bean and cheese burrito I&apos;ve tasted. So I have to compare it to my favorites. The beans were great! The tortilla was kind hard on some areas which that was a turn off since the best are all soft. The cheese was way at the bottom and not even melted by the time I got to it. I could see it was grated very finely. I like thick grated cheese melted all through out. But it wasn&apos;t bad still very good compared to most places but not the best.  If I was in the area I would eat one again for sure. Now I would try the Covina location .
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Sheep M. 
 
 9 friends 72 reviews 

 Sheep M. 
 
Sacramento, CA
 11/30/2011 
I&apos;ve been hooked on this place for years, and I&apos;m sure to stop in and get a fix everytime I&apos;m in town.

They serve up the best chili cheese fries and breakfast burritos around. A must try!!

Too bad they don&apos;t take card- be sure to swing by an ATM first.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from nic p. 
 
 0 friends 3 reviews 

 nic p. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 4/29/2012 
Best Mexican food in town. Hands down! Everything is good here.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Daniel R. 
 
 0 friends 33 reviews 

 Daniel R. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 4/5/2012 5 Check-ins Here 
Best Mexican fast food restaurant in town! Every thing is amazing. Chilli fries are awesome!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from V L. 
 
 30 friends 30 reviews 

 V L. 
 
Manhattan, NY
 5/1/2012 
Oh my.  Deep fried heaven I think this maybe more barrio food than Mexican food. It&apos;s packed with regulars and by the looks of it, they love t here. I will maintain my girlish figure and have the finger for dessert.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Arial B. 
 
 63 friends 32 reviews 

 Arial B. 
 
Alhambra, CA
 8/1/2011 
I use to come here once in a while just because the chili cheese fries were delicious. However, I completely boycotted Pepe&apos;s ever since I experienced SEVERE food poisoning! I honestly thought I wasn&apos;t going to make it!!!

The food is good and the price is reasonable- especially since you receive more than what you pay for. But after that food poisoning experience, that set me back.

Ladies, the employees would most likely check you out and flirt with you. I know a girl that got a free drink because they thought she was pretty.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Pancho V. 
 
 229 friends 668 reviews 

 Pancho V. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 6/2/2011 7 photos 
Pepe&apos;s Mexican Food

*Announcement

Come check out the best breakfast burrito in town!
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~­~~~
Ha, Ha, Ha............. Oh NO you didn&apos;t..................

I noticed the above disclaimer on their profile page and just had to go check out what they claim is the best breakfast burrito in town.

Breakfast Burrito (Bacon) - http://www.yelp.com/biz_… Bacon, Eggs, Potato&apos;s, Beans and Cheese, a large burrito that was unfortunately lacking a sufficient amount of bacon, then again I always want more bacon....I&apos;d normally give this burrito 3-Stars, BUT.........

There are several reasons that make this above average 3-Stars, most very large breakfast burritos like this are overfilled with potato that overshadows the other ingredients, but not this one. This burrito has a very nice balance of Eggs, Potato, Beans&amp;Cheese http://www.yelp.com/biz_… and great flavor going on here!

Salsa Verde - http://www.yelp.com/biz_… Some real good salsa

&quot;IF&quot; this only had a good amount of bacon, then I&apos;d say they beat Lucky Boy for Best Breakfast Burrito in Town, but for now that&apos;s a BIG IF
 
 Listed in:
	</body>
</document>
