<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004487" url="http://jobs.com/valparaiso_indiana_us_jobs_161706" time="2012-07-12-20:54" support="1" score="0.0014529960506840954" bingtitle="Jobs in Valparaiso, Indiana | Jobs.com" webtitle="Jobs in Valparaiso, Indiana | Jobs.com">
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="226"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Lead Field Corrosion Technician - Gary, IN ... plan and allocate all resources in order to ... Retail Cashier Are You Ready For Success? We ...</description>
	<body>
		Career Advice | Career Tools | Post your resume | Communities | Security | 
 For Employers 
 Post a job Search Resumes Hiring and Recruitment 
   What? Where?   Find Jobs Advanced Search   Selections 


 Indiana Valparaiso 






















 Get this as an RSS Narrow Your Search Radius 25 miles 
 50 miles 
 100 miles 
 Posting Date Today (17) 
 Yesterday (37) 
 Last 3 days (71) 
 Last 7 Days (132) 
 Last 14 Days (211) 
 Last 30 days (321) 
 Last 60 days (347) 
 Industry Business Services - Other (11) 
 Education (7) 
 Healthcare Services (53) 
 Insurance (11) 
 Manufacturing - Other (39) 
 Other/Not Classified (45) 
 Retail (25) 
 Telecommunications Services (8) 
 Transport and Storage - Materials (23) 
 Travel, Transportation and Tourism (16) 
 More... Accounting and Auditing Services (2) 
 Aerospace and Defense (2) 
 Agriculture/Forestry/Fishing (1) 
 Automotive and Parts Mfg (1) 
 Automotive Sales and Repair Services (6) 
 Banking (5) 
 Chemicals/Petro-Chemicals (3) 
 Computer/IT Services (3) 
 Construction - Industrial Facilities and Infrastructure (5) 
 Construction - Residential&amp;Commercial/Office (3) 
 Consumer Packaged Goods Manufacturing (2) 
 Energy and Utilities (4) 
 Engineering Services (4) 
 Financial Services (5) 
 Food and Beverage Production (6) 
 Government and Military (7) 
 Hotels and Lodging (1) 
 Internet Services (7) 
 Legal Services (2) 
 Management Consulting Services (5) 
 Medical Devices and Supplies (5) 
 Metals and Minerals (2) 
 Nonprofit Charitable Organizations (1) 
 Printing and Publishing (2) 
 Real Estate/Property Management (5) 
 Restaurant/Food Services (6) 
 Staffing/Employment Agencies (1) 
 Waste Management (1) 
 Wholesale Trade/Import-Export (1) 
 Category Accounting/Finance/Insurance (13) 
 Administrative/Clerical (13) 
 Engineering (11) 
 Installation/Maintenance/Repair (29) 
 IT/Software Development (11) 
 Logistics/Transportation (33) 
 Manufacturing/Production/Operations (24) 
 Medical/Health (56) 
 Other (30) 
 Sales/Retail/Business Development (64) 
 More... Banking/Real Estate/Mortgage Professionals (4) 
 Building Construction/Skilled Trades (8) 
 Business/Strategic Management (6) 
 Customer Support/Client Care (9) 
 Editorial/Writing (4) 
 Education/Training (4) 
 Food Services/Hospitality (9) 
 Human Resources (5) 
 Legal (2) 
 Marketing/Product (2) 
 Project/Program Management (5) 
 Quality Assurance/Safety (1) 
 Security/Protective Services (3) 
 Career Level Student (High School) (9) 
 Entry Level (49) 
 Experienced (Non-Manager) (153) 
 Manager (Manager/Supervisor of Staff) (44) 
 Executive (SVP, VP, Department Head, etc) (4) 
 Education Level High School or equivalent (81) 
 Certification (25) 
 Vocational (2) 
 Some College Coursework Completed (10) 
 Associate Degree (8) 
 Bachelor&apos;s Degree (46) 
 Master&apos;s Degree (2) 
 Years of Experience Less than 1 Year (22) 
 1+ to 2 Years (60) 
 2+ to 5 Years (79) 
 5+ to 7 Years (18) 
 7+ to 10 Years (2) 
 10+ to 15 Years (1) 
 Job Type Full-Time (283) 
 Part-Time (38) 
 Per Diem (1) 
 Employee (308) 
 Temporary/Contract/Project (12) 
 Company Army National Guard 
 Brookdale Senior Living Inc. 
 C. R. England 
 Golden Technologies, Inc 
 NW. Indiana Times 
 Pilot Flying J 
 More... Adecco 
 Avon 
 Building Materials Corporation Of America 
 IncreMedical 
 Interim HealthCare 
 PAM Transport 
 Pilot Travel Centers LLC 
 Take Care Health Systems 
 Visiting Nurse Association of Porter County, Indiana 
 Job Title CNA 
 Driver 
 Drivers 
 Healthcare Positions 
 Receptionist 
 Retail Shift Supervisor 
 More... Assistant Store Manager 
 Carpenter 
 Electrician 
 Leasing And Sales Representative 
 Maintenance Mechanic 
 Restaurant Manager 
 Retail Manager 
 Sales 
 State Farm Insurance And Financial Services Agent 
 Popular Job Searches: Carmel Jobs, Indiana 
 Columbus Jobs, Indiana 
 Vincennes Jobs, Indiana 
 Terre Haute Jobs, Indiana 
 More... Crown Point Jobs, Indiana 
 Marion Jobs, Indiana 
 Richmond Jobs, Indiana 
 Merrillville Jobs, Indiana 
 Michigan City Jobs, Indiana 
 Mishawaka Jobs, Indiana 
 Fort Wayne Jobs, Indiana 
 Brownsburg Jobs, Indiana 
 New Albany Jobs, Indiana 
 Logansport Jobs, Indiana 
 New Castle Jobs, Indiana 
 More Degrees by Title Photography University Programs In Indiana 
 Grant Writing Training Programs In Indiana 
 List Of Dental Schools Programs In Indiana 
 Teaching Esl Certification Programs In Indiana 
 More... Online Education Courses Programs In Indiana 
 Master Of Public Health Schools Programs In Indiana 
 Graphic Design Classes Programs In Indiana 
 Counseling Colleges Programs In Indiana 
 Online Graphic Design Classes Programs In Indiana 
 Grant Writing Courses Online Programs In Indiana 
 Adult Education Diploma Programs In Indiana 
 Video Production Programs Programs In Indiana 
 Medical Assistant Training Online Programs In Indiana 
 Holistic Nursing Certification Programs In Indiana 
 Society For Public Health Education Programs In Indiana 
 
Jobs in Valparaiso, Indiana
 &lt;&lt;previous | Displaying 1-25 of 347 results | next &gt;&gt; Truck Driver - CDL Training Provided PAM Transport - Valparaiso, IN (10 hours ago) Truck Driving Job With CDL Training Provided! No experience needed! - We&apos;ll provide you with a complete CDL training program at a top-notch truck driving school. PAM Transport Offers: Earn up to $40,000 1st Year! $1,200 Sign-On Bonus! No upfront CDL training costs! No experience needed! No credit checks! We&apos;re currently hiring new truck drivers and providing a full truck driver training course for...
 full job description Maintenance Technician The Sterling Group - Valparaiso, IN (2 days ago) Maintenance Technician: Sterling Management, a leader in multifamily housing (apartments), is currently seeking a Maintenance Tech to join our team in Valparaiso, IN to maintain the inspection, repair and maintenance of all buildings, apartments, common area facilities, grounds, and equipment related to the property. We offer a competitive salary and benefit package. Qualified candidate should hav...
 full job description Truck Driver - Gary/Hammond, IN Con-way Freight - Valparaiso, IN (2 days ago) Compensation&amp;Benefits: Pay starts at $19.22 per hour and may also include the opportunity for overtime and an annual company bonus. Benefit plans are based on length of employment, beginning with 401k eligibility and expanding up to full medical, dental, vision, prescription, life insurance and disability. Con-way Freight is a great opportunity for a challenging career with tremendous growth pot...
 full job description Truck Driver Trainee - Gary/Hammond, IN Con-way Freight - Valparaiso, IN (8 days ago) Job Summary: At Con-way Freight, our driver position involves more than driving behind the wheel of a state of the art commercial truck. Our drivers deliver freight to our service centers and customer&apos;s businesses safely, efficiently and free from damage, they are also involved in unloading and distributing the freight at their destination. A Con-way driver is a key part of our customer service te...
 full job description Sales Executive General Insurance Services - Valparaiso, IN, 46384 (10 days ago) We are currently seeking a sales professional that would feel comfortable selling to senior level executives and business owners. This is in the B2B market, using a highly consultative sales approach. You will be targeting business owners, CFO’s, CEO&apos;s, and other high level executives. If you can&apos;t see yourself in a consultative selling environment, with a sales proposal in the $60K-$250K range th...
 full job description Media Consultant - Outside Sales Yellowbook - Valparaiso, IN (10 days ago) Since 1930, Yellowbook has focused on connecting consumers with local business clients to fuel small business growth and success. Today, as a national leader of customized small business marketing solutions, Yellowbook manages an expansive portfolio of digital, mobile and print tools to help its clients efficiently and effectively market their businesses. Yellowbook&apos;s marketing portfolio includes:...
 full job description Wireless Sales Associate - Part-Time -Target Mobile RadioShack Corporation - Target Mobile - Valparaiso, IN (17 days ago) Wireless Sales Associate - Part-Time - Target Mobile Purpose: Are you enthusiastic about wireless technology? Do you thrive in a performance based, commission environment? Do you have a strong work ethic and enjoy working with people? If so, the multi-billion dollar wireless communications industry is calling you. RadioShack has partnered with Target Stores to develop, deploy and operate Target Mo...
 full job description Outside Sales Golden Tech - Valparaiso, IN (23 days ago) Job Description: Outside Sales Position Top Reasons to work at Golden Tech·Consistently amazing, talented colleagues from whom you can learn and with whom you will do your best work·Stellar business track record, with many years of growth ahead as culture meets technology·We pay aggressive fair market to attract and keep the high performers every company wants·Freedom and responsibility cu...
 full job description Flex-time Pharmaceutical Sales Representative inVentiv Health - Valparaiso, IN (41 days ago) We are currently seeking a highly motivated, results-oriented professional for the role of Flex Pharmaceutical Sales Representative to manage a Valparaiso, IN territory. The primary responsibility of this position will be development and management of a designated territory with the goal of maximizing sales. This role is responsible for identifying and developing business relationships with primar...
 full job description Part-time Service Representative BMO Harris Bank - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (10 hours ago) BMO Harris Bank is seeking a Part-time Service Representative to work in our Valparaiso, IN location. To explore this great career opportunity, visit our website at: Click here to Apply At our company, we have been helping our customers and communities for over 125 years. In July 2011, our parent company BMO Financial Group acquired Marshall&amp;Ilsley Corporation (M&amp;I). Over the next year, we will ...
 full job description Nurses HomePointe Health Care - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (1 day ago) HomePointe HealthCare is currently recruiting nurses with homecare experience, tracheotomy and ventilator experience to staff cases located in Valparaiso and St. John. HomePointe HealthCare is a pediatric specialty agency that cares for medically fragile children with Trachs, G-buttons, and Ventilator dependent children. We offer an excellent benefit and wage package: Medical and dental coverage a...
 full job description Controller Cathay Pigments USA, Inc. - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (1 day ago) Cathay Pigments (USA) Inc. is a manufacturer of synthetic iron oxides for use in the cosmetic, printing, coatings, and construction industries. Our manufacturing plant is located in Valparaiso, IN. More information can be found by visiting our website at www.cathaypigmentsusa.com. Cathay is looking for an accounting professional that will be very hands-on and organized, to help the organization co...
 full job description Insurance Sales Professional- Financial Services Sales Western&amp;Southern Financial Group - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (1 day ago) About the Opportunity Did you know that nearly 10,000 Baby Boomers will reach retirement age every day for the next 19 years?¹Or that almost half of the households in the U.S. are underinsured?²This means that many Americans could face financial vulnerability and uncertainty at a stage in life when they can least afford it. At The Western and Southern Life Insurance Company (Western&amp;Southern...
 full job description Machinist Aero Machine - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (2 days ago) Aero Machine is a well established Machine Shop looking for machinists with a minimum of 8 years experience operating manual lathes and milling machines in a job shop environment. Must have good blueprint reading skills and own tools. Excellent wage and benefit package for the right applicant....
 full job description Technical Writer Urschel Laboratories, Inc. - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (2 days ago) WRITING TECHNICAL WRITER Urschel Laboratories Incorporated, maker of precision machinery for food, pharmaceutical, and chemical applications, is seeking a Technical Writer to join our publications team in Valparaiso, Indiana. The technical writer will work closely with the Publications Manager and other publications professionals in the development and revision of user manuals and related document...
 full job description Physical Therapists, Physical Therapist Assistants - IN IncreMedical - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (2 days ago) IncreMedical: A National Rehabilitation Leader We have Physical Therapist and Physical Therapist Assistant opportunities, full-time, part-time and prn hours available in Northwest Indiana. These are GREAT career opportunities for a PT or PTA who enjoys working in an outpatient or inpatient setting with an experienced and friendly staff providing a stimulating work environment. Our commitment is to...
 full job description Client Service Representative Teller 1st Source Bank - Valparaio, IN, 46383 (4 days ago) BANKING Client Service Representative (Teller) Positions with flexible hours available at branches located in Valparaiso, Chesterton, Portage, Michigan City and Hebron. At 1st Source Bank, you will partner with our clients to understand their needs and work to develop solutions in a team based environment. CSR&apos;s are responsible for developing strong relationships to help our clients achieve securi...
 full job description Healthcare Positions Back Home Again - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (5 days ago) HEALTHCARE WE NEED YOU! Back Home Again is hiring full and part time employees to add to their home care team Physical Therapists, Occupational Therapists, Speech Therapists, Skilled Nurses, and Personal Care Attendants needed. Apply in person at 291 N. State Rd. 2 Valparaiso, IN 46383 or fax your resume to 219-473-4336....
 full job description Project Management TestAmerica - Valparasio, IN, 46383 (5 days ago) LABORATORY PROJECT MANAGEMENT TestAmercica Valparaiso has an opening in the Project Management Department. The position requires direct contact with clients to coordinate the client&apos;s projects through all phases of laboratory operations. Qualified candidates will have BS/BA in Chemistry/Science, 6 months of client relationship/customer service experience and experience in a laboratory or field env...
 full job description iPhone/Pad Developer Urschel Laboratories - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (5 days ago) iPhone/iPad Developer Urschel Laboratories, maker of precision machinery for food, pharmaceutical, and chemical applications, is seeking an iPhone/iPad Developer to work out of our Valparaiso, Indiana headquarters. The iPhone/iPad Developer will participate in technical projects by creating solutions to support a range of iPhone/iPad uses within the organization. The successful candidate will poss...
 full job description Retail Cashier Pilot Flying J - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (6 days ago) Retail Cashier Are You Ready For Success? We understand. You want your talents to be rewarded. You want to be able to grow with a company you can be proud of. Pilot Flying J is a $25 billion company with over 550 travel center locations across North America, and we&apos;re still growing! If you thrive in a fast-paced, high-energy environment, then we&apos;ve got the opportunity you&apos;ve been looking for. Abou...
 full job description Office and Administrative Support Workers, Other Company Confidential - Valpo, IN, 46383 (7 days ago) Job Purpose: To assist Real Estate Appraiser with typing of appraisal reports and memos and helping the office to run smoothly and efficiently by performing general clerical duties on a part time basis. Duties: Typing appraisal reports and other office documents, answering a multi-line telephone, checking email regularly, ordering office supplies, small office payroll, maintaining Excel spreadshee...
 full job description JOHN DEERE Sales Person A&amp;M Farm Center - Valparasio, IN, 46383 (7 days ago) SALES JOHN DEERE SALES POSITION Salary based on experience. Paid vacation and sick time. 401K. Health and dental insurance available. Experience selling farm or outdoor power equipment preferred. Friendly, non-smoking atmosphere. Fax resume: 219-548-5984 or Email: amfarmcenterinc@hotmail.com...
 full job description QMRP Help at Home - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (7 days ago) HEALTHCARE Help At Home, Inc. is looking for a QMRP to oversee cases in the Valparaiso area. The candidate must have excellent communication and organizational skills, and must work well unsupervised. A bachelor&apos;s degree in a related field is preferred. We offer a salary of $30K or more, PD vac, PD Sick, Full Health and Dental, Mileage. For consideration please send resume to Shara Oman at 500 W. ...
 full job description Drivers Company Confidential - Valparaiso, IN, 46383 (8 days ago) DRIVERS CLASS A CDL DRIVERS Needed for regional and local deliveries. Must be at least 23 years of age with 2 years verifiable tractor trailer experience. Clean MVR needed and able to pass a drug test. Weekends are required. Competitive wages and benefits are available. Please call 219-464-4845...
 full job description &lt;&lt;previous | Displaying 1-25 of 347 results | next &gt;&gt; Get Results only for:  Indiana ,  Valparaiso Advice for Job Seekers 
 View more career advice articles Steer Clear of Interviewers&apos; Pet Peeves Improve Your Admin/Support Communication Skills 

 Build Your Brand Know the Signs of a Failing Restaurant View more career advice articles 
 

 

 

   Sponsored results Sell Avon® Visit the official AVON site to become an AVON Representative. youravon.com #1 Home Typist JobSite © Highest Paying Home Typing Jobs , Immediate Openings&amp;Paid Training www. typeathome.com Get Hired For A Great Job Search For Local Job Listing Hiring Immediate Positions To Be Filled! TrustedCareers.com/GetHiredToday Find Local Jobs Find Job Seeking Where Businesses Shop&amp;Save Today! www. business.com Popular Categories: Popular Job Titles: Popular Companies: Popular Keywords Biotech/R&amp;D/Science 
 Business/Strategic Management 
 Creative/Design 
 Logistics/Transportation 
 Quality Assurance/Safety 
 View all Carpenter 
 Engineer 
 Pharmacy Technician 
 Photographer 
 Receptionist 
 View all BAE Systems 
 CSC 
 Deloitte 
 Modis, Inc. 
 The Mergis Group 
 View all customer service 
 sales 
 Customer Service Rep 
 Santa Fe, NM 
 renewable energy, organic, environmental, green 
 View all Popular International: Popular Jobs: Popular Cities: Popular States: Canada 
 Denmark 
 Egypt 
 Peru 
 Thailand 
 View all Caregiver Jobs 
 Financial Analyst and Advisor Jobs 
 &quot;Green&quot;Jobs 
 Network Systems and Data Communications Analyst Jobs 
 Physicians Assistant Jobs 
 Birmingham 
 Houston 
 Phoenix 
 Portland 
 Sacramento 
 View all Delaware 
 Idaho 
 Illinois 
 North Dakota 
 Virginia 
 View all 
 About Us | Popular Keywords | Advanced Search | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Monster Network | Contact Us | International | Security
	</body>
</document>
