<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004827" url="http://www.manolith.com/2009/04/19/17-foods-with-the-most-caloric-bang-for-your-buck/" time="2012-07-12-21:20" support="6" score="0.010311212400152725" bingtitle="17 Foods With The Most Caloric Bang For Your Buck |" webtitle="17 Foods With The Most Caloric Bang For Your Buck | Manolith">
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>Did anybody really think that eating these foods was healthy? A double six dollar burger prepared at a fast-food restaurant ... don&apos;t complain when you have to buy two seats ...</description>
	<body>
		Manolith Search for: 
17 Foods With The Most Caloric Bang For Your Buck
 Posted on April 19, 2009 by Yosef Solomon 
 

 

Have you ever wondered what foods have the highest Caloric counts? Have you ever wondered what they foods had the highest calorie count per $1? Well, for the most part these are synonymous. The following is a list of some of the worst foods in the world for you–in health terms–as well as a breakdown of exactly how you get what you are paying for. After reading this, you‘ll mostly likely vow to never eat these menu items again.

 Chili’s Awesome Blossom 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2130 
 Fat (g): 213 
 Saturated Fat (g): 31 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium(mg): 1320 
 Price: $11.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 178 

This menu item was long-considered the most unhealthy thing you could eat at in an American restaraunt, until after tons of bad press, Chili’s removed it permanently from their menu. We felt compelled to add it to this list, because what American can rightfully said they’ve never had at least one whole Awesome Blossom in their life?



 Chili’s Chicken Crisper Tacos (3 pc) 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2020 
 Fat (g): 104 
 Saturated Fat (g): 25 
 Sugar: n/a 
 Sodium(mg): 6050 
 Price: $8.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 225 

The‘Crisper Tacos, while relatively low in the saturated fat department, make up for this by  having an extremely high calorie and sodium count. Probably best avoided, in favor of a water and some raw veggies… 
 

 Outback Steakhouse Aussie Cheese Fries 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2710 
 Fat (g): 203 
 Saturated Fat (g): 25 
 Sugar: n/a 
 Sodium(mg): 6360 
 Price: $6.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 388 

This“aussie-tizer”features more sodium and more fat than any other item still known to be featured on a menu. It is also offers more calories per $1, than any other food we could find. 
 

 Baskin Robbin’s Large Oreo Chocolate Shak e 

 

 source 
 

 
 Calories: 2600 
 Fat (g): 135 
 Saturated Fat (g): 59 
 Sugar (g): 263 
 Sodium (mg): 1700 
 Price: $6.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 372 

Named by Men’s Health as the worst food item in the world, this shake is embarrassingly unhealthy. You can expect BR to remove it from their menu by year’s end. 
 

 Cold Stone Creamery’s Gotta Have it Founder’s Favorite 

 

 source 



 Calories: 1600 
 Fat (g): 52 
 Saturated Fat (g): 42 
 Sugar (g): 84 
 Sodium (mg): 280 
 Price: $5.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 267 

While relatively better than the Oreo shake, this desert is still ridiculously high in saturated fat: 42grams! Don’t give into this tasty treat’s subliminally advertised name; it actually ought be avoided. 
 



 Macaroni Grill Spaghetti and Meatballs with Meat Sauce 

 

 source 



 Calories: 2430 
 Fat (g): 128 
 Saturated Fat (g): n/a 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): 5290
 Price: $ 10.79 
 Calories per $1.00: 225 

This is just wrong. 
 



 On the Border Dos XX Fish Tacos with Chipotle Sauce, Refried Beans and Rice 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2440 
 Fat (g): 159 
 Saturated Fat (g): 36 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): 5390 
 Price: $12.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 188 

These beer-battered tacos are bad on so many levels. They constitute more than an individual’s daily caloric intake, more than 2x the suggested daily fat intake, and over 2x as much sodium as a healthy adult should consume in a day. 
 



 Ruby Tuesday Fresh Chicken and Broccoli Pasta 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2060 
 Fat (g): 128 
 Saturated Fat (g): n/a 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): n/a 
 Price: $11.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 172 

“Fresh Chicken and Broccoli”sound like adjectives to describe a healthy meal. It is however, the dubious name of a pasta dish at the Ruby Tuesday restaurant chain. And they all but fail to mention the overwhelming layer of cheese on the dish–read the fine print! 
 



 Quizno’s Large Tuna Melt 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2090 
 Fat (g): 175 
 Saturated Fat (g): 31 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): 2190 
 Price: $5.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 349 

Talk about pulling the wool over the public’s eyes; tuna melts are supposed to be healthy. At Quizno’s they are not. But somehow this is featured on the brand’s healthy eating menu. Questionable… 
 

 Uno Chicago Grill’s Pizza Skins 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2400 
 Fat (g): 155 
 Saturated Fat (g): 50 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): 3600 
 Price: $ 9.29 
 Calories per $1.00: 258 

In terms of grams of fat, this is one of the worst items for you in America. If you are going to eat this, try to share it with some friends…about 6-8 of them. 
 



 The Cheesecake Factory Chris’ Outrageous Chocolate Cake 

 

 source 

 Calories: 1380 
 Fat (g): n/a 
 Saturated Fat (g): n/a
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): n/a 
 Price: $7.56 
 Calories per $1.00: 183 

What is more outrageous about this cake: the price, or how bad it is for you? Much like Outback, The Cheesecake Factory is not open about the nutritional information for many of their food items. A good rule of thumb is do not eat something if you do not know how bad it is for you.



Chili’s Smokehouse Bacon Triple-the-Cheese Big Mouth Burger with Jalapeno Ranch Dressin

 

 source 



 Calories: 2040 
 Fat (g): 150 
 Saturated Fat (g): 53 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): 4900 
 Price: $8.99 
 Calories per $1.00: 227 

One of the best indicators that something is bad for you, is when in the name are these three words in succession:”triple”and“the cheese”. With that said, it’s no wonder this item has more than double what The American Heart Association recommends for daily sodium intake (2400). 
 



 Outback Steakhouse Baby Back Ribs – Full Rack 

 

 source 

 Calories: 2260 
 Fat (g): n/a 
 Saturated Fat (g): n/a 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): n/a 
 Price: $18.49 
 Calories per $1.00: 122 

 “I want my‘baby back, baby back, baby back…”, is most likely what you’ll be signing if you find yourself eating this on a regular basis. The only problem, is that it will be in reference to your boyfriend/girlfriend/spouse that left you due to your gaining a ton of weight. When I spoke to an Outback manager about the nutritional data, all he could do was advise against ordering the ribs if I was concerned about my diet. 
 



 Uno Chicago Grill Chicago Classic Deep Dish Pizza 

 

 source 

 Calories (g): 2310 
 Fat (g): 162 
 Saturated Fat (g): 63 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): 4470 
 Price: $10.59 
 Calories per $1.00: 218 

This is one of the fattiest food items on this list. Although the pizza referenced in this study is meant for two people, it is not uncommon for an individual to have a‘personal’pizza to their self. So, it’s not just a clever name. This‘pie definitely scores scores extremely high in fat, saturated fat, and sodium: eat at your own peril. 
 



 P.F. Chang’s Tam’s Noodles 

 

 source 

 
 

 Calories: 1 678 
 Fat (g): 93 
 Saturated Fat (g): 17 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): n/a 
 Price: $8.95 
 Calories per $1.00: 187 

Asian food is sometimes deceptively unhealthy. This item is case-in-point. 
 



 Chili’s Buffalo Chicken Fajitas with The Works 

 

 source 

 Calories: 1730
 Fat (g): 117 
 Saturated Fat (g): 31 
 Sugar (g): n/a
 Sodium (mg): 5690 
 Price: Calories per $1.00: 173 

This pseudo-Mexican feast is super high in fat, and is off the charts in terms of sodium. 
 



 Carls Jr. Double Six Dollar Burger 

 

 source 

 Calories: 1520 
 Fat (g): 111 
 Saturated Fat (g): 44 
 Sugar (g): n/a 
 Sodium (mg): n/a 
 Price: $6.49 
 Calories per $1.00: 234 

Even though these sandwiches now typically go for more than $6.00–even though the original burger’s name a stab at‘expensive burgers’a few years ago–it packs quite the caloric bang for your buck. At 234 calories per $1, it is towards the higher end of the spectrum. Unfortunately for many, because of the negative publicity this sandwich has received in the last year or so, it has been largely pulled from Carls Jr. menus.

 For more our lists check out: 

 12 Hottest Geek Girls 

 Hottest Videogame Babes 

 40 More Hottest newswomen in America 

 10 Hottest Addicts 

 10 Sexiest Video Game Women 

 
 ← My Bloody Valentine Secret Show at The El Rey, April 17th What is Zero G Like? → 
Related Posts

 Organic Foods Low Fat Diet Healthy Diet Sodium Nerds Rule on The Big Bang Theory 
 
78 Responses to 17 Foods With The Most Caloric Bang For Your Buck 
 ← Older Comments 
 crimped says:
	</body>
</document>
