<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004369" url="http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/5-napkin-burger-2/?restaurantid=67481&amp;page=2" time="2012-07-12-20:37" support="8" score="0.03311235436546943" bingtitle="5 Napkin Burger - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Burgers ..." webtitle="5 Napkin Burger - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Burgers, American (Traditional), Sushi Restaurant Search">
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="4"/>
	<description>Love the burgers - and the beer selection is great too. ... tipped however because a different waiter took my order. ... Movies near 5 Napkin Burger</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 11183 Menus for New York City Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Brooklyn East Village/ LES Midtown East Midtown South / Chelsea Midtown West Murray Hill / Gramercy Soho/Trbca/FinDist Upper East Side Upper West Side Uptown Village/ W Village All Neighborhoods Bath Beach Bay Ridge Bedford-Stuyvesant Bensonhurst Borough Park Brighton Beach / Manhattan Beach Brooklyn Hts / DUMBO Brownsville Bushwick Canarsie Central Village / Noho Chelsea / Midtown South Chinatown / Two Bridges Cobble Hill / Carroll Grdns Coney Island Crown Heights Ditmas Park Dyker Heights East 30&apos;s East 40&apos;s East 50&apos;s East 60&apos;s East 70&apos;s East 80&apos;s East 90&apos;s East Harlem East New York East Village Financial District Flatbush Flatiron / Union Square Flatlands Fort Hamilton Ft. Greene / Clinton Hill Gramercy / Kips Bay Gravesend Harlem Kings Highway / Homecrest Lefferts Gardens Lower East Side Marine Park / Gerritsen Beach Midwood Mill Basin / Bergen Beach Morningside Heights Park Slope / Prospect Hts Prospect Park South / Kensington Sheepshead Bay Soho / Little Italy Sunset Park Tribeca Washington Hts / Inwood West 30&apos;s West 40&apos;s West 50&apos;s West 60&apos;s West 70&apos;s West 80&apos;s West 90&apos;s&amp;100&apos;s West Village Williamsburg / Greenpoint Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Burmese Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan New England Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Portuguese Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Sri Lankan Steakhouses Sushi Swiss Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
5 Napkin Burger
 + SHARE 


 $$$ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Burgers, American (Traditional), Sushi 2315 Broadway , New York   NY 10024 40.7869837 -73.9777622 (At 84th St) Subway Directions 
 
 Make a Reservation Online» 
 
 
 
 Phone: (212) 333-4488 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/5-napkin-burger-2/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
User Ratings (Based on 34 reviews) 
 3.21 5 
 Food 3.4 Value 2.6 Service 3.4 Atmosphere 3.5 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (212) 333-4488 Website: www.5napkinburger.com Notes: Major Credit Cards Hours: Mon-Fri: 11:30am-12am Sat-Sun: 11am-12am Brunch: Sat-Sun: 11am-4pm Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner,
 
 Brunch Features: Gluten Free Items,
 
 Online Reservations,
 
 Accepts Credit Cards 
User Reviews
 
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Perri on 05/11/2011 
 
Pretty good
 
Very pleasantly surprised; food (had burger special w/goat cheese; they mixed up our order but were very nice in taking the food back to fix. Fries delicious. One problem with the greeter as for some reason she had attitude and acted as though she was Princess Kate Middleton! Otherwise, all was great; enjoyed the cosmos too.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by annonymous on 03/16/2011 
 
Must Try
 
We were seated sooner than expected. Good customer service. The server was helpful. Love the burger, appetizer and desserts.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Anonymous on 02/26/2011 
 
Best gluten-free burgers
 
Although the menu doesn&apos;t state this, they can prepare most burgers gluten-free, including a gluten-free bun. I was told the fries are also gluten free and prepared in a dedicated frier. The burgers and fries are excellent, I only wish I knew earlier that they could do gluten-free.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by snowgirl51 on 01/20/2011 
 
My Veggie burger lead to enlightenment
 
Forget if you eat meat or not. This veggie burger is very unique and worth a try. When I bite into it I get a taste of hazelnuts and it the color of beets (minus the taste of beets). The 5 Napkin Sauce, that goes on top, goes with the burger perfectly. I like this burger on a salad just as much as I do on the bun. I never knew veggie burgers like this existed before. So good.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Anonymous on 12/27/2010 
 
Great Place Except for 1 time
 
I have eaten here over 30 times since it opened on the upper west side. The food and service are always great, but, the last time I went there I was exteremely disappointed with how the manager handled a family with kids who were running around and disturbing other customers.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Anonymous on 12/14/2010 
 
Amazing
 
Amazing burgers, amazing salads, amazing apps, the best beer on tap [their 5 Napkin Nut Brown Ale]. The food is fresh and amazing. The size of drinks is huge. The service is very good. Just a little loud! A must go!
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by deshaz on 11/24/2010 
 
Eat the veggie burger!
 
I randomly went in with a friend to get a to-go burger because a carnivore friend told me she goes there for the veggie burger. It&apos;s made from actual veggies (not soy protein) and doesn&apos;t fall apart. It&apos;s delicious! We sat at the bar and received our orders fairly promptly (and in brown paper bags). The only problem is finding out where we had to place the order. There were 3 very flustered people at the host station and none of them was able to even respond to me for a few minutes. The first response was a vague point and&quot;over there&quot;. The second one was a much clearer&quot;at the bar.&quot;
 
 
 « ‹ 1 2 3 4 5 › » 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near 5 Napkin Burger
 AMC Loews 84th Street 6 
2310 Broadway

New York
 The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Tyler Perry&apos;s Madea&apos;s Witness Protection  (PG-13) Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter  (R) Brave  (PG) Brave 3D  (PG) Show More [+] More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages NYC Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
