<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004276" url="http://www.wellsphere.com/articles/fast-food-health-statistics" time="2012-07-12-20:31" support="1" score="0.006288818942572489" bingtitle="Fast Food Health Statistics - Articles &amp; Information - Wellsphere" webtitle="Fast Food Health Statistics - ArticlesInformation - Wellsphere">
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>Fast food = health food by Jean D. Posted ... All takeout containers, trays, and tableware will be made ... products are super... of both science and nature in order ...</description>
	<body>
		Health knowledge made personal 
 Home Communities WellPages Resources Near You WellTools My Wellsphere 
 
 Sign Up! • Log in 
 
 
 
 Fast Food Health Statistics 
 + Bookmark › Share 
 
 
 ‹Main Articles Discussions Pictures More 
 People Resources Tips Videos 
 
 Please enter a search word or phrase. Close The search word cannot have more than 100 characteres. Close All HealthBloggers 
 Go 
 Search posts: 
Fast Food Health Statistics - Articles
 Sort by: Newest Most Comments Relevance 
 Write a blog post 
 Finally! Fast food = health food by Jean D. Posted 















Wed 14 Jan 2009 8:48pm The Health Food Hut, a new chain of fast food restaurants is getting started in Florida. Big deal, you say? Well, yes, it actually is. 

 Get this: The menu? All organic... and the origin of every item. 

 Even better – not only is the food organic, the entire restaurant is totally green. All takeout containers, trays, and tableware will be made of the latest Read on» Fast Food Health Care by Steven .. Posted 















Thu 03 Jul 2008 5:10pm Another datapoint in the trend towards the retailing of healthcare:Walgreen Buying Health Centers, Wall Street Journal, March 18, 2008.

Walgreen-the nation&apos;s largest drugstore chain(by $)- bought I-trax Inc ($259.7 million cash) and Whole Health Management ($???). The purchase gives Walgreen over 500 worksite (in businesses like Lowe&apos;s, Toyota Read on» Laurel On Health Food | Health Food , Healthy Eating, and Nutrition by onhealthfood Posted 















Wed 12 Jan 2011 3:00am Laurel on Health Food is a blog about nutrition, healthy eating, and health food . It summarizes articles in the news, lists healthy recipes, offers tips and personal feedback on healthy eating, and reports on nutritional research.

Laurel is a writer, blogger, and certified holistic health counselor/ health coach living in New York Read on» Choosing Health Food and Health Drinks over Bad Habits by Cliff S. Posted 















Wed 14 Jul 2010 8:39pm Choosing health food and health drinks instead of bad habits is something most people desire, but because of fear they stick to old favorites. It becomes too challenging... at a time. The idea is to gradually swap unhealthy choices for smarter health food and health drinks until each one becomes a comfortable part of the daily routine. Making one Read on» Agave: Health Food , Health Fad or Health Fraud? Part Two by Chris M. Posted 















Sat 09 Oct 2010 1:24pm , and no significant effects are seen for fasting triacylglycerol or body weight with intakes of 3) J Agric Food Chem. 2009 Jul 31. [Epub ahead of print] Formation of Hydroxymethylfurfural.... PMID: 12234125 5) Environ Health .  2009 Jan 26;8:2.  Mercury from chlor-alkali plants: measured concentrations in food product sugar.Mercury cell chlor-alkali products are used Read on» Agave: Health Food , Health Fad or Health Fraud? Part One by Chris M. Posted 















Fri 01 Oct 2010 3:47pm is that it is lower in the glycemic index.  Is Agave really a health food and something you should be including in your diet?

No, but to understand why, let us take a closer look at the issues... the elevated levels of fructose in High Fructose Corn Syrup, some health food stores, will not carry any product that has HFCS in it.  Yet on the other hand, they carry a full line Read on» Sunrider Health Foods and Health Drinks Elevate Intake of Valuable Nutrients by Cliff S. Posted 















Fri 20 Aug 2010 10:47am With its headquarters in Los Angeles, Sunrider is a company that has taken the concept of health foods and health drinks to an entirely new level. Their products are super... of both science and nature in order to create health foods and health drinks that provide maximum nutrition with very few calories, and little or no fat and cholesterol Read on» No Health Food Found in Most Health Clubs by Cliff S. Posted 















Tue 15 Sep 2009 10:01pm Finding health food at fitness clubs is almost as impossible as finding health food at a football game. Notice all the protein bars being sold at health clubs that are made..., vitamins and minerals. It’s not easy to find health food made with whole food ingredients that are processed carefully enough to maintain their natural structure. If the nutrients Read on» Feb 7, Raw Food Research - The Latest Food &amp; Health Discoveries by Esme S. Posted 















Tue 10 Feb 2009 11:29am The debate is over: raw food research shows that organic vegan, whole food diet is best. Find here underlying research on topics such as organic, msg, trans fats, aspartame, fluoride and much more. Read on» Eat These 8 Foods For Your Health by Andrea C. Posted 















Sat 17 Jan 2009 2:50am My friend from work let me borrow this great book called, Eat This, Not That. It was jam packed with easy to understand information about food . As the title suggests, it gives you information on what to eat vs. what not to eat. Like when you go into a restaurant or fast food place…it gives information (calories, fat etc…) on the food choices you Read on» 1-10 of 457886 «Previous 1 2 3 4 5 Next»   
Related Searches
 fast food health statistics fast food health effects of fast food on health fast food and health risks fast food and your health fast food health concerns fast food health dangers fast food health effects fast food health facts fast food health hazards 
Related Discussions
 Studying Social and Mental Health Issues of Adolescence with CF Benlysta.... thoughts...? Does anyone else suffer from both prolapsed bladder and prolapsed uterus? EA Sports Active Celebrities design lingerie for breast cancer charity&apos;s auction The Instructive British Institute (IBI) the hardest greif I ever had to contend with Madal Bal natural Tree Syrup basics about meditation Infographic: Solutions to Automated External Defibrillator Challenges Wellsphere: About Us | Contact Us | FAQ | Health Mavens | HealthBlogger Network | Awards | Video Health Stories | Share Wellsphere | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Security Policy WellPages: A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 See all the latest blog posts. Salmonella Nutrition Bars Children Staph Infection How to Reduce LDL Life Expectancy Emphysema Itchy Swollen Eyelids Fibromyalgia Disability Bone Density Medications Causes of Swelling Pregnancy Brown Discharge Sore Neck Glands Itchy Rash on Arms Itchy Throat Cough Pinched Nerve Neck Symptoms Burning Sensation During Urination Blood Clots During Period Swollen Lymph Node Armpit Causes of Lump Causes of Itching Swollen Lymph Nodes Groin Signs of Pregnancy Before Missed Period Causes of Rash Toddler Rashes Coughing Up Phlegm Enlarged Groin Lymph Nodes Early Pregnancy Brown Discharge Gillian Barre Syndrome Sore Throat Body Aches Symptoms of Swelling Side Effects of Flu Shot Distended Abdomen Find a Counselor Wellsphere does not provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. See additional information. Copyright©2012 Remedy Health Media, LLC. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
