<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004715" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowTopic-g147293-i28-k3062477-Fast_Food_Restaurant_in_Punta_Cana-Punta_Cana_Dominican_Republic.html" time="2012-07-12-21:13" support="4" score="0.01428179716332748" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant in Punta Cana - Punta Cana Forum - TripAdvisor" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant in Punta Cana - Punta Cana Forum - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000799" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="209"/>
	<description>Punta Cana Forum: Fast Food Restaurant in Punta Cana ... 28&amp;g=147293&amp;faqid=52&amp;qid=1141 Entry and Exit ... grub is grub, there is also an amazing pizza place ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Punta Cana 
 Punta Cana Tourism Punta Cana Hotels Punta Cana Vacation Rentals Flights to Punta Cana Punta Cana Restaurants Things to Do in Punta Cana Punta Cana Travel Forum Punta Cana Photos Punta Cana Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
Punta Cana
 
 Punta Cana Tourism Punta Cana Hotels Vacation Rentals Flights to Punta Cana Punta Cana Hotel Deals More On Punta Cana Restaurants Things to Do Travel Forum Photos Videos Map Punta Cana Deals Hotel&amp;Air Packages Travel Guide 
 Free Newsletter 
Interested in Punta Cana ?

We&apos;ll send you updates with the latest deals, reviews and articles for Punta Cana each week.
 
Recently Reviewed Hotels in Punta Cana 
 
 Be Live Grand Punta Cana 1,115 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #51 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Catalonia Bavaro Beach, Casino&amp;Golf Resort 2,484 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 #44 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Barcelo Dominican Beach 1,804 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #64 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Excellence Punta Cana 5,545 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #12 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Gran Bahia Principe Bavaro 4,168 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #42 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Melia Caribe Tropical 4,185 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 #30 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Paradisus Punta Cana 2,088 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 #35 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Barcelo Punta Cana 2,174 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #57 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 ClubHotel Riu Bambu 1,670 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #50 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Grand Palladium Palace Resort, Spa&amp;Casino 955 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #37 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 IFA Villas Bavaro Resort&amp;Spa 1,132 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #52 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Riu Palace Punta Cana 1,650 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #40 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Sirenis Tropical Suites 1,360 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #46 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Sivory Punta Cana Boutique Hotel 306 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 #21 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 Riu Palace Macao 1,021 Reviews Last reviewed Jul 6, 2012 #45 of 98 hotels in Punta Cana
 
 Explore the world! TripAdvisor has reviews and information on over 400,000 locations, including: Hotels 
 Holiday Inn Santee Sofitel New York in New York City Hilton Cocoa Beach Oceanfront Hampton Inn Metairie Holiday Inn Express Hartford 
 Travel Destinations 
 Anaheim hotels Overland Park Atlantic City deals Washington deals 
 Sightseeing 
 Tropical Sailing in Fort Lauderdale 
 
 Home 
 Caribbean Dominican Republic Punta Cana Forums 
 
 
Punta Cana Forum: Fast Food Restaurant in Punta Cana
 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 Majestic Colonial Punta Cana 7,619 Reviews Punta Cana, Dominican Republic Read reviews Barcelo Bavaro Palace Deluxe 1,940 Reviews Punta Cana, Dominican Republic Read reviews Tortuga Bay Puntacana Resort&amp;Club 255 Reviews Punta Cana, Dominican Republic Read reviews 
 All hotels in Punta Cana (98) Top questions about PUNTA CANA 
   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=1596 Inside Pages   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=1139 Electricity   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=1142 Health Questions?   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=1141 Entry and Exit Questions   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=1105 Weather   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=1396 Dominican Baseball League   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=137 Arrivals and Departures&amp;Taxi rates   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=6242 Wedding Information   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=7876 When Will My Review Get Posted?   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=7972 Can I Drink The Tap Water In Punta Cana?   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=8135 Current Taxi Rates From Punta Cana Airport   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=8156 Resort Area Map   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=9185 Where Can I Get The Trip Advisor&quot;Insiders&quot;Travel Guide For The Dominican Republic?   ABS:ForumFAQ?action=detail&amp;i;=28&amp;g;=147293&amp;faqid;=52&amp;qid;=9990 Total Rooms 
 Collected by our Destination Experts Brooklin 6,529 forum posts dropusaline 4,955 forum posts hlywud 9,128 forum posts TravelPro198 4,081 forum posts 
 Members who are knowledgeable about this destination and volunteer their time to answer travelers&apos; questions. Free Punta Cana Guide 
Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.
 Grab it and Go! Beyond destination forums 
 Air Travel Business Travel Timeshares / Vacation Rentals 
 › See all Which Punta Cana hotels are on sale?
	</body>
</document>
