<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004324" url="http://www.winegiques.com/food_and_drink/" time="2012-07-12-20:34" support="2" score="0.0025636426633320213" bingtitle="Wine Giques: Food and Drink" webtitle="Wine Giques: Food and Drink">
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>&quot;And we&apos;re going to drink a Sideways bottle of wine.&quot; That got my attention. ... he was saving for his tenth wedding anniversary, from a foam cup in a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Wine Giques 

&quot;Robert Parker Meets Sex and the City.&quot;
 
 Little Morocco and the Night of the Banshee 
 
 
 
A few weeks ago, my buddy Jeffy showed up for the holiday we call&quot;Bah, Humbug! Day,&quot;with a heavy, beautifully-wrapped package from Vroman&apos;s . (If you don&apos;t know Vroman&apos;s, you&apos;re not a book lover. If you&apos;re ever in Pasadena, go there.)

 

Inside the package? Paula Wolfert&apos;s The Food of Morocco . Now, here&apos;s what I know about Morocco: The closest I ever got was a trip to southern Spain, when Dubya was president, and the U.S. had embarked on our latest imperialist invasion. (No, I&apos;m not bitter about #43. Why would you think that? Unless you read my other blog .) Americans were not advised to visit Morocco, even though it was mere miles away, across the Strait of Gibraltar. We did make it to Gibraltar, where we ate some English stuff, and the monkeys scared the crap out of my daughter. But I digress.

So, the book became a totem: How do you make Moroccan food? Jeffy said: &quot;Let&apos;s cook some next week!&quot; I said&quot;Sure!&quot; He said&quot;Let&apos;s make this !&quot; I said&quot;Not a chance!&quot;(Seriously,&quot;this&quot;is called pastilla and it takes three days. I&apos;m ambitious, but not that ambitious.)

I settled for an Orange, Leafy Green and Date Salad, Roasted Beet Salad with Cinnamon, and the pièce de résistance , Chicken Smothered in Olives. BTW, I have learned that French is Morocco&apos;s unofficial second language, so it&apos;s appropriate to say&quot;pièce de résistance.&quot;

Here&apos;s another Moroccan saying: وكان هذا الغذاء لا يصدق ، وخاصة بالنسبة لطبخ المغربي لأول مرة.

It means: &quot;The food was incredible, especially for a first-time Moroccan cook.&quot;

Now, the interesting thing about Moroccan food is that it reflects a myriad of influences. Given the country&apos;s location - prime fodder for young conquerers with land-lust - and its diverse population (ever wonder where Berber carpets were invented?), there&apos;s a little of this and a little of that in just about everything. It&apos;s like the Moroccans sent the crazy conquerers and carpet-sellers on their way, and kept all the precious things that made their food so delicious. 

Which brings us to the wine, which came to us courtesy of our other dinner guests, neighbors S. and M. (I know what you&apos;re thinking. And those are really their initials.)  When I said&quot;Moroccan!&quot;they said&quot;What wine?&quot;and I said&quot;I have no Moroccan idea!&quot; So they brought a wine that has a little of everything:  Banshee 2009 Mordecai .

The brilliance of the Banshee is that the winemakers collect precious small lots of wine from some of California&apos;s best vineyards, and blend them together into a Rhone-influenced, vibrant, spicy blend. While their actual sources are secret and mysterious--genie in a bottle anyone?-- the resulting wine is not. It&apos;s a bit bold, a little exotic, and possibly dangerously addictive. 

Just how I imagine Morocco to be. 
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on January 17, 2012 in Books , Food and Drink , Friends , Wine Online_ | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Liquidity Event 
 
Oh, my. The Wine Giques have been very busy NOT writing about wine. But don&apos;t fret, gentle reader: it doesn&apos;t mean that we&apos;ve dispensed with DRINKING the wine, as well. We continue to pursue that noble occupation, every chance we get.

Case in point: I was lucky enough to attend a forum hosted by a noted business school last night about investing in digital media. Given that digital media is my other obsession (we&apos;ll speak about shoes and handsome men later), I found the topic incredibly fascinating (the presence of many handsome men did not hurt). Speakers from Shamrock Capital , Rustic Canyon Ventures , DLA Piper , Ocean Road Partners ... each one more glorious than the previous. But the capper came when Silicon Valley Bank , which is smart enough to fund technology startups and fine wine producers (genius!), produced this guy&apos;s doppelganger:

  
Yes, Prince Harry apparently makes fine wine. And very fine wine, it is. Good enough for a royal wedding, and then some.

Actually, the gentleman at hand was named Peter Stolpman. He and his father, Tom, and mother, Marilyn, own Stolpman Vineyards , a gracious slice of paradise located in the Santa Ynez valley; an acquisition funded by those aforementioned geniuses at Silicon Valley Bank. Stolpman is dedicated to producing Rhône-style wines, with a special focus on Côte-Rôtie, and the occasionally foray into outliers like Sangiovese.

Peter had brought along L&apos;Avion 2008 , a white made with 100% Roussanne; a 2007 Sangiovese ; a 2008 Hilltops HD Syrah ; and most impressively, the 2009 La Cuadrilla blend (50% Grenache, 50% Syrah)--all profits from the sale of La Cuadrilla are given directly to Stolpman&apos;s vineyard crew. (Handsome and conscientious!)

Now, I have said repeatedly that I am a Rhône-style girl, and these wines tugged at my heartstrings: plummy, rich in fruit, smoky, delicious textures ... and of course, that Prince Harry doppelganger. And with prices ranging from $25 per bottle for La Cuadrilla to a little north of $50 per bottle for the Syrah, these are wines that lovely enough for your finest special events, but won&apos;t break the bank if your latest shoe obsession has gotten the best of you. 
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on May 04, 2011 in Current Affairs , Food and Drink , Hot Guys , Social consciousness , Tasting_ , Wine Online_ | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 First Night and the Sideways Bottle 
 
 &quot;What are we doing tonight?&quot; I asked Jeffy, early on New Year&apos;s Eve. Having just bounced off a plane as an escapee from Snowpocalypse 2010 , for me, 2011&apos;s first night was not destined to be a raucous affair. 

&quot;We&apos;re cooking,&quot;said Jeffy. &quot;And we&apos;re going to drink a Sideways bottle of wine.&quot;

That got my attention. 

As a wine lover and a movie lover, Sideways was something of a seminal moment for me. More affecting, certainly, than Bottle Shock (although Chris Pine&apos;s wig certainly made an indelible impression). It is true that, when you&apos;re a wine lover, your relationship with the beloved grape sometimes takes precedence over relationships with other, more minor things, such as -- say -- people.  At least, that is what Paul Giamatti&apos;s character would have us believe.

But who can forget the penultimate scene in the movie, when Giamatti drinks his prized bottle of 1961 Chateau Cheval Blanc , the one he was saving for his tenth wedding anniversary, from a foam cup in a fast food restaurant, by himself? We all have our Sideways bottles, and the revelation is that they&apos;re not defined by their price points, but by the people we plan to drink them with. 

Jeffy&apos;s bottle?  Geyser Peak 2006 Block Collection River Road Ranch Sauvignon Blanc . Compared to that Chateau Cheval Blanc, it&apos;s a lowly bottle, with a retail price of only twenty bucks. But it was purchased on a romantic ramble through the wine country, with a love now lost. We replaced that lost love with some Morbière cheese, a roast chicken, a bit of feline company, and lots of chatter, which almost seemed to do the trick: there certainly was no wistfulness around the table as we ushered 2010 out the door. 

My bottle? I actually have more than one. Several that, like the Geyser Peak, were purchased to be consumed with lost loves, whose faces I sometimes see in my dreams. But my foremost Sideways bottle? A 2006 La Sirena Cabernet Sauvignon . Made by Heidi Barrett (remember Chris Pine&apos;s wig ?), a woman winemaker, and secreted away, to be uncorked with friends on an upcoming -- momentous-- birthday. And, as lovely as the wine will be, its memory will be defined not by the moment when I drank it, but by the company I was keeping. 

Happy new year, my friends.  
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on January 02, 2011 in Film , Food and Drink , Friends , Tasting_ , Travel , Wine Online_ , Wine Varietals | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Tips for Storing Wine 
 
Although we Wine Giques like to share wisdom about wine and how it relates to parties, boys and shoes (not necessarily in that order), we also occasionally like to include some basic, useful info, just to prove that we know what we&apos;re talking about. So, given the recent heat wave on the Left Coast , and Suenarita&apos;s recent departure for the sultry climes of the Deep South , we thought it might be useful to hand out a few tips for storing wine, just to remind ourselves that a little pampering goes a long way for just about anything. 
 Wine lovers like to say that wine is a living, breathing
thing.    While you may not be
as attached to your wine as you are to your pet Chihuahua, wine is an organic
substance that reacts to things like heat and light, often adversely.   Properly storing your wine ensures that
you’ll have the best drinking experience, whether you’re uncorking your latest
bottle tomorrow night, or a few years down the road.   Here are some tips for maximizing the life of your wine: 

 


 1)      Store wine
on its side. 
 
 Wine bottles have been
traditionally stoppered with corks for hundreds of years.   Cork is a natural substance that is
easily moldable to the shape of the bottle, and also has the valuable trait of
slowing the entry of oxygen into the bottle, which “oxidizes” the wine, changing
its flavor and color.   Keeping a
wine bottle on its side ensures that the cork remains moist, which is necessary
to slow down that potentially nasty oxygen exchange.    Modern winemakers are experimenting with different
kinds of closures – you may have purchased bottles with synthetic (generally a
form of plastic) or composite (made with cork granules) corks.   You may have even purchased a fine
bottle of wine with a screw top.   This experimentation is happening because cork trees are somewhat
endangered, and because natural cork itself can generate mold.    These modern closures are quite
effective, but haven’t been tested for long-term wine storage.   So, to be safe, keep your wine on its
side.   
 

 


 2)      Keep
bottles away from heat and light. 
 
 When you sit in the sun too long,
you get a sunburn, correct?   Heat
and light also affect wine.   While
many modern bottles are treated to screen out UV light, it’s best to keep your
wine in a cool, dark location that is as free of variables in temperature as
possible.   The best way to store
wine is in low light, at a constant temperature of around 50-55 degrees F/10-16
degrees C for reds, and 45-50 degrees F/7-10 degrees C for whites.   High humidity is best, as well.   If you can purchase a small wine
refrigerator, all the better.    
 
 


 3)      Keep
bottles away from vibrations. 
 
 This advice is directed mostly at red wines that you
plan to store for long periods of time.   Vibrations can disperse sediments – which are tannins and pigments in
the wine that break down over time – and keep them from settling, resulting in
wine that feels “gritty” in the mouth.   Keeping wines free from vibration, and setting red wines upright for a
while,   as well as decanting them
before drinking, are useful ways to help the sediment settle and save you from
a “rocky” drinking experience.   
 

 


 4)      Keep
bottles away from strong-smelling substances. 
 
 Remember that oxygen transfer that we discussed
earlier?   Well, it can also bring
strange smells to your wine.   A
wine’s aroma is a large and important part of the drinking experience.   Storing your wine with your garlic may
ensure that vampires will not come to share it with you, but you probably aren’t
going to want to drink it, either.   
 

 


 5)      Re-cork
bottles that aren’t fully consumed … and drink the rest of the wine as soon as
you can. 
 
 This is perhaps the easiest tip to follow: drink all your wine as soon as possible
after you’ve opened it. Removing
the stopper allows oxygen to enter the wine much faster, sometimes resulting in
oxidation in a matter of hours. Replacing the cork in the wine bottle, or using a wine bottle stopper,
will slow this process somewhat, but usually only buys you an extra day or
two. If you like a glass of wine
in the evening, aren’t inclined to consume an entire bottle, consider
purchasing half-bottles and splits instead. 


 

 Et voilà! Advice delivered. Now back to boys and shoes ... 
 



 





 

 


 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on July 22, 2010 in Advice , Food and Drink , Friends , Hot Guys , Parties and gifts , Shoes , Tasting_ , Wine Online_ | Permalink | Comments (1) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 ¡Micheladas! 
 
 My friend Marissa turned me on to this NY Times article on my favorite summer drink, the michelada . Both she and I seem to love the versions they make at ¡Lotería! , a local authentic upscale Mexican eatery, with locations in Hollywood and at Farmer&apos;s Market (and yes, you must use those explanation points when you refer to it). 

And, as usual, even though it&apos;s written up in the venerable Grey Lady, you&apos;ve got to hand it to La-La Land for pioneering the trend ... most NY restaurants don&apos;t seem to have heard of this tasty concoction, as the author himself points out. 

Score another one for the Left Coast. What&apos;s the talley now? Eleven-eleven million to oh, six? Manhattanites, feel free to respond. But not before you hoist a michelada or two.  

 Photo from the NY Times. 
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on July 21, 2010 in Cocktails , Food and Drink , Friends , General snarkiness , Travel | Permalink | Comments (4) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Oh, honey ... No. 
 
Suenarita and I apologize. We&apos;ve been busy -- she, decamping for the wilds of Hotlanta, me, well, doing whatever it is I do all the time. 

But when I saw this, I knew we had to spring into action. This is not proper Wine Giques attire.  

  


It&apos;s obviously called the&quot; Wine Rack .&quot; I can&apos;t think of any place where this might be appropriate, unless perhaps you&apos;re loading it up with box wine for a&quot;Little KISS&quot;reunion concert. THEN it might be considered somewhat clever and ironic.  

Get yourself a cooler, honey. And some GoVino ® wine glasses. We&apos;ll talk. 
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on July 19, 2010 in Advice , Etiquette , Food and Drink , General snarkiness , Parties and gifts | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Quaffing Oscar: Wine Pairings for the Best Picture Nominees 
 
  
Well, it&apos;s the big weekend here in La-La Land. Nope, not the end of another winning Pac-10 hoops season . Nope, not the 1000th stirring episode of The Hills . Nope, not the moment when we abandon the rain to ski the 170 inches of snow on Mammoth Mountain. It&apos;s time for the big dance, the party where only the cool kids get to go, the ultimate in eye candy for pop culture junkies everywhere: It&apos;s the 82nd Annual Academy Awards® , known colloquially as the Oscars®.  

And, in true Wine Giques fashion, now that we&apos;re through shopping for our fancy party shoes , we&apos;re offering up 10 wine picks to accompany the 10 Best Picture nominees, in honor of the hoi-polloi like us, who are enjoying the festivities with friends in the comfort of our own private screening, er, living rooms. The movies are listed in alphabetical order, by the way, as we&apos;d hate to betray our favorites: the Wine Giques are friends to everyone in Hollywood. After all, you never know who you&apos;re going to run into in a small town like this. 

 Avatar -- Well, the more obvious among us would say that the proper wine to pair with this dimensional sci-fi extravaganza would be Blue Nun. We&apos;re going to take the high road and suggest that you procure a magnum of 1992 Screaming Eagle , and then invite 37,352 friends over to help you enjoy the biggest, most expensive wine you&apos;ve ever had.

 The Blind Side --The touching tale of Baltimore Ravens offensive tackle Michael Oher might deserve a wine that&apos;s a bit lyrical with a hardscrabble backstory. We took a simpler route and chose our favorite from a recent blind tasting: 2007 Trenza Tinto . An unusual and delicious blend of Spanish Tempranillo with classic Rhône varietals from California&apos;s San Luis Obispo region, it&apos;s the kind of wine created by winemakers who are not blinded by tradition. 

 District 9 -- This one was easy. South Africa is apparently producing both spectacular filmmakers and spectacular wines these days. We recommend 2008 Indaba Shiraz . Indaba apparently means&quot;meeting of the minds&quot;in Zulu, and although that seemed unattainable in District 9 , we&apos;re sure that you won&apos;t mind meeting this lovely bottle laced with fruit and spice. And at $10 a pop, it&apos;s an affordable pleasure -- just like this great indie film.  

 An Education -- As the parents of teenage daughters, this movie frightens us. However, we can&apos;t deny the deliciousness of its soundtrack, filled with classic torch songs and sultry French chanteuses. We chose a French classic ourselves, 1999 Chateau Pavie Macquin St. Emilion . Apparently, the grapes in this wine escaped a hailstorm that pummeled the rest of the countryside that year, to reach a transcendence denied others in their peer group. Very appropriate.  

 The Hurt Locker -- By now, we all know about the media-manufactured rivalry between the director of this film, Kathryn Bigelow, and her ex-husband, James Cameron, who directed a certain blue-themed movie listed above. We&apos;d like to applaud Ms. Bigelow for blazing trails in what is still very much a boys club, and offer up a wine by one of our very favorite woman winemakers:  2005 Martinelli Jackass Hill Zinfandel , made by Helen Turley and Bryan Kvamme. Will set you back $165, but like every fine woman, it&apos;s worth every penny. 

 Inglourious Basterds -- We know Quentin Tarantino is an acquired taste, one we have grown to love over the years, as we&apos;ve cultivated our knowledge of wine, shoes, movies and Japanese swords . We can only wish that his imaginative retelling of WWII were true, then salute Christophe Waltz&apos; tour de force performance with our favorite Grüner Veltliner, Domäne Wachau Federspiel Terrassen 2008 . Only $17, and after a few glasses, you&apos;ll no longer fear that umlaut. 

 Precious -- Yes, we know the movie&apos;s actual title is longer, but we&apos;re tired of typing and want to get on to more important things, like telling you what to drink. For this harrowing tail, we&apos;re tempted to recommend a stiff shot of oblivion-inducing Everclear , but in the interest of consistency, we&apos;ll stick to the wine. Our choice:  2005 Brown Estate Chaos Theory . Like the movie&apos;s heroine, it&apos;s a unique blend -- in this case, Cabernet&amp;Zinfandel -- and it comes from one of the precious-few African-American-owned wineries in the country.

 A Serious Man -- Although chaos theory is certainly appropriate for this modern retelling of the parable of Job, we chose to focus on the other physics-related aspects of the latest Coen brothers&apos;opus. Face it, despite its distinctly Jewish flavor, this is really a film about Shrödinger&apos;s Cat .  So we recommend the very serious 2005 EMH Vineyards Black Cat Cabernet . A few sips, and you&apos;ll be grateful to Hashem for creating such pleasures. 

 Up -- Although this putative children&apos;s movie is filled with balloons and airiness, it&apos;s ultimately a down-to-earth story about friendship, love, and coming to terms with loss. Pixar&apos;s continuing ability to make us laugh while yanking our heartstrings is worth a rousing toast, and our libation of choice is Iron Horse Cuvee Joy! , a vintage sparkling wine from John Lasseter&apos;s beloved Sonoma County. It&apos;s produced only in magnums, so make sure you pack as many friends as possible into your house before you unpack the bubbles and take off for the Amazon. 

 Up in the Air -- Ordinarily we&apos;d avoid a film about a professional corporate downsizer, given the current depressing state of employment and its concomitant effect on the wine industry. However, we&apos;d attend the opening of an envelope if George Clooney were involved ... so, here we are. To celebrate this quirky, complicated, and ultimately satisfying film, we offer up a similarly-themed wine: 2005 Shypoke Charbono . Made from an underused varietal grape, like the Clooney, it goes down smooth but finishes with a punch. 

So, there you have it. There&apos;s still time to go shopping before the cameras start rolling. And have your people call our people after the show, darling.  Kiss kiss.
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on March 07, 2010 in Current Affairs , Film , Food and Drink , Hot Guys , Tasting_ , Television | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Three Things. 
 
    

Three things made me very happy last night (even though it was Giorgio the houseboy&apos;s night off):

1) The delicious vegetarian cassoulet I made.  Recipe here. 

2) The big, honkin&apos;glass of 2007 Les Hèrétiques I drank with the cassoulet. Carignan&amp;Syrah blend, classic flavors from the Languedoc for a classic Languedoc dish (well, sans the carnivorous stuff).

3) The Daily Show&apos;s brilliantly ironic skewering of cable news&quot;expert&quot;panels .

That is all.
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on November 04, 2009 in Current Affairs , Food and Drink , Rampant cynicism , Tasting_ | Permalink | Comments (1) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Stocking the Apothecary 
 
  
It all started a few weeks ago, the night my teenage daughter got grounded for the first time ever. I&apos;ll spare you the details over the transgression (needless to say, it involved boys), and tell you instead that it led me on a trip straight to Ralph&apos;s -- which was the only joint open at the time -- to refill my medicine cabinet wine rack.

Now, I know parenting is best performed in a sober state, but sometimes, just sometimes (especially when you&apos;re raising a child on your own, as I am), you just need to take the edge off. Especially when your grounded offspring spends the entire day begging you if she can go to a party that night. I&apos;m serious. Every 15 minutes, all day long. Now, I&apos;ve raised my kid to have a mind of her own, and to be relentless in pursuing what she wants, but Rhonda, I&apos;m tellin&apos;you, on that Saturday, I regretted it. 

So I did what any sane mother would do.  I locked myself in the garage-cum-guesthouse with a baguette, some Cowgirl Creamery Red Hawk, and a container of tiny Niçoise olives. Then I dragged out the Shakespeare in Love DVD, and proceeded to self-medicate, ignoring the pleading looks periodically cast through the French doors. By periodically, I mean every 15 minutes, all day long. 

My catholicon of choice?  2007 Apothic Red , apparently named for some mythical place in 13th century Europe where they blended and stored wine. An appropriately mysterious moniker for a California blend of uncertain provenance. Pretty soon, I was wrapped up in the deliciousness of the wine and Joseph Fiennes: both somewhat forward and a bit fruity (well, the clothes they wore then were kind of foppish, weren&apos;t they?), with a smooth touch on the lips and decidedly elegant finish.  

By that time, the sun had gone down, and the teenager had realized that I wasn&apos;t giving in, no matter how hard she tried. She buckled and I invited her in, and we finished off the cheese with a celebratory viewing of Jurassic Park. (I know just how that T-Rex felt, believe me. Very, very irritated.)

The cost for my mental poultice, by the way? $8.99, on special, $11.99 when not. Such a bargain that it&apos;s now a mainstay in the pharmacy, where it&apos;s been busy curing the neighbors of their own teenager-related afflictions, one lovely sip at a time. 
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on November 02, 2009 in Advice , Food and Drink , General snarkiness | Permalink | Comments (3) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 
 Smoke and Wine 
 
 Summer is not letting go gracefully here in Southern California. The end of August has given birth to dog days of uncommon ferocity, with temperatures near 100°F even on the coast, and raging wildfires that threaten to reduce both our Twitter accounts and our stargazing abilities to dust. Outside activities are curtailed, houses are sealed up tight, and the constant pillar of smoke on the horizon has created a lurking apocalyptic anxiety even among the most cheery of Angelenos. 

Under the circumstances, we all could use a stiff drink. 

Ever the public servant, I set about cataloging my favorite fire-themed wines, to recommend them to you, dear readers, as a more social alternative to Xanax and uncontrollable sobbing. Fires are an undeniable and unwelcome fact of life in California; winemakers are just as prone as anyone else to enjoying a bit of irony in their lives.

 2003 Shafer Firebreak&quot;Last Chance&quot;Sangiovese : 2003 was the last vintage of this wine, and like all lost classics, we mourn its passing.  Firebreak originally earned its moniker in 1981 when winery owner John Shafer planted a vineyard near his house to serve as a firebreak after one conflagration too many. Redolent of cherries, red currents and a bit of tobacco, it has always reminded me of my favorite Cal-Italian lover (no, I never kiss and tell): sweet on the lips, smooth going down. If you know someone who has a bottle, cultivate a friendship with him/her, and insist on an invitation to dinner. $40, if you can find it. 

 2006 Fire Station Red Cabernet Sauvignon:  This label was actually created by John Drady, owner of Sonoma Coast Winery. A firefighter himself, Drady accurately assessed that making available a kick-ass wine just might help fundraising efforts for fire departments everywhere. He was correct. I prefer mine served by the smokin&apos;hot gents from Engine Company 29 . Cherry, raspberry, chocolate-coffee, not overly tannic, and a bargain at $12.

 2006 Sea Smoke TEN Pinot Noir : Yes, it&apos;s less about fire and more about fog, but I thought it deserved a place on the list. As I slurped it down at a wine-tasting event , I made these notes in my WineSnob iPhone app: &quot;Deserves its name. Tastes of salt air.&quot; Yes, I write that kind of crap at wine-tastings. The wine is a classic, and at $125 bucks a bottle, it better be.  Be sensible, go buy it, and run away to Washington State coastline with your favorite sailor, where you&apos;ll be able to enjoy it in the aforementioned cool salt air.

And, just for fun, here&apos;s the song in the title from Hank Williams III. Please don&apos;t forget to donate to your local Red Cross. If you&apos;re in the LA area, donations of money and pet food are welcome, as well. Photo provided to the New York Times by a reader.
 
 Posted by Angela Wilson Gyetvan on August 31, 2009 in Current Affairs , Food and Drink , Hot Guys , Music , Religion , Social consciousness , Tasting_ , Wine Online_ | Permalink | Comments (0) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | | | Digg This | Save to del.icio.us 
 Next » 
 About 
 
Google Ads
 
 
 
Snooth Search
 
 
 
Recent Posts
 
 Little Morocco and the Night of the Banshee Dark and Stormy Liquidity Event First Night and the Sideways Bottle Tips for Storing Wine ¡Micheladas! Oh, honey ... No. Quaffing Oscar: Wine Pairings for the Best Picture Nominees Three Things. Stocking the Apothecary 
 
Blogs We Like
 
 Tasting Table &quot;Sorry, not my table…&quot; Qmckenna’s Weblog The Fearless Chef Tasting Notes Wine Library TV: Gary Vaynerchuk&apos;s daily wine video blog Eater SF: The San Francisco Restaurant, Bar, and Nightlife Blog Eater LA : The Los Angeles Restaurant, Bar, and Nightlife Blog Go Fug Yourself 
 
   Subscribe in a reader 
 
Recent Comments
 
 Hampers uk on Tips for Storing Wine marissa on ¡Micheladas! nativenapkin on ¡Micheladas! Angela Wilson Gyetvan on ¡Micheladas! nativenapkin on ¡Micheladas! brandon schrey on Three Things. www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=1360010180 on Stocking the Apothecary Angela Wilson Gyetvan on Stocking the Apothecary Randy Watson on Stocking the Apothecary nativenapkin on Noshing with the Native Napkin. 
 
BlogCatalog
 
 Blog Catalog Blog Directory 
 
Wine Giques Review Database
 
 WineGiques Review Database 
 
OpenWine Consortium
 
 
 View my page on OpenWine Consortium 
 
 
Blidget
 
 
 
Flickr
 
 Flickr Fotos www. flick r .com 
 This is a Flickr badge showing public photos from awgyetvan . Make your own badge here . 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed 
 Categories 
 
 Advice Books Cocktails Current Affairs Etiquette Film Food and Drink Friends General snarkiness Hot Guys Magical Elixirs Music Parties and gifts Rampant cynicism Religion Shoes Social consciousness Sports Tasting_ Television Travel Weblogs Wine Online_ Wine Varietals 
 
Creative Commons
 
 
 
This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.5 License . 
 
 See how we&apos;re connected Add me to your TypePad People list 
 Archives 
 
 January 2012 June 2011 May 2011 January 2011 July 2010 March 2010 November 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 

 More... 
 

 
 
 Blog powered by TypePad
	</body>
</document>
