<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004249" url="http://www.scam.com/showthread.php?p=1113081" time="2012-07-12-20:30" support="1" score="0.0006766462847096355" bingtitle="Don&apos;t buy a car here" webtitle="Don&apos;t buy a car here">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>Dealer Name: PD Cars Phone Number: (602) 910 4448 ... listed on their site is a Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant, not a car ... listed on their site is a business park but no car ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Add To Favorites Tweet 
 
 
   scams &gt; Message Board &gt; Used Car Scams Don&apos;t buy a car here 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 

 Register Blogs FAQ Radio Show Today&apos;s Posts Search 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Search Blogs Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 

   Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
  # 1   11-08-2011, 08:45 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Don&apos;t buy a car here Dealer Name: Pete Autos
Name(s): Jake Pete Solan
Email Addresses: jake@peteautos.com sales@peteautos.com 
 financial@peteautos.com 
Phone Number(s): (208) 352-3111&amp;(877) 225-9969
Physical Address: 1360 Kimberly Rd., Twin Falls, ID 83301

Website: http://www.peteautos.com 

Pete Autos is an overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on their fraud.

They are not a licensed Idaho car dealer which was verified by calling the Idaho Transportation Department at (208) 334-8681.

Pete Autos continues to run this scam even after being removed from Cars.com and autotrader.com for being the frauds they are. 


 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-08-2011 at 08:52 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 2   11-08-2011, 08:51 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Adam&apos;s Car Store (Birmingham, AL) Fraud Dealer Name: Adam&apos;s Car Store
Phone Number: (205) 994-2369
Physical Address (Alleged): 463 Green Springs Hwy, Birmingham, AL 35209

Website: http://www.adamscarstore.com 

Adam&apos;s Car Store is an overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have.

They are not a licensed Alabama car dealer as verified by checking the active license listing at http://www.ador.state.al.us/licenses/Active.htm 

Adam&apos;s Car Store continues to run this scam even after being removed from Cars.com and autotrader.com for being the frauds they are. See http://www.m3post.com/forums/showthread.php?t=587002 for a thread that includes one person driving by the location to verify they did not exist. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 3   11-08-2011, 08:53 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Solan Auto Sales (Dallas, TX) Fraud Dealer Name(s): Solan Auto Sales
Name(s): David Hoff
Email Addresses: sales@solanautosales.com contact@solanautosales.com 
Phone Number(s): (469) 232-7219
Physical Address (Alleged): 1011 South Beckley Avenue, Dallas, TX 75203
Website(s): http://www.solanautosales.com 
Listing Sites: http://ssolan.autodealerspoint.com ( http://www.solanautosales.com redirects Auto Dealers Point) They did use Auto Trader but that was closed down by Auto Trader.

Dealer does not exist. They are an overseas fraud attempting to get you to wire them money. This is quite similar in name to the http://www.solanmotors.com (the link is dead) scam that took a California man for $63k. See story http://www.cityofmadison.com/inciden...l.cfm?id=12614 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-08-2011 at 09:00 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 4   11-08-2011, 08:58 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Solan Auto Sales (Dallas, TX) Fraud Dealer Name: Solan Auto Sales
Name: David Hoff
Email Addresses Used: sales@solanautosales.com contact@solanautosales.com 
Phone Number: (469) 232-7219
Physical Address: 1011 South Beckley Avenue, Dallas, TX 75203
Website: http://www.solanautosales.com 
Listing Sites Used: http://ssolan.autodealerspoint.com ( http://www.solanautosales.com redirects Auto Dealers Point) They did use Auto Trader but that was closed down by Auto Trader.

&quot;Dealer&quot; is not licensed and is wants you to wire him money for deals that are too good to be true. This is similar to the Solan Motors, http://www.solanmotors.com (site not up) scam that took a California man for $63k. See http://www.cityofmadison.com/inciden...l.cfm?id=12614 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-08-2011 at 09:49 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 5   11-08-2011, 09:04 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Quick Motor Sales (Renton, WA) Fraud Dealer Name(s): Quick Motor Sales (also uses JP Sports Cars)
Phone Number(s): (425) 243-5928
Physical Addresses: 1698 Duvall Ave NE, Renton, WA 98059
Website(s) Used: http://qmotorsales.com 
Listing Sites Used: quickmotorsales.autodealerspoint.com (no longer up)

This is another scam where the vehicles don&apos;t exist but the scammer is attempting to get you to wire him money overseas. There is no dealer in Washington by this name or at the address provided as verified by State of Washington
Business Licensing Service at (800) 451-7985

It appears this fraud site may is not actively maintained but since it remains online I wanted to ensure it was reported. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 6   11-08-2011, 09:06 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Santos Auto House (Pineville, LA) - Fraud Dealer Name: Santos Auto House
Name(s): Gabriel Santos, Eugenio Santos, Marianne Bellinnes, Martin Miller, Erik Novak, Petra Markulis, Helena Meyer, Trent Wilson, Wyatt Slydell
Email Addresses: gabriel@santoscars.com eugenio@santoscars.com james.hurwitz@santoscars.com marianne.bellinnes@santoscars.com martin.miller@alabamadeluxecars.co erik.novak@santoscars.com petra.markulis@santoscars.com helena.meyer@santoscars.com trent.wilson@santoscars.com wyatt.slydell@santoscars.com 
Phone Number(s) Used: (318) 528-7323
Physical Addresses: 215 Bragg St, Pineville LA 71360
Website(s) Used: http://www.santoscars.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

Another scam listings cars they do not have for sale. This &quot;dealer&quot; is not a licensed dealer in the State of Louisiana. They attempted to add a bit of spot-legitimacy to their site be stating &quot;Santos Auto House is a trademark of SANTOS AUTOMOTIVE CENTER INC., New Orleans, LA 70119&quot; except that &quot;Santos Auto House&quot; is not trademarked and Santos Automotive Center, Inc. does not know Santos Auto House. They did appropriate Eugenio Santos&apos; name in doing up their website however. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 7   11-08-2011, 09:17 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Alabama Deluxe Cars (Pratville, AL) Fraud Dealer Name: Alabama Deluxe Cars
Name(s): Robert Rossi, Alexandar Novak, James Hurwitz, Marianne Bellinnes, Martin Miller, Erik Novak, Petra Markulis, Helena Meyer, Trent Wilson, Wyatt Slydell
Email Addresses: robert@alabamadeluxecars.com michael@alabamadeluxecars.com james.hurwitz@alabamadeluxecars.com marianne.bellinnes@alabamadeluxecars.com martin.miller@alabamadeluxecars.com erik.novak@alabamadeluxecars.com petra.markulis@alabamadeluxecars.com helena.meyer@alabamadeluxecars.com trent.wilson@alabamadeluxecars.com wyatt.slydell@alabamadeluxecars.com 
Phone Number(s): (334) 610 1175
Physical Address (Alleged): 581 McQueen Smith Road S, Prattville AL 36066
Website: http://www.alabamadeluxecars.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self-Hosted, Recently removed from Cars.com

Another scam listing cars they do not have for sale. Just another attempt to get you to wire them money so they disappear with your hard earned cash. This &quot;dealer&quot; is not a licensed dealer in the State of Alabama as verified by the active license listing at http://www.ador.state.al.us/licenses/Active.htm 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 8   11-08-2011, 10:07 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Dealer ID Theft - Freedom Motors (Abilene, TX) Be aware of this scam where the scammer stole the identify of a legitimate dealer. The scam artist used a real dealer&apos;s name and address but used a different domain or listing service to carry out the scam. See the story about America Auto Sales in Memphis, TN for an example of how this scam works. In this case these guys copied the real Freedom Motors of Abilene with a new website using Freedom Motors on Auto Dealers Point 

Dealer Name: Freedom Motors
Email Addresses: abilene.freedom.motors@gmail.com 
Phone Numbers: (325) 261-6986 Fax: (325) 261-9593
Physical Addresses: 702 S 14th Street, Abilene, Texas 79065 (This address is also the same address for the legitimate Freedom Motors of Abilene 
Website(s) Used: Freedom Motors on Auto Dealers Point 
Listing Sites Used: Freedom Motors on Auto Dealers Point 

The listing site of Freedom Motors on Auto Dealers Point was taken down today but please be vigilant for this fraud. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 9   11-08-2011, 10:11 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Dealer ID Theft - Southern Auto Brokers (Atlanta) The scam artist used a real dealer&apos;s name and address with with a listing service to carry out the scam. See the story about America Auto Sales in Memphis, TN for an example of how this scam works.

In this case these guys used the real Southern Auto Brokers with a new website using Southern Auto Brokers on Auto Dealers Point . (Listing service terminated listing account due to the obvious fraud)

Dealer Name: Southern Auto Brokers
Email Addresses: southernautobroker@gmail.com 
Phone Number: (678) 619-1609 Fax: (888) 684-9552
Physical Addresses: 449 Metropolitan Pkwy Sw, Atlanta, Georgia 30315 (This is the address of the legitimate dealer)
Website(s): Southern Auto Brokers on Auto Dealers Point 
Listing Sites Used: Southern Auto Brokers on Auto Dealers Point Also used Cars.com.

Why this type of fraud? The scam artist is attempting to circumvent anyone checking up on them. A casual search will show them as a dealer in Yellow Pages, etc... but the phone number is different. The real phone number for the legitimate Southern Auto Brokers is (404) 669-9450.

Making matters more confusing is that there is another Southern Auto Brokers that is also in the Atlanta area and is a legitimate one in Alpharetta, GA. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 10   11-09-2011, 03:07 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 PD Cars (Gilbert, AZ) Fraud Dealer Name: PD Cars
Phone Number: (602) 910 4448
Physical Address: 875 South Val Vista Drive, Gilbert, AZ 85296-3798
Website: http://www.pd-cars.com 

At the address they listed on their site is a Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant, not a car dealer. Furthermore, they are not a licensed Arizona car dealer which was verified at http://www.azdot.gov/mvd/MotorVehicl...DealerListID=1 

PD Cars is another overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on their fraud. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-11-2011 at 04:11 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 11   11-09-2011, 04:14 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Michigan US Cars Dealer Name: MichiganUSCars aka Michigan US Cars
Name(s): Bobby Claymore Tania Elmer Mark Mindwel Joseph Torres
Email Addresses: michiganuscars@yahoo.com 
Phone Number(s): (734) 206-2186
&amp;(888) 797-7819
Physical Address: 14637 Superior Street, Southgate, Michigan 48195

Website: http://www.michiganuscars.com 

Michigan US Cars is an overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on their fraud.

They are not a licensed Michigan car dealer which was verified by doing a dealer search at https://webapps.sos.state.mi.us/lrsa/Default.aspx?id=VD 

This fraud is run by the same fraudster behind the now taken down carsandcarsus.com which use to point to the now terminated carsandcarsus.autodealerspoint.com. They went by the dealer name of US Cars and Cars (Akron, OH).

Their inventory has many of the exact same cars that were on carsandcarsus.autodealerspoint.com and the site popped up almost immediately after the account and listings were terminated at carsandcars.autodealerspoint.com

The phone number for the now defunct US Cars and Cars is (330) 400-3063. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-11-2011 at 04:10 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 12   11-11-2011, 04:07 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Adam Rush Junior - aka olautos.com (Cheyenne, WY) This &quot;dealer&quot; is almost an exact duplicate of Paul Junior Cars. Even the address and phone number are the same (they may have planned on changing the address and phone number on one of them but they didn&apos;t get around to it). See details here.

Dealer Name(s) Used: Adam Rush Junior (domain of olautos.com)
Phone Number(s) Used: (307) 222-0067
Physical Addresses Used: 141 Storey Boulevard, Cheyenne, WY 82009-3527

Website(s) Used: http://www.olautos.com 

Listing Sites Used: Using Joomla on Yahoo

Description of Scam: Typical scam where they don&apos;t have the cars for sale but hope you will wire them money so they can disappear with it. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-11-2011 at 04:11 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 13   11-11-2011, 04:09 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Paul Junior Cars (Cheyenne, WY) see Adam Rush Jr. This &quot;dealer&quot; is almost an exact duplicate of olautos.com - aka Adam Rush Junior which just appeared in the past few days. Even the address and phone number are the same (they may have planned on changing the address and phone number on one of them but they didn&apos;t get around to it).

Dealer Name(s): Paul Junior Motors
Phone Number(s): (307) 222-0067
Physical Addresses: 141 Storey Boulevard, Cheyenne, WY 82009-3527
Website: http://www.pauljuniorcars.com 

Listing Sites Used: Using Joomla on hosted site in the Czech Republic

Description of Scam: Typical scam where they don&apos;t have the cars for sale but hope you will wire them money so they can disappear with it. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-11-2011 at 04:16 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 14   11-14-2011, 11:27 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Lukas Cars (Lebanon, MO) Fraud Dealer Name: Lukas Cars
Name: Rodney
Email Addresses: sales@lukascars.com rodney@lukascars.com 
Phone Number: (417) 322-9653
Physical Address: 22712 Pleasant Drive, Lebanon, MO 65536-5134
Website: http://www.lukascars.com 

At the address they listed on their site is a Dean&apos;s Used Cars that is not affiliated with the fraud Lukas Cars. Furthermore, they are not a licensed Missouri car dealer which can be verified by calling Missouri Department of Revenue, Dealer Licensing Section at (573) 526-3669 or via email dealerlic@dor.mo.gov 

Lukas Cars advertises the best prices and best services and you will get neither from them as they are just another overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on this fraud. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 11-14-2011 at 06:52 PM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 15   11-14-2011, 06:50 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Oskar Cars (Billings, MT) Fraud Dealer Name: Oskar Cars
Email Addresses: contact@oskarcars.com 
Phone Number: (406) 272-5023 Fax: (866) 674-3761
Physical Address: 5607 Interstate Ave, Billings, MT 59101
Website: http://www.oskarcars.com 

Oskar Cars is not a licensed Montana car dealer which can be verified by calling Montana Department of Justice Motors Vehicle Division at (406) 444-3933 or via email mvd@mt.gov 

Oskar Cars is hosted on Yahoo but pulls their site data from Site5. Why pay for hosting on one site and pull in your entire site&apos;s data from another site unless you want to be able to be back up and running once one site is revealed as a fraud? 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 16   11-21-2011, 10:49 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Junior Motors (Billings, MT) Fraud Dealer Name: Junior Motors (see also Oscar Cars, Billings, MT in this same thread)
Email Addresses: contact@jumotors.com 
Phone Number: (406) 272-5023 Fax: (866) 674-3761
Physical Address: 5607 Interstate Ave, Billings, MT 59101
Website: http://www.jumotors.com 

Junior Motors is not a licensed Montana car dealer which can be verified by calling Montana Department of Justice Motors Vehicle Division at (406) 444-3933 or via email mvd@mt.gov 

Junior Motors is, curiously, listed as the same address and phone number as http://www.oskarcars.com (Oskar Cars).

Junior Motors is just another overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 17   11-21-2011, 10:50 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Junior Motors (Denver, CO) Fraud Dealer Name(s) Used: Junior Motors
Name(s): Larry Templeton (Owner); Matt Waggi (Sales Manager); Jeff Krueger (Inventory Manager) Gary Rojahn (Sales) Brenda Letley (Business Manager)
Email Addresses Used: llarry@junior-motors.com matt.waggi@junior-motors.com jeff.krueger@junior-motors.com gary.rojahn@junior-motors.com brenda.letley@junior-motors.com 
Phone Number(s) Used: (720) 259-7788
Physical Addresses Used: 1190 S. Broadway, Denver, CO 80210
Website(s) Used: http://www.junior-motors.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

Description of Scam: Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. You can verify Junior Motors is not a legitimate dealer simply by calling Dealer Licensing at the Colorado Department of Revenue Enforcement Board: (303) 205-5696 or via email at dealers@spike.dor.state.co.us 

This is the same Junior Motors that purported to be a &quot;dealer&quot; in Austin, TX about six weeks ago. They resurrected the domain name after taking it down for a few weeks. The previous information for Junior Motors, Austin, TX was:

Dealer Name(s) Used: Junior Motors
Phone Number(s) Used: (512) 782-9922
Physical Addresses Used: 4120 Todd Lane Austin, TX 78744
Website(s) Used: http://www.junior-motors.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 18   11-23-2011, 11:48 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Luka Cars (Lebanon, MO) Fraud - Prev. Lukas Cars Dealer Name: Luka Cars
Name: Rod
Email Addresses: rod@lukacars.com sales@lukacars.com financial@lukacars.com 
Phone Number: (417) 501-5954 Fax: (877) 882-3319
Physical Address: 22712 Pleasant Drive, Lebanon, MO 65536-5134
Website: http://www.lukacars.com 

This is a new attempt on the previously reported Lukas Cars using the exact same address with a different phone number. At the address listed on their site is a Dean&apos;s Used Cars that is not affiliated with the fraud Luka Cars. Furthermore, they are not a licensed Missouri car dealer which can be verified by calling Missouri Department of Revenue, Dealer Licensing Section at (573) 526-3669 or via email dealerlic@dor.mo.gov 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 19   11-27-2011, 09:49 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Village Motor Center (Conway, SC) Fraud Dealer Name(s) Used: Village Motor Center
Name(s) Used: Carl Jenson George Horowitz Wilbur Suttinger Elaine D&apos;Angelo Martin Meyer Rick Pasmus
Email Addresses Used: c.jenson@villagemotorcenter.com george@villagemotorcenter.com wil.suttinger@villagemotorcenter.com e.diangelo@villagemotorcenter.com 
Phone Number(s) Used: (843) 279-0391
Physical Addresses Used: 1220 Village St., Conway, SC 29526
Website(s) Used: http://www.villagemotorcenter.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted Using Joomla. Also used Auto Trader but their listings are being removed.

Description of Scam: Another scam listings cars they do not have for sale. This &quot;dealer&quot; is not a licensed dealer in the State of South Carolina as can be verified by calling the South Carolina Department of Motor Vehicles Dealer Licensing and Audit Unit at (803) 896-2611.

This is the same website as Alabama Deluxe Cars and Santos Auto House. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 20   11-29-2011, 02:38 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Toby&apos;s Cars (Grand Junction, CO) Fraud/ID Theft This is a different type of fraud with the same concept. The scam artist uses a real dealer&apos;s name and address and creates a website to make it appear they are the legitimate dealer. See the story about America Auto Sales in Memphis, TN for an example of how this scam works. In this case these guys are using the name and address of a legitimate Toby&apos;s Cars with a different phone number.

Dealer Name(s) Used: Toby&apos;s Cars
Email Addresses Used: sales@tobyscars.com 
Phone Number(s) Used: (970) 812-3306 Fax: (877) 638-4728
Physical Addresses Used: 2128 Bond Street, Grand Junction, CO 81501 (This address is also the same address for the legitimate Toby&apos;s Cars)

Website(s) Used: Toby&apos;s Cars 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

These guys are using the same site template they used for Luka Cars . 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 21   12-01-2011, 11:34 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 OM Autos (Pocatello, ID) Fraud Dealer Name: OM Autos
Phone Number: (208) 904-2528
Physical Address: 1529 North Hayes Avenue, Pocatello, ID 83201
Website: http://www.omautos.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted (Same template as steinautos.com, pd-cars.com, rush-motors.com, qmotorsales.com, olautos.com, pauljuniorcars.com, adamscarstore.com, junior-motors.com (some of the templates changed or the sites are now down).

At the address they listed on their site is Fire Station #2 for the Pocatello Fire Department (See http://www.pocatello.us/fire/fire_tours.htm ). Furthermore, they are not a licensed Idaho car dealer which can be verified by calling the Idaho Transportation Department, Division of Motor Vehicles Dealer Licensing office at (208) 334-8681 or emailing DMV-Dealers@itd.idaho.gov .

OM Autos is just another overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on this fraud. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 22   12-02-2011, 11:51 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 BL Autos (Twin Falls, ID) Fraud - Also OM Autos Dealer Name: BL Autos (See also OM Autos ).
Phone Number: (208) 904-2528
Physical Address: 390 Victory Street, Twin Falls, ID 83301
Website: http://www.omautos.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted (Same template as steinautos.com, pd-cars.com, rush-motors.com, qmotorsales.com, olautos.com, pauljuniorcars.com, adamscarstore.com, junior-motors.com (some of the templates changed or the sites are now down).

The address they listed does not exist. The closes is Victory Avenue as oppose to Victory Street which shows only a distribution warehouse and not a dealership. Furthermore, they are not a licensed Idaho car dealer which can be verified by calling the Idaho Transportation Department, Division of Motor Vehicles Dealer Licensing office at (208) 334-8681 or emailing DMV-Dealers@itd.idaho.gov .

BL Autos (aka OM Autos) is just another overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on this fraud. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 23   12-03-2011, 03:38 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 JR Autos (Salt Lake City UT) Fraud Dealer Name: JR Autos
Name: Jeremiah Wright Matt Koch Erin Rifer Adam Arens Edward Simpson
Email Addresses: jeremiahwright@jr-autos.net matt.koch@jr-autos.net erinrifer@jr-autos.net edwardsimpson@jr-autos.net 
Phone Number: (801) 657-5501
Physical Address: 2157 South 3200 West, Salt Lake City, UT 84119-1298
Website: http://www.jr-autos.net 

At the address they listed on their site is a business park but no car dealership. Furthermore, they are not a licensed Utah car dealer which can be verified by calling the Utah Motor Vehicle Enforcement Division at (801) 297.2600 or via email mved@utah.gov 

JR Autos is just another overseas scam attempting to get you to wire them money for cars they do not have. See http://www.kmvt.com/news/local/Fake-...132751173.html for a recent story on this fraud. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 12-03-2011 at 04:24 PM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 24   12-06-2011, 12:39 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Marion Autos (Cheyenne, WY) Fraud This &quot;dealer&quot; previously was known as Paul Junior Cars at the same address and phone number. The website template is the same as many of their previous scam sites: BL Autos , OM Autos , PD Cars , Adam Rush Junior , Q Motors Sales (aka JP Sports Cars , Adam&apos;s Car Store , Rush Motors , and Stein Autos .

However, based on WHOIS Data we anticipate this fraud may try to change their address and phone number to South Carolina in the near future.

Dealer Name(s) Used: Marion Autos
Phone Number(s) Used: (307) 222-0067
Physical Addresses Used: 141 Storey Boulevard, Cheyenne, WY 82009-3527

Website(s) Used: http://www.marion-autos.com 

Listing Sites Used: Using Joomla

Description of Scam: Typical scam where they don&apos;t have the cars for sale but hope you will wire them money so they can disappear with it. 

 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 12-06-2011 at 12:43 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 25   12-06-2011, 01:29 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Golden Autos (Crown Point, IN) Fraud Dealer Name: Golden Autos
Phone Number: (317) 682-0288
Physical Addresses Used: 506 East Summit, Crown Point, IN 46307
Website(s) Used: http://www.goldenautos.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. You can verify Golden Autos is not a legitimate dealer simply by calling Indiana Secretary of State Auto Dealer Services Division at (317) 234-7190 or via email to dealer@sos.IN.gov 

Furthermore, the Crown Point is in Northern Indiana with area code 219 while this fraud used a Google Voice area code of (317) which is central Indiana (Indianapolis). They used the same exact template as more than close to ten other sites in the past few months.

Finally, the location (see photo) is a vacant warehouse and is not zoned to allow for a car dealership. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 26   12-07-2011, 05:23 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 South Parc Autos (Los Angeles, CA) Fraud Dealer Name: South Parc Autos
Phone Number: (394) 392-3983
Physical Addresses Used: 3727 Green Lane, Los Angeles, CA 90020
Website(s) Used: http://tes.freeclassifiedposts.com 
Listing Sites Used: Sub Domain of freeclassifiedposts.com

You can verify South Parc Autos is not a legitimate dealer simply by calling the California Department of Motor Vehicles at (800) 777-0133. Furthermore, the address listed is not a valid street address in Los Angeles and the phone number provided is not a valid phone number since there is no 394 area code. We more than likely came upon this site prior to it becoming fully active since the inventory shows the stock template save for the one Audi that was listed as available on December 7, 2011.

South Parc Autos is nothing more than a typical overseas fraud attempting to scam you out of your hard earned money with nothing but heart ache in return. Buyer beware this fraud. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 27   12-08-2011, 04:38 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Coderre Autos (Auburn, MA) Dealer ID Theft / Fraud Dealer Name: Coderre Autos
Phone Number: (774) 633-9111
Email: sales@coderreautos.com 
Physical Addresses Used: 147 Oxford Street North, Auburn, MA 01501
Website(s) Used: http://www.cr-autosales.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. In this case there is another dealer called Coderre Autos at the same address this fraud is using except their phone number is (508) 832-2821.

Buyer beware this fraud whose prices are too good to be true and who offers no VINs to research legitimate cars. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 28   12-14-2011, 03:59 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Marion Cars (Cheyenne, WY) Fraud aka Marion Autos This &quot;dealer&quot; previously was known as Marion Autos at the same address and phone number.

Dealer Name(s) Used: Marion Cars (aka Marion Autos)
Phone Number(s) Used: (307) 222-0067
Physical Addresses Used: 141 Storey Boulevard, Cheyenne, WY 82009-3527
Website(s) Used: http://www.marion-cars.com 

Listing Sites Used: Using Joomla

Description of Scam: Typical scam where they don&apos;t have the cars for sale but hope you will wire them money so they can disappear with it. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 29   12-14-2011, 05:13 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Marion Cars (Granger, IN) Fraud Dealer Name(s) Used: Marion Cars (previously known as Marion Autos in Cheyenne, WY)
Phone Number(s) Used: (765) 507-9636
Physical Addresses Used: 12655 Industrial Park Drive, Granger, IN 46530
Website(s) Used: http://www.marion-cars.com 
Listing Sites Used: Using Joomla

Description of Scam: Typical scam where they don&apos;t have the cars for sale but hope you will wire them money so they can disappear with it.

Vehicle Identification Numbers offered on their site as of 12/14/2011:

2007 BMW 335i Convertible VIN: WBAWL735X7PX46679
2010 Nissan GT-R VIN: JN1AR5EF2AM230589
2010 Cadillac Escalade Premium VIN: 1GYUCCEF8AR283651
1959 Cadillac El Dorado Biarritz VIN: 59E039744
2010 Audi TTS VIN: TRUB1AFK5A1018158
2011 Volkswagen Touareg VR6 LUX AWD VIN: WVGFF9BP6BD003645
2005 Ford F350 VIN: 1FTWW32P05EA07013
1957 Chevrolet Bel Air/150/210 VIN: VC57J256530
1962 Chevrolet Impala VIN: 21767G118424
1964 Austin Healey BJ7 Mark II VIN: HBJ8L27063
1969 Chevrolet Corvette VIN: 1194679S700760
1995 Chevrolet Corvette VIN: 1G1YZ22J2S5800405
2004 Bentley Continental GT VIN: SCBCR63W54C021052
2005 Cadillac Escalade EXT VIN: 3GYEK62N35G101588
2006 Dodge RAM 2500 VIN: 1D7KS28C86J215180
2007 Dodge RAM 3500 VIN: 3D7ML48CX7G718472
2010 Ford F-150 SVT Raptor VIN: 1FTEX1EV9AFB61540
2010 Nissan 370Z NISMO VIN: JN1AZ4EHXAM500115 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 30   12-14-2011, 05:17 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Re: Golden Autos (Crown Point, IN) Fraud Golden Autos changed their phone number to (219) 488-2995 which addresses the wrong area code for location issue on their fraudulent website.

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by FightOnlineCarScams Dealer Name: Golden Autos
Phone Number: (317) 682-0288
Physical Addresses Used: 506 East Summit, Crown Point, IN 46307
Website(s) Used: http://www.goldenautos.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. You can verify Golden Autos is not a legitimate dealer simply by calling Indiana Secretary of State Auto Dealer Services Division at (317) 234-7190 or via email to dealer@sos.IN.gov 

Furthermore, the Crown Point is in Northern Indiana with area code 219 while this fraud used a Google Voice area code of (317) which is central Indiana (Indianapolis). They used the same exact template as more than close to ten other sites in the past few months.

Finally, the location (see photo) is a vacant warehouse and is not zoned to allow for a car dealership. 
 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 31   12-17-2011, 11:53 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Dubois Cars (Winchester, KY) Fraud Dealer Name(s) Used: Dubois Cars
Phone Numbers: (216) 539-7173 Fax: (216) 619-9896
Email: contact@duboiscars.com 
Physical Addresses Used: 1294 Fulton Road, Winchester, KY 40391
Website(s) Used: http://www.duboiscars.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self-Hosted Using Wordpress Automobile Theme by Templatic

Just another overseas scam. There is no Dubois Cars at the phone number and address listed in Winchester, KY as verified by the Kentucky Motor Vehicle Commission at (502) 573-1000.

Finally, the phone numbers used are for Cleveland, OH and not anywhere near Winchester, KY. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 32   03-11-2012, 10:40 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Ovo Luxury Cars (Glassport, PA) Fake Dealer/Fraud Dealer Name: Ovo Luxury Cars
Phone Numbers: (412) 567-1417
Emails Used: sales@ovoluxurycars.com flopez@ovoluxurycars.com financial@ovoluxurycars.com 
Physical Addresses Used: 1280 Edmundson Drive, Glassport, PA 15045
Website(s) Used: http://ovoluxurycars.com 
Listing Sites Used: self-hosted and carsforsale.com (for inventory)

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. You can verify that Ovo Luxury Cars is not a legitimate dealer by calling the Pennsylvania DMV at (717) 783-1697 or email to RA-ST-VEHICLE@pa.gov 

Ovo Luxury Cars uses a single family residence as their address as well. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 33   03-11-2012, 10:41 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Ax Motors / Ax Motors Reno (Reno, NV) Fake Dealer Dealer Name: Ax Motors and Ax Motors Reno
Phone Numbers: (775) 391-4249 (866) 568-3971
Emails Used: sales@AXMotors.com support@AXMotors.com loan@AXMotors.com service@AXMotors.com 
 orderparts@AXMotors.com 
Physical Addresses Used: 6667 Windy Hill Way, Reno, NV 89511
Website(s) Used: http://www.axmotors.com and http://www.axmotorsreno.com 
Listing Sites Used: carsforsale.com and self-hosted

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. Ax Motors and Ax Motors Reno both use the same address which is a single family residence. They are not legitimate dealers. You can also verify this by calling the Nevada DMV at (775) 684-4690. 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 34   03-11-2012, 10:44 PM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 Gold Vehicle Center (Dallas, TX) Fake Dealer/Fraud Dealer Name: Gold Vehicle Center
Phone Number: (214) 329-9044
Physical Addresses Used: 2928 Irving Boulevard, Dallas, TX 75247-6213
Website(s) Used: http://www.vehicle-center.com 
Listing Sites Used: Self Hosted

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. You can verify Gold Vehicle Center is not a legitimate dealer simply by calling the Texas DMV at (512) 465-3000 

 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
  # 35   03-29-2012, 06:51 AM 
 FightOnlineCarScams Member   Join Date: Nov 2011 Posts: 59 
 MG Auto Center (Pompano Beach, FL) Dealer ID Theft Dealer Name: MG Auto Center, Inc.
Phone Numbers: Office: 954-773-9101 Cell: 754-444-6908 Toll Free: 888-681-2970 Fax: 877-619-0314
Emails Used: sales@mgacenter.com 
Physical Addresses Used: 4321 NW 19 Avenue, Pompano Beach, FL 33064
Website(s) Used: http://www.mgacenter.com and http://www.mgautocenter.com (this site is already taken down)
Listing Sites Used: self-hosted

Typical non-dealer advertising vehicles they do not possess in order to get you to wire them money with which they will disappear. There is a legitimately registered M G Auto Center, Inc. (note the space between and M and the G) at the address listed but this website is a scam that appropriates the name and address but uses different phone numbers. Do not fall prey to any vehicles listed for sale on this fake website.

Last month MG Auto Center was being hosted at http://www.mgautocenter.com but in typical fashion this fraud took down that site and quickly put up http://www.mgacenter.com 


 Last edited by FightOnlineCarScams : 03-29-2012 at 06:58 AM . 
 
 FightOnlineCarScams View Public Profile Send a private message to FightOnlineCarScams Find all posts by FightOnlineCarScams 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts vB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is On 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Message Board   Political Chat   MLM Scams   Internet Scams   Religious Scams   Work at Home Scams   Chat Here   Racial Chat   Business Scams   Conspiracy Theories   Investment Scams   Science Controversy   Mortgage Scams   Corporate Scams   Mail Order Scams   Insurance Scams   Lottery Scams   Government Scams   Used Car Scams   Contest Scams   Retail Scams   Nigerian Scams   Charity Scams   Auction Scams   Medical Scams   Sports Scams   Hotel Scams   Romance Scams   Weird News   Free Health Advice   Fast Food Recipes Exposed   Don&apos;t Watch These Movies   Youtube Videos   I Love Radio.Scam.com Moderator Forum 
 

 
 

 This site may contain advice, opinions and statements of various information providers. Scam.com does not represent or endorse the accuracy or reliability of any advice, opinion, statement or other information provided by any information provider, any User of this Site or any other person or entity. Reliance upon any such advice, opinion, statement, or other information shall also be at the Users own risk. Neither Scam.com nor its affiliates, nor any of their respective agents, employees, information providers or content providers, shall be liable to any User or anyone else for any inaccuracy, error, omission, interruption, deletion, defect, alteration of or use of any content herein, or for its timeliness or completeness, nor shall they be liable for any failure of performance, computer virus or communication line failure, regardless of cause, or for any damages resulting therefrom. Just because a business, person, or entity is listed on scam.com does not necessarily constitute they are scammers. This is a free open forum where people can debate the merits from the consumer&apos;s or business owner&apos;s perspective. Registration and participation is always FREE. 

 All times are GMT -5. The time now is 01:30 PM . 
 
 

 Contact Us - Scams -
 
 
- Advertising - Complaints -





 - Images - Top 

 Scams Message Board - Copyright 2004-2012 Scam.com , All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
