<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004571" url="http://www.betterbudgeting.com/articles/frugal/savingmoneyeatingout.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:03" support="2" score="0.0009537297771557384" bingtitle="Saving Money on Restaurants and Fast Food" webtitle="Saving Money on Restaurants and Fast Food">
			<query id="000875" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="147"/>
	<description>With a family of 6, eating out can often cause some ... money at restaurants, and get the most delicious meal ... And by lowering your total bill, your 15-20% tip will be ...</description>
	<body>
		As Seen in
 Newsweek, The Associated Press, Woman&apos;s Day Magazine and More! 
 Home | Sitemap | Budgeting
 Class | Frugal Cookbook | FREE
 Membership 
 Better Budgeting is
 Dedicated 
to Educating&amp;Encouraging
Families to Save Money
&amp;Live a Better Life! 

 

 www.BetterBudgeting.com 
 
 
 Michelle
 Jones 
Editor&amp;Founder 
 
   
 

 
 
 
 Learn how
 to start a budget and manage your money BETTER with our free budgeting
 worksheets, frugal recipes, homemade
 gifts and thousands of tips to help you save money all
 through the year!  

 Home 

 Free
 Budgeting Articles 

 Free
 Budgeting
 Calculators 

 Free
 Budgeting Forms&amp;Worksheets 

 Budgeting
 Class 

 Budgeting Planners&amp;Software 

 Site Index 

 Free
 Membership 

 Contact
 Us 



  Our Ebooks  

 

 Frugal
 Family Recipes Cookbook... 

 

 101
 Coupon Tips... 

 

 Free Ebook Gift
 for Better Budgeting Members! 

 Dealing
 with Debt... 

 
 
 
 
 

 Living a Better Life
 (featured column... from the editor&apos;s desk) 

 Saving Money on Restaurants and Fast Food  
 by Michelle Jones 

 With a family of 6,
eating out can often cause some serious damage to our budget. But over the
years, we&apos;ve learned lots of little tricks to save money while eating out
and I thought they might be helpful for you too. 

 * * * 

 First thing, WATER!    

 If money is really tight or you&apos;re on a mission to be as
frugal as possible, order water for everyone. And when your family starts
to complain, just remind everyone&quot;water is good for you!&quot; 

 On those days when you really want to have something to drink
besides water, try ordering one large tea or soda, and share... yes, I said
share. I hate to admit it but this is what we do quite regularly. We
don&apos;t even notice the stares any more, really! 

 Occasionally 

 The comparison between them and our large family is something
I should never even consider, but I just have to laugh when I realize we&apos;re
splitting a large coke, for 6. But hey, we are saving money! 

 Okay, okay, if this completely grosses you out, then just use
my first tip for ordering water, you will still save a fortune over a year&apos;s
time! 

 Restaurants 

 One of my favorite ways to save money at restaurants, and get
the most delicious meal for my money, is to order just a salad (or appetizer),
and dessert. Forget the main course, that&apos;s the most expensive part, and
if you order one you won&apos;t even have room for dessert, low-fat of course!
;o) Seriously though, this is a fun way to save money and you&apos;ll be saving
on calories too. And by lowering your total bill, your 15-20% tip will be
less too, so that&apos;s more money saved. 

 Fast Food 

 This one is confusing for me at times, when we&apos;re rushed and
on the go between baseball games and other activities, it&apos;s hard to remember
exactly which place is the cheapest and what I&apos;m supposed to order to get the
cheapest meal.   

 Sometimes I can feed most of us for under $6.00, and sometimes
it can cost $15.00 or more. Those $15.00 trips are the ones I try most to
avoid.   

 I should make myself a list, of exactly when and how I&apos;ve
gotten the best deals, but for now I&apos;ll try to recall a few of them for you. 

 Taco Bell is a good one, we can order tacos for everyone and
share two large drinks, for under $10.00. But the best deal I got was when
there was just 4 of us. I ordered the combo meal that had a chalupa and
two tacos, and then ordered one extra taco. The cost was around $5.00!  

 Another great deal is the two cheeseburger combo at Burger
King, or is it McDonald&apos;s? I&apos;m not sure, but you can look for it. And I think it&apos;s Wendy&apos;s that has chicken nuggets for .99 cents, and instead of
ordering happy meals for all the kids, you could get those and then share a
large drink and fries for everyone... saving at least $1.00 per person. I
know it doesn&apos;t seem like much, but the savings add up quick, believe me! 

 The Main Point 

 Wherever you eat out, the most expensive thing you want to
avoid (except on special occasions), is to order everyone their own full
meal. Cut back, combine, and share whatever you can.   

 When eating out on your own, you can save money by ordering
just the sandwich and water, skipping the fries. The combo meals are your
next best bet, but then you add another $1.00 or more to your order and about
2,000 calories, depending on what you get.   

 And for those of you that are thinking,&quot;gosh, I can&apos;t
even afford a $5.00 meal out right now,&quot;we&apos;ve been there too. The
great thing is, the money-saving tricks you are learning now, when you don&apos;t
have any extra spending money, will help you save money in the future, when
times are better and you do. :o) 

 God bless,
Michelle 

 

 Copyright 2002 by Michelle Jones. 
 &quot;Like
 Us&quot; 
 Facebook 

 Twitter 

 Pinterest 

 
 
 
 Frugal
 Family Recipes 

 Our Frugal Family
 Cookbook 

 Grocery Tips and
 Coupons 

 
 
 Editor&apos;s
 Book Pick of the Month 

 Budgeting, How to Save Money, Get Out of Debt and
 Live Well on Less 
 
 
 
 The Better Budgeting Class 
 Sign up for our next 5-week
 session and learn how to create a budget that works for you! 
 
 
 
 

 
   
 


 Thank
you for visiting with us today...   
 Don&apos;t
forget to sign up for your FREE
SUBSCRIPTION&amp;BONUS GIFT! 
 
 Home | About Us | Contact
Us | Article
Index | Affiliates 
 Reader Feedback | Disclaimer | Privacy | Subscribe | Unsubscribe-Change
Address 

          

 Copyright 
 2001-2012 by BetterBudgeting.com , a
subsidiary of Blue
Ridge Publishing, Inc. 

 All rights reserved. 
 
 Living a
 Better Life is a registered trademark of BetterBudgeting.com and it&apos;s parent company,
 Blue Ridge Publishing, Inc.  No portion of this Web site or its
 publications may be reprinted without the written permission of the editor. Please ensure that any reference to our content (shared in print, Social
 Media or on the Web) includes credit back to us with a link to
 BetterBudgeting.com. You are welcome to link to our Web site or
 individual pages. Thank you for your support! 

 Members...
 Have you told your friends and family about us? Do we have your correct email address?
	</body>
</document>
