<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004364" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/recent-comments/n/72/46153/Outside-Edmonton.html" time="2012-07-12-20:36" support="1" score="0.0002587110868995395" bingtitle="Recent reviews of Outside Edmonton Restaurants | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Recent reviews of Outside Edmonton Restaurants | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>Or are you that lazy/disorganized to make change? ... Wally&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant |Its where you stop when your going to ... they allow minors and have a stack of booster seats ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In   
 Choose a city:    Calgary     Los Angeles     New York     Salt Lake City     Seattle     Vancouver       More Cities... Urbanspoon Alberta Home &gt; Alberta &gt; Outside Edmonton  &gt; 

Recent user reviews of Outside Edmonton Restaurants


 Honeypot Eatery&amp;Pub mobile review 
by Christine J Gold ( 3 reviews )
 July 11, 2012 - I tried the Thai Crispy Chicken Salad, it was fresh, spicy and delicious! Yes this is the only place to eat! 
 | Not helpful 
 Burger Queen mobile review 
by Katie J ( 1 review )
 July 10, 2012 - Kitchy atmosphere. Food was ok. Incredibally rude waitress decided to change our order, take her own tip and got angry and refused to take payment when my sister took issue with that. Visiting Alberta and decide to visit after a family member suggested it. I will never visit this establishment again. 
 | Not helpful 
 Burger Baron (Redwater) Drive-In&amp;Restaurant mobile review 
by Adam ( 3 reviews )
 June 27, 2012 - As stated in the other reviews, this building should be demolished/condemned. As for the food it&apos;s anything but great. It&apos;s high school cafeteria food. Most of it is pre-manufactured/processed food that is just dunked in the deep fryer&amp;served. Anything that is prepared by them is boring, plain, uninspired&amp;50 years ago. Probably the only reason they get any business is that there isn&apos;t much competition here in Redwater (a Subway, two Chinese restaurants, a Diner, a Pub/Diner&amp;a Pub that has pitiful service). 
 | Not helpful 
 Wally&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant mobile review 
by Gussy ( 1 review )
 June 19, 2012 - Awesome Food ! Always packed , great place to stop leaving Fort Mac or going to :-) 
 | Not helpful 
 Chin&apos;s Cafe mobile review 
by Lyle Tuck ( 1 review )
 May 31, 2012 - Worst food ever 
 | Not helpful 
 Village Pizza&amp;Subs (Pigeon Lake) mobile review 
by Barry Lake , Washington State
 ( 1 review )
 May 31, 2012 Tasty Pizza. Friendly people. Reasonable price 
 | Not helpful 
 Burger Baron (Redwater) Drive-In&amp;Restaurant mobile review 
by Jon Kerr ( 1 review )
 May 29, 2012 Greesy gross food cooked in a building that should be condemned 
 | Not helpful 
 Cactus Cafe (Redwater) mobile review 
by Charlie ( 1 review )
 May 29, 2012 - Good food but horrible service. Waitress is too busy yapping with people she knows than taking orders when there are only 3 tables of people. It has been half an hr and she still hasn&apos;t taken our order. She took the menus away from us but apparently forgot that people come to a restaurant to eat. 
 | Not helpful 
 Drayton&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Sports Lounge mobile review 
by ivin ( 2 reviews )
 May 13, 2012 - Not a fan. The place was dead when I came in and no one was there to seat me. Then the service was so slow I almost felt like leaving. After finishing my meal it took 15 minutes just to get the check. By that time I had felt like I&apos;d done enough waiting. I don&apos;t know how they call it a sports loung when there&apos;s hardly a tv in the place. 
 | Not helpful 
 Boston Pizza (Rocky Mountain House) Great Work! 
by jenn-seniuk ( 1 review )
 May 12, 2012 - This is hands down one of the best family resturaunts in the small town! They even have a great patio for the summer season- everyone is truely welcoming and always willing to help out and go that extra mile! Thanks guys keep up the good work! 
 | Not helpful 
 Ecocafe (Pigeon Lake) Just order fries to go or go for pizza 
by joosey2 ( 1 review )
 May 05, 2012 Food prepared terrible. When we asked the waitress about the menu she acted annoyed plus she visited with her friend at another table rather than attend to us. And we were the only ones in the restaurant! That was a sign. The grilled vegetable panini had 3 thinly sliced pieces of vegetables and a dime size of cheese. No flavor. Go to the pizza place in the village instead or just order fries. 
 | Not helpful 
 Oriental Wok mobile review 
by Jodi ( 1 review )
 April 20, 2012 Amazing! Must try the dry garlic ribs...they are worth driving 2 hours for. 
 | Not helpful 
 Honeypot Eatery&amp;Pub mobile review 
by PSYoung ( 49 reviews )
 April 17, 2012 - This is the only place worth eating at when in Wainwright. 
 | Not helpful 
 
 Wally&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant Awesome burgers 
by Inukshuk , Edmonton
 ( 135 reviews )
 March 14, 2012 - This is&quot;the&quot;place to stop on your way to or from Fort McMurray. This is your classic family style burger joint and they do what they do very well. Three of us stopped in and grabbed a few things. The smell of fresh beef on the griddle and fries bubbling away in clean hot oil was a welcome treat. The shakes were amazing and the onion rings as good as any diner that makes them well. The fries appeared to be fresh cut which is always a plus. The burgers were great. I&apos;m not a mushroom burger fan but my buddy who is raved about it. I got the Wally burger, the house special that boasts 2 huge patties and the works. It was massive but I proudly&amp;happily powered through. Next time through Grasslands I&apos;m definitely stopping back in. 
 | Not helpful 
 Tofield Gas and Grill mobile review 
by Lisa , Edmonton
 ( 1 review )
 March 08, 2012 - Best pizza in town! 
 | Not helpful 
 Boston Pizza (Drayton Valley) mobile review 
by mitch ( 1 review )
 March 04, 2012 - Hm... Got stranded by a snowstorm tonight and thought hey... BP has a consistent menu, good atmosphere for a single person, and hospitable service. At least the one in Red Deer does. I really shoulda went to the chinese restaurant. I tried on of the promotional pizzas, and it seemed consistent with the quality I&apos;d expewct from them. In trhe lounge, service started out consistent and prompt (tho I&quot;interrupted&quot;the server&apos;s dinner.. She was still friendly and hospitable). 1.5 beers in and some great hocky recaps (flames... Er Lames lose yet again!); pizza arrives. Ample size and not too bad (meat lovers). Bolognese sauce was pretty basic and fit well with crust pieces; else was like a runny Salsa for rest of pizza). After a few slices and beer #3, I was asked if I wanted it boxed up; and so was and&quot;presented&quot;with my bill. Um...? I had still planned to have a couple more drinks and enjoy a game of pool, or buckhunter. Took about 15mins of my cc on the bill, with empty drinks on table, to settle the cheque. Sigh... Really? Am I not fitting into your clientelle here? I put the pizza into the truck, and came back for a little buck hunter. Ordered a Kokanee @ the bar, since the waitress didn&apos;t want me in her section (guess she was busy with those 2 tables/5 people..?). Bartender asked me in a confused and derogatory look&quot;..that&apos;s IT?!&quot;. I mentioned I&apos;d like to play buck hunter.. Is it loonies or twonies? He or the waitresses had&quot;no clue&quot;. Ok.. So you&apos;re too frikken stoopid to realize what&apos;s going on @ your workplace. I get it. Well.. Loonies will cover it.&quot;Could I get $10 in loonies?&quot;I ask.&quot;All I&apos;ve got is 2 loonies&quot;is bartender&apos;s reply. Really? You expect me to believe that? Or are you that lazy/disorganized to make change? I play 1 game, and attempt to choke down my beer. Game sucks. Laser + site not even close. Waiting for bartender to&quot;check office&quot;for more loonies. End of game, 10mins later, and 4 sips into my beer. Damn why did I sip it.. Shouldn&apos;t have tried choke it down + demand my money back. I&apos;m sincerely sorry, dear corporation and Franchisee owner, of trying to pass my funds to a local franchisee and business. Next time I&apos;ll support the Rocky Mountain House ewconomy instead. I am upset that my requesat to be treated like a patron did not fit in with you, or your staff&apos;s consumer audience paradigm, and hope you can save us both embarrassment in future visit attempts with proper disclaimers on your menu, by server, on door or better yet bright shiny red neon outside...&quot;Customers not needed&quot;Regards, M.g. March 4, 2012 
 | Not helpful 
 Bamboo Chopsticks Babmoo Chopsticks 
by Candace ( 1 review )
 January 10, 2012 Best Chinease EVER 
 | Not helpful 
 Patti&apos;s Place mobile review 
by Ollie ( 6 reviews )
 January 09, 2012 - This place is awesome! Sandwiches, subs and wraps that you can tell ate homemade and fresh every day. And there&apos;s the daily soups which are to die for! A broth and cream soup every day, and homemade and delicious! There&apos;s also daily hot sandwiches, such as hot ham or chicken breast! In short, go and eat here! It&apos;s so worth it! 
 | Not helpful 
 Honeypot Eatery&amp;Pub The Jewel of Wainwright 
by Alphabet , Edmonton
 ( 50 reviews )
 December 30, 2011 - While visiting a military friend we stopped in at the Honeypot. I love the atmosphere here, the wood walls and furnature, lighting, and decor all make it feel very comforting and relaxed. I ordered a Double Decker ($14) which is a _single_ patty burger, but it is buried under tasty onion rings. So many in fact you have to eat 5 or 6 rings before you can get your mouth around the burger. The house sauce MAKES the burger, and I wish they would bottle it up and sell it. I would make a special trip to this particular corner of the boonies to taste it again. The service there is fantastic; very friendly staff and the food is prompt. Next time I make a MeatCo run or visit the base I will make a point to come here again. 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 Boston Pizza (Wainwright) mobile review 
by Scott Smith , Edmonton
 ( 4 reviews )
 December 18, 2011 - Brutally average, even as far as Boston Pizza restaurants go. 
 | Not helpful 
 Village Pizza&amp;Subs (Pigeon Lake) dissapointing 
by fkozack ( 1 review )
 November 06, 2011 We went to Village pizza last evening Nov. 5/11; there was one other couple already seated, we sat and waitress took our order. The place got quite busy after that with sit ins and take outs. We are patiently waiting, soon looking right at the server and after 25 minutes,she doesn&apos;t acknowledge us at all, when I finally asked how long we would be she asked what name our order was under - she had not asked our names and even worse turns out the person in kitchen hadn&apos;t even started our order, no apologies -the&quot;chef&quot;just threw order in garbage. We had been to this place a number of times during the summer but we will not be back, this is a quieter community in the winter and the winter customers I would hiope are just as improtant - perhaps they should check with ECO to see how that is done. 
 | Not helpful 
 Ecocafe (Pigeon Lake) mobile review 
by Tod Rudge , Edmonton
 ( 1 review )
 October 01, 2011 - Rude service we left and didn&apos;t even try the food. Went to Black Bull which was friendly and had good food. 
 | Not helpful 
 Mallard&apos;s Landing Cafe This place is exceptional! 
by lscheers ( 1 review )
 September 28, 2011 - The best small town cafe I&apos;ve ever eaten at! Everything is so delish but there are some outstanding choices. Homemade soups are always unique and flavourful. Perogies with dill, bacon, caramelized onion and cream sauce are unbelievable. The clubhouse is a flavour explosion with lots of bacon, mayo, ham and tomatoes - and it&apos;s huge! These are small town people running a small town cafe in the perfect location if you&apos;re headed to the lakes in northeastern Alberta. Stop in - you won&apos;t be disappointed!!! 
 | Not helpful 
 Bamboo Chopsticks dont even bother walking in 
by Rachel MacDonald ( 1 review )
 September 24, 2011 ordered the meal for 3, and subbed an item, that brought our before tax total to around 31.00. On the menu it states any order (before tax) over $30.00 will receive a free order of dry ribs. They inform me on the phone that&quot;he&quot;says substitutions don&apos;t count, even though Im paying for it, and it&apos;s over 30 before taxes. I told her if that is how it is, cancel my order, I wont buy from someone that picky about unwritten rules and having false advert. She said no it&apos;s ok, i will talk to him (not a huge deal, i know, but it&apos;s the principle ) When my husband went to pick up, she loudly and rudely stated that she told me on the phone that we would not get them because of this unspoken,unwritten rule..he spoke to the owner, an older chinese man, who yelled at him, said he has been doing this for 30 years...He told him he would never get our buisness again..seems like a small sacrafice to make for a good customer They refused to give us a refund, so we were stuck with the food..got it home, seemed like rather large portions...i soon discovered why..CHEAP tasteless ingredients, the egg rolls and chicken balls tasted like greasy dough..the rice tasted like dirty oil, the only thing that seemed ok, was the pineapple sauce. I left my roll and chkn balls, couldnt eat them..the chow mein tasted like something i made once with mr noodles and left over chicken....TERRIBLE terrible food, EVEN WORSE CUSTOMER SERVICE.WE WILL NEVER EAT HERE AGAIN, .Just so the owner knows, you just lost out on an ATLEAST&amp;200.00 table next week when our family is in town. 
 | Not helpful 
 Patti&apos;s Place mobile review 
by Heidi ( 1 review )
 August 22, 2011 - It&apos;s delicious, fresh food that&apos;s made from the heart! And the best pie I&apos;ve ever had! 
 | Not helpful 
 Wally&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant |Its where you stop when your going to fort mac 
by JonJonPoPong , Edmonton
 ( 168 reviews )
 August 19, 2011 - I normally power through grassland when im going up to fort mac, to stop would be to add more time to ones trip. However I decided to drop into wallys and grab a quick milk shake and I was glad I did. The girl behind the counter was quick with getting me my order even though the place was doing brisk buissness and the milk shake itself was nice, pretty sweet but a good milk shake at a decent price. If I dont fly back to Edmonton I will have to stop in again. 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 Burger Baron (Drayton Valley - Drive-in) mobile review 
by Tom ( 1 review )
 August 12, 2011 It is closed 
 | Not helpful 
 Ecocafe (Pigeon Lake) Owner is rude&amp;unprofessional 
by Aliciaha ( 1 review )
 August 06, 2011 - We have a house in pigeon lake and since the other dinner place at the village closed we are limited to Eco cafe and the black bull. The menu selection is nice at Eco cafe and their coffees are good, however overpriced as their desserts are and we didn&apos;t even find them that tasty. We like that they support local farmers and are&quot;organic&quot;. For a small town cafe, the owner isnt very friendly, disciplines her staff in an unprofessional manner right out in the open, is curt with customers and comes across as pretentious. 
 | Not helpful 
 Ecocafe (Pigeon Lake) Skip for breakfast 
by Charlotte Wallewein , Calgary
 ( 5 reviews )
 July 31, 2011 It&apos;s a shame we came to the Eco Cafe for breakfast because the lunch menu looked a lot better. From the breakfast menu, it was hard for us to determine exactly what was&quot;eco&quot;about this cafe - it looked like a menu I&apos;d expect to find at any other middle-of-the-road Alberta breakfast joint. It started with the coffee - we ordered one coffee and one vanilla latte, and the latte came to me with so much sugar in it that I couldn&apos;t even handle more than a sip. Think Starbucks, then double or maybe triple it. It was 15-20 minutes before I was able to return this as I hadn&apos;t sipped it before the server took our breakfast order and no one returned to the table until our breakfast was ready. This leads me to the other issue: breakfast. At a place called&quot;Eco Cafe&quot;, you&apos;d expect to be able to find something healthy and vegetarian, I thought. This is not the case. If you don&apos;t want french toast or pancakes (something we&apos;d been offered for free and turned down before we went to the cafe!) you are pretty much SOL if you don&apos;t want a large pile of eggs. And eggs would have been fine, but when I asked the server where the eggs came from (if I&apos;m going to eat eggs I want them ethical) she seemed confused and puzzled by the question. How can an&quot;eco cafe&quot;not educate its staff as to where its eggs are sourced from? I couldn&apos;t find anything&quot;eco&quot;about the experience! So, in the end, while I had been hoping for a healthy meal with fresh vegetables (something SERIOUSLY lacking from the menu), I instead ended up with oatmeal and hash browns. This cafe might as well have been called&quot;greenwash&quot;cafe for all the ethical and responsible options it provided on its menu. And while the hash browns were good, I&apos;m sure free pancakes would&apos;ve been good too. And free. On another note, the place seemed like it wanted to be urban and modern but also seemed to require all its servers to wear black pants with white shirts - BORING. I was actually put off by this. Let them wear something nice and look good, rather than put on something so uninspired. This cafe was a serious let down - perhaps my expectations were just too high - it is rural Alberta after all. 
 | Not helpful 
 Village Pizza&amp;Subs (Pigeon Lake) mobile review 
by Kyle K ( 1 review )
 July 24, 2011 - Excellent pizza, with fresh toppings and fresh crust. 
 | Not helpful 
 Boyle Truck Stop Restaurant No, not that hooters... 
by Alphabet , Edmonton
 ( 50 reviews )
 July 20, 2011 - This place is attached to a convenience store called Hooters, no relation to the place with the big... plates of wings. It&apos;s only a two person operation as far as I can tell, one server and one cook, so things will be slow coming to your table. However the server&quot;knows&quot;her regulars and knows exactly what they come in for. And there&apos;s a lot to choose from! Their menu reads like a napa autoparts catalog; chinese, ukrainian, italian, burgers, wraps, anything you can think of. I ordered a&quot;loaded&quot;burger with fries and my wife picked the ginger beef with rice. We both had milkshakes. The milkshakes have many different flavor choices (I had coconut) due to a large rack of flavoring bottles but the ice cream was real and it was smooth and creamy. When you do get your meal you will notice they are very generous with their portion sizes. I&apos;ll admit that when I looked at their large menu I thought they&apos;ll be a victim of a Food Network makeover, but I could not find fault with any of their food. Both the burger and the ginger beef (sampled) were excellent! 
 | Not helpful 
 
 Burger Baron (Redwater) Drive-In&amp;Restaurant Great food, but... 
by Randal , Edmonton
 ( 1 review )
 June 15, 2011 - Some of the best hamburgers, fried chicken and pizzas I&apos;ve ever had. However they no longer serve ice cream, which is a real bummer. And the building they&apos;re located in should be demolished; it&apos;s old and run-down. They keep it clean, but it&apos;s just time to rebuild. 
 | Not helpful 
 Town Pump Restaurant I like there pizza 
by a tata , Ontario
 ( 3 reviews )
 June 11, 2011 - There pizza is great!!!...and is not frozen. Someone is losing it... 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 A&amp;W (Barrhead) Typical chain restaurant. 
by Malt Lover , Edmonton
 ( 166 reviews )
 April 26, 2011 - Typical chain restaurant like most A&amp;Ws but with friendly and cheerful staff. Appeals to lots of families and Seniors. Clean with clean washrooms. I like that they have salt and pepper shakers at each table, unlike the Stony Plain A&amp;W. 
 | Not helpful 
 Town Pump Restaurant mobile review 
by RoadCrit ( 1 review )
 February 17, 2011 - PIZZA***Exhaust all frozen options before you waste your money on this pizza. All dough and minimal toppings...12 inch Loaded only $25.99+. Did I mention the grease? 
 1
 
 person recommends this review | Not helpful 
 Boston Pizza (Drayton Valley) As expected from BP 
by FoodReviewer , Edmonton
 ( 6 reviews )
 November 28, 2010 - All the pizzas were quickly prepared and the waiters were very kind. The service there was proficient, I don&apos;t have much of a problem with it. I overall, recommend this restaurant. 
 | Not helpful 
 Burger Baron (Drayton Valley - Drive-in) Rustic! 
by Malt Lover , Edmonton
 ( 166 reviews )
 November 24, 2010 - The dine in area is rather rustic, with an open kitchen. The burgers are good, but the fries are nothing to write home about. Hard ice cream sold in summer in a choice of flavours seemed more popular even than the burgers when we were there! The drive through is even powered wheelchair friendly, as we observed with one regular customer. 
 | Not helpful 
 Drayton&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Sports Lounge The restaurant is popular and cozy. 
by Malt Lover , Edmonton
 ( 166 reviews )
 November 24, 2010 - Friendly staff make the difference here. Wide variety of food offered, including some Greek dishes. Look for the daily specials on the chalkboard for some good deals! Can&apos;t comment on the bar next door, although it always seems busy. (4/5) 
 | Not helpful 
 Boston Pizza (Drayton Valley) Reliable 
by Malt Lover , Edmonton
 ( 166 reviews )
 November 24, 2010 - A reliable restaurant and Sports bar following the dictates of Boston Pizza franchises. Good food and good drinks! 
 | Not helpful 
 Gondola&apos;s Steak&amp;Pizza (Lamont) unreal 
by jordan ( 1 review )
 July 16, 2010 This restaraunt is located in a small town about 45 min from edmonton. I must say for a small town this restaraunt was exquisite. From the meals to the staff to the decor, i would recommend this place to anyne who enjoys amazing eatery! 
 | Not helpful 
 Smoky&apos;s Grill (Seba Beach) Well worth the drive! 
by Malt Lover , Edmonton
 ( 166 reviews )
 June 27, 2010 - We didn&apos;t make it back until June, but found it well worth the drive. Smokey&apos;s Burger at $8.95 is a bargain. A six ounce patty of pure, hormone free, grass fed, local beef on a big bun, with Dijon mustard (not for me, but for my wife), ketchup, lettuce, onion and tomato, and a pile of freshly cooked fries. Add bacon for $1 (four strips) and a slice of cheese (not&quot;plastic&quot;but real) for $1.50. Other add-ons include mushrooms. Steaks and steak sandwiches also from the same local beef supplier. Friendly service and a pleasant patio overlooking the driving range. 
 | Not helpful 
 Zorba&apos;s Restaurant niece Alexandra Jeffries 
by Alexandra Jeffries ( 1 review )
 June 10, 2010 Hi. My name is Alexandra I am a relative of my Uncle Costas. I am writing the review for Zorbas as an exquisite place to eat!!!! The warmth of Zorbas fine restaurant and good food will make you happy!!! Thios Costas, How have you been? Hi Thia Fefi!!! God Bless you all George and Spiros!!! I wish I was there. If you all wish to send work via this email website please I will write soon. My new number is 910-599-3083. A cup of coffee is great!!!! I love you!!!!! LIfe is good!!!!! 
 | Not helpful 
 Gondola&apos;s Steak&amp;Pizza (Lamont) Tipical small town restaurant 
by James Atkinson ( 2 reviews )
 May 29, 2010 This little place is your average small town eatery. The food is good and the prices are decent. The decor is faux-Italian and the staff is friendly if a little slow at times. The menu is extensive running from standard italiant fare to pizza to family restaurant favorites. Overall it&apos;s a fine little place in a town low on places go eat. Best pizza in Lamont but then there are only two places in town that serve pizza and the other is a burger joint... 
 | Not helpful 
 Smoky&apos;s Grill (Seba Beach) Not Family Friendly 
by doug ( 1 review )
 May 16, 2010 I took my family of 4 to this restaurant on a sunday. We were drawn to this place by their delicious sounding menu and claim of being family friendly. Unfortunately there is nothing family-friendly about this place other than they allow minors and have a stack of booster seats in the corner which I had to get myself. There was no crayons and paper, or anything else to occupy my two year old. My wife ordered a hawaiian pizza, which was generous wiyh toppings and cheese, very delicious. My 16 year old ordered the chicken caesar wrap wich came with fries. The chicken was moist, and the fillings fresh, with just the right amount of sauce, very good. I ordered the staek sandwich with fries and a side of gravy, a HUGE disappointment. The steak was thick and chewy with a big fat rind in the centre. The garlic toast was a piece of texas toast which came out dark and I couldn&apos;t taste the garlic. The gravy was almost black, had no flavor and was very thick and chunky, not good. Overall this restaurant was just okay. If you are looking for run of the mill pub grub at a decent price, this is it. If you are looking for a true family place with great food, keep looking!!! 
 | Not helpful 
 Smoky&apos;s Grill (Seba Beach) It&apos;s a Shame they only open in Summer 
by Malt Lover , Edmonton
 ( 166 reviews )
 December 21, 2009 - What an interesting find! Locally sourced almost organic beef. Great burgers. Alley Kat microbrewery beer on tap. I can&apos;t wait for May to go back! 
 | Not helpful 
 

 See more recent reviews 


 Home &gt; Alberta &gt; Outside Edmonton  &gt; 
 Careers | Add Restaurant | Contact Us | Blog | Go Mobile | About Us | Terms of Service | Privacy | FAQ   Get Urbanspoon on the iPhone Partner Sites: Ask Answers | Life123 | Bloglines | Citysearch | Insider Pages | MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
