<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004052" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/241/1518995/restaurant/Oklahoma/Pembertons-Eufaula" time="2012-07-12-20:16" support="3" score="0.0032446577478916056" bingtitle="Pemberton&apos;s - Eufaula | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Pemberton&apos;s - Eufaula | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="46"/>
	<description>... perfection, they cook it all fresh not a fast food restaurant. ... view from your very comfortable cushioned seat ... The beverage selection is large and who can&apos;t ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Oklahoma » Eufaula » Pemberton&apos;s 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Austin Dallas/Fort Worth Kansas City Los Angeles New York Oklahoma City Tulsa More... 
 
Pemberton&apos;s
 
(918) 689-7100
 Eufaula SW Corner Hwy 69&amp;Texanna Rd 
 Eufaula , OK 74432 
 pembertons-ok.com 

Added by Bill C 
 See all 32 reviews Cuisine Steakhouse , Seafood , Italian Features Kid Friendly , Late Night , Romantic , Sports Bar , Takes Reservations Menu $$ $10-15 per entree southern fried steak, Salmon View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   114 people have voted 88 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 June 29, 2012 Mobile review by Jamie Jones Johnson ( 1 review ) Just left Pemberton&apos;s. The atmosphere is swanky the food phenomenal! The service was spot on. We had the red snapper and the shrimp scampi. We may need a standing reso. Best seafood around Muskogee! Makes red lobster the mcdonalds of seafood. June 11, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it A verry unhappy almost customer by Jeannice Calkins ( 1 review ) Very unpleasing experience. Two hours and never got our food. Waitress was rude and hatefull, she never should have been able to continue working after the way she treated our party of 30+. First time to ever go there and the last. For my son and his fried who order their steaks med/well it was still moving. I will pass this experience on to all our community and they lost some customer that goes there many of times that spend a great deal of money. The manager has no business being a manager. He hides behind the counter and can not speak for himself. He should have sent the waitress home after the comments she made to some of the women in our group. Good luck if you try this restaurant out. Over priced and over rated!!! March 23, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by jon shaw ( 2 reviews ) Had reservations at 7. It&apos;s 8:15 and we still haven&apos;t been seated. An added bonus, although we are welcome to wait in the bar, we&apos;ve been asked to move 3 times and were told we couldn&apos;t sit at a table in case they needed it. Who cares that the food is good when the service is crap. I can drive to Tulsa and eat. April 3, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Don Cotton ( 1 review ) I had the Tillapia, it was just awesome, service was top notch, it takes time for perfection, they cook it all fresh not a fast food restaurant. 3 out of 3 found this review helpful March 11, 2011 Really likes it fantastic food, fantastic service, fantastic atmosphere by dian ( 1 review ) this place is a must! doesn&apos;t look like much from the outside but&quot;wow&quot;when you walk through the door it&apos;s elegant. carpeted floors, linen napkins and table cloths. the kitchen is in full view from your very comfortable cushioned seat with side arms. seven generations of pemberton photographs hang from the forest green walls. you are greeted with a smile and treated like royalty. everything is fresh. no pots of precooked food sitting on their stove. if you would like to substitute something on the menu, it is their pleasure to please you. if it isn&apos;t on the menu and they have it in the kitchen, its their pleasure to prepare it for you. pembertons have a full service lounge and a terrific wine list. there is also a smoking lounge where the excellent food is served. there is a dance floor and juke box in the lounge. they also have a fine assortment of cigars. angi is their 6 foot tall bartender and she is a hoot. be sure to tip well for the excellent service. butch (the... more» this place is a must! doesn&apos;t look like much from the outside but&quot;wow&quot;when you walk through the door it&apos;s elegant. carpeted floors, linen napkins and table cloths. the kitchen is in full view from your very comfortable cushioned seat with side arms. seven generations of pemberton photographs hang from the forest green walls. you are greeted with a smile and treated like royalty. everything is fresh. no pots of precooked food sitting on their stove. if you would like to substitute something on the menu, it is their pleasure to please you. if it isn&apos;t on the menu and they have it in the kitchen, its their pleasure to prepare it for you. pembertons have a full service lounge and a terrific wine list. there is also a smoking lounge where the excellent food is served. there is a dance floor and juke box in the lounge. they also have a fine assortment of cigars. angi is their 6 foot tall bartender and she is a hoot. be sure to tip well for the excellent service. butch (the owner) has done a great job. she has put all of the nice things inside the green metal building. she is usually there and will come by your table to make sure everything is great. this is a must try! no one exceeds pemberton&apos;s 3 out of 3 found this review helpful September 25, 2010 Likes it by jim - cherry ( 1 review ) great atmospher, great food , great service. just what eufaula needs. jim&amp;cherry nippert 3 out of 3 found this review helpful March 12, 2011 Really likes it BEST FOOD, BEST SERVICE,AND LOTS OF FUN by STEPH ( 1 review ) Eufaula has needed a place like this to eat at for years.. The steaks are the best, ZAC who is the cook can make ur food taste better than u have ever had it before... ANGI the bartender can make u any drink u ask for and u will LOVE it!!! Come out for some fun in the lounge, they have an X-BOX that u can bowl on like u are really bowling, which is alot of fun and other games. They just got a jukebox that u can download any song u want to hear. Come give them a try.. U WONT BE DISAPPOINTED!! 3 out of 3 found this review helpful March 18, 2012 Really likes it WONDERFUL!!! by Karen Spradlin Kinsey ( 1 review ) Worth the wait if you have to! My husband and I had dinner at Pemberton&apos;s for our 15th wedding anniversary. The food was to die for and the service Excellent! I would recommend asking for Kathy to wait on you! She went above and beyond! The decor&apos; is upperclass. You should phone ahead and make a reservation! This has become our favorite restaurant! March 10, 2011 Likes it Seceret Place for Fine Dining by george drake ( 3 reviews ) Wow, Pembertons is one of the best kept secrets of the area. The food is excellent, service outstanding and the restaurant is clean as a pin. You know it is going to be good when the kitchen is in full view for you to see. I have eaten there several times and always amazed at the great atmosphere and quality food at a reasonable price. Give them a try it is simply outstanding. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful +2 more review from george drake July 12, 2011 Mobile review I took the family to pembertons for a 4th of July dinner and the food was awesome. It is quality food in a very nice atmosphere and reasonably priced. It is a very nice restaurant I highly recommend it. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 16, 2011 Mobile review Wonderful food with friendly service. Their filet is outstanding. Hidden secret at lake Eufaula February 11, 2011 Likes it Harry&amp;Diana Hillyard by Harry Hillyard ( 1 review ) We have dined at Clancy&apos;s in New Orleans,La Ciccia in San Francisco,Mado in Chicago,Olivia in Austin and many other fine establishments and Pemberton&apos;s in Eufaula Ok. stands with the best in selection,preparation,service,and atmosphere.A delicious experience not expected at Lake Eufaula,Ok. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful December 1, 2010 Likes it southern fried steak by Kathryn Roberts Pemberton ( 1 review ) southern fried steak -
its new on the menu as well as other items a must try all meat and very little breading (its all about the meat) 2 out of 2 found this review helpful March 7, 2011 Likes it Best Little Steakhouse in OK by Shasta ( 1 review ) This is the best little steakhouse in OK. The owner is a gal named&quot;Butch&quot;and she has the best Chef in these parts. There is no western decor, just comfortable chairs and tablecloths like your granny laid out for Sunday dinner. Chef Zac can cook any of those steaks as well as any you&apos;ve ever eaten. The food and service are always excellent. I&apos;ve eaten steaks, seafood, pasta with the appetizers, salads and desserts. You won&apos;t be disappointed. Try the Caesar. It&apos;s the best!! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful July 9, 2010 Likes it Nice by Leigh ( 1 review ) I loved the service and the food was great! The steaks are wonderful and the atmosphere was so nice. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful February 28, 2012 Likes it Pemberton&quot;s in Eufaula by Naomi Kindred ( 1 review ) One word....SWANKY. Not another place around that compares. One side fine dining, and other side a nice lounge, which features, the wonderful Harley Hamm on Thursday, and Friday evenings. The food is out of the world...stick with steak and grilled Tilapia......no one can beat it in this area. August 10, 2011 Likes it Great food by sissy&apos;s mom ( 13 reviews ) We went while on vacation. Had 9 people in our group. Wasnt sure what to expect when we drove up. Wondrful experience, great food, great service, friendly staff. Never had to ask for drinks to be refilled. If we asked for something, we got it in a quick manner, with a smile. We live an hour away and we will be back and bring friends. Worth the cost and the time to drive down there. Keep it. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 5, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by mark gilliland ( 1 review ) Absolutely great food, great service and the best bread pudding ever. Butch offers the best of everything for a good price. We love it and visit at least twice a month from Muskogee!!!! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 5, 2011 Really likes it Mobile review by Tami ( 1 review ) We have been searching for a local place to eat since we moved from Utah, this is it. Good price for excellant service and food is outstanding. Prime Rib is the best and desserts are to die for. The best place to eat in Oklahoma. So ecited to find this gem. Will definately b a recuring customer. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful July 9, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Colleen Jackson ( 1 review ) Fresh and delicious food! Great service and a great chef. Open concept kitchen so you can watch Zach work his magic. We also had a good time after dinner listening to the live music in the bar. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful January 22, 2012 wonderful by HLS ( 1 review ) excellent food and service, a true delight for the Eufaula area April 30, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Jody Walker ( 3 reviews ) I have to say I was pleasantly... Very pleasanly suprised with the quality of the food and service. At first glance from the internal atmosphere I expected a good meal. But the steak was extremely tender and juicy, cooked to just the right temperature. The service was fantastic and don&apos;t even get me started on the bread pudding... Best I&apos;ve ever had. If your looking for good food try another place. If your looking for excellent full flavor quality food. You&apos;ve found it! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful 
 Show 10 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Butch Pemberton Pemberton&apos;s by Butch Pemberton Pemberton&apos;s 
 All 19 photos View larger map Driving directions People reached this page by searching for: 
 pembertons eufaula ok pembertons eufaula pemberton&apos;s restaurant eufaula ok pembertons restaurant eufaula ok pemberton steakhouse eufaula ok 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
