<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004068" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/3/1346388/restaurant/New-York/Canarsie/Fisheye-Bar-Grill-Brooklyn" time="2012-07-12-20:17" support="3" score="0.0043572872219117065" bingtitle="Fisheye Bar &amp; Grill - Canarsie - Brooklyn | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Fisheye BarGrill - Canarsie - Brooklyn | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>... because we were just about ready to leave from ... ok fish eye never said they were a fast food restaurant and ... I ordered my food to go and was amazed that i had ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 New York » Brooklyn » Canarsie » Fisheye Bar&amp;Grill 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Baltimore Hartford Los Angeles North Jersey Philadelphia Providence More... 
 
Fisheye Bar&amp;Grill
 
(718) 451-3474
 Canarsie 5913 Foster Ave 
 Brooklyn , NY 11234 See all 34 reviews Cuisine Caribbean , Seafood Features Free Wi-Fi , Happy Hour , Late Night , Live Music , Romantic , Sports Bar Menu $$ $10-20 per entree View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch Dinner               Late               
   379 people have voted 88 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Bonnie&apos;s Grill 88% $ Park Slope - American, Burgers, Soups 278 5th Ave 
 
 Lenny&amp;John Pizzeria 92% $ Flatbush/Midwood - Pizza 2036 Flatbush Ave 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 April 20, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by daprd00 ( 4 reviews ) I forgot to mention the service. Nicole served us promptly and foresaw our needs. Definitely worth it.. +1 more review from daprd00 April 20, 2012 Mobile review The cuisine was great. The Alfredo white wine sauce was amazing. The drinks were hard core slammin. If you like the spicy stuff, you&apos;ll love it. December 12, 2010 Likes it Ambiance and Seafood..my favs! by Rachael E. ( 10 reviews ) The ambiance here is great, we stayed quite awhile and enjoyed their bar menu. The Bammie was a sight to see, one of my favorite Jamaican dishes, and the crab cakes were also outstanding. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful August 10, 2011 Likes it relaxing place to hang out with gf&apos;s by Lexi Mc Commick ( 1 review ) It was the first time my gf and i went to fisheye bar and grill and i could say it was worth our while. the food was fingure licking and oh gosh what a good rasta pasta. I could say the price range is descent and its jus the right spot to hang out with good music and vibes. it is my new hang out place now.. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful March 3, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it DISGUSTING by Remonia ( 1 review ) We took my friend to this awful establishment for her birthday. Two of us got there before the others so we ordered appetizers. It took the appetizers 45 minutes to get to the table. Our server&apos;s (Nicole) attitude got nasty after she realized that our group was not ordering liquor. She took some of our orders after we had to call her over twice. We realized that another forty five minutes passed before we got our food. We quickly order three more entrees and more drinks, which took almost an hour to get to the table. One of our fish meals was cold. We called over the manager because we were just about ready to leave from all the bad service and mediocre food. The manager was defensive of the cold meal they brought out. With the cold plate in his hand, he told us that the fish was made to order. It definitely wasn&apos;t if it&apos;s cold along with the sides. Then Nicole came over to say that it was&quot;Impossible&quot;that the fish came out cold. Excuse me! She came to pick up the check faster than she came to get our orders. This&quot;establishment&quot;(and I use the word loosely when it comes to them) is for the DOGS!! February 25, 2012 Really likes it Mobile review by Khola ( 1 review ) Great atmosphere... Awesome chill spot also great Food and Drinks (^_^) February 16, 2012 Likes it Valentine&apos;s Night Was Great by Eugenia Thomas ( 1 review ) On Valentine&apos;s day my husband and I went to Footprints but when we got there the wait time was too long. My husband then suggested to go to Fish Eye where he had been to a couple of times to have a drink, but he never ate there. We decided to go to Fish Eye, and we were greeted by a tall slender gentleman who we later found out was one of the owners. He brought us to our seat and a waitress came over shortly with a menu. Overall my experience there was great and I was glad my husband had suggested to go there. The food and service was good,the price was very reasonable, and the music was very appropriate for the occasion. I will definitely be going to Fisheye for Valentines Day next year and most likely even before that. November 6, 2011 best spot in bk by Sparks Scott ( 1 review ) fisheye is a very popular and too bad for those who find there service for food was a bit tooo long. fisheye is a more of stand up atmopshere and everyone seem to be okay with it. if you want to go to a place where you can get your food serve right away, fisheye is not the spot for that. i love it, my friends love it and we&apos;ll continue to go there. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 27, 2011 Mobile review by jackie ( 1 review ) It with great pleasure to recommend everyone to Fisheye. When u r looking for an evening or night with good caribbean food, relaxation, an excellent service check out this restaurant. The staff are friendly, great location and prices are average. I have a wedding reception there a week ago and it was amazing. Everyone is still calling me telling me how the food is soooooooooo good. You should stop bye. Loving it. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 1, 2011 Likes it Nice Experience by Shannon J. ( 1 review ) I went to Fisheye the other nigh after hearing many good things about the place. I went with two of my girlfriends and we had a great time. I had stuffed lobster which was tasty and my friends had salmon which they enjoyed. The only thing i can honestly complain about was the service. The waitress was pleasant however the wait time was too long. It was worth waiting though. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 15, 2011 Likes it love it by cee ( 1 review ) I travel all the way from NJ...love fisheye and it is the only spot in bklyn that i can always count on for good music and good food alike. Crowd is very laid back, no issues, no drama and more importantly no gunshots ...food&apos;s good for the price however if you want oxtail call ahead and check if it&apos;s on the menu because as we&apos;ve learned it is not a staple item on the menu/ not anymore. The rasta pasta is on point..just add some jerk chicken and you&apos;re good to go. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful November 17, 2011 Likes it great, great ,place by ms couture ( 1 review ) i love fisheye the is great the food is excellent , a very great place to go and just chill have some food and drinks and listen to some music&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;the staff are very polite and nice January 17, 2009 Absolutely Great by LaDii_Kween12 ( 1 review ) The food at Fisheye Bar&amp;Grill is wonderful. I&apos;ve been there over 10 times and I still love going there. The food is great, the service is great, the atmosphere is great and I can&apos;t ask for anything better. It is like experiencing a Manhattan restaurant in Brooklyn. August 4, 2009 Likes it Fast food joint by Sparkle ( 2 reviews ) This is for people who dosent use good judgement ok fish eye never said they were a fast food restaurant and yes if you order your food to go it would be longer than usual foot prints is the same thing and Sally is a restaurant that is design for take out service. Sometimes I wonder why we as humans don&apos;t use better judgement instead of they criticize another man&apos;s work just because they didn&apos;t use good judgement +1 more review from Sparkle August 4, 2009 Fridays and Saturdays Awwwww this is the spot in bk since sugar cane. My friend and I love it dispite it be so crowded. They say when a place has a good Dj and good food you know it&apos;s a sell off. We love it we try not to go every weekend to become regulars but we love love it. Yuh dun know March 23, 2009 Likes it Luv it by mepknight ( 1 review ) I have been going to De-eye as we call it - its a wonderful place to hang - meet people and have fun - the drinks price compare to the city is good - I can cook and when I tell you&quot;De Chef a say one&quot;- music and di vibes a sey&quot;SELL ON&quot;- the staff friendly -management cool - mek yuh feel relaxed - everybody have dem own opinion - respect to Management and Staff of De-Eye January 21, 2010 Likes it Great Place ! by LADii Brklyn ( 3 reviews ) i love Fish eye. anyone who has a problem with paying to get in has a serious problem. i totally disagree. this place is totally worth it. the service could be a little better but however i dont have any problem with paying. a few dollars isnt going to make anyone richer or poorer. its all about spending time with ur friends in a place with great music, great food and ok service. the lady at the door greeted me well. i didnt hav a problem with paying however other people did. she simply told them he policy and many disagreed. i will continue going here. it has become mi favorite spot. fisheye is de best ! +2 more review from LADii Brklyn April 19, 2009 De BEST !!! I love this place ! Great ambiance, goo food, good music, but the service could be better. I love going to Fisheye to hang out with friends. The prices are good especially for the good quality of food. They have different events like comedy and others which I really like and the dj mixes are great. I like going to Fisheye because its like experiencing a Manhattan lounge/bar but without those expensive prices. I would definitely recommend Fisheye to friends and family ! April 19, 2009 De BEST !!! I love this place ! Great ambiance, good food, good music, but the service could be better. I love going to Fisheye to hang out with friends. The prices are good especially for the good quality of food. They have different events like comedy and others which I really like and the dj mixes are great. I like going to Fisheye because its like experiencing a Manhattan lounge/bar but without those expensive prices. I would definitely recommend Fisheye to friends and family ! February 18, 2009 Doesn&apos;t like it Really Dissapointed by Samiyr ( 1 review ) I used to pass this bar and grill on my way home from work, and decided to stop and see if the food was any good. I ordered my food to go and was amazed that i had to wait for over forty-five for two simple dishes. The person who took my order never gave me a update until I asked him if I can pay for my stuff so when it is done i can leave. The woman who took my payment told me that my order will be out in a couple of minutes . So i went back out to my car and waited another 10-15 minutes before I came back in, mind you there was no more then 10 people in the grill and they were all there before me so I doubt they were waiting for food, and they were at the bar drinking. After coming back in I waited another 5 minutes before my food came. When I got home and pulled everything out I was extremely disappointed, the jerk chicken was a couple of jerk winglets, and the sesame chicken was OK. I don&apos;t mind paying money for good food, but this was not worth the money paid. Overall I know... more» I used to pass this bar and grill on my way home from work, and decided to stop and see if the food was any good. I ordered my food to go and was amazed that i had to wait for over forty-five for two simple dishes. The person who took my order never gave me a update until I asked him if I can pay for my stuff so when it is done i can leave. The woman who took my payment told me that my order will be out in a couple of minutes . So i went back out to my car and waited another 10-15 minutes before I came back in, mind you there was no more then 10 people in the grill and they were all there before me so I doubt they were waiting for food, and they were at the bar drinking. After coming back in I waited another 5 minutes before my food came. When I got home and pulled everything out I was extremely disappointed, the jerk chicken was a couple of jerk winglets, and the sesame chicken was OK. I don&apos;t mind paying money for good food, but this was not worth the money paid. Overall I know for a fact that I will never recommenced this place the food was over priced, and the service poor. To add insult to injury I paid with CC and they decided to add a 5 dollar tip to my order, when i know I did not leave them a tip because the service was poor. Next time I will go to Sally&apos;s or FootPrints. Also the person who stated this place was like a grill/bar in Manhattan must impress easily. April 29, 2010 Wednesday Nite by Maxine ( 3 reviews ) I visited fish eye bar and grill on Wednesday nite with a few friends, I got a flyer stating they were having all you can eat crab legs and wings, to my surprise I went there I was only allowed to eat four legs its limited, my question, if you cannot afford do not advertise and the Disc Joc keep on saying all you can eat, its a shame. When I want crab legs, I will stay in Queens -- fisheye is not ready for such an event, and it was poorly attended what if they had more people, shame on you fisheye bar and grill +2 more review from Maxine January 11, 2010 DISASPPOINTED My visit to Fisheye Bar&amp;Grill on New Years Eve was a great disappointment, the woman at the door should not be in the public eye, she has no public appearance nor manner to deal with the clients, fisheye is a Bar and Grill not a night club, my friends left from NJ to visit with friends in new york and was really disturbed by the woman approach to us, we did sure left fisheye and went to a lovely spot around the corner called Footprints where we were greeted with respect and sure had... more» My visit to Fisheye Bar&amp;Grill on New Years Eve was a great disappointment, the woman at the door should not be in the public eye, she has no public appearance nor manner to deal with the clients, fisheye is a Bar and Grill not a night club, my friends left from NJ to visit with friends in new york and was really disturbed by the woman approach to us, we did sure left fisheye and went to a lovely spot around the corner called Footprints where we were greeted with respect and sure had a very pleasant night. Its fisheye loss we had only good intention to bring in the New Year in good taste, we were sure ready to pop bottles so we did that the great footprints ... we will be back there for sure. If you gonna have someone at the door, please use someone pleasant. January 11, 2010 The Building is beautiful but the greeter at the door should be put in a cage. October 29, 2009 Likes it the best garlic shrimp im bk by SWEETSEXYMICHELLE ( 3 reviews ) yes i&apos;m back to salute the chef @ fisheye. i usually order the garlic shrimp because i really enjoy it....shrimps are really big n tasty...crab cakes are great too...i find fisyeye&apos;s menu to be more than satisfactory. and you cant comment on fisheye with out shouting out dj chris....he&apos;s the best with his oldschool reggae....i dance my ass off when he plays....see 4 ya self..!!!! #1 in my book +1 more review from SWEETSEXYMICHELLE March 30, 2009 thank god for dj chris i found fish eye to be pretty pleasant place, nice enviorment, nd the food wasnt that bad...but the dj made my night...the comedy show was ok...again the dj made my nite, dj chris is the best at what he does...hell make u get out ur seat!!!!! try it u just may like it... i did!!!! September 5, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Jacqueline small ( 1 review ) I had my daughters graduation party at Fish Eye Bar&amp;Grill on Sunday September 4th right before Labor Day and owner Dave give the date I wanted without any problem. I used Fish Eye&apos;s food menu and that was great! Everything was on time and proffesstional. I recommend Fish bar and Grill to anyone for parties. September 3, 2011 Don&apos;t Go There, Please by michelle ( 1 review ) I was very, disappointed being that I heard such good things about Fisheye, however I could of went to the corner store and got better service, I was seated in the front by the speaker all night, we waited 2 hours for the food I ordered jerk chicken and yellow rice and got jerk bones and dry out rice after waiting for 2 1/2 hours the server never set the table she just dumped a bunch of forks and knives on the table and we were on our own. My guest ordered crab cakes and it took her 2 hours to get them and my mom ordered a drink and it took her 3 hours to get it when we inquired as to what was the hold up the young man stated that he gave us the drink and he did not know what we were talking about. Fisheye you need to train your staff better and get more mature servers to work with you this does not make any sense you need to stop this foolishness. The service sucks the food is overpriced and they need guidance badly. Instead of your place being called Fisheye it should of been called catch me if you can or make me wait. I would never go there again.!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 
 Show 7 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Rico Grinds Fisheye Bar&amp;... by Kysh Fisheye Bar&amp;... 
 All 3 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 E Z Foster Av Deli Canarsie - Sandwiches/Subs Dunkin&apos; Donuts $ Canarsie - Donuts, Breakfast/Brunch Subway $ Canarsie - Sandwiches/Subs, Fast Food, Soups Teena&apos;s Cake Fair 92% $$$ Canarsie - Bakery Sally&apos;s West Indian... 92% Canarsie - Caribbean 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 fisheye restaurant fisheye bar and grill fisheye lounge fisheye club fish eye restaurant 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
