<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004929" url="http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/sonic-drive-in-c33210.html" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="14" score="0.031400751535175075" bingtitle="Sonic Drive In Complaints, Reviews - Very unprofessional manager ..." webtitle="Sonic Drive In Complaints, Reviews - Very unprofessional manager behavior">
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000224" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000724" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>I walk up to the menu board (which had busted ... laryngitis working the drive through in a fast food restaurant ... It was a reeses peanut butter cup. I didnt ...</description>
	<body>
		The most trusted and popular consumer complaints website 
 
 Everything 
 Everything Complaints Articles News&amp;Stories Recalls Videos Groups Questions 
 Home News&amp;Stories Tips&amp;Tricks Questions Videos Photos Recalls Groups Submit Complaint Connect With: Login Register 
 
 
 
Recently Discussed Complaints
 1. (0 mins ago) 
 Pimsleur Approach 
Fraudulent Billing scam 2. (2 mins ago) 
 PSYCHIC CHIP COFFEY 
CYBER BULLY AND LIAR 3. (5 mins ago) 
 department of financial investigation 
fraud 4. (5 mins ago) 
 Sinister Soles 
Neglectful Customer Service 5. (13 mins ago) 
 iTalkBB 
Stay away from iTalkBB 


Consumer Tips&amp;Tricks
 
 
 
    How do Cable and Satellite Compare? 
 
 
 
    How To Cope When Creditors Crumple Your Credit Line 
 
 
 
    Credit/Debit Card Fraud Prevention Tips 
 

 
Latest News&amp;Stories
 
    French Total wins gas drilling tender 
 
    Deceptive Marketing For Prepaid Calling Cards Targeting Immigrants 
 
    Who&apos;s Paying For What? Washington Takes Aim at Secret Political Money 
 


Latest Questions
 sueing cr england not getting my welfare check from govement Neotel SA NO RESPONSE MY MISSING MOBILE PHONE E-MAIL my order 

 
 
 
Sonic Drive In Complaints&amp;Reviews - Very unprofessional manager behavior
 Review all Sonic Drive In complaints 
Sonic Drive In
 
 Posted: 2007-11-05 by Lisa Allen   [send email] 
 
 
 Very unprofessional manager behavior 
 Complaint Rating: Tweet I went to sonic the other day by my house and i go there often because my kids love their drinks. As i was ordering i look in and see one of the managers canoodling with one of the carhops. Well i happen to know that girl and she&apos;s only 17 and i know he&apos;s way above her age limit plus its very unprofessional and i can&apos;t believe that the general manager is allowing a 20 something manager who is supossed to set an example for the other employees mess around with another employee who is underage. Comments United States Fast Food Restaurants Share with others:          
 Was the above complaint useful to you?
	</body>
</document>
