<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004256" url="http://tipswatch.com/2011/06/15/provocative-post-is-it-time-to-short-tips/" time="2012-07-12-20:30" support="1" score="0.00012783521545597443" bingtitle="Provocative post: Is it time to short TIPS? | Treasury Inflation ..." webtitle="Provocative post: Is it time to short TIPS? | Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities">
			<query id="001435" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>... out that mutual funds investing in TIPS are riding near 5 ... on SeekingAlpha.com with a post titled, ‘Don’t count ... using your WordPress.com account. ( Log Out / Change )</description>
	<body>
		Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities TIPS: Perfect investment for imperfect times? News, ideas, alerts Skip to content 
 Home About This Blog Upcoming TIPS auctions Why TIPS? 
 ← U.S. inflation is heating up, right? Yield on 30-year TIPS? Ouch. → 
Provocative post: Is it time to short TIPS?
 Posted on June 15, 2011 by tipswatch 
Personally, I am not going there. I don’t short, that’s not my style, and I definitely don’t feel I could accurately predict the future trend of TIPS mutual funds and ETFs, although I don’t own any at the moment and have repeatedly pointed out that mutual funds investing in TIPS are riding near 5-year highs.

So along comes The Inflation Trader blog on SeekingAlpha.com with a post titled,‘Don’t count Bill Gross out just yet.’(Not that I would ever count Bill Gross out.…Come on.)

Inflation Trader, I will just call him IT, points out that bonds had a big selloff on Tuesday, and that also affected TIPS, by the way. Since I am following the 30-year TIPS to be auctioned next week, I was interested in this development Tuesday:

 That 30-year yield took a very nice leap upward on Tuesday, and anything getting it closer to 2% would make next week’s 30-year TIPS auction a lot more appealing. But the point is, Tuesday was not kind to Treasuries. (Wednesday was another matter, and I will write about that tomorrow.)

Back to IT, who writes:
 
Maybe bond guys just realize that if all of this bad news is in place, and not many folks are expecting a cheerful resolution from the Greek crisis, there are few reasons for Treasuries to rally further.… I also wonder if it is time to be short TIPS .
 
IT wrote this before Wednesday’s inflation numbers, which were a little worse than expected, so that counters (somewhat) the rest of his argument, which includes:
 
A small miss lower on CPI will not change the fact that the overall trend is upward, but it would serve to reduce the fear premium currently embedded in TIPS. A miss higher would keep that fear premium stable or even increase it a little bit, but that would probably be in the context of rapidly rising rates overall.
 
My point is that there is an anti-TIPS sentiment brewing, versus the overwhelming  pro-TIPS sentiment of the last several months. This is a lot more important for people who invest in TIPS mutual funds and ETFs. It is less important for people–like me–who invest in TIPS and hold them to maturity.

But what about that 30-year TIPS auction next week? Time to ponder.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. This entry was posted in Investing in TIPS . Bookmark the permalink . ← U.S. inflation is heating up, right? Yield on 30-year TIPS? Ouch. → 
One Response to Provocative post: Is it time to short TIPS? 

 Michael Ashton says: June 16, 2011 at 7:50 am 
TIPSwatch! I didn’t know about this blog. You are doing a great service to your readers. I need to add this to the IIIA website (Inflation-Indexed Investing Association).

Just a quick disclaimer–I have been saying for a very long time that TIPS to your investment horizon should be the risk-free security rather than T-Bills, since the latter have inflation risk. (And I have written academic papers about TIPS, including this one entitled“Maximizing Personal Surplus: Liability-Driven Investment for Individuals”at http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1699347 . I was also bullish on TIPS throughout the spring despite low yields, because the Fed was buying all net supply and there was evident end-user demand on top of that.

So to be clear, I’m no‘hater’(read my other comments to see this!). My comment on Tuesday is more about valuation. I think there will be a better time to buy TIPS, and once the 10y is above 1% or 1.25% and the 30y is above 2% or 2.25% I will be actively recommending them again.

IT
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Next up: 10-year TIPS new issue will auction July 19, 2012 More‘Operation Twist’? So far, no big deal for TIPS 30-year TIPS reissue auctions at record-low 0.520% Headline inflation turned to deflation in May Next TIPS auction: 30-year reissue on June 21, 2012 10-year TIPS reissue auctions at record low -0.391% Inflation in April 2012: Unchanged 
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 
 
Blogroll

 FAQs on TIPS Historical Auction Query Historical TIPS data How to buy TIPS S&amp;P TIPS index Tentative auction schedule The Inflation Trader TIPS in Depth TIPS/CPI Data Treasury Direct U.S. Inflation Calculator WSJ: Current TIPS values 
 
Categories

 I Bond Inflation International bonds Investing in TIPS Savings Bond 
 
 
 
TIpswatch.com on RSS

 RSS - Posts 
 
 Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities Theme: Twenty Ten Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“Treasury Inflation-Protected Securities” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
