<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004930" url="http://www.hydroponicsonline.com/store/VINTAGE--1950S--DOG--N--SUDS-DRIVE-INS-CAR--HOP--TRAY-_180786864368.html" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="1" score="0.009969006096331999" bingtitle="VINTAGE 1950&apos;S DOG N SUD&apos;S DRIVE-IN&apos;S CAR HOP TRAY for sale" webtitle="VINTAGE  1950&apos;S  DOG  N  SUD&apos;S DRIVE-IN&apos;S CAR  HOP  TRAY  for sale">
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>... is only for sale , NO FAKE DISPLAY FOOD COME WITH TRAY ... Vintage Taco Tico Mexican Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant Fire ... Make your own nutrient solution, Your experience ...</description>
	<body>
		Hydroponic Systems 

 Hydroponic Kits Ebb and Flow Aero Garden Hydrofarm Cloning Drip Systems General Aeroponic Deep Water Culture DWC 

 Hydroponic Grow Lights&amp;Bulbs 

 LED HPS HID Metal Halide Fluorescent CFL Conversion 

 Hydroponic Tents&amp;Grow Boxes 

 Hydroponic Ballasts 

 Grow Light Reflectors 

 Hydroponic Nutrients 

 Grow Media Rocks 

 Hydroponic Pumps 

 Hydroponic Pots 

 Hydroponic Books 

 Meters 

 Hygrometers pH Meters 

 Hydroponic Exhaust Fans 

 Hydroponic Seeds 

 Hydroponic Foggers 




 






 
 
 
 
 Home Store Blog Forums FAQs Lesson Plans Pictures 
 
 
 Search: 
 
 
VINTAGE 1950&apos;S DOG N SUD&apos;S DRIVE-IN&apos;S CAR HOP TRAY For Sale
 
 
 
 

This item has been shown 221 times.

 


VINTAGE 1950&apos;S DOG N SUD&apos;S DRIVE-IN&apos;S CAR HOP TRAY :
$45



 
peterson42760 store

This is Vintage Dog-n- suds Drive-In car hop tray and- ( authentic 1950&apos;s attendant return tray card ) This will make a neat accessory for a carwindow at a show, or just as a piece ofcollectible .This shows signs of use but it isstill in very nice condition. ( SEE THE PICTURE ) The tray and attendant card is only for sale , NO FAKE DISPLAY FOOD COME WITH TRAY, The tray come with original red-green rubber covered leg&apos;s hook&apos;s . Good luck Thank-you for offering

1. THIS IS A PAY-PAL sale ONLY!!!

SHIPMENT TO THE UNITED STATES ONLY( Due to restrictions in other countries, I will only ship to U.S.).


 
 
 
 
 Other Popular Hydroponic Items: 


 
Colonel Sanders KFC Kentucky Fried Chicken Autograph 

 
1970&apos;S ADVERTING KFC KENTUCKY FRIED CHICKEN TABLECLOTH 

 
GIANT SAFE T CUP ICE CREAM CONE LIGHTED DISPLAY DAIRY QUEEN SOFT SERVE DESERT 

 
NICE VINTAGE ALUMINUM TRACO CAR HOP DRIVE IN WINDOW TRAY VERY GOOD CONDITION
	</body>
</document>
