<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004134" url="http://vanguardnewsnetwork.com/letters/62404letters.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:22" support="1" score="0.0007197845848367293" bingtitle="Letters: 24 June 2004" webtitle="Letters: 24 June 2004">
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>... reports that Deborah Lipstadt wants to throw ... find a fence, bus shelter, park bench, trash bin or fast-food restaurant ... for some reason, you want to construct a container ...</description>
	<body>
		Reader Mail: 24 June 2004 
 
 
 


 

======================================

 Subject: hot on VNNF today... 

Has your daughter been murdered by a gang of niggers yet?

 http://www.vnnforum.com/showthread.php?t=6517 

Here lots of Brooks, Jones, Griffin and Linder over One Sheaf, One Vine :

 http://www.vnnforum.com/showthread.php?t=6518 

14 nigger-filled cities get special crime attention:

 http://www.vnnforum.com/showthread.php?p=76910#post76910 

======================================

 Subject: jew Wolfowitz 

Attack of the Wolfman

By MAUREEN DOWD

 http://www.nytimes.com/2004/06/24/opinion/24DOWD.html 

Published: NYT June 24, 2004

WASHINGTON

CUT//Tuesday, Mr. Wolfowitz, Rummy&apos;s top deputy, told the House Armed 
Services Committee that one reason so many negative stories come out of Iraq is that 
&quot;a lot of the press are afraid to travel very much, so they sit in Baghdad and 
they publish rumors and rumors are plentiful.&quot;

Beyond sliming journalists (much as he slimes his hair with his own saliva in 
Michael Moore&apos;s new movie) who are risking their lives traveling around Iraq 
to cover the cakewalk that became chaos, Mr. Wolfowitz dodges the 
responsibility he bears for turning Iraq into a shooting gallery and Al Qaeda recruitment center.

When challenged by Democratic lawmakers about the lack of a connection 
between Saddam and Sept. 11, Mr. Wolfowitz was unrepentant and unmoved by the 9/11 
panel&apos;s conclusion that Saddam and Al Qaeda had no collaborative relationship.

&quot;I don&apos;t need proof of involvement in Sept. 11 to be concerned that Saddam 
Hussein is providing mutual support to Al Qaeda,&quot; he said. &quot;It seems to me it&apos;s 
like saying if someone breeds Rottweilers and leaves the gate open but doesn&apos;t 
tell the dog who to attack, that he&apos;s not operationally involved in the 
thing.&quot; (What&apos;s he talking about, and why are we still paying him?)

Perhaps that&apos;s not the most felicitous metaphor, given the revelations that 
it was Donald Rumsfeld who O.K.&apos;d the use of vicious dogs by U.S. guards to 
threaten Iraqi prisoners.

The White House refuses to admit that, as far as U.S. security was concerned, 
Saddam was more bark than bite. As Hans Blix put it, Saddam had put up a 
&quot;Beware of Dog&quot; sign, so he didn&apos;t bother with the dog.

But instead of admitting he got the Saddam threat wrong, Mr. Wolfowitz 
lectured Americans not to be impatient. Referring to our foes, he said, &quot;The more 
they sense that we&apos;re impatient . . . the more car bombs there will be.&quot; He 
seems to imply that we&apos;re complicit in killing our soldiers if we don&apos;t sanguinely 
go along with the Bush administration&apos;s delusions.

&quot;The notion that this was `a war of choice,&apos; that we could sit there and live 
with the Middle East status quo after Sept. 11, I think is wrong,&quot; he said.

Once again, Mr. Wolfowitz conflates 9/11 and Iraq. Instead of finishing off 
Osama in Afghanistan, the neocons dragged us into an Iraq adventure, which has 
ended up destabilizing the Middle East. So much for the &quot;status quo.&quot; 

At least Colin Powell has the decency to be embarrassed about the State 
Department&apos;s preposterous initial understatement of terror incidents. 

Wolfie&apos;s never embarrassed, even as he continues to spin his version of the 
truth about why we went to Iraq, how we&apos;re doing there and when we&apos;ll be able 
to leave. The man is quite a talented propagandist Michael Moore without the 
laughs.

==========

ICHEE.org footnote:

Wolfowitz is one of the cabal - many of them former Trotskyites - critized by 
General Zinni (May 21, 2004)

&quot;Well, it starts with at the top. If you&apos;re the secretary of defense and 
you&apos;re responsible for that. If you&apos;re responsible for that planning and that 
execution on the ground. If you&apos;ve assumed responsibility for the other elements, 
non-military, non-security, political, economic, social and everything else, 
then you bear responsibility,&quot; says Zinni. &quot;Certainly those in your ranks that 
foisted this strategy on us that is flawed. Certainly they ought to be gone 
and replaced.&quot;

Zinni is talking about a group of policymakers within the administration 
known as &quot;the neo-conservatives&quot; who saw the invasion of Iraq as a way to 
stabilize American interests in the region and strengthen the position of Israel. They 
include Deputy Defense Secretary Paul Wolfowitz; Undersecretary of Defense 
Douglas Feith; Former Defense Policy Board member Richard Perle; National 
Security Council member Eliot Abrams; and Vice President Cheney&apos;s chief of staff, 
Lewis &quot;Scooter&quot; Libby.

Zinni believes they are political ideologues who have hijacked American 
policy in Iraq.

&quot;I think it&apos;s the worst kept secret in Washington. That everybody - everybody 
I talk to in Washington has known and fully knows what their agenda was and 
what they were trying to do,&quot; says Zinni.

&quot;And one article, because I mentioned the neo-conservatives who describe 
themselves as neo-conservatives, I was called anti-Semitic. I mean, you know, 
unbelievable that that&apos;s the kind of personal attacks that are run when you 
criticize a strategy and those who propose it. I certainly didn&apos;t criticize who they 
were. I certainly don&apos;t know what their ethnic religious backgrounds are. And 
I&apos;m not interested.&quot;

======================================

 Subject: shooting muzzy with bullets from izzy: bad idea 

 Here. 

Hey, at least we PAID FOR THAT AMMO.

Worse PR to let Israelis kill people with American stuff provided free of charge.

======================================

 Subject: &quot;Fahrenheit 9/11&quot; 

Moore&apos;s Magic: 9/11 Electrifies

by Rex Reed
rreed@observer.com

 http://www.observer.com/pages/onthetown.asp 

Michael Moore leaves no turn unstoned. There are multitudes of shattering, 
seminal moments in his brilliant Bush-whacking documentary, Fahrenheit 9/11, 
that reveal more about the cynicism, greed and ineptitude in the U.S. government 
than you will ever learn from any sound bite on the right-wing late-night 
cable-channel blabfests, but one will stay with me forever. Forget about the 
&quot;official&quot; reports from the White House about the activities of George W. Bush on 
the fateful morning of Sept. 11, insisting he learned about the Al Qaeda 
attacks while meeting with Florida pre-schoolers and quickly dashed from the room to 
save the country. The truth, it is now revealed, is that he was informed of 
the first attack on the World Trade Center before he even entered the 
schoolroom, and he decided to continue with his photo-op anyway. There he is on camera 
when Andrew Card informs him of the second plane and utters the fatal words, 
&quot;We&apos;re under attack!&quot;but he continues to read My Pet Goat for another seven 
minutes, his eyes sliding sideways in his puzzled face, like a moron looking 
for a bathroom, until his staff insists that he leave. (He stayed for another 
half hour.) If nothing else, that defining moment says volumes about what we can 
expect from the President of the U.S. in the center of a supreme, 
history-altering crisis: He&apos;s just clueless.

There are other moments that will impact some viewers and polarize others. So 
many, in fact, that you watch Fahrenheit 9/11 with disbelief, and leave 
shaking with rage. Sometimes sarcastic, always funny, Mr. Moore is armed with 
facts, and he presents them accurately and succinctly. The controversial filmmaker 
stated on the Today show that White House mouthpieces have denounced the film 
as &quot;outrageously false&quot; without seeing it, and right-wing Republicans have 
charged Mr. Moore with staging a &quot;left-wing conspiracy&quot; to influence the 
forthcoming election. Well, duh. For years, reactionary conservatives have been famous 
for staging right-wing conspiracies of their own to disgrace and discredit 
elected Democratic public officials. Maybe this is payback time. Whatever it is, 
everyone should see Fahrenheit 9/11 firstbefore debating the issues. The 
purpose of any documentary is to influence opinion. But instead of the 
customarily droning voice that comments on the action and tells you what to think, this 
one asks tough, logical questions, gets rational answers, and never loses its 
entertainment value.

======================================

 Subject: loans 

Interesting...

 http://www.biblebelievers.org.au/usury.htm#Money! 

The following are extracts from Rev. Charles E. Coughlin&apos;s famous book Money! Questions and Answers. The title is self-explanatory as to the easy-to-read format of this wonderful book. The book is available from N.D.I.N.S, GPO Box 3126FF, Melbourne, 3001 for A$16 plus A$2 postage and handling.

When an individual borrows money from a bank, does the banker lend him money that other private individuals have brought to the bank?

No. That is what the bankers would like to have you believe, but it is not true.

How do banks create money out of nothing by mere book-keeping entries?

By the following manufacturing process:

John Jones, a business man, needs $10,000. He goes to the bank and explains the nature of the busi ness he proposes to conduct. He takes to the bank certified figures indicating the value of his business, factory, farm, home, etc. If the banker is satisfied with the amount of real wealth to be pledged, he gives John Jones a note to sign. This note is a mortgage upon the wealth John Jones owns, and gives the banker legal power to confiscate the wealth, if John Jones does not pay at a specified time the number of dollars he is borrowing. The banker then manufactures the money on his ledgers.

How does he do this?

When the banker accepts John Jones&apos; note, on the asset side of the ledger he writes: Assets Liabilities Loans and Discounts...............$10,000 On the liability side he writes: Deposits.......................................10,000

At that instant, there is $10,000 more money in existence and available for use than before the banker made these entries.

What does John Jones do with this bookkeeping money?

He goes back to his factory with a bank book, not with actual currency, showing a deposit to his account of $10,000.

What is the exact nature of the item on bank balance sheets called &quot;Deposits&quot;? 
The &quot;Deposits&quot; are actually and legally nothing but liabilities of the bank. They are the money the bank owes, not what it has. A bank deposit is actually a bank&apos;s promise, nothing more.

What can John Jones do with this newly created deposit?

He can and does write cheques against this deposit to pay labourers, buy raw materials, and pay general overhead, incident to carrying on the manufacture and distribution of wealth.

How is this possible?

Other banks are doing the same thing at the same time. A bank against which cheques are drawn receives the proceeds of similarly manufactured deposits in other banks. Each bank receives cheques drawn on other banks which offset those drawn against it. They all have to work together. If there were only one bank the fraud would be soon discovered.

Is this process honest where John Jones pledges real wealth to secure the banker&apos;s fictitious bookkeeping money?

No, because it enables the banker to lend purchasing power (money) which costs him nothing but the general overhead of running a bank, and forces John Jones...to pay interest for the existence of bankers&apos; bookkeeping money, with which 95% of...business is transacted.

When the banker manufactured $10,000 and loaned it to John Jones, who began to write cheques, exchanging that bookkeeping money for wealth and services, what happened to the price levels?

They were increased, because there was $10,000 more money in existence than there was prior to John Jones&apos; loan. This new money came into existence, however, without a corresponding increase in the volume of goods and services, thus decreasing the unit value of money already outstanding. The value of outstanding money went down, which meant that the price level went up, i.e., the same amount of goods would then command more money. This principle is well recognised by all economists.

For example, if there are only $10,000 in existence in the egg market and only 10,000 eggs to be had we will say that each egg is worth $1.00. Now supposing that there are $20,000 in existence in the egg market and still only 10,000 eggs to be had. Each egg becomes worth $2.00. It is the old law of supply and demand. The double amount of money represents the demand. But the same quantity of eggs represents the supply. The egg merchants desirous of getting as much as they possibly can per egg will exhaust the supply of egg money.

When John Jones, the business man, is forced to pay his loan at the bank, what happens to the volume of money in the nation?

It is reduced by the number of dollars that John Jones pays.

What happens when a large number of business men are forced to pay their loans?

A large volume of the necessary medium of exchange is extinguished, i.e., cancelled out of existence.

What is a genuine loan?

In making a genuine loan the lender advances real money which represents a transfer of real purchasing power. Thus, if &quot;A&quot; earns $1000 working at the production and distribution of wealth, he may exchange that $1000 for wealth, or he may abstain from using or possessing wealth and lend his $1000 to another. If he lends his $1000 so acquired, he is a party to the making of a genuine loan.

Why are bankers as a rule opposed to the existence of genuine money and prefer the existence of so-called credit money?

If bankers are compelled to lend genuine money they are merely acting as agents for some real depositors and thereby are profiting only insofar as they are handling genuine money to the extent of the total amount of genuine money deposited with them. If bankers are privileged to lend credit money it means that they are not lending, as a rule, depositor&apos;s genuine money but are lending ten or fifteen or twenty times the amount of genuine deposits. They create credit money or fictitious money by a flourish of the fountain pen. Thus instead of lending only actually, for example, a million dollars of total deposits at 3% with the return of $30,000 profit the bankers are lending under the credit money racket, for example $20 million, $19 million of which is fiction. In this latter case their profit would be approximately $600,000. 
Therefore, bankers are opposed to honest money and to honest lending because of the difference of profits which in the case above would amount to approximately $570,000.

But why should citizens be opposed to bankers making this extra profit? 
Because this extra $570,000 must be taken out of the sweat of the labourer. It is a social injustice which permits privileged classes to reap where they did not sow.

Do fundamental, Christian, moral, ethical and philosophical principles harmonise with private ownership of property employed in or available for use in producing wealth?

Yes. Private ownership of honestly acquired property, employed in production is in full harmony with Christian principles.

Is capitalism, as we find it in operation today, in perfect harmony with Christian, moral, ethical and philosophical principles?

Emphatically, no. Masquerading under the title of capitalism, modern capitalism is notorious for the following errors which are contrary to human nature and to good government.

1. Modern capitalism borrows money at interest for non-productive and destructive purposes.

2. Modern capitalism, while professing in the belief in private ownership, concentrates the wealth in the hands of a few and deprives the mass of private individuals from owning the tools of production.

3. Modern capitalism professes to believe in the private coinage and regulation of money...

Does social justice imply that its followers adhere to the doctrine of modern capitalism?

No. In the four above mentioned errors of modern capitalism, social justice is opposed to this economic system.

Did Karl Marx ever attack private money creation privileges and international bankers?

No, his whole system proposed not the abolition of illicit private money creation and destruction powers, but its consolidation under a system of complete economic, political and religious domination of the entire world by a few internationalists.

Do all people have equal opportunity under our present money system? No, they do not.

&quot;They say to us that we all have an equal opportunity, and that it is our fault that we do not become rich. They seek, however, in every way possible, to prevent us from taking the only opportunity we have to all become successful for they know that if we did, it would end their exploits.&quot; (From &quot;Why is Your Country at War&quot; by Charles A. Lindbergh, Sr. in a speech urging the passage of a bill to provide a honest money system.)

Why is it that the modern newspaper (free press) upholds modern capitalists?

Because the modern newspaper, in many instances, is owned or controlled by the banker or the banker dominated advertiser who insists that the editorial matter in a modern newspaper does not militate against the interests of the modern capitalist.

Is usury opposed to morality?

Yes, and it is also opposed to Christian teaching.

======================================

 Subject: what is AmeriKwa? 

Dear Pit,

This is all taking place in a little town at the northern part of route
1,
Georgetown, Illinois. It&apos;s a town about 15 minutes south of Danville.
I&apos;ll
try my best to list here in order the things that have happened just this
year.

- A few months ago, there were 4 black men trapped a white couple in
their
car,
after beating them with cut down broom handles, a friend of ours heard
the
noise and ran outside&amp;called the police. The local police showed up and
let the men go, sent the couple away, they left with the poles still in
their hands and the couple bruised up and car dented.

- Blacks are seen walking the neighborhood side streets, urinating in the
middle of the streets, two times known to me, but probably more I would
imagine?

- Two houses have burned to the ground because of meth labs within a
block
of eachother, one was an abandoned house, the other had blacks living in
it.

- Most of the houses in Georgetown are for sale or vacated, as well as in
Chrisman and Ridge Farm, the two small towns right next to Georgetown.
People are leaving.

- My boyfriend, a paraplegic of 25 years has been cussed and flipped off
by
young black kids walking past his home while he is doing yard work. He
has
neighbors who have been cussed or threatened by blacks that pass by if
any
whites are outside. (I know this shows definate racial marks but it is
exactly the way things are right now)

- About a month or less ago a 13 year old boy was with another boy the
same
age walking home. Along the way a group of men got the boys into their
house, and the 13 year old was raped, forced to give &quot;bj&apos;s&quot;. They put the
boys into the bathroom, where they escaped thru the bathroom window as
soon
as they had a chance. The 13 yr old doesnt talk much anymore, where
before
he has been known to help people and was also a helper at the local
grocer.
The black man who did it has aids and the boy is now having to take
medication for treatments that are costing well over $700.00 a month.
The man was arrested the day it happened, but the other men that were
there
were never approached. One black man that was with them all had just been
released from prison for child molestation. The parents were absolutely
besides themselves.

- This past monday two very large black men came to the boy&apos;s family
(their
house), arriving in a rented black cadillac and claiming to be relatives
of
the one who commited the rape. They told the parents that they would be
back
soon to take their family and burn their house. The family called the
police, they refused to do anything.

- Tuesday the boy went with his cousin to the park, and three black older
teens (also related somehow to the rapist) jumped the boy and beat him
while
the police watched.

- The police have told the boy&apos;s mother that if she is found on one end
of
town she will be pulled over and arrested.

This all sounds so insane, but it is really happening. The hearing to
decide
the charges and trial stuff are being held this afternoon, the town
streets
are empty at night and quiet and the police are NOT patrolling at all.
The
father has not been able to find a lawyer willing to take their case. The
rapist has returned to Georgetown on bail (same day the men showed up to
threaten the family)

What do you suggest? If you would like to contact me on msn messenger,
you
can add me on xphnxfiresx@peoplepc.com . Any thing helpful we will be
most
grateful for.

Thank you for your time,
Holly

Holly,

I do believe all this is happening as its happening all over our country
and world. The sad thing is from what you have said that it sounds like
the &apos;groids have pretty well taken over the town with there drug dealing
and various other crimes. Like you have said the cops will do nothing,
it&apos;s
because they are either afraid or on the gangs payroll. To be honest the
best thing you all can do is move yourselves away from there. If all the
people would have stood together and kept this type of criminals from
taking over none of this would have probley ever happened to the boy
Seems everyday that people see the truth only after a tragedy takes
place. Many places it is too late that is why we try to get people to see
the truth about the lies of races being equal. All I can say is it&apos;s your
right to protect yourself and your property so always be prepared.

Pit
33/6 IL

======================================

 Subject: jews not growing like weeds 

 Here. 

Jewish people near zero growth

June 24, 2004

By TOVAH LAZAROFF

The Jewish population is approaching zero growth, warned a new study on the global state of Jews which will be presented to the cabinet this Sunday by the Jewish People Policy Institute (JPPI).

According to the study, &quot;the survival of the Jewish people is not assured, though there are great opportunities for a thriving future.&quot; 
 
Among the dangers listed in the report, entitled &quot;The Jewish People 2004: Between Thinking and Decline,&quot; are assimilation, anti-Semitism, and the proliferation of weapons of mass killing in the hands of anti-Jewish and anti-Israeli elements.

To understand anti-Semitism one has to look at the connection people are making between the Middle East conflict, terrorism, and Jews, said demographer Sergio DellaPergola, a senior researcher for the institute. 
 
The study warned that the global campaign to undermine the legitimacy of Israel was alienating left-liberal Jews from Israel: &quot;This could weaken links between Israel and Diaspora Jews. The new anti-Semitism demoralizes Diaspora Jews, while the continuation of terrorist attacks may have similar effects in Israel.&quot;

The comprehensive study showed that Jews are well off physically. Some 92 percent of the Jewish population lives in countries that are in the top 20 percentiles of standards of living. While this allows them many advantages, it also increases the likelihood that they will assimilate into those countries and lose their Jewish identity, the study said. 
 
The challenge for world Jewry, according to the JPPI, is &quot;how to maximize the benefits of external influences and participation in the global context, while minimizing the erosion of Jewish identity and commitment.&quot;

The problem is particularly acute in America, where the community &quot;is experiencing an alarming erosion of communal identity, with much of its population doubting the need to maintain its distinctiveness.&quot; 
 
The study&apos;s statistics show that in 1970 the number of American Jews stood at 5,686,000, while in 2003 there was a slight drop to 5,671,000. In 2020, according to the study, it is expected that the US Jewish population will have dropped to 5,581,000.

In Canada, though, Jews have maintained their Jewish identity while participating in an open Western society. Their population has grown from 286,000 to 371,000. In 2020 the number will rise to 381,000. 
 
But overall, the JPPI said, the future for Jewish growth looks bleak: &quot;Trends clearly move in the direction of decline.&quot; 
 
&quot;Jewish population growth approached zero, at 13 million people in 2004. Between 1970 and 2003 the world&apos;s total population grew by nearly 2.5 billion, an increase of over 70 percent. In contrast, the total Jewish population increased by only 250,000, or 2 percent,&quot; said the study.

The JPPI said it is worried about the demographic future of Jews in Israel as well, even though the population has grown from 2,582,000 in 1970 to 5,094,000 in 2003, and is expected to reach 6,228,000 in 2020. 
 
Equally worrying is the significant threat to the Jewish character of Israel because of demographic, social and ideological trends, said the study. 
On the positive side it noted that committed Diaspora Jews are better educated than ever and that more Jewish parents are choosing to send their children to Jewish day schools.

The JPPI also asked Israel to look at the implications on world Jewry of its decisions with respect to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict: &quot;Innovative measures are required to ensured the involvement of the Jewish people in this critical decision-making process while maintaining Israel&apos;s right to make its own decisions.&quot; 
 
The institute, chaired by former Middle East envoy Dennis Ross, hopes this is the first in a series of annual reports in which it will update the Israeli government on the state of Jews in Israel and around the world.

======================================

 Subject: Sobran/ NR 

Vital item about Sobran/NR here:

 Here. 

======================================

 Subject: latest on hoaxer Dunn 

Judge sets trial date for Professor Dunn

DA expects trial to last three days

By ROD LEVEQUE, STAFF WRITER

POMONA - A Claremont McKenna psychology professor entered a plea of not guilty 
Tuesday and a judge set a July 19 trial date on charges she vandalized her own 
car and falsely reported it as a hate crime. Prosecutors allege Kerri Dunn 
slashed her own tires, spray painted racial and religious epithets on her car 
and then lied when she reported the vandalism occurred at the Claremont 
Colleges while she spoke at a March 9 free speech rally.

The Redlands woman, charged with two counts of felony insurance fraud and one 
misdemeanor count of filing a false police report, faces more than four years 
in state prison if convicted. Dunn, 39, appeared in Pomona Superior Court for 
an arraignment hearing Tuesday morning.

Dunn&apos;s attorney, Jennifer Coon, asked Judge Jack Hunt to delay the trial until 
September, saying her co-counsel, attorney Gary S. Lincenberg, would be 
unavailable until then because of other cases and vacation. Hunt balked and 
insisted he would not allow the case to drag on that long. California law 
requires judges to set trial dates in felony cases within 60 days from 
arraignment in Superior Court unless they find good cause for a delay.

&quot;If he can&apos;t try it within the statutory time frame then (Dunn) needs to get 
another lawyer,&quot; the judge said. Coon on Tuesday also said she plans to file a 
motion prior to trial challenging the two insurance fraud counts against Dunn 
and asking a judge to dismiss them. The charges, both felonies, are the most 
serious allegations Dunn faces.

Dunn called her insurance company March 10, reported the damage to her car and 
asked if repairs would be covered under the terms of her policy. During a 
preliminary hearing last week, prosecutors said Dunn&apos;s conversations with the 
insurance company amounted to filing a false insurance claim.

Dunn&apos;s attorneys, however, say Dunn never demanded coverage or payment, and 
that her conversations with her insurer were nothing more than innocent 
inquiries. Los Angeles County Deputy District Attorney Martin Bean said he 
expected Dunn&apos;s trial to last about three days.

Rod Leveque can be reached by e-mail r_leveque@dailybulletin.com or by phone at 
(909) 483-9325.

======================================

 Subject: &apos;groidblog on Truman State, Brown and race-and-education in Missouri in general 

 http://www.byroncrawford.com/2004/05/brown_v_board_o.html 

WARNING: IT&apos;S A LONG (AND WINDING) POST. BUT READ IT ANYWAY. IT&apos;S NOT LIKE YOU&apos;VE GOT SHIT ELSE BETTER TO DO.

Greetings, bitches. With Making the Band II off the air now, as you can see, I&apos;m a bit hard up for shit to write about. I skimmed an article in this (last?) week&apos;s Newsweek about this Brown v. Board of Education mess and thought it might be interesting to write a little bit about all of the various race issues that are going on in public schools these days. I actually have a rather interesting (not really) background when it comes to the racial makeups of the schools I&quot;ve attended. You didn&apos;t think I learned how to write shit like this in Kirksville, did you? Shame on you. You fucking racists!

Let&apos;s start from the end (a week ago today, actually) and work our way backwards.

I went to this little dumbass school out in the middle of nowhere called Truman State University. It&apos;s basically where kids go in the State of Misery when they&apos;re kinda smart, but not smart enough to go anywhere worthwhile. It only costs somewhat more than it costs to go to community college and a good majority of the students are on fake, indentured servitude-style scholarships (the number of students on real, according-to-Hoyle scholarships like they have at other schools is something scandalous like 2, or something) and those are pretty much the upsides. The downsides are too lengthy to get into here.

Anyhoo, this school is fucking white. I went to a high school that was about 85% white, and when I got there, I was like, &quot;Whoa, this shit is white.&quot; And that&apos;s the thing, this school is white enough that your average white guy from the suburbs of St. Louis would stick out, let alone a black man such as myself. The whole scene is right out of a John Cougar Mellencamp video, only advanced 20 years so that the Tasty Freeze is all boarded up and the townies are on meth, or at least have really bad dental work.

Supposedly the school is 3% black, but I did the math and that would mean that there are something 180 black kids there, which is obviously (to me at least, you&apos;ve never been there) not true. The explanation: I&apos;m pretty sure they&apos;re counting in all of these random ass African kids they&apos;ve got walking around there as black too, which is I guess kinda true, but also very disingenous. In fact, I wouldn&apos;t be surprised if they brought those kids there for that sole purpose. They do have methods of bringing in negroes, you know, domestically, but they never net more than a few each year.

As far as the actual numbers are concerned, based on the fact that there were about 4 black guys who graduated with me, I&apos;ll be generous and guess that there are about 10 per grade and maybe about twice as many black chicks. And then, you know, enough smelly Jehova&apos;$ Witne$$e$ to equal 180. Fortunately, I guess being mostly smart kids and not being in the South or anything (although the town&apos;s not without its issues), the school didn&apos;t have any HUGE racial issues other than the ones that come naturally from having only a few random, mostly 85er black kids mixed in with so many of these teenage Billy Graham types.

But enough about that shithole. Before that, I went to Parkway North here in St. Louis--the suburban West County part though, not the part that was featured in National Lampoon&apos;s Vacation (that scene in the film was more documentary than anything else). Like I said before, it was mostly white, but not in the same way that the college I went to was white. In general, you could say it was a lot more urbane and, um, of this century. Not that it was necessarily the most pleasant place to be (picture about 1300 Fitzes and D-COYs running around), but I could deal with it.

North was one of those schools that had black kids (called &quot;VST kids&quot;) imported fresh daily from the ghetto to, I guess make it more diverse. Or maybe it was so that those ghetto kids could get a decent education. Like I said, I didn&apos;t do a whole lot of research before I wrote this other than to skim an article. Anyhoo, basically, the deal with these kids was that they were either the world&apos;s most incredible athletes, or the world&apos;s most ridonkulous jackasses. In most cases both, but in some cases, only one or the other. The guys, I mean. The girls, I&apos;m not sure. I think they just kinda hung out in one hallway and listened to Keith Sweat or something. Nobody really knew what was going on with them.

And then there were a handful of random black kids who actually lived in the district, of which I guess you could say I was one. I kinda hesitate to even include myself in this group just because while technically I&apos;m one of them, I&apos;m definitely not one of them. Ever notice that pretty much everybody I know are these entirely oblivious, hardcore Republican types? That&apos;s no coincidence. That&apos;s how people from around here are. I, on the other hand, am not actually from around here.

Before I went to Typical Suburbanite High School and the Midwest Branch of Regent University (and 3 different middle schools, interestingly enough), I went to what was probably one of the only all black (and by all black, I mean not a cracka in sight) elementary schools in the area. Definitely one of the very few, if not the only such school, in the County. The scene back in those days was very Lean on Me (the movie, not the song, dipshit), even for an elementary school. Crack was all over the place. Kids weren&apos;t actually smoking it (yet), but the shit was all over the place.

Being from the ages of 4 to 11 at the time, of course I don&apos;t have any idea how in the fuck the school got like that in the first place. It was in U City (where most famous rappers these days come from), which, at the time (the mid to late &apos;80s) was probably about split evenly between white and black, but it was on the far black end of town. I remember on two separate occasions there were white kids who went there for a little bit. Let&apos;s just say neither of those situations ended well. If there was any white folk at that end of town (and there might not have been any), I guess they just found something else to do with their kids.

You would think that having attended schools at each end of the racial and socioeconomic spectrum (at least as far as the State of Misery is concerned), I would have a certain sense of perspective on a lot of these issues that schools today are facing, but I don&apos;t really.

For example, there&apos;s the issue with black kids being complete and total fucking idiots. It was true when I was coming up too, but I have no idea why this is so. Having taught myself to read at the age of 2, I really wasn&apos;t trying to listen to those retards take 8 minutes at a time to sound out a sentence and so, being the jackass that I am, I would make fun of them. A lot. I fought constantly. In Kindergarten, I was about the size of the actual teacher, and then I got bigger and bigger and bigger. I remember a couple of occasions where I beat up two kids at once. Of course, I got gradually worse and worse at fighting as I got older (not unlike Joe Pesci in Casino) and, while everybody else got that much more coordinated, I became, you know, a guy who sits behind a computer all day. I&apos;ve still got the size advantage though.

As far as what it&apos;s going to take to get black and hispanic kids on the same level as everybody else, I really have no idea, but I&apos;m going to go out on a limb and guess that training kids as if they were monkeys to pass standardized tests isn&apos;t going to help matters any. Granted, I could be wrong. I&apos;m sure Fitz or somebody will disagree. But probably the bigger issue, as far as I&apos;m concerned, is why are we even bullshitting ourselves about education to begin with. If we could go back to the times where dumb people could still get jobs that paid enough to pay the rent and have some left over to, you know, eat, then all of this education bullshit wouldn&apos;t be an issue one way or the other. Most so-called educated people in this country aren&apos;t that smart anyway, they just &quot;went to college.&quot; This way, they could stay home and free up resources (and tang) for actual smart kids.

Then, I guess, the other main issue (according to the shit I&apos;ve been reading) has to do with the racial makeup of the schools. Most schools today, even 50 years after the big Brown v. Board of Education whatever-it-was, are either mostly black or mostly white. Even the ones that are more racially diverse are kinda split within themselves with black, white and hispanic kids having their own separate school functions and what have you. The cause of all of this is, to me, kinda obvious and not worth getting into, but the issue that interests me is whether or not this is a big deal one way or the other. According to the article I skimmed (and left out in the car), there&apos;s a wide variety of opinions on this matter. Some people think that it&apos;s important and some people don&apos;t. I&apos;m going to go ahead and take the controversial opinion that it sorta is and sorta isn&apos;t.

Let&apos;s face it, if you&apos;re white, especially if you live out in the flyover zone, but probably in the suburbs of big cities too, you could probably live your entire life without having to deal with black people one way or the other. I didn&apos;t really realize it as much until I had to live out in the middle of nowhere for 5 years, but it&apos;s true and I&apos;m sure it happens all the time. In that case, who cares how many black kids there were at your high school? On the other hand, if you&apos;re black, then of course that&apos;s just plain not a possibility. Even if you&apos;re living in the blackest parts of the blackest cities in America, you&apos;ll probably still end up buying rent-to-own furniture from a Jewish guy or some shit. But chances are you&apos;re going to have to deal with white people day in and day out and in that case, it probably would help to be more accustomed to dealing with people outside of your own race.

I could go on, but I&apos;m getting tired and hungry. Having only been born in the 1980s, I don&apos;t really have that much of a perspective on the history of the public school sytem or even the country in general for that matter (but I got a degree, beeyotch!). I think that there&apos;s this tendency to want to believe that things today are automatically that much better than they were 50 years ago, but the more I read (er, skim) about shit like this, the more that I realize that shit doesn&apos;t just get better just because time goes by. I don&apos;t know what went wrong for the first 50 years of Brown v. Board of Education, but they had better get somebody in there to figure that shit out soon because, let&apos;s face it, not every child is lucky enough to have been reading the Wall Street Journal (except for the ridonkulous op-ed page, of course) since the age of 3.

======================================

 Subject: AmeriKwa 

Too many rules, regulations and conventions, both legal and social. Bars closing at 1AM. Cops throwing you out of parks (parks !) at 8:01PM. Having to be careful of which jokes you say to whom. Not complimenting a women on her appearance, so that I&apos;m not accused of harassment in the workplace. Restraining myself from honking at assholes on the road, for fear that they&apos;ll pull a gun on me. Those charming &quot;America: love it or leave it&quot; bumper stickers (talk about freedom of expression!). Not even dreaming of possibly buying E or pot from a stranger. Having to pee in a cup in order to get a job. Being unable to rent a porn flick in a video store. Being repeatedly told that my girlfriend and I should get married (actually she gets that a lot more than I do). Not being able to buy a beer in store after 8PM, or on sunday. Little things - that add up. Admittedly, I come from the most liberal city of a fairly liberal country - and I moved to Connecticut. So I guess I asked for it...

======================================

 Subject: Philadelphia full of niggers too 

Philadelphia has a very large black population and crime to attest to it. There are parts of Philadelphia I wouldn&apos;t even drive through during the day, never mind at night. The city has beautiful old houses which used to house white middle and working class people. Now they are in the worst disrepair, and guess who lives in them?

======================================

 Subject: Muslims see Mary, or whatever Muslims hallucinate 

Muslims Flock to See Messiah After Web Hoax

BERLIN (Reuters) - Hundreds of Muslims flocked to a German hospital where an 
Internet site said the Messiah was being breast-fed by its resurrected mother, 
a hospital spokesman said Thursday. Spokesman Burkhard Buescher said large 
groups of women with children were among those who had traveled across Germany 
and from the nearby Netherlands in the last two weeks asking porters at the 
Essen university clinic to let them visit the &quot;Messiah.&quot; &quot;The story ended up 
being that there was a woman in the clinic who had given birth to the Messiah 
and who had died. She was later dug up and was still alive but her whole body 
was burned -- just her two breasts were unharmed,&quot; said Buescher.

&quot;Allah ordered the woman to feed the child for 40 days and then die again. This 
crazy story was seen by people on a Turkish Internet site,&quot; he said. On the 
Internet portal Turkdunya.de, chatterers discussed the story and one 
contributor claimed to have seen the woman. Hospital guards had told visitors 
there was no such woman in the maternity clinic, and the number of visitors had 
dwindled since German media reported the story was an Internet hoax, Buescher 
said. &quot;But some people just wanted to believe it.&quot;

======================================

 Subject: Mueller letter 

Dear Fellow Patriot!

Yesterday I forwarded you a very poor translation of
the Raspail interview: &quot;The Fatherland Betrayed by The
Republic.&quot; Thanks to Dr. Fredrick Toben and Peter
Wakefield-Sault we have a much better translation, and
here it is:

[START]

The Fatherland Betrayed by The Republic

Following the articles by Helene Carrère d&apos;Encausse,
Alexandre Adler, Michel Wieviorka, Alain-Gerard Slama,
Max Gallo and the conversations with Rene Girard,
Claude B&lt;h
	</body>
</document>
