<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004523" url="http://www.hotfrog.co.uk/Products/Takeaway-Restaurant" time="2012-07-12-20:56" support="2" score="0.003545450741932543" bingtitle="Takeaway Restaurant - Hotfrog - your UK business directory" webtitle="Takeaway Restaurant">
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... email, and we with manipulate the image to put ... Credit Card or Cash on Delivery. Discounts on all food ... chinese restaurant Fast Food Restaurant Chinese Food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Login 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Takeaway Restaurant
 1 - 40 of 804 businesses results Sponsored links Pizza Hut Special 5 Offer 
 www.pizzahut.co.uk/Special_5_Pizzas 5 Special pizzas. 5 days a week. Only £5 each. Offer ends Friday! 
 Crown Crust   Kids Eat Free £5 Special Five   New Menu 
 Order Takeaway Online 
 www.just-eat.co.uk/Takeaways 12000+ Takeaways. 100% Safe Orders! Order Takeaway Online in UK 
 Get Chinese Delivery - Now   Get Indian Delivery - Now Get Pizza Delivery - Now   Get Thai Delivery - Now 
 Take-a-way 
Goole, North Humberside
 Email 
Take-a-way.co.uk is a free site listing images of takeaway menus, it is growing in popularity with customers and businesses alike. Fully searchable b…
 
Latest updates
 144,000 page views in 4 weeks to 3… - 04/01/2012
 of these are unique, several time we passed 6,000 visitors per day.
We m… Read more: A Thouseand new visitors per day - 03/03/2011
 sitors per day.
Our hit count continues to rise in an ever steepening cur… Read more: 
 More info 
 Fill My Belly 
Nottingham, Nottinghamshire
 Email 
Order your takeaway online through fillmybelly.com, pay online and have delicious takeaway food delivered direct to your door. We have a fantastic se…
 
Latest updates
 Takeaway Nottingham - 20/05/2011
 At Fillmybelly.com order your takeaway and fast food online for delivery f… Read more: Takeaway Aberdeen - 20/05/2011
 fillmybelly.com is an award winning, fast easy and fun way for you to
 or… Read more: 
 More info 
 Millan Tandoori 
Shoreham by Sea, West Sussex
 Email Phone 
We are Millan Tandoori, one of the leading Indian restaurants and tandoori restaurants in Brighton, Worthing and West Sussex. We offer an unrivalled …
 
Latest updates
 Buy one get one meal free! - 06/06/2012
 Buy one main dish and get one FREE Read more: order online - 09/01/2011
 just visit us at Read more: 
 More info 
 
Related information
 Takeaway Nottingham 
Fill My Belly - 20/05/2011
 At Fillmybelly.com order your takeaway and fast food online for delivery from takeaways and restaurants in Nottingham. fillmybelly.com is an award winning, fast easy and fun way for you to 
order your takeaway online. Nottingham is a great place to live if you 
order takeaway food online. For almost four years we have been 
providing you an easy way to order food and drink in Nottingham. Online takeaway menus includes Indian, Chinese, Pizza, Italian, Mexican and Thai. A free web presence for takeaway restaurants 
Take-a-way - 03/02/2011
 Every takeaway can have its menu displayed online for free.
No website required.
Just send us a copy of your menu Order takeaway online for home delivery 
EatEasy Ltd - 03/02/2011
 Order takeaways from local restaurants for home delivery. Select from a wide range of menus on the www.eateasy.co.uk website. It is free to order, delivery is often free depending upon the restaurant, membership is free and we give discounts to all new members Advertising a Takeaway 
Takeaway Deliveries - 19/01/2011
 Adding your takeaway to our listing Takeaway menus online - No Charge 
Take-a-way - 03/11/2010
 scan them and manipulate the image
to show the pages in the correct order.

Alternatively menus can be emailed to us, ideally as a high quality image of no more
than 8 megabytes per email, and we with manipulate the image to put the pages in order.

If you have no leaflet type image then perhaps you could create one using &apos;Word&quot; or 
something similar and again we will put them on our site.
This would enable one to try it out before investing in a fully embellished menu.

The only imag… Free Delivery Service 
New Sun Rise - 28/10/2010
 Our takeaway specialises in Cantonese and Thai Cuisine Situated on
 Church Street near Seaford Train Station. We offer you a good variety 
of quality food which are always freshly prepare. We offer Free Delivery Service for order over £15 within 3 Miles Thai restaurant in Basingstoke 
The Lime Leaf Thai Restaurant - 04/05/2010
 m. High chairs and baby changing facilities are available. At lunchtime you can choose from our Business Lunch menu. And on those occasions when you fancy a quick bite to eat our Express Menu has a tasty selection of noodles, wraps and pittas. Disabled Access - The Lime Leaf restaurant offers ground floor accessibility to wheelchair users. Children Welcomed - We offer children&apos;s portions, high chairs and nappy changing facilities. The Lime Leaf does not impose a service charge. Tips are shared …   The Lime Leaf Thai Restaurant 
Basingstoke, Hampshire
 Phone 
…to eat our Express Menu has a tasty selection of noodles, wraps and pittas. Disabled Access - The Lime Leaf restaurant offers ground floor accessibility to wheelchair users. Children Welcomed - We offer children&apos;s…
 
 chinese 
 Tongs 
Hove, East Sussex
 Phone 
Our takeaway specialises in Peking, Cantonese and Szechuan Cuisine
Situated on Waterloo Street just off Western Road Hove. We offer you a
good variety of quality food which are always freshly prepared.
 
 chinese Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway Chinese Food 
 EatEasy Ltd 
Marks Tey, Essex
 Phone 
…Credit Card or Cash on Delivery.  Discounts on all food and drink from all of our partner restaurants. EatEasy lists over 28,000 restaurants and nearly 5,000 full menus of takeaway restaurant s that deliver across the UK.
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway takeaway menus Menus Online 
 New Sun Rise 
Seaford, East Sussex
 Phone 
Our takeaway specialises in Cantonese and Thai Cuisine Situated on
 Church Street near Seaford Train Station. We offer you a good variety 
of quality food which are always freshly prepare.
 
 chinese Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway chinese restaurant 
 Olympus Fish&amp;Chip Restaurant 
Bolton, Lancashire
 Phone 
The award winning Olympus Fish&amp;Chip Restaurant is one of Bolton&apos;s most popular eating places. Although specialising in Fish&amp;Chips this establishment also provides a varied menu with healthy options combined…
 
 
 RICE BOWL EXPRESS 
Rothwell, Northamptonshire
 Phone 
RICE BOWL EXPRESS is on a mission to provide the highest quality chinese food, by using the finest ingredients and making each dish fresh by order. Our menu consists of the very best chinese food from different regions.…
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway Chinese Food 
 Namaste Nepal 
Bristol, Avon
 Phone 
namaste nepal is family run business. We serve authentic nepalese food aswell as indian food. The restaurant was established in June 2011. However, so far customers have loved our food and service which are our main go…
 
 
 Blandford Forum Chinese Takeaway Lucky … 
Blandford Forum, Dorset
 Phone 
Chingwaa Chinese takeaway blandford forum dorset lucky house wings happy garden salisbury street east street salisbury poole bournemouth ferndown verwood shaftesbury westbury warminster ringwood
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway chinese restaurant Chinese Food 
 Dinertext Ltd 
Pinner, Middlesex
 Phone 
Dinertext is an SMS/Bluetooth marketing service dedicated to helping restaurants, bars, pubs and clubs to fill their establishments with paying customers as well as promoting better communication.  Our services focus on…
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway UK restaurants chinese restaurant 
 Chinese King 
York, North Yorkshire
 Phone 
Chinese King is a takeaway based in York, . The Chinese King offer great tasting currys, pizzas, burgers, Kebabs and Southern Fried Chicken. Order online at Chinese King York,
 
 
 Ruby Chinese 
York, North Yorkshire
 Phone 
Ruby Chinese is a takeaway based in York, Yorkshire. The Ruby Chinese offer great tasting Currys, Soups, sweet and sour dishes and Much more. Order online at Ruby Chinese York, Yorkshire
 
 
 Takeaway Planet 
London, London
 Phone 
Takeawayplanetis an intuitive and easy to use online ordering system that brings a huge range of restaurants for takeaway food delivery to your fingertips. With our headquarters in Nottingham, so based in the Midlands w…
 
 chinese chinese takeaway 
 Eatsy - Bristol takeaways 
Bristol, Avon
 Phone 
All Bristol Takeaways in one place. Browse and Compare every menu before placing your order directly with takeaway.
 
 chinese Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway chinese restaurant 
 uk online takeaway 
London, London
 Phone 
Aggregating the online takeaway companies to provide you with the most comprehensive list of takeaways to order online from
 
 chinese takeaway 
 Skippers 
Harwich, Essex
 Phone 
…delicious fish and chips. We also cater for parties, sporting events and retirement homes. Fancy a takeaway tonight? How about fish and chips? Come to Skippers Fish and Chip Shop in Parkeston - a family run business.…
 
 
 Seri intan 
Prestatyn, Clwyd
 Phone 
Situated in the heart of Prestatyn Seri Intan is popular amoung locals and visitors alike for it&apos;s authentic Thai, Malaysia and Oriental cuisine served in a friendly atmosphere featuring bright colours and warm ambient …
 
 
 Weso Web Design And Development 
London, London
 Phone 
Weso tailor our services to fit each clients needs. From the person who 
knows what they want, to the business or organization needs just the 
right item to compliment an IT business solutions. WESO also specializes in …
 
 chinese chinese takeaway 
 TAKARI INDIAN RESTURANT 
London, London
 Phone 
Takari is an Indian restaurant which boasts traditional cuisine. Located in the heart of Drury Lane it is surrounded by the capitals best theatre offerings. The attractive surroundings and dedicated staff ensure that yo…
 
 
 China Inn Restaurant 
Hove, East Sussex
 Phone 
…of the cooking are more important and the food tastes better and healthier . China Inn also caters for takeaways and deliveries with the same high quality food. In order to ensure MSG-free status on our food…
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway Chinese Food 
 Cafe Spice Limited 
Sturminster Newton, Dorset
 Phone 
Welcome to Café Spice Whether your looking for a Restaurant or just a Takeaway Cafe Spice is here to take your order. We are based in the lovely town that is Sturminster Newton, at the heart of the Blackmore Vale, Dorse…
 
 
 Takeaway Deliveries 
Peterborough, Cambridgeshire
 Phone 
Find Takeaway Deliveries in your local area. Chinese Take aways, Indian take aways, pizza deliveries, food to your door, visit the website for all the menu&apos;s of takeaways in your city. Takeaway Deliveries in England, Ba…
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway chinese restaurant Chinese Food 
 Kebab Center 
Middlesbrough, Cleveland
 Phone 
Kebab Centre has been established since 1993 and has been running ever since.Yes it has been passed on by the founder Mr Raad.Currently it is owned by Ali&amp;Sons. Kebab Centre specialises in all kebabs eg. Donner …
 
 
 Yummy House Chinese Takeaway 
Bath, Avon
 Phone 
Yummy House are famous in Bath for their fantastic Chinese, Thai&amp;Malaysian cuisine. They deliver all over Bath with free delivery if
your order is over £10. For you next Chinese Takeaway order to Yummy
House on E-…
 
 chinese 
 Chubby Changs 
N7 8LT, London
 Phone 
Chubby Changs is simply the cool side of Chinese food. A contemporary interior makes Chubby Changs a lot different to other restaurants of similar type. Delicious home cooked food, good service and incredible prices com…
 
 chinese chinese takeaway chinese restaurant Chinese Food 
 hing loon house 
London, London
 Phone 
Hing loon house provides daily freshly cooked chinese, malaysian, singapore, thai and vietnames food to take away or deliver. Friendly and great services offered to new and regular customers and benefits on special occa…
 
 chinese Chinese Take Away 
 Le Taj Restaurant 
Halifax, West Yorkshire
 Phone 
Successful five star indian restaurant with 48 covers.  Contemporary interior with cracked glass effect tables on black granite and italian lighting. Genuine reason for sale - Business is based in Halifax, West Yorkshi…
 
 
 Asha Dial-A-Curry&amp;Indian Takeaway 
Malvern, Worcestershire
 Phone 
Asha Dial-A-Curry is an Indian takeaway in Malvern, Worcestershire. It specialises in balti dishes, tandoori and all Indian currry dishes. Asha is open seven days a week - taking orders from 5.30pm - last orders 11.30pm…
 
 
 Takeawayz 

 Phone 
Takeawayz.com provides a comprehensive takeaway food delivery service. Users can search the UK for takeaway restaurant s, view menu’s, make recommendations and order online. Many restaurants offer free delivery
 
 
 takeaway2nite.com 
Rochester, Kent

takeaway2nite.com – UK takeaway menus online. NEW search directory for takeaways in your area. You&apos;ll never be without a menu again! Comprehensive searchable directory of takeaways throughout the UK. Search the director…
 
 chinese takeaway takeaway menus Menus Online 
 Jintana Thai Restaurant 
Bowness-on-Windermere, Cumbria
 Phone 
Jintana Thai Restaurant is an extra special combination of authentic Thai Restaurant, Take-away, Cafe, Outside Catering service and Thai Cookery School located in the heart of the Lake District
 
 chinese Chinese Take Away 
 Royal China Restaurant Aberdeen 
Aberdeen, Aberdeenshire
 Phone 
Royal China Restaurant situated at 309 North Deeside Road, Peterculter, about 8 miles from Aberdeen city. Building built and opened in 1995. Royal China Restaurant offers one of the finest Cantonese and Chinese dining e…
 
 Chinese Take Away Chinese Carry Out chinese takeaway chinese restaurant 
 MEI Restaurant 
Chobham, Surrey
 Phone 
mei asian bar&amp;restaurant is set in a beautiful, grade II listed building in the quaint village of Chobham. The interior of the restaurant has a twist of modern, while sympathetically retaining the charm of the origina…
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway chinese restaurant authentic Asian food 
 the-food-place 
Bolton, Lancashire

I have just completed a new website listing restaurants in the bolton and horwich area and will soon be updating it to include more areas, any restaurant can be added to the site so please visit and add your restaurant…
 
 chinese 
 Tikka Tikka Restaurant 
Scarborough, North Yorkshire
 Phone 
Tikka Tikka, a contemporary designed Indian restaurant located in the heart of Britain&apos;s First Resort - Scarborough. The menu takes you on a journey across the different regions of India presenting a superb combination…
 
 
 Golden Bowl Chinese Takeaway 
Birmingham
 Phone 
Golden Bowl Chinese is a fantastic new Chinese takeaway restaurant in Great Barr in B43 in the Birmingham area. It specialises in the delivery of Chinese takeaway food and has a great menu choice. You can order you food…
 
 chinese takeaway fried rice 
 Online Menus Cornwall 


Online Menus Cornwall host restaurant, takeaway, pub, cafe, bistro, fish and chip shops and hotel menus online in Cornwall. Menus never get lost online! Visit our website to see some of the best places to eat in Cornwal…
 
 Chinese Take Away chinese takeaway chinese restaurant Chinese Food 
 The Wok&amp;Roll cafe 
Birmingham, West Midlands
 Phone 
 Chinese Food 
 First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (804) 
 Related keywords 
 restaurant restaurants Eating and Drinking Places chinese chinese takeaway Take away Chinese Take Away takeaway chinese restaurant Indian Restaurant 
 Takeaway Restaurant by county 
 West-Yorkshire West-Midlands Essex Kent Hampshire Lancashire Surrey Tyne-And-Wear Middlesex Cheshire 
 Takeaway Restaurant by region 
 East of England Yorkshire and the Humber East Anglia West Country North-West England East Midlands Heart of England Scottish Lowlands Thames Valley Peak District 
 Takeaway Restaurant by city/town 
 BIRMINGHAM, West-Midlands LEEDS, West-Yorkshire EDINBURGH, Midlothian GLASGOW, Lanarkshire PLYMOUTH, Devon NOTTINGHAM, Nottinghamshire NORWICH, Norfolk NEWCASTLE UPON TYNE, Tyne-And-Wear WALSALL, West-Midlands BRADFORD, West-Yorkshire 
 Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
 Tongs 
 Coupons (1) 
 Millan Tandoori 
 Coupons (1) 
 Dinertext Ltd 
 Coupons (1) 
 
 
 Take-a-way 
 Products (6) 
 Millan Tandoori 
 Products (4) Coupons (1) 
 Tongs 
 Coupons (1) 
 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 Chinese King 20/12/2011 Ruby Chinese 28/11/2011 Namaste Nepal 04/10/2011 Fill My Belly 20/05/2011 RICE BOWL EXPRESS 07/03/2011 Takeaway Deliveries 19/01/2011 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search enquiry 
Most popular
 
 Dinertext Ltd China Inn Restaurant Tongs Online Food Menus - TakeAway,… Kebab Center Millan Tandoori 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
Share on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.7mvt.009 )
	</body>
</document>
