<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004531" url="http://www.trulia.com/property/3060609199-5-Woods-End-Ln-Springfield-IL-62711" time="2012-07-12-20:56" support="1" score="0.014980355246831112" bingtitle="5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL - Trulia" webtitle="5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL - Trulia">
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="9"/>
	<description>If so, claim this home and add facts. With more facts, we can provide better ... Location Information near 5 Woods End Ln</description>
	<body>
		Homes ▼
 Homes Rentals Local Info Advice Professionals Mortgages Advanced Search 
 Buy 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Rent 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Advice 
 Q&amp;A Advice Blogs Guides Ask a Question Write a Blog Post 
 Mortgage 
 Home Loans Mortgage Refinance Mortgage Trends Mortgage Advice Mortgage Calculators 
 Local Info 
 Local Home Foreclosure Center Directory 
 Find a Pro 
 Real Estate Agents Brokers Mortgage Brokers or Lenders Builders/Developers Property Managers 
 
 Help Log in Sign up 
 
 Trulia Mobile For Professionals 
It looks like Javascript is disabled in your browser.
 Trulia requires Javascript to be enabled in order to use our site.
 Please follow these instructions to enable Javascript. 
 unknown 
5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL 62711
 housing 39.807304 -89.72997 Home Facts Photos 12 Map&amp;Nearby Sales Trends Schools 
 
 
 
 
 Status: Unknown Bedrooms: 6 Bathrooms: 4 Property type: Single-Family Home Size: 6,205 sqft Lot: 108,900 sqft Year built:  Added on Trulia: 180+ days ago Zip: 62711 Are you the owner? If so, claim this home and add facts. With more facts, we can provide better price estimates. 
 Contact an agent Follow home Share 
 Send email Share on Facebook 
 Check your credit Get Prequalified More 
 Print this page Ask a question 
 Description provided by Trulia This Single-Family Home is located at 5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL. 5 Woods End Ln is in the 62711 ZIP code in Springfield, IL. The average listing price for ZIP code 62711 is $338,418. 5 Woods End Ln has 6 beds, 4 baths, and approximately 6,205 square feet 
Listing Info for 5 Woods End Ln 
 Most recent information provided by Grady Realtors, Inc.: 
 Price: $509,900 Status: Unknown 6 Bedrooms 4 Bathrooms 6,205 sqft Single-Family Home Lot Size: 108,900 sqft Basement Deck Patio Dishwasher Refrigerator Oven Dryer Microwave Wet Bar Heating Fuel: Natural Gas Hot Tub Spa 
 
Location Information near 5 Woods End Ln 
 
 Schools Nearby Homes Crimes Amenities Transit 
 Property Nearby homes Schools Crimes Amenities Transit $1,099,500 4 br / 2 ba Single-Family Home OPEN HOUSE Sun Oct 16, 2pm to 4pm Springfield local info 
 Elementary Schools Middle Schools High Schools Type GreatSchools Rating Distance Schools in Springfield Public School District 186 View Homes Schools in Pleasant Plains Cmty Unit Sd 8 View Homes No public schools where found for this property and grade level. Pleasant Plains Middle School View Homes Public 8 4.6 mi Pleasant Plains High School View Homes Public 9 11.2 mi Owen Marsh Elementary School View Homes Public 5 2.2 mi Jane Addams Elementary School View Homes Public 3 2.4 mi Lindsay Elementary School View Homes Public 5 2.8 mi Dubois Elementary School View Homes Public 2 3.1 mi Elizabeth Graham Elementary School View Homes Public 2 3.4 mi Private Schools No private schools where found for this property and grade level. Springfield Christian School View Homes Private - 1.2 mi Springfield Sda School View Homes Private - 1.3 mi Montessori Schoolhouse View Homes Private - 1.5 mi Our Saviors Lutheran School View Homes Private - 2.0 mi Calvary Academy View Homes Private - 2.4 mi Springfield Christian School View Homes Private - 1.2 mi Springfield Sda School View Homes Private - 1.3 mi Our Saviors Lutheran School View Homes Private - 2.0 mi Calvary Academy View Homes Private - 2.4 mi St Agnes School View Homes Catholic - 2.8 mi Lutheran High School View Homes Private - 0.7 mi Calvary Academy View Homes Private - 2.4 mi Sacred Heart - Griffin High School View Homes Catholic - 3.0 mi Grace Baptist Academy View Homes Private - 4.4 mi Park Meadows Baptist Academy View Homes Private - 29.2 mi 
 indicates schools assigned
 to this home. School data provided by OnBoard Informatics.
 Boundaries provided by Maponics. 
Homes near 5 Woods End Ln 
 Loading data 
Individual Crimes near 5 Woods End Ln 
 Loading data 
Nearby Restaurants, Banks, and Grocery Stores
 Loading data 
Transit Stops near 5 Woods End Ln 
 Loading data 
What Trulia users think of this area
 Overall area rating: 

 Excellent We need more ratings to calculate an average. Top rated categories: 

 Safety 

 Cleanliness 

 Pet-friendly 

 Schools We need more ratings to calculate top categories. Total ratings: 420 | View all ratings Last updated 12 hours ago Rate this area: Rate it Rate these categories: 
 Safety Rate it Pet-friendly Rate it Walkability Rate it Restaurants&amp;Shopping Rate it 
 Rate and Review Read 3 reviews » 
Brokered by
 Grady Realtors, Inc. 1501 S. MacArthur Blvd., Springfield, IL, 62704 (217) 753-2121 Thank you, your email has been sent to the agent. Sorry -- An error occurred. Please try again. 
Contact local agents near 5 Woods End Ln 
 From Subject Schedule a viewing Property still available? Learn more details Alert me on similar homes Make an offer Other Message I am searching for a home in 62711 and I found 5 Woods End Ln, Springfield IL 62711 with 6 bedrooms, 4 bathrooms. Please send me more information about this or other similar listings in this area. 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Ki McCurley (217) 689-2447 Chuck Sattler (217) 622-1516 John Giordano (217) 806-4031 Tina Davidson (217) 469-5657   1 Want to be listed here? Learn more Done «See similar homes Prev Next Sponsored Resource Center Buying a Home? Check your Credit Score today for - $0 Unpack discounts up to 40% with Discount Double Check. Get A Quote. This property may be overpaying their property taxes. Check For Free Discussions in Springfield, IL 177 followers 2 recent questions Ask Question Recent Activity I AM FROM OUT OF TOWN AND AM INTERESTED IN A HOME FAR SALE AT 27 ARABIAN TRAIL. I DO NOT KNOW ANY THING ABOUT THIS AREA. 4 answers wondering if there is a limit on the amount of income you can make and still qualify for the 8000 dollars 4 answers you don&apos;t answer the question. How do I get my house on trulia? 8 answers ow do I get my house on trulia? 4 answers How do I get my house on Trulia? 4 answers Who lends to medical students? 2 answers Did you know IL Welcomes Heroes Home with a VA grant? 1 answer View 2 recent questions More local advice More Advice: 
 Recent Q&amp;A in Springfield, IL Recent blog posts in Springfield, IL Find a real estate professional Springfield, IL 
 
 Send this property to a friend 5 Woods End Ln, Springfield IL 6 br , 4 ba , Single-Family Home Friend&apos;s email: [+] Add another friend&apos;s email Your email: Your name:
 (optional) Message:
 (optional) Cancel Send 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Done       

 My Notes Done Save a personal note that only you can view. Clear Save my note       

 Report Listing Error 5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL Error Type: Please select... Property Sold/Withdrawn Price has changed Incorrect Agent/Broker Link Doesn&apos;t Work Incorrect Photo Incorrect Property Details Incorrect Map Other   Current Revised Price: $509,900 $ Property Type: Single-Family Home Select One Single-Family Home Condo Townhouse Coop Apartment Loft TIC Apartment/Condo/Townhouse Mobile/Manufactured Farm/Ranch Lot/Land Multi-Family Income/Investment Houseboat Unknown Listing Type: -- Select One Resale New Home Beds: 6 Baths: 4 Sqft: 6,205 Lot size:
 (acres) 108,900 sqft Year Built: n/a     Please remove this listing
until this issue is resolved Details: Your name Your email
 (optional): 
 Cancel Send 
 Done       

 Ask a question about this property Sorry, we couldn’t find contact information for this agent. Try asking your question on Trulia Voices below. 
 Did you know? You can ask the Trulia Voices community about this property to get information and advice from real estate experts and locals .
 150 characters left Question Ask real estate experts,locals, and friends... 1000 characters left More Details (Optional) Optional details about your question This question is about this property: http://www.trulia.com/property/3060609199-5-Woods-End-Ln-Springfield-IL-62711   Get email alerts as people answer my question ASK!       

 Success! DONE       
 Nearby homes 
 10 Woods End Ln #1 Springfield, IL 1 Woods End Ln Springfield, IL 5 Woods End Ln #1 Springfield, IL 3917 W Bluffs Rd Springfield, IL 20 Nightingale Dr #1 Springfield, IL 4130 Highbury Springfield, IL 22 Forest Green Dr Springfield, IL 505 Old Tippecanoe Dr Springfield, IL 
 Show more 69af80a5f77faaabbb5f87e7d6b4c56a 
 What do you think of this area? 
Thanks! Your review has been submitted

Thanks! Both your review and ratings have been submitted
 
Thanks! Your changes have been saved
 Done We are collecting ratings for the surrounding area, not for this or any other specific property or listing.       
 
 Communities near 5 Woods End Ln, Springfield 
 Springfield Real Estate Springfield Real Estate Springfield Foreclosures Springfield Single-Family Homes 62711 Real Estate 62711 Single-Family Homes 62711 Apartments for Rent Springfield Apartments for Rent 
 
 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Grandview Homes for Sale Leland Grove Homes for Sale Jerome Homes for Sale Southern View Homes for Sale Devereux Heights Homes for Sale Cantrall Homes for Sale See All Nearby Cities 
 
 Real Estate and Mortgage Guides Springfield Real Estate Guide Springfield Schools Springfield Home Prices Heat Map Illinois Home Prices Heat Map Springfield Mortgage Springfield Refinance Springfield Home Loan 
 

 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Grandview Homes for Sale Leland Grove Homes for Sale Jerome Homes for Sale Southern View Homes for Sale Devereux Heights Homes for Sale Cantrall Homes for Sale Spaulding Homes for Sale Riverton Homes for Sale Sherman Homes for Sale Barclay Homes for Sale       

Residential Real Estate

 San Francisco real estate  |  New York real estate  |  Los Angeles real estate  |  Orlando real estate  |  Miami real estate  |  Philadelphia real estate  |  Phoenix real estate  |  San Diego real estate  |  San Jose real estate  |  Chicago real estate  |  Arizona real estate  |  California real estate  |  Florida real estate  |  Illinois real estate  |  Massachusetts real estate  |  New Jersey real estate  |  Pennsylvania real estate  |  Texas real estate  |  Other local real estate  |  California apartments  |  New York apartments  |  Texas apartments  |  Apartments for rent  |  Home price maps  |  Real estate community  |  U.S. Property records 
 
Explore Trulia

 Homes for Sale  |  Homes for Rent  |  Stats&amp;Trends  |  Real Estate Advice  |  Real Estate Apps  |  Trulia Labs  |  Trulia API  |  Trulia Estimates 
 
For Professionals

 Agents  |  Brokers  |  MLS  |  Advertisers&amp;Partners  |  Tools&amp;Widgets  |  Submit Your Listings  |  Real Estate Leads 
 
Corporate

 About Trulia  |  News Room  |  Trulia Blog  |  Careers  |  Privacy  |  Terms of Use  |  Subscription Terms of Use  |  Community Guidelines 
 This Single-Family Home is located at 5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL. 5 Woods End Ln is in the 62711 ZIP code in Springfield, IL. The average listing price for ZIP code 62711 is $338,418. 5 Woods End Ln has 6 beds, 4 baths, and approximately 6,205 square feet Copyright©2012
 Trulia, Inc. All rights reserved. |  Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity Have a question? Visit our Help Center to find the answer 
 
 5 Woods End Lane, Springfield IL
 Follow Share Contact agent
	</body>
</document>
