<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004611" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/199176-how-do-i-stop-drinking-diet-coke-lose-weight/" time="2012-07-12-21:06" support="1" score="0.0008278991249552083" bingtitle="How Do I Stop Drinking Diet Coke &amp; Lose Weight? | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="How Do I Stop Drinking Diet Coke&amp;Lose Weight? | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>Photo Credit glass of ... as soon as you get to work because you feel tired and need the energy? Are you drinking it because it&apos;s convenient, as in a fast-food restaurant&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Beverages Diet Soda How Do I Stop Drinking Diet Coke&amp;Lose Weight? 
 
 How Do I Stop Drinking Diet Coke&amp;Lose Weight? 
 Nov 21, 2011 | By Jenni Wiltz Photo Credit glass of soda image by Kalani from Fotolia.com 
Just because you&apos;re drinking a diet soda doesn&apos;t mean it&apos;s good for you. Diet drinks may not have calories, but they still have sodium, caffeine and artificial sweeteners that can wreak havoc on your diet without providing any useful nutrition. Use a gradual approach to stop your addition to Diet Coke and lose weight at the same time.
 
Study Your Consumption Pattern
 
Step 1

Keep a record of how many diet sodas you drink in a week---you might be surprised at how many you tally. The California Center for Public Health Advocacy reports that Americans drink an average of 50 gallons of soda and other sweetened drinks per year.
 
Step 2

Note when and why you&apos;re drinking each soda. For example, are you drinking a Diet Coke as soon as you get to work because you feel tired and need the energy? Are you drinking it because it&apos;s convenient, as in a fast-food restaurant&apos;s value meal?
 
Step 3

Watch your serving sizes. According to the Center for Disease Control and Prevention, some 20-oz. bottles contain 2.5 servings, although the nutrition facts reflect a single serving. The more aware you are of how much you drink, the easier it is to limit yourself.
 
Step 4

Make sure you&apos;re not overeating just because you&apos;re drinking a diet soda. University of Texas epidemiologist Sharon Fowler discovered that the more diet sodas her research subjects drank, the more likely they were to gain weight. Some people may overindulge precisely because their sodas have no calories, while Fowler questions the stomach&apos;s response to soda itself. She believes it reacts to anything other than water with a production of gastric acid, which may increase feelings of hunger.
 
Change Your Behavior
 
Step 1

Change what you buy at the grocery store. If you keep a supply of alternate beverage on hand, you&apos;ll be less likely to reach for a Diet Coke every time you&apos;re thirsty. Nutritionist Katherine Zeratsky of the Mayo Clinic suggests swapping soda for 100 percent fruit juice, skim milk, sparkling water or still water with additives like a hint of lemon or cranberry juice.
 
Step 2

Decrease your dependence on Diet Coke&apos;s caffeine with lifestyle modifications. If you&apos;re feeling a lack of energy, try going to bed half an hour earlier, getting more exercise, and limiting afternoon and evening caffeine consumption that can cause sleeplessness.
 
Step 3

Exchange your afternoon soda for a sweet-tasting treat that packs a healthier punch. Try munching on fresh fruit, chocolate-flavored rice cakes, dried fruit, yogurt or a whole-wheat bagel with low-fat cream cheese.
 
Step 4

Skip soda at restaurants. Clemson University Extension suggests you choose sparkling water, mineral water, fruit juice, or unsweetened drinks like diet lemonade or unsweetened iced tea.
 
Tips and Warnings

 Set small goals for yourself, such as cutting your Diet Coke consumption by a can a day. The more you succeed, the more you&apos;ll want to keep reducing your overall soda consumption. 
 
Things You&apos;ll Need

 Pencil Paper 
 
References

 California Center for Public Health Advocacy: Soda Fact Sheet CDC: Rethink Your Drink CBS News: Can Diet Soda Make You Gain Weight? Mayo Clinic: Diet soda: Is it bad for you? Clemson University Cooperative Extension: Fast Food&amp;Take-Out Meals 
 
Article reviewed by Roman Tsivkin Last updated on: Nov 21, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Bloating and Weight Gain With Diet Coke 
 
 Bad Side Effects of Drinking Diet Coke 
 
 If I Stop Drinking Wine, Will I Lose Weight? 
 
 Is Drinking One Can of Diet Coke a Day Harmful? 
 
 Does Diet Coke Cause Temporary Weight Gain? 
 
 Diet Coke&amp;Weight Loss 
 
 Diet Coke&amp;Weight Gain 
 
 Will I Lose Weight if I Stop Drinking Diet Soda? 
 
 Good Reasons to Stop Drinking Diet Soda 
 
 How to Quit Drinking Diet Coke Without the Crushing Headaches 
 
 Is Diet Coke Bad When You Are Pregnant? 
 
 Can a Person Lose Weight by Not Drinking Coke&amp;Pepsi Products? 
 
 How to Stop Drinking Coca-Cola&amp;Lose Weight 
 
 How to Lose Weight With Diet Coke 
 
 Diet Coke&amp;Weight Gain or Loss 
 
 If I Quit Drinking Diet Pepsi, Will I Lose Weight? 
 
 Quitting Diet Coke&amp;Weight Loss 
 
 Can Your Teeth Be Saved if You Stop Drinking Diet Soda? 
 
 How to Lose Weight After Quitting Diet Soda 
 
 23 Secrets From The World&apos;s Best Trainers 
 Show More Stop Drinking advertisement Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
