<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004750" url="http://www.marketwire.com/press-release/Hungry-Man-TV-Premieres-Winner-of-the-Fattest-Car-in-America-Survey-882164.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="3" score="0.002527862091383801" bingtitle="Hungry Man TV Premieres Winner of the Fattest Car in America Survey" webtitle="Hungry Man TV Premieres Winner of the Fattest Car in America Survey">
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>... study of automobile manufacturers &amp; fast food restaurant ... consumption of fast food via number of cup holders, food trays ... mailing list on www.hungrymantv.com to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		News Site 
 
 Sign In 
 My Marketwire Account Marketwire Resonate Mediahub News Dashboard 2.0 Personal Beat Hot Off the Wire 
 Register Français Marketwire Blog Contact Marketwire 
 
 
 Marketwire MAP Marketwire Heartbeat Marketwire Distribute 
 Distribution Channels 
 Global Newslines Trade Media Specialty Media Custom Lists 
 Disclosure, Regulatory Filing&amp;XBRL 
 Webcasts and Conference Calls XBRL EDGAR Filing Services SEDAR Filing Services UK Regulatory Filing Services 
 Marketwire Impress Marketwire Mediahub Editorial and Translation SEO, Social Media and Multimedia 
 Social Media 2.0 Releases Embedded Photos and Videos 
 Distribution Reporting 
 Marketwire Resonate 
 
 All News Headlines Only Advanced Search RSS Newsfeeds 
 
 Marketwire Blog Case Studies Emerging Media Investor Relations and
 Disclosure Marketing
 and
Communications Strategies Measurement and ROI Media and Blogger
 Relations Media Monitoring Public Relations and
 Corporate PR Search Engine Optimization Social Media 
 
 Personal Beat Features Newswire Newsfeeds 
 
 News Room 
 
 
 Email Print Friendly Share 
 
 SOURCE: Hungry Man Entertainment 
 
July 23, 2008 13:46 ET

Hungry Man TV Premieres Winner of the Fattest Car in America Survey

 
www.hungrymantv.com
 


NEW YORK, NY--(Marketwire - July 23, 2008) - Hungry Man TV premieres the results of its
FATTEST RIDE IN AMERICA investigation TODAY on Hungrymantv.com at 12pm EDT
/ 9am PDT.
The survey, completed as a two-part investigation by Hungry Man TV&apos;s
Internet series &quot;Undercover Cheerleaders,&quot; was an informal study of
automobile manufacturers&amp;fast food restaurant chains to determine which
car in America best promotes obesity.
Over the course of several months, the team visited fast food drive-thrus
in New York, Chicago and Los Angeles and counted which make and model cars
went through the most. Car manufacturers&apos; designs were also examined to
see which vehicles best facilitated the consumption of fast food via number
of cup holders, food trays and storage containers. Other data, including
manufacturer sales figures&amp;interior dimensions, were also analyzed.
The &quot;Undercover Cheerleaders&quot; mission is to fight social and political
injustices throughout the world.
&quot;Faced with a dwindling economy, record gas prices and ever-rising
unemployment rates, the &apos;Undercover Cheerleaders&apos; represent a true ray of
hope...&quot; says Mark Grande, Head of Development at Hungry Man. &quot;We&apos;re
thrilled to be involved with these modern day super heroes.&quot;
The episode will be launched in 2 parts on Hungry Man TV, approximately one
week apart. The webisodes can be seen by logging onto www.hungrymantv.com .
About Hungry Man TV
Just over a year old, HMTV is a comedy-driven web channel launched by
Hungry Man Entertainment, a division of the award-winning commercial
production company. The site has won Davey and W3 Awards for Best
Entertainment and two of its series, &quot;Phistophicles&quot; and &quot;Mouthpieces,&quot;
received Official Honoree Awards for Best Writing at the 2008 Webby Awards.
The channel has become equally popular with fans, with &quot;Phistophicles&quot;
&quot;Book Two&quot; gaining over 400,000 views on YouTube in one weekend alone.
From the insanely irreverent, to the darkly comedic, HMTV aims to do one
thing -- entertain.
Be sure to join our mailing list on www.hungrymantv.com to receive all
HMTV-related news and updates!
Click here to view the episode: http://www.hungrymantv.com/series.php?sid=undercover&amp;vid=fat_ride1 
 
Contact Information

 
 Contact:
Mark Grande
Hungry Man, Inc.
212-625-5628
 Email Contact 

 
 
 
 
 
 Email Print Friendly Share 
 News Room   
View Related News

 About this company Hungry Man Entertainment 
 From this industry Automotive 
 Computers and Software 
 Media and Entertainment 
 Medical and Healthcare 
 From this sub-industry Cars 
 Internet 
 Software 
 Television 
 Health and Nutrition 
 

See all RSS Newsfeeds 
   
Multimedia
 
 
 (Click here for details) 
 View Image 
   
 About Marketwire Site Map Privacy 

 US: 1.800.774 _ .9473 Canada: 1.888.299 _ .0338 UK: +44.20.7220 _ .4500 
 Follow Marketwire
 
 ©2012
 Marketwire, Incorporated. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
