<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004988" url="http://travel.yahoo.com/p-travelguide-18927043R-liltex_restaurant-i" time="2012-07-12-21:31" support="1" score="0.0011163977234080425" bingtitle="Lil-Tex Restaurant - Copperas Cove, Texas - Yahoo! Travel" webtitle="Lil-Tex Restaurant - Copperas Cove, Texas - Yahoo! Travel">
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>... little more than I would spend for a family of 4 to eat at a fast food restaurant, I can have a fresh hot meal ... fried steak.Wonderful German waitress. Gorgeous cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Travel 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Travel Ideas 
 Travel Articles Beach Family Golf Honeymoon National Parks Ski Summer Weekend Winter 
 Travel Guides Book a Trip 
 Deals Flights Hotels Car Rental Vacations Cruises Specials Vacation Rentals 
 My Travel 
 My Profile My Trips Create a Trip TimeTraveler 
 Visit Britain Disney Travel 
 Walt Disney World Resort Disneyland Resort Disney Cruise Line Aulani Resort, Hawai&apos;i Disney Vacation Club Adventures by Disney 
 
 
 Travel Guides Explore Trip Plans 
 Search Yahoo! Travel Search Welcome! Please sign in. Home Airport: Unavailable Edit»     Change Home Airport Enter a city or airport code to find your home airport. SUBMIT Loading... You must sign in to change your home airport. You must sign in again to change your home airport. SIGN IN We&apos;re sorry, your airport could not be saved. Please try again in a few minutes. We&apos;re sorry, there was a problem. Please try again in a few minutes. Please re-enter a city or airport code and select an airport from the list to continue.     SHARE   PRINT Facebook Twitter Delicious StumbleUpon Home &gt; Travel Guides &gt; United States &gt; Texas &gt; Copperas Cove &gt; Copperas Cove Restaurants &gt; Lil-Tex Restaurant Copperas Cove 
 OVERVIEW HOTELS VACATION RENTALS THINGS TO DO RESTAURANTS TRIP PLANS MAP DEALS 
   
 Lil-Tex Restaurant , Copperas Cove
 502 S Main St, Copperas Cove, TX 76522           AVERAGE USER RATING Contact: (254) 542-6677 View more information on Yahoo! Local No Photos Available Image Search» See all Copperas Cove Restaurants»   Map   Add to Trip     Loading... Interactive Map of Copperas Cove, TX       Expand Full List Show Fewer Results     Refresh Map Items Reset Map Map Refresh On? 
By keeping map refresh on, you will see new search results as you move the map.
 Yes, keep on No, turn it off Updating Map         WRITE A REVIEW   
Yahoo! User Reviews
 Reviews for Lil-Tex Restaurant: 11           AVERAGE OVERALL RATING Showing 1 - 10 of 11 Previous | 1 | 2 | Next Sort By: Most Recent Positive Negative Most Helpful           USER RATING By Cande , 7/21/10 Breakfast, lunch or dinner it&apos;s always a good choice. They have it all and if you don&apos;t see it just ask. The prices are very reasonable! For a little more than I would spend for a family of 4 to eat at a fast food restaurant, I can have a fresh hot meal, be waited on and have enough for leftovers. Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Steven , 7/17/10 Great chicken fried steak.Wonderful German waitress. Gorgeous cashier.What else could you want? Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Yo , 5/6/10 Okay. Their services has gotten better in the evening since they have moved some of the girls around. Before it was terrible. Wife and I refused to go back. But we gave them another chance and we were please. Still has room for improvement. Management doesn&apos;t want to give, that&apos;s the problem. Only thing is; you can never call them because their telephone I think is off the hook. I try to call several times for 15 to 20 minutes straight and the phone is constatnly busy. For a quick sit down hot meal it&apos;s okay. Do have the usual local loud mouth female/male/family groups that come in and those that don&apos;t control their children who think they are at their home. But, all in all I recommend the Lil Tex in Coppersa Cove again. I eat breakfast/lunch/dinner threr throughout the month. Jsut odn&apos;t eat the mexican plate, you&apos;ll be disappointed&quot;Bo&quot; Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Lin , 7/10/09 I am surprised at the complaints about the prices at this restaurant, so I had to write a review. I dont really go here often, but they are ok.

The reason I would go there is because they are affordable. If you consider $5-$10 for a full meal expensive I am shocked.

It&apos;s worth a try! Guess you cant go wrong with burgers, enchiladas, salads, chili, soup, corn bread, sandwiches and fries.... Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By A Yahoo! Contributor , 8/20/08 Depends on what you get I think. First time we went we had the cat fish dinner as it was during Lent, I didn&apos;t think it was all that great. Husband and I went back several weeks later and both got the chicken fried steak, I thought it was pretty good and our waitress was really nice. One thing I really didn&apos;t understand was she told us we weren&apos;t allowed to take leftovers. Thought that was weird. We&apos;ll probably go back again but not very often. Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Clare , 5/28/08 I&apos;ve been there a few times in the past, because my friend loves to eat there. The food is OK, but a bit overpriced. The last time I was there I swore I&apos;d never go back. I&apos;d ordered one of the lunch specials that came with 2 sides of my choice. One of the sides I ordered was peach cobbler. 

The waitress brought all our food, except the cobbler. I asked her to bring that, too. She flatly refused, saying I had to eat every bite of my food before I could have desert. I thought she was kidding, but it turns out she wasn&apos;t. She kept refusing to bring it. 

I&apos;m in my 50&apos;s and nobody has a right to tell me I can&apos;t have my desert along with my lunch, much less a waitress half my age at a restaurant where I&apos;m paying for my food! I finally told her to bring it or we&apos;d leave and tell the manager why we didn&apos;t eat the food or intend on paying the bill. She finally brought my peach cobbler, very grudgingly.

Is that how waitresses are supposed to treat paying customers? Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Neffy , 3/30/08 I have to agree with the overpriced, average food. The first time we went there I was excited, thinking I&apos;d found a good spot for a coffee shop and cheap food. I hadn&apos;t expected much in the quality of food (by the atmosphere), but I&apos;d expected it to be MUCH cheaper. We tried it one more time, hoping it was just a bad first experience, but nope. Same thing. And the service was just OK. Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Nicole , 2/1/08 On several occassions my company has ordered from Lil-Tex and were not blown away with the food. It was okay, and we did order from them again. Normaly, most people here order the marinated chicken salad, which is quite good. However, on more than one occassion, I&apos;ve noted that people have complained on the freshness and the quantity for the price. We&apos;ll likely order from them again, but it is not a restraunt I would recommend to someone looking for a good meal. Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING By Kasey , 11/29/07 I ate dinner here once and breakfast here once. I was not impressed either time. The chicken fried steak was tough and the mashed potatoes were instant. The scrambled eggs were good, but the biscuits and gravy were lacking. The atmosphere was old diner and not very clean. Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem           USER RATING I love this place. By Melanie , 1/9/06 Breakfast, Lunch and Dinner all the same..Friendly atmosphere, really nice people.... love going there Was this review helpful? ( Yes — No ) Report a problem Showing 1 - 10 of 11 Previous | 1 | 2 | Next Loading... Loading...     
Explore the Copperas Cove, TX Travel Guide
 
Popular Attractions in Copperas Cove, TX 

 Cobble Stone, The 
 
Popular Hotels in Copperas Cove, TX 

 Comfort Suites Copperas Cove BEST WESTERN Inn&amp;Suites Super 8 Copperas Cove Relax Inn Budget Inn Apartments Days Inn Copperas Cove Cactus Inn&amp;Suites 
 
Popular Cities near Copperas Cove, TX 

 Austin, TX New Braunfels, TX Killeen, TX Waco, TX San Marcos, TX Buda, TX Fredericksburg, TX Round Rock, TX Bryan, TX Boerne, TX Seguin, TX 
 Suggest an Attraction Suggest a Hotel     
 Copperas Cove Hotels 
Great Rates at Hotels in Copperas Cove , TX. Book and Save Today!
 Hotels-Rates .com Choice Hotels ® Texas 
Affordable. Comfortable. Excellent Service. Best Web Rate Guaranteed!
 www. ChoiceHotels .com/Copperas-Cove Copperas Cove Hotels 
110% Best Rate Guarantee! Hotels For Less Everyday.
 www. hotelsbycity .com 
     
Yahoo! Users Voted
 Top tags for Lil-Tex Restaurant, Copperas Cove  ()  ()  () No entries yet. Vote on what it&apos;s best for... See additional tags for this restaurant   VOTE       Available in the App Store     
 Not the right restaurant for you? View similar restaurants: 
 
In this neighborhood
 El Corral Restaurant Kettle Restaurant Church&apos;s Chicken Craw Daddy&apos;s Cajun Grill China Chess Browse all Copperas Cove restaurants»     Submit a change or correction for this restaurant       Home &gt; Travel Guides &gt; United States &gt; Texas &gt; Copperas Cove &gt; Copperas Cove Restaurants &gt; Lil-Tex Restaurant Travel Ideas Travel Articles Beach Family Golf Honeymoon National Parks Ski Summer Weekend Winter Travel Guides Travel Guides Explore Trip Plans Book a Trip Deals Flights Hotels Car Rental Vacations Cruises Specials Vacation Rentals My Travel My Profile My Trips Create a Trip TimeTraveler Other Yahoo! Services Downloads Yahoo! Travel: Your best choice for cheap airline tickets , hotels , and other great deals!     Suggest a Hotel or an Attraction *Terms&amp;Conditions: Savings calculation is based on Flight + Hotel vacation package bookings for a 3 month period for 2 adults with a 2+ night length of stay compared to price of the same components if booked separately during same period. Savings will vary based on origin/destination, length of trip, travel dates and selected travel supplier(s). Savings not available on all packages.

 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Copyright/IP Policy - About our Ads Portions copyright©2012 Y! TimeTraveler App for iPhone - Timed Travel Made Possible -   
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
