<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004305" url="https://www.activediner.com/bridge-way-diner-&amp;-restaurant/restaurant/old-bridge/nj/us/profile/340978" time="2012-07-12-20:33" support="1" score="0.00041710168364520877" bingtitle="Bridge-way Diner &amp; Restaurant Overview, 3030 Route 9 S, Old Bridge ..." webtitle="Bridge-way Diner&amp;Restaurant Overview, 3030 Route 9 S, Old Bridge, NJ, 08857, (732) 679-1599 - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>Bagel Shop; Banquet/Party Room; Bar; Barbecue ... - American, Diner, Deli/Sandwich/Subs, Fast Food Restaurant ... They will ask you to pay the bill before you&apos;re ready to leave.</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 Chinese 
 Italian 
 American 
 Thai 
 Bagel Shop 
 
 more... 
 American Bagel Shop Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Brewery/Pub/Tavern Buffet Casual/Family Catering Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Country Dance Floor Deli/Sandwich/Subs Delivery Diner Dinner Early Bird Special Fast Food Happy Hour Italian Kids Friendly Live Entertainment Lunch Pizzeria Romantic Seafood Steak House Take Out/Carry Out Thai Wheelchair Access 
 
 


Nearby Cities
 Edison 
 New Brunswick 
 Plainfield 
 Perth Amboy 
 Somerville 
 
 more... 
 Avenel Basking Ridge Berkeley Heights Bernardsville Bound Brook Carteret Clinton Colonia Dunellen Fords Frenchtown Highland Park Iselin Lambertville Manville Matawan Metuchen Middlesex Milltown North Brunswick Parlin Piscataway Princeton Raritan Sayreville South Amboy South Plainfield South River Spotswood Warren 
 
 



 
Dining Specials
 Thai Shangri - La 
 - Thai, Catering, Delivery, Kids Friendly Restaurant in
Old Bridge 
 
 
 


 
 United States &gt; New Jersey &gt; Old Bridge Restaurant Guide (1 ratings) 
Bridge-way Diner&amp;Restaurant
 (732) 679-1599 
 3030 Route 9 S, Old Bridge, NJ 08857 | MAP 
   | Share | Features 
 Diner 

 
 Overview 
   
 Reviews (1) 
   
 Map 
   
 



 UPDATE THIS LISTING 
 
Recent Bridge-way Diner&amp;Restaurant Reviews
 A diner 
 from Old Bridge, NJ gave an overall rating of on August 2, 2009 @ 12:36 PM

  I only eat here because the location is nearby. The food is ok at best and the owners watch how much you eat at the salad bar. They will ask you to pay the bill before you&apos;re ready to leave. The service is lousy and the bathrooms are never clean. No comparison to some of the finer diners in NJ and NY. 
   »   See All Old Bridge Restaurant Coupons &amp; Deals 
 

 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
