<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004928" url="http://dfwfurniturestore.com/forum.php" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="8" score="0.013202843108200127" bingtitle="Dallas-Fort Worth Local Forum: Food, Cities, People, Businesses, etc." webtitle="Dallas-Fort Worth Local Forum: Food, Cities, People,  Businesses, etc.">
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>It is extremely hard to find a place in the ... The only good fast food restaurant I can suggest to comment #1 is ... Dallas and try to get a bite to eat and a hot cup ...</description>
	<body>
		dfwFurnitureStore.com 
 
 Home How to buy Contact Terms&amp;Conditions 
 Washers used washers for sale, top-load washer, washing machine, front-load washer, compact washer Dryers 110v dryer, clothes dryer lowest prices, commercial dryer, electric dryer, GE dryer, used dryers for sale Washer and Dryer Sets Matching washer dryer set, used washer and electric dryer combo, washer-dryer pair, stackable washer dryer Refrigerators almond refrigerator, compact fridge, side-by-side refrigerator, used refrigerators for sale, freezer on top Stoves, Ovens, Ranges freestanding range, cheap stove, built-in oven, self cleaning, 220V range, ceramic glass range Dishwashers 24&quot; built-in dishwashers, dishwashers with delay start, under counter dishwasher, ENERGY STAR Qualified 
 . . 
 Categories 
 Appliances Furniture Kids Furniture Home and Garden 
 
 Beds 
 
Dallas washers, dryers, refrigerators. Same day delivery&amp;low prices.

 View dfwFurnitureStore.com company profile on GetFave.com. 

 View our Superpages listing here 

 Yellow Pages Used Appliances 
 
 Thank you for your interest in Dallas-Fort Worth Forum. You may submit opinions on any topic related to local life in DFW Metroplex.
All entries will be reviewed by editor within 24 hours before they are published on www.dfwfurniturestore.com/forum.php. If you would like to make changes to your comment, fill out our forum form below.
 
Your Name: Your E-Mail Address: 

Please provide a detailed description of your topic or view concerning Dallas-Fort Worth:
 
 
 Comment 1: January 28, 2010
Looking for suggestions. I am very serious about my food. It is extremely hard to find a place in the metroplex that has good food and exceptionally warm service. Any price range: fast food to upscale fine dining. I was under impression that Pappadeaux is a restaurant on my list of a few places that I thought cannot fail, but when I went to the Pappadeaux location in Arlington of I-30, I sat there as long as I could humanly stand on a hungry stomach. I figured if I was going to eat, I needed to leave that place. It seemed to me that the only thing they were serving was apologies and excuses (they dont taste very well, though). Bill Graham of Arlington, TX. 

 Comment 2: January 28, 2010
Oh yeah, I had that same thing. I noticed when me and my kids were at the Burger King on Eastchase in Arlington, while I was there, they were having an issue with salmonella. Uhh, my kids were playing on that playground so many times. People just dont care any more about food and places they eat in. Takisha of Arlington, TX. 

 Comment 3: Januart 31, 2010
How about refried French fries? Any one noticed that when you ask for fresh and hot fries in a fast food burger place, they just drop the same fries back in the oil and serve them. But cannot fool the public. The fries will be very greasy and taste horrible. 
The only good fast food restaurant I can suggest to comment #1 is McDonalds on interstate 20 in Forst Hill, from Fort Worth exit Forest Hill drive. They really do try their best. And you dont ever have to repeat over and over about the coffee. If you ask for fresh coffee, you will DEFINITELY get a hot fresh cup of coffee. Elaine of Fort Worth, TX. 

 Comment 4: February 7, 2010
Yall, I was over there in Dallas. I came into town to take care of some business from out there in McKinney. And I stop there in McDonalds for coffee and apple pies. Them darn pies were probably 3 days old, they can ruin that stuff like that. I am just saying, every time I go to Dallas and try to get a bite to eat and a hot cup of coffee, it just like pulling teeth. And I am telling you, they need to do something better. They supposed to have these health inspectors, how do they pass these places. They are just not doing anything. I called and complained, all I get is that they are doing ongoing investigation. I am just saying they are investigating while people are paying money for some crappy food (excuse my French). Ive had some better cow manure that taste better than that stuff. 
Well, if people speak up more, maybe they will stop serving cold and stale stuff. Joe66 of McKinney, TX. 

 Comment 5: February 16, 2010
I am just looking for any kind of firsthand information about the area. I am getting transferred for my job and would like to know the best little city near Fort Worth to rent or buy. 
Any one, please? I got little kids and want something safe without bars on the windows.

 Comment 6: February 20, 2010

Welcome to Dealing with TXU Energy Nightmare

SOLUTION: SWITCH ELECTRIC PROVIDERS

One would think that after thousands of rip off reports, consumer complaints, letters to Attorney General of Texas from Texas residents, TXU Energy utility company should go out of business, but I guess stealing millions of dollars from hard working men and women does not interest consumer rights bureaus and government officials. TXU Energy gets away with all sorts of illegal stuff.

Where should I start: putting bogus charges on a bill, double billing for a single month, switching account numbers without customers authorization, tripling the bill after it is consistent month to month, or how about the odds of billed exactly the same amount for usage for two months in a row without a penny difference, or maybe receiving a $100 bill for a month on vacation with the main breaker shut off entire 30 calendar days. Not to speak of the rude and dump behavior of the customer representatives whose calling stations are located in India, Philippines, etc. These are just a few things that I can sum up from my experience in the last few years. But the final straw is getting an electric bill for over $550 in 1400 square foot brick home, built 2003, with only 20% of the entire month spent at home (winter month, too).

TXU Energy is very much aware of how much time and money that we, hard working people, cannot afford to lose arguing back and forth. Majority of the people pay the outrageous electric bills they receive, those of us who try to call TXU Energy customer service to address the issue and errors -we get a run around, get hung up on, laughed at, lied to, you name it.

We ALL need to go about it a different way: sue TXU Energy is only one way and it simply sounds easier than it is done. Plus settling the matter most likely will come out of a backroom deals with one lawyer paid off by the other to lose your case.

Lets switch to another electric provider. Lets inform the community. Every time we go to a local store or gas station, tell everyone how dirty TXU Energy company is. If everyone switches, TXU cannot survive without your money.

 http://www.ripoffreport.com/utility-companies/texas-utility-txu/texas-utility-txu-ripoff-dou-dq66d.htm 

 http://www.ripoffreport.com/corrupt-companies/txu-energy/txu-energy-ripoff-dishonest-fr-j3eff.htm 

 http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/scam-billing-c48927.html#c234404 

 http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/rip-off-scam-billing-c139695.html 

 http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/scam-charges-c197999.html 

 http://www.complaintsboard.com/complaints/disruption-in-service-c206910.html 

 http://www.my3cents.com/showReview.cgi?id=57675 

KEYWORDS: txu ripoff, txu double billed, txu disconnect stories, txu scam billing, TXU Energy corrupt company, TXU Scam. Craig of Fort Worth, TX. 

 RSS 
 Read Our Policies Before Buying 
www.dfwFurnitureStore.com
Email: contact@dfwFurnitureStore.com
Copyright©2006 dfwFurnitureStore.com Used Furniture and Appliances etc.
used appliances for sale, washers dryers fort worth, appliance dealer dallas, used appliance stores.
 http://dallas.craigslist.org/ 
 http://www.apartmentfinder.com/
	</body>
</document>
