<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004786" url="http://www.stltoday.com/news/local/crime-and-courts/state-rethinking-safe-haven-law/article_5a2acd9f-d04e-50b9-b69e-e78687cbd205.html" time="2012-07-12-21:17" support="2" score="0.0010559783612820008" bingtitle="Missouri rethinking safe haven law" webtitle="Missouri rethinking safe haven law">
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="70"/>
	<description>... explained Debby Howland, a proponent of a bill ... in alleyways and behind a St. Charles County fast-food restaurant. ... Burwell: MU throws away tradition, serves youth ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Today&apos;s Post-Dispatch Suburban Journals St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal STLHighschoolsports Ladue News Feast ShopSTL Mobile 

 Login | Register | Subscriber Services 
 weather 
 Search 
 
 Search Stories Search Web Search Classifieds Search Local Directory 
 
 Missouri rethinking safe haven law 
 
 Home 
 Weather Obits Opinion Columns Traffic Lottery Multimedia Newsletters Apps Contests Archives Photo Reprints Chats E-Edition 
 News 
 Opinion Blogs Metro Illinois St. Charles Obits Nation Politics Crime Education Religion Galleries Videos Databases Forums 
 Business 
 Stock quotes St. Louis stocks Calendar Press releases Blogs Public Salaries Galleries Twitter 
 Sports 
 Cards Rams Blues Mizzou Illini SLU High School Golf Racing More sports Blogs Forums Galleries Videos Chats Timelines 
 Entertainment 
 Calendar Music Dining Movies Movie Times TV Arts Books Celebs Comics/Games Horoscopes Blogs Forums 
 Health 
 Live Well Golden Age Health Services Directory Health Calendar Medical Ads 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Food Feast Magazine Home&amp;Garden Health&amp;Fitness Fashion Travel Pets Moms and Dads Blogs Galleries Videos St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal 
 Suburban News 
 AFFTON CHESTERFIELD COLLINSVILLE EDWARDSVILLE GRANITE CITY O&apos;FALLON MO ST. CHARLES ST. PETERS WILDWOOD MORE TOWNS... BLOGGER NETWORK 
 Classifieds 
 Business Opportunities Notices Travel Tickets/Events Pets Estate Sales Garage/Yard Sales Bargain Box Merchandise Place an Ad 
 Find n Save 
 Get It Local Directory Coupons Newspaper Ads Circulars Special Sections P-D Store Today&apos;s Deal Today&apos;s Deal Blog 
 Homes 
 Place an Ad Search Homes Mortgage Guide Agent Directory Your Next Home New Home Folio What Did It Sell For 
 Autos 
 New Used Certified Research Services Dealer Specials Reviews 
 Jobs 
 Salary Wizard Cost of Living Wizard Post a Resume Search Jobs Employers Post a Job Work at the P-D or SJ 
 
 HOT TOPICS 
 ESPY AWARDS $500 GAS GIVEAWAY ALL-STAR CARDINALS WASHINGTON AVE. STL SPORTS TOP 10 JUNE&apos;S MUG SHOTS OLYMPICS 
 Home /  News /  Local /  Law&amp;Order 
Missouri rethinking safe haven law

Misunderstanding of current policy called a barrier for desperate
moms.
 Share | 
 Story Discussion Image 
 Missouri rethinking safe haven law 
 BY NANCY CAMBRIA • Nancy.Cambria@post-dispatch.com &gt; 314-340-8238 stltoday.com |Posted: Wednesday, March 14, 2012 12:05 am | ( Loading… ) comments. 
 Font Size: Default font size Larger font size Emily Rasinski 
Betty Crowder found a newborn baby early this morning wrapped in
a towel beneath this pine tree next to her home at 120 Westridge
Parc Lane in Ellisville on Thursday, Feb. 16, 2012. Photo by Emily
Rasinski, erasinski@post-dispatch.com
 
 Missouri&apos;s Safe Haven Law 

• Enacted in 2003 with the intention of preventing the criminal abandonment of newborns and infants that can lead to death.

• Enables those unable or unwilling to parent their children to safely relinquish custody at designated safe havens: hospitals, firehouses, EMS stations and law enforcement agencies.

• Gives immunity from prosecution to parents who use a safe haven within five days of birth.

• Gives parents of children older than 5 days but under 1 year the right to use a safe haven, but does not guarantee them immunity from prosecution.

• Child safety advocates want the 5-day-old window guaranteeing immunity from prosecution expanded to 45 days.

• All 50 states have some form of safe haven law.
 
On the same day a young mother was criminally charged last month with abandoning her new baby boy under a pine tree in Ellisville, lawmakers gathered in a Jefferson City hearing room to discuss better ways to prevent such a thing from happening.

&quot;The Ellisville baby was very much on our minds,&quot; explained Debby Howland, a proponent of a bill that would increase the scope of Missouri&apos;s existing Safe Haven Law and simplify its terms so mothers aren&apos;t afraid of using it.

Missouri&apos;s current law seeks to enable mothers to relinquish custody of a baby up to 5 days old at a designated safe haven, such as a hospital or firehouse, anonymously and without fear of prosecution. Proponents of the bill say that the window isn&apos;t long enough and want to expand it to 45 days — a national average for such laws. They also want to clarify questions over legal immunity and anonymity in the existing law that could discourage parents from placing an infant in a safe haven.

Howland, coordinator of the Kansas City Child Abuse Roundtable Coalition, testified on behalf of the proposed changes in the House Children and Families Committee on Feb. 28, the same day Kaitlin Norton, 19, was charged with child abandonment and child endangerment for allegedly leaving her newborn wrapped in a towel on an Ellisville lawn after giving birth. Bail was set at $40,000. If found guilty, Norton would face at least five years in prison before possible parole and could receive a maximum jail sentence of 15 years.

&quot;Had she only known there was a legal way to do the right thing,&quot; Howland said.

If Norton had left her child at a legal safe haven, she likely wouldn&apos;t be facing incarceration, and the baby&apos;s life wouldn&apos;t have been put at risk, Howland said.

After she was charged, Norton&apos;s lawyer told the Post-Dispatch his client panicked after delivering the baby Feb. 16 alone in the basement laundry room of her boyfriend&apos;s home. In behavior common to cases of infant abandonment, Norton had hidden the pregnancy.

About two hours after the birth, a nearby resident spotted the towel — and what she thought were abandoned puppies wrapped inside — and called police. The baby is now in custody of the Department of Social Services and is expected to be adopted.

 &apos;SIMPLE AS POSSIBLE&apos; 

It&apos;s unknown if Norton was aware of the Safe Haven Law. But advocates of the bill worry that even when desperate moms know of it, the law isn&apos;t clear enough about the limits of punishment or the use of police, and that may scare them away.

It&apos;s difficult to prove to police and doctors that a newborn is less than 6 days old during a drop-off, and that can lead to unwanted scrutiny by police and possible prosecution of the mother, said Suzie Girten, a maternal care nurse at St. Luke&apos;s Hospital in Kansas City.

The bill seeks to clarify standards by which the anonymity of the mother is kept and stipulates that the mother&apos;s identity cannot be demanded.

It also aims to simplify the prosecution issue.

Missouri&apos;s current law not only has a five-day window for using a safe haven after birth, but it also applies to mothers with babies less than a year old. Yet mothers who relinquish babies older than 5 days are not fully protected from prosecution for child abandonment. Instead, the current law entitles mothers to an &quot;affirmative defense&quot; — a legal term that requires the court to take into consideration that the mother put the safety of her child first in choosing to use a haven.

&quot;We realized very quickly that no one, including those working in safe havens, understood what affirmative defense even was,&quot; Howland said. &quot;The fact that we have had so much misunderstanding and misinterpretation has been a barrier to women using the law.&quot;

Nick Silverio, a national proponent of safe havens, said affirmative defense, though intended to encourage desperate mothers to use a safe haven, is an unintended deterrent. It can lead to dangerous child abandonment and should never be a part of such laws, he said.

In Florida, where Silverio is based, the state&apos;s Safe Haven Law further stipulates the babies go directly to private adoption agencies. This, said Silverio, keeps state child welfare investigators and police out of the dynamic. In Missouri, babies go into the custody of the Department of Social Services and foster care, where various court and legal entities take over.

&quot;The law needs to be as simple as possible,&quot; Silverio said, noting language that allows police inquiries or the sharing of the mother&apos;s information with various agencies will deter the use of safe havens.

&quot;What&apos;s the bottom line here for these laws? The bottom line is we&apos;re trying to save lives,&quot; he said.

The bill under consideration in Missouri originally eliminated the use of affirmative defense in exchange for increasing the window to use a safe haven to 45 days.

But at the urging of Rep. Jay Barnes, R-Jefferson City, a substitute version of the bill currently maintains an affirmative defense clause for mothers who relinquish babies age 45 days to one year. Barnes said he did not want to put additional babies at risk by limiting the law to just the 45-day window. The substitute bill is now with the House Rules Committee.

Rep. Kevin McManus, D-Kansas City, who sponsored the bill, said the substitute is a trade-off he can live with.

&quot;The five days was a very narrow window of time,&quot; he said. &quot;This allows us a wider window and at the same times gives added protections up to a year.&quot;

 TRAINING IS KEY 

Bill proponents argue Missouri&apos;s Safe Haven Law needed revision given several cases of newborn abandonment.

In three local cases, living newborns were found in trash bins in alleyways and behind a St. Charles County fast-food restaurant. Grass clippings, other refuse and even a sealed plastic trash bag were credited with keeping the babies insulated and alive.

But in other cases, abandoned babies did not beat the odds.

Child advocates in the Kansas City area first pushed to strengthen Missouri&apos;s Safe Haven Law in 2009 after a 25-year-old woman in nearby Overland Park, Kan., delivered her child alone and hid the baby girl in an unused refrigerator in her parents&apos; basement, where the baby died. A firehouse safe haven was just three blocks from the home. The incident led both states to review their laws, Howland said.

Safe havens have been used 31 times since 2005, according to statistics kept with the Missouri Department of Social Services. But a state spokesman cautioned that number could be higher because employees at safe havens don&apos;t always fill out state paperwork identifying the abandonment as such.

Indeed, Missouri, like many states, has not done a good job tracking the law&apos;s usage, nor has it properly trained safe haven workers in basic aspects of the law, said Girten, the Kansas City nurse. In most cases, it&apos;s unknown if mothers who used the havens went on to be outed or prosecuted.

Girten said even the best-crafted safe haven laws are ineffective without training and public awareness — which are lacking in Missouri.

After the baby died in Overland Park, advocates in the Kansas City area created billboard campaigns and signs to mark safe havens. They also developed training at safe havens for employees, everyone from emergency room nurses to cleaning staff. Girten also helped develop a safe haven Web page that enables employees to directly report a safe haven baby to the Department of Social Services to ensure that the baby is tallied.

Although typically a mother doesn&apos;t stick around to talk, Girten encourages safe haven workers to give her two things.

The first is a letter thanking her for making the brave decision to protect her child.

The second: a blank sheet of paper and a pen.

&quot;It&apos;s a great gift from Mom to write a letter to the baby,&quot; she said.

The bill is HB1568.
 
 Copyright 2012 stltoday.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Posted in Crime-and-courts , Parenting on Wednesday, March 14, 2012 12:05 am Updated: 6:51 am. | Tags: Safe Haven , Baby Abandonment , Affirmative Defense , Ellisville Mo , Missouri Legislature , Kaitlin Norton , Debby Howland , Suzie Girten , Rachel Storch , Hb1568 , Nick Silverio , Kevin Mcmanus , Jay Barnes ,
 
 Print Email 
 
Sponsored Links
 
most popular
 
 Facebook Most Read 
 
 Canadian chef Anthony Sedlak dies at age 29 Setting the record straight: Top 10 moments in St. Louis sports history St. Louis woman sentenced for performing sex acts on dog Trade talk surrounds San Diego closer Street 2 suspects still at large after St. Louis police kill man during home invasion Tony&apos;s twists keep Cards&apos; All-Stars on their toes Votto wants Cards, Reds to &apos;turn the page&apos; Woman from St. Louis area electrocuted while swimming at Lake of the Ozarks Gordon: One glaring need holds back Cardinals Young couple buys landmark Stuart Castle in Eureka Couple killed in motorcycle crash in St. Louis County identified Bernie Bytes: Cardinals midseason awards Will success kill Washington Avenue? 
 

 St. Louis Coupons: Get fantastic deals—up to 80% off—sent to your e-mail.
 Sign up today! PPG Porter Paints® Stores - Only $30 for $60 towards PPG Porter paints, stains, primers,&amp;more at PPG Porter Paints® Stores! 
Sections

 Home Page News Obituaries Business Sports Entertainment Health Life&amp;Style Photos Jobs Autos Homes Directory Classifieds 
 
Services

 Subscriber Services Advertise on Our Site Email Newsletters RSS E-Edition Mobile Site Events Calendar Newspapers in Education Archives Contact Us Terms of Service Privacy / About Our Ads Copyright Corrections 
 
 St. Louis Apartments St. Louis Attorneys St. Louis Auto Dealers St. Louis Auto Parts St. Louis Auto Repair St. Louis Beauty Salons St. Louis Car Rental St. Louis Dentists St. Louis Doctors St. Louis Flowers St. Louis Hotels St. Louis Insurance St. Louis Loans St. Louis Mortgages St. Louis Movers St. Louis Pizza St. Louis Realtors St. Louis Restaurants St. Louis Storage St. Louis Tax Preparation St. Louis Travel Featured More... 
 
Marketplace

 Local Directory The List Classifieds Jobs Rides STL Homes ShopSTL Newspaper Ads STL Coupons DineSTL Post-Dispatch Store STLshopper St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal 
 
STLtoday Network

 St. Louis Post-Dispatch Suburban Journals Ladue News St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal Feast Go! STL Health and Fitness STL Moms and Dads STL High School Sports MySTLtoday.com 
 
© Copyright 2012, stltoday.com , 900 N. Tucker Blvd. St. Louis, MO | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
