<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004842" url="http://www.lawknowledge.org/employment-labor-law/9175/" time="2012-07-12-21:21" support="2" score="0.002684272363570905" bingtitle="Employment &amp; Labor Law: Can en employer force direct deposit ..." webtitle="Employment&amp;Labor Law: Can en employer force direct deposit Washington - lawknowledge.org">
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="138"/>
	<description>can employers pay server wages for mandatory ... was fired/quit from her job in a &quot;healthy fast food&quot; restaurant ... First I had to wait for 3 weeks for my order but ...</description>
	<body>
		Home » LAW »
 Employment&amp;Labor Law (Employment,Labor Law) »Can en employer force direct deposit Washington

 Employment&amp;Labor Family Law Real Estate Immigration Criminal Bankruptcy&amp;Credit Traffic Lawyers Accidents 
 LAW Category Accidents&amp;Personal Injury Law Additional Legal Subjects BANKRUPTCY&amp;CONSUMER CREDIT BUSINESS&amp;FINANCIAL&amp;Corporate LAW Consumer Law&amp;Fraud COURTS, LAWYERS&amp;LITIGATION CRIMINAL LAW&amp;PROCEDURE Employment&amp;Labor Law Family Law Government&amp;Administrative Law Immigration Law Insurance Law Intellectual Property Real Estate&amp;Property Law Tax Law Traffic Law Wills&amp;Trusts 

 Reference 
 
Can en employer force direct deposit Washington
 Tags: deposit , direct , employer , employment , force , labor , law , protect , secure , washington My employer wants to force direct deposit. I am usually all for it, but she has no secure way to protect our data and as such I don&apos;t want to give her my bank #s.

What does WA law say??? Post my Comments Now 
 &quot; 
Employment&amp;Labor Law
 &quot; Open Questions Can Employers tell other Employees what your salary is? Minnesota Minnesota My manager disclosed my wages to other employees that I work with that has resulted in unwanted hostility from other employees. Can my manager do this? Do I have any privacy rights regarding that area?... Can employers require you to be on-call during your vacation? location: California company is requesting we carry laptop, pager, cell, etc.&quot;at all times&quot;and&quot;respond immediately&quot;to requests. if individuals are on vacation, is this mandate legal? the job description itself does not specify on-call support.... Can employers require you to be available during your vacation? location: California company is requesting we carry laptop, pager, cell, etc.&quot;at all times&quot;and&quot;respond immediately&quot;to requests. if individuals are on vacation, is this legal? the job description itself does not specify on-call support.... can employers pay server wages for mandatory meetings? I am a server at a diner. I was recently scheduled for a manatory staff meeting. The meeting lasted almost 2 hours. When I received my paycheck I noticed that I had not been paid for the meeting. I brought it to my boss&apos;s attention. He said I&apos;d be receiving my $6 in my next check. Obviously that...... can employers lower your pay (retaliation)? my mother has been working for a company for longer than 6 months and she was up for a review and got a raise. she&apos;s been getting paid this amount for a little over a month. one day she went to receive her pay, opened the envelope to read it, and some co-worker whore looked over her shoulder to...... Can employers hold a paycheck? What is the name of your state? Illinois
My daughter (19 years old) was fired/quit from her job in a&quot;healthy fast food&quot;restaurant last week. She took a $50 bill from a customer&amp;their policy is not to do such. Afterwards, the manager started yelling at her in front of both the...... Can Employers do this... Texas... I was injured on the job (hernia) and taken to the hospital by ambulance. It took three doctors including the company doctor two months to diagnose the problem. 
 I was scheduled for surgery in early January due to the holidays. My company does not have light-duty (this I was told in a...... Can Employers devulge employee salary details to non-employees? Alabama I would like to know what laws permit or prohibit employers from sharing salary information of employees with non-employee individuals such as customers. My employer shared my salary amount with a customer and says that there&apos;s nothing that prevents them (the employer) from doing so, yet I felt...... Can employers bash on you to make you quit? Massachusetts Hello,I quit my job roughly 7 weeks ago,the reason for my departure was&gt;due to an unhealthy work environment. I had been verbally abused by my&gt;project manager for about the last 6 months of my employmentevery morning i would get yelled at for no aparent reason,all because the person...... Can employers ask questions about sick days? What is the name of your state? CT
If a union employee takes a sick day that is granted and is in accordance with their contract can employers call your home and ask questions as to the nature of your illness or reason for taking the sick day? Can employers require a doctor&apos;s note to validate...... 
 
 Post a Comment Now. Comments Post a Comment Now. 

 Maybe you&apos;re interest in these... What is the name of your state?What is the name of... [ BANKRUPTCY&amp;CONSUMER CREDIT ] What is the name of your state?What is the name of your state?Texas Am being sued over a credit card debt that is about 4 years old. It was bought from the bank and now I am being sued by a collection attorney. I had by-pass operation about the time I started having problems with the finances. I......... Birth&amp;marriage certificate [ Immigration Law ] a-- Posted via http://britishexpats.com...... Another note to cbg [ Insurance Law ] Hi Cbg,
I&apos;m back again with another question. Remember I told you my husband&apos;s 12 weeks ended on Dec. 31st? Well, I just got a note from a friend saying,&quot;The law states you are entitled to 12 weeks FML per YEAR! So, as of Jan. 1st (the beginning of a new year), it seems to me your husband......... tickets, help. [ Traffic Law ] #1 Yesterday, 10:52 PM 
clearcutboy87 
Junior Member Join Date: Mar 2005
Posts: 1 
speeding/racing ticket, help please. 
--------------------------------------------------------------...... Can you will Parental rights to others? [ Wills&amp;Trusts ] What is the name of your state? Texas
If I die before my children are adults, can I transfer my parental rights to my father-in-law in a will? I know that I can not terminate my husbands rights, but can I give his father what would amount to joint custody of my children?...... what rights do I have? [ COURTS, LAWYERS&amp;LITIGATION ] What is the name of your state? MN
I am disabled and confined to a w/c. The state pays for a caregiver to come into my home each day and help me with personal cares, shopping/cooking, and helping to maintain a clean environment. 
The careprovider left my home to drive 3 blocks to the......... Where do we go from here/what do we need to expect? [ Accidents&amp;Personal Injury Law ] What is the name of your state? TN
I was sitting at a red light waiting to turn, when a truck ran a red light and was t-boned right into me, head on. I went to the doctor for some muscular pain done to my back as a result of the accident. The truck driver was at fault and his insurance adjuster......... Grocery store pricing question - Ontario, Canada [ Consumer Law&amp;Fraud ] I was wondering if anybody knew the law in Canada concerning grocery store pricing and specials. My specific question: I was at Sobey&apos;s today where I noticed that the bulk cashews were now&quot;on special&quot;for $8.99 a pound. The problem is that just last week they were regularly priced at......... FILING STATUS [ Tax Law ] MY HUSBAND PASSED AWAY IN JULY 2000. TO MY KNOWLEDGE HE HAD NOT FILED OUR 1999 TAXES. IF I FILE THEM NOW, DO I FILE AS A WIDOW OR A MARRIED PERSON?...... backing out of a contract [ BUSINESS&amp;FINANCIAL&amp;Corporate LAW ] What is the name of your state (only U.S. law)? Ohio
Can I back out of a contract before the effective date? The contract states that it becomes effective when signed by all parties and payment is received. Payment was received 1/26 by them. The current contract expires 1/30. This is a service......... 
 
 &quot;Employment&amp;Labor Law&quot; Headlines Can empolyer ask you to fill up sick or vaction form if you clock in late? California Can employor make you give up rights assigned by the Labor Code? CA can employers withold vacation pay from you? New Jersey Can employers take away vacation-KY can employers sue employees for this in nj ? Can employers keep part of the money from a tip pooling arrangement? Ohio Can employers garnish wages without a court order? Can employers force hourly employees to stay late? Massachusetts Can employers fine their employees can employers drop pay? 

 LAW Blogs Tax Types and Numeric Tax Codes (Virginia Department of Taxation) OVERTIME IS THE LAW! The Fiduciary Exception to the Attorney-Client Privilege -- Physician Sentenced for Private Health Insurance Fraud New Court Ruling Renders U.S. Anti-Subsidy Law Inapplicable to China Purchasing Workers&apos;Compensation Insurance (Pennsylvania) Workers&apos;Compensation&amp;the Injured Worker (Commonwealth of Pennsylvania) 2011 in Review: The Year Secrecy Jumped the Shark Israeli Firm Allot Communications Ltd Under Fire for Selling Spyware to Iran Election Law 

 &quot; Employment&amp;Labor Law &quot; Related Questions Can employers choose which FT employees get insurance in New Jersey My boyfriend works full-time for a non-profit in Jersey, and while other FT employees receive (intermittent) health insurance, they&apos;ve managed to delay granting him coverage for almost 5 months. Is this legal? They claim it&apos;s one of his benefits, but keep&quot;losing&quot;his paperwork and...... Can employers charge employees for losses of the usual type What is the name of your state (only U.S. law)? Michigan
At our recent meeting we were informed that the employers (a 6 doctor private practice) wil lbe charging the individual employee(s) that did NOT collect the co-pay from the patient at the time of&quot;check in&quot;.
Co-pays range...... can employers charge employees for drawers shortages in PA? Can employers charge their employees for drawer shortages in PA?... can employers change Holiday Schedule midyear? What is the name of your state? CA
all employees were emailed a 2006 Holiday Schedule at the beginning of the year. It included 9 holidays. This week they revised it and we only have 4. Can they do that? One of the holidays they reneged on is President&apos;s Day which is only 5 days away. If I&apos;ve...... can employers be selective on employees who get 15 min breaks Florida im new to this forum:p but i UNDERSTAND! that an employer ISNT:cool: required to give 15min unless the agree under specific conditions they (employer) agrees to (in FLORIDA) but if an emplorer ALLOWS a&quot;15 min break&quot;to one of the employees:eek: isnt the other employee(s) allowed one...... Can employers ask these kind of questions? What is the name of your state?Colorado
I went to an inerview and it started out pretty good until the employer asked me if I had any disabilities, then she asked if I had any disorders that can make me ill. She also asked if I had any kids. 
After answering the questions she told me to call...... Can employers ask about pending charges at an interview? What is the name of your state (only U.S. law)? New York
I was recently asked at an interview if I have any pending charges? Which I do, but I said no. I haven&apos;t yet been to court for my DWI. 
They are running a background check on me. Would that show up in a background check? Can they access...... Can Employer withold expense reimbursement for late reporting? Texas I filed my expense reports late due to personal issues with my divorce and my employer refuses to reimburse expenses that came out of my pocket claiming they were filed late and company policy does not allow them to pay. This is costing me $6k out of pocket. Do I have any recourse?... Can employer withhold pay for damages... Nevada I recently quit my job with a no call no show. I was the opening supervisor and did not notify the owner that I was quitting. Once I got back from my trip (about two weeks later), I came back to pick up my final paycheck. The owner refused stating that there where damanges because they had to...... Can Employer Withhold Final Paycheck New Jersey Hi Guys, I&apos;m new here so hope this is in the correct forum. Here&apos;s my situation. I worked for an employer whose office is in New Jersey. My employer contracted me out to a company in Bellevue, Washington where I worked for 6 months. When I first joined my employer I signed a contract which meant...... Can Employer Withhold Expense Reimbursement until certain Paperwork is done? Wisconsin I frequently travel out of state for my job. I am provided a credit card, but there are still some expenses that I pay for in cash, that I am out of pocket. When I return from my trip I am required to write a report on the visit. Sometimes I get many weeks behind. Can my employer withhold my...... Can Employer waive vacation policy Illinois Can an employer waive the requirement of losing your vacation in a given year? In other words, if an employee asks to carry forward 5 days into 2007 and terminates his employement in January. Is the employer obligated to pay for the 5 days if there is documented that supervisor approved the...... Can Employer use arrest when making employment decesions What is the name of your state? OHIO
I was fasley arrested in June 2004 for Importuning. This arrest went to the grand jury who issued a no bill, no indictment, the charges were dropped.
I have been working for a school system as a consultant and they wish to hire me full time, a position will...... can employer terminate you when you are on long-term disability? I live in the state of California. I was diagnosed with cancer last year and currently under long-term disability (partly) until the end of the month (I work part-time and the other part is disability). I feel that I need to extend my part disability and work part time. However, I am afraid that...... Can employer terminate without any notice ? What is the name of your state? MI 
My employer company (a software service provider) has NOT sent me any notice by email/letter, still they wants to stop my employment&amp;not paying my salary for the 2-weeks (as 2-weeks notice was written in my employment letter)&amp;also denying my...... Can employer tell me who I can/cannot socialize with? What is the name of your state? Iowa
I am working on a project for the state. I am a contractor - there are 9 contractors working on the project. I have developed a friendship with a couple of the other contractors and my boss and another&quot;senior&quot;member of my company told me to...... 
 
 lawknowledge.org is one of your best friends, we&apos;ll greah appreciate if you tell us what&apos;s you want to know and pinpoint the weakness of us. Function Links: Content Directory Latest Questions Popular Tags Free to Join us Map.XML Find To us: About us Advertise Contact DMCA Help/Faqs Links Privacy Terms of Use ©2001-2012 lawknowledge.org, LLC. All rights reserved. lawknowledge.org does not provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. Application: 390.63 ms
	</body>
</document>
