<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004623" url="http://www.franchise.com/fast-food-restaurant/candy.cfm" time="2012-07-12-21:07" support="1" score="0.007866537985968142" bingtitle="Candy Franchises for Sale, Food Franchises Candy Franchise ..." webtitle="Candy Franchises for Sale, Food Franchises Candy Franchise Opportunities">
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Start a Food Franchises Candy franchise or business with the help of our franchise directory. Find the right franchise for sale or business opportunity for you to buy.</description>
	<body>
		Directory of Franchise Opportunities&amp;Business Franchises for Sale

 franchises 
 Subway Franchise For Sale 7-Eleven, Inc. Kona Ice Franchise For Sale Visiting Angels Coverall Health-Based Cleaning System Little Caesars Enterprises Nestlé Toll House Café by Chip West Sanitation Home Helpers Franchise For Sale Fast-Teks Franchise For Sale 
    |    franchises by state 
 Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
    |    advertise with us    |    site map 
    |        Email Us Find Your Franchise: Select Category Automotive Franchises Beauty Franchises Beverages Franchises Business Opportunities Business Services Children Related Cleaning&amp;Maintenance Computer&amp;Internet Earth Friendly Education Franchises Financial Services Food Franchises Health&amp;Fitness Home Related Low Investment Master/Area Developers Minority Focused Pet Related Photo&amp;Video Printing Packing&amp;Shipping Retail Franchises SBA Approved Senior Services Sports and Recreation Travel Franchises Veterans Franchises Women&apos;s Franchises Work From Home Select Location Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington Washington DC West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Canada US Territories Not USA or Canada 
   Franchises by Category 
 Automotive Franchises 
 Beauty Franchises 
 Beverages Franchises 
 Business Opportunities 
 Business Services 
 Children Related 
 Cleaning&amp;Maintenance 
 Computer&amp;Internet 
 Earth Friendly 
 Education Franchises 
 Financial Services 
 Food Franchises 
 Health&amp;Fitness 
 Home Related 
 Low Investment 
 Master/Area Developers 
 Minority Focused 
 Pet Related 
 Photo&amp;Video 
 Printing Packing&amp;Shipping 
 Retail Franchises 
 SBA Approved 
 Senior Services 
 Sports and Recreation 
 Travel Franchises 
 Veterans Franchises 
 Women&apos;s Franchises 
 Work From Home 
 VIEW ALL 
 

 Franchise Directory 

 Top 25 Franchises 

 Big Opportunities 
 Home  &gt;  Franchise Categories  &gt;  Food Franchises  &gt; Candy Food Franchises - Candy Franchises&amp;Business Opportunities 

 Looking for other food franchises franchises? Narrow your search: 
 Hamburger  |  BBQ  |  Ice Cream/Frozen Yogurt  |  Fast Food  |  Soup&amp;Salad  |  Chicken  |  Sandwich Delis  |  Wraps  |  Candy  |  Seafood  |  Pizza  |  Wings  |  Breakfast, Donuts&amp;Bagels Interested in selling a product that everyone enjoys? Consider buying a candy franchise within the food industry. From retail opportunities to vending machine companies, these franchises offer entrepreneurs a way to start their own business with an established business model. Businesses for sale will provide you with products, training and support. Explore the wide variety of franchises and business opportunities for sale in this category by clicking on the links below and remember to inquire to multiple opportunities to learn which business is right for you. Sort by: Company Name Cash Required 1. YoFresh 
 Cash Required $50,000 
Enter the growing natural food industry with a YoFresh franchise and never pay royalty fees. Other opportunities in the Food Franchises industry 
 1. Happy&apos;s Pizza 
 Cash Required $150,000 
Capitalize on the popular fast casual dining and pizza industries when you own a Happy&apos;s Pizza franchise. 2. Wings Etc. 
 Cash Required $150,000 
Serve the best wings in the booming food service industry and enjoy a built-in fan base when you own a Wings, Etc. Restaurant&amp;Pub. 3. GoWaiter Inc 
 Cash Required $20,000 - $50,000 
Own a unique, high-demand business opportunity that provides consumers a much needed service. No experience needed. 4. Little Caesars Enterprises 
 Cash Required $50,000 
Little Caesars is growing in prime markets across the country, and offers franchisee candidates an opportunity for independence with a proven system. 5. Sobik&apos;s Subs Franchising 
 Cash Required $35,000 
No experience needed to own a Sobik&apos;s Subs franchise for as little as $59K. Capitalize on Sobik&apos;s more than 40 years of experience in the submarine sandwich shop industry. 6. Nestlé Toll House Café by Chip 
 Cash Required $100,000 
Nestlé Toll House Café by Chip is the only major, national dessert café that features top-quality branded cookies, baked goods, coffee, ice cream and smoothies. Nestlé products offer strong brand reco... 7. Saladworks 
 Cash Required $75,000 - $200,000 
Own the Nation&apos;s #1 Salad Franchise and provide a fully customizable and calorie conscious menu as an alternative food offering for people on the go in your preferred geography. 8. Coffee Beanery 
 Cash Required $50,000 - $150,000 
Coffee may be common, but should never be ordinary! At the Coffee Beanery, we&apos;re providing opportunities in one of the fastest growing franchise markets today. The Speciality Coffee Industry! Domes... Opportunities You Should Know About: MAACO Collision Repair and Auto Painting 
 
Join the world&apos;s leading collision repair&amp;automotive painting franchise. Benefit from our brand recognition and time-tested, turnkey system.
 Paul Davis 
 
No experience is needed to join the leader in the $60 billion insurance restoration industry.
 Top Food Franchises Businesses 
 Doc Popcorn 
 

Type: Food&amp;Beverage
Financial Assistance: 3rd Party
 
 Learn More 
 Saladworks 
 

Type: Soup&amp;Salad
Financial Assistance: 3rd Party
 
 Learn More 
 Souper Salad 
 

Type: Soup&amp;Salad
Financial Assistance: 3rd Party
 
 Learn More 
 Happy&apos;s Pizza 
 

Type: Pizza
Financial Assistance: 3rd Party
 
 Learn More 
 Nestlé Toll House Café by Chip 
 

Type: Coffee
Financial Assistance: 3rd Party
 
 Learn More Are you outside of the United States and interested in owning a franchise? International Franchise Services can help: 

IFS helps match franchise candidates with US based franchisors in over 35 countries across the world.

 Learn more  »
   LEARN ABOUT FRANCHISING 
 Franchise Business Glossary 
 Franchise Articles 
 Finance&amp;Start a Small Business 
 New Franchises For Sale TOOLS AND RESOURCES 
 Business&amp;Franchising Events 
 Franchisee Testimonials 
 Net Worth Calculator 
 Franchise FAQ&apos;s COMPANY INFORMATION 
 About Franchise.com 
 Advertise With Us 
 Privacy Statement 
 Franchise Blog Franchise.com Home    Disclaimer    Site Map    Contact Us Copyright 1995-2012 Franchise.com
	</body>
</document>
