<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004895" url="http://www.foodfranchise.com/fooddailyspecials.asp" time="2012-07-12-21:24" support="4" score="0.006620266900525143" bingtitle="The Online Resource for Food Franchises" webtitle="The Online Resource for Food Franchises">
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="42"/>
	<description>Food Franchise provides a comprehensive directory for the food industry entrepreneur. ... Just click on any of the banners below to receive more information about that ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Hottest Concepts Quick Submit Resources Subscribe to Updates Advertise With Us 
 
 

 
 
 
 Restaurant Picker 
 Pick an investment range...
Pick a sector...
Pick a state... 
We&apos;ll find the franchise that matches your requirements. 
 
 Select Industry Baked Goods Bar-B-Q Beverage Candy/ Snacks Chicken Coffee Deli/ Sandwiches Fast Food/ Take-out Fish/ Seafood Fresh Juice and Smoothies Full Service Restaurants Gourmet Hamburger Hot Dogs and Sausages Ice Cream/ Frozen Treats Mexican Pizza Soups / Salads Vegetarian Vending 
 - or / and - 
 Select Investment All Levels $25K or Less $25K - $50K $50K - $100K $100K + 
 - or / and - 
 Select State Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
 
 
 Categories 
 
 Baked Goods Bar-B-Q Beverage Candy/ Snacks Chicken Coffee Deli/ Sandwiches Fast Food/ Take-out Fish/ Seafood Fresh Juice and Smoothies Full Service Restaurants Gourmet Hamburger Hot Dogs and Sausages Ice Cream/ Frozen Treats Mexican Pizza Soups / Salads Vegetarian Vending 
 
 
 Featured Franchise 
 
 
 
 IFA 

 
 
 
 
 Hottest Concepts 
 

Daily Specials

Welcome to our Daily Specials page. This is where Food Franchise proudly spotlights many fine franchise companies and their individual concepts. Their inclusion in this section is an additional listing, as they are also found by sector within the Franchise Server and can be found as you inquire within the Investment Range pages.

Just click on any of the banners below to receive more information about that particular franchise. Good luck with your search!

 

 
 
 
 

 Home | About Us | Contact Us | Quick Submit | Hottest Concepts | Franchise News 
 Site Map | Privacy Policy and Website Usage Policy | Advertising 
 
 
All images, text and code©1999 - 2012 FoodFranchise.com, LLC. All Rights Reserved.
phone: 888.363.3390
	</body>
</document>
