<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004834" url="http://eveydog.livejournal.com/" time="2012-07-12-21:21" support="4" score="0.00441227342366607" bingtitle="eveydog" webtitle="eveydog">
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="60"/>
	<description>Favorite fast food restaurant? whatever ones have ... Which store would you choose to max out your credit card? i&apos;m not allowed ... Leave a comment</description>
	<body>
		LiveJournal Remember Me 
 Forgot your password? 
 
 
 Open ID Google Mail.ru VKontakte 
 

 Create an Account 
 
You are viewing eveydog &apos;s journal
 
 
eveydog

Recent Entries
 
 Recent Entries Archive Friends User Info 

 Previous 
 
You are viewing the most recent 10 entries
 
April 27th, 2006
 04:36 pm : hey 
 

 Leave a comment 
November 9th, 2005
 03:44 pm : this is so you know me

1. What time did you get up this morning? many times
2. Diamonds or pearls? i like my collar
3. What was the last film you saw at the cinema? um. sometimes i eat stuff from the trash
4. What is your favorite TV show? the one with urkel
5. What did you have for breakfast? brown stuff from my plate
6. What is your middle name? whats middle?
7. What is your favorite cuisine? i like to go outside
8. What foods do you dislike? hmmmm... new foods when i&apos;m starving
9. What is your favorite chip?ooh those rawhidey ones
10. What is your favorite CD at the moment? food can says c/d on it
11. What kind of car do you drive? i&apos;m too short for that
12. What is your favorite sandwich?all of them
13. What characteristics do you despise?um... if you try to take my bone or chip
14. Favorite item of clothing? brown jewelery collar
15. If you could go anywhere in the world on vacation, where would you
go?outside more
16. What color is your bathroom?the color of the whole world
17. Favorite brand of clothing? i like to watch dog tv... its outside the front window
19. Favorite time of day?breakfast and dinner and snack time
20. Where were you born?my mommy
21. Favorite sport to watch?cats being dumb
22. Who do you least expect to do this? me
23. Person you expect to do it first? O.P.A.L.
24. What type of detergent do you use?for what
25. Coke or Pepsi? does it have ice? i like ice!
26. Are you a morning person or night owl?i sleep whenever
27. What size shoe do you wear?paws dont need shoes
28. Do you have pets?theres a cat next door that comes in my yard. his name is smooch.
29. Any new and exciting news you&apos;d like to share with everyone? i&apos;m hungry
30. What did you want to be when you were little? me
31. Favorite Candy Bar?all of them
32. What is your best childhood memory?the first time i woke up and i lived with mommy ad kathleen
33. What are 3 different jobs you have had in your life? just a regular dogt
34 What color underwear are you wearing? ha!
35. Nicknames? too many
36. Piercing? i have a piercing stare with im begging
37. Eye color? dark brown
38. Ever been to Africa? ive been to petsmart
39. Ever been toilet papered? i like to eat that
40. Love someone so much it made you cry? i dont like crying
41. Been in a car accident?whats that
42. Croutons or bacon bits? yes
43. Favorite day of the week?there are different days?
44.Favorite restaurant?leftovers
45. Favorite flower?rye grass for my tummy
46. Favorite ice cream?ICE CREAM
48. Favorite fast food restaurant? whatever ones have wroappers i can lick
49. What color is your bedroom carpet?the house floor color
50. How many times did you fail your driver&apos;s test? i said im too short for that
51. From whom did you get your last e-mail?i think i am too short for that too
52. Which store would you choose to max out your credit card? i&apos;m not allowed
53. What do you do most often when you are bored?get into the trash
55. Who are you most curious about their responses to this
questionnaire? everyone!
56. Last person you ate out with?i always eat in
57. Ford or Chevy? pedigree
58. What are you listening to right now? noises
61. How many tattoos do you have? one. it says evie on my thigh. its spelled wrong
62. Which came first, the chicken or the egg? um. id eat chicken first
63. Time you finished this?dinnertime?

 Leave a comment 
October 14th, 2005
 11:26 am : me 
here is me. i like to have my picture taken. i dont like to look like i like it. i like to look away. or look at kathleen like i despise her.

 

 

 

 

 

 

i&apos;m still busy being bad. i think i know how to get in this new trash can that steve and sissy bought.

the lady next door says that orange cat&apos;s name is smooch. and the greyandwhite one is called boo... what dumb names. they dont have people names like me. that is why dogs are better than cats. and smarter.

cats arent smart enough to like trash either.

 Current Mood: wanting trash Leave a comment 
October 6th, 2005
 06:27 pm : i have a new orange friend who likes to run with me. well, more like in front of me. as i chase it. i love cats! see how they run!

 Leave a comment 
September 25th, 2005
 11:55 pm : Grrr 
Lately no one understands my needs. I love trash. Is that so wrong? The tall ones keep putting it up higher, but just wait till they leave tomorrow morning! So this morning when I was outside this boy doggy was growling through the fence at me, like I was up in his business.. I justed wanted to be friends, but he didn&apos;t seem too neighborly. I&apos;ve been keeping an eye out for the kitties hanging out lately, I&apos;m letting them do their thing, acting like I don&apos;t seem them, but I&apos;m just waiting for the right moment...! I&apos;m so tired, I was they&apos;d go to bed. My favorite spot is right where their legs go :)

 Current Mood: mischievous Leave a comment 
September 18th, 2005
 05:41 pm : grrr. 
i don&apos;t know why that tall guy andrew thinks i&apos;m ever going to listen to him. he doesn&apos;t know how to share his food!

 Leave a comment 
September 1st, 2005
 10:47 pm : garlic bread 
um. kathleen caught me rummaging in the trash... well, i wasnt still in the trash, i was sneaking off with this great empty box that used to have garlic bread in it... she took it away from me. how could she?

 

 Current Mood: i sleep all day Current Music: everybody being loud Leave a comment 
August 13th, 2005
 08:04 pm : (sigh). 
steve went away.

i hope he&apos;s coming back.

i miss him.

(sigh.)

i need a nap.

 1 comment | Leave a comment 
August 3rd, 2005
 08:59 pm : hey! hey you up there! 
i can smell the food on the counter!

you should give it to me!

there&apos;s something else i was thinking about, too...

you should give me that food!

oh, and cut out that loud booming outside. scary.

i need a nap.

 Leave a comment 
June 22nd, 2005
 03:21 pm : things i do to relax... like my sister said to write about

lay on the coffee table

watch out the window

lie in the sun on mommys bed

drink ice water that mommy leaves out for me

making gnome cities really helps me relax... its true

 Current Mood: creative Current Music: crocodile rock 16 comments | Leave a comment Powered by LiveJournal.com
	</body>
</document>
