<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004642" url="http://www.goodfood.sg/halal_muslim/restaurants" time="2012-07-12-21:08" support="3" score="0.004668441866557637" bingtitle="Halal Restaurants and Fastfood Outlets (Updated ! Sep 2007) in ..." webtitle="Halal Restaurants and Fastfood Outlets (Updated ! Sep 2007) in Singapore Food Guide&amp;Restaurant Directory :: GoodFood.SG (BETA)">
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>How has the 2% increase in GST (July&apos;07) affected your dining/food bills ?: ... Looking for home-delivery fastfood orders ? Check out the list of delivery ...</description>
	<body>
		GoodFood.SG (BETA) 
 Singapore Food Guide&amp;Restaurant Directory Categories | Places | Forum 

 

 
Today&apos;s Menu
 
 About Categories and Dishes Contact FAQ Forum Locations and Places News Polls Restaurants 
 
User login
 Username: * Password: * 
 Request new password 
 
Search
 

 
Poll
 How has the 2% increase in GST (July&apos;07) affected your dining/food bills ?: Still the same / no change Still the same, but portions are smaller ! Prices are up about 2% as well Prices have gone up by more than 2% ! 
Feed me !
 
 
 

 Similai ?! (What&apos;re these ?) Halal ? Home 
Halal Restaurants and Fastfood Outlets (Updated ! Sep 2007)
 
Halal Eateries By Zones
Click on the different parts of the Singapore map below to see the listings for that Zone. 
 
 City Central City East City North City West 
 
 Central Singapore Eastern Singapore Northern Singapore North-eastern Singapore North-western Singapore Western Singapore 
 

Some of Singapore&apos;s restaurant, fast food and cafe chains have recognized the Muslim community&apos;s desire for halal versions of popular foods including contemporary international cuisine, Chinese zhi-char, seafood and even Korean food. Over the years, some formerly non-halal chains have converted to be halal eateries and have not looked back since.

Today, there is no lack of halal eating places in Singapore. However finding one suitable for the occasion can be daunting, and even more so when you are in a hurry and need to find the nearest restaurant in the vicinity. For this reason, GoodFood.SG has compiled a list of air-conditioned halal eateries geo-organized by zones.

For outings and having a lunch or dinner with a group of friends, an air-conditioned setting makes it more comfortable and easier to have a conversation without too much of a sweat over your spicy food.

Whereas the ubiquitous McDonald&apos;s and Burger King can be found just around every corner, the more upmarket Breeks and Delifrance chains serve up a wider choice of western selections than the usual burger sandwich and fries.

For Korean barbeque hotplate and steamboat soups, we have Seoul Garden with their halal buffets and Zingdo for their kimchi and ramen. Thai food-lovers can turn to Siam Kitchen with their restaurants in many of the shopping malls around the island. Closer to home, we have Casa Bom Vento in Joo Chiat for halal Peranakan/Eurasian dishes and Sakunthala&apos;s Restaurant provides Indian thosai in Little India&apos;s Dunlop Street (see our main Halal-Muslim section for these last two restaurants).

 [Go to All Restaurants Directory ][ Back to Halal Food main page ] 
 login to post comments | email this page 
Hmmm .... del.icio.us !
 
Delivery Hotlines
 Looking for home-delivery fastfood orders ? Check out the list of delivery telephone number hotlines . 
Categories I (Common)
 24hrs 
 Ah Balling 
 Bak Chor Mee 
 Bak Kut Teh 
 Beef Kway Teow 
 Cakes and Pastries 
 Carrot Cake 
 Char Kway Teow 
 Cheng Tng 
 Chicken Rice 
 Chwee Kueh 
 Claypot Rice 
 Crab 
 Curry Rice 
 Dessert 
 Dim Sum 
 Duck Rice 
 Fishball Noodles 
 Fried Oyster Omelette 
 Hainanese 
 Halal-Muslim 
 Hokkien 
 Hokkien Mee 
 Ice Kachang 
 Indian 
 Indonesian 
 International 
 Kway Chap 
 Laksa 
 Lor Mee 
 Malay 
 Mutton Soup (Chinese) 
 Mutton Soup (Indian Muslim) 
 Nasi Lemak (Halal Malay) 
 Ngor Hiang (Five Spices) 
 Noodles 
 Peranakan Nonya 
 Pig Organ Soup 
 Popiah 
 Porridge 
 Prawn Mee/Noodles 
 Roast Meat (Chinese) 
 Rojak (Chinese) 
 Roti Prata 
 Sarabat 
 Satay 
 Seafood 
 Seafood (BBQ) 
 Soon Kueh 
 Soups 
 Steamboat 
 Tau Kwa 
 Teh Tarik 
 Teochew 
 Teochew Kueh 
 Vegetarian 
 Vegetarian (Chinese) 
 Vegetarian (Indian) 
 Wanton Mee 
 Western Food 
 Yong Tau Foo 
 Zhi Char 
 
Zones
 City-Central 
 City-East 
 City-North 
 City-West 
 West 
 Northwest 
 Central 
 North 
 Northeast 
 East 
 
Areas
 Geylang 
 Toa Payoh 
 Ang Mo Kio 
 Bukit Merah (Redhill) 
 Joo Chiat / Katong 
 Little India / Jalan Besar 
 
Did you know ...
 
...that you&apos;ll get to access many more categories of foods and dishes when you register and sign-on as a user ? Sign up today. Our privacy policy assures you of our commitment to your safe and spam-free surfing experience.
 
 
 Daily
Food
Photo    Best barbequed with
 
 Site Map | Terms of Use | Privacy | About | Contact 
Copyright©2006 www.goodfood.sg. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
