<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004561" url="http://www.funtrivia.com/quizzes/for_children/topics_for_kids/food_for_kids.html" time="2012-07-12-20:58" support="7" score="0.015342114189344353" bingtitle="Food for Kids Quizzes and Food for Kids Trivia -- Fun Trivia" webtitle="Food for Kids Quizzes and Food for Kids Trivia -- Fun Trivia">
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000044" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>People eat different types of food in different countries. I will give a menu and some hints at what is on the table from a country and you choose which country you are in.</description>
	<body>
		Fun Trivia | Quizzes | Games | People | Services | Help | Me 
   Register - Log In 
 

 

 
Quizzes - Food for Kids
 Fun 
Trivia : Quizzes : For Children : Topics for Kids : Food for Kids 


 New Random 

 

 

 

 Editors: NatalieW, 
agony, 
looney_tunes Quiz Search: 

 

 
 1 Fruit, Fruit Everywhere! 

 Fruit keeps us nice and healthy. We can find fruit everywhere from songs to up in trees. Enjoy! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q jonnowales
Aug 18 07
11307 plays 2 Food Cuisines for Kids 

 This quiz is about different types of foods from a lot of different countries. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q zh1322 
Jul 29 04
13338 plays 3 It&apos;s Time For a Fruit Rhyme 

 Fruit is really good, and is often sweet, and fruit is something we all should eat. So let&apos;s see what you know, and off to the fruit market we will go! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q beergirllaura 
Nov 01 09
2757 plays 4 Let Me Eat Cake 

 Let&apos;s explore some of the yummy cakes that can treat your taste buds. 
 Average 
10 Q looney_tunes 
May 02 12
2706 plays 5 Fruit for Kids! 

 This quiz is meant for children. There are lots of names for fruits on this page. Have you tried all of these fruits? 
 Very Easy 
10 Q thejazzkickazz 
Feb 19 00
24972 plays 6 What is Mommy Making? 

 Watching our parents make food is fun. Sometimes we say &quot;Yummy, I want some more&quot; or &quot;Ew, I don&apos;t like that&quot;. Think about the foods and if you like them while answering these questions. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q rebapitt
Jun 21 06
13206 plays 7 What did I grow? 

 Just a little quiz about what I grew in the garden this year and what the different colors were. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q spokanemikel
Dec 10 08
3471 plays 8 Guess the Food 

 Hello! Just try to guess what food is being described! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q happyfeet1
Jul 27 07
8694 plays 9 Don&apos;t Spill the Beans 

 Not all beans are the same. There are some beans you won&apos;t find in the fruit and vegetable section at the supermarket. And, there are some beans that are actually fun! 
 Easy 
10 Q beergirllaura 
Oct 22 09
1536 plays 10 The Life of a Blender 

 The name&apos;s Durr. Blynn Durr. I am a blender. Join me as I make some refreshing beverages. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q salami_swami 
Mar 31 09
2052 plays 11 Easy Cooking for Kids 

 Like to help your parent in the kitchen? Here is a quiz for you. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q ashling
Nov 20 03
10464 plays 12 Food that&apos;s good for you! 

 Here are some questions about food that is good for you! 
 Easy 
10 Q blacrosse
May 24 07
7110 plays 13 Yummy Ballpark Foods For Kids! 

 Take me out to the ballgame and get me lots of food! I&apos;ll describe a ballpark food and you tell me the name of the food I&apos;m describing. Let&apos;s go to the ballpark! (Note: questions are US-specific.) 
 Very Easy 
10 Q baseball2k8
Apr 30 07
7215 plays 14 All About Fruits 

 This is my first quiz so please rate it and tell me how you like it.
Shut your eyes and think of fruit: what color, what shape, what taste? Beats me! It&apos;s your job to discover about fruits in this quiz! 
 Easy 
10 Q Jessie4646a
Aug 10 07
5283 plays 15 Restaurant Hopping 

 People eat different types of food in different countries. I will give a menu and some hints at what is on the table from a country and you choose which country you are in. 
 Easy 
10 Q Auszev 
Jan 31 05
6783 plays 16 Kids&apos; Kitchen 

 This easy little quiz is about those yummy snacks we love. Give this quiz a try and have some fun. Good luck! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q califredrose
Jan 23 01
15525 plays 17 Yummy Breakfast Foods For Kids! 

 This is the second quiz of my series &quot;Yummy Foods for Kids!&quot;. This time I&apos;m trying to figure out what&apos;s for the most important meal of the day-breakfast! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q baseball2k8
Jun 01 07
6465 plays 18 What&apos;s for Lunch? 

 Childhood smells are great memories - can you guess what&apos;s for lunch? 
 Very Easy 
10 Q SweetypieNC
Aug 05 10
1485 plays 19 Rising to the Occasion, at the Very Yeast 

 Bread Making 101 - fun for children and adults and the results are scrumptious. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q mlcmlc 
Jan 31 11
738 plays 20 Mmm! Fun Foods and Drinks! 

 Hey, young trivia fans! What is the treat I am talking about? 
 Very Easy 
10 Q Arr0w
Dec 08 02
13266 plays 21 What&apos;s for Breakfast 

 Breakfast can get the day started off to a great start. See how many of these breakfast dishes you can identify. 
 Very Easy 
10 Q SweetypieNC
Jul 25 10
1419 plays 22 Eat your vegetables 

 We&apos;ve been told all our lives to &quot;Eat your vegetables,&quot; how many can you recognize? 
 Very Easy 
10 Q SweetypieNC
Jul 25 10
1482 plays 23 Food From Europe 

 Many food dishes are associated with a specific country. Nowadays these meals are eaten all over the world. Match the food and the country. 
 Easy 
5 Q minch 
Jul 01 00
10848 plays 24 Food Groups For Kids! 

 It is important to know what foods are in which groups so you can learn to eat healthy! Good luck! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q bsblover4
Jun 06 02
11721 plays 25 Traditional Dishes 

 An easy quiz for children about which dishes come from which country. 
 Easy 
10 Q georgia91
Jan 21 07
5349 plays 26 Know Your Roots! 

 All of these vegetables grow underground. Some really are roots, others are just pretending. Let&apos;s dig up the garden and see what we can find! 
 Average 
10 Q Flamis
Feb 26 10
1326 plays 27 On Top of the US Food Pyramid 

 This is a quiz to see just how much you know about the US food pyramid. It contains how many servings in each section and you must put the food in the correct group. Have fun! 
 Average 
10 Q holland5361
Jul 14 07
3285 plays 28 Which food is the odd one out? 

 I will give you four choices. You need to pick the one that does not belong. Godd luck and have fun! 
 Very Easy 
10 Q meister88 
Jan 20 11
1491 plays 29 Kids&apos; Simple Cooking Ingredients 

 This is a really easy quiz, meant for kids. It&apos;s about ordinary cooking ingredients found in most kitchens. 
 Easy 
10 Q Fi B
Jan 10 03
9558 plays 30 Food, Glorious Food 

 This quiz, for young children, is about food found in traditional nursery rhymes and stories. UK versions and spelling. 
 Average 
10 Q lilyalli
Aug 16 09
1944 plays 
 

 Goto page: 1 2 
This is category 4522
Last Updated Jul 04 12 6:22 AM 

 
 Some sample questions from this category: 
* This is a long yellow fruit. Monkeys love to eat them!
* This is a red, delicious fruit. One a day will keep the doctor away!
* Some people call this red fruit a vegetable, but it&apos;s really a fruit...and very juicy!
* Which of these fruits is not considered a citrus fruit?
* This fruit comes in bunches, and is most commonly red, purple or green.
 

 
 = highest rated quizzes = 
added recently = has extra info for each 
qn
 = Editor&apos;s Pick = FunTrivia Editor = Gold Member 
  · All content on this website is copyright 
FunTrivia.com, 1997 - 2010.
 · You may not copy, reprint, publish or use any of our content without prior written consent.
 · By using FunTrivia.com you agree 
to our Terms and Conditions
	</body>
</document>
