<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004325" url="http://www.marijuana.com/threads/whats-you-fav-things-to-eat-drink-and-do-while-stoned.256596/" time="2012-07-12-20:34" support="1" score="0.0005002876935856858" bingtitle="Whats you fav things to eat , drink and do while stoned ..." webtitle="Whats you fav things to eat , drink and do while stoned ?? | Marijuana.com">
			<query id="000249" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>fun things to do/drink while high, dynasty warriors and weed, beat fast food restaurant to eat while high ... Marijuana Could Save the U.S. $13.7 Bill... ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in or Sign up 
 
 Advanced Forum Search 
 
Share
 Help Us Redesign! Loading... 
 Home Forums 
 Main Forum Join the discussion Lifestyle Share your stories Drug Testing Be prepared for a drug test Growing Topics Growing Questions&amp;Tips Vaporizers Vaporizer Discussion&amp;Topics Paraphernalia Show off your latest piece Knowledge Brush up on your weed knowledge Fine Arts Art, Music&amp;Entertainment Forum 
 News Wiki Pass A Drug Test 
 Drug Testing Guide Pass your drug test today! Drug Testing Products Find the right product Drug Testing Forums Discuss upcoming drug tests 
 Seeds 
 Feminised Seeds Best-selling feminised seeds Autoflowering Seeds Best-selling autoflowering seeds Medical Seeds Best-selling medical seeds Cannabis Cup Winners Best-selling cannabis cup winners 
 Vaporizers 
 What is a Vaporizer? Vaporizer Information&amp;Tips Vaporizer Study Scientific Studies of Vaporizers Vapor Nation Shop Vaporizers&amp;Accessories 
 Medical Marijuana 
 Find A Dispensary! Top-rated Dispensaries Find A Doctor! On WeedMaps.com SC Labs Tested Meds Find tested strains near you 
 
 
 Search Forums What&apos;s New? 
 
Marijuana.com Most Popular&amp;Essentials

 
Weed Chicks
 
Start Your Own Collective
 
LA Dispensary
 
Hydroponics
 
Daily Deals
 
Got Legal Buds?
 
 Marijuana.com Home &gt; Forums &gt; Lifestyle &gt; Places and People &gt; 
Whats you fav things to eat , drink and do while stoned ??

Discussion in &apos; Places and People &apos; started by rosswhite2k8 , Jan 20, 2010 .
 1 2 Next&gt; 
 Jan 20, 2010 Post # 1 
 rosswhite2k8 rosswhite2k8 

 New Member Since: Nov 10, 2009 Posts: 32 Likes: 4 
 i dont have a one fav thing to eat yet ? any suggestions
also i just like to chill and i only get high at night so any funny ideas as to what i could do ??
thanks homies Jan 20, 2010 Post # 2 
 024 024 

 Sr. Member Since: Nov 1, 2009 Posts: 5,035 Likes: 1,111 
 Nice cold beer, pizza, mountain dew. list goes on &lt;3 Jan 20, 2010 Post # 3 
 MemphisBBQ MemphisBBQ 

 Sr. Member Since: Nov 4, 2009 Posts: 1,069 Likes: 346 
 024 said: ↑ Nice cold beer, pizza, mountain dew. list goes on &lt;3 This

Or

Rip its - 99c energy drinks sold at the gas station next to my house. Usually when I buy a Ripit I grab another snack to go with, but it&apos;s always something different. 1 people like this. Jan 20, 2010 Post # 4 
 Marsh™ Marsh™ 

 New Member Since: Dec 17, 2009 Posts: 426 Likes: 72 
 Those energy drinks suck sober. I bet while high they&apos;re great. I have had red bull stoned,.. fuck it was good. Jan 20, 2010 Post # 5 
 kidswithguns kidswithguns 

 New Member Since: Aug 19, 2008 Posts: 552 Likes: 204 
 my favorite drink would have to be either vitamin water (the purple one, I think it&apos;s pomegranate and acai), or A&amp;W cream soda.

food I don&apos;t really care everything is good when you are stoned.

I like to do lots of different things when I&apos;m stoned. I usually enjoy being outside, checking out what the natural world has to offer or looking at city lights from miles and miles away (I&apos;m about an hour north of the nearest big city, and in certain spots in my town you can see some of the lights, it&apos;s pretty awesome).

Sometimes I like to go to class stoned, but not just any class because sometimes smoking before makes me not want to do any work or just makes me suck at putting words together. So only classes like art and psychology are cool for me to be high in. Jan 20, 2010 Post # 6 
 StonedOutOfMyMind StonedOutOfMyMind 

 New Member Since: Oct 1, 2009 Posts: 354 Likes: 58 
 Food- Taco bell, Papa johns, frozen burritos, fried shrimp, anything unhealthy is always a plus.

Drink- ginger ale, ice cold beer, water.

Things to do...watch adult swim, sleep, space out, eat, drink, lay on my bed, call the girl im in love with and see how her day was, etc etc. Jan 20, 2010 Post # 7 
 Hawkfrag Hawkfrag 

 New Member Since: Nov 26, 2008 Posts: 118 Likes: 44 
 I was just thinking about this!

Make a sandwich, Watch seinfeld, Record some music, Play Dynasty Warriors, Practice drums. haha all in a days work

(man, hit one bong as soon as i got up....effin BLASTED) Jan 20, 2010 Post # 8 
 Killerchron Killerchron 

 Get ya shine on Since: Oct 10, 2006 Posts: 4,079 Likes: 1,543 
 Yoohoo or a ice cold Newcastle. Can&apos;t go wrong with a good pizza. Jan 20, 2010 Post # 9 
 emuhhleee emuhhleee 

 emtard smash! Since: Oct 13, 2008 Posts: 3,715 Likes: 1,312 
 valley hotel, open 24 hours, always has the best pizzas&amp;pies. i usually get chicken fried steak or the teryaki burger. so good. Jan 20, 2010 Post # 10 
 strutinshizz strutinshizz 

 Sr. Member Since: Oct 21, 2009 Posts: 1,766 Likes: 368 
 chocapics :| Jan 20, 2010 Post # 11 
 KuSHiNATOR KuSHiNATOR 

 New Member Since: Jan 5, 2010 Posts: 70 Likes: 4 
 oreo&apos;s, cereal, pizza,

milk, water, coca cola


ohhh and my fav thing to do is smash on call of duty 360 Jan 20, 2010 Post # 12 
 DC420 DC420 

 New Member Since: Nov 10, 2009 Posts: 104 Likes: 14 
 eat : pizza, bk, taco bell
drink: arizona arnold palmer (half iced tea + half lemonade = amazing) 

jamming, movies, and web surfing are def my favorite things to do high. i&apos;ve written a few decent songs high Jan 20, 2010 Post # 13 
 newpotmoker newpotmoker 

 New Member Since: Jul 5, 2009 Posts: 1,162 Likes: 108 
 get one of these , eat the whole thing and watch pineapple express Jan 20, 2010 Post # 14 
 KG1990 KG1990 

 New Member Since: Sep 6, 2006 Posts: 238 Likes: 38 
 i will eat anything when im high. gatorade is the best drink hands down, high or not. and as for an activity- i would say skiing is one of the better activities i enjoy while high Jan 20, 2010 Post # 15 
 femalesmoker femalesmoker 

 Active Member Since: May 5, 2009 Posts: 402 Likes: 55 
 Latly, pizzas hut unlimited toppings on any size pizza Jan 26, 2010 Post # 16 
 rosswhite2k8 rosswhite2k8 

 New Member Since: Nov 10, 2009 Posts: 32 Likes: 4 
 red bull high ? 

id never of thought red bull and high ??? but ill give it a try ( that rhymed )
thanks for posting guys peace ! Jan 26, 2010 Post # 17 
 theblizzard2009 theblizzard2009 

 New Member Since: Jan 26, 2010 Posts: 42 Likes: 8 
 rosswhite2k8 said: ↑ i dont have a one fav thing to eat yet ? any suggestions
also i just like to chill and i only get high at night so any funny ideas as to what i could do ??
thanks homies 
Anything and everything.... sometimes will power goes up in smoke Jan 26, 2010 Post # 18 
 Blackbear Blackbear 

 Sr. Member Since: Jul 20, 2009 Posts: 1,521 Likes: 530 
 i was blazed out of my mind the other night, and a friend gave me some fresh warm apple cobbler or pie or something, with some vanilla ice cream, and it was literally the best food ive ever eaten in my whole life Jan 26, 2010 Post # 19 
 theblizzard2009 theblizzard2009 

 New Member Since: Jan 26, 2010 Posts: 42 Likes: 8 
 Blackbear said: ↑ i was blazed out of my mind the other night, and a friend gave me some fresh warm apple cobbler or pie or something, with some vanilla ice cream, and it was literally the best food ive ever eaten in my whole life MJ has that effect on things that normally taste great, amplifying it to nirvana. Jan 26, 2010 Post # 20 
 cannabicide420 cannabicide420 

 Sr. Member Since: Feb 10, 2009 Posts: 1,382 Likes: 230 
 pretty much anything is gonna be good. whatever you have lying around, pretty much any snack food, fast food is always good. my personal favorite is a few mcchickens and a mountain dew. 
 (You must log in or sign up to reply here.) Show Ignored Content 1 2 Next&gt; 
Share This Page
 
Users found this page by searching for:
 
 
favorite thing to eat when high
, 
best thing to drink while high
, 
good things to drink when high
, things to eat or drink while high , things to drink while stoned , whats the best thing to drink while high? , fun things to eat when high , best things to eat when high , can you drink while high , is it bad to drink while high 
 
Log In/
Sign Up
 Your name or email address: Do you already have an account? Forgot your password? 
 No, create an account now. Yes, my password is: 
 Stay logged in 
 Find Your Bud! 
 
 Rite Greens Santa Ana, CA Email: ritegreens@att.net 
Phone: 714-558-7167 
 4.7 (100) 
 Medx Downtown Express Collective Los Angeles, CA Website: medxclub.com 
Phone: 213-746-6256 
 4.5 (292) 
 Desert Valley Treatment Palm Springs, CA Email: Contact@DVTPalmSprings.com 
Phone: 760-383-2774 
 4.8 (152) 
 
 More Featured Listings» 
 Jul 12, 2012 

 from 
 
Today&apos;s Featured Video:
 2012 High Times Medical Cannabis Cup in San Francisco - Part 2 
 
Marijuana News Brief

Get recaps of hot forum discussions, recent
weed photos, and breaking weed news
delivered to your inbox daily.
 
 
 More Subscription Options 
Featured Sponsors

 

Sponsor Showcases

 WeedMaps WeedMaps/Doctors How To Pass A Drug Test Vaporizers Cannabis Seeds Cannabis Seeds Cannabis Essential Oil Weed Shirt Marijuana Bottles Jons Smoke Shop Hydroponics Marijuana Attorney Oil Vaporizer Autoflowering Seeds Cheapest Online Headphop Buy Quality Cheap Bongs PURE/HIGHEND Bongs 
 
Helpful Apps!
 Marijuana.com App Go Now! Find Your Buds! Go Now! 
Currently, there are 171539 Active Users.
 
 Recent Discussions You&apos;re a Libertarian too, I&apos;ll prove it... Smoking rules for apprentice tokers... Do you believe that Marijuana has... Long boarding high or sober which do... Is it worth it to steal weed or stuff... Using an E cigarette as a weed vaporizer Flowing Thoughts(Feedback?) Gov. Of NJ says end&quot;war on drugs&quot; You know you&apos;re high when... Johnny Richter from KMK Fires Up That... 

 Forum Categories News Main Lifestyle Knowledge Fine Arts Games and Fun Stuff Paraphernalia Place Drug Testing Feedback Wikiweedia 

 Recent Articles Marijuana.com Is Down With&quot;Good Pot 2&quot;... Is Getting High on Marijuana the Muse fo... Top 25 Medical Marijuana Strains for Jun... Marijuana Collectives Cultivate A Compas... Nevada Assemblyman Wants To Cultivate Me... DEA To Legalize Natural THC... But Only ... Legalize Marijuana and Stop the Prohibit... Win A Da Vinci Vaporizer... And Enjoy Th... Operation Ghost Click: Is The FBI Spying... Can THCv Cure Type II Diabetes and Obesi... 

 Featured Sponsors Weedmaps Street Team Weedmaps.com Weed Doctors Growshops 420 Dating WeedBlog.com Stoner Forums How To Pass A Drug Test Vaporizers Cannabis Seeds Marijuana/Cannabis Essential Oil Marijuana Bottles Jons Smoke Shop Hydroponics Marijuana Lawyer Delta 9 Vapes Autoflowering Seeds Buy Quality Cheap Bongs 
 
 Contact Advertise About 
 
©2012 Weedmaps Media Inc.
	</body>
</document>
