<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004391" url="http://businessplanworld.com/restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-20:38" support="4" score="0.007575002418413789" bingtitle="How to open a Restaurant and creating a Restaurant Business Plan ..." webtitle="How to open a Restaurant and creating a Restaurant Business Plan learn from a real Restaurant Owner!">
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>Restaurant Business Plan - Table of Contents ... Works with a wide variety of industry standard receipt ... Find out about other upcoming Business Plans. Resources.</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Business Plan From the &quot;Actual Business Plan Series - Part 3&quot; 
 Get the Restaurant Business Plan - Podcast (

) 

 
 
 Restaurant Business Plan - Table of Contents 
 EXECUTIVE SUMMARY 

Restaurant Overview

 GENERAL INFORMATION 

Name of Company
Type of Business
Location of Business
Type of Business Ownership
Hours of Operation

 PRODUCT/SERVICE 

Description of Restaurant Product/Service
Restaurant Menu
Restaurant Food Specifications
Restaurant Cooking
Restaurant Inventory
Restaurant Customer Service
Restaurant Atmosphere
Restaurant Location
Restaurant Human Resources

 MARKET SUMMARY 

Restaurant Marketing Environment
Restaurant Trading area analysis
Identify the area
Demographics
Restaurant Competitor analysis
Product analysis
Restaurant Physical boundaries
Restaurant Location
Opportunity analysis
Restaurant Target Markets
Trends in the Restaurant Market
Key Marketing Points
Household Incomes Rising
More women in the ranks
Current Restaurant Marketing Objectives
Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities&amp;Threats
Strengths
Weaknesses
Opportunities and Threats
Marketing Implementation&amp;Strategy
The Product or Service, Policy and Guidelines
Factors that may affect the Product
Restaurant Promotion&amp;Distribution
Brochure Development
Direct Mail
Magazines
Newspaper&amp;Television
Most Effective Marketing Areas
Restaurant Financial Controls
Sources of Marketing Funds - Year 1
Sources of Marketing Funds - Year 3
The Internet&amp;Restaurant Marketing
Pricing
Conclusion

 APPENDICES 

Sample Restaurant Menu Selection
Financials
Restaurant Start-up Costs
Restaurant Balance Sheet
Restaurant Income Statement
Restaurant Cash Flow
Restaurant Financial Notes
Restaurant Resources Used

 
 


 


 How to Purchase Purchase a copy of the electronic files 


 
 Methods of Payment: 
 BusinessPlanWorld.com uses only the best encryption techniques to secure your credit card orders . BusinessPlanWorld.com also accepts payment by regular mail or call us toll free to place your order by phone . 
 Ordering Process: 
 Making your purchase is easy! After your credit card is approved, you will be forwarded an email with instructions for downloading the files. You can even have your purchase sent to you on CD-ROM or sent as email attachment. Ordering Online using your credit card is the fastest way to obtain the files since most orders are approved within minutes. 
 


 
 
 The Restaurant Business Plan Includes: 
 An Actual Restaurant Business Plan (47 pages) for use in MS Word.
3 year Projected Income Statement for use in MS Excel.
Balance Statement for use in MS Excel.
Actual Start up Costs for use in MS Excel.
Cash Flow Statement for use in MS Excel.
 Cost $35.00 for all files - no hidden fees 
 
 
 
 
 


 Special Offer - Free Demo Restaurant Point of Sales System Point of Sales System Now Available 


 
 Restaurant - Point of Sales System Features: 

 All Features are enabled in this free DEMO! Create Gift Certificates Password Protection Inventory Management Manage Employee Schedules Manage Account Payments Free Tech Support Free Online Help Works on a Network Import Existing Customers and Menu Data Works with all Windows Operating Systems Works with a wide variety of industry standard receipt printers
Download and try this free Multi-Language Support Point of Sales System available in English, French, Spanish, Italian, German, Dutch, Portuguese, Icelandic, Albanian or Chinese.
If you enjoy the software you can purchase a registration key for Cost $275.00 for the software - no hidden fees 
 
 
 
 




 


 Business Planning Tips An audio interview with a manager of an actual restaurant Requires Windows Media Player 

 
 AUDIO INTERVIEWS: 
  The greatest challenge of operating a Restaurant. 
  What is the greatest reward of operating a Restaurant. 
  Tips on Restaurant Business Focus. 
  Tips on People Skills in the Restaurant Business. 
  Tips on Pricing - How to beat the Restaurant Competition. 
  Tips on Real World Experience - Real tips from an entrepreneur running a Restaurant! 
   Download the entire interview - MP3 (duration 3min 12sec). 


 
 We have worked together with an existing restaurant entrepreneur to provide you with the most realistic business plan possible. The interview clips above will outline what one entrepreneur has found to be the greatest challenge and the most rewarding thing about running this type of business. 
 



 

 
 
 
 The Actual Business Plan Series - Other Business Plans.
 Find out about other upcoming Business Plans. 
 Resources.
 Online Restaurant Resources for new and existing Restaurant Operators. 
 
 EXTRA EXTRA READ ALL ABOUT IT! - Daily Restaurant Business News 
 We have created a new feature for those wanting to get the most up-to-date Restaurant News from around the globe! Try it out, it is free! 
 
 Tell us what you think about this Restaurant website!
 Tell us what you think! Your suggestions and comments will help in providing you with the best in business planning information. 
 
 Talk to the Boss.
 Do you require additional information not contained on the website? Just drop us an email at: theboss@businessplanworld.com or provide your question via this link.
	</body>
</document>
