<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004509" url="http://parentingteens.about.com/od/teensandjobs/ht/teenjobfastfoodrestaurants.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:55" support="5" score="0.0068452979221995175" bingtitle="Teens, Get a Job at a Fast Food Restaurant Help Your Teen Get a ..." webtitle="Teens, Get a Job at a Fast Food Restaurant Help Your Teen Get a Job Series for Parents">
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Article and resource for Parents of Teens, Get a Job at a Fast Food Restaurant Help Your Teen Get a Job Series for Parents</description>
	<body>
		Parenting 
 Teens Search 
 Parenting Teens Teens Today Summer with Teens Teen Health 

 Share 
 Free Teens Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 Teens, Get a Job at a Fast Food Restaurant - Help Your Teen Get a Job Series 

By Denise Witmer , About.com Guide
 See More About: 
 teen jobs working teens teen rules and responsibilities 
 Jobs at fast food restaurants offer valuable opportunities to teens. They will gain work experience in a fast pace employment area, learn how to deal with the public and gain an understanding of work-life stress . While it may not be a glamorous job, many of the restaurants in the fast food industry offer incentives to teens who work for them, like scholarship opportunities. You can help your teen obtain and keep a job at a fast food restaurant by following the steps below. Difficulty: Average Time Required: One Month 
Here&apos;s How:

 Talk to your 16-year or older teen about what working in a fast food restaurant will be like, what will be expected of them and what their expectations are. For instance, do they prefer cooking or taking orders? They may be asked to do both. Make this a positive talk with your teen, reminding them of the benefits of working along with the responsibilities and your confidence in them. Have your teen list out their abilities that will help them with getting a job at a fast food restaurant. Are they punctual, easy-going, organized, have a good memory, can cook, pleasant speaking, trustworthy , can make change, fast leaner and can they use a computer? This list will help your teen fill out their application. While some fast food places have applications at the restaurant, many are turning to the internet to take care of them. Call before you stop in to see which is the preferable way to apply. Be sure your teen has all of the information they will need to fill out applications when they go to do so. Social security number, dates of other employment and reference information will be needed. A week after filling out the applications, encourage your teen to make call-backs to the fast food restaurants they applied to, ask if there are any openings and if their application is being considered. Role play interviews with your teen until they are comfortable answering questions about themselves. This is also a good time to go over how many days a week you will allow your teen to work, as they will be asked that question in an interview. Be willing to drop off and pick up your teen without showing that it was a hassle. Fast food restaurants have odd work hours for their part-time staff. Be willing to change your curfew on work nights. Many fast food restaurants are open until late at night and will ask your teen to work these hours. If your weeknight curfew is 10 p.m. you may have to change it to 11 p. m. or midnight on your teen’s work nights. 

Tips:

 Check-in with your teen about their hygiene before an interview. Clean cut may not be necessary, but walking into an interview with BO isn’t going to get them the job. And longer hair on a boy may be in style, but it will force him to endure wearing a hair net if he is working over a stove flipping burgers. Therefore, he may want to get it cut now–before the interview–rather than later. Also, clean finger nails devoid of chipping nail polish is something your teen will want to avoid. 
 
Suggested Reading

 Teens, Get a Job Babysitting Teen Jobs Quiz: Is Your Teen Ready to Get a Job? Summer Job for Teens - How to Help Your Teen Get a Summer Job 
 
Suggested Reading

 Parenting Teens School Problems - Your teen is too involved and over scheduled. 
 Related Articles 
 Five Places Teens Should Look for Summer Employment Teen Acne - Fast Facts about Teen Acne Teen Job Search Guide Tattoo and Body Piercing Friendly Companies and Employers - Getting a Job W... Getting a Job - Parenting Children with Dyslexia 
 
 Denise Witmer 
Teens Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter 

 Headlines Forum 
 Related Searches fast food restaurants fast food restaurant social security number glamorous job life stress scholarship opportunities Explore Teens Must Reads 
 Is your teen confident? Find out now! Talking to Teens About Tough Issues Quiz: Are You Raising a Healthy Teen? Teen Birthday Party Planner Parenting Teens: Your Teen&apos;s Body Image 
 Most Popular 
 Harry Potter Mega Trivia Quiz on All 7 Harry potter Books Summer Fun for Teens Teen Depression Quiz for Parents of Teens Harry Potter and the Sorcerer&apos;s Stone Book 1 of Harry P… Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows - Book 7 Trivia Quiz 
 See More About: 
 teen jobs working teens teen rules and responsibilities 
 By Category 
 Family Fun and Activities Teen Crafts Ages and Stages Teen Birthday and Party Events Ideas and Planning Parenting Advice: College Family Life Education Talk to Your Teen Troubled Teens Help for Parents Rules and Responsibilities Parenting Advice: Teen Dating Teen Drug Use and Abuse Teen Health Teen Sex and Teen Sexuality 
 Teens 
 About.com Parenting Teens Rules and Responsibilities Teen Jobs Teens, Get a Job at a Fast Food Restaurant Help Your Teen Get a Job Series for Parents 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
