<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004532" url="http://forum.volition.com/topic.asp?TOPIC_ID=830&amp;whichpage=49" time="2012-07-12-20:56" support="16" score="0.029567537763846786" bingtitle="List the most bizarre things that ever happened to you while ..." webtitle="List the most bizarre things that ever happened to you while mystery shopping?">
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000655" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000912" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000914" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>I calmly left the store, parked my car, went back ... have been necessary to place an order at a fast-food restaurant ... back in and said that I get to go around and pick ...</description>
	<body>
		Username: 
 Password: 
 Save Password Register Forgot Password / Username? 
 
 
 Home | Search | Chat | FAQ | Posting Rules 
 
 

 

   All Forums 
   Mystery Shopping, Merchandising&amp;Demo 
   Mystery Shopping 
  List the most bizarre things that ever happened to you while mystery shopping?   Reply to Topic 
   Printer Friendly 
 

 Previous Page | Next Page 
 

 
 
 Author  Topic  Page: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 of 50 
 Roberta07 
 Contributor 
 


 Chambersburg , PA 
 USA 
 58 Posts 
 
 Posted - 12/15/2011 : 08:20:48 AM     I had a gas station shop. The beginning portion of the shop was a mystery and the second part was revealed. This location had a sandwich shop inside it. Being a route shopper, I tend to eat in places like this when I am on the road. I may rethink that in future!

I entered the store and chose my purchase. The cashier rang up the purchase and as I was paying I looked up - right into the eyes of a dog, standing on the counter where the sandwiches are prepared. I calmly left the store, parked my car, went back inside with my gear and revealed myself. The dog was still there. I whipped out my camera, snapped the picture, the cashier blinked, realized a camera was in my hand, and dove in front of the dog. Arms waiving, the cashier pleaded with me to delete the photo because the owner wouldn&apos;t like having the dog there and would fire everyone. I responded that I could not do that, and the cashier asked, &quot;Why?&quot; I told the cashier, &quot;Because that would be unethical and dishonest.&quot; What I THOUGHT was....&quot;Dude, you DO realize that ALL of this is on camera, including this conversation?&quot;
	</body>
</document>
