<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004123" url="http://starbuckseverywhere.net/Log_2009_05_11_July.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:22" support="10" score="0.012702475688599524" bingtitle="Starbucks Everywhere Travel Log" webtitle="Starbucks Everywhere Travel Log">
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>And yet I keep smacking my head against the brick wall ... I quickly took my ticket, receipt, and card, and looked ... It was already near 5:00 when I arrived at Hertford, and ...</description>
	<body>
		World Tour 2009 


 

 



 NEWER ENTRIES 



 July 31, 2009 

8:17, bah, too late to make the 8:58 train to Lyon. The next train, at 9:17, was really slow, and arrived just 8 minutes before the faster 10:58 train, so I decided to wait and use the time for photos. Unfortunately, I quickly discovered that I might have spoken too soon about the Nikon&apos;s post-fall condition. The photos of Rond-Point de Plainpalais from the previous evening, around dusk, seemed fine. But for some reason my photos from the morning had the white balance and/or exposure all off, depending on where I pointed the camera and from which angle I shot with relation to the sun. Spent a good 30 minutes there trying to figure out what was going on, fiddling with settings.

By the time I shot the other three stores, fiddling with the angle and lighting each time, it was getting close to my train, and I did not have time to make the best use of my remaining seven francs. I had to simply go for the blueberry muffin from Starbucks, which is actually really good here in Switzerland, and the not-so-good overpriced juice. One advantage though, I was able to pay 7 francs in cash and the other 2.40 on my card.

Discovered I could not buy the ticket to Lyon, France from the machine, and all of a sudden I was looking at missing my train. I bought the ticket with maybe 2-3 minutes to spare, and I had to rush to Platform 8, a special platform for France that included passport control and customs. I contrast this with my trips across Germany, Switzerland, Austria, and even the Czech Republic--no control.

Made it just in time, as did a pair of attractive (one above average, the other simply gorgeous) English-speaking young women. I took our shared experience as an opportunity to break the ice by saying &quot;Barely made it, eh?&quot; From the curly-haired, tan-skinned one&apos;s response I gathered they were Australian, and asked as much. She replied &quot;yes&quot; but did not follow up. I few minutes later I asked &quot;Where in Australia are you from?&quot; She replied Perth, then after a second, as if she was thinking about it, asked where I was from. &quot;Texas,&quot; I said, and replied &quot;Cool.&quot; She smiled as she did so, but she immediately turned her head again, as she had done before, a clear indication that she had no interest in chatting with me.

So put on my headphones and resumed The World podcast and wondered to myself, why do I waste my time trying to talk to women who are that attractive. I already know they have no interest in me. To them I am a non-entity, just an annoyance, something to be tolerated and ignored. And yet I keep smacking my head against the brick wall that is the gorgeous woman (if you are not a gorgeous, or rich, man). If I had any willpower at all, I would vow to never again speak to a gorgeous woman unless I was paying her for some service. Unfortunately, I can no more promise myself that than I can promise that I will not binge on beignets or beignet-ish donuts the next time I find them. I just too weak.


Yay!!! Back in France for the first time in 4 1/2 years!!!

Weird. I&apos;d only been in Germany and Switzerland for barely two weeks, yet when I bumped into a man at the Gare Lyon Part-Diue I said &quot;Entschuldigung&quot; (check spelling) without even thinking about it.

Ach! Finally lost the small water bottle I&apos;d been carrying around for nine weeks. Discovered this just as I was tossing my bottle of juice, taller but slightly thinner, into the trash. I thought about it and decided, why waste money on a bottle, so I fished it out and washed it at the Starbucks.

Once I oriented myself and asked some passersby for directions, the Villeurbanne store appeared to be less than two miles away. I figured I&apos;d waste 5-10 minutes trying to figure out what bus or train or tram or subway to take, so I just hoofed. Wanted to get a grounds-eye view of the Lyon cityscape anyway.

I walked into the Villeurbanne with my mind set on not using any English, except words I did not know, and even then I tried to talk around the unknown word. In fact, I wanted to avoid using English during my entire stay in France, but a more practical goal was probably 24 hours. I was butchering the language though. I cannot imagine how horrible my accent and grammar must have sounded to the baristas&apos; delicate French ears.

Ooh, because of a 2006 French law, the first thing I saw when connecting to the wi-fi was a page explaining that I had to fill in my personal information as part of that anti-terrorism law.

Oops, I spoke to myself in English. My bad.

No multi-day wi-fi option in France. All that was available was 30 minutes for 2 euros or 60 minutes for 4 euros. I paid with my card, of course, and I was surprised when the barista asked for my ID, with the sheepish explanation &quot;that&apos;s what I&apos;m supposed to do.&quot; Perhaps it&apos;s different here--I could not remember the last time, anywhere, where I was asked for ID for a credit card purchase at a Starbucks.

Yay!!! The store on on of the Canary Islands, at the airport, is licensed, SSP, so I save myself a bunch of time and money making a trip in and out for that one store.

Nuts. Bus ticket was 1.60 euro, and I had just 1.40 and bills. That was fine, I needed to eat anyway, and I found a Turkish doener place a few blocks away that served burgers, 5 euros for cheeseburger, fries, and a Coke.

OMG, the wi-fi at the Lyon store was ridiculously slow, and with every minute counting, since I did not have an unlimited plan like with T-Mobile or AT&amp;T;, I was painfully aware of just how slow it was.

Ach! I said &quot;sorry&quot; in English.

Since Lyon was a smaller city, I hoped that I could find massages at reasonable prices of around 20 euros for half an hour, maybe 30-40 euros for an hour. I googled for a list and found a bunch of locations all near the Starbucks, roughly in the direction of the gare. Of the places that were actually at the address, and offering massage, I was surprised to find prices that were higher than I expected. The final place I found turned out to openly offer erotic massage, as well as regular massage, and the prices were ridiculous. I saw prices from 130 to 300, I think, euros on the erotic menu. And 60 for the regular massage, in euros, would have been high even if it had been for an hour. For 30 minutes, it was ridiculous.

Ach! Stupid passenger, whose train was to depart in 8 minutes, caught me off guard by speaking to me in English, and I responded in kind.

Missed the 17:30 train to Paris by a few minutes. The 18:00 had just 1st class available, for about 30 euros more, and I decided it wasn&apos;t worth it. I needed time to plot all the stores in Paris and charge up the laptop anyway, so I bought a ticket for 19:00.

Interesting. I went into a cafe just so I could keep the laptop charged while I waited and plotted locations, and I ordered an ice cream. When the waiter brought it, the spoon was inside a tall glass of water. The ice cream, BTW, cost 5.00 for about the same amount that I paid 1.60 for in Germany. Yes, I expected to pay more so close to the station, but that was a shock. I cringed to think at what Paris prices were going to be like.

BTW, the restaurant one or two spaces down had a burger on the menu for 22 euros. Don&apos;t know what all came with it, but damn.

I don&apos;t know if this means anything, but I finally plotted the nearly 40 Paris stores I needed to visit, and it just so happened neither of the two hostels I had booked were in the middles of the clusters of stores. Oh well.

Here&apos;s a map , excluding one in Versailles and two well east of the city.

Boarded the first car I saw, went upstairs, and picked a seat with a table. I noticed numbers above the seats, and I asked the man sitting across if the seats were reserved. He said his was, but he wasn&apos;t sure about the others. I looked at my ticket and noticed it had a seat assignment, and just they a dour-looking man arrived at the seat the pointed. I had gotten so used to unassigned seats (most were) in Germany, Switzerland, and the Czech Republic that it didn&apos;t even occur to me to look at my ticket.

The train was a TGV (Tequila-Gin-Vodka), and from the window it appeared it was moving really fast. The young man sitting across from me said he thought its speed (&quot;vitesse&quot;, not &quot;velocite&quot;, chuckle all you want at my gaffe) was 200 kM/hr, but it looked higher to me.

Train arrived late, as the French are neither Germans nor Swiss, but, as the French are neither British, the nearest store, Roquette, was still open, and so was the nearby Saint Antoine.

This was my third trip to Paris, but this time was much better. First time, 1993, as part of the Normandy Scholars Program at the University of Austin, we spent three weeks in Caen and flew in an out of Paris. At the end of it we had 2-3 days in the city, plus during the program we had a free weekend with the host family, and my host &quot;brothers&quot; took me to Paris. I didn&apos;t know what the heck I was doing back then, and I waste a lot of time, and probably money, including some gambling and getting ripped off on tickets for the French open.

The second time, on December 31st, 2004, I flew in on a whirlwind tour of Paris, London, and Madrid. I drove to the nine stores in Paris, and between worrying about the car, finding the stores, and getting to them all in one day, I can&apos;t say I could really enjoy the city.

But now, with at least five days planned, and no car to worry about, I could take my time and really look around and notice things, like the pair (maybe more) of homeless who actually possessed a camping tent and had set it up next to the door of a parking garage. Not very inconspicuous, their large grey tent, and I wondered how the gendarmes handled homeless in Paris.

However, my camera was still worrying me. I had no problems shooting the Lyon stores, and I managed to get a decent shot of Roquette even in the fading light, but the camera only managed to one decent shot of Saint Antoine before the lighting went all screwy. Didn&apos;t really matter, since I misunderstood the closing time when I asked at the other store and arrived 15 minutes late--I&apos;d have to return.

Aw, nuts, stupid Paris has that same system for the travel card (Paris Visite) wherein if the card is used at the end of the day it still counts for a day instead of going on a 24-hour cycle. Bah.

Sweet--I had the mighty thirst, and I decided to try something different, a juice drink called Pago, for 1.80. Well, the vending machine already had 50 euro cents credit!!! That&apos;s the best thing that happened to me all day, besides visiting Lyon and returning to Paris, minor stuff like that.

Damn. I walked into the hostel and completely forgot to speak French. Didn&apos;t even make it 12 hours without English.

 



Ah, another reason why I don&apos;t ever want to be separated from my bags. At the hostel, on the bulletin board, a sign stating that somebody had walked up with one of another guests suitcase, and to please return if taken &quot;by mistake&quot;. By mistake--yeah, right.

Ouch. Unexplained craving for sodas/juices that day, including late at night when my only option was an Orangina from the hostel bar... for a whopping 3 euros (for a small bottle than I had gotten at the station for 2).



 July 30, 2009 

7:56

Let&apos;s go shopping... Swiss style. Went into Migros for some groceries. Wasn&apos;t sure if I had to do that self-weighing of produce that I had encountered the previous year, so I went over to the registers to see if I spotted a scale. I didn&apos;t, and I puzzled over how to indicate what item I was weighing because I did not see the UPC code on the fruits and veggies. I finally noticed that the bins contained numbers, and the scale contained a panel with a square of numbers. Next, the yogurt. Many brands came in packs of two, and I had to ask if I was allowed to buy just one. Next, the juice, and I was surprised to find that a 750 mL container was just 3.10, cheaper than in Germany or the UK, although the taste was not as good. Better than the brand they had at the Swiss Starbucks, however, which cost 5.50 for about half the amount.

I had asked the night before, and I asked again in the morning at the ticket counter, if there was a way to save money on a ticket to Bern/Geneva when I also needed to go to the Arena shopping center. Nope, I was told, and had to get on the RegioBus to Arena. The ticket machine did not have an English option, and a young kid seemed to try to help me out. Except he kept punching in the wrong options, like the 1/2 price option and some other ones. Maybe he was just confused, or maybe he was trying to get me to have to use a 20-france note and get change, which he would then ask me for. I ended up just buying a single ticket, instead of a return, because all I had in coins was 3 francs and did not know to what extent the machine would give me change. Didn&apos;t want to risk paying with a 20 and not getting all my change.

Another wave of e-mails, including one from a pair of students in Sankt Gallen who wanted to meet me. I told them when I would be returning to the Hauptbahnhof and taking the train out, but I figured they were probably in school.

Aw, nuts, there went my second, of three, pair of briefs, left hanging to air out on the bed frame. I&apos;d lost the first over a month earlier, and now I was done to just one. I&apos;d have to wash it more often.

Oh boy oh boy oh boy, here we go again... returned to the Hauptbahnhof and, with 30 minutes to wait until my train to Bern, I plugged in my laptop and went to buy a muffin and get a free wi-fi card. Got back to the computer to find it was not charging, and I assumed the plug had fallen out of the adapter. It had not, but I pulled it out and plugged it back in again, only to see the adaptors indicator light turn green and then fade to black. No no no no no no no no no no!!!

Tried another plug, same thing. As usual, I instantly began to worry that my trip would come to a premature end. I hoped it was the plug adaptor, and not the laptop adaptor, and I was glad that I would be in France that evening where I could try my European adaptor. Still, I worried that my laptop would run out of power, even in sleep mode, in the 6+ hours I expected it to take me to get to Lyon. More, because I might need to waste time looking for an Internet cafe.

Nothing to do but get on the train, and during the trip it occurred to me that I should have tried to plug in my camera battery charger to make sure it was the plug adaptor and not the laptop adaptor. Grrr... a computer brain like Data&apos;s would not have made that mistake, but my weak human brain overlooked the logical course of action. Curse you, weak human brain!!!

Had to ask around about the Starbucks when I reached Bern, but it was close to the station. First thing I did was test the battery charge--didn&apos;t work. Yep, must be the plug adaptor. I was kind of relieved, that it wasn&apos;t the laptop adaptor, which I could not replace as easily. The other new store happened to be in a shopping center (3.80 bus right, yoicks!!!), and there was of course an electronics store (Migros, which also has a restaurant and grocery store--weird) where I bought a replacement. I cannot overestimate the relief I felt when I had the cashier plug it in and found it worked!!! Like a great weight had been lifted off my shoulders, like I was free again instead of trapped by lack of connectivity and info.

Back in front of the Bubenbergplatz store, on the tram tracks, waiting for a photo, I saw this cute little chug-chug pass by.

 

 



Finally found a burger stand, a doener stand actually, on the way back to the Bern Hauptbahnhof. 7.50 for the burger and fries, but menu option was the type in which the fries are put inside the burger, something I had previously encountered in Beirut.

Views from the train approaching Lausanne. That tennis court must be a sweet place to play. Wonder what a view like that costs.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 



I was still miffed that I had to spend extra money to visit the shopping centers in Sankt Gallene and Berne, but at least I was able to take the train to Geneve all the way to the airport. I still had to pay 3 francs for a ticket back to the main station, but I saved a franc or two.

However, I nearly ended my project, for a fifth time , when, as I rushed to try and make the 19:36 train from the airport, the STUPID FUCKING ZIPPERS on my FUCKING EDDIE BAUER backpack came unzipped, as they had tended to do if I zipped them up symmetrically instead of to one side or the other, and my camera fell out onto the ground!!! I gotta hand it to Nikon for building a sturdy camera--it still appears to work.

As I expected the lone new Starucks in the city was open until 9:00, and I made it in time to log on and figure out what I was going to do next. Lyon was no longer an option, because the last train was at 20:44. I had to call back one hostel in Geneva to see if they had had a cancellation. They did not, but the attendant gave me a number of another place, Cite Universitaire, that had beds. It was not that far away, so I walked (only had 7 francs left anyway), but I had to keep checking my map on the laptop to navigate my way.

Cite Universitaire turned out to be a university dormitory that rented out rooms for hostelers. After I checked in I went out into a common area to get online and book my Paris rooms (couldn&apos;t get consecutive nights), and a group of students from UC Davis were chatting at a table waiting for the bus to take them out on the town. I felt a bit wistful and a longing for my younger years when I was in college. Oh, to be 22 or 23, and in college again, but with the money and knowledge I have now.

 





 July 29, 2009 

Ach! I hate alarm clocks. Even worse than an alarm clock is one that keeps going off because somebody keeps hitting the snooze button instead of just waking up. I see no value in being woken up every 10 minutes when sleeping straight through until you have to get up would be more restful. But what could I do? I was a guest, and thus I had to endure until Michelle finally decided to get up.

We were out of her flat right around 7:00, and I used all the time I had before meeting the report in Zurich to walk around the five Starbucks in Basel and take more photographs.

I reached the station shortly before 9:00 AM, ostensibly with plenty of time to catch a train to Zurich in time for my 11:00 AM appointment. And then everything started to go wrong. First, the Reisezentrum was busy, and I after quite a wait I asked the agent about a travel pass and was shocked to time that the only option was for four days, for 290 CHF!!! Ridiculously expensive. I had to get out of line, go over to the self-service kiosk, and try to figure out if it would be cheaper to buy individual tickets. I immediately saw something called a super-saver fare for 9.40 CHF, but I would later learn this was a misleading price (as ads often are). Fortunately I had thought to grab a counter ticket in advance, and I only had to wait a few minutes to speak to an agent. She told me that the super-saver fare was only available from the computer, which I kind of expected, but also that I had to print it out--I could not have the ticket on my laptop. This was extremely annoying, because that meant I had to go off hunting for an Internet cafe with a printer.

I asked at the bakery/cafe across the street, but the cashier did not know of one. I walked over to the Starbucks and asked, and the barista directed me outside, down some stairs, into an underground corridor. I saw a sign that read &quot;Internet Cafe&quot;, but when I walked into the room all I saw was what appeared to be a small restaurant. The cook, seemingly of Indian descent, said something in German. I asked if she spoke English, and then I asked about the Internet cafe. I did not hear her reply well enough to understand, and I had to wait for her to turn her attention back to me, come out from behind the counter, and indicate that I should follow. She did not say anything, however, so I had to ask again about the Internet cafe, and she impatiently said &quot;Yes, yes.&quot; She led me over to the room next door, and as she unlocked it I asked &quot;Do you have a printer?&quot; Again, her reply was curt and unfriendly. She did not seem inclined to do more than the bare minimum to help me.

I pulled up the SBB site and quickly saw, to my dismay, that the super saver fares were only for the specified times, and that the really cheap fare was for 9:33, just four minutes away. No way I could make that, so I logged off and went to see if the unfriendly lady was going to charge me less for the few minutes of time I used. Nope, as I expected, she was a bitch and charged me the full 3 CHF even though I told her I was not able to find the ticket I wanted. While I&apos;m throwing around insults, I supposed I should ascribe bitchness to the SBB agent who failed to give me the all relevant details about the super saver tickets. Thanks for making me waste 3 francs, bitch.

Back to the station, where used the self-service kiosk out in the lobby (not the self-service computers in the Reisezentrum) to figure out pricing. It appeared that I could save a few bucks by buying a ticket from Basel to St. Gallen via Zurich and Rapperswill rather than buying the tickets separately. I wanted to make sure of the rules, however, so I waited in the line to buy a ticket from an agent. And I waited, and I waited, for ahead of me was a man, perhaps of Middle Eastern descent, who was buying tickets for 9 adults and 5 children. It wasn&apos;t good enough for the agent, however, that he specify 5 children--no, she needed to know the exact ages of all the children! AARRGHH!!! By the time I bought my ticket, I had just a couple of minutes before the 10:07 ICE that would have gotten me to Zurich in time. I quickly took my ticket, receipt, and card, and looked around for the signs indicating where platform 10 was. I saw no indications I could understand, and I had to rush back to the counter, with an alarmed look on my face that got the agents attention. I frantically asked, &quot;WHERE IS PLATFORM 10???&quot; She directed me up the stairs, and despite my sprinting I missed the closing of the doors by 5 seconds!!! AARRGHH!!! 

Of course the reporter&apos;s train had been on time, but since she had come 3 hours from Frankfurt, she waited for me. I was surprised she had come all that way instead of just sending me questions via e-mail or having me call her, but then Zurich is a very pretty city, and perhaps a refreshing change from Frankfurt.

It was nearly 2:00 when she finished her questions and photos, and I went off in search of a cheap burger. With just two days in expensive Switzerland, I intended to survive on as cheap food as I could find (not counting McDonald&apos;s--that would be disgusting). However, to my amazement, I walked around for 20 minutes without finding a goddamn burger joint--say what what what??? I finally gave up and went into Migros, a local grocery store chain. Made sure they took cards, as I did not want to use my francs unless I had to. Went with the currey turkey and the white rice. When the cashier asked me if I wanted grosse or kleine, the man next to me translated, not realizing I knew exactly what she had said. I felt a little insulted, but I know he was just trying to be helpful.

Perhaps I do not always read people correctly. I had the impression that the supervisor in Rapperswil was merely tolerating my presence, but when I came back into the store after taking the photos I found a small cup of the new lemon hibiscus Frappuccino waiting for me. A bit later, he offered me a Frappuccino that had been marked out.

I arrived in St. Gallen with the possibility of visiting all four stores before they closed, but it was more complicated than that. I got online immediately and looked up hostels in Bern and St. Gallen. The hostel in Bern (I was surprised my google found just one) was full, but St. Gallen had a room. Though I would have preferred to go ahead and go to Bern and get a head start, I feared what kind of prices any available hotels would charge. On top of that, traveling to Bern that night, and then to Geneva in the morning on another ticket, would cost 10 francs more than traveling on one ticket with a stopover, which had to be done on the same day.

Why... so... serious?

 



I thus went with the St. Gallen hostel, and I was a bit irked that the lady on the phone told me checkin was from 5-7 and did not seem to understand that I was asking her if I could check in later. This was only important because the hostel was a good 20 minute walk up a hill, and I had to checkin and then walk back into town for food.

 



Once more I failed to find a burger joint. I asked a pair of young men on a corner if they could think of a place for burgers, and then I asked if it was the case that burgers are not common in Switzerland. One of them seemed to nod his head in agreement, that burgers are not so common.

I kept walking around and finally decided to try the albondigas with rice from Bar Barcelona, for 21.50 (plus god knows how much for the soda). I led with Spanish of course, to ask for the menu, and the waitress quickly said she did not speak Italian. The man on a stool next to me understood, however, and he translated. I looked over the menu and then asked, in German, 
if they had Coke in a can or bottle, and if I could pay with a card, and if I could sit down. I had those phrases covered at least.

For some reason I kept speaking to the waitress in Spanish even though she did not understand.

Though the portion was small, the meal was excellent. The albondigas (meatballs) were tasty, and I could not find fault with the rice, except maybe that it wasn&apos;t mouth-wateringly tasty like at the Latin restaurant in Muenchen. Would have been better if I had had a side, like potatoes or beans or vegetables, as I find just rice and meat a little plain for my tastes, but I walked away feeling like the price, though expensive, had been well worth it.

 





 July 28, 2009 

8:50

Heh. Seen on a street in Mannheim.

 



Finally found a cheap half our massage, 25 euros, albeit from a Thai place, not a German salon, but it was still pretty good. Interestingly enough, the therapist spoke better German than English. For a change, I had her start off with the Thai massage, because it was only 18 euros instead of 25, but after a few minutes I decided I just didn&apos;t like the style and had her switch to the Swedish massage (called oelmassagen) instead.

Arrived in Freiburg to find a bunch of messages in my Inbox, and I guessed that the article in Spiegel must have been published.

Went to the old store by mistake, because of a renaming I&apos;d failed to catch, and I stayed there longer than I expected because of all the e-mails. When I reached the other store, I was surprised to find a young German man, Alexis, expecting me. He had read the article, and while he had not specifically known I would be there at that time, he took a guess. That was cool, only the second or third time somebody had read or heard about me and come out to a store to meet me.

Previous to Freiburg, my last coffee had been more than 18 hours earlier in Saarbruecken, and by the time I reached that store I was already starting to jones. Because that would be my only new store of the day, I wondered if a sample would be enough, and was considering buying a short. Fortunately, the manager happened to remember my story from the internal newsletter, and I brought over a tall.

E-mails continued, from reports and fans alike, and I pushed my schedule back to the 17:01 train, which was okay because Michelle would not be able to get off work &apos;til 6:00 anyway.

WTF??? Why is it that I see burger stands, or doener cafes that serve burgers, everywhere, when I don&apos;t want them, but as soon as I do (because I wanted a cheap meal to tide me over before dinner with Michelle), I can&apos;t find a single one. Finally ran out of time and had to go for pasta. At first it seemed overpriced, but I actually got a rather large portion, which meant my dinner plans were ruined. I&apos;d only be able to munch on something light.

At the train station I encountered another fan who had been e-mailing me in the previous two hours. He had indicated he had to work, but he managed to get away, I guess, and called out to me as I was rephotographing the Starbucks.

OMG, the Google translation of the Spiegel article is hilarious!!! 

Yay, met Michelle at the Centralbahnplatz store in Basel and we went a-walking. I had absolutely no memory of Basel while on the train, but once I exited the station and looked around I started to remember. It still continued to trouble me, how my memory just continued to disappoint me. Oh, to have my 27-year-old brain back with my 37 years of experience.

Cool metalwork in a fountain. Forget the name of the artist, but I think Michelle said he has a museum nearby.

 

 

 

 



I offered to treat Michelle to dinner, least I could do given she was putting me up, and I remembered from last year that Switzerland is expensive, but I was still shocked when I found out her buffet was 19 frances. Jeez, Louise!!!

I figured, because it was in Europe, Michelle&apos;s flat would be really small and dumpy, especially after her descriptions of how the place only had two washers and thus allowed just two wash times per month ! However, her flat actually looked very nice, but nicer than what I imagine you could get in New York or San Francisco for the same price, despite the fact that Swizterland is expensive! 

During our chatting I pointed out to Michelle that it appeared I had kept up with culture/news back home despite my traveling much more than Michelle had, even though she had long since settled in. I commented that because I had been constantly on the move for over two months, I really needed to keep up with the news, music, movies, TV, and other culture from back home in order to have something to ground me and provide stability. I can&apos;t imagine I&apos;d feel very comfortable being away from so long if I did not have such a constant stream of online communication and access.



 July 27, 2009 

8:32, a little later than I had hoped, as the Starbucks opened at 8:30, but an extra 10 minutes wouldn&apos;t have mattered, because the best train I could take was at 9:41, and I made it. I even had time to stop at Bio fuer Alles and get some yogurt and fruit. I even had time, upon reaching the station, to confirm my itinerary at the service point. Surely because it was just minutes before 9:41, the agent printed out an itinerary for the 10:35, but that didn&apos;t matter. I just wanted to know the connections, the first of which was Backnang.

Nuts!!! In my hurry to make the train, I failed to notice that the yogurt I bought was soy, dairy-free. Wasn&apos;t awful, but far from my preference.

Super nuts!!! After about a week with the small hole in my left pants leg, I finally managed to catch my toe in the hole while putting them on, and I made the rip really big. You could call it fashionable in some circles, but I was more worried about being cold at night, on plane flights, or even on chilly trains while I tried to sleep.

Super duper nuts!!! The bogus congestion charge penalty was already issued, and subsequently paid by Hertz, on the BofA card, even though I had blocked it, and thus my blocking it and subsequent credit limit reduction turned out to be completely useless. I was going to suffer a lack of credit for no benefit whatsoever.

Esslingen was easy, but the Ludwigsburg store is in Breuningerland, a shopping center well outside the town center. When I had called the store for info on Saturday, the barista had told me there was no train to the center, that I would have to take a bus (I assumed she was referring to the Ludwigsburg bahnhof, which is what I had specified). Once I had time to think, I doubted this, and it turned out the S-Bahn had a stop in Tamm, about a mile from the center. There was a bus waiting at the stop outside the station, but what I thought I heard the bus driver said was the fare was 1.95 euro, and that was a bit above my value threshold. I always assume that I can walk a mile, no problem, and even though it takes time, peaceful walking has value to me.

After the uninteresting walk, however, I might have been prepared to pay for the ride back, if the bus had been waiting and I could confirm the fare with an English speaker. It was still six minutes away though, and that was just enough time that I decided to walk it again. There was no predicting, really, whether the bus ride would save me anything. The trains back to the Stuttgard Hauptbahnhof ran every 15 minutes, and it was just as likely as not that the bus would get me there right after the train left, as opposed to right before it arrived.

A good illustration of just how prevalent the legal sex trade in Germany is, I found a brothel not a five minutes walk away from the large, posh, shopping center. This was the suburbs, mind you, not even the city center. Pick your favorite American suburb and, assuming prostitution were legal in the U.S., ask yourself if the local municipal council would allow a brothel near the posh shopping mall. Anyway, I investigated, and I found the pricing to be pretty much the same as in Nuernberg, with one additional piece of information that became clear. The girls were tended to charge more for just massage than for sex or a blowjob. In one sense there is a logic to this--it is less work to just lay there, or to perform fellatio, than to massage. Still, this is just the opposite of America and Canada, where massage for a full 30 minutes can be had relatively cheaply, and anything more, if even available, costs more. Regardless, just as with the bus ride, 50 euros for 20 minutes of massage was not a good value to me, and 30 euros for a blowjob, which was almost surely required to involve a condom, had almost zero value to me. And straight sex, quick and rushed as it was sure to be, again, zero value.

Hungry as fuck, but I missed my chance for food before the train to Saarbruecken because I was wasting my time on the phone with a Bank of America agent trying to get my credit limit increased. Every now and again you will hear a news report about people who work in call centers, and they often report abuse from callers. However, I have never heard a single one admit that he incited the abuse by refusing to act like a human being. I myself kept calm during the call, although emphatic, but the person I was speaking to was guilty of acting like an inhuman computer. A minimum human reaction would have been to acknowledge that BofA did wrong by extending me a $10,000 line of credit and then pulling it back with no notice while I was already in Europe and had informed them I needed the card to buy a plane ticket back!!! On the heels of having taken $45 BILLION from the U.S. government in TARP funds, to not be able to extend my credit by $1200 for a ticket is, quite simple, an evil act.

A boycott is useless--not going to happen. But I wonder if I could successfully appeal to people&apos;s baser instincts and organize a mass campaign of criminal mischief.

Damn, that bitch was persistent. Let me make it clear that &quot;bitch&quot; is not equivalent to &quot;woman&quot;, no more than &quot;asshole&quot; is equivalent to &quot;man&quot;. But when a woman, on the street in Mannheim (getting food while waiting for train to Saarbruecken) calls out to you and asks for money for the ticket again, after you&apos;ve already denined her obvious scam the first time, then you are justified in calling her a bitch, and that is not being misogynistic!

I think President Obama should give his weekly radio and Internet address in rap form, and adopt the moniker &quot;Flowbama&quot; while doing so.

While I&apos;m having great ideas, I think some Vanilla Ice track should play from the speakers every time an ICE train arrives at the station.

Wow, is there not end to the fucked-up-ness of this Dell? Now the mouse is freaking out on me, either not moving or moving erratically. If I just hold my finger on the touchpad it jiggles around. And of course I cannot reboot the machine for fear that it will not come back up.

Ow. My ass tingles. It could be because of my time on the toilet, or it could be the after effect of getting fucked by Hertz, by Dell, by Bank of America.

Bad planning, or poor assumptions, ended up costing me. Once I knew I would not reach Freiburg in time to visit the Starbucks and move on to Basel. I googled hostels in Freiburg, Mannheim, and Saarbruecken, but I assumed that, because it was Monday, if there was a hostel, there would still be rooms available. That was a mistake, and not only was Freiburg booked, but also nearby possibilities like Karlesruhe. I tried one hostel in Frankfurt, technically in the other direction, but free since I had a rail pass, but even they were full. I could have made more calls to Frankfurt hostels, but the Hotel Luxa in Mannheim was about to close the desk, and I needed to call back quickly if I wanted that room. I was hesitant, because it was 49 euros, not the 39 euros I had seen online, but I had little choice. Yes, there was a train itinerary that allowed me to sleep for an hour here, and hour there, a couple of hours there, while making connections, but I would reach Freiburg at around 5:00 AM and have to just wait somewhere for Starbucks to open. I could also try just staying awake in Mannheim the whole time, wandering around, but that was risky. If I fell asleep somewhere I could lose all my stuff, and regardless I would be exhausted on Tuesday, and that seriously affects my enjoyment.

Meanwhile, as I was doing all this investigating and making calls, a strange-looking older woman with wild hair and bad teeth sat a couple of seats from me, looking over at me with my laptop and microphone, and said something that ended in the word &quot;Teknik&quot;. I assume she was commenting on my equipment, but I was too busy to be inclined to understand her, and I just turned and smiled. A few seconds later she said something else, and I had to say &quot;Es tut mir leit. Ich muss... zug.&quot; I meant &quot;I must catch a train&quot;, but I left out the verb. I think she finally got the message.

Dude, 49 euros, and they could not even provide free Internet access? The attendant sensed my displeasure and offered me up a code for three free hours.

At least I was able to mitigate the cost by using the sink to wash all my socks, briefs, washcloth, and even my shirt. Not as good as a real wash, but it would save me 3, 4, maybe even 5 euros for a few days at least.

 



After washing I went out to sate my mighty thirst, and something unusual happened. I found myself with a sudden craving for ice cream, and a minute later I passed an restaurant displaying ice cream. I decided to get jiggy and deviate from my usual vanilla, and I tried a combination of the Snickers flavor and the mandarin yogurt. And, to continue my wild and crazy night, I had a Fanta.



 July 26, 2009 

Figured the Starbucks would open no earlier than 10:00, if even that, so I stayed in bed &apos;til 9:30.

Determined or stupid? I guess that depends on the outcome. Upon waking up I stepped outside the room, dropped to the floor to do a couple of push ups, and quickly decided to give my hand/wrist a break. Went back into the room, thought about it a moment, and decided the pain wasn&apos;t that bad, and that I didn&apos;t want to be a wuss. Went back outside, and the pain turned out not to be that bad after all. Of course if I started to hurt worse later, I&apos;d feel foolish.

 AARRGHH!!! WHY DIDN&apos;T I CALL THEM!!! WHY DID I ASSUME THAT THE STORE WOULD BE OPEN SUNDAY JUST BECAUSE IT IS NOT IN A SHOPPING CENTER. MY WHOLE SCHEDULE IS NOW @*^&amp;NSI;%^KNF#*P@P(HNFWF)SIGH)QW*GF!!! (I&apos;m so frustrated I can&apos;t even swear right).

I walked around and photographed the stores, of course, and rephotographed the stores I had visited, and then I went into the one store that was open at that hour to plan my day. I confirmed that the new store in Munich, Platzl, and the store in Esslingen, were both open. The ICE train to Munich would get me there in an hour, not a big deal, but I would still need to return to Nuremberg on Monday after visiting Ludwigsburg, or perhaps before--I hadn&apos;t figured it out yet. At least with my rail pass it wasn&apos;t going to cost me anything, just time on the train.

Just four stores visited on Saturday, and this meant I was starting to jones. Traveling even the hour-plus to Munich without any coffee would be painful, I predicted, and I decided this was a good opportunity to have the obligatory-when-overseas non-Starbucks cup of coffee, a cappuccino from the cafe next door to the Starbucks, Casa Nane, accompanied by something called a knielkuechle.

Had enough time before my train to stop at the hostel again and reserve my bed for that night. I could have done it by phone, but I wanted to talk to the attendant who had checked me in personally, in the hopes that he would waive the 3 euro fee for the sheets that I had already dumped in the laundry bin. For the last three nights, the hostels I had found all required an extra 2 or 3 euros for sheets. If staying several nights, the charge wasn&apos;t so bad, but for one-night stays it was annoying. Fortunately, the attendant threw in the sheets for free since I was staying another night.

SCORE!!! With time to kill, I remembered to google for Latin restaurants, and I found Caramba and called to confirm tostones. Took a while to walk there, but it was sooooo worth it. It was the best meal I&apos;d had during the entire trip. Pricey, at $25, but worth every pennies. The tostones had an excellent crispiness and taste. The steak, unlike at most Latin restaurants I visit, was not tough. The chicharron was tasty, and I ate every bite. Even the rice and beans had a great taste--I could have eaten them by themselves with tostones and had a great meal. Only the sausage had a bit of a taste that was strong for me, but mixing it with the beans and rice made it taste just fine. I left wistfully sad that I would not be able to enjoy another meal--wish it would have been in Berlin where I was for several days.

 



Wow, it is true!!! Just the other day I was listening to a brief NPR report about how Pepsi gave in to the Argentinians and changed its advertising to read &quot;Pecsi&quot;, the way they pronounce it. The report said the Argentinians pronounce other sounds differently, and I definitely heard this from the Argentenian waitress, most notably a &quot;ch&quot; sound for a double L.

When I got back to the hauptbahnhof I learned that the next train to Esslingen would take 2 1/2 hours, and then to go to Nuremberg I would not arrive until past midnight. I thought about it, waffled back and forth, and finally decided I did not want to spend nearly 8 hours traveling. I decided to just go back to Nuremberg on the train and then go from their to Ludwigsburg and Esslingen. The upside of this plan, a second crack at Caramba, for dinner, once I digested my late lunch.

OH... MY... GOD!!! FUCK BANK OF AMERICA!!! FUCK THEM ALL TO HELL FOR ETERNITY!!! THEY ARE SO EVIL!!! Reporting my card lost on Tuesday to prevent Hertz from further raping me had an unexpected side effect--they issued the new card with the credit limit reduced to $5800, barely above the balance!!! They cut $4200 of my credit limit, and that seriously affected my travel and other plans. I planned to use that credit to get back to America, for another possible trip easy, to pay my car insurance, for basically all my expenses in order to avoid spending the cash I had in the bank until I got a new job. All of a sudden, unless I could convince them tomorrow to raise it, I WAS FUCKED!!!

Even worse, I could no longer afford to cancel my Chase card, which is the one I might have given Hertz as a backup (stupid, stupid, stupid). That meant I had to pay the bogus congestiona charge penalty charge, if if had not been paid and billed already by fucking Hertz. I couldn&apos;t risk cancelling the card because that would leave me dangerously low on funds once I bought my ticket back to America. I still had to assume I would not be able to find a new contract right away, and I wanted to have several grand in the bank upon starting that job.

I&apos;m so pissed off I can hardly think straight.

Walked around to build up my appetite, and during the walk I did something extremely unusual, I bought a spurious Coca-Cola. By which I mean that I did not need the soda to accompany a meal. It had been years, I think, since I had consumed a cola when not eating, at a party or other social event, or at a club (when drink purchase required). But to drink a cola just because I was thirsty--that was something I stopped doing long ago.

Well, I did my best, but I was not able to finish the second &quot;bandeja paisa&quot;. I did well though, and I ate more that day than I had during any other day of my trip.

Meanwhile, while I try to avoid getting into philosophy or politics in discussion groups, as I used to do way too much when I was younger, I could not help but getting pulled into this
	</body>
</document>
