<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004461" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/16446427/imm-final" time="2012-07-12-20:53" support="4" score="0.006319219714816311" bingtitle="imm final. - Scribd" webtitle="imm final.">
			<query id="000567" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000822" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000819" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000840" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>Your partner puts up the money and assumes the ... either have to call a 900 number or have a credit card ... the &quot;Speedee Service System&quot; in 1948 modern fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   AMITY global BUSINESS SCHOOL “ International market ing of mc Donald’s” I’M LOVING IT…… B Y   SIRISHA ACHANTA ACKNOWLEDGEMENT I am thankful to my project guide Mrs. D. Surekha Thakur for helping me formulate this project and guiding me in its analysis and impleme ntat ion. I convey a sincere gratitude to my parents and friends for their encouragement and support. I offer a word of thanks to the almighty who gave me strength, courage and blessing to carry out a successful study. Sirisha achanta Roll No: AGV30601908001   DECLARATION I, the undersigned, hereby declare that the project report entitled inter nation al market ing of Mc Donal d’s has been written and submitted under the guidance of Mrs. D. Surekha Thakur. I further declare that it is original work done as a part o f o u r ac ad e m i c c o u r s e an d h as n o t b e e n s u b m i tt e d else where. The conclusi ons and recomme ndations writ ten in thi s pr oj ec t ar e ba se d on the da ta co l le cte d by me wh il e prep aring t his report. Sirisha Achanta Roll No: AGV30601908001 INDEX: CHAPTER1: of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
imm final.
 international marketing of mc doanlds Download or Print 9,277 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: ( 2 Ratings) Upload Date: 06/15/2009 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: mc doanlds mc doanlds ( fewer ) 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
