<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004683" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090608095741AAZIde5" time="2012-07-12-21:11" support="6" score="0.011380874155455429" bingtitle="I was in McDonalds barefoot and slipped on the floor that was ..." webtitle="I was in McDonalds barefoot and slipped on the floor that was being mopped and hurt my back. Do I have a case? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000661" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>What would you do if a person entered a fast food restaurant ... college teachers allow students to enter their ... in both cases you were looking at the menu board ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Politics&amp;Government &gt; Law&amp;Ethics &gt; Resolved Question 
 Jack Member since: 07 May 2009 Total points: 14 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
I was in McDonalds barefoot and slipped on the floor that was being mopped and hurt my back. Do I have a case?
 The manager told me that they were not responsible because a sign on the door says that shoes must be worn and because a wet floor sign was on the floor. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Sheriam Member since: 13 December 2006 Total points: 51,560 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 If you indeed like going barefoot in public, as the list of questions someone else quoted suggests, then please don&apos;t ask questions that perpetuate the *myths* that going barefoot is dangerous, that barefooters are likely to sue when they themselves mess up by not watching where they&apos;re going, and that going barefoot should be against the law and/or insurance regulations.

Looking at your previous questions, I don&apos;t for a moment believe this actually happened to you. Apart from your&apos;obsession with going barefoot&apos;and making up barefoot questions to satisfy this, bare feet can be slippery on a wet floor, but when you&apos;re barefoot you are more aware of where you walk. You will feel immediately that the floor is wet so even if you hadn&apos;t seen the&apos;wet floor&apos;sign (which are usually placed so that they&apos;re hard to miss) you probably wouldn&apos;t have slipped. I&apos;ve been barefoot for 13 years -in many McDonalds and other places, they don&apos;t have signs against bare feet here in Europe- and I&apos;ve never slipped. I *have* slipped back when I was still wearing shoes, with dressy leather-soled shoes I didn&apos;t feel how slick the floor was until it was too late. (still didn&apos;t sue or even think of suing, I take my own responsibility for where I walk, as everyone should).

And the signs on US stores reflect store/company policy only; other barefooters have checked and contrary to popular belief, there are NO laws against going barefoot in stores and restaurants. Any stores or restaurants that post signs saying&apos;by order of the Health Department&apos;are lying -or as McDonalds corporate said when confronted with the letters proving there were no State laws, it referred to their own internal Health Department and not the State or county ones (which is misleading since of course the public thinks it&apos;s the government rather than the company&apos;s HD...)

Also barefooters have checked many insurance policies and while we haven&apos;t read them all -it&apos;s much harder to prove a negative with insurance than with the government, where there is a known number of States- we have NEVER found an insurance policy that DID require or even recommended footwear for customers.

Fortunately both Health Departments and insurance companies seem to know better about the *real* risk of going barefoot (very, very small) than the general public. I can only hope that those of the public who read this will check the links below and educate themselves :-) 
Source(s):
 No laws against going barefoot in stores and restaurants:
 http://www.barefooters.org/health-dept 
More general info about going barefoot on the main page:
 http://www.barefooters.org 
and 13 years of going barefoot always and everywhere, without any trouble. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 40% 2 Votes 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; I was in McDonalds b… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (24)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by shoe1div... Member since: 02 April 2006 Total points: 11 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You can try to sue for negligence, because actually, they are not suppose to be mopping during business hours, while there are customers in the store. When I was little, I went into a MacDonald&apos;s, where they were mopping and they had the sign up, and I slipped and fell. My parents then sued for negligence, and we ended up settling out of court. Contact you a lawyer, or you can proceed with the case pro- se. Also, start going to the doctor, for treatment of your back, to help strength you case. Good luck. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Anon28 Member since: 27 May 2006 Total points: 4,822 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 This would be a case in negligence. You would have to show that they were in some way unreasonable, and if there was a wet floor sign up, that does make it hard for you.

Also, even if they WERE negligent, there is the issue of comparative negligence, meaning were you unreasonable, leading to your injuries. The fact that there is a&quot;no shirt, no shoes&quot;is unlikely to matter for this. The question is whether a reasonable person would go into a McDonald&apos;s without shoes, and whether that contributed to your injury. Depending on what jurisdiction you are in, this can have one of two effects:

1) pure comparative negligence jurisdiction: If the jury finds you are liable for 75% of your injury, and they are for 25%, they have to pay you 25% of your damages.

2) modified comparative negligence jurisdiction: if you are found to be 50%+ liable, you get nothing.

They may also bring up an issue of&quot;duty.&quot;You can only be liable for negligence if you have a duty to not be negligent towards the injured person. They can claim that since they say not to come in without shoes, they have no duty to people who do. However, there is general public access. It would be an interesting case.

At the end of the day, you likely have no case. there was pretty clear negligence on your part by not wearing shoes, and the hypo doesn&apos;t point to any particularly negligent action on their part (they have to wash the floor sometime.) In particular, it sounds like if you are in a modified comparative liability jurisdiction, you would be wasting your time. Better to just move on. Sorry. Feel better. 
Source(s):
 Just finished law school. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by John73 Member since: 21 June 2006 Total points: 7,907 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No, you don&apos;t have a case, but you wouldn&apos;t likely do very well even if you had shoes on. If a wet floor sign is posted when employees are mopping the floor, that&apos;s really the best McDonald&apos;s can do. While I am sure the restaurant tries to avoid mopping during business hours, circumstances like a spilled soda may lead to daytime mopping. In short, McDonald&apos;s was not negligent, so you would lose.

If McDonald&apos;s was negligent, then the issue of your bare feet would come up as a form of comparative negligence. The restaurant&apos;s negligence would be compared to your negligence in failing to obey the NS3 instructions. In the end, I don&apos;t think the restaurant was negligent, so this issue should not even need to be considered, but if it was to be considered, I would expect an unfavorable response from a jury. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by laughter... Member since: 25 April 2006 Total points: 176,820 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 There are a couple principles involved. The first is negligence. McD&apos;s is not a guarantor of your safety. Any claim would have to be based on some claim of negligence. You didn&apos;t mention any. The other is called&quot;assumption of the risk.&quot;If you knowingly encounter a hazard, (by seeing the wet floor and walking on it) you assume the risk of any resulting injury. Then there is comparative negligence. If you did not look where you were going, then you are at least as much as fault as the person that mopped the floor.
That being said, taking legal advice from the person you might have a claim against is generally unwise. No rule of law requires that person to agree with you or to give good advice even if they had intentionally injured you. If you want legal advice, hire a lawyer instead of asking the manager of a McDs. If you want a burger, go to McDs instead of to your lawyer. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by jackson Member since: 18 March 2006 Total points: 44,321 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No case......

The store showed normal due diligence by putting a wet floor sign up.

Sign on the door says you must wear shoes. You did not. A judge will laugh you out of court at McDonalds won&apos;t even have need to give any settlement. They would probably turn around and go after you for THEIR legal costs. And since it is such a large corporation that could be quite a huge sum.

Having the huge bank of legal backup they could keep this in court forever. You would need to pay a lawyer each time and then to find out that they filed for a continuance.... still have to pay a lawyer. McDonalds would outspend you till you caved. And then demand all of their legal fees dealing with this.

You probably would not even find one to take the case. Even if you found a personal injury lawyer that would when all is said and done the lawyer would end up with most all of it.

If there was no wet floor sign and you were wearing shoes of course they would be forced to deal with you. But this is not the case in your situation.

Just being honest. But I will say that join the normal world.... wear shoes. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Death Scouter Member since: 02 June 2009 Total points: 2,646 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You have&quot;shared liability&quot;or&quot;shared culpability&quot;in this case.

First... you didn&apos;t belong PAST the threshold because you were without shoes.

Second... you had no traction because you were shoeless

Third... they PROBABLY had a&quot;wet floor&quot;sign, which pretty much absolves them of any wrong-doing as slippery situation was clear.

In order to win, you&apos;d have to prove they are liable for you slipping... in a place you didn&apos;t belong..... in a condition you didn&apos;t belong.... ignoring the situation in which you were personally responsible. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by (Ken doll) Member since: 12 June 2008 Total points: 2,311 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You sure like bare feet, don&apos;t you?:

Would you mind if at a baseball game the person behind you put their barefeet on the empty chair next to you?
In Etiquette - Asked by Jack - 1 answer - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

What would you do if a person entered a fast food restaurant barefoot and sat next to you?
In Etiquette - Asked by Jack - 16 answers - 2 weeks ago - In Voting

If your friend wanted to go into a fast food place barefoot, would you go with him/her?
In Other - Dining Out - Asked by Jack - 17 answers - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

I&apos;m obsessed with being barfoot, even in public. Are there other people like me and why am I like this?
In Other - Society&amp;Culture - Asked by Jack - 9 answers - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

I&apos;m obsessed with being barefoot, even in public. Are there other people like me and why am I like this?
In Other - Society&amp;Culture - Asked by Jack - 2 answers - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

I&apos;m obsessed with being barefoot, even in public. Are there other people like me and why am I like this?
1 In Psychology - Asked by Jack - 6 answers - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

Should I go barefoot in public for my boyfriend?
In Other - Society&amp;Culture - Asked by Jack - 17 answers - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

If you got a new job at a small office where half the people are always barefoot would you do it too?
2 In Other - Society&amp;Culture - Asked by Jack - 6 answers - 2 weeks ago - Resolved

If you got a new job in a small office where people always walk around barefoot would you do it too?
In Fashion&amp;Accessories - Asked by Jack - 10 answers - 3 weeks ago - Resolved

Should college teachers allow students to enter their classes barefoot?
In Etiquette - Asked by Jack - 11 answers - 4 weeks ago - Resolved

Should teachers allow students to enter their classes barefoot?
In Higher Education (University +) - Asked by Jack - 3 answers - 4 weeks ago - Resolved

What would you do if a person entered a public library barefoot and sat next to you?
In Other - Society&amp;Culture - Asked by Jack - 10 answers - 4 weeks ago - Resolved

Store owners, do you mind cusotmers entering your store barefoot?
In Other - US Local Businesses - Asked by Jack - 4 answers - 1 month ago - Resolved

Why do people leave their flip-flops on when sitting somewhere in public? Isn&apos;t it more comfortable barefoot?
In Other - Society&amp;Culture - Asked by Jack - 8 answers - 1 month ago - Resolved

If you owned a restaurant would you allow customers to enter barefoot?
3 In Etiquette - Asked by Jack - 58 answers - 1 month ago - Resolved 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Sophist Member since: 25 May 2006 Total points: 88,462 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Strangely, all that doesn&apos;t make any difference. All you have to do is convince a judge or jury that McDonald&apos;s owes you. Your lawyer will probably recommend a sum that McDonalds will accept without going to court. They get sued all the time for this. It is cheaper for them to pay you to shut up and go away than to fight it. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Crazycud... Member since: 21 August 2007 Total points: 8,403 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 no you can not sue...on every store or restaurant it states..no shoes, no shirt no service..

you walked in at your own risk..you do not have a case 
Source(s):
 not to mention this is mcdonalds why would you go barefoot in there in the first place ewwww 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Yo it&apos;s Me Member since: 17 September 2006 Total points: 41,943 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 NO. If I were the manager I would have called the cops on you for disobeying a law meant to protect you, McDonalds and other customers. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by ♪♥§♫Arizona Chick♫§♥♪ Member since: 10 May 2007 Total points: 6,828 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 How come you weren&apos;t wearing shoes in the first place?
You would lose that one.
You would have a case if you were wearing shoes and fell because there wasnt a&quot;wet floor&quot;sign. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Golden Member since: 15 March 2009 Total points: 80,661 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 you said it yourself, you had no shoes on and the wet floor had a sign. had you worn shoes, you might have a case. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Matt Member since: 11 April 2008 Total points: 3,360 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 If the business policy was for customers to wear shoes and there was a&quot;wet floor&quot;sign, you have absolutely no case. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by camille Member since: 27 March 2009 Total points: 2,317 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No case you didn&apos;t follow the rules. so if these things must be worn inside then you forfeited anything coming because you yourself was negligent 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Charles Member since: 20 May 2009 Total points: 550 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No you don&apos;t, plus if there was a sign on the floor saying wet floor and you were supposed to be wearing shoes then heck no 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 5 people rated this as good 
 by Because I said so Member since: 13 January 2007 Total points: 35,596 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It would probably depend on the jury but you certainly don&apos;t deserve anything. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by xtina Member since: 10 March 2007 Total points: 19,711 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No shirt, no shoes, no service. But I suppose a slip&apos;n fall lawyer might make a case for U. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by Me Member since: 01 December 2007 Total points: 5,883 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 There were two signs. You ignored them both. I say you don&apos;t have much of a case. Sorry. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by gmrfl Member since: 16 June 2008 Total points: 64 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 probably not, i dont think they allow people to wlk bafefoot in the resturant 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 5 people rated this as good 
 by Lexie Member since: 20 April 2009 Total points: 27,577 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I doubt it. I think the manager was right. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 8 people rated this as good 
 by Nvr2soon Member since: 20 July 2007 Total points: 11,542 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Get a job like the rest of us. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by wizjp Member since: 06 April 2006 Total points: 440,476 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 You got nothing here. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 20% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by ? Member since: 09 June 2009 Total points: 97 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 NOOO
free money dont come so easy !!! 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 

 by Lordpercywooster XXV Member since: 15 May 2009 Total points: 9,785 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Answer hidden due to its low rating
 so he admits his floors are dangerous while not stopping you?
that is teh equivalent to have a sign that says road ends here but no barrier, did teh sign say floors not safe for beare foot people, no it just said that its a macdosnalds rule, which your obliged to follow
doesnt the sign say no shirt no shoes no service? it doesnt say this floor unsafe for people with no shoes
I bet in discovery there are thousands of cases whey had shoes on and slipped so it wasnt being barefoot that was the problem it was their nrgligence
the sign wasnt in a prominate place you didnt see it
he also admits his floor were wet but didnt take any action to stop you?
where where teh barriers ?
in both cases you were looking at the menu board and look up as mcdonals are designed to do
faulty design of mcdonalds

he is done , sue he has already admited liablity
the baove answers are rubbish, you cant wigle out of libility 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Law&amp;Ethics 

 Is there anyway of taking legal action against an anonymous accusation? Can i get a licence in another state if i&apos;m disqualified ? Question regarding copyright infringement? Do common law couples in texas have power of attorney? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Are you allowed to film in a McDonalds during business hours? Is it illegal to send a McDonalds double cheeseburger through… Can I sue Mcdonalds for having beef in their french fries? Is it legal for McDonalds to not give high school students water? How much is a 1967 Mcdonalds employee Uniform worth? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Politics&amp;Government 
 Civic Participation Elections Embassies&amp;Consulates Government Immigration International Organisations Law&amp;Ethics Law Enforcement&amp;Police Military Other - Politics&amp;Government Politics 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 The black belt gu… 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
