<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004940" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100223034525AAglwtd" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="6" score="0.018403355790837687" bingtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Which metro manila fast food chains accept credit ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Which metro manila fast food chains accept credit card for delivery?">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>and drop it onto the &quot;Home&quot; icon. Select &quot;Yes&quot; from the pop up window. Nothing ... Which metro manila fast food chains accept credit card for delivery? 2 years ago</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Philippines &gt; Manila &gt; Resolved Question 
 Cougcat Member since: April 07, 2009 Total points: 186 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Which metro manila fast food chains accept credit card for delivery?

 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Abet Member since: March 03, 2010 Total points: 656 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Pizza hut and Shakey&apos;s all of pizza fast food chain. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 67% 2 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Which metro manila f… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by ツ The §hining Knight ツ Member since: June 27, 2009 Total points: 12,006 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Most of them... 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Ozeki Member since: June 14, 2006 Total points: 38,193 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yes usually, if not just pay with tuyo 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Manila 

 Where can I find the nearest Cakes and pastries shop In Manila? I need a steak house/grill resto name please? What is the best buffet here in manila? Where to buy an extended battery for sony ericsson xperia play in the philippines? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Philippines 
 Baguio Boracay Cebu Davao Makati Manila Other - Philippines Paranaque Pasig Quezon City Tagaytay 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
