<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004756" url="http://www.seekglasses.com/news_2007-9-1/50731.html" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="2" score="0.002127928735155417" bingtitle="Four letters to McDonald&apos;s success: QSCV--International News ..." webtitle="Four letters to McDonalds success: QSCV--International News--SeekGlasses.com,Seek for Glasses all over the world.">
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001243" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>... been recognized as one of the world famous fast food restaurant ... It is such a rigorous selection system and improve ... 31 Japan-China PP market plastic warehouse receipts ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Seekglasses. Home | Sing In | Jion Free | Blacklist | About Us | Site Map | Glasses Shop 
 
 Popular Searches: frames 3D glasses Glasses brand Optician&apos;s Glass lens glasses 

 Home Men&apos;s Glasses Women&apos;s Glasses Bifocals&amp;Progressive Goggles New Arrivals Discount Glasses   (0) 

   Four letters to McDonald&apos;s success: QSCV   
  In 1937, brothers Mike and Dick McDonald&apos;s McDonald&apos;s in East Los Angeles opened a restaurant car. They make the burgers delicious inexpensive, welcomed by customers. Although every hamburger sold only 15 cents, but still an annual turnover of more than 25 million U.S. dollars. However, as more and more other vehicles restaurant, business has become increasingly difficult.
  In response, McDonald&apos;s franchise bold brothers, began to sell McDonald&apos;s franchises. In 1953, a man named Fox who is only paid to the McDonald brothers $ 1,000, we have obtained a McDonald&apos;s franchise, in Phoenix opened a McDonald&apos;s fast food restaurant. However, in the early days, stores and fast payment a week in addition to access to the basic description of the service, the other nothing. Both financially and in business, the franchise must be entirely on its own. Precisely because of this, many McDonald&apos;s franchisees will arbitrarily change the taste of McDonald&apos;s hamburgers or business variety, seriously damaged the reputation of McDonald&apos;s. More than a dozen McDonald&apos;s franchises in the business conditions generally shrouded in the shadow of failure.
  At this time, Crocker appeared. At the time, Crocker just a paper cup and Hunban machine salesman, but for McDonald&apos;s tremendous development potential, he also clearly than the McDonald brothers. That was when the U.S. entered the stage of rapid economic development, people&apos;s lives, to speed up the pace of work, less time for meals; in particular, a large number of individual car ownership, the way the demand for quick meal there. Crocker know, like McDonald&apos;s so clean, cost-effective, high quality and convenient fast food shops, will be popular.
  After negotiations with the McDonald brothers Crocker became the only McDonald&apos;s franchise in the U.S. agents. In 1954, Crocker as a McDonald&apos;s franchise agent for the McDonald brothers deal with the transfer of franchise matters.
  In 1961, the McDonald brothers 270 million dollars to transfer all the Kroc McDonald&apos;s, McDonald&apos;s since embarked on a rapid development by way of franchising the highway. 1968 McDonald&apos;s 1,000 stores in 1978 amounted to 5,000. After 40 years of development, McDonald&apos;s has more than 28,000 stores around the world more than 128 countries and regions. Today, McDonald&apos;s has been recognized as one of the world famous fast food restaurant, the golden arches &quot;M&quot; logo in the world market has become to understand without translation that mass culture, its corporate image is even more deeply in the minds of consumers roots.
  McDonald&apos;s restaurants in the world, 70% of the restaurant business by the franchisee management. McDonald&apos;s 13,000 U.S. stores in the franchise as high as 86%. McDonald&apos;s as the world&apos;s most successful operator of a chain, with its proud chain mode of operation, has successfully achieved the exotic market development and international operations. The development of chain operation in its history, has accumulated a lot of very valuable experience. According to the British research laboratory in the business concluded the following for reference.
  First of all, Crocker change the original concessionaire McDonald&apos;s system by the people and promise them unrelated condition, he thought the franchise&apos;s success depends on people by the promise of success. Only when each subject Xuren Fu Yu and the entire franchise system to become more powerful. Therefore, the Crocker attaches great importance to the operation of stores. Early on, every franchise license fee is only $ 950, the other cost is based on a franchise fee of 1.9% of turnover, so the headquarters of the operating profits and is strongly associated stores, headquarters and stores in the economic interest is consistent.
  Franchising is often affected by the general headquarters of the temptation of money and &quot;exploitation&quot; stores, such as high license fees received, sale of raw materials, equipment and other products to franchisees, thereby undermining the long-term relations of cooperation. Crocker firmly opposed to this practice. In the McDonald&apos;s franchise system, the headquarters is the main source of income to pay the license fees and franchise royalties, and for stores to provide advice and guidance and other services. Although the stores sell some equipment and products, but insisted on not profiteering. In procurement, Crocker insisted on the principle of closing commission to allow stores to enjoy the benefits of collective purchasing.
  McDonald&apos;s franchisees in good faith in exchange for loyalty. Mutual restraint, coexistence and common prosperity partnership recount for joining to create the conditions so that all franchisees after another good way of marketing, which in turn enhance the value for the McDonald&apos;s brand has achieved a lot. For example, swept the world, &quot;Ronald McDonald&quot; is a successful franchisees and advertising companies created, enabled and promoted by head office. &quot;Joint Advertising Foundation&quot; mode is established by McDonald&apos;s franchisees, headquarters used to be. UK Venture Lab believes it is the franchisee&apos;s reasonable proposals for the formation of the corporation power to promote the reform of the company, thus increasing the market competitiveness of McDonald&apos;s brand, to achieve a win-win results.
  Secondly, not a regional franchise system. Although the sale of the concession area is easier to make money, but also increases the risk. If a franchise is not successful, the trouble is not too large; but if the store has franchises throughout the region, then the consequences can imagine. In Crocker&apos;s view, &quot;If you sell a large concession area, it is equal to all local business to him. His organization instead of your organization, you will lose control.&quot; Therefore, the first McDonald&apos;s franchise restaurant selling only one. Meanwhile, McDonald&apos;s provides franchisees with outstanding performance can have a number of stores, while the poor performance of the franchisees can own a shop.
  Moreover, McDonald&apos;s franchisees in the financial position of a very clear and strict requirements. Prior to joining the beginning, franchisees must pay the initial fee. If the franchisees are buying a new store, you will need to pay 40% of the total cost; if the old shops, franchisees need to pay the cost of only 25%. The funds have to come from its own funds the individual franchisees, franchisees held that cash, equities, bonds and so on. Because each store is different, so the amount of franchise fee charged does not strictly quantified. Usually personal, non-borrowed funds in the $ 175,000 or more, McDonald&apos;s will consider whether to participate to join us. A few cases, McDonald&apos;s also allows equipment rental, this is only for those who are particularly good candidates. These people may not be able to McDonald&apos;s own funds requirements, but they are quite good in all aspects of the other, even more than the usual standard. In this case, the model can be used equipment leasing, purchase equipment on behalf of the McDonald&apos;s first, and will lease them to franchisees. But even so, McDonald&apos;s franchisees are still required at least have 10 million or more of its own funds. Of course, money is not paid in vain. McDonald&apos;s franchisees to provide a set of employee training, human resources, service operations, design, marketing, machinery and equipment and procurement of services to ensure the performance of stores and McDonald&apos;s brand consistency, establishing a leading position in McDonald&apos;s. Operational consultant to join McDonald&apos;s franchise system from the beginning to start providing one on one services to help franchisees to McDonald&apos;s QSCV standards. The past 10 years, McDonald&apos;s hamburgers in the regional establishment of the International University, the world has seven, respectively, in Germany, Brazil, Australia, Japan, the United States, Britain and Hong Kong each year more than 5,000 students from around the world to the hamburger University participation in training courses. It is such a rigorous selection system and improve the follow-up services to ensure the success of McDonald&apos;s often joining a to a.
  Finally, unified for all franchisees, McDonald&apos;s unique business approach. In fact, early in the northeast of Crocker in Chicago opened the first truly modern McDonald&apos;s franchise, the store reflects the Crocker on the operating principle, that is, attention to quality, service, health and economic benefits, McDonald&apos;s is well-known strategic significance QSCV.
  Q (Quality) is quality, quality. McDonald&apos;s high standards of raw materials, not round and cut the bread do not have grievances, milk mixture to cargo temperature to below 4 ℃, the high was to return. A small number of beef patties to go through 40 quality control checks. Have a shelf life of any materials, lettuce ingredients from the freezer to get only 2 hours on stage the shelf, throw out of date. Using computer-controlled production process and standard operating, the fat content of hamburger should be between 17 to 20.5 percent, and reject the use of additives; meat pie also provides 83% of the shoulder must be 17% of the finest meat and pork, mixed; French fries, potato is specifically used for training, carefully selected, and after the appropriate storage time to adjust the content of starch and sugar. If more than 7 minutes fries, hamburgers are not sold more than 10 minutes, we should throw away generously, because McDonald&apos;s is always on the customer&apos;s commitment to quality, customers can enjoy the freshest, most authentic taste of food, in order to establish a high degree of credit.
  S (Service) is the service, including shop building comfort, convenience and hours of operation of the service sales staff attitude. McDonald&apos;s characteristic smile is all the employees are smiling, cheerful place and talk to customers, work, make customers feel satisfied. Staff entered the McDonald&apos;s to accept the system of training. Staff to implement fast, accurate and friendly service, customers do not line up more than 2 minutes; to be completed in the customer point of the food, the waiter to the food within a minute to the customer. The restaurant also offers a variety of services, such as birthday parties for children have fun, to groups ordering and free delivery services.
  C (Cleanliness) refers to the health, clean. McDonald&apos;s employee specification, there is a provision that &quot;Instead of resting against the wall, it is better to clean up and&quot; tens of thousands of stores around the world that all employees must comply with this provision. Employees engaged in the operation of the former must be strictly sterilized with a bactericidal hand sanitizer, rubbing hands provided at least 20 seconds and then rinse, then dry the hand dryer. If contact with the hair, clothes and other things we should re-hand disinfection, the staff in various positions to be constantly doing cleaning work. All of the plate, the machine will be thoroughly cleaned and disinfected after the closing, to scrub clean the floor, in front of the restaurant have to keep clean.
  V (Value) is the value, meaning &quot;to provide the most valuable high-quality goods to customers.&quot; McDonald&apos;s food was scientific ratio, nutrient-rich and the price is reasonable. In a clean environment for customers to enjoy fast food nutrition, these factors combined, called &quot;value for money.&quot; The gradual formation of the modern society of the need for high quality standards, and consumer preferences have become diversified, McDonald&apos;s Value, is to create and add new value.
  As a rule, every McDonald&apos;s hamburger franchises variety, quality, price must be consistent, and even store decoration and service are exactly the same way. Use of all McDonald&apos;s spices, meat and vegetable quality standards by the head office of uniform provisions. In order to enable the stores are able to achieve satisfactory service to consumers and standardization, McDonald&apos;s has established a strict inspection and supervision system. There are three McDonald&apos;s system, check system: First, the regular monthly evaluation, the second inspection of the company headquarters and the third is random, that is the shops in selected once a year. Regional Steering regular customers often visit stores as to the freshness of food, temperature and taste, floors, ceilings, walls, tables and chairs are clean and tidy, and the tellers, customer service attitude and speed. UK business laboratory that it is this strict rules and inspection system so that the customer into any McDonald&apos;s anywhere in the restaurant, saw the building exterior, interior furnishings, food specifications and attendant behaviors, dress and strikingly similar, and many other aspects, but also can give customers enjoy the same standard.
  It is with this philosophy as the core of a McDonald&apos;s set a record of the world&apos;s largest chain system. UK business lab found not only in the United States, even in Japan, the McDonald&apos;s chain, represented by the industry, and rarely by the impact of socio-economic conditions.
  McDonald&apos;s success has made it worthy of a benchmark company in this area, it is the later franchise business and learning to savor.   Related glasses News   Frame a pair of glasses, you have the unique qualities of  (2007-9-1)   Even though there is a saying: If you want to be the focus of everyone, please wear sunglasses indoors. This is recognized as the most convenient and most effective fashion expression, known as th... January 31 early assessment non-ferrous metals  (2008-1-31)   Copper down, short-term remains long formLondon Metal Exchange base metals fell across the board, copper early oscillations, floor trading in the fall, Zhong Pan to close at $ 7,160, down $ 131 on... January 31 Japan-China PP Plastic stock market briefly  (2008-1-31)   China Plastics Price Index fell 1.23 points to 1261.73 points; the plastic stock index fell 0.16 points to 1247.88 points.First, the upper reaches of Letters:New York Mercantile Exchange, light ... January 31 Japan-China PP market plastic warehouse receipts Comment  (2008-1-31)   First, the market overview:Today, the overall performance of warehouse receipts in the plastic PP downturn, low to continue down. Open opened low, pre-shock consolidation, after the disk is calm, ... Four letters to McDonald&apos;s success: QSCV  (2007-9-1)   In 1937, brothers Mike and Dick McDonald&apos;s McDonald&apos;s in East Los Angeles opened a restaurant car. They make the burgers delicious inexpensive, welcomed by customers. Although every hamburge... Labor Contract Law of Human Resources or training of the eight affected  (2008-1-31)   January 1, 2008 start of the &quot;Labor Contract Law&quot; to protect labor rights as a starting point, and promote long-term employment relations, and promote industrial upgrading for the purpose. That its ... SMEs on how to brand the complex challenges?  (2007-9-1)   Ironically, the large-scale advertising investment just let the public know the role played, but the real problem is often the consumer even know you still do not want to buy, this time is definite... Shortage of experienced personnel guide the market, Harbin  (2008-1-31)   Manpower shortage of hot ice and snow tourism guideIce and Snow Festival is one year, the ice city of Harbin to once again become a tourist hot. According to tourism management department statisti... Beijing talent supply and demand ratio of 1.67 compared with 1  (2008-1-31)   Beijing Municipal Personnel Bureau released the fourth quarter of last year, talent demand and supply information. Job seekers registered with the intermediary service organizations, nearly 1,516,00... 


 
 About us   |   Service   |   Payment   |   Friendly Link   |   Contact us   |   Links   |   Add to favorite 
 ©2005 Copyright:-www.seekglasses.com
Service hot line-Shenzhen:(86)-0755-26000344
	</body>
</document>
