<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004251" url="http://www.mvpsource.com/interview_dress_code.html" time="2012-07-12-20:30" support="1" score="0.0001489069542673988" bingtitle="Interview dress code - How to dress for your Interview" webtitle="Interview dress code - How to dress for your Interview">
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="182"/>
	<description>... show up at an interview disheveled and expect to ... look and what to wear to a job interview in order ... customer service type job, such as at a fast food restaurant or a ...</description>
	<body>
		Job Interview Dress Code 
 
 Home    Interview
Services    Interview
Resources    Testimonials   Join Our
Team    Contact
us   
 Interview
Dress Code - What to wear for your Interview 

There are many components to a job interview that need to be considered
in order for a person to be successful and land the perfect job. Having
the right amount of experience, a positive attitude, and a flawless
resume are just a few of the things that you need. Equally important to
whether you end up being hired is how you look during an interview. How
well groomed and well dressed you are has just as much impact on job
interview success as anything else.

Needless to say, if you show up for a job interview wearing
jeans and a t-shirt and you smell a little musty because you have not
showered for three days, the odds are pretty good that the interview
will not only be very short, but you will not get the job. This is
common sense stuff, and most people realize that they cannot show up at
an interview disheveled and expect to get the job. Unfortunately, some
people overcompensate for this and dress to the nines when it would not
necessarily be appropriate to do so. Obviously, it would not be a good
idea to show up for an interview in a tuxedo or cocktail dress.

Most people dress for their interview in the type of clothing
that they expect to be wearing if they actually get the job, but this
can be hazardous as well. If you are applying for a roofing job, for
example, you will probably be wearing jeans on the job. The problem is,
you still need to make a good first impression.

So as you can see, it can be confusing to try to figure out
how to look and what to wear to a job interview in order to have the
best possible chance of getting the job. As for hygiene and grooming,
use common sense. You should show up to the interview freshly showered,
hair styled neatly and conservatively, and women should not apply too
much makeup. Go light on the perfumes or colognes, if any at all.

As for what to wear, it does really depend on the job you are
applying for. If it is an entry level customer service type job, such
as at a fast food restaurant or a mass merchandiser store, there is no
need to show up in a power suit. For men, wearing unwrinkled khakis and
a button-down shirt or sweater should be sufficient. Women can get away
with the dress slacks and a conservative blouse, or a long dress and
cardigan sweater.

For professional positions being applied for, you will need to
step it up a notch or two for the interview. Men should really be
wearing dress slacks, dress shirt, and a tie, not to mention a jacket
that matches the slacks. Until you are aware of the protocols within
the company, do not try to show your individuality by wearing a colored
shirt or loud tie. Go with navy or black for the suit, white for the
shirt, and a subdued color for the tie. Women do well wearing either
pant or dress suits in solid dark colors.

It is important to remember shoes and accessories when
dressing for success. Tennis shoes are never going to be appropriate,
especially when worn with dress clothes, so make sure that you have the
right shoes. The shoes should match in color to the main color of your
outfit.

Men&apos;s accessories are pretty simple. Wearing a watch signifies
that you are concerned with being on time, and can give that impression
of timeliness to the interviewer. Earrings should not be worn, and if
you wear a necklace, keep it inside your shirt.

Women tend to go overboard sometimes with jewelry and other
accessories, so keep it toned down. A small necklace that complements
the outfit, small earrings, and maybe a tasteful lapel pin are
sufficient.

With a little bit of common sense and these helpful hints, your next
job interview should be just around the corner. An Interview Coach can
help you with these common question and one relative to your specific
depending on what position you are interviewing for.

 Call MVPSource today at 704- 837-8203 
 
 Click here to
find out what an Interview Coach can do for you.

 Click
here for Other
Common Interview Mistakes 
 
Click here for our  Charlotte Interview
Coaching Services 

 Also
know what to wear - read the Interview
Dress Code 

 Click
here for more Common
Mock Interview Questions and Answers 

Click here for Three
most common interview Questions 

 Click
here for more Mock Interview Prep 

Click here for Mock
Interview Services 

 Click here
for Job Search Coach 
 
 Home   Services   Resources    Testimonials   Join Our
Team   Partners    Affiliate
Program   Contact
us    Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
