<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004747" url="http://www.persadajohor.com/facilities.php" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="5" score="0.013640158358353515" bingtitle="Welcome to Persada Johor :: Our Facilities" webtitle="Welcome to Persada Johor :: Our Facilities">
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Enter your e-mail ... 401) with a nonflexible seating ... A fast-food restaurant to cater to family dining and the specific ...</description>
	<body>
		e-Newsletter Subscription 
 Enter your e-mail   Subscribe Unsubscribe 
 
 
 Group Hotels Directory Choose a destination... Puteri Pacific Johor Bahru Sibu Island 
 Resort Johor Hotel
 Selesa Johor Bahru Hotel
 Selesa Pasir Gudang Selesa
 Beach Resort Port Dickson Johor Corporation 
 
 
 
 Cafe&amp;Restaurant | DOWNLOAD PERSADA JOHOR BROCHURE 
 
 
   
 
 
 Our Facilities   
 
 Persada Johor Floor Plans 
 Dimension and Capacity Information 
 
 
 
 
PERSADA JOHOR BROADBAND INTERNET CHARGES
 
Store value Pre-paid Card: 30-min Card (within 12 hrs). - RM20 
Store value Pre-paid Card: 60-min Card (within 12 hrs) - RM40 
Store value Pre-paid Card: 24-hr Card (within 3 days) - RM100 
Unlimited Access 30-day Card (within 30 days) - RM400 
 
 
   ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ For reservations and new 2010 seminar packages, please contact our Sales Team at :- Tel : 07-219 9962/ 07-219 9958        Fax : 07-223 5522 Email : info@persadajohor.com ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------ 
 
 
   
 Convention Halls 301, 302, 303&amp;Meeting Rooms 304, 305, 306&amp;307 
 Persada Johor’s main Convention Hall (3,078 sq.m.) has a highly modular floor layout that can be easily converted into three smaller fully soundproofed Convention Halls: Hall 301 (1,058 sq.m.) with a maximum capacity of 1,000 persons; Hall 302 (902 sq.m.) with a maximum capacity of 900 persons; and Hall 303 (903 sq.m.) with a maximum capacity of 900 persons. All Convention Hall capacities stated are in theatre-style but fully convertible to reception, classroom and banquet arrangements. 
 
   
   Exhibition Halls 101 and 102 
 Exhibition Hall comprises two separate halls that can be combined to offer a total floor space of 3,070 sq m (33,051 sq ft), which can be used for exhibitions, conventions, banquets, concerts, trade shows and sporting events. Exhibition Hall 101 (1,931 sq m) is able to accommodate 100 booths of 3m x 3m stands with a ceiling height of 9 metres, while Exhibition Hall 102 (1,140 sq m) can accommodate 50 booths with a limited ceiling height of 4.5 metres.   
   Gallery Level, Auditorium&amp;Meeting Rooms 402 and 403 
 
At the Gallery Level (Level 4), there are two meeting rooms (402 and 403) that can accommodate 60 persons each, and an auditorium (401) with a nonflexible seating capacity of 84 persons. At the Convention Hall Level (Level 3), there are four meeting rooms: Room 304 (60 persons), Room 305 (60 persons), Room 306 (120 persons). All Meeting Room capacities stated are in theatrestyle arrangement but fully convertible to reception, classroom and banquet arrangements.
   
   Restoran Selasih @ Persada Johor Culinary Excellence All Around You 
 
The Selasih Malay Restaurant is just about the only place in Johor Bahru offering up market Malay-style dining. There’s deliciously authentic Johorean cuisine and all day dining, either from the a la carte menu or its tantalizing buffets. Open daily from 7.00am to 10.30pm.

A fast-food restaurant to cater to family dining and the specific needs of children.
 A selection of mobile restaurants that come looking for you. The mobile restaurants are unique features at Persada Johor, serving fresh, hot and chilled food, as well as snack items in mobile units. Hot drinks are also ready to be served. Visit Restoran Selasih 
 
 
 
 
 
 HOME | ABOUT PERSADA | CORPORATE INFO | OUR SERVICES | OUR FACILITIES | WEDDING | EVENT CALENDAR | PROMOTIONS | CONTACT US   
 Site 
 Map | Privacy 
 Policy | Terms&amp;Conditions Copyright©Persada Johor International 
 Convention Centre. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
