<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004367" url="http://www.avvo.com/legal-answers/found-bug-roach-in-food-while-eating-at-restaurant-7609.html" time="2012-07-12-20:37" support="17" score="0.05679751931733867" bingtitle="Found bug/roach in food while eating at restaurant, under TX law ..." webtitle="Found bug/roach in food while eating at restaurant, under TX law personal injury lawsuit due to making me sick - Avvo.com">
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000044" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001030" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000236" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>I went to a fast food restaurant and there was a fried roach in my food and when I presented to the manager..all she could do was say eeww thats nasty, now I had ...</description>
	<body>
		We&apos;ve detected that your browser does not support scripting. 
Scripting must be enabled to use Avvo. Turn on scripting and reload this page. 
Expert Advice When You Need It Most

 Sign in with: Sign in Register Are you a Lawyer? 
 
 LEGAL HEALTH 

 Research Legal Advice Ask a Lawyer Find a Lawyer Review Your Lawyer 
 Legal Advice 
 Lawyers Doctors Dentists Legal Advice Health Advice 
 Home  &gt;  Legal  &gt;  Research Legal Advice  &gt;  Personal Injury  &gt;  Found bug/roach in food while eating at restaurant, under TX law persona... 
 Found bug/roach in food while eating at restaurant, under TX law personal injury lawsuit due to making me sick 
 Flag 
Asked almost 4 years ago - Tyler, TX

 Lawsuits Personal Injury 
 
Loading...
 
I went to a fast food restaurant and there was a fried roach in my food and when I presented to the manager..all she could do was say eeww thats nasty, now I had taken a bite before I noticed it, I asked everyone that was at the table to verify what I had found, this made me sick and no one ate their food that was purchased.. I feel like this is was handled wrongfully by the company. What legal action can I take?
 Save Tweet 
Attorney answers (3) 

 Licensed in TX 
 Robert A. Kraft Pro 
 Dallas Personal Injury Lawyer Contributor Level 10 
4
 Helpful votes 
 Answered August 17, 2008 20:01 . The situation was certainly mishandled from a public relations standpoint. Pardon the pun, but it left a bad taste in your mouth for this restaurant, and I&apos;m sure your friends feel the same way. The restaurant should have apologized and let everyone eat for free, or perhaps given everyone a gift certificate for a meal some other time.

Unfortunately, you probably shouldn&apos;t expect the restaurant to do much more than that for you. In Texas you can&apos;t file suit for what MIGHT HAVE happened. You can only recover for damages you actually did suffer, and Texas courts are very unfriendly to emotional distress claims. In other words, if you haven&apos;t suffered significant physical injuries, it&apos;s tough to make a financial recovery.

I think you will have a hard time finding a lawyer to take this case, but you do have the right to file suit yourself in small claims court. You can just go to the nearest Justice of the Peace court, and the clerks there will help you with the paperwork.

Good luck to you! 
 
 Mark as helpful Comment Flag 
 
 Oscar Michelen 
 New York Personal Injury Lawyer Contributor Level 15 
7
 Helpful votes 
 Answered August 12, 2008 08:55 . You would certainly be entitled to a refund of all of your purchases, but not much else. If you were to send a claim letter asking for dmages for emotional distress, etc., you might get the company to offer a &quot;nuisance settlement&quot; of between a few hundred to a few thousand dollars or so. Youmay wnat to look on the internet to see if this restaurant has been the subject of prior complaints and lawsuits. Fortunately, you did not ingest the insect or require any medical treatment of any kind. If you had then the damage amount might be sigificantly higher. I suggest you contact a qualified attorney in your area to see if they will take your case on. Most will do so on a contingency basis and not charge you unles they recover a settlement. 
 
 Mark as helpful 1 comment Flag 
 
 Alan James Brinkmeier 
 Chicago Personal Injury Lawyer Contributor Level 20 
2
 Helpful votes 
 Answered October 29, 2009 17:43 . You will need to prove damages to be successful. Disgust about a bug will not be enough to make a lawsuit worthwhile.

Write to the store and perhaps you will get some coupons and an apology.

Good luck to you.

God bless.

NOTE: This answer is made available by the out-of-state lawyer for educational purposes only. By using or participating in this site you understand that there is no attorney client privilege between you and the attorney responding. This site should not be used as a substitute for competent legal advice from a licensed professional attorney that practices in the subject practice discipline and with whom you have an attorney client relationship along with all the privileges that relationship provides. The law changes frequently and varies from jurisdiction to jurisdiction. The information and materials provided are general in nature, and may not apply to a specific factual or legal circumstance described in the question. 
 
 Mark as helpful Comment Flag 
 
 
Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Ask a Lawyer 

Get free answers from experienced attorneys.
   Enter your question 
 Ask now 
   Add details City and state 
*All fields required
 Cancel 
 20,087 answers this week

 2,014 professionals answering
 
Ask a Lawyer

 Ask a Lawyer 

Get answers from top-rated lawyers.

 It&apos;s FREE It&apos;s easy It&apos;s anonymous 


 20,087 answers this week

 2,014 professionals answering
 
Find Personal Injury Lawyers
 
 Atlanta (731) Miami (776) Boston (366) San Diego (466) Chicago (990) San Francisco (467) Dallas (1367) Seattle (869) Los Angeles (701) New York (1331) 
 
Expert Advice When You Need It Most
 
 
Avvo Legal

 Ask a Lawyer Find a Lawyer Free Legal Advice Review a Lawyer 
 
Avvo Health

 Ask a Doctor or Dentist Find a Doctor Find a Dentist Free Medical Advice Review a Doctor Review a Dentist 
 
For Professionals

 For Lawyers For Doctors For Dentists Claim Your Profile For Law Firms For Medical Groups For Dental Groups 
 
Company Info

 About Us Jobs Avvo Blog Support Partner With Us Naked Law Blog Naked Health Blog 
 
 
FOLLOW US ON 

 ©2012 Avvo, Inc. All Rights Reserved | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Community Guidelines 
 We&apos;ve detected that your browser does not support scripting. 
Scripting must be enabled to use Avvo. Turn on scripting and reload this page.
	</body>
</document>
