<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004851" url="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118715/trivia" time="2012-07-12-21:21" support="1" score="0.0005735965623757369" bingtitle="The Big Lebowski (1998) - Trivia - IMDb" webtitle="The Big Lebowski (1998) - Trivia - IMDb">
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>The fast-food restaurant In &amp; Out Burger is referred to during the movie, for which John ... Pete also told the Coens about a story where his car was stolen and ...</description>
	<body>
		IMDb More All Titles TV Episodes Names Companies Keywords Characters Videos Quotes Bios Plots Register | Login | Help 
 Movies 
 In Theaters Coming Soon Top Movies Showtimes Trailers Watchlist MyMovies New: DVD&amp;Blu-Ray Top 250 Genres Editors&apos; Spotlight Independent Film Summer Movie Guide 
 TV 
 TV Home TV Listings TV Episodes&amp;Clips Best TV Series 
 News 
 Top News Movie News TV News Celebrity News Featured News 
 Trailers 
 Trailer Gallery 
 Community 
 Message Boards Contributor Zone Newest Lists Your Lists Your Ratings 
 IMDbPro 
 IMDbPro IMDb Resume 
 Apps 
 Apps Home iPhone App iPad App Android Phones App Android Tablets App IMDb App on Kindle Fire Windows Phone App IMDb Trivia App IMDb Buzz App IMDb Mobile Site 
 
 Your Watchlist Edit 
 ◄  The Big Lebowski (1998) 
 
Did You Know?

 Trivia Goofs Crazy Credits Connections 
 Showing all 62 items Jump to: Cameo  (3)  | Spoilers  (4) The screenplay was written with Jeff Bridges , John Goodman , Steve Buscemi and Sam Elliott in mind.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The bowling alley scenes were filmed at the former Holly Star Lanes near Santa Monica and the 101 Freeway exit ramp. The bowling alley has since been torn down and a new elementary school stands in its place.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The house in which the dude meets with Jackie Treehorn was designed by architect John Lautner. The movie makes it look as though it sits on the beach, in actuality it sits on the side of a hill overlooking the city of Los Angeles.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: A lot of the Dude&apos;s clothes in the movie were Jeff Bridges &apos;s own clothes, including his Jellies sandals.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Almost all the music on the soundtrack is revealed to be playing on a radio at some point. Examples: &quot;The Man in Me&quot; in the first dream sequence fades out after The Dude wakes up, but we still hear it, tinny and distant on his Walkman. &quot;Hotel California&quot; plays through out the entire scene with Jesus at the bowling alley, and even during the brief flashback, apparently as a song playing on the alley&apos;s PA system. The big band music that plays as The Dude leaves his house fades and is heard playing on Da Fino&apos;s car radio as they talk. Additionally, at the beginning of the film, the opening song, &quot;Tumblin&apos; Tumbleweeds&quot;, fades into a muzak version of itself as the Dude shops for his creamer in the grocery store; when it cuts to the Dude outside the store, the song has faded back into its original version.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Nearly all of the visible symbols in The Dude&apos;s second dream sequence are taken from earlier scenes: - the black and white tile is seen earlier in the Big Lebowski&apos;s entry way when The Dude walks with Brandt and again at the end - the tool belt and workman outfit The Dude is seen wearing is identical to the one worn by Karl Hungus in Logjammin&apos; - Saddam Hussein is mentioned briefly by Walter in the car outside the bowling alley; in the opening credits, we see a man looking a bit similar to Saddam spraying the bowling shoes at the alley - Maude&apos;s gold bowling ball bra cups are taken from bowling balls seen on the rack behind Walter in an earlier scene at the bowling alley - the scissors wielded by the red-clad Nihilists are seen in a painting with a red background on Maude&apos;s wall - the red-on-black bowling ball is the same as the one in the earlier dream sequence and is also visible on the rack behind Walter and The Dude at the bowling alley. - The initial scene of The Dude&apos;s exaggerated walking in while casting a big shadow is similar to his landlord&apos;s shadow dance to &quot;Pictures at an Exhibition.&quot; - Maude Lebowski&apos;s trident is from a statue at The Big Lebowski&apos;s home.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude was based on independent film promoter Jeff Dowd (aka Jeff &quot;The Dude&quot; Dowd), who helped the Coen brothers secure distribution for their first feature, Blood Simple. . Like his fictional counterpart, Dowd was a member of the Seattle Seven and takes a casual approach to grooming and dress. The Port Huron Statement that The Dude refers to himself as being one of the original authors of, is a real document/statement written by The Students for a Democratic Society at a national convention meeting in, Michigan, June 11-15, 1962. Jeff Dowd was not one of those students, being not quite 13 years old, as he was born on November 20, 1949.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The fictional German techno-pop band in the movie, Autobahn, is a parody of (or homage to) the legendary electronic band Kraftwerk . The Autobahn album cover is stylistically similar to the cover of the Kraftwerk album &quot;The Man-Machine,&quot; and the group name Autobahn is the name of a Kraftwerk song. The title of Autobahn&apos;s album &quot;Nagelbett&quot; is German for nail bed. In Swedish, Peter Stormare &apos;s native tongue, it means nail bite.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The fast-food restaurant In&amp;Out Burger is referred to during the movie, for which John Goodman once did a commercial.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The private detective that&apos;s following Lebowski says that Bunny&apos;s family is from a farm &quot;outside Moorhead, Minnesota&quot;. Moorhead is the home town of Jeff Bridges &apos; wife and is located directly across the state line from Fargo. ( Fargo was the title of the Coen brothers&apos; previous film). Bunny&apos;s high school cheer-leading photo shows her wearing orange and black, the real school colors of Moorhead.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The reason Steve Buscemi &apos;s character, Donny, is constantly being told to &quot;Shut the fuck up!&quot; by Walter ( John Goodman ), is because Buscemi&apos;s character in Fargo would not shut up.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The word &quot;dude&quot; is used around 161 times in the movie. 160 spoken and once in text in the credits for &quot;Gutterballs&quot; the second dream sequence.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The F-word or a variation of the F-word is used 292 times.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude says &quot;man&quot; 147 times in the movie, nearly 1.5 times a minute.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude has a habit of repeating phrases he hears from other characters. The George Bush speech &quot;This aggression will not stand&quot; is repeated by the Dude. Maude Lebowski uses the phrase &quot;Parlance of our times&quot; Dude repeats this one in the limo. The Big Lebowski says he &quot;Will not abide another toe!&quot; at the end of the movie &quot;The Dude abides&quot;
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Premiere voted this movie as one of &quot;The 50 Greatest Comedies Of All Time&quot; in 2006.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Norwegian posters and video cassettes carried the text &quot;anbefales av norsk bowling forbund&quot; (recommended by the Norwegian Bowling Association).
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude drinks nine White Russians during the course of the movie. (He drops one of them at Jackie Treehorn&apos;s mansion.)
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Unusual for an American movie, a bad guy wields a cricket bat rather than a baseball bat.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: In the Dude&apos;s first dream sequence, the person who throws the giant bowling ball, seen out of focus and upside down as the ball rolls down the lane, is Maude.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The second time we see Treehorn&apos;s thugs, they&apos;ve swapped clothing!
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Charlize Theron was considered for the role of Bunny Lebowski.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The name on the Dude&apos;s last shirt is &quot;Art&quot;.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: One of the inspirations for the character of Walter is the Coen Brothers&apos; friend, writer-director John Milius , an infamously bombastic right-winger with an obsession with all things militaristic and an enthusiasm for guns. His girth, beard, hair style, and shades are also all reflected in Walter&apos;s physical appearance. The Coens had tried to cast Milius in the film Barton Fink in the part eventually played by Michael Lerner .
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude&apos;s car is a 4-door 1973 Ford Torino. Two vehicles were used in filming: one was destroyed during the filming, the other was destroyed in the filming of The X-Files: Salvage .
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Of all the different personalized bowling shirts Donny wears throughout the film, none of them bears his name.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Recipe for making a White Russian: 2 parts vodka, 1 part coffee liqueur (such as Kahlúa) and 1 part cream. Served with ice in a low ball glass.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude is in every scene of the movie. Even in the scene where the Nihilists are ordering pancakes you can see the van in which the Dude and Walter are driving. This is in keeping with the traditional film-noir, in which the protagonist is the narrator and acts as the audience&apos;s guide throughout the film.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The man shown bowling in the picture on The Dude&apos;s wall is President Richard Nixon . Nixon was an avid bowler; the picture in the movie is a well-publicized shot of Nixon in the bowling alley underneath the White House.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: When the John Turturro &apos;s character Jesus has to go door to door, sharing that he is a convicted sex offender, he has a large bulge in his tight pants. The bulge was formed by a bag of birdseed.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Before filming a scene, Jeff Bridges would frequently ask the Coen Brothers &quot;Did the Dude burn one on the way over?&quot; If they said he had, he would rub his knuckles in his eyes before doing a take.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: When the Dude picks Walter up, just before the money drop, we learn that Walter works at his own company: Sobchak Security.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude tells Maude he was a roadie for Metallica on their (fictional) &quot;Speed of Sound&quot; tour and refers to the band members as a &quot;bunch of assholes.&quot; Metallica themselves were flattered to be referred to in a Coen Brothers movie, with guitarist Kirk Hammett once noting in an interview that they&apos;d tried to think of a way to incorporate that scene into their live shows.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: When The Dude is thumbing through Maude&apos;s albums and pulls out the fictional &quot;Autobahn&quot; album, the album directly behind it is Herb Alpert &apos;s &quot;Whipped Cream&amp;Other Delights&quot;, an actual album.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The license plate of Bunny&apos;s red convertible spells &quot;LAPIN&quot;, French translation of rabbit (bunny).
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: In an early draft of the script, The Dude&apos;s source of income was revealed. He was an heir to the inventor of the Rubik&apos;s Cube. It was Joel Coen &apos;s idea to drop this and never say.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Flea from Red Hot Chili Peppers plays a character in a band called Autobahn, which is a jab at the German band Kraftwerk (Kraftwerk had a single called &quot;Autobahn&quot;). The two bands have played venues together in the 80&apos;s.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The lawyers that the dude mentions, are William Kunstler and Ron Kuby , radical lawyers noted for defending numerous controversial defendants including suspected terrorist leaders and the daughter of Malcolm X .
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Song titles on the &quot;Autobahn&quot; LP &quot;Nagelbett&quot; are: Saturation, Faking It, Hit and Run, No Way Out, Violate U-Blue, Beg me, Take It In, Edelweiss (Club mix).
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The photo that the Private Eye shows the Dude of Bunny Lebowski&apos;s farm is that from Truman Capote &apos;s &quot;In Cold Blood&quot;. Oddly enough, Philip Seymour Hoffman , who plays Brandt, plays Truman Capote in 2005&apos;s Capote , and &apos;Mark Pellegrino&apos;, who plays Blond Treehorn Thug, plays Dick Hickock (one of the murderers of that farm&apos;s inhabitants) in Capote .
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: John Goodman &apos;s favorite film of his own.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: In an interview with Rolling Stone magazine, John Goodman stated that The Dude referring to The Big Lebowski as a &quot;human paraquat&quot; was one of the only improvised lines to make it into the final film. Virtually every other line, including every &apos;man&apos; and &apos;dude,&apos; was scripted.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: When we&apos;re introduced to the Dude&apos;s (bowling) arch-nemesis Jesus, a flamenco version of The Eagles song &quot;Hotel California&quot; plays (and is portrayed as playing on the bowling alley&apos;s PA system). Later, we learn in the taxicab scene that the Dude &quot;...hate(s) the fuckin&apos; Eagles, man.&quot;
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude meets a lot of new people throughout the story, outside his &quot;tribe&quot;. But only three, Brandt, Jackie Treehorn and The Cowboy show enough &quot;respect&quot; for him to call him &quot;Dude&quot;.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The gun that Walter pulls in the bowling alley is a Colt model 1911 .45 caliber semi automatic handgun.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: While urinating on the Dude&apos;s rug, the Threehorn thug says &quot;Ever thus to deadbeats, Lebowski!&quot; This is a play on the Latin phrase &quot;Sic semper tyrannis!&quot; (Thus always to tyrants!), which was allegedly spoken by the murderers of Gaio Giulio Cesare and Abraham Lincoln during the assassinations.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude calls The Big Lebowski a &quot;human paraquat.&quot; Paraquat is an herbicide. During the late 1970s, a controversial program sponsored by the US government sprayed paraquat on marijuana fields in Mexico.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Dude&apos;s gait in the opening shot to the &quot;Gutterballs&quot; sequence resembles the gait used by the characters in Robert Crumb &apos;s famous &quot;Keep on Truckin&apos;&quot; cartoon.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The initials for Walter Sobchak&apos;s security company (Sobchak Security) are &quot;SS&quot;. The Jewish Walter&apos;s company shares the same initials as the Schutzstaffel, or SS. The Schutzstaffel were arguably the most demonic force of Nazi Germany. The Nuremberg Trials attributed most of the Holocaust atrocities to this group.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The $0.69 check the Dude writes at Ralph&apos;s for half and half is dated September 11, 1991, exactly ten years before the 9/11 attacks. While he is writing the check, George Bush can be heard on the television railing against Saddam Hussein .
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: DaFino refers to himself as a &quot;brother Shamus&quot;, which was a common slang term for a private investigator during the interwar years, incidentally when the Raymond Chandler story the Coen Brothers were inspired by to make this film, was written. The Dude, of course, has no idea what it means.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: According to the plaque on the dog carrier, the Pomeranian&apos;s name is Thurston.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: In a version that was edited for television broadcasts, the famous line &quot;This is what happens when you fuck a stranger in the ass!&quot; was changed to &quot;This is what happens when you find a stranger in the Alps!&quot;, which is regularly cited as one of the most &quot;creative&quot; edits made for a film to be aired on TV.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The checque that The Dude writes in the beginning of the movie, for only $0.69, is post-dated. He clearly writes the date as 9/11/91 and when he speaks to his landlord later in the movie the landlord reminds him that &quot;Tomorrow is the tenth.&quot;
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The plot and characters of The Big Lebowski basically (if creatively) follow the 1939 Raymond Chandler detective novel and 1945 Howard Hawks film noir The Big Sleep. The equivalent characters are: private detective Philip Marlowe (Humphrey Bogart)/unwilling investigator Jeffrey &quot;the Dude&quot; Lebowski (Jeff Bridges); General Sternwood (Charles Waldron), the wealthy wheelchair-bound man who summons Marlowe / Jeffrey Lebowski (David Huddleston), the wealthy wheelchair-bound man who summons the dude; Vivian Rutledge (Lauren Bacall), the wealthy man&apos;s unconventional older daughter who becomes romantically involved with Marlowe/Maude Lebowski (Julianne Moore), the the wealthy man&apos;s unconventional daughter who becomes romantically involved with the dude; Carmen Sternwood (Martha Vickers), the wealthy man&apos;s younger daughter who comes on to Marlowe and is involved with pornography/Bunny Lebowski (Tara Reid), the wealthy man&apos;s younger wife who comes on to the dude and is involved with pornography ; Arthur Geiger (Theodore von Eltz), a pornographer who has filmed Carmen Sternwood in compromising positions /Jackie Treehorn (Ben Gazzara), a pornographer who has filmed Bunny Lebowski in compromising positions.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: 
Cameo 
 Charlie Kaufman : in the audience during the interpretive dance scene. Kaufman&apos;s own script, Being John Malkovich , also contains an interpretive dance sequence.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Asia Carrera : the girl appearing opposite Bunny Lebowski and the nihilist in the porno movie that Maude shows The Dude is an actual porn star.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Aimee Mann : The musician is the nine-toed Nihilist woman who we see briefly at the diner.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: 
Spoilers 
 
The trivia items below may give away important plot points.
 Steve Buscemi dies in three of the five Coen Brothers films in which he appears (with the notable exceptions of The Hudsucker Proxy and Barton Fink ,). Additionally, with each successive role his remains are smaller: in this film, his ashes blow all over The Dude when Walter scatters them at the ocean. (See also Miller&apos;s Crossing , Barton Fink , The Hudsucker Proxy and Fargo .)
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The only time Donny doesn&apos;t get a strike is before they fight the Nihilists at the end of the movie.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: The Coen Brothers were inspired by several sources and stories. Possibly the leading source was their friend Peter Exline , who coined the phrase &quot;It really tied the room together&quot; to describe one of his own rugs. Pete and a friend of his &quot;Big&quot; Lew Abernathy (a private detective who the Coens don&apos;t know) are considered to be the partial basis for the character Walter. Pete, a Vietnam veteran and college professor, once jokingly tried to scare his students by exclaiming &quot;First Vietnam, now this?!&quot; while hitting a chair, similar to the way Walter (non-jokingly) inappropriately compares everything to Vietnam. Pete also told the Coens about a story where his car was stolen and Abernathy helped him investigate. They found the homework of a 14-year-old and, instead of telling the police, they put the homework in a plastic bag and drove out to the kid&apos;s home to confront him (though unlike the movie, the kid did not actually steal the car and Abernathy did not end the confrontation by bashing a car outside the kid&apos;s house). Another story related by Pete was the time that Abernathy was arraigned by a Santa Monica sheriff who, as in the movie, insulted him and told him to &quot;stay out of my beach community!&quot;
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: Everything Walter says to do with Bunny&apos;s kidnapping comes true. The fake kidnapping, the fake severed toe and the lack of ransom money.
 Share this Hide options Facebook   |   Twitter   |   Permalink: ad feedback Share this page: 
Quick Links:
 overview full cast and crew - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - taglines plot summary synopsis plot keywords parents guide - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - quotes trivia goofs crazy credits alternate versions connections soundtracks - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - release dates box office/business company credits filming locations technical specs literature - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - photo gallery trailers and videos posters - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - newsdesk recommendations - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - awards faq user reviews user ratings external reviews metacritic reviews message board newsgroup reviews - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - miscellaneous sound clips video clips photographs Create a list  » 
Related Lists
 250 movies that are better than the Shawshank Redemption. a list of 250 titles by whitethomas61 created 20 Mar 2011   Laughing-Out-Loud Comedies a list of 388 titles by mehransolou created 11 months ago   Watched Movies a list of 2,087 titles by k-gjorgjiev created 4 months ago   The Best Movies of All Time a list of 120 titles by tlo1996 created 3 days ago   ntv555 a list of 332 titles by morveberisi678 created 3 months ago   See all 11086 related lists  » Getting Started | Contributor Zone  » 
Contribute to This Page
 Edit page 
 
Explore More About The Big Lebowski
 
Credits
 full cast and crew 
 about WGA 

Story
 taglines 
 plot summary 
 synopsis 
 plot keywords 
 parents guide 

Did You Know?
 quotes 
 trivia 
 goofs 
 crazy credits 
 alternate versions 
 connections 
 soundtracks 
 
Details
 release dates 
 official sites 
 box office/business 
 company credits 
 filming locations 
 technical specs 
 literature 

Photos&amp;Video
 photo gallery 
 trailers and videos 
 posters 
 
Opinion
 awards 
 faq 
 user reviews 
 user ratings 
 external reviews 
 metacritic reviews 
 message board 
 newsgroup reviews 

External Links
 miscellaneous 
 sound clips 
 video clips 
 photographs 
 
Related Items
 NewsDesk 
 showtimes 

Professional Services
 get more at IMDbPro 
 add posters&amp;stills to this title 
 
 
   
 
 Home | Search | Site Index | In Theaters | Coming Soon | Top Movies | Watchlist | Top 250 | TV | News | Video | Message Boards | Press Room 
 Register | RSS | Advertising | Contact Us | Jobs | IMDbPro | IMDb Resume | Box Office Mojo | Withoutabox | LOVEFiLM 

IMDb Mobile: iPhone/iPad | Android | Mobile site | Windows Phone 7 | IMDb Social: Facebook | Twitter 

International Sites: IMDb Germany | IMDb Italy | IMDb Spain | IMDb France | IMDb Portugal 



 Copyright© 1990-2012 IMDb.com, Inc. 
 Terms and Privacy Policy under which this service is provided to you.
An company.

 Amazon Affiliates Amazon Instant Video 
 Watch Movies&amp;
TV Online
	</body>
</document>
