<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004437" url="http://www.muninetguide.com/jobs/TX/arlington/restaurant-+-food-service/" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="1" score="0.0013893611871504852" bingtitle="25 Restaurant &amp; food service jobs in/near Arlington, TX - Apr 17, 2012" webtitle="33 Restaurant&amp;food service jobs in/near Arlington, TX - Jul 12, 2012">
			<query id="000131" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Assistant General Manager. Monster.com ... servers (waiters &amp; waitresses), cooks, and cashiers. ... setting decorations, condiments, candles, napkins ...</description>
	<body>
		Home » Jobs index » Texas » Arlington 
33 Restaurant&amp;food service job listings in the Arlington, Texas area 

Job listings, help wanted ads and employment postings (last updated on Wednesday, July 11 )

 
 Store Manager Trainee - Arlington,TX 

Monster.com

TX-Arlington, Are you looking to develop your career in retail? If you love merchandising, sales and the excitement of a hands on retail position, check into becoming a Dollar General Store Manager in Training. We&apos;re one of the fastest growing discount retail companies in America with more than 9,200 neighborhood stores in 35 states. We offer tremendous career growth opportunities for our employees that get res… MORE INFO 
 
 Store Manager Trainee - Arlington,TX 

Monster.com

TX-Arlington, Are you looking to develop your career in retail? If you love merchandising, sales and the excitement of a hands on retail position, check into becoming a Dollar General Store Manager in Training. We&apos;re one of the fastest growing discount retail companies in America with more than 9,200 neighborhood stores in 35 states. We offer tremendous career growth opportunities for our employees that get res… MORE INFO 
 
 Panda Express - Restaurant Manager - Dallas-Fort Worth - West Texas 

Monster.com

TX-Mansfield, At Panda, we all share a common mission: “Deliver exceptional Asian dining experiences by building an organization where people are inspired to better their lives. ” We invest in our people because great people run great operations that will exceed our guests’expectations. Talk to any of our associates and you will experience a culture dedicated to its mission and our five fundamental values - Pro… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Manager - Dallas Fort Worth Texas 

Monster.com

TX-Fort Worth, Casual Service Restaurant with top consumer ratings, financially stable company, trend-setting menu, with comfortable but fun service (you will impress people when they know where you work!) Full Benefits Package Assistant Restaurant Manager - Grapevine, Arlington, Fort Worth, Southlake and throughout Tarrant County Salary: $45,000 - $55,000 + bonus potential Requirements: 2-3+ years Full Serve/Up… MORE INFO 
 
 Business Development Manager - Sales (DFW) 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER—Territory Sales Location: Dallas / Fort Worth areas Job Description As a Business Development Manager with R. W. Smith&amp;Co. , you will build and develop new business customers within your region. Reporting to a Director of Business Development, the Business Development Manager must be able to self-generate leads and have the ability to close new foodservice businesses… MORE INFO 
 
 Night Order Selectors 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, Hardies Fruit&amp;Vegetable Company a Dallas based Produce Company in the Oak Cliff area is looking for night selectors to stack, palletize, and load trucks with 1 year of experience working in a cold warehouse environment. Must be able to repetitively lift at minimum 50lbs and meet probationary standards of 80 packages per hour consistently. Must have electric pallet jack and fork lift experience,… MORE INFO 
 
 Retail Sales - S. Dallas, TX - ( S. Dallas / Duncanville area) - Day Shift - $9hr + Bonus Potential! 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, If you are looking to work for a company that is stable, an industry leader, with 2100 locations throughout the United States, then Public Storage is it! With an exciting customer-centric focus, Public Storage provides a full range of storage solutions to its customers. Public Storage is the largest self storage company in the United States. By joining our team of talented storage experts, you bec… MORE INFO 
 
 STORE MANAGEMENT (Retail/Grocery) - Fort Worth, TX 

Monster.com

TX-Fort Worth, There’s something in the air…Respect. Ambition. Pride. There are a lot of qualities we’re proud of here at Save-A-Lot. We’re a close-knit, down-to-earth group that thrives in a fast-paced environment. We need people who can grow along with us, who are ready to step up and be a leader. Will you be one of them? . ………………………………………………………. Leaders Made Daily What gets you up in the morning? People? Commun… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Assistant Manager-Fort Worth, TX 

Monster.com

TX-Fort Worth, As a Restaurant Manager at Panera Bread you would be responsible for providing outstanding leadership to your team. You should be passionate about the industry, inspiring others, coaching, counseling, creating a profitable environment, and delivering an exceptional customer experience. Our Associates must maintain high standards of restaurant cleanliness, sanitation, food quality, and facility man… MORE INFO 
 
 Hourly Team Member - Whataburger 

Monster.com

TX-Bedford, Whataburger Star Concessions Restaurant restaurant employee Server restaurant job restaurant employment restaurant careers restaurant hourly jobs restaurant server jobs Restaurant host restaurant host job customer service jobs customer service career Retail jobs Retail Employee Customer Service Host Bartender Busser Cook Prep Cook Waiter Waitress Hostess Part Time Full Time… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Management 

Monster.com

TX-Bedford, - Panda Express Is Now Hiring Management - General Managers&amp;Assistant Managers needed throughout the Dallas Fort- Worth areas! Interested? Submit a resume&amp;call 562-596-7072 for appointment info Email Resume To: PXD@FoodBizJobs. com The ideal candidate will have experience as a General Manager, Assistant Manager, Restaurant Manager, Supervisor, Leader, Kitchen Manager, District Manager, Area Man… MORE INFO 
 
 Manager 

Monster.com

Fort Worth, Riscky&apos;s BBQ was established in 1927. It is a family owned and operated company with 8 Locations that include Full Service BBQ Restaurants, Steakhouse, Burger Place, Deli&apos;s and a Full Catering Department. We are looking for Experienced Managers that are ready to be part of a growing company that provides great service, a family atmosphere, a great product with a Texas theme! Our ribs are habit for… MORE INFO 
 
 PIE FIVE PIZZA CO. HIRING NOW! ALL MANAGEMENT POSITIONS! 

Monster.com

TX-FT WORTH, HIRING NOW! Restaurant GMs and Assistant Managers Needed All DFW Areas Available WE&apos;RE A BIG HIT AND WE&apos;RE LOOKING FOR HIGH ENERGY LEADERS TO JOIN OUR TEAM! Pie Five pizza co. is a new concept for Fresh Pizza Fast! Are you innovative? Are you a People-person? Do you want to be a leader in your field? Then Pie Five is looking for you! At Pie Five pizza co. , we are passionate about great food, great… MORE INFO 
 
 Hourly Team Member - Whataburger 

Monster.com

TX-Irving, Whataburger Star Concessions Restaurant restaurant employee Server restaurant job restaurant employment restaurant careers restaurant hourly jobs restaurant server jobs Restaurant host restaurant host job customer service jobs customer service career Retail jobs Retail Employee Customer Service Host Bartender Busser Cook Prep Cook Waiter Waitress Hostess Part Time Full Time… MORE INFO 
 
 Store Manager - Fort Worth,TX 

Monster.com

TX-Fort Worth, Are you looking to develop your career in retail? If you love merchandising, sales and the excitement of a hands on retail position, check into becoming a Dollar General Store Manager in Training. We&apos;re one of the fastest growing discount retail companies in America with more than 9,200 neighborhood stores in 35 states. We offer tremendous career growth opportunities for our employees that get res… MORE INFO 
 
 Service Technician 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, Labatt Food Service is seeking a hard working, dedicated individual for a Beverage Technician job opening. In this job the employee will drive a company vehicle to various customer locations to service, clean and/or install beverage equipment. The employee will be responsible for keeping machinery and equipment in good repair, examining machines for defects in operation, replacing defective parts,… MORE INFO 
 
 Cook-Chilis Too @ DFW Airport 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, Summary: The Cook is responsible for preparing cooked foods, and must be able to perform all station functions of Fry, Flat Top Griddle, Pantry, and cooking eggs; communicating ticket times and potential problems to the manager on duty and servers as necessary; providing the highest quality of service to customers and associates at all times; performing all other responsibilities as directed by th… MORE INFO 
 
 Host/Hostess - Lead @ Chili&apos;s Too - DFW Airport 

Monster.com

TX-DFW Airport, Summary: The Host/Hostess is responsible for the receiving and seating of guests and performing a variety of other tasks within a restaurant establishment which may include ringing up orders, refilling beverages, setting tables, and cleaning eating/serving areas; performing all other responsibilities as directed by the business or as assigned by management. This is a non-exempt position and typica… MORE INFO 
 
 Starbucks Barista @ DFW Airport 

Monster.com

TX-DFW Airport, Summary: The Barista is responsible for fulfilling orders and completing sales transactions within a Starbucks establishment and performing other support functions which may include cleaning the food preparation, customer seating or stock areas and maintaining inventory; performs all other responsibilities as directed by the business or as assigned by management. This is a non-exempt position and… MORE INFO 
 
 Server - Tequileria @ DFW Airport 

Monster.com

TX-DFW Airport, Summary: The Server is responsible for taking food and beverage orders; entering orders quickly and in proper sequence; serving food and beverages for guests in their section as well as other sections; coordinating with the kitchen to ensure timely service and quality of the food; and providing the highest quality of service to the customer at all times; performing all other responsibilities as di… MORE INFO 
 
 Barista 

Monster.com

TX-DFW Airport, Summary: The Barista is responsible for fulfilling orders and completing sales transactions within a Starbucks establishment and performing other support functions which may include cleaning the food preparation, customer seating or stock areas and maintaining inventory; performs all other responsibilities as directed by the business or as assigned by management. This is a non-exempt position and… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Managers&amp;General Managers (All Levels) 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, CORNER BAKERY CAFE IS NOW HIRING FOR THE DALLAS METROPLEX!! COMPANY OVERVIEW Corner Bakery Cafe is the type of restaurant or company you simply don&apos;t see much of anymore. While we understand the importance of a healthy bottom line, we also believe in simply being healthy - knowing that we&apos;re all here to make a living. We also believe in making a difference, and that difference comes from hiring pe… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Manager - Sous Chef or KM Hot Concept! 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, body&gt; Restaurant Manager Professionals Sous Chef Dallas, Plano, Frisco, Addison DFW Metroplex Is your career everything you want it to be? Picture yourself in a position where you can grow and learn more about the industry you love. We are currently looking for highly dedicated, highly energetic, and highly skilled Restaurant Manager and Chef professionals to add to our already stellar staff. If y… MORE INFO 
 
 Assistant Manager 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, Come join the best of the best! The Palm Restaurant is looking for an experienced ASSISTANT MANAGER in Dallas, TX!!! The Assistant Manager will serve as an assistant maitre d’to meet or exceed each customer’s expectation of the dining experience. You will maintain standards for food, beverage, service, and atmosphere while building positive customer relations. The Assistant Manager will support t… MORE INFO 
 
 Panda Express - Restaurant Manager - Dallas-Fort Worth - East Texas 

Monster.com

TX-Dallas, At Panda, we all share a common mission: “Deliver exceptional Asian dining experiences by building an organization where people are inspired to better their lives. ” We invest in our people because great people run great operations that will exceed our guests’expectations. Talk to any of our associates and you will experience a culture dedicated to its mission and our five fundamental values - Pro… MORE INFO 
 Shown below: Arlington restaurant&amp;food service area jobs provided by 
 FOOD SERVICE FOREMAN 

Army and Air Force Exchange Service (AAFES)–Dallas, TX –  Indeed.com 

Job Qualifications 6 MONTHS OF RESTAURANT OR RELATED FOOD SERVICE OPERATIONS EXPERIENCE. OR SUCCESSFUL. . . OF RESTAURANT OR RELATED FOOD SERVICE OPERATIONS. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Food Service Manager 2 

Sodexo–Fort Worth, TX –  Indeed.com 

of multifunctional food service operations to ensure. . . services including restaurants, fast food, vending, catering services, institutional services, mall food. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Manager 

Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s–Arlington, TX –  Indeed.com 

the best combination of food, drinks and games in an. . . management system, food safety audits, station testing and recipe knowledge, food quality indicators, and. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Manager - Restaurant Food Service General Manager 

Taco Cabana–Dallas-Fort Worth, TX –  Indeed.com 

Restaurant Manager—Restaurant Food Service General. . . clothing allowance Restaurant Manager—Restaurant Food Service General Manager Fiesta Restaurant Group is. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Server 

Le Meridien Dallas by the Galleria–Dallas, TX –  Indeed.com 

some restaurant shifts, and some room service shifts. . . service standards, guest relations and etiquette. •Knowledge of the appropriate table settings, service. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Director of Food&amp;Beverage 

Dallas–Dallas, TX –  Indeed.com 

Palmer fine dining restaurant. Featuring the award. . . charismatic, innovating and service focused restaurant professionals to lead our Food&amp;Beverage team at. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Food&amp;Beverage Outlets Manager 

Hilton Dallas Lincoln Centre–Dallas, TX –  Indeed.com 

food and beverage outlets to maintain high standards of food and beverage quality, service. Responsible. . . standards of food and beverage quality, service and. . .… MORE INFO 
 
 Restaurant Supervisor/Host(ess) 

Kimpton Hotels and Restaurants–Dallas, TX –  Indeed.com 

Providing restaurant guests with friendly and professional service, excellent food quality, strong price. . . be assigned. SERVICE: Proper guest service requires. . .… MORE INFO 
 

 Find more restaurant&amp;food service jobs in the Arlington area» 
 . Popular job listing searches for
Arlington, TX 
 Call Center (30)

 Warehouse (34)

 Correctional Officer (5)

 Assembly/Assembly Line (30)

 Career Fair (25)

 Work at Home (25)

 Equipment/Forklift/Crane Operation (30)

 Elementary school teacher&amp;teaching (4)

 CAD/Drafting (31)

 Optical (24)

 Truck Driving (30)

 EMT/Paramedic (18)

 Vehicle Inspection (20)
 More job types in and near Arlington, Texas 
 Accounting »

 Attorney&amp;lawyer »

 Construction »

 Database development&amp;administration »

 Graphic design »

 Hospitality&amp;hotel »

 Inventory »

 Legal admin »

 Marketing »

 Nursing »

 Pharmacist »

 Real estate »

 Restaurant&amp;food service »

 Middle&amp;high school teacher&amp;teaching »

 Warehouse »
 Job seeker&amp;employer tools 
 
 
«Back to the Arlington, TX page
 . Jobs by Indeed 
 

 About MuniNetGuide   |   Site Index   |   Contact MuniNetGuide   |   Privacy Policy   |   Disclaimer 

©2012 by RICIC, L.L.C. MuniNet Guide, P.O. Box 533, Hinsdale, IL 60522-0533 / (847) 337-3106



Thu, July 12 @ 12:53 pm
	</body>
</document>
