<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004182" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/364028-low-calorie-meals-at-restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-20:25" support="12" score="0.033887269780662796" bingtitle="Low-calorie Meals At Restaurants | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Low-calorie Meals At Restaurants | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="6"/>
	<description>The food choices you make when you eat out may affect your weight ... Obesity&quot; found that of over 7,000 fast food ... want an appetizer, ask for a raw veggie tray ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Calorie Basics Low Calorie Meals Low-Calorie Meals at Restaurants 
 
 Low-Calorie Meals at Restaurants 
 Jun 14, 2011 | By Diane Lynn Photo Credit Jupiterimages/Brand X Pictures/Getty Images 
Americans spend between 34 and 48 percent of their food budget on meals away from home, according to a 2010 publication by the Bureau of Labor Statistics. If you eat restaurant meals on a regular basis, you may find it difficult to maintain your weight due to the tendency for these items to be high in calories and fat. Learning how to make wise choices while dining out may help you avoid consuming too much sodium, fat and calories.
 
Significance

The food choices you make when you eat out may affect your weight, cholesterol levels and blood pressure. A 2009 study published in the journal &quot;Obesity&quot; found that of over 7,000 fast food restaurant purchases, the average meal contained 827 calories, and more than 33 percent were over 1,000 calories. Sandwiches purchased in combination with drinks and a side dish averaged more than 1,200 calories a meal. If your ideal caloric intake is 2,000, a 1,200-calorie lunch is more than half your daily calories.
 
Salads

Fast food and sit-down restaurants often feature enticing salads on their menus. Salad greens and vegetable toppings are low in calories, unless the restaurant adds breaded and fried meats, high-calorie sauces, fried croutons or large amounts of cheese. Some restaurant entree&apos; salads have over 800 calories, according to a publication by the American Institute for Cancer Research. Choose salads with lean, grilled skinless chicken or steamed fish rather than salads topped with fried chicken pieces. Ask the server to leave off the cheese and to bring the dressing in a separate bowl. Select fat-free or low-fat dressings, if you have a choice.
 
Main Dish Entrees

Portion size and preparation methods present a challenge when choosing low-calorie entrees. Restaurant meals often offer cuts of steak and pieces of chicken that are double the recommended 3- to 4-oz. size. Pasta entrees may completely fill your plate, making the calorie count prohibitive. Share an entree with your dining companions, ask the server for a smaller portion and choose entrees which offer plain grilled meats with little or no sauce. Select pasta entrees with red instead of white sauce, eat only half the pasta and have a small green salad instead of a buttery roll.
 
Side Dishes

Even if you successfully order lower-calorie entrees, appetizers and side dishes can add unnecessary calories to your meal. Think of unending bowls of tortilla chips, free rolls and buns and fried seafood or cheese appetizers as unnecessary. If you want an appetizer, ask for a raw veggie tray with fat-free dressing. Order side dishes such as potatoes with fat-free sour cream or butter on the side. Substitute salad or fruit for French fries, choose baked chip bags over fried and ask the server for suggestions on lower-calorie side dish options.
 
References

 Bureau of Labor Statistics: Food for Thought; November 2010 PubMed.gov: What People Buy From Fast-Food Restaurants: Caloric Content and Menu Item Selection, New York City 2007; Andrea Truncali, et al.; July 2009 American Institute for Cancer Research: Experts Eye &quot;Sabotaging Salads&quot;; February 4, 2010 Vermont Department of Health: Eating Healthy Can Be Easy and Does Not Have to Cost a Lot American Heart Association: Tips for Eating Out 
 
Article reviewed by Lauren Fritsky Last updated on: Jun 14, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Healthy Dinners at Restaurants 
 
 Low-Carb Foods at Restaurants 
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Restaurants 
 
 Weight Loss&amp;Restaurants 
 
 How Can a Diabetic Eat Right at Restaurants? 
 
 Diabetes Friendly Restaurants 
 
 Low-Sodium Restaurant Meals 
 
 Healthier Eating Options at Mexican Restaurants 
 
 Low-Calorie Choices in Mexican Restaurants 
 
 What Is Healthy to Eat at Restaurants? 
 
 Healthy Options at Restaurants 
 
 Healthy Food Choices at Restaurants 
 
 Low-Fat Lunch Choices at Restaurants 
 
 Applebee&apos;s Low-Cholesterol Restaurant Meals 
 
 What Are the Health Benefits of Olive Garden Restaurants? 
 
 The Traveler&apos;s Guide to Restaurant Eating 
 
 Low-Calorie Restaurant Guide 
 
 Healthy Restaurant Appetizers 
 
 Vegan Food at Restaurants 
 
 Healthy Entrees at Restaurants 
 more Low Calorie Steak advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 Easy Low-Calorie Diet Menus 
 
 Low-Calorie Fall Dinner Ideas 
 
 Calories in the Entrees at Capital Grille 
 
 Low Calorie Pasta Salads 
 
 Vegetarian Low-Fat, Low-Calorie Lunch Meal Ideas 
 
 Low-Calorie Drink Options 
 
 Applebee Restaurants Menus&amp;Calories 
 
 Simple Low-Fat&amp;Low-Calorie Crockpot Meals 
 
 Low-Calorie Dinner Ideas 
 
 The Best Meal Replacement Shake With Low Calories 
 
 Low-Calorie Salad Dressing Ideas 
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food Options 
 
 The Foods With the Lowest Calories at an Italian Restaurant 
 
 How to Look Up Calories for Restaurant Dishes 
 
 Menus for Low Calorie Diets 
 
 Restaurant Pasta Meals With the Lowest Calories 
 
 How to Make a Low Calorie Caesar Salad 
 
 Low Calorie Foods for Lunch 
 
 What Is a Low Calorie Mexican Food Option? 
 
 What Diet Is Best: Low Carb or Low Calorie? 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
