<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004897" url="http://www.articlesbase.com/teenagers-articles/history-of-burger-king-products-2007179.html" time="2012-07-12-21:24" support="1" score="0.0005741256840648827" bingtitle="History Of Burger King Products - Free Articles Directory | Submit ..." webtitle="History Of Burger King Products">
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>Items such as the Texas ... In order to appeal to as many demographic groups as possible and better compete with its fast food restaurant competitor Wendy&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Online Articles Directory 
 Why Submit Articles? Top Authors Top Articles FAQ AB Answers 

 Publish Article 
 
 Login Login via Register 

 Hello My Home Sign Out 
 Email 
 Password 
 Remember me?
 Lost Password? 
 Home Page &gt; Home and Family &gt; Teenagers &gt; History Of Burger King Products 
History Of Burger King Products
 Posted: Mar 18, 2010 | Views: 871 | 
One of Donald N. Smith&apos;s first changes to the menu was the addition of the Burger King Specialty sandwich line in 1979, which significantly expanded the breadth of the BK menu with many non-hamburger sandwiches including new chicken and fish offerings. The new specialty sandwich line was one of the first attempts to target a specific demographic, in this case adults 18-34, members of which would be willing to spend more on a higher quality product.[6]  One of Smith&apos;s other significant contribution to the menu was the addition of a breakfast product line, which until this time was not a market Burger King had entered. Besides the addition of the Croissan&apos;Wich in 1983, the breakfast menu remained almost identical to the McDonald&apos;s offerings until a menu revamp in 1985. This expansion introduced BK&apos;s Am Express product line which added new products such as French toast sticks and Mini-muffins.

 Claim burger king gift card Here 

As the company expanded both inside and outside the US, it introduced localized versions of its products that conform to regional tastes and cultural or religious beliefs. International variations add ingredients such as teriyaki  or beetroot  and fried egg to the Whopper,[49]  beer in Germany, Italy and Spain, and halal or kosher  products in the middle East and Israel.To generate additional sales, BK will occasionally introduce limited time offers (LTOs) that are versions of its core products or new products intended for either long or short term sales. Items such as the Texas Double Whopper and various sandwiches made with mushrooms and Swiss cheese have been rotated in and out of its menu for several years while products such as its 1993 offering, a Meatloaf  Specialty Sandwich and limited table service along with special dinner platters, failed to generate interest and were discontinued.
 
 Claim burger king gift card Here 

In order to appeal to as many demographic groups as possible and better compete with its fast food restaurant competitor Wendy&apos;s, Burger King added a multi-tiered value menu in 1993 with items priced at 99¢, $1.99 and $2.99 (USD). The project, called Operation Phoenix, was an attempt to add not only a value menu but a line of value meals. The tiered menu was replaced with a more standard value menu in 1998, while the value meals were separated into their own menu segment. This value menu featured seven products: Whopper Jr., 5 piece Chicken Tenders, a bacon cheeseburger, medium sized french fries, medium soft drink, medium onion rings and small shake. In 2002 and 2006, BK revamped its value menu adding and removing several different products such as chili and its Rodeo Cheeseburger. Many of these items have since been discontinued, modified or relegated to a regional menu option.[56]  To better appeal to a more adult palate and demographic, BK introduced several new products to its menu in 2003, including several new or revamped chicken products, a new salad line and its BK Joe brand of coffee. Some of the new products, including its Enormous Omelet Sandwich line and the BK Stacker line, brought negative attention due the large portion size, amounts of unhealthy fats and trans-fats. Many of these products feature higher quality ingredients like whole chicken breast, Angus beef, natural cheeses such as Cheddar and pepper jack.[60][61]  Again, not all these products, such as the BK Baguette line, have met corporate sales expectations.
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.articlesbase.com/teenagers-articles/history-of-burger-king-products-2007179.html &quot; beautyexpert - About the Author: 


beautyexpert

 
Questions and Answers
 Ask our experts your Teenagers related questions here... Ask 200  Characters left 
 
 Does burger king grill their burgers? 
 
 Does burger king microwave their burgers? 
 
 Does burger king have veggie burgers? 
 
 Rate this Article 1 2 3 4 5 vote(s) 0 vote(s) Feedback Print Re-Publish Source:   http://www.articlesbase.com/teenagers-articles/history-of-burger-king-products-2007179.html 
Article Tags:

 burger king products 
 , 
 burger king gift card 
 
 
Related Articles
 
Latest Teenagers Articles
 
More from beautyexpert
 
 
 Difference Between Coupons, Vouchers and Gift Cards 
 
Free printable coupons are an integral part of today&apos;s world. With the appearance of large number of brands, companies try to make their products more recognizable and induce customers to consume more of their products. This is not easy in the saturated markets, so many companies issue printable coupons, vouchers and gift cards to introduce their products to the outsiders and attract more new customers.
 By: Elliot Clark l Shopping l Nov 22, 2010 l Views: 126 
 New&quot;Rabbit&quot;Card Brings e-Money System to Bangkok Transit and Retail 
 
Travelling, shopping, and eating in Bangkok has just gotten a whole lot easier.
 By: Thailand Update l Travel l Jun 15, 2012 
 Get Freebies for free 
 
This article gives you details on how to get free stuffs,freebies and other gifts online.All the stuffs are free and you can grab it easily without much effort.
 By: Dennies John l Internet &gt; ECommerce l May 05, 2011 
 Online Discount Vouchers And Coupons 
 
Voucher Codes are one of the best way by which you can save your money, although shopping Online. If you are new to Online Shopping, you might have curiosity that what these Discount coupons are.
 By: Chris Jones l Shopping &gt; Gifts l Mar 29, 2011 
 Building a Referral Based Sales Channel 
 
Tips and tricks to help you generate new leads from old. How to take the new channels that you&apos;ve opened up and prime them to keep the leads flowing in. Although this article is targeted at the Payroll industry, the methods discussed are applicable to most service business models.
 By: Logan Cashwell l Marketing &gt; Marketing Tips l Oct 09, 2008 
 Get Free Coloring Pages From Your Computer 
 
Every kid loves coloring pages, and drawing. That&apos;s something that any child can enjoy and spend some time with, and if you think back on your own childhood, certainly you were the same way. You get to spark your imagination and creativity, and let that run wild as you have a great time. Today, it&apos;s easier than ever to get access to all the coloring pages you need for all of the kids in your life. All you need to do is have a seat at your computer, open up your internet browser and start searchi
 By: jim knowles l Home and Family &gt; Teenagers l Jul 10, 2012 
 Why are Online Coloring Pages so Popular? 
 
One of the most popular trends these days online seems to be coloring pages. Parents, babysitters, teachers, caretakers and more all across the globe head online and search for coloring pages they can find on websites to download and print them at their command. Certainly, this has its advantages, but why is it so popular these days, and what makes it something that you should be involved with for yourself?
 By: jim knowles l Home and Family &gt; Teenagers l Jul 10, 2012 
 How to Find Best Summer Camps for Struggling Teens in Columbia 
 
There are numerous specialized rehab centers, specialty boarding academies and wilderness healing programs for supporting the lives of stressed adolescents. Treatment centers recommend excellence and secure programs for making the recuperation successful.
 By: stevenson l Home and Family &gt; Teenagers l Jul 05, 2012 
 3 Big Time Reasons Laughter Benefits You and Your Daughter 
 
One of the quickest ways to connect with your daughter is through laughter. But let&apos;s be honest. Does your daughter&apos;s silliness and playfulness drive you nuts sometimes?
 By: Colleen O&apos;Grady l Home and Family &gt; Teenagers l Jul 04, 2012 
 Avoid Mean Spirited Humor: 10 Guidelines for Positive Humor 
 
Laughter is medicine for the soul and has many health benefits. It helps you bond with your daughter. It decreases stress and releases the endorphins that make you feel good. In other words laughter helps you lighten up, enjoy your life and enjoy your relationships.
 By: Colleen O&apos;Grady l Home and Family &gt; Teenagers l Jul 04, 2012 
 Triactol Breast enlargement product Final Review 
 
If you are looking for a breast enlargement product that is clinically proven to work, then you need to purchase Triactol. This solution is the most effective product on the market and has women from all over the world raving about its positive results.
 By: beautyexpert l Health &gt; Women&apos;s Health l Feb 14, 2011 
 Triactol Breast enlargement product Review part 4 
 
Would you like your clothes to fit you better? Do you avoid wearing body-hugging tops or bikinis? Then you will be happy to know that you can easily improve the shape and size of your breasts with Triactol™ Breast Serum. This revolutionary product can dramatically enhance your breasts so that you can feel more confident about yourself. Having a better sense of self-worth lets a woman lead a much happier life.
 By: beautyexpert l Health &gt; Women&apos;s Health l Feb 14, 2011 
 Triactol Breast enlargement product Review part 3 
 
Have you been looking for an all-natural breast enlargement solution that is not associated with negative side effects or long recovery times? Then you should purchase Triactol to help you get the breasts that you have always wanted!
 By: beautyexpert l Health &gt; Women&apos;s Health l Feb 14, 2011 
 Triactol Breast enlargement product Review part 2 
 
Triactol Breast Enlargement Serum #1 Effective Product on the Market Triactol has been taking the market by storm. This product caters to women that have less-than-perfect breasts and are interested in having fast and noticeable results. Its attributes are appealing because they do not involve ineffective lotions, breast pumps, exercises or costly surgeries. Triactol allows women to have a safe and natural solution for small breasts with a 50ml airless bottle.
 By: beautyexpert l Health &gt; Women&apos;s Health l Feb 14, 2011 
 Preparations For 2010 World Cup 
 
Five new stadiums have been built for the tournament, and five of the existing venues are to be upgraded. Construction costs are expected to be R8.4bn.
 By: beautyexpert l Sports and Fitness &gt; Soccer l Apr 12, 2010 Author Navigation 
 My Home Publish Article View/Edit Articles View/Edit Q&amp;A; Edit your Account Manage Authors Statistics Page Article Widget 

 My Home Edit your Account Update Profile View/Edit Q&amp;A; Publish Article 
 Author Box beautyexpert has 10 articles online Contact Author Subscribe to RSS Print article Send to friend Re-Publish article Articles Categories All Categories Advertising Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive Beauty Business Careers Computers Education Finance Food and Beverage Health Hobbies Home and Family Home Improvement Internet Law Marketing News and Society Relationships Self Improvement Shopping Spirituality Sports and Fitness Technology Travel Writing Home and Family Accessories Babies Elderly Care Fathering Genealogy Holidays Parenting Pets Pregnancy Teenagers Need Help? 
 Contact Us FAQ Submit Articles Editorial Guidelines Blog 
 Site Links 
 Recent Articles Top Authors Top Articles Find Articles Site Map Mobile Version 
 Webmasters 
 RSS Builder RSS 
 Business Info 
 Advertising 
 Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the Terms Of Use and Privacy Policy | User published content is licensed under a Creative Commons License .
 Copyright © 2005-2012 Free Articles by ArticlesBase.com, All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
