<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004218" url="http://www.waow.com/story/16936538/update-car-crashes-into-patrol-car-in-weston" time="2012-07-12-20:27" support="1" score="0.0007941166006658703" bingtitle="UPDATE: Car crashes into patrol car in Weston - WAOW - Newsline 9 ..." webtitle="UPDATE: Car crashes into patrol car in Weston - WAOW - Newsline 9, Wausau News, Weather, Sports">
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>The fast-food restaurant celebrated it&apos;s grand opening in Plover ... responded to a call Tuesday morning, after a car ... &quot;This is the end result.&quot; Authorities said other ...</description>
	<body>
		WAOW - Newsline 9, Wausau News, Weather, SportsUPDATE: Car crashes into patrol car in Weston
 Member Center: 
 Create Account | Log In Manage Account | Log Out 
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 HOME 
 WAOW Mobile Rewards Club Jefferson Awards Advertiser Services 
 NEWS 
 Wausau Metro Stevens Point Marshfield Wisconsin Rapids Northwoods 34 Politics International Health Water Cooler Crimestoppers 
 WEATHER 
 Current Conditions iTrack Interactive Futurecast Report Storms Closings Weather Blog 
 SPORTS 
 Athlete of the Week Scoreboard National Football League Major League Baseball Official Packers Station Pack Attack Northland Adventures 
 COMMUNITY 
 Obituaries Gas Buddy Jefferson Awards 
 VIDEO 
 ABC Video Player 
 WHAT&apos;S ON 
 THIS TV Network Program Guide CW Discover Wis. Travel Guide 
 WAKE UP 
 Ticket Tuesday Birthdays Web Favorites Pet Pause Touch of Class 
 OUTDOORS LIFESTYLE 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 MOBILE 
 Wireless Emergency Alerts 
 ABOUT US 
 Closed Caption Contact QNI WYOW-TV34 CW Fox 55 WAOW Jobs Privacy Policy Terms of Use FCC/EEO Reports NewsTeam Advertise with us 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
UPDATE: Car crashes into patrol car in Weston
 Posted: Tuesday, February 14, 2012 7:53 PM EST By Anna Carrera, Multimedia Journalist - bio | email 
 
 Most Read Stories Most Read Stories More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Man drowns after jumping into river for a swim 

 Man drowns after jumping into river for a swim 
 Police say an Oshkosh man drowned after jumping from a bridge into the Fox River for a swim. More &gt;&gt; Police say an Oshkosh man accidentally drowned after jumping from a bridge into the Fox River for a swim. More &gt;&gt; 
 Police arrest father in deaths of 3 girls in Wis. 

 Police arrest father in deaths of 3 girls in Wis. 
   Three girls are dead and their father is in jail as police investigate an apparent triple homicide in the western Wisconsin city of River Falls. 

  More &gt;&gt;   Three girls are dead and their father is in jail as police investigate an apparent triple homicide in the western Wisconsin city of River Falls. 

  More &gt;&gt; 
 Former Langlade Co. deputy charged with child sex assault 

 Former Langlade Co. deputy charged with child sex assault 
 A former Langlade County Sheriff&apos;s deputy has been charged with 22 felonies relating to sexual assault of several children. More &gt;&gt; A former Langlade County Sheriff&apos;s deputy has been charged with 22 felonies relating to sexual assault of several children. More &gt;&gt; 
 Wausau councilman Ed Gale resigns 

 Wausau councilman Ed Gale resigns 
 A Wausau city council member and former candidate for mayor has announced he&apos;s resigning. More &gt;&gt; A Wausau city council member and former candidate for mayor has announced he&apos;s resigning. More &gt;&gt; 
 UPDATE: Officials say boy went through Lake Wazeecha dam intentionally 

 UPDATE: Officials say boy went through Lake Wazeecha dam intentionally 
 Emergency crews pulled a teen from Lake Wazeecha Thursday evening. More &gt;&gt; Emergency crews pulled a teen from Lake Wazeecha Thursday evening. More &gt;&gt; 
 Update: $1 million bond set in embezzlement case 

 Update: $1 million bond set in embezzlement case 
 A Marathon County judge set bond at $1 million for Jay Fischer. Authorities in Waupaca County tell Newsline 9 he is out of jail. More &gt;&gt; A Marathon County judge set bond at $1 million for Jay Fischer. Authorities in Waupaca County tell Newsline 9 he is out of jail. More &gt;&gt; 
 Busy weekend for Wausau 

 PREVIEW: Big upcoming weekend for Wausau 
 The Wausau Balloon Rally and Glo and Rib Fest kick off Thursday at the Wausau Airport. More &gt;&gt; Two of the cities most anticipated events are just days away. More &gt;&gt; 
 Naked man found near Wausau whitewater course 

 Naked man found near Wausau whitewater course 
 Wausau police say officers found a naked man near a busy kayak course. More &gt;&gt; Wausau police say officers found a naked man near a busy kayak course. More &gt;&gt; 
 Wis. girls coach punches player after loss 

 Wis. girls coach punches player after loss 
 A Wisconsin basketball coach faces a battery charge in Indiana after allegedly attacking one of his players. More &gt;&gt; A Wisconsin basketball coach faces a battery charge in Indiana after allegedly attacking one of his players. More &gt;&gt; 
 UPDATE: Former Langlade Co. deputy sheriff resigned during investigation 

 UPDATE: Former Langlade Co. deputy sheriff resigned during investigation 
 Authorities said Michael Brayton resigned a week after he was placed on administrative leave.  More &gt;&gt; Authorities said Michael Brayton resigned a week after he was placed on administrative leave.  More &gt;&gt; 

 
 Most Watched Videos Most Watched Videos More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Former Langlade Co. deputy charged with child sex assault 

 Former Langlade Co. deputy charged with child sex assault 
 A former Langlade County Sheriff&apos;s deputy has been charged with 22 felony counts relating to sexually assaulting several children.  More &gt;&gt; 
 World Championships attracts athletes from across the world 

 World Championships attracts athletes from across the world 
 
 Fishing on Lake Michigan 

 Fishing on Lake Michigan 
 
 Wausau councilman Ed Gale resigns 

 Wausau councilman Ed Gale resigns 
 Ed Gale announced Tuesday he plans to resign. He cited health and personal reasons for his decision.  More &gt;&gt; 
 State files embezzlement charges against Wausau businessman 

 State files embezzlement charges against Wausau businessman 
 A WAUSAU BUSINESS OWNER HAS BEEN CHARGED WITH STEALING MORE THAN A MILLION DOLLARS IN MORTGAGE MONEY. More &gt;&gt; A Wausau business owner has been charged with stealing more than $1 million in mortgage money. More &gt;&gt; 
 UPDATE: Former Langlade Co. deputy sheriff resigned during investigation 

 UPDATE: Former Langlade Co. deputy sheriff resigned during investigation 
 
 Teen pulled from Lake Wazeecha 

 Teen pulled from Lake Wazeecha 
 A 16-year-old boy was pulled from Lake Wazeecha Thursday evening.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Wausau approves big 400 block concert 

 Wausau approves big 400 block concert 
 The Wausau city council has approved a concert featuring a former American Idol contestant.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Campers get creative at Hodag 

 Campers get creative at Hodag 
 
 Naked man found near Wausau whitewater course 

 Naked man found near Wausau whitewater course 
 Alan Gruna, 37, is charged with lewd and lascivious behavior.  More &gt;&gt; 
 
 MARATHON COUNTY (WAOW) -- On Tuesday morning, two different area squad cars were involved in crashes in Marathon County. Officers said crashes like these are more common than you may think.

One lieutenant said he knows at least nine officers whose cars have been hit while they were responding to a scene. Most recently -- this morning around 7AM.

Marathon County deputies responded to a call Tuesday morning, after a car rolled over on Highway 29 -- near County Road J in Weston. Shortly after they got there -- another car crashed into their squad car.

&quot;Luckily the deputy was not in his vehicle at the time or getting into it because if that was happening, there would have been serious injury,&quot; said Marathon County Sheriff&apos;s Department Lieutenant Dale Wisnewski. &quot;But he was off to the side of the road with the motorist of the previous crash.&quot;

Everest Metro police officers came to the scene as well.

&quot;Some person was going too fast for conditions and ended up striking the rear of our squad,&quot; said Wisnewski.

Wisnewski said slick streets may have played a role in the crash. He said drivers need to remember to keep their foot on the brakes when they see flashing lights.

&quot;It&apos;s so surprising when you have a situation where you have two squads, a vehicle rolled over and traffic still does not slow down,&quot; said Wisnewski. &quot;This is the end result.&quot;

Authorities said other Marathon County roads have earned reputations for dangerous driving conditions, especially when winter weather hits.

&quot;[Highway] 51, Brokaw, Rib River, those are always notorious for us getting crashes in that area whenever there&apos;s a snow storm,&quot; said Wisnewski.

Regardless of the season, officers said they hope people will pay close attention to what&apos;s going on -- to help keep everyone safe.

The State Patrol is coordinating the investigation. At this point, no charges have been filed.
 
 All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WAOW. All Rights Reserved.
For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
