<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004705" url="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Restaurant_Review-g274958-d1097735-Reviews-Vapiano-Tallinn_Harju_County.html" time="2012-07-12-21:13" support="9" score="0.030453416937903693" bingtitle="Vapiano Restaurant Reviews, Tallinn, Estonia - TripAdvisor" webtitle="Vapiano, Tallinn - 119 Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001268" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000234" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>Not a restaurant of my taste: order foods and drinks from different stations and try to find a place to sit. ... an ordinary restaurant, it is more like a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Vapiano Restaurant Reviews, Tallinn
 
 Home Tallinn 
 Tallinn Tourism Tallinn Hotels Tallinn Holiday Rentals Flights to Tallinn Tallinn Restaurants Tallinn Attractions Tallinn Travel Forum Tallinn Photos Tallinn Guide 
 Hotels Flights Holiday Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; Europe &gt; Estonia &gt; Harju County &gt; Tallinn &gt; Tallinn Restaurants &gt; Vapiano 
 
 All 344 Tallinn Restaurants» 
Vapiano
 Hobujaama tn 10 , Tallinn 10151 , Estonia +3726829010 Website 11 visitor photos Ranked #21 of 344 restaurants in Tallinn 119 Reviews Price range: £3 - £10 Good for: Cheap Eats Dining options: Lunch Spot, Dinner, Takeout, After-hours, Dessert Restaurant details Good for: Cheap Eats Dining options: Lunch Spot, Dinner, Takeout, After-hours, Dessert Update restaurant details Write a Review 
119 reviews from our community
 85% Recommend 
 Excellent 53 Very good 47 Average 15 Poor 3 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 119 reviews sorted by Date Rating Dutch first English first French first German first Italian first Norwegian first Russian first Swedish first Any Druusi Helsinki Senior Reviewer 8 reviews Reviews in 6 cities 3 helpful votes “Italian food experience” Reviewed 11 July 2012 NEW 
The food in Vapiano was nice, and you collect all payments on your card before actually paying while exiting. A nice place.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? KalleHelsinki Helsinki Senior Contributor 44 reviews Reviews in 18 cities 33 helpful votes “Italian fast food” Reviewed 10 July 2012 NEW 
This place has been there already some years and it is one of my favorites in Tallinn. The location is perfect to have a nice quality meal before your ship sails to Helsinki. Maybe 12-15 min walk to the ship. It works even if you have limited time resources, but you can also enjoy a laid back&amp;relaxed dinner... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? kaidakaida Tallinn, Estonia Senior Reviewer 7 reviews Reviews in 4 cities 1 helpful vote “It&apos;s OK” Reviewed 10 July 2012 NEW 
It all depends on which cook you get. Generally it&apos;s good, but sometimes they are not able to meet the standard. It&apos;s fast food, but beats any fast food chain anytime :)
The cooks and waiters/waitresses are generally friendly and smily, which is a great plus.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by kaidakaida for Tallinn RWat88 Atlanta, Georgia, United States Senior Reviewer 7 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “Cheap&amp;quick” Reviewed 29 June 2012 
It&apos;s not a unique Estonian experience, but good if you want cheap Italian-style food, salads, etc.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by RWat88 for Tallinn Ana S London, United Kingdom Contributor 17 reviews Reviews in 5 cities 1 helpful vote “italian restaurant” Reviewed 27 June 2012 
I like italian cousine very much. Nothing special. But pasta and pizza were tasty. Also good price.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 7 more reviews by Ana S for Tallinn abbagoochiette 1 review “Cheap fast food in a classy restaurant” Reviewed 19 June 2012 
Good food for the value,real nice and hectic with the feel of a nice&quot;real&quot;restaurant
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Hoon31 Newcastle upon Tyne, United Kingdom Reviewer 4 reviews 3 helpful votes “Modern Italian just outside Old Town” Reviewed 19 June 2012 1 person found this review helpful 
Came here for lunch, on arrival the welcoming member of staff explained how the system worked (you are given a store credit card which is charged at the varying ordering stations where the food is prepared in front of you) and we were seated.
The food is really good value, myself and my girlfriend shared a large antipasto plate, bolognese... More 
 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by Hoon31 for Tallinn getaboutalotwales wales Top Contributor 59 reviews Reviews in 24 cities 39 helpful votes “modern pizza/pasta restaurant near Hotel Metropol” Reviewed 11 June 2012 1 person found this review helpful 
The reataurant was very busy when I went in for lunch.When I arrived I was handed a&quot;credit&quot;card which I took to the bar to order my drink which was scanned onto my&quot;credit&quot;card.The same thing happened when I oredered my calzone pizza.I was also handed a buzzer which buzzed to tell me to go and collect my meal.The pizza... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 6 more reviews by getaboutalotwales for Tallinn McKanu 2 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “Nice and fast place to enjoy pasta” Reviewed 11 June 2012 via mobile 
Visited second time here to enjoy nice pasta and pizza. Service is exellent. When we came in there where only few people having lunch so we get our orders very soon. Highly Recommend also for families cause kids have their own place to play.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Lynda1961 Ireland Contributor 20 reviews Reviews in 7 cities 9 helpful votes “Cooked in front of you” Reviewed 8 June 2012 2 people found this review helpful 
We had never been to this style of restaurant, where you chose your pasta,sauce etc go to a desk order it and watch it being cooked, then take it to your table. As people who don&apos;t like the concept of&apos;carvery&apos;(ie Serving youself), we weren&apos;t sure if we were going to enjoy the experience! It was very busy and... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 6 more reviews by Lynda1961 for Tallinn 1-10 of 119 reviews « 1 2 ... 12 » 
Travellers who viewed Vapiano also viewed
 Kohvik MOON 82 Reviews Tallinn, Harju County Von Krahli Aed 288 Reviews Tallinn, Harju County   Leib Resto ja Aed 73 Reviews Tallinn, Harju County Porgu 82 Reviews Tallinn, Harju County   All restaurants in Tallinn (344) 
Been to Vapiano? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage Vapiano, register now for free tools to enhance your listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Hotels travellers are raving about...

 My City Hotel Tallinn 106 Reviews Read reviews Tallinn, Harju County Taanilinna Hotel 81 Reviews Read reviews Tallinn, Harju County Hotel Bern 368 Reviews Read reviews Tallinn, Harju County 
 All hotels in Tallinn (82) 
Browse nearby
 Restaurants (344) | Hotels (82) | Things to Do (114) Vapiano Hobujaama tn 10 Tallinn 10151 Estonia Get Directions What&apos;s Nearby: Hotels Restaurants Things to Do Click map pins for more information. You are zoomed out too far to see location pins. Please zoom back in. Interactive map 
Free Tallinn Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Tallinn restaurants

 Von Krahli Aed Tchaikovsky Neh Horisont Kohvik MOON Leib Resto ja Aed Restaurant O Porgu F-hoone Dominic Ribe Chedi Alter Ego Kapten Tenkes Bocca The Pierre Chocolaterie Fish&amp;Wine Hell Hunt Mix Kompressor 
 
Hotels around Tallinn

 Meriton Old Town Garden Hotel 3.5 out of 5, 115 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 Radisson Blu Hotel Olumpia 4.0 out of 5, 118 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 St Olav Hotel 3.5 out of 5, 311 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 Gidic Backpackers 3.0 out of 5, 6 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 Scandic Palace Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 77 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jul 2012 Tallinn Backpackers 4.5 out of 5, 47 reviews Last reviewed 10 Jul 2012 Domina Inn Ilmarine 4.0 out of 5, 293 reviews Last reviewed 9 Jul 2012 Sokos Hotel Viru 4.0 out of 5, 177 reviews Last reviewed 9 Jul 2012 Park Inn by Radisson Central Tallinn 4.0 out of 5, 287 reviews Last reviewed 8 Jul 2012 Clarion Hotel Euroopa 4.0 out of 5, 102 reviews Last reviewed 4 Jul 2012 OldHouse Apartments 4.5 out of 5, 24 reviews Last reviewed 28 Jun 2012 Tallink City Hotel 3.5 out of 5, 98 reviews Last reviewed 28 Jun 2012 16EUR Hostel 4.0 out of 5, 38 reviews Last reviewed 26 Jun 2012 Kuninga Apartments 4.0 out of 5, 10 reviews Last reviewed 13 Jun 2012 Metropol Hotel 4.0 out of 5, 151 reviews Last reviewed 11 Jun 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 Caruso&apos;s Italian Restaurant 4.0 out of 5, 7 reviews Al Colombo in Venice 2.5 out of 5, 75 reviews Texas Roadhouse 4.5 out of 5, 4 reviews Solo Pizza 4.5 out of 5, 30 reviews Vlaamse Frites 4.0 out of 5, 1 review 
 Hotels 
 Berghof Hotel in Koblenz 4.5 out of 5, 3 reviews Last reviewed 14 Apr 2012 Retaj Al Rayyan Hotel in Doha 3.0 out of 5, 48 reviews Last reviewed 20 Jun 2012 Econo Lodge in Fayetteville 3.5 out of 5, 35 reviews Last reviewed 9 Jul 2012 Days Inn Little Creek in Norfolk 3.0 out of 5, 45 reviews Last reviewed 5 Jul 2012 Henwick House Bed&amp;Breakfast in Worcester 4.0 out of 5, 36 reviews Last reviewed 26 Jun 2012 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, holiday rentals, holiday packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, holiday rentals, holiday packages, and lots more! Visit TripAdvisor&apos;s international sites: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Owners | Help Centre | Business Listings | DMO/CVB © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
