<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004977" url="http://www2.westminster.net/discovery/instructorhandbook.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:29" support="15" score="0.029692183361221314" bingtitle="Discovery Ninth Grade Instructor Handbook - The Westminster Schools" webtitle="Discovery Ninth Grade Instructor Handbook - The Westminster Schools">
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000787" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001258" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000380" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000976" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001226" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000693" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>... never feed animals and should pick up any food scraps or crumbs in order ... the staff chooses to eat at a fast food restaurant ... Explain the menu board. Tell the students ...</description>
	<body>
		Ninth Grade 

 Discovery 

 Instructor 

 Handbook 


 I. Introduction 

           You have one of the hardest jobs at Westminster. It requires a level of responsibility and maturity that many people in today’s society purposefully avoid. We expect you to not only design and run learning activities for Westminster 9 th graders, but also to actively look after their physical, mental and emotional well being. For many students their Discovery experience is one of the most powerful experiences they have during their high school years. I firmly believe that there is no more challenging job at the school, and none with more rewards. This manual is your primary resource for everything you will be expected to know and do as a Discovery Instructor, from philosophy to cleanup. The policies and procedures in the manual also set the safety standards for Discovery. You are expected to know them and abide by them at all times.  The foundation of everything we do is safety and awareness . The more familiar you are with the program and activities that makeup the Discovery experience the more comfortable you will become with making critical decisions about program design. At every level of the program, however, you must always be asking yourself such questions as:“What could go wrong here? How can I cover all possibilities in my briefing? Where should the staff be positioned to spot?” As you gain experience these questions will become second nature and your eye for potential problems will become more focused. However, until that time you need to always be extra vigilant. 

           There is no replacement for good judgment. The information in this manual will never replace your awareness and prudence. You are the Discovery program, in a very real sense, because you bring to life the philosophy, objectives, policies and procedures of this manual. We expect a lot from you and will always hold you to a very high standard of safety and integrity. In return, we pledge to give you honest, direct evaluation, support in your professional development and our deepest appreciation for a very difficult job done well.
 
 History of Discovery 

           The Discovery Program was founded in 1980 when High School Principal, Charlie Breithaupt, invited Ralph Puckett to design and run a required program for 9 th graders. Discovery is an Outward Bound adaptive program, based on the philosophy and ideas of Kurt Hahn, the founder of not only the Outward Bound Schools, but also the Salem School in Bavaria, the Gordonstoun School in Wales , and the United World College system, currently in 5 locations around the world. Kurt Hahn’s clearest statement of his philosophy is: “ I regard it as the foremost task of education to insure survival of these qualities: an enterprising curiosity, an undefeatable spirit, tenacity in pursuit, readiness for sensible self-denial, and above all, compassion .” Dave Kolb served as the Director of Program from 1984 to 1991, when Don Snider assumed the Directorship. Henry Wood joined the faculty as Assistant Director in the spring of 2001. Heather McCarey became 9 th Grade Program Coordinator in the fall of 2001. The Discovery Program, while required of all 9 th graders at Westminster, also works with every part of the Westminster community from pre-first classes to committees of the Board of Trustees.
 
 
 
 
 Session Related Jobs/Responsibilities 

 Session Director (SD) 

The Session Director will be either the Assistant Director of Discovery, the Ninth Grade Program Coordinator, or the Director. The Director must approve, in writing, any others for this position. The Session Director reports to the Director. The Session Director is the most important staff position on a 9 th grade Discovery session. S/he is responsible for the organization and administration of the session, supervision of student and faculty, overall safety, leadership, education of and interaction with the 9 th grade students, staff training (during the session), and evaluation of the session.

           The Session Director must review pertinent Westminster Discovery safety policies to all staff prior to the session start. S/he must be familiar with all program areas. S/he must also document all accidents, near misses, and any safety related problems during the session.

The Session Director should see her/himself as a trainer. Opportunities for on-the-job staff training must be sought out and can occur at the pre-session orientation, during all programming on campus, and especially on expedition.

           It is expected that the Session Director will be an active, dynamic, supportive leader. S/he makes final decisions after consultation with the staff and is responsible for the morale of 9 th graders and staff (both adult and student). S/he is the representative of the Westminster Schools and of the Discovery program and as such is expected to carry out all aspects of the program in a manner consistent with the mission and the goals of the School and the Discovery program.

 Discovery Faculty 

           Discovery Faculty members (including part-time faculty) are primarily responsible for supervising and evaluating the performance of student staff, instructors, and assistant instructors. The faculty is also responsible for insuring the safety of each activity and providing first-aid when needed. Faculty will review activities with student staff and provide feedback on sequencing, objectives, and safety concerns. Discovery Faculty are expected to be familiar with all Discovery goals, safety policies, and procedures and to make sure that student staff understand and follow safety policies and procedures for each activity.

 Chaperone/Guest 

             Chaperones are adults who are invited to participate either during an entire Discovery session or on a Discovery expedition. They are under the direct supervision of the Session Director and serve to support the trained adult staff in working with groups, debriefing, and other areas which don’t require any specific safety training.

 Student Staff Levels and Qualifications 

             The Discovery Student Staff is the corner stone of the Discovery Program. While the program was created as a freshman program, the chance for upperclassmen to learn and develop as outdoor educators is rarely repeated in other high schools around the country. In order for Student staff to gain the most out of this program, staff must be highly motivated and seek out every learning opportunity that Discovery provides. Attending staff trainings and working sessions is not enough to become a good outdoor educator. In order to develop a wide breadth of experience, staff will be expected to attend seminars and Discovery Adventure trips which are offered throughout the year. Staff should expect to be both written and orally evaluated during a session. This allows the staff to work on the areas where they need improvement and to know their strengths.

           There are several levels that staff members go through during their tenure as a Discovery Leader. Below are the expectations and how to achieve each level.

 Senior Instructor– Has the same responsibilities as an Instructor but is also responsible for other staff and their development. Senior instructors are good at developing a plan in accordance with the needs of their group. Senior Instructors must be able to give feedback to other staff, assist them in developing lesson plans, and provide them with next steps for improvement.

-    Must be able to brief and debrief all Discovery activities.

Instructed 4 sessions, with positive evaluations

Successfully completed at least 2 Advanced Staff Seminars

-        Design and run a Staff Training

-        Recommendation of Discovery Faculty

-        Must have a current CPR and Wilderness First Aid

 Instructor– Is the lead instructor for a group of 9 th graders during a Discovery Session. This person must be able to organize and plan the activities of a session including the expedition.

-        Must be able to articulate the philosophy of Discovery.

-         Plan and orchestrate a session that reflects the desired outcomes of the program.

-        Must have successfully completed all Basic Discovery seminars or have equivalent training (all equivalent training will be assessed by the Director of Discovery).

-        Must have worked as an Assistant Instructor for 2 sessions (including expeditions) and received positive evaluations.

-        Must have current CPR and have Discovery first aid/emergency training.

-        Must be able to brief and debrief a majority of Discovery activities.

-        Must receive a recommendation from Discovery Faculty.

-        Must have successfully completed a pre-season refresher day prior to working that semester.

 Assistant Instructor– Is assigned to a session to assist the Instructor. This is viewed as a training role taken after completion of New Staff Training.

-        Must have successfully completed an entire New Staff Training Course.

-        Must have current CPR.

-        Must have successfully completed a pre-season refresher day prior to working that semester.

 Interns –A general helper, not assigned to a specific session or group. This role is designed for someone interested in the logistics and running the activities of Discovery. Interns must have completed New Staff Training. They will be used to assist instructors on the High Ropes days and the Issue and De-Issue days. This person will not be attending the expedition.


 Discovery Philosophy 

 I went to the woods because I wished to live deliberately, to confront only the essential facts of life, and see if I could not learn what it had to teach, and not, when I came to die, discover that I had not lived.    Thoreau

            During a Discovery session students learn about themselves, others, and their environment by participating in activities designed to involve a wide variety of critical thinking skills. Every 9 th grader at Westminster must complete a Discovery session in order to meet a graduation requirement.

           All Discovery programs contain four cornerstone objectives:

 Self-Awareness Responsibility Compassion Environmental Awareness   

Whatever the topic of instruction, these four objectives are incorporated into the lesson, with the final goal being to educate the whole person. Ninth graders are presented with a series of activities, both individual and group oriented, which are designed to develop communication, trust, problem-solving, leadership, stewardship, confidence, and interpersonal skills. 

           Classes are held outside all year long so students learn to appreciate and respect the natural world. Participants are not forced to do any activity; they are encouraged by staff and peers to try their best. Activities might include: backpacking, rock climbing, caving, ropes course events, emergency response training, wilderness living skills, and other related activities. These program elements provide personal challenges for an individual and a medium for trust and interdependence for a group. Students will realize they can do things they never thought possible. The main goal of the Discovery Program is to provide a vehicle for positive growth through challenge and exploration in a supportive environment.

 Discovery Environmental Ethics and Practices 

           Environmental Awareness is one of the four cornerstones of the Discovery Program. Awareness, however, is only the first step in helping students develop a sound environmental ethic which will lead to conscientious practices in their daily lives. It is important that all aspects of the program model such practices and ethics. 

           In all of our programs we will abide by the principals of“ Leave No Trace .” Those 7 principals are:

•           Plan Ahead and Prepare - We can avoid unnecessary impact on the environment if we have the right equipment, shelter, and food. For example, there is no need to build a fire if we have stoves and fuel to cook our food and if we have proper clothing for the conditions.

•           Travel and Camp on Durable Surfaces - During backpacking trips it is important to point out impacted camp sites and to maintain travel on the designated trails as much as possible. Camp sites should be located 200 feet from water (about 70 paces).

•           Dispose of Waste Properly - Pack out everything that you bring into wild country. Store food properly to keep wildlife out. Pick up all spilled food. Wash out and bring back recyclable items (glass, aluminum, and card board), and deposit in appropriate containers at base. For human waste, a cathole is dug 6 to 8 inches deep (in active soil) and at least 200 feet from water, camp, or trails. Use toilet paper sparingly. Use a waterless antiseptic hand cleaner for hand cleanup instead of water. 

•           Leave What You Find (except for trash) - Treat our natural heritage with respect. Leave plants, rocks, and historical artifacts as you find them. Use existing campsites or bare areas to camp. Do not build structures, furniture, or dig trenches.

•           Minimize Campfire Impacts - The Discovery Program carries stoves for all cooking. Whenever we do have a fire, use the existing fire ring, use only dead twigs and branches for kindling and, in base camp camping, buy firewood for larger pieces. Make sure that the campfire is put out completely and remove all unburned trash.

·               Respect Wildlife - Discovery will minimize the impact on wildlife by encouraging students to be quiet while hiking in the woods. Students should never feed animals and should pick up any food scraps or crumbs in order to prevent the habituation of animals to humans. Discovery will also protect wildlife and food by storing food and trash properly (i.e. bear hangs).

·                Be Considerate of Others - Discovery should try very hard to avoid calling attention to itself while in the mountains. We are typically a relatively large group and therefore run the risk of disturbing other visitors’“wilderness experience”. We should observe the following methods:

 1.      Be courteous. Yield to other users on the trail.

 2.      Step to the downhill side of the trail when encountering pack stock.

 3.      Take breaks and camp away from trails (when possible) and other visitors.

 4.      Let nature’s sound prevail. Avoid loud voices and noises .

           If we travel to program areas where indigenous cultures lived or still live (such as the Cherokee land in North Carolina or the Apache of New Mexico and Arizona), it is important that we stress respect for the spiritual, ceremonial, sacred, and private nature of those peoples (including any artifacts that might be found). The most likely conflict which we are more likely to run into is with“mountain”people in North Georgia and North Carolina. They are easy“targets”for our“sophisticated”city kids who lack the sensitivity to see beyond the accents and bib coveralls. Let’s help our students be respectful of those differences and guide them to find connections with their own lives and values.

           Wise stewardship of our natural resources, respect for others, awareness of the impact of our actions, and a willingness to accept responsibility for our use of them are the guiding principles behind our environmental ethic. Our job is to help students develop those same characteristics during their time with us in Discovery.

 Discovery Program Objectives 

1. To provide students with opportunities for self-discovery through participation in activities which are challenging and fun.

2. To improve the self-concept of students by their successful confrontation with psychological, physical, and mental challenges.

3. To develop within students an increased sense of responsibility, tolerance, respect, and trust for others through participation as a member of a small group of people who remain together throughout the program.

4. To develop leadership by placing students in positions of responsibility. These opportunities will be carefully selected by Discovery staff as challenging, yet appropriate, for the individual student concerned.

5. To develop the skills necessary for safe participation in adventure related activities.

6. To demonstrate the need for some structured authority, and a certain amount of acquiescence, through participation in activities where the respect for rules and procedures is necessary.

7. To help students take responsibility for their learning by participation in challenging activities which require rudimentary mastery of specific skills.

8. To enhance physical well-being through a series of programmatic elements which require physical exertion over extended time.

9. To improve faculty-student rapport by having classroom faculty participate in Discovery. The shared experiences of exhilaration, discomfort, joy, and apprehension assist in the development of fellowship.

10. To develop a better appreciation of the interdependence of all life forms and the realization that some responsibility for the conservation and preservation of nature rests with each one of us. This goal is accomplished through participation in experiential education programs and service projects in the outdoors.


 Safety Philosophy 

The Westminster Discovery Program emphasizes perceived risk activities and minimizes the actual risk through equipment, training, awareness, and information. The Discovery Program uses programmed stress activities to teach interpersonal skills. A student may be anxious about jumping off of a secure perch 30 feet above the ground in order to reach a swinging trapeze. The stress in this activity is the student making the decision to jump or climb back down the tree. Either way the student comes away feeling s/he tried hard to do the event. This feeling will foster a sense of self-confidence. The perception of risk is very real to the student even though the belay rope will easily catch a fall in the hands of the belayer. 

Staff must be sure that students have a clear understanding of the environmental hazards that exist in their specific course area and ways for the group to collectively develop an attitude of“group safety”where everyone is looking out for themselves and each other. All activities begin with a safety briefing which informs participants about objective hazards they need to be aware of such as: steep rock faces, moving water, poison ivy, bees nests, sun exposure, or anything else which might have an adverse effect on the participants. Safety briefings also address subjective hazards to include the personal responsibilities of the group members toward each other and themselves. 

All staff members must develop a keen sense of awareness towards safety. The development of this characteristic will result in the goal of accident prevention. Solid Safety knowledge knows what factors are needed to create the accident potential (when objective and subjective hazards can lead to an accident, i.e. lightning on exposed ridges, or not dressed warmly enough in cold windy weather). Both objective and subjective hazards are to be considered when planning and supervising activities. Safety awareness identifies these factors early and eliminates them. This elimination is the result of a proper safety attitude which is created by the professional conduct of the staff at all times. Accident potential is then transformed into accident prevention. 

 Staff Safety Training 

Staff members will be trained in all activities they are responsible for leading. The training will be sequential and include classroom work, readings, mentoring in the field by more experienced students and faculty, and a final approval by the Director for promotion. Training will include specific procedures, objectives, and safety considerations of each activity area. Through training and supervised work, staff will develop the awareness needed to detect and prevent possible accidents. All student staff will be closely evaluated during classes and critiqued by faculty when debriefing the session. A written evaluation of each student staff member’s performance will be written by the Discovery Faculty at the end of each session.

Safety awareness must permeate every aspect of Westminster Discovery Program. The Discovery staff is responsible for their own personal safety as well as that of the students. All activities are closely monitored by professional staff members. Student staff are trained and tested on safety policies and procedures. Adherence to the written policies, as well as to the concept behind them, is a condition of participation in and employment by the Discovery Program.
 
 
 Briefing 

           Giving a thorough and clear briefing can be the key to a successful initiative, activity, and even session. There are five main goals that you should keep in mind while briefing a group:

 Set out the rules of the activity.  Be clear about what the rules are for the initiative or activity. This means that you must know all of the rules/guidelines yourself before briefing an activity. If you do not know all of the rules/guidelines, look in the handbook or ask a faculty member. 

 Set the tone of the experience . Your tone during the briefing will be directly reflected in the attitude and actions of the group. It is important that you find a balance between being excited about the activity and being focused on the task at hand. It is also important that you not only set out the rules of the activity, but engage the students in your briefing. You could do this by telling a creative story or by running a theme throughout the initiative. However you choose to brief the activity, keep it exciting and interesting! 

 Set objective goals for the group . Make sure that the group knows exactly what they are trying to accomplish. Are they trying to build a bridge across a creek or make a world class dinner? 

 Set safety precautions for the group.  Make sure that the group understands any safety precautions that should be taken. You must be extremely clear about this. 

 Be sure to frame your briefing around the entire session.  If your session is going backpacking, brief activities such that they relate to the expedition. Framing is when you bring in subjective goals of the activity. Encourage the group to think about goals such as teamwork, communication, or overcoming individual fears prior to the activity so that you may return to these themes in your debriefing. 

Remember, when you are briefing a group of students, you are giving a presentation of your ideas, thoughts, and attitude. It is important that you keep public speaking skills in mind:

 Before you start your briefing make sure you have the full attention of your audience. A good way to get this is to ask the students to sit in a circle. Do not talk until the entire group is listening to you. Make sure you speak clearly. Your briefing should go in a logical order. If you need to, write down everything you want to say in your briefing before the students get there. Speak UP! Make sure that your group can hear you. Communicate with your co-staff. Make sure that everyone knows who will brief the activities before the students arrive. 

 Debriefing     
           Debriefing is a formal process of reflection engaged in by a group and led by a Discovery staff member. Sometimes an evening debrief around a campfire with the entire group is just right, and other times a meeting of smaller groups is more appropriate. Discuss with the Session Director the format you favor, time of day, place, and size of group rather than just assuming a debrief will take place after dinner.

Debriefing is an essential part of any initiative or activity. This is a time when an individual or the group can reflect upon the activity and the group interactions that occurred, and can begin to integrate their learning into the rest of the program and their lives. It also creates closure and completeness. Debriefing can be one of the hardest jobs for Discovery Staff.  Here are some considerations to take into account in order to help you facilitate a successful debrief: 

 Be an active watcher during the activity . Take mental or even written notes of any group interactions that you could use to help initiate conversation during the debrief. Listen carefully to what is being said . Don’t just nod in anticipation of what you think will be said. No matter how many times you have lead a debrief and are certain about what people are going to say, remember that for each student this is a rare and unique experience for them. Listen to each one as if she/he was the first one you ever heard! Don’t go in blind . Have an idea about what you want to cover in your debrief. Are there specific questions you want to ask? Is there a specific incidence that needs to be covered? Don’t be afraid to continue with more probing questions to engage students in thinking reflectively about broader issues which may be arising. Watch the non-verbal reactions in the rest of the group . See who is nodding in agreement and who is nodding off. Be prepared to follow-up with students who are showing strong nonverbal cues. You don’t always have to go in a circle . Be flexible . Allow students to take the conversation in the direction that they need to as long as the discussion stays focused on the activity being debriefed. Avoid asking yes/no questions . Is everyone participating? Try to create an environment that encourages people to participate. Be aware of your students’personalities and comfort levels and know when to offer the chance for students to“pass.”  Keep a sense of humor . Debriefs do not always have to be serious, especially if nothing“significant”happened during the activity. Don’t open up a subject you do not have the time or skills to deal with . Be a role model for appropriate sharing. Not every activity needs to be debriefed . Assess your group and determine whether a debrief would add to their experience. Find a positive way to reach closure of the debrief . Don’t leave things hanging. If after closure you notice that someone is still troubled or was reluctant to speak out in a group, seek that person out for a little“one-on-one”debrief. Use different types of processing techniques in order to tap into different learning styles. You do not have to stick with the traditional question and answer debrief. Here are some other debriefing ideas: 
 Pair up and share the experience with a partner. Return to the group and tell your partners’story. This is a good exercise for listening and communication skills. Have the group tell the story of the day/initiative/activity by each member saying one sentence then passing it to the next member. This can be an interesting view on different peoples’perspectives. Make a sculpture out of anything to represent the experience. Map: participants may draw a“map of the journey”or“river of life,”metaphorically letting their drawings and or symbols stand for their experience. This is a good one for sharing life and course experiences creatively. Journaling: Any time you can have students write in their journals about the experience is great. Ask a couple of specific questions and then send them off to write about them for 15 minutes or so. Or, have them record their version of what just happened. Have students report back or paraphrase what they wrote. Human sculpture: One group member uses one or more other members to construct a human sculpture that reflects how they felt at a certain point of the activity. Highs or lows, going off the swing, falling off the platform, etc. Pass around a candle, stick, or stuffed animal to be used as a talking stick or microphone as each person takes a turn speaking. M&amp;M’s!!! Pass around a bag of M&amp;M’s. Participants are told to take some, but not to eat them yet! Each person says something about the event or experience before eating the candy. Debriefing cards: use these great cards with pictures on them to help you debrief. Either lay out several cards on the ground and ask each student to choose one, or pass around the deck and get each student to pick the top card. Then ask the students to relate their card with the day’s experience. Some questions to spark conversation: 


Were the group goals met?

Name one person (it could be yourself) who you are proud of and why.

What are some strengths of the group you would like to carry to other activities?

What are some weaknesses you would like to leave behind?

How did the activity help you realize how you are alike or different from others in your group?
 
 II. Session Outline 

           Standard Discovery sessions meet twice a week on either Mondays and Wednesdays, or Tuesdays and Thursdays.“Intensives”meet Tuesday through Thursday the first week, Monday through expedition the second week. Staff report at 3:00 PM on the Session Planning Day to plan the session with the Discovery faculty. Usually, the planning day is the day prior to the start of the session. This should also be a time for identifying the session’s themes, instructor goals/development, and to discuss current risk management issues. Staff will also report at 3:00 PM on Discovery days in order to plan that day’s activities and to set up the activities prior to the students’arrival. Each day, 9 th grade students arrive at 3:45 PM and are released at 5:45 PM. Seven afternoon meetings precede the expedition which leaves at 1:45 PM on Friday and returns by 4:00 PM the following Monday. Discovery is considered a regular part of a student’s school day, so Monday’s absence from classes is excused.

           The typical design of a session is based on a flow which begins with group building activities (name games, problem solving initiatives, and trust building sequences), moves through individual and group challenges (high and low ropes course activities and backpacking), and culminates with personal reflection and self-assessment. Recognizing that each group progresses at a different pace and that some groups begin ready to work at a higher level, it is the responsibility of the student staff to work with the adult faculty to design and modify a sequence that is best for each group. It is also the responsibility of the student staff to design on-campus activities that prepare their students for the challenges of the backpacking expedition. This not only includes thorough clothing checks and a skills day but also structuring briefings and debriefings, while on campus, in a way that students begin to think about how they will work together once they are in the backcountry.

 A standard outline of the session might include: 

           1. Team building/group dynamics . Through a succession of carefully chosen initiatives and low ropes course activities, 9 th graders are challenged to learn about each other, develop an awareness of the variety of strengths and talents within their group, and develop trusting, supportive relationships. The instructors choose activities which will move the group in a sequential manner from relative strangers to a functioning team. Instructors closely supervise the safety and well being of each participant during each activity.

           2. High Ropes . The high ropes activities during Discovery give each participant opportunities to find the courage within themselves that allows them to overcome perceived limitations. As with all Discovery activities, high ropes are a self-challenge. It is important that each participant is encouraged to try his/her best, but is never pushed beyond that fine line between“try”and“trauma.”Instructors provide a complete safety briefing prior to the beginning of high ropes events. Instructors also monitor all knots, clip-ins, and belays. Support, encouragement, and the involvement of the rest of the group as“psychological”belayers are important aspects of every high ropes activity.

           3. Skills Day and Pack-out . This is the time for participants to learn about the equipment they will be responsible for during their expedition. Instruction is given in care, maintenance, and usage of all camping equipment. Instructors make certain that each 9 th grader understands the safety aspects of proper equipment set-up and usage. This typically requires two full afternoons to complete.

 The first day can be spent teaching map and compass skills, stove use/maintenance and safety, tent/tarp set-up, backpack packing, and a personal gear and clothing check (see Backpacking Curriculum for specific topics). Be sure to have the students practice these skills after you have demonstrated it. If students do not get hands-on experience you will be re-teaching it the first night in the field! The next day, which is typically the last on-campus activity day, should be spent issuing personal and group gear and packing out food (see Issue Process ). 

           4. Expedition . Expeditions begin with packing the mini-buses, double checking to make sure all equipment is packed, and briefing students about whistles and the buddy system prior to loading them into the buses. The groups will drive to the course area that afternoon. Often, the staff chooses to eat at a fast food restaurant on the ride up rather than trying to cook in the dark once they arrive in camp. Typically the groups will camp in a group campsite near the bus on Friday night. During times with more daylight, it is sometimes possible to hike the group in a short distance and spend that first night on the trail. Each expedition includes instruction in camp craft skills (campsite selection, tents, tarps, stoves, cooking, sleeping bag use, etc.), and backcountry travel skills (map and compass/navigation, trail technique, etc.). The expedition is the culmination of each Discovery session. It is the final test of teamwork and group development. Every effort is made to challenge, support, and encourage students to make the most of the whole experience.

           4. Solo/Course Critique . On every expedition there will be a period of reflection (solo) during which students are asked to review their participation during the session and spend some time on deeper self-assessment. This period is critical in the experiential process because it allows for structured time during which the emotions from the activities can be reviewed and then integrated into each person’s insights and life experiences. During this time, 9 th graders are also expected to write a short critique of their Discovery session. This critique is handed into the Session Director.

           5. Cleanup . To reinforce the lessons of Packout, students learn how to clean and take care of the equipment they have just used. Instructors work closely with the Discovery faculty to ensure that all equipment is cleaned and stored in its proper place, ready to be issued to the next session’s students (see De-issue Process ).
 
 

 III. Activities 

(General Safety Policies are listed at the beginning of each activity)

 A. Games and Initiatives 

 General Safety Policies 

1. Rules and procedure for each event will be followed.

2. Events and equipment will be checked prior to use.

3. The staff will review the rules and procedures of the initiative prior to use.

4. The instructor will supervise all events and insure adequate spotting.

5. Participants are not allowed on events unless the group has been briefed and is performing that event.

6. There will be no human pyramids more than three levels high.

7. A belay will be used for events where spotting is inadequate due to height, such as the Challenge Ropes Course.

8. The event site will be cleared of any hazards prior to use.

9. Instructors will stop the exercise and/or correct students to insure safe execution of the event.

10. Jewelry and shop objects will be removed prior to participation in initiatives and games.

11. Only Discovery equipment will be used.

12. Individual events will not be timed, unless otherwise stated.

13. No gum chewing.

14. A ratio no larger than one adult and 2 student staff to 10 9 th graders will be maintained.
 
 
List of Initiatives

  = can be used as rainy day activity
 
 
 Name Games 

Bumpity Bump Bump 

General Name Game 

Group Juggling 

Peek-a-who 
 Ice Breakers 
Have you Ever 

Hog Call 

Human Scavenger Hunt

Moonball

No Person is an Island 

The Whole Truth 

 Active Games 

 Ankle Biters 

 Elbow Tag 

 Low Level Initiatives 

 A-Frame 

 Acid Pour 

 All Aboard 

 Spider’s Web 

 TP Shuffle 

 Traffic Jam 

 Trust Activities 

 Flying Carpet 

 Human Ladder 

 Trust Fall 

 Willow in the Wind 

 Low Rope Initiatives 

 Islands 

 Mohawk Walk 

 Nitro 

 Swinging Balance Beam 

 The Wall 

 Whale Watch 

 Full Day Initiatives 

 Nancy Creek Crossing 

 Liter Rescue 
 
 Name Games 
 Bumpity Bump Bump Bump 

 Objective: To have fun and learn names.

 Description: Students stand in a circle with someone in the middle. The middle person goes around the circle trying to state everyone’s name.

 Rules: Have everyone stand in a circle with the instructor in the middle. The instructor walks up to a student in the circle and says“left,”“right,”or“you.”The student in the circle then has to say the name of the person to their left, right, or their own name, depending on the command the instructor gave. The student in the circle must say this name before the instructor says,“Bumpidity, bump, bump, bump.”If the student is not able to do this then he or she becomes the person in the middle and the game continues. To make the game more difficult the person in the middle can say,“two to the right”or“three to the left.”

 Group Juggling 

 Objective: To learn names in the group and to develop communication and cooperation.

 Description: The group stands in a circle facing in. One ball is tossed around the circle. Every time the ball is tossed to a new person the person throwing the ball must say the name of the person they are throwing it to.

 Rules: The group stands/sits in a circle facing in. The instructor starts with one ball and throws the ball across the circle to another group member, calling out the person’s name at the same time. That person then does the same until the ball has made it all the way around the circle and back to the instructor. No one can receive the ball twice (have them cross their arms when they have gotten the ball). Have the students remember the order that they threw the ball in. On the next go round, the instructor adds in several balls to the activity until as many balls as possible are being juggled around the group. This can move into Warp Speed where the students try to figure out how fast they get one ball around the group in the same order. Remember, tossers must say the name of the student on the receiving end of their throw. Balls may not be hurled forcefully at anyone.

 Equipment: 1 to 8 tennis balls (stuffed animals, koosh balls…).

 No Name Game 

 Objective: To have fun and learn names.

 Description: Students sit in a circle and go around the circle saying their name and something interesting about themselves.

 Rules: Form a circle with everyone facing in. Sit down and explain the game. Start with yourself and tell the students that they need to say their name and 1) something that rhymes with their name 2) their favorite ice cream, car, etc. 3) someone (famous or otherwise) that they’d like to have lunch with. After the first person goes, the second person says the first person’s name and the fact they stated, as well as their own name and fact. This continues until it goes all the way around the circle and ends as it began, with the instructor.

   

 Peek-a-who 

 Objective: To have fun and learn names.

 Description: The group is broken up into two“teams.”Half of the group stands on one side of a tarp or sheet that the instructors are holding up while the other half stands on the other side. The two sides then proceed to have a“name war”and try to win everyone over to their side of the tarp.

 Rules: Break the group in half. Hold a tarp or sheet (that you can not see through) up between the two halves. Each half of the group should be on one side of the tarp and should not be able to see the other half. Have each side of the group send one person to the tarp. There will be one person on either side of the tarp but they will not be able to see each other. On the count of three, drop the tarp so that the two people can see each other. These two students must try to be the first person to say the name of the person they are now facing. The student who says the other students’name first“wins”that person over to their side of the tarp. This continues until everybody has been“won”to one side of the tarp. You can vary this by sending more than one person up to the tarp at a time. You can also have students stick hands or feet under the tarp to be identified rather than having their whole face identified.

 Equipment: One large opaque tarp or sheet.

 Ice breakers 

 Have You Ever 

 Objective: To have the group get to know everyone better.

 Description: The group stands in a circle facing in. Each member of the group stands on a poly spot. The instructor stands in the middle of the group ask the group a question such as“Have you ever been to Alaska?”If a student answers the question with a“yes,”then he or she must find a new poly spot to stand on. The person left without a poly spot becomes the new person in the middle who asks the group questions.

 Rules: Have every student stand in a circle facing in. The circle should be large enough that people can run in the middle of it. Have each student take a poly spot and stand on top of it in the circle. The instructor should stand in the middle of the circle and ask the group a question such as,“Have you ever been to Alaska?”The person in the center of the circle must ask a question that they can answer“yes”to. After the person in the center asks the question, anyone who can answer the question with a“yes”must find a new poly spot to stand on. The poly spot must be at least one poly spot away from their original spot. The person in the center also tries to find a poly spot to stand on. The student who ends up without a poly spot takes the spot in the center of the circle and continues to ask the group questions. The game continues in this fashion.

 Equipment: Poly spots: one less than the number of members in the group.

 Hog Call 

 Objective: To have the group become more comfortable with each other. Great game to play to break the group into smaller groups/pairs.

 Description: Have the group get into pairs and then pick a matching set of words (i.e. peanut-butter, penalty-kick). Each student needs to pick one of the words as their own.

 Rules: 1. Have the pairs separate to opposite sides of the field (or room) and put on blindfolds.

2. At a given signal the group starts to yell their word and finds their partner.

3. Make sure that students have their hands up in a“bumper”position when they are blindfolded.

4. Spot and guide the blindfolded students so they do not run into any obstacles.

*This game can also be played by giving each student an animal. The student must make the sound of that animal and find other people that are the same animal as they are.

 Equipment: Animal names if you want to hand them out to the students, blindfolds.

 Human Scavenger Hunt 

 Objective: To get to know each other better. To get the group more comfortable with each other.

 Description: Each student must fill out a Human Scavenger Sheet by finding other students that fulfill the requirements that are written on the handout.

 Rules: Give each member of the group a Human Scavenger Sheet and a pen or pencil. On the Human Scavenger Sheet there are statements such as“has ridden a horse,”or“has a twin.”Each student must go around the group and find someone who has fulfilled each statement. Give the students five to ten minutes to complete the hunt. After the hunt has been completed, gather the students together and talk about who has completed each statement.

 Equipment: Enough pens and Human Scavenger Sheets for every member of the group.

 Moonball 

 Objective : To develop teamwork and communication.

 Description : Students are given a beach ball and challenged to keep the ball in the air for as long as possible. Have the students set a goal:&quot;How many times do you think you can hit the ball without it touching the ground?&quot;

 Rules : A player cannot hit the ball twice in succession. The group should count out loud after each hit.

 Equipment : One giant beach ball per group.

 No Person is an Island 

 Objective: To have fun and get to know the members of the group better by sharing personal stories.

 Description: Members of the group stand on squares that have a statement on them such as,“I have met someone famous.”The fact that the student stands on must be true for the student. After each student has claimed a square, the group sits down and each member of the group shares his or her fact and why it is true.

 Rules: Have each member of the group stand around a tarp that has a grid taped onto it. In each square of the grid there is a statement such as,“I know someone famous,”or“I have been on TV.”Have students find a square to stand on that has a fact on it that is true for them. A student cannot stand on a square if no other student is standing on a surrounding square. In other words, the square that a student stands on must be connected to a square that another student is standing on. After each student has found a square to stand on and the entire group is connected, have the group sit down and share the story that makes the fact they stood on true. 

 Equipment: One large tarp with a grid taped onto it (the Maze tarp works great), enough printed“facts”to fill each square of the grid. Suggested facts: has met someone famous, has been on T.V., speaks a foreign language…

 The Whole Truth and Nothing but the Truth 

 Objective: To have fun and get to know the members of the group better.

 Description: Each student gets a note card and pen and writes their name and three experiences they have had that they think no one else in the group is aware of. The experiences are read out and the group tries to guess who the experience belongs to.

 Rules: 1. Have three volunteers stand up and give facilitator their cards.

2. Facilitator will read ONE experience from the cards.

3. The group will try to guess who actually had the experience by questioning the three volunteers.

4. Each volunteer will try to convince the group that THEY had the experience, whether this is the truth or not.

5. After several minutes of interrogation, ask each member of the group to state who they think actually had the experience.

6. After each member in the group has guessed, ask the person who truly had the experience to step forward.

Good debrief questions: Did anyone surprise you? Why did you ask the questions you did? What did you look for in the volunteers’answers? When you were a volunteer, what was going through your mind as you answered the questions?

 Equipment: One note card and pen for each student.

 

Active Games

 Ankle Biters 

 Objective: To have fun and get the group more comfortable with each other.

 Description: Each player is given a sword (foam pipe) and three lives. The object is to be the last warrior standing. Each player tries to eliminate the other players by hitting them below the waist with their sword. Each hit subtracts a life. After being hit below the waist three times (you can’t be hit three times in a row by the same person) the afflicted warrior immediately loses the use of his or her legs and metamorphoses into an Ankle Biter. As soon as a player becomes an Ankle Biter, they must remain stationary and kneeling. Their new job is to pivot from a kneeling position as they try to hit the ankles of the remaining warriors with their swords. The game continues until all but one warrior has been turned into an ankle biter.

 Rules: 1. Ankle biters can only pivot from a kneeling position.

2. Players may only hit below the waist.

3. Clear the area of debris.

4. Set specific boundaries that everyone must stay within (the closer the boundaries, the quicker the game).

 Equipment: Enough foam pipes for everyone in the group.

   

 Elbow Tag 

 Objective: To have fun and get the group more comfortable with each other.

 Description: This is a wild and fun tag game where“home base”becomes group team members.

 Rules: 1. Have everyone in the group get a partner.

2. Partner will link together by connecting arms at the elbows.

3. Break up one pair of students. One student of this pair is going to be“it”and is going to chase the other student of the pair.

4. The other pairs are standing around the field with arms linked while the“it”is doing the chasing.

5. The student being chased can run up to a pair and link arms with one of the students in the pair. When this happens, the student who was being chased is now safe.

6. As soon as the chased student links arms with a pair, the student in the pair who the original chased student did not link arms with becomes the new chased student.

7. As soon as the“it”student tags the chased student, the roles are reversed. The original chased student must count to ten and then transforms into the new“it”and must chase the original“it”student.

8. Make sure that boundaries have been set and are clear.

9. Make sure that there are no major obstacles or debris within the boundaries.

Variations: To make the game even more chaotic, allow pairs to run around the field, making it harder for the chased student to find a“home base.” 

 

Low Level Initiatives

   

 A-Frame 

 Objective: To build cooperation, communication, and teamwork.

 Description: Students must use the materials provided (ropes and three boards) in order to move one person from point A to point B. The students cannot touch the ground between points A and B. There can only be two points of contact with the ground at all times.

 Rules: 1.“A-frame”must maintain at least one point of contact with the ground at all times and never move more than two.

2. Only one person can touch the boards when the group is in motion from point A to point B.

3. Ropes cannot touch restricted areas.

4. No helpers can be within five feet of the student moving from point A to point B when the student has started to move.

5. Check area for obstacles.

6. Be in a position of control.

7. Spot students on“A-frame”as the frame starts to walk.

 Equipment: Five 18’ropes, 2 long boards, one short board.

 Acid Poor  

 Objective: To build cooperation, communication, and teamwork.

 Description: Students are to poor“acid”from one #10 can into another using the rubber band and strings. The cans are inside a 3’circle, which is inside a 20’roped off area.

 Rules: 1. No part of any student may go in the roped off area.

2. If the“acid”is tipped over, they start again.

3. Check the area for obstacles.

*If this is used for indoors as a rainy day activity, use a solid material such as ping pong balls for acid rather than water.

 Equipment: 1. One 3’rope, one 20’rope.

2. 2 #10 cans (one with H2O).

3. 1 or 2 large rubber bands made from bike tires (optional).

4. One 10’p-cord for every student (or every other student).

 All Aboard 

 Objective: To develop communication and teamwork.

 Description: Students are to get the whole group on the platform at the same time for a) one minute, b) the count of 10 by an instructor, c) for the duration of a song they must sing (row-row-row your boat)

 Rules: 1. All feet must be off the ground.

2. If the student feels they are falling from the platform, they should step down.

3. Students can stack two high.

4. Check the area for obstacles.

5. Spot as students get on each other’s back.

6. Make sure you are in a position of control.

7. Spot the group.

8. Make sure platform is on level ground.

 Equipment: One 2’by 2’board (you can start with larger squares and try progressively smaller ones).

 Spider’s Web 

 Objective: To work on communication and teamwork. To get the group more comfortable with each other.

 Description: The entire group must get through the spider’s web without touching the web.

 Rules: Students will try to get through the web one at a time without touching it.

 Only one student at a time can cross the web. If the web is touched, the spider comes out and the entire group must start over. Once an opening has been successfully used by a group member it is closed for further use. No one can go over the top of the web. No jumping, dropping, or leaping. One person can go under the web. There must be a staff member on either side when the web is started. If the group uses a student’s back, they must step on hips or between shoulders to prevent back problems. Be sure to clear the area of debris and obstacles. The leaders must always be in a position of control to catch the head and neck of the person being passed through the web. Be sure that there is adequate spotting. There will be no diving though the web. 

 Equipment: One spider web (this can be made out of p-chord that is strung between two points).

 Touch my Can 

 Objective: To develop teamwork.

 Description: The entire group must touch a soda can (number ten can, cup, tennis ball, etc.) without touching each other. One person’s nose must be touching the object. The object can get progressively smaller, winding up with a film canister. (Note: the more people, the greater the challenge.)

 Rules: The entire group must touch the object but cannot touch each other. Be sure to tape the pop-top and hole of any soda can you use in order to prevent students from getting cut.

 Equipment: Soda can, number ten can, film canister, etc. (various objects that decrease in size).

 TP Shuffle 

 Objective: To develop communication and team work.

 Description: The group lines up on a log in“alphabetical”order. They must then completely reverse positions without stepping off the board.

 Rules: If anyone steps off, the whole group must begin again.

Tell the students to step down if they are going to fall. Clear the area of any obstacles. The instructor should always stay in a position of control.

There are many variations to this game. For example, you can give students an animal and have them line up from smallest to largest without talking (they could either act out the animal or make the animals’sound).

 Traffic Jam 

 Objective: To develop communication and problem skills.

 Description: Students are divided into two groups. There is a line of poly-spots on the ground made of enough poly-spots for every member of the group to stand on one with one extra spot left over. One half of the group will stand to the right of the center poly-spot and the other half will stand to the left of it. Each student should stand on their own poly-spot with the extra empty spot in the middle of the two groups. Both groups should face the middle of the line towards the extra spot. Using the following moves (described in the rules) the groups must switch sides.

 Rules: 1. Every student must be on a poly-spot at all times.

2. A student can move into an empty space in front of them.

3. A student can move one space at a time.

4. A student can move around a person facing them into an empty space.

5. A student cannot move backwards.

6. A student cannot move around a person on their own team.

7. Only one student can move at time.

 Equipment: Enough poly-spots for everyone in the group to have one, with one extra spot left over.

Trust Activities

 Proper Spotting Technique: 

Feet should be shoulder width apart with one foot slightly in front of the other. Knees should be bent. This stance gives the spotter optimal balance. The spotter should have one hand in front of his or her face to protect against flying hands or feet, and the other hand placed slightly higher. It is not the spotter’s job to catch his or her partner if she or he falls. Rather, it is the spotter’s job to make sure that the partner lands softly on the ground and that the partners head, neck, and spine are protected.

(An example of a nice trust sequence: teach proper spotting technique—person to person trust fall—willow in the wind—flying carpet—trust fall)

 Flying Carpet 

 Objective: To develop trust within the group.

 Description: A student is lifted up above the group’s head and carried like that for several yards and then lowered down.

 Rules: Students form a tight circle with everyone facing in, hip-to-hip. Have one participant stand in the middle with his or her feet together, arms crossed, eyes closed, and stiff joints. It is very important that the student in the middle stands as straight and rigid as possible. After using the commands listed below, the student in the center will gently fall backwards into another student’s arms. The student who“catches”the falling student should be predetermined and in spotting position. After the student in the center has fallen backwards, the rest of the group moves in and lifts this student to shoulder level and carries him or her a short distance. The group will then gently lower the lifted student to the ground, feet first. There are several rules that should always be followed:

 The student to be lifted must remain stiff, with his or her eyes closed, and feet crossed. The instructors need to position themselves in order to catch the head and shoulders, should the lifted student be dropped. Most of the support should be in the torso/trunk area. Students should be lowered slowly, feet first. No one should let go of the lifted student until he or she is standing on his or her own. Instructors should remove any obstacles in the area. Instructors should always make sure that the group is focused and in control at all times. Commands: Faller : Spotters ready? 

                                Spotters : (when ready) Ready.

                               Faller : Falling.

                               Spotters : Fall on.

This initiative can be done in conjunction with Willow in the Wind. (Variation: If the group is small or the person is heavy, just have the group lift the person to their shoulders.)

 Human Ladder 

 Objective: To develop trust and cooperation within the group.

 Description: Students create a horizontal ladder for other group members to climb or walk across.

 Rules: 1. Break the group up into pairs. Pairs should be made up of students who have about the same body size.

 Each pair of students is given one“rung”of the ladder (a wooden dowel or piece of PVC pipe). Half of the students stand shoulder to shoulder with their partners standing directly across from them in another line, also standing shoulder to shoulder. Students will stand with their feet in a spotting position and will hold their“rung”with their partner at about waist level. This forms the“ladder.” Do not allow students to hold the rungs above their shoulders. Have one student volunteer to be the climber. The climber starts at one end of the ladder and climbs onto the first rung. The climber then proceeds to move from one rung to another.  As soon as the climber passes by, the students holding that rung may leave their position and walk to the end of the ladder, adding another run to what becomes an infinitely long ladder. The students should not remove the rung until the climber is completely off of it. Instructors should make sure that the group remains focused at all times. Instructors should be spotting the climber during the entire initiative and help the climber off of the ladder when he or she is finished. 

   

 Person-to-Person Trust Fall 

 Objective: Develop trust within the group and to teach proper spotting techniques.

 Description: Students get into pairs. Each pair practices falling back and being caught by the other person. 

 Rules: Have each student get a partner. Teach proper spotting technique. Have one person be the spotter while the other person is the“faller.”The faller must stand with his or her feet together, arms crossed with a straight back at all times. The partner stands directly behind the“faller”in spotting position. After saying the commands listed below, the“faller”slowly falls back towards the spotter. The spotter gently catches the“faller”and carefully places them back on their feet. The spotter and“faller”should then switch positions.

 Commands: Faller: Spotter Ready?

                   Spotter: (when ready) Ready.

                   Faller: Falling.

 Spotter: Fall on.

 Trust Fall 

 Objective: To develop trust within the group by having each participant fall into the arms of the group.

 Description: Begin by having one student stand on a table or platform approximately 3 to 4 feet off the ground. Their back should be facing the group, and their eyes should be closed. They must remain straight and stiff during the entire initiative. Divide the group in half, into two lines, facing each other, shoulder to shoulder. Their feet should be shoulder width apart with one slightly in front of the other. Have the spotters hold their arms out in front of them, extended from the elbows, palms up. After using the commands listed below, the student falls backward, remaining stiff. The group catches him or her and then sets him or her down feet first.

 Rules: 1. The group must be in a spotting position, arms bent at the elbow in front of them, before the student gets on the platform.

2. The group should keep their heads back so that the student won’t hit them when he or she falls.

3. The student should cross his or her arms on his chest so they won’t hit the group.

4. The faller needs to remain straight during the entire initiative; the faller should NOT bend at the waist.

5. Divide strength equally within the group. Make sure strong group members support the area where the torso and bottom hit.

6. Every one in the group needs to remove watches and glasses.

7. Instructors should make sure that the area is cleared of any obstacles.

8. Make sure that the group is ready before the student gets on the platform.

9. The instructors should place themselves in a position of control. There should be one staff at the end of the line looking towards the faller and one staff member standing behind the possible weakest link.

10. Teach students to“give with their legs to absorb weight,”to lessen stress on the back.

11. Commands: Faller : Spotters ready?

 Spotters : (when ready) Ready.

 Faller : Falling.

                         Spotters : Fall on.

 Willow in the Wind 

 Objective: To develop trust within the group.

 Description: Students stand in a tight circle, facing in, hip-to-hip. There should be one person inside the circle who will be the“faller.”Every one in the circle will be in spotting position. After saying the commands listed below, the“faller”will gently fall backwards. The members of the group in the circle will gently and slowly roll the“faller”around the circle.

 Rules: 1. The“faller”must keep his or her feet stationary at all times. Feet should be firmly planted on the ground.

2. The“faller”needs to stand as straight as possible throughout the entire initiative with his or her arms crossed.

3. Group members in the circle need to be in spotting position at all times.

4. Do not allow group members to throw the center person.

5. When the instructor motions, the group should gently place the“faller”back on his or her feet, OR move into a Flying Carpet.

6. The instructors must remain in control of the group at all times.

7. Commands: Faller: Spotter Ready?

                      Spotter: (when ready) Ready.

                     Faller: Falling.

 Spotter: Fall on.

Low Rope Initiatives

 Islands 

 Objective: To develop teamwork and communication within the group.

 Description:  The group must get all of the members from the small island to the large island by using the boards provided and by crossing over the middle medium size island.

 Rules: Every member of the group must start on the small island. The group is given two boards, neither of which is long enough to reach the other islands. Using the boards and each other, the group must move to the larger island by crossing over the middle, medium size island. Jumping to different islands is not allowed. If a member in the group or a board touches the water around the island, the entire group must start over. Instructors should spot students as they pass from island to island.

 Mohawk Walk 

 Objective: To build communication and teamwork within the group.

 Description: The entire group must move from point A to point B by walking on top of a series of cables without falling off.

 Rules: 1. Start the group at one end of the series of cables and explain to them that the entire group must make it to the other end of the cables.

2. The entire group must move together.

3. If any student feels like he or she might fall off, that student should STEP off the cable in order to prevent a bad fall.

4. Instructors should walk along the length of the cable and spot students walking on the cable.

5. You can either have all of the students start over every time a student steps off the cable, OR you can tell the group that a certain number of falls will be allowed during the game. They should try to get to point B in the least number of falls. If that number exceeds the number the instructor set forth in the beginning, then the entire group must start over.

 Nitro 

 Objective: To develop communication, cooperation, and problem solving skills.

 Description: Using only the items they are wearing, students must retrieve the swinging cable without stepping over the boundary lines. They must then get the whole group and a can of water over the area within the boundaries without touching the enclosed area or spilling the water.

 Rules:  1. Students must not touch the area between the boundaries or knock off the bamboo poles that are the boundary lines. If they do, the entire group must start over.

2. The can of water must be brought over without spilling, or the entire group must begin again.

3. No jumping, dropping, or leaping from the cable.

4. There must be two staff spotters on the far side to catch incoming students until there are enough students on the far side to fill this role.

5. No sticks or rocks can be used to retrieve the cable.

6. Students should not throw the cable across the area. They should let it drop from their grasp.

7. The instructors should be in a position of control at all times.

8. Be sure that all obstacles and debris have been cleared from the area.

Variations: Have students land on an All Aboard.

 Swinging Balance Beam 

 Objective: To build group communication.

 Description: One student at a time will step onto the beam and, trying to balance, will walk down to the end, turn around, and come back to the start. The student then steps off the beam.

 Rules: 1. Teach proper spotting technique to the students.

2. As a student walks across the log, the rest of the group will be spotting him or her on either side of the beam.

3. The balancing student can grab onto the spotter’s heads to keep from falling off the beam.

4. No jumping, dropping, or leaping from the beam.

5. Students must walk around the beam, not between the tree and the beam as they could get a leg crushed.

 The Wall 

 Objective: To develop problem solving, trust, and team work.

 Description: The group must plan a way to get every member over a 12.5’high wall.

 Rules: 1. At Tull Hall, anytime a student is coming off the backside of the wall, all students must go to the back to spot.

At the Summer Camp, anytime a student is coming off the backside of the wall, several students must hold the ladder for the student as he or she climbs down.

2. Everyone who is not directly involved with the event must be spotting.

3. Once a participant has gone over the wall, they can no longer help any other student over the wall. They become“ghost spotters”and can only spot the student who is going over the wall.

4. Students cannot climb the sides of the wall or use any natural items or clothing to get over.

5. Activity only takes place on one side of the wall at a time. If a student is climbing off the wall, then no other student should be climbing up it.

6. No jumping, dropping, or leaping.

7. Students are not allowed to stick any fingers in the cracks of the wall.

8. The will be no stacking more than three levels high.

9. No more than four people can be on top of the wall at once.

10. The feet of those on top of the wall must remain on the platform.

11. A student at the top of the wall can only hang over the wall if hanging is done by the armpits, facing the wall, anchored by a person at each shoulder.

12. Before allowing the group to begin, instructors should make sure that all of the students understand the rules.

13. The instructors should always maintain a position of control so they can“catch”a fall and protect the head and back.

14. Make sure that spotters stay alert, are in the correct position, and are always spotting anyone going up the wall.

 Whale Watch 

 Objective: To develop teamwork and communication

 Description: The group must balance themselves on the whale watch without it touching the ground.

 Rules: 1. Split the group in half and position each half at each opposite ends of the platform. The students must maintain a balanced whale watch for at least 10 seconds.

2. Be sure that no one is standing at the sides of the whale watch so that no feet are smashed.

3. Have students exit and enter the whale watch from the center.

Variations:

 With the whale watch balanced, have the 50/50 divided group standing on opposite ends attempt to change ends without letting the platform make contact with the ground. Do a blindfold walk to the whale watch. Place the blindfolded students on the whale watch and have them balance the group. 

   

   

Full Day Initiatives

 Nancy Creek Crossing 

 Objective: To develop teamwork, communication, and cooperation within the group.

 Description: Students build a rope bridge across Nancy Creek and send as many students as time allows across the bridge.

 Rules: Split the group in half. Half of the group stands on one side of the creek while the other half stands directly across from them. Half of the students have the ropes while the other half across the creek has webbing, p-cord, and carabiners. Brief the activity by telling the students that they must build a bridge across Nancy Creek. The bridge must be built between the two trees designated by a Discovery staff member. In addition to building a bridge, the group must also build a safety line that the person crossing the bridge can be hooked into. This means that the group must also build a harness for the person crossing the bridge. Large ropes cannot be thrown across the creek and cannot get wet.

 Safety: There should be at least one Discovery staff member on either side of the creek. A Discovery staff member must approve the trees that the students use to build the bridge. Before any student crosses the bridge, a Discovery staff member must check and approve all knots and harnesses. The group cannot throw the large ropes from one side of the creek to another. Tell the students that the rope must not get wet. Students cannot throw large rocks or carabiners across the creek. Make sure that the safety line the students build is not at neck level. Make sure that students help the bridge-crosser on and off of the bridge.   

 Equipment: One 40’dynamic climbing rope, 4 carabiners, enough webbing to make a harness, 30’of p-cord (can be in pieces), and large ropes to use as foot bridge.

 Litter Rescue 

 Objective: To develop teamwork, communication, and cooperation within the group. To prepare the group for an emergency in a wilderness setting.

 Description: The group must figure out what is wrong with a patient and then give the patient the first aid he or she needs. They must then organize and carry out an evacuation of this patient in a litter.

 Rules: The entire group must give the patient proper first aid care for his or her injuries. They must then organize and implement a plan to evacuate the patient. The patient must be securely fastened to the liter with plenty of padding. The patient should tell the group if they are in pain or are uncomfortable with the way the group is handling the situation. Before the group evacuates the patient, an instructor must make sure the patient is secure within the liter. Have the group carry the patient from point A to point B. You can make the initiative more challenging by asking the group to cross Nancy Creek or to travel off of the trails. During the liter carry, make sure that the entire group is helping and that the brunt of the weight does not lie on one or two people.

 Equipment: Litter, old sleeping bags, sleeping pads, tent poles, old clothing, first aid handbook, webbing, ropes.

 B. Artificial Climbing Wall 

           At times instructors may find it appropriate to use the Smith Climbing Wall as part of Ninth Grade Discovery. The climbing wall provides a great opportunity for the freshmen to work together and develop trust. It may also provide an opportunity for students to challenge their fear of heights and feel a sense of accomplishment. Due to the size of the climbing wall it is best to use it with smaller groups. Large groups become chaotic and people may loose their concentration. Only climbing wall certified instructors have the option of using the wall as part of their session. If an instructor wants to become certified they must attend the Climbing Wall seminar which is offered twice a year.

           It is important for the instructor to be able to teach the following curriculum in the following sequence in order to maximize your time on the wall and the freshman’s understanding of indoor climbing. It is the instructor team’s responsibility to be prepared for all of these classes prior to starting the day’s activity!

 Climbing Wall Introduction– This is the time to introduce the wall. Show your students where the equipment is found and issue shoes, harnesses, belay devices, locking carabiners, and chalk bags. You should also give a thorough safety briefing and review the safety policies.

 Harness– Demonstrate how the Petzel harnesses are put on. Explain the different parts to the harness. Note that the Petzel harness buckles do not need to be doubled back. If you need to use the Misty Mountain Fudge or other harness that requires being double backed for any reason, be sure to demonstrate how they are properly used. Make sure that the hip belt fits over the hips in order to prevent students from falling out of it. Harnesses should be secure and allow for no more than 4 fingers to be slid between the harness and the climber.

 Shoes– If your group decides to use climbing shoes, instruct them on the proper way to fit and lace climbing shoes. For the purposes of beginner climbers, the shoes should fit snuggly but still comfortably. Tight shoes are for more advanced climbing and sadomasochists!

 Knots– Teach your students the proper way to tie a“figure 8 follow through”knot. Be sure to teach them to“dress”their knots. The tails should be no shorter and no longer than double the width of the knot. If the tail has the proper length, no so called“safety knot”is needed. At times, Discovery chooses to use figure 8 on a bite with a locking carabiner in order to tie into the rope. Unfortunately, when using this method, the student does not learn how to“clip”proper knots for climbing. It also creates a knot that is difficult to untie at the end of the activity. This method should be reserved for Junior High climbing programs and on the occasion when time is short.

 Belaying– The instructors should demonstrate a clear and organized belay school. As always, position your students in way that everyone can see what is going on! Create the order of events when preparing to climb. There are three members of the belay team– the belayer, the climber, and the back-up belayer. The belayer demonstrates the proper way of loading a belay device with the break hand being the dominate hand. The climber should demonstrate how to properly tie into the climbing end of the rope. The back-up belayer stands behind the belayer, holding onto the brake hand side of the rope. They will take in rope at the same time as the climber moves upward. If the belayer accidentally removes their brake hand when the climber falls, the back-up belayer is there to catch the falling climber.

The party should demonstrate thorough safety checks.

1. The belayer shows that the belay device is threaded correctly and the locking carabiner receives a squeeze check. They should also show that their harness has been put on correctly and the buckle is double backed if necessary.

2. There are no twists in the rope.

3. The climber is properly tied in to the end with a dressed knot and the right amount of tail. Climbers’harness has been put on correctly and the buckle is double backed if necessary.

4. The team insures that they have a back-up belayer.

 Belay Motion– Discovery uses the BUS method of belaying: this stands for Break, Underhand, Slide. Demonstrate this with the students and allow them to practice before they actually belay. See illustration .

Insert Illustration

 Belay Commands 

Now the team commits themselves to a contract. The“Primary”belayers are accepting the responsibility of keeping the climber safe from falling. The belayers will not remove their break hands from the rope under any circumstances. The contract begins with the belayer and ends with the climber.

 Belayer , “On Belay, Johnny.”

 Climber ,“Climbing Frankie.”

 Belayer , “Climb, Johnny.”

Discuss with your students the terms that may be used while the climber is climbing such as up rope, slack, watch me , etc.

Once the climber has reached the top or wants to be lowered to the ground, the team returns to the contract.

 Climber ,“Tension, Johnny!”

 Belayer responds by removing any slack that might still be in the rope.

 Climber ,“Lower me, Johnny.”

 Belayer responds by backing up their break hand with their guide hand and slowly lowering the climber.

When the climber reaches the ground the contract is ended when…

 Climber ,“Belay Off, Johnny!”

Now it is safe for the belayer to remove their brake hand from the rope.

Once this entire sequence has been demonstrated and the students have been given an opportunity to practice, it is time to climb. Be sure to have the students follow the rules exactly as they were taught. Failure to follow the rules may result in a student being dismissed from the wall.


 C. High Ropes 

 Purpose 

a.      To provide opportunities to develop self-confidence by confronting fears.

b.     To provide an opportunity to test balance and coordination and fear of heights.

c.      To teach students to be responsible for the physical and emotional safety of other members in the group.

 Pole Course 

Safety Policies

a.      High Ropes events may be postponed because of unfavorable weather conditions.

b.     Only locking steel carabiners will be used on running belays on the pole course.

c.      The crab claw lanyards will be attached to the harness with a locking carabiner.

d.     The carabiner will be attached through the belay loop on the harness.

e.      Harnesses will be worn correctly with the buckles facing out and properly threaded. The harness should be snug enough to allow no more than 4 fingers to slide between the harness and the body.

f.       Rescue equipment will be available on the swing platform.

g.      Instructors will be anchored at two separate anchor points at spotting stations off the ground or will be anchored into running belays above platforms.

h.      A qualified staff person will do a final check of a student’s harness, helmet, and crab claws prior to the student entering the tube net.

i.        A staff member will supervise all belay switchovers.

j.       All students will have completed ground school under the supervision of a qualified staff person prior to participating in the pole course.

k.     Students will not put their hands in the loops, or wrap the hand lines around their wrists on the giant swing.

l.        Students will wear helmets on all high element activities.

m.    Students will be hooked in continuously from the moment their hips are above the tube net.

n.      Students will stay behind designated boundary lines unless they are participating in the event.

o.  Everyone inside of the ropes course fence will wear a helmet whenever anyone is on the course.

p. No gum chewing while on the course.

q.  A ratio no larger than one adult and 2 student staff to 10 9 th graders will be maintained.

 Updated 11/20/02 


 Presentation 

 Equipment 

       a. Helmets . Introduce the use of helmets and demonstrate proper fit and adjustments. The helmet should be firm on the forehead, not tight on chinstrap .

       b. Harnesses . Introduce the harness and demonstrate proper fit. Put on leg by leg. Never drop or step on harness. The harness must go outside of the top layer of clothes and the buckles must be visible. The harness should be snug enough to allow no more than 4 fingers to slide between the harness and the body.

       c. Crab claws . Discuss different lengths of lanyards, strength of steel carabiners, and note that the screw gates on the carabiners on each set of crab claws are two different colors (one gold/one silver). Demonstrate how to adjust the crab claw lanyards by sliding the prussic knot. Demonstrate how to wear the crab claws. Crab claws should be attached to the harness with a locking carabiner, which must go through the belay loop.

 Ground School 

As soon as everyone has their helmets and harnesses adjusted, take them over to Ground School. Tell people not to sit down while wearing their harnesses, as it causes wear and tear on the leg loops. A student staff should demonstrate and teach the following:

1.     Proper places to clip in on the ropes course,

2.     What a squeeze check is and when it needs to be done; it does not need to be done when a student is climbing the staples (teach the“screw down so you don’t screw up”motto to ensure students are flipping and locking their carabiners).

3.     How to prevent double unclippings.

4.     How to transfer carabiners by color by using the following command system:

            Person on course:“Glynnis, transferring gold.”      

                           Ground Belayer:“Watching, Josh.” 

      After the person on the course hears“Watching…”they unlock and move the carabiner to new cable, clip in, flip the carabiner, and screw gate closed ( not too tight ).

 Person on course:“Squeeze check gold, Glynnis.”  (Squeezes gate, next one needs to have gate opposed to first carabiner)

                           Ground Belayer:&quot;Thank you, Josh.”  

                                                  Repeat for silver carabiner.

5.     How to climb staples:

-- do not screw down the locking sleeve of the carabiners when climbing staples

-- make sure that carabiners are clipped into two different staples

-- make sure that the carabiners are clipped into staples above the climber’s waist

       Make sure that ground belayers know that they must be watching the transfers at all times. If they cannot see the carabiners, they should move or ask the person on the course to do another squeeze check.                                                                                                                               Updated 11/20/02 

 Procedures/Flow 

1.     Student successfully completes Ground School.

2.     Student goes over to tube net with partner (ground belayer) for a final hands on (head to toe) check of equipment with a staff person.

3.     Staff person will check the harness, helmet, and crab claws of the climber, and review commands with the climber and the ground belayer.

4.     Staff person will instruct ground belayer on holding the tube net until the climber has clipped into the first event.

5.     Climber must be clipped into the ropes course before his or her hips are out of the tube net.

6.     Climber can go either to the right or the left (the post man’s walk or the Burma Bridge).

 Remember, climbers on the course should be encouraged to challenge themselves as much as possible by not holding onto their crab claws. Both crab claws should be over one shoulder, never on each side of the head . Carabiners will be locked and opposed at all times while on a running cable. 

 Wild-Woozy Procedures 

1. Students will not interlock fingers.

2. Both lanyards of the students’crab claws need to be behind the student.

 Giant Swing Procedures 

1. Discovery Faculty is clipped in at the end of the wild-woozy.

2. Waiting students should be clipped into the running belay above the platform.

3. Clip Swinger into 2 different anchors on pole.

4. Swinger moves onto swing seat.

5. Swinger attaches seat belt around thighs (make sure the buckle clicks).

6. Pull up Swing assembly.

7. Swinger clips Swing carabiner through the belay loop of the harness and locks it.

8. Unclip retrieval carabiner and lower to the ground - right front (on the outside of the cable).

9. Unclip“Silver”carabiner and attach above Delta ( never on hand loops !).

10. Unclip“Gold”carabiner and attach above opposite side of Delta.

11. Crab claw lanyards should be put between the student’s legs to keep them out of the way.

12. Swinger holds red and blue hands cords; students should not put hands through cords.

13. Make sure crab claw rope loops are not around feet or hooked on any obstructions.

14. When swinger is ready, undo seat belt.

15. Swinger moves to edge of seat and takes off.

Exit from the giant swing–Swinger lowers on of the crab claw lanyards to the side of his/her body. Person on the ground uses the lowered lanyard to slow down the swinger. 2 people will hold the ladder while a staff person supervises the unclipping from the swing. Make sure that the swing’s big locking carabiner is still attached to the swing. Attach the retrieval line to the side of the delta.

 Site Management–Staffing 

 Required 

A qualified Discovery faculty at the giant swing will supervise everything from a bird’s eye view. The primary responsibilities of the faculty are getting participants safely across the wild-woozy, and both into and safely off of the giant swing. The faculty also needs to be aware of everything happening on the course and on the ground. They are also responsible for calling and organizing an evacuation of the course in case of lightning, and for conducting any rescues.

       Recommended  

 One staff member at the intersection of the balance beam and swinging bridge. This person will help participants ascend the pole to the high woozy and will be an extra set of eyes on the course, watching and double-checking all transfers.

 One staff member on the ground at the tube net entrance to the course . This person is responsible for the final hands-on check of every harness, helmet, and crab claw prior to a participant entering the tube net. This person is also responsible for the student’s exit from the giant swing. They must organize the ladder crew for moving the ladder to the swing and holding it steady, stop the swinger by grabbing hold of his or her crab claw, and spot the person as they exit the giant swing.

 Total recommended: 2 student staff, plus one supervising Discovery faculty .                 

  Closure 

Put away harnesses, helmets, and crab claws. Debrief the day. Take crab claws up to“Jabba the Hut”and hang on hooks. Wipe inside of helmets with Lysol. Hang helmets from appropriate hooks on back wall. Make sure that use of the equipment is logged in the Usage Book.


 Trapeze 

 Safety Policies 

a.      A trained staff member, or supervised participant, will belay the trapeze. 

b.     The belay runs through a friction pole and must be checked by a faculty member.

c.      The student climbing and the two students holding the ladder will wear helmets.

d.     A double figure eight on a bite will be used to attach the carabiner to the climber.

e.      The carabiner will be attached through both loops on the back of the full body harness.

f.       Before climbing the trapeze pole, each student must be checked by a trained staff member and must use the command system with the belayer.

 Presentation  

       Equipment 

 a. Helmets . Introduce the use of helmets and demonstrate proper fit and adjustments. Helmets should be firm on forehead, not tight on chinstrap. 

 b. Harnesses . Introduce the full body harness. Demonstrate proper fit and adjustments. Put on leg by leg. Never drop or step on harness. Must go on outside of top layer of clothes and buckles must be visible. Clip a non-locking carabiner through chest loops for adjustment. Tighten all adjustable straps, legs and chest.                

 c. Belay rope . Explain that the belay works by using friction created in the friction pole. The rope should be attached through both loops on the back of the full body harness by using a double figure eight on a bite and a steel carabiner.

 Procedures/Flow 

1.     Demonstrate helmet and full body harness.

2.     Describe how to climb up the rope ladder and staples to the platform. After climbing onto the platform, the student will turn around and jump for the trapeze.

3.     Describe the belay commands:

 Belayer: “On Belay.”

 Climber: “Climbing.”

 Belayer: “Climb.”

4.     The climber must not leave the ground until he/she has completed the commands, has been checked by a trained Discovery staff member, and has two ladder holders.

5.     When the climber gets on the platform, the belayer must be careful to take up the slack without pulling the climber off. Participants should be encouraged to go as high as possible and if they are balking at jumping for the trapeze ask them to at least step off, so that they initiate the experience. Never force or pull someone off! 

6.     When the person jumps, the belayer should quickly take up the slack by taking a step back while pulling the belay rope through the pole.

7.     Slowly lower the jumper to the ground to be a staff person, who will meet the jumper and ensure a soft, secure touchdown.

 NOTE: The student group makes good belayers, too! In order to keep everyone involved, consider teaching them how to belay as a group and then have them take turns belaying each other.

Remember, some staples on the tree are slippery, so the belayer must be alert for a possible early peel off. Variations: 1) blindfold the climber 2) have several members of the group belay.

 Site Management–Staffing 

       Required 

A qualified Discovery Staff member at the belay station and a staff person to check knots, help adjust full body harnesses, double check harnesses and helmets before student climbs, supervise ladder holders, and maintain crowd control.

 Total recommended: 2 people, at least one Discovery faculty. 


 Zip Line 

 Safety Policies            

a.      The Discovery Faculty will be clipped into two separate anchors on the zip platform.

b.     The crab claw lanyards will be attached to the harness with a locking carabiner. The carabiner must go through the belay loop of the harness.

c.      Students will be hooked into two different staples above the waist when climbing the tree to the large platform.

d.     Students will be clipped into the running belay over the Two-Line Bridge.

e.      Each student must have a final hands on (head to toe) check of his/her harness, helmet, and crab claws by a trained Discovery staff member prior to climbing onto the element.

f.       Every student participating in the activity must be wearing a helmet.

g.      Rescue equipment will be available at the zip platform with the Discovery Faculty.

 Presentation   

 Equipment 

 a. Helmets . Introduce the use of helmets and demonstrate proper fit and      adjustments. They should be firm on forehead, not tight on chinstrap.

 b. Harnesses . Introduce and demonstrate proper fit of harness. Harnesses should sit above the hipbones. Put on the harness leg by leg. Never drop or step on harnesses. Harnesses must go on outside the top layer of clothes and all buckles must be visible. Harnesses should fit snug enough to allow no more than 4 fingers to fit between the webbing and the body.

 c. Crab Claws . Crab claws must have two locking steel carabiners of different colors (one silver/one gold). Attach crab claws with a locking carabiner through the belay loop on the harness.

 Procedures/Flow 

1.     A Discovery staff person will perform a final hands-on check of“zippers’”harness, helmet, and crab claws. 

2.     “Zipper”will ascend the ladder with two students holding the ladder steady.

3.     When the“zipper”reaches the first staple in the tree, s/he will clip into the staple and continue to ascent to the platform. The“zipper”must be clipped into two separate staples above his/her waist.

4.     On the platform, the“zipper”will clip into the safety line above the platform with both carabiners.

5.     The“zipper”moves to the end of the platform and clips into the running belay above the Two Line Bridge, making sure to do a squeeze check for each carabiner.

6.     The“zipper”crosses the Two Line Bridge until he/she reaches the Discovery Faculty at the zip platform.

7.     When the“zipper”reaches the platform, the faculty member will hook him/her into two separate anchors on the tree.

8.     The“zipper”should be sitting on the platform. The“zipper”is then clipped into the pulley assembly and the retrieval line is lowered to the ground.

9.     The Discovery Faculty then unclips the“zipper”from the tree anchor and attaches the crab claw carabiners to the“zipper’s”harness.

10. The“zipper”then slowly slides off the zip platform.

11. When the“zipper”has stopped, students help him/her unclip from the zip line. Make sure that the carabiner is still attached to the pulley assembly.

12. Attach the retrieval line to the pulley system.

13. A student should walk up the hill towards the zip platform with the retrieval line. This student should walk past the zip platform until the Discovery Faculty is able to grab hold of the pulley system.

14. The process continues with a new“zipper.”

 Site Management–Staffing 

 Required 

 A Discovery faculty member on the zip takeoff platform . The faculty member’s job is to oversee the entire zip line. This includes the Two Line Bridge and the ladder used to take“zippers”off of the zip line. Faculty members must also clip“zippers”into zip pulley system.

 One student staff at bottom of ladder checking harnesses, helmets, and crab claws prior to the“zipper”entering the element. This student is also in charge of retrieving harnesses from the zip take off ladder to the zip entrance ladder in order for new“zippers”to use them. This student is also in charge of the ground site management; he or she must make sure all students on the ground have on their helmets and that all students are well behaved. Lastly, this student is in charge of maintaining a steady flow of students up to the zip line platform.

 One student staff stationed on the first platform, clipping students into the safety line above the platform and into the running belay above the Two Line Bridge. This student must be clipped into the safety line above the platform.

                   Total recommended: 2 student staff, plus one Discovery faculty. 

                                                                                                            Updated 11/20/02 

 IV. Expedition 

 A. Skills Day/Packout 

    The main purpose for skills day is to train students to use the equipment that they will need for shelter and food preparation during their Discovery expedition. In addition to this training they will plan and pack their food for the expedition as well as pack their group gear. Discovery Faculty has the discretion to organize the skills day and packout sequence in the most effective manner for their particular group. The 3 main areas of instruction during packout are tarp set-up/tent set-up, stove use, food packaging, and clothes check.

 Shelter Set-up 

Students should know how to properly set-up whichever shelter is being taken on their expedition. It is advised that you issue the Eureka tents when camping in the mountains during winter session (i.e. Session 3–Spring Intensive 1). This will keep students warmer and dryer when the weather is poor. Tarps are much lighter and emphasize the need for quality construction if they are to keep one dry in a downpour.

 Note: It is important to remember to inventory and check all shelters that you issue both before you leave for expedition and when you return! 

Tarp Set-Up

Students will be taught the standard A-frame tarp set-up. The only knot that needs to be taught is the trucker’s hitch. Students will set-up tarps between two trees. Each side of the“mid-line”will be tied off with truckers hitches to adjust tightness. The four corners and four side tie-outs should be staked out appropriately using the truckers hitch to set the tension. Tarps should be taut enough to bounce a coin off of. Students will be shown the top and bottom side of the tarp (bottom side has more obvious seams). Tarps are stored in a stuff sack with 8 stakes. Approximately 8 feet of parachute cord will be attached to each grommet on the tarp.

Insert Diagram of truckers hitch and tarp set-up here

 Tent Set -Up 

Students will be assigned to a tent group. In their tent group they will put up their assigned tent (either a 4 or 6 person tent). Proper care of the tents will be taught, as well as, how to set it up and take it down. Each group is responsible for making sure that the zippers, tent poles, junction tubes, rain fly, parachute cord, and stakes are all in good shape and are packed back into the stuff sack with the tent. A tag with the names of each person in the group will then be attached to the stuff sack for base camp expeditions. Backpackers will divide up the tent components and pack them as part of their group gear.


 Stove Use 

Students should be able to demonstrate how to assemble, light, and safely use the stove that will be taken on their expedition. This should be taught on campus prior to leaving for the field.

 MSR Whisperlite 

The MSR Whisperlite is one of the most commonly used stoves in the outdoor industry. It is fairly simple to use and maintain in the field once you are familiar with it. This stove burns on white gas which is very flammable. Make sure you use the red bottles for white gas. The stove uses about¼of a liter per day in the summer and 1/3 of a liter in the winter.

 To set up and light the stove: 

1- Place the pump onto the fuel bottle. Make sure that the pump has a rubber gasket where it connects with the bottle. Then see that the pump is on securely, but beware of cross-threading and destroying the plastic threads on the pump.

2- Place the lower wind screen on the stove body and then extend the legs.

3- Connect the fuel line on the stove body into the fuel tube on the pump. Snap safety bail around the pump in order to avoid a fuel spill.

4- Place stove on a level spot that has been cleared of leaves and debris that could catch on fire.

5- Pump 15-20 times to pressurize fuel bottle.

6- Turn valve on a½turn and wait until fuel begins to enter priming cup. Turn off valve.

7- Light fuel in priming cup. The flame will now heat up the generator. This allows for the fuel to turn into a vapor once it passes through the hot generator. Once it is a vapor the fuel will burn easily out of the jet without flaming up too high .

8- Once the fuel in the priming cup has burned out, you may turn the valve back on. When you hear the fuel hissing out of the jet you should light stove on top of the burner. Caution! If the stove is not sufficiently primed there will be liquid and vapor fuel coming out of the jet. It sounds like a loud, squirting hiss. Do not light stove at this point. If you do you will create the flaming tower of inferno! Instead, turn the stove back off and re-prime. 

 Insert Stove photos here 

Things to tell students!

-         Avoid walking through the kitchen unnecessarily. This could result in a tipped over stove or pot of hot water.

-        Do not try to take the stove apart until it has sufficiently cooled off.

-        Store extra fuel outside of the kitchen.

-        Avoid placing the stove directly in the dirt. It is important to keep the stoves free of dirt and grime that could clog the jet and fuel line. If this happens you will be spending part of your night cleaning stoves instead of cold-hard chillin!

·       See Appendix for STOVE MAINTANANCE information.

Trangia

Sometimes instructors may decide to use a less complicated stove on their expedition. The Trangia set up is fairly simple and cooking on one is easier to manage. Caution! During winter sessions it is important to remember that the Trangia stoves do not burn as hot and take more time to boil water than the Whisperlite stoves. This may be of some importance in an emergency situation.

 Here are the steps to teaching the Trangia: 

 Step #1– Demonstrate the proper set-up of the Trangia. Show the students how to remove the nesting pots, how to reverse and attach the two base pieces of the stoves together. Explain how the 3“pot holders”flip up and down in order to accommodate different size pots.

 Step #2 –Discuss the difference between denatured alcohol and white gas. Make sure that your students know that the denatured alcohol should only be stored in the silver fuel bottles.

 Step #3 - At this time you should introduce the brass fuel charges. Show the students the three parts to a fuel charge- the fuel charge body, the threaded lid (make sure that there is a rubber gasket on the inside of the lid. Do not place lid on a hot fuel charge! It melts the rubber gasket.), and the simmer cap. Explain how the parts work and how to insert the charge into the Trangia body. Tell your students to fill the charges and store the fuel outside of the kitchen. You should never travel with full fuel charges. Despite the rubber gasket on the lid, fuel inevitably leaks out and contaminates other items in your backpack.

 Step #4 - Now it is time to“Let there be light”! Teaching ninth graders how to use fire is always a scary proposition but it is mandatory in order to eat. Either by using a match or an extended lighter, simply light the fuel that is in the fuel charge. There will be no giant burst of flame or any other violent explosion as long as you are using the correct fuel. In fact, at first you may not see a flame at all. The denatured alcohol needs time to warm up before there is a medium sized blue flame.

 Step #5 –Cook your food! Be careful not to turn over the stove. This will cause the fuel to spill and the flame to become dangerous. You may use the simmer lid to control the flame if you need one.

 Step #6 –To extinguish the flame, simply close the simmer lid and place it on top of the fuel charge. This scares even the boldest ninth grader. One must be deliberate when snuffing out the flame! Make sure that the stove is cool before collapsing the stove.


 Pack Fitting 

           Prior to a Discovery backpacking expedition, you should teach your students how to fit their backpacks properly. If a student carries 40 pounds in a poorly fitted pack for an entire weekend they are going to complain the entire time. However, if your student’s packs fit comfortably they will be happier and have more energy to learn what you have to teach them and to enjoy being in a beautiful place. So, make sure that you work in time to fit all of your student’s packs.

            Backpack Anatomy 101 

 Insert photo of pack and text to correspond with it. 

            Pack fitting 101 

(See charts in equipment room)

 Insert photo of properly fit pack. 


 Issue Process 

           Issue day should take place as the last on-campus day activity. It is a day that is dedicated to prepping for the expedition. You will issue food and equipment to your students and organize for the Friday departure. It is very important that you are organized and have a plan before you begin this day. Therefore, you should plan on being at the Discovery Office no later than 3:00 pm. Use the previous days for menu planning and deciding what gear you want to take. It can be very stressful if you do not have your ducks in a row! Most likely, there will be 2-3 groups issuing at the same time. Make sure to co-ordinate with the other instructors about the day’s schedule and where you will have your group.

            The two main tasks for issue day will be food and gear issue. You should have previously taught your students skills, such as pack packing prior to this day so that they will know what to do with all of the equipment issued to them. Some groups have time to go over the individual clothing on this day. If you choose to wait until the last day to check clothes, your students may not have enough time to find replacement clothes if what they brought is not appropriate . Make sure to at least read through the clothing list with your students early in the session! 

 Food Issue 

Discovery uses a“Bulk Ration”system. This means that we buy food in large quantities, store it in large bins, and then issue it in amounts that are specific to the individual course’s size and needs. Buying in bulk has many advantages. It reduces packaging waste, is more cost effective and allows for better long term storage. Most importantly, it allows students to learn the skill of rations planning for an expedition.

Before you take students into the food room you should have already organized the following details:

-        The menu is already planned and quantities are posted on the board.

-        Food room is clean to set the standard for how it should be left once issue is finished.

-        There are clean scoops and the scales are out.

-        You should have 2-3 purple bins to pack your food. If you want to leave the last day’s lunch in the bus, label one bin as“VAN FOOD.”

 Once your students are in the food room you should brief them on these following points: 

 Give the students a thorough tour of the food room. Show them where the various types of food are located, what is in the fridge, where plastic bags are located, empty jars, etc. Explain the menu board. Tell the students how you arrived at the quantities and the importance for packing the exact amount shown by the food type. If you pack less than what is indicated you will be short of food. If you pack too much you will carry extra weight. One of the staff members or a TRUSTED student should stand by the board throughout food issue and check off items that have been assigned and bagged. Explain the clean up procedures (sweeping, mopping, washing scoops, recycling, etc.). Set the standards high! Be sure to tie loose knots in the plastic bags! If they are too tight it will be difficult to untie in the field. Have students pour powder foods over the sink. When they spill it is difficult to clean. Once food is bagged it should go into the purple bin. 

 Now it is time to pack the food! 

As instructors it is your job to stay actively involved during food issue. Answer student questions and make sure that tasks are being done with quality. Once you have packed all of the food and the food room is clean, take the bins down to the garage and pack the food into backpacks. You can issue stuff sacks from the gear room for food. That way you can divide the rations evenly amongst the group.

 Gear Issue 

Prior to gear issue you should have already filled out the Gear Issue Sheet found in the Discovery Office. These sheets should be kept on the issue clip boards in the gear room. Make sure to collaborate with your co-instructor on what types of gear you want your students to take before your students show up. For example, do you want to take Whisperlites or Trangia stoves? Tarps or tents? Mark the categories as you issue each item in order to insure that you do forget anything.

 Here is a suggested progression for gear issue: 

 Issue backpacks. Be sure to match students with the proper size pack. You may choose to fit the pack now or wait until later (See pack fitting ). Issue sleeping bags. This includes a compression stuff sack, a sleeping bag system (summer bag, winter bag, fleece liner-combination depends upon season and forecasted weather), cotton liner, ensolite pad, and plastic ground sheet if tarps are used. Issue cup, bowl, and spoon. Have students pack these in the top lid of their backpack. Now have the students divide up the group gear. This should be in a central pile or bin and should include the food if you have already bagged rations. Students can work this out amongst themselves. This Give them some indication, however, on ratio of body weight to pack weight. No one should carry more than 50% of their body weight. Even this is too much for the standard Discovery weekend backpacking trip! At this point, have your students pack these items into their backpacks. Hopefully you will have checked the student’s clothing and they can pack that as well. Store your packed packs in a neat pile in the gear room. Make sure that your gear does not get mixed up with another group’s! 

Here are some other tips!


 Consider labeling packs with the student’s name. You can use masking tape found on the work bench. That way each person knows whose pack is whose. Leave the filled out issue sheet on a clip board hanging in the gear room. One less piece of paperwork you have to lug around. Check your Whisperlite stoves before you leave! These stoves require maintenance. Light them up and see if they burn a strong blue flame. You don’t want to get into the backcountry and discover that your stove is bunk. Make sure you inventory the stove bag so that you have all the needed parts. Be clear and directive with your instructions! This does not have to be complicated. 



 B. Expedition 

 Vehicles 

 Safety Policies and Procedures 

1. Vehicles will only be operated by approved, licensed drivers who have a completed DMV form on file with the school.

2. Only authorized personnel will be allowed to ride in vehicles. They will be safely seated before vehicle departs.

3. Seat belts will be worn at all times the vehicle is in motion.

4. A vehicle will not be loaded beyond its safe seating capacity unless in an emergency. In emergency circumstances, additional passengers must be secure within the vehicle.

5. Passengers must wait for the vehicle to come to a complete stop before boarding or dismounting.

6. Horseplay in vehicles will not be permitted.

7. Vehicles will be kept clean.

8. All vehicles must come to a full stop at railroad crossings and observe the laws of that state relative to coming to a full stop before entering a state highway or county road.

9.   Each driver will have directions to the program use areas, a set of relevant maps, and a vehicle first-aid kit.

10. Vehicles will travel with lights on at all times.

Your primary job during travel in the vehicles is to help with“crowd control”. Make sure that the students are not distracting the driver and are safe and comfortable. When the faculty member locks up the vehicle prior to heading out, make sure that you know where the key is stashed in case of an emergency.

 1. Backpacking 

 Backpack Packing 101 

           If you are going to take folks backpacking you’re going to have to teach them how to pack their backpack. One way for your students to have a better time in the woods is for them to have a well packed backpack. Backpacks that are packed correctly carry better, allowing you to have more energy to enjoy the natural world. It also makes your group look like they know what they are doing when they pass those rag-tag gypsy-types that call themselves backpackers, on the trail!

           Always remember, when packing your pack that ounces equal pounds and pounds equal PAIN! You might say to yourself,“that crazy creek chair only weighs about½a pound and the extra cotton shirt only weighs 6 oz.”But when you begin to add all those extras up you will soon be in need of a visit to the chiropractor. Take only what you really need and limit your“luxury items”to only one or two things.

One of the most important rules of pack packing is put everything on the inside of your pack! Many backpackers string cups, water bottles, ball caps, and camp shoes on the outside of their backpacks to the point where they look like newly weds driving off for their honeymoon. Not only does this method cause one to become snagged on branches, make lots of noise walking down the trail, or potentially lose important equipment, but it looks amateur! There will be some times when you cannot fit everything on the inside. When this is the case, choose a piece of gear that can be securely lashed down such as a sleeping pad or the tent poles. Have these items inside of a protective stuff sack so that they do not become broken. If properly lashed, these items will not cause you despair when hiking on or off trail.

 The A,B,C,&amp;D’s of Pack Packing! 

 Accessibility– It is a bummer to have to unload your entire pack at lunchtime to find the peanut butter that you packed near the bottom. Therefore, it is important to anticipate what pieces of equipment you will need throughout the day when packing your pack in the morning. Think about the gear that you only use at camp. Hmmm…sleeping bag, tarp, those extra warm fleece pants, pots and stoves, etc. What are the things that you will need during the day–map, hat, water bottles, snack food, headlamp, rain gear, a warm layer, etc. Put the things that you will not need towards the bottom of your pack and things that you will need towards the top. Utilize the top lid to help you organize those items that you want accessible, as well as any side pockets that might come with your pack.

 Balance– No one wants to carry a pack that is top heavy or that lists to the side. Make sure that you center the heaviest equipment just behind the lumbar region of the pack. This keeps the weight closer to your center of gravity and allows the pack to carry the way its designers intended it to. Try to put the lighter but bulkier items in the bottom and top thirds of the pack. Avoid putting heavy water and fuel bottles in outside pockets which also throws off your balance. Instead, use your top lid or place them just inside your pack on top.

 Compactness– In order to get everything into your backpack, you should try and fill every cubic inch of dead air space that you can. Use compression stuff sacks to pack down your bag and those bulky warm camp clothes. Try to fill pots, cups, and bowls with food or other items so that space doesn’t go unused. Instead of putting everything in a stuff sack, consider breaking those items up and putting them in spots where they fit best. A tent fly packs much easier if it is crammed into the nooks and crannies that are created by other items. You should also teach your students how to use the compression system on their backpack. Using the compression straps and load adjustment systems will make your pack much less bulky and it also gives the pack more rigidity causing it to carry better.

 Dry– At the end of a long rainy day, you will be looking forward to a hot drink and a warm and dry place to curl up. The last thing that you will want to do is climb into a soggy sleeping bag! Make sure that the items that need to stay dry, such as a sleeping bag, clothes and maps, are packed in stuff sacks lined with heavy-duty garbage bags. For smaller items you can use zip lock bags. Remember! You do not have to waterproof every item in your backpack. It is of no consequence if your stove and cook pots get wet, so don’t bother with these items. Besides, these sorts of things usually puncture the plastic bags anyway.

 Other Considerations: 

- Pack fuel below your food! Even if small amount of fuel leaks from your fuel bottles it can contaminate all of your food. So minimize this risk by putting fuel bottles down next to your sleeping bag. Make sure that it will not be punctured if the backpack is dropped on the hard ground.

- Develop your personal organizational style so that you are efficient and know where everything is located. Share your personal tips with your students.


 Campsite Selection 

When on an expedition one should be able to choose an appropriate campsite that falls in line with the Leave No Trace Principle of“Camp and travel on durable surfaces”and is safe from objective hazards. It is important to remember that when choosing a campsite you are not just looking for a place to sleep but also a place to cook, teach, and socialize. Remember to spread these spots out so you do not concentrate the impact of 12 to 14 people in a 20 square foot area. You should teach this class on the first night in the field in order to give your students an opportunity to choose their sites the rest of the expedition. Here are some topics you should cover when teaching your students how to choose a site:

-         Durable vs. fragile surfaces –Most of the campsites that we use here in the Southeast are heavily impacted, established sites that have been used for years. When given the choice we should choose impacted sites, first. However, there are times when we use campsites that have seen little to no use prior to our arrival. When choosing a“pristine site,”you should first look for rock slabs, sandy areas, and duff. If you must camp on vegetation, avoid woody stemmed or moist broad leaf plants, which are far less durable than grasses.

-         Be sure that your site is free from natural dangers such as low branches that might injure someone’s eye, widow-makers (dead trees or branches that might fall on top of the tent during a storm), game trails, and sites vulnerable to lightning strikes.

-         Choose a site that allows your group to be comfortable. Use the leeward side of boulders and treelines to protect your kitchen and tent sites from wind and weather. Find sites that are flat for sleeping. Look for sites that have pretty views!


 Sleeping Warm and Dry 

           On the first night of the expedition you will need to teach your students how to properly use their sleep kit. What you will issue them to sleep in depends upon the weather and the time of year that you are working. In the Fall and Spring, they should be equipped with a ground sheet, sleeping pad, summer sleeping bag, and a cotton liner. During the winter sessions, the students should be issued either a winter bag or a summer bag with a fleece liner. You should make sure that they turn the summer bags inside-out so that the dark blue color is showing. This will extend the life of these bags.

            The system is as follows: 

-        Place ground sheet down first. This is to keep your sleeping bag and pad dry if you are sleeping on wet ground. Make sure that the sheet does not extend outside of the tarp. If it does it will channel rain water right to you and make things soggy. Yuck!

-        Now put the sleeping pad down. Not only does the pad add comfort for your nights sleep but it also combats heat loss from conduction with the cold ground. If it is really cold out, advise your students to put more items underneath themselves for more insulation.

-        Line the inside of the sleeping bags with a cotton liner. This way we only need to wash the liners instead of the sleeping bags themselves (however, we do wash the bags a couple of times a year!).

-        Students should be taught how to use the zippers and draw strings on the particular bag that they are using. This may sound basic but, believe it or not, students have spent cold nights on Discovery trips because they did not know that their mummy bag had a hood on it!

 What do I wear? 

           This is a commonly misunderstood topic in the art of staying warm at night. The old wives tale said not to wear anything at all in order to be warm. This just isn’t entirely true! It is, however, based on the fact that if you wear all of your warm layers to bed on a chilly night you will probably become too hot in your sleeping bag and begin to perspire. When this happens you become wet. Then, as the evening goes on, the temperature drops and your metabolism (which produces heat in the first place) begins to run low on food, you begin to cool off. Moisture is a good transporter of heat and therefore, despite all those clothes that you are wearing, you get cold!

           One way to avoid this is to not wear all of your clothes to bed. The most important item of clothing to wear to bed is a wool or fleece hat. Our scalps are a poor insulator of heat. There is little insulating fat there and many blood vessels come near the surface of our skin. So cover up that noggin. I suggest that in the winter you wear at least a base layer of polypro tops and bottoms to bed, and some warm, dry socks. If this is not enough then put on another layer. If you are cold, put on clothes! Try to regulate your body temperature through layering. Remember, avoid becoming too hot or too cold.

 Henry, what other great knowledge do you have to share with us? 

 A sleeping bag only insulates what is put in it. If you put a warm turkey in it, it will keep it warm. If you put an ice cube in it, it will keep it cold. Therefore, it is important that you are warm before you enter into your sleeping bag.

 Here are some tips to sleeping warm– 

-        EAT! It’s cold out and your body is burning lots of calories to stay warm. You are not going to get fat! Emphasize to your students the importance of eating a full dinner prior to going to bed. This will give your body the calories it needs to heat you.

-        DRINK! Water, water, water! Your body cannot keep itself warm if it isn’t properly hydrated. You should be drinking 3-5 liters per day depending on the severity of the cold and the activities you are performing. Hot teas and cocoa just before bed are great for keeping you warm. It has also been suggested that eating or drinking something salty right before bed will help you retain the water you drink during the night.

-        EXERCISE! The best way to warm up is to do something that will get the blood flowing. I like sit-ups, jumping jacks, and rounds of toe twister!

-        PEE! You wake up and it is dark and cold out. You are warm in your bag but you have a bladder that is in need of being emptied. Bad luck for you! But if you stay in your bag, not only will you be unable to sleep, but you will get cold too. Your body needs to maintain its core temperature which is around 98 degrees F. If you have a liter of water in your bladder your body will spend calories keeping that warm too. Furthermore, your bladder is at the core of your body. Therefore, it will work to keep this useless urine warm before it will keep you toes warm! So fight the urge to stay in your bag and be uncomfortable. Face the cold and warm up those toes!

-        EXTERNAL HEATING–If you have a student that just cannot get warm you can make hot water bottles for them. Just put boiling water into a lexan water bottle. Wrap the bottle up in a t-shirt so that it will not burn the student with direct contact and place it in the bag. Remind the student that as soon as this bottle has cooled down it should be taken out of the bag so that you will not spend any energy trying to keep it warm. Voila! Warm freshman!


 Trail Techniques 

           This section will cover some points that you should teach to your students about trail travel while on expedition. You won’t be able to teach all of this information on the first day, but you should try to make an effort to teach this curriculum early on in the course. Getting the students equipped with the proper skills early allows them more time to put them to good use!

 Energy Conservation 

-        Avoid sprinting out of the gate just to become tired early.

-        Avoid moving so slow that you end up wearing your backpack more than you need to!

-        Take breaks, but not too many and not for too long. Breaks are important for resting, but taking too long allows warm muscles to cool down and it also wastes time. You can rest once you get to camp.

 Managing Students on the Trail 

-        The group should always be in sight of each other.

-        Travel the pace of the slowest person. It can help to put the folks who are struggling or walk slower in the front of the group. That way the fast folks do not leave anyone behind.

-        Make sure there are a couple of people in charge of the map. Everyone should be reading the map but you will need someone to carry it and look at it from time to time while you are walking.

-        Have a time keeper–Have the group decide their walk to break ratio (ex. walk 50 minutes: break 10 minutes). Assign a person with a watch to hold the group to this plan.

-        Have a point and a sweep person. The point person does the path finding and the sweep makes sure that the group remains together. The sweep should also make sure that nothing and no one is left behind when leaving camp or break sites.

 Hydration and Nutrition 

-        You need fuel for a car to run; the same holds true to your body!

-        Students should drink between 3 and 4 liters of water per day, not including hot drinks.

-        Encourage your students to drink water throughout the day.

-        REMEMBER! Lunch begins right after breakfast and ends at dinner. Many small meals burn better than one big lunch dumped into you belly.

-        Have all of your students eat a solid breakfast prior to hiking. After a long day students must eat dinner in order to help them recover.

 LNT on the Trail 

 Camp and travel on durable surfaces! 

-        Try to avoid hiking in groups larger than a standard Discovery group. This number is typically 13 (students, staff, and faculty), which is an already enormous group. The“recommended”group size in the wilderness areas that we operate in is 10. If you run into another Discovery group, take a break or pass. Try to avoid becoming one large group. Not only is this hard on the land but, most importantly, it is a high social impact to other backcountry users.

-        Do not cut switchbacks!

-        Take breaks off of the trail so that other visitors do not have to walk around you. This will avoid beating up the sides of the trail.

-        Avoid walking around muddy or wet spots in the trail. This causes unnecessary widening of the trail.

-        If you are traveling off trail on fragile vegetation, have your group spread out.


 Water Treatment 

While on Discovery Expedition your students will be provided with the training and the equipment to properly treat the water that they drink in the field. This will need to be taught to them either prior to leaving school or on the first night of the trip. You should give them a thorough class on the pathogens that they are protecting themselves against and methods to reduce the risks.

 There are 3 main ways to treat your water: 

 #1. Chemicals 

-        The standard water treatment system used at Discovery will be 10% Providone Iodine. Squirt 10 drops of iodine into 1 liter of water. Allow water to stand for 20 minutes (up to 30 minutes if it is below freezing). Then bleed the threads of the water bottle or flush the tube of the camelback and then the water is ready to drink.

-        You can also use iodine in a pill form (Potable Aqua) or in a crystalline iodine form (Polar Pure). Follow the directions on the package. Both take approximately 20-30 minutes to treat a liter of water.

-        Chlorine treatments such as Halazone and Aqua Mira also work well. (see direction written on container)

 #2 Boiling 

-        Boiling kills protozoa, bacteria, and viruses. You only need to bring the pot of water to a rolling boil (212 degrees F or 100 degrees C) to take these little suckers out!

 #3 Filter 

-        Filters strain out little creatures down to 0.2 microns in size. They do a great job getting protozoa and bacteria. Due to the tiny nature of viruses, a filter without a chemical element in it (such as iodine) will not kill them.

-        Filters will clog very easily, so it is important to filter out of a cook pot if water is shallow. This prevents sand and dirt from clogging the filter unnecessarily.

-        Look for students who are allergic to iodine. Often, people who are allergic to shellfish are actually allergic to iodine. If you have someone who is allergic to iodine, issue your group one of the Sweetwater filters in the gear room.

 Micro-organisms in Backcountry H2O: 

 Protozoa– Protozoa are single-cell creatures. They are the largest or the waterborne pathogens. Their size ranges from 2 to15 microns. The two types of protozoa that most concern backcountry users are Giardia Lambia and Cryptosporidium.

 Giardia Lambia –This is the one that we are most concerned with here in the Southeast. Giardia is approximately 2 to 15 microns in size but can fit through a 5 mircron diameter hole due to its flexibility. It is spread through fecal and oral transmission. Animals such as beavers and muskrats are guilty of spreading the protozoa because they live in aquatic environments. Livestock, domestic pets, and humans are responsible as well. Basically, when one of these creatures defecates in the water they infect that water. If someone gets giardia they will not become ill until 1 to 4 weeks after exposure. It takes time for the cysts to multiply in the intestinal tract before the body reacts to their presence. Symptoms include: diarrhea, flatulence, weight loss, fatigue, and abdominal cramps.

 Cryptosporidium – Approximately 4-6 microns in size but can fit through a 3 micron hole. Due to a hard shell, they are more difficult to kill and are safe from iodine and chlorine. The only way to kill them is to either boil the water or filter it. The symptoms of cryptosporidium are the same as giardia only with less flatulence and accompanied with a low-grade fever.

 Bacteria– Bacteria range from 0.2 to 10 microns in size. Types of water-borne bacteria are cholera, Escherichia Coli, and campylobacter. These bacteria are found in developing countries due to poor water treatment (feces contaminated water). E-coli is associated with traveler’s diarrhea.

 Viruses– Viruses are very small and cannot be treated by filter alone. They must be boiled or treated with chemicals such as iodine and chlorine. The biggest concern here is contracting hepatitis A, which causes fatigue, loss of appetite, stomach pain, and nausea.


 Cooking In The Backcountry 

           Cooking in the wilderness is a great experience for our students. It creates a sense of empowerment and self-reliance. At the end of a long day there is nothing better than a hot drink and a bowl of tasty food eaten in a scenic place. You need to remember that your students have probably not cooked for themselves very often, and certainly not on a camp stove. Therefore, it is important that you spend the appropriate amount of time with them so that they learn how to cook well.

One of the first things that you should give your students is a food identification class in order for them to know what types of foods they are traveling with. You should also develop a system so that students know what items they are specifically carrying. This will save you time when you sit down to lunch and no one seems to know who has the peanut butter. Some instructors label each individual food bag with the contents, but this seems to get confused after the first meal and the food has been switched around. Another method is to keep a group journal and record who is carrying certain food items.

Most importantly, teach them the proper techniques for cooking rice, pasta, soups, quesadillas, etc. Students should learn how to prevent burning or under cooking their food. Nothing brings morale down more than uncooked rice or burnt oatmeal! They should also be taught what’s in the spice kit and how to use it. That little bag of seasoning goes unused far too often. Instill the belief that food is not merely fuel but something to look forward to and an outlet for creativity! 

There should be an instructor in the kitchen at all times. The kitchen is the place where most backpacking accidents occur. Burns from boiling water, Whisperlite stoves, or cuts from chopping vegetables are only a few possible injuries that can occur in a backcountry kitchen.

Be sure to provide some sort of structure so that all group members have an opportunity to work in the kitchen. A rotation seems to work best. Avoid gender stereotypes such as girls cooking and cleaning while the boys play in the woods banging on trees with sticks! This only creates a division in the group when it is cohesiveness that they should be striving for.

 It is not only valuable for them to begin learning how to cook for themselves but it requires teamwork and co-operation in order to create a tasty meal. Find the appropriate balance between teaching, risk management, and giving the students enough room to make mistakes and learn from them. While you may not want to eat poorly cooked food, do not underestimate the power of a burnt meal after a long day to teach students about natural consequences! Here is one more opportunity for your students to put into practice the tools that you have equipped them with up to this point.


 Foot Care 

The great outdoor educator Johnny Hikealot once said,“When you are on the trail, you are traveling under diesel power!”He pointed at his feet and said,“dees’ll get you in and dees’ll get you out!”

 It is important to remember to take care of your feet. Remind your students daily of the importance of preventative foot care. Encourage your students to speak up when they first get a“hotspot”(a burning sensation that is the first sign of a blister) so that you can treat it. It is much easier to prevent blisters in the first place than it is to treat them once they have occurred. Be Proactive! 

Teach your students how to properly put on socks and lace their boots. Often, folks leave wrinkles in their socks, particularly when they are using a double sock system. Your students should make sure to roll their socks and sock liners on, starting with the toe, and make sure that there is no extra material that will rub blisters. Avoid cotton socks because they stay wet which makes your skin tender and susceptible to blisters. Socks should also be free of foreign objects such as dirt and burrs which might also rub. Lacing your boots is another important step in blister prevention. Some people think that to maximize the ankle support in your boot you must lace them tight. This is a terrible presupposition! Lacing boots tightly is a sure-fire way to get blisters. The tighter that they are laced, the more friction and heat they will create. This heat and friction will quickly cause blisters. To demonstrate this point, have your students rub their hands together with a lot of pressure. The friction creates heat which will eventually cause a burn or blister. Now have them rub their hands together with no pressure. They will agree that there is less friction and therefore less chance of blisters.

 Stages of blisters and treatment 

The first stage is a hotspot . A hotspot feels like a slight burning or rubbing point. It is usually only a small red spot on the foot. The easiest way to treat a hotspot is to place a piece of athletic or duct tape over the top of it. Make sure that the tape is secure in order to prevent it from slipping and doing more damage to the foot. If the hotspot is in an advanced stage, try covering it with a piece of mole skin. Cut a round piece of mole skin that will cover the entire area. Then tape it down to increase its ability to stay in place.

           The second stage is a blister with a water bubble . If the blister is the size of a nickel or smaller, you should avoid popping it. A closed blister is less prone to infection because it is a closed wound. To treat this blister, you should cut a donut shaped piece of mole foam large enough to encircle the bubble without touching it. This will provide protection and padding that will stop the rubbing. It will also prevent the bubble from being popped. Now tape the donut in place. If the blister is larger than a nickel you should drain it because it will most likely pop on its own. Drain the blister using a sterilized needle. This blister should then be treated as a soft tissue injury (see below).

           The third stage of a blister is an open blister or a soft tissue injury . A blister that has popped is likely to become infected without proper care. You should treat these blisters as described above, only you must first use an antibiotic ointment and non-stick gauze to treat the injury. Clean the injury daily with an antiseptic solution such as iodine or zephiran, put ointment on injury, and cover it with a band aid or non-stick gauze. Then cover it with a mole foam donut and tape in place. Another option is to use 2 nd skin. 2 nd Skin is a watery and slimy material that can be cut into what ever shape you may need. It is then placed directly on the blister. Then place athletic tape over the top to keep it in place. If you want to keep hiking, you should also put the mole foam donut on in order to give the blister extra protection.

 Map and Compass Class 

Navigation in the backcountry is one of the primary responsibilities of a Discovery group while on expedition. This allows students to practice the skills of teamwork and communication that they learn on campus. By working together to determine their location and where they need to travel they will have genuine experiences using these skills. It is important for your students to gain a working knowledge of how to use a map and compass in order for them to navigate. You should teach a basic class to your students before they leave for the field. Review the different aspects of a topographical map (i.e. colors, cardinal directions, the legend, scale, latitude and longitude, etc.). Then do an exercise that will reinforce these map features. Possibly have the students navigate around campus using a topo map of that area or have them sculpt in the sand land features that are on a map.

 Consider waiting until you are in the field before you teach a more advanced map class that would include advanced topographical features, determining distances, and triangulation.

Here’s an example of a class that you may use in the field:

 Step #1: 

Put away the map!“Ground yourself in reality.”Observe your surroundings with a 360 degree look. Seek a good view.

 Things to look for:  

 Features –Learn to identify these land features in reality. Ridges, Saddles, glaciers, peaks, lakes, clearings, cirques/bowls.

 Distance– from you to identifiable features. Get accustomed to the scale of the area that you are in. How fast do you and your group walk?

 Direction– Know cardinal directions of the features around you.“Where is the sun right now?”

 Elevation– Your elevation relative to the features that are around you.“Are we higher or lower than the peaks around us?”

 Step #2: 

Orient the map (use a compass if you are in thick vegetation).

Try to find your surroundings on the map. Decipher contour lines. What do they mean in reality?

Peaks - show up as bulls eyes

Saddles - reversed parentheses

Drainages/valleys - appear like V’s that point towards peaks (uphill)

Ridges - look like valleys, only they point downhill

Slopes - steep vs. shallow

 Insert illustrations/ examples of these 

 Step #3: 

Develop an argument or case for your location. Find areas on the map that show all the things we see in reality.

 Step #4: 

Share and hear with the other folks in your group. Synthesize the best arguments and come to an agreement on where you are and the best way to travel to where you are going.

 Common Mistakes! 

-        The group thinks that they have traveled further than they actually did.

-        Only a couple of students are reading the map and not all opinions are presented. If the 2 map readers are wrong and the whole group goes the wrong way then there is no one to blame but the entire group!

-        The map is not oriented correctly at the beginning of the map check! This will really throw a wrench into your plan.

The Compass

The compass is an important tool when navigating in the backcountry. Unfortunately, this device can easily be used incorrectly. Many times this little guy has thrown off people’s ability to navigate accurately. Therefore, it is important that you know how to use it and when you don’t need it. Described below are the different features of the compass, how to orient a map with a compass, and how to shoot and follow a bearing. Make sure that you are comfortable using a compass before you put this into the hands of ninth graders!

The Parts of a Compass

Insert Diagram here

Orienting The Map With A Compass

Probably the most useful purposes of a compass here in the Southeast is for orienting the map. You will definitely develop your map skills quicker if you try to orient the map by using topographical features, but sometimes the vegetation is just too thick!

 Step 1 

Set the bezel of the compass so that North or 360 degrees lines up with the Direction of Travel Arrow.

 Step 2 

Find the magnetic declination shown at the bottom of your USGS map.

 Step 3 

Line the side of the base plate up with the magnetic north line of the magnetic declination angle.

 Step 4 

Now rotate map until the north-seeking needle is boxed inside the orienteering arrow.

 Voila! Your map is oriented. 


 River Crossing 

             Crossing rivers in the backcountry requires experience and judgment. It is also a great opportunity for groups to practice teamwork, organization, and leadership. However, rivers have the potential to be very dangerous if taken lightly. While river/creek crossing in the southeast seems minor when compared to the rivers out west, they still present a threat. As instructors, you should be prepared to safely manage your group across them. Once you have taught your students river crossing skills, you should allow them to practice under close supervision. Here are some key points you should cover when teaching this class: 

 River Features: In order to choose a crossing site, one must be able to read a river and know some of the basic principals of river hydrology. By studying the river you will learn where the current is fastest, deepest, and what objective hazards to look out for.

-         Current– Current is caused by the gradient and shape of the riverbed. If a river begins to drop elevation quickly the water flows faster. When rivers are flat and wide they are slower. The current is typically stronger when it flows through narrow channels or on the outside of bends.

-         Depth– The depth of the river is affected by the amount of water that is draining into it. When rainfall is heavy, creeks rise. Some rivers are dam controlled and either flow at a consistent level, or rise and fall depending upon the scheduled releases by the dam. Water is typically the deepest in slow sections, the outside of bends where it has washed away the sand, and in areas where you cannot see the bottom. White, foamy water is an indicator of shallow water that has a heavy current.

-         Eddy –Eddies are spots downstream of large boulders or other obstructions where the current of the river is blocked. Here, there is either no current at all or it is flowing in the opposite direction of the main current. These can be islands of safety when crossing a river. People can actually“eddy hop”when crossing rivers in order to get a break from the swift current in the main channels.

-         Strainers– Strainers are downed trees and logs that become jammed on rocks and along the banks. They allow water to flow through but“strain out”solid objects transported by the water. Becoming entangled with a strainer is a grim situation indeed and should be avoided at all costs. Therefore, you should avoid crossing just upstream of strainers.

-         River bottom –The bottom of the river is an important consideration when choosing a place to cross. Smooth and sandy river bottoms are much more pleasant and make it easier to maintain your balance than slick boulder strewn bottoms.

Insert River Diagram Here

 Scouting– When you have determined that you must cross a river, you should begin looking for the right spot for your group. Often, people become too focused on the place that is directly in front of them instead of walking up and downstream looking for a better site. If a trail leads you to a river it does not always make it the safest or best place to cross. Therefore, it is important to scout for a good location. This is a great opportunity to practice judgment and decision-making once the students know what to look for in an appropriate crossing site.

 You are looking for the following: 

-        A wide shallow spot where the current is slow.

-        Good entrance and exit points. Avoid undercut banks or steep rocky areas.

-        What hazards lay downstream? Are there any strainers, rapids, or waterfalls that would injure someone in the event that they were swept away?

-        Scout before you reach the river by looking at your map. A map can give you a lot of information when looking for a place to cross. You can determine if a river drains a large area or not, what the gradient of the river is by looking at the topographical lines, and if it is better to cross several of the river’s smaller tributaries upstream or the main river itself.

 Crossing Techniques– One other factor to crossing a river is deciding what technique to use. Sometimes you may be able to find a spot that allows for a“dry crossing”(walking on top of rocks and logs) while other situations demand that you use a“wet crossing”(wading) technique.

 Dry Crossing– While it is nice to keep your feet dry, it is important for you and your students to know the limitations of dry crossings. When rock hopping, watch out for slick rocks and never leap between them. Anticipate the sequence of steps prior to walking out there. Consider using a hand line that will help folks balance. The same goes for crossing logs because they can be slick. Find logs that are thick, stable, and dry. Ask your students what the consequences would be if one were to slip while rock hopping or if someone fell off. Many backcountry travelers have broken bones and even drowned while trying to prevent wet feet.

 Wet Crossing– Water that is ankle to mid-calf can usually be crossed without the assistance of other group members. It is, however, nice to use a trekking pole or a large, strong stick to provide more stability on slick rocks and to feel for underwater obstacles. When water becomes mid-calf to mid thigh, you should consider a buddy system. Here, two people can use each other for support. From mid-calf to waist deep, things get a bit tricky. Consider looking for an alternate crossing spot. If this is not an option, you should use the“eddy method.”This is where the group stands in a line facing upstream. Place the larger people in the front. Each person has their hands on the backpack of the person in front of them. The leader uses a stick to help them lean into the current. The leader breaks the current creating an eddy and making it easier for the people behind to cross. In unison the group takes small side steps until they are across. Good planning and communication are an essential element to this technique.

 Other Considerations: 

-        The group should arrive at a consensus. Everyone in the group needs to be comfortable with the site and the technique that is chosen.

-        What shape is your group in at that time of day? If it is early in the morning the group may be better off than crossing at the end of a tough day. Is there trust in the group or is there a subjective hazard that might cause something to go wrong?

-        What is the swimming ability of the group? Be sure to know who cannot swim.

-        When crossing with heavy packs, try to shift weight around the group until everyone is comfortable with their loads. Consider ferrying loads for folks who are really concerned.

-        Practice creek crossings without packs before having them do it with heavy loads.

-        Use spotters when someone being swept downstream is a possibility. Place people downstream in places where they will be able to pull a swimmer out of the water.

-        Remind your students to unbuckle their hip belt and sternum strap when crossing water where they could potentially drown if they fell in. This procedure allows the hiker to remove their backpack easily in the event that someone is washed downstream and needs to be able to swim. Backpacks have been known to hold people down underneath the water.


 Southern Nantahala’s 

 Geologic History 

           The gentle Southern Blue Ridge Mountains have a rich history involving collisions, molten magma intrusions, and peaks 20,000 to 30,000 feet high. The mountains we travel through now have traveled themselves through a journey lasting 500 million years, which has molded and formed them into the wilderness we now explore.

           The Southern Blue Ridge Mountains were formed during three separate orogenies, or mountain building periods. The first orogeny, the Taconic Orogeny, occurred 500 million years ago when the protocontinents collided. 120 million years later, 380 million years ago, the Acadian Orogeny occurred. During this orogeny, which lasted about 20 million years, immense metamorphism occurred in the rock. The word“metamorphism”is Greek for“changed form,”which is exactly what was occurring to the geology of the area during this time. Igneous rocks, formed during volcanic activity, and sedimentary rocks, formed during deposition of material, were being changed due to intense pressure and heat created deep within the earth’s crust. The metamorphic processes occurring during this orogeny changed the original rocks’textural features, and even chemical makeup. During this time much of the current bedrock of the Southern Blue Ridge was going through ingenious intrusion as well, meaning it was being injected by molten material. While the Taconic and Acadian Orogenies played a part in forming our current mountains, most geologists agree that it was the Alleghenian Orogeny that had the greatest impact on the mountains we explore today. During the Alleghenian Orogeny, what is now eastern North America smashed into current Northwestern Africa, forming the super continent of Pangaea, which means“all lands.”During this process, the mountains that were to become the Southern Blue Ridge Mountains rose to an elevation of 20,000 to 30,000 feet, a height equivalent to the present day Himalayas. Geologists believe that the 260 million years of time and weathering since the Alleghenian Orogeny has eroded 4 to 5 miles from these magnificently elevated mountains. Erosion is a continuous process that is still shaping the landscape of the Southern Blue Ridge Mountains.  

 Cultural History 

           The leaves of the forest floor have cushioned many feet prior to our stiff gortex boots. Some of these feet have traveled through the land without a trace, while others have left a footprint that imprinted the very nature of the wilderness. The land throughout the Southern Nantahala’s has seen many peoples cross its mountains and wade through its rivers. Historians believe that the first people to walk through this land were a nomadic people who hunted and gathered in the Southern Blue Ridge Mountains about 12,000 years ago. These nomadic people never made a home in the mountain knolls, but instead settled into the valleys where they could farm the arable land. In fact, the Cherokees themselves never made a home in the rugged mountains. The land was too steep, too high, and too cold. Mountain streams were not large enough to provide enough fish for the tribe and flood planes were not wide enough to provide enough arable land for farms. The Cherokee did explore the land looking for game and edible plants and roots, which is why much of the land throughout the Southern Nantahala’s has names originating from the Cherokee tongue. Nantahala stems from the Cherokee word Nun daye li , which was the name of a Cherokee settlement on the banks of the Nantahala River, and means“midday sun.”The Nantahala gorge that surrounded this Cherokee settlement had banks so steep that it was not until midday that the village received sunlight. 

           The Cherokee, along with Siouan tribes, lived throughout the mountain valleys up until the early 1800’s when white settlers began to establish homesteads on the land. In 1828, these settlers discovered one precious mineral that was to change the course of 1,000’s of Indian lives: GOLD! With the discovery of gold in the Southern Nantahala’s, prospectors began to flood the mountains with their mining equipment, homes, families, and dreams of wealth. This flood of settlers pushed many Indians off the land. During the winter of 1838, President Jackson ordered the US Army to remove any remaining Cherokee Indians from the rolling mountains. Thousands of Indians lost their lives due to famine and frost in what would later be called the Trail of Tears. By the 1870’s, most of these white settlers had moved further west where there was more arable land. However, dreams of gold were replaced with plans for timber, and by the early 1900’s much of the land was being forested by both large scale logging companies and private land owners. By the 1960’s, even the old growth forest that remained on the steeper mountain slopes had been logged. It wasn’t until 1977 that the Forest Service started to express interest in protecting the land from commercial uses, and started to acquire large acreage from the Vogel Land Company, Irvington Investment Company, and the Nature Conservancy. The Forest Service even acquired 1,196 acres of land from the Girl Scouts who use to run a camp in the area, which included the 5,000 foot Big Scaly. The Girl Scouts chose to sell this land to the Forest Service rather than a ski resort who was also interested in the purchase. In 1984, Congress declared 23,714 acres of the southern Nantahala a wilderness area. This wilderness area spans into both Georgia and North Carolina and covers 37 square miles of land. The Southern Nantahala Wilderness includes four peaks over 4,000 feet in elevation: Big Scaly at 5,060 feet, little Bald Knob at 5,050 feet, Ridgepole Mountain at 5,060 feet, and Standing Indian at 5,499 feet.

 Legend of Standing Indian 

           It was fall. Rich colors filled the mountain slopes with warmth as the Cherokee village prepared for the cool mountain weather. One evening, as members of the village crowded around the fire, they heard a screech so fierce and so loud that it shook the very ground on which the village stood. Suddenly, a vicious winged monster filled the sky with its ferocious call and foul odor. The creature circled the fire once, twice, then swooped down toward the fire and, with its sharp talons, snatched up a little boy screaming in fear. The village stood staring at the sky as the monster flew away, carrying the screaming child into its cave lair high in the cliffs of a nearby mountain. Immediately, the Chief of the Village sent a warrior into the mountains to stand guard by the monster’s lair. The village prayed with deep anguish to the Great Spirit, asking for help in slaying the ferocious monster. After days of prayer, the Great Spirit sent an enormous lightening bolt that shattered the monster’s lair and much of the mountain top. The lightening was so great that it killed the beast and its offspring. It also destroyed the forest on the mountain top, creating a grassy bald where the monster’s lair once stood. The Indian Warrior sent into the mountains to stand guard over the monster’s lair was also killed by the lightening and turned into stone, some say as punishment for being a poor sentry. Over the years since the warrior’s death, most of the stone statue has been worn away. The only thing that is left is the grassy bald and a pillar of stone with the shape of an ill defined head.


 Joyce Kilmer-Slickrock Wilderness Area 

 Joyce Kilmer 

             Joyce Kilmer Memorial Forest derives its namesake from poet Alfred Joyce Kilmer who was born in New Brunswick, NJ on December 6, 1886. He attended Rutgers College from 1904 to 1906 and then went on to study at Columbia University in 1908. After teaching high school for a year, Kilmer began to focus on his writing career. He took a job with the New York Times and soon became an editor and reviewer as well as a successful journalist. In 1914, the year World War I began, Kilmer gained recognition as a poet when his famous poem“Trees”was published. In 1917 Kilmer enlisted in the New York National Guard and was sent to France in October to help fight in World War I. On July 30, 1918 Joyce Kilmer took part in a reconnaissance mission to locate enemy machine gun placements. During the reconnaissance, Kilmer was shot in the head by an enemy bullet and died. His fellow soldiers buried him near the banks of the Ourcq River in France . In 1934 the Bozeman Bulgar post urged the Federal Government to set up a memorial in honor of Joyce Kilmer. On July 30, 1936, 18 years after Kilmer’s death, Joyce Kilmer Memorial Forest was named in his honor.

     TREES 

I think that I shall never see
A poem lovely as a tree.

A tree whose hungry mouth is prest
Against the earth&apos;s sweet&apos; flowing breast.

A tree that looks at God all day
And lifts her leafy arms to pray.
A tree that may in summer wear
A nest of robins in her hair.

Upon whose bosom snow has lain;
Who intimately lives with rain.
Poems are made by fools like me,
But only God can make a tree. 

 -Joyce Kilmer 

 Cultural History 

           Joyce Kilmer Memorial Forest posses a magical history that is rich with Indian culture, forestry, fires, floods, and beauty. Prior to the 1800’s, the woods of Joyce Kilmer sheltered many Indian tribes including the Cherokee and the Creek. In the early 1800’s several white settlers began to establish farms along the Tellico and Little Tennessee Rivers. Settlers began to flood the area with their families and dreams of wealth after 1828 when gold was discovered in the mountains of North Georgia and North Carolina. By 1938, as more and more settlers moved into the area, President Andrew Jackson began the forceful exit of all Native Americans from their homeland in what is now known as The Trail of Tears. One of the most surprising stories that come out of this period of history is that of Chief Junaluska, who saved Andrew Jackson’s life only to be betrayed by him during the Trail of Tears.

In the early 1900’s, when settlers’dreams of gold faded, lumber companies began to see the area in terms of wealth found in timber. In 1915 the Babcock Land and Timber Company bought the land that now makes up Joyce Kilmer Memorial Forest and began to timber the area. In 1920 this same company bought the land that is now the Citco Creek Wilderness Area. The Babcock Land and Timber Company forested most of their newly acquired land by 1922. However, in 1922 the remaining trees in the Joyce Kilmer Wilderness were saved from the axe by a flood caused by the construction of Calderwood Lake. This flood took out the rail system along the Little Tennessee River and halted timber operations. Operations were halted in the Citco Wilderness area when a large fire, now referred to as the Babcock fire, burned over half of the land. Because of the fire and flood, pockets of virgin forest remained safe from logging companies. Much of the forest we hike through today actually consists of old growth, not virgin wood. In the late 1920’s a lethal chestnut blithe arrived in the mountains and by 1940 most of the towering chestnuts were reduced to grey snags. The blithe, along with the Babcock fire, killed many of the original trees. Only the yellow popular trees in the forest possess the ability to reach heights as grand as the chestnuts stood.

           In 1936, the US Forest Service bought 13,055 acres for $28/acre from the Babcock Land and Timber Company after the company began to lose profit and interest in the wilderness area. Most of the land surrounding the wilderness area was being sold for only $3 to $4 dollars. This was a typical business interaction for lumber companies and the Forest Service in the 1930’s. The US Forest Service was originally established in order to restore watersheds and return the land to productivity after timber companies had ravished it. Timber companies would sell used land to the US Forest service to avoid paying taxes on it.

           The Joyce Kilmer Wilderness Area not only has an extended logging history, but also a history thick in Indian culture. One of the most famous stories of the Cherokee Indians, who lived throughout current day North Carolina, is that of Chief Junaluska. Chief Junaluka was born in the mid 1700’s in North Carolina, near the current day town of Murphy. In 1814 Junaluska led 500 Cherokee scouts to help General Andrew Jackson fight against at the Creek Indians during the Creek wars. During the battle of Horse Shoe Bend, General Jackson found himself fighting a war in which the situation was stacked against him. Junaluska, along with two other warriors, came to the aid of General Jackson by swimming across the Tallapoosa River in the dark of night and steeling the Creek warriors’canoes amidst rounds of Creek gunfire. Without the use of their canoes, the Creeks loss the advantage they had over the forces of General Jackson. In the battle that followed, Chief Junaluska drove a tomahawk through the skull of a Creek warrior who had General Jackson had his mercy. After helping General Jackson win the battle against the Creeks and then saving his life, Chief Junaluska, along with all the other Cherokee, felt betrayed by Andrew Jackson when he forced them from their homeland in 1838 in the Trail of Tears. The Trail of Tears is by far one of the most tragic events in Native American History. Over 16,000 Indians were driven from their homes and forced to walk over 800 miles on a journey that killed over 4,000 Native Americans. One soldier who witnessed the expulsion of the Indians from their homeland wrote, &quot;I saw the helpless Cherokees arrested and dragged from their homes, and driven by bayonet into stockades. And in the chill of a drizzling rain on an October morning I saw them loaded like cattle or sheep into six hundred and forty-five wagons and started toward the west.” Chief Junaluska led one of the seventeen contingents of Cherokee on this“trail where they cried”, where he lost not only his homeland but also his wife. In 1847, The General Assembly allowed Chief Junaluska to return to his native land in North Carolina. The Assembly awarded Junaluska full citizenship, 337 acres, and 100 dollars. Chief Junaluska lived on this land that he farmed until he died at the age of 100. His grave can be found on a hill in the mountain town of Robbinsville.


 2. Base Camp Expeditions 

 Safety Policies and Procedures 

1. Groups will not divide unless it is an emergency situation, it is approved by the Session Director, or it is a scheduled activity such as Solo. In an emergency situation, the divided groups will have a minimum of three persons in each party.

2. Each person will carry a whistle at all times outside the tent.

3. Shoes or other approved footwear will be worn at all times except when inside a tent.

4. A roster of participants, directions to program site, and a schedule of activities will be left with a pre-designated individual prior to any off-campus activity.

5. First-aid kits and appropriate rescue equipment will be readily accessible.

6. Faculty will carry emergency procedures for the area and the medical forms for all participants including staff.

7. Students will be briefed on specific environmental hazards of the program use area and emergency procedures for that area.

8. No flames of any kind are allowed in tents, around climbing equipment, or in vehicles.

9. Faculty will carry maps of the area, compass (when appropriate), and flashlight.

10. There will be at least one Discovery Faculty member or designated adult chaperone per student group.

11. A buddy system will be in place at all times; if someone needs to“go”in the middle of the night they must wake someone else up to go with them.

12. All day hikes will be led by qualified staff and a first aid kit will be carried.

13. Medications will be given to the Session Director prior to departure with clearly written instructions regarding dosage and times to be taken. It is the Session Director’s responsibility to make sure all medications are taken properly. Items which require immediate use, i.e. inhalers or personal epi-pens will be carried by the individual student, but the Session Director must be notified about their use.

 Procedures/Flow 

           While still on campus, students will be briefed about the safety policy regarding whistles and the use of the buddy system. A whistle will be issued to each student as they enter the bus. Expeditions begin with the bus ride to the camping site. Proper conduct in the bus is a safety issue . While the Discovery faculty is responsible for driving, instructors are responsible for conduct in the bus. 9 th graders are frequently excited and anxious about the upcoming weekend, so this is a good time to talk with them about what to expect and to give them a general overview of the weekend.

•           Upon arrival at the camping site, trailers/bus should be unloaded in a systematic, organized manner and shelter (tents and tarps) should be set up first thing. Instructors are responsible for circulating among the groups to help with set up. It is important to let the 9 th graders assume the responsibility for setup, so instructors should serve as the final check and not as an active participant in actual setup. It is crucial, however that the tents and tarps be set up properly. Experiential learning is never to be confused with the“sink or swim”method of instruction. Work with each group to help them get it right. If it pours in the middle of the night and a tent collapses, you are the one who winds up dealing with cold, wet students. Careful supervision can prevent a lot of potential problems.

            Briefing and debriefing each activity during expedition is a crucial part of the instructor’s role. The first night’s debriefing sets the tone for the rest of the weekend. During the next 3 days, instructors will be responsible for all safety briefings, demonstrations, and supervision of activities (food preparation, dish line, caving, rock climbing, etc.).

•           While tarps and tents are being set up, the first night’s dinner will be prepared by the Discovery faculty. Because we frequently arrive at our campsite near or after dark, this is a good way to make sure that everyone gets a good, hot meal for the day. As with all aspects of camping, proper food preparation, consumption, and clean-up are important safety issues. Pay attention to people’s eating habits–make sure that they are getting the fuel needed to be able to enjoy the expedition’s activities.

•           Dish line/clean up will be set up, briefed, and monitored by a staff person.  The sump hole will be set up near the dish line and clearly marked. Only liquid waste goes in the sump hole, all solid waste go in the garbage. There well be 3 separate dish line stations: 1. Warm, soapy water for washing; 2. Hot rinse; 3. Disinfectant rinse (1 capful of Clorox per 5 gallons of water); make sure that dishes are left in the disinfectant rinse for at least 2 minutes. Make sure that pots and pans are being scrubbed clean after each meal and that everything is rinsed well; soap is a powerful laxative. Separate all glass, aluminum, and cardboard for recycling. Clean all glass jars, crush all cardboard boxes and aluminum and bimetal cans, and clearly separate them from the rest of the waste. Also stress personal hygiene, hand washing especially .

 •          The first night’s briefing will include a reminder of safety policies regarding whistles, buddies, and shoes outside of tents. In addition, it is important to set the“lights out”time and the final“everybody quiet”time. Discuss how to stay warm in sleeping bags (wear a hat and sleep in a simple layer like boxers and polypro). Too many layers cause sleepers to sweat, which cools off the body. An evening reading can really help to establish the tone for the rest of the expedition. Set a wake up time and brief everyone about tomorrow’s activities, what to expect, and anything they’ll need to do to prepare for the activities.

•           Tucking people in for the night gives you an opportunity to check in with folks informally about how the day has gone. Use this opportunity also to double-check their sleeping system. Make sure that everyone has a sleeping pad, that their sleeping bag is not inside out (yes, it happens all the time), and they know how to work the draw-string. This is also a time to be checking for candy,“Walkmen,”etc. Try to ease people into getting ready for sleep–a wild tag game is not the best activity just prior to“lights out.”Remember, no coed tents! Once everyone is in their tents, your job is to circulate between tents until everyone is quiet and asleep. Take turns with other staff, but someone must always be out circulating until things are under control.

•           The morning of Day 2 (Saturday), is usually the first time students use their stoves. Staff need to be circulating at all times, helping each cooking group set up the stoves and supervising the morning’s food preparation. A staff member will also be setting up the dish line for the morning. Keep an eye out for who winds up cleaning the dishes for the group, and make sure that the fun gets spread around. As you are circulating, remind people about the day&apos;s activities and what they&apos;ll need to bring to the morning meeting. A morning reading or“thought for the day”is a great way to get everyone focused prior to loading up the buses and heading out. Before leaving camp for the day, make sure that all tents are zipped closed, group bins are closed securely, tarps are tight, and all food is put away.

 Cloudland Canyon 

 Geologic History 

             Most people perceive the beach and the mountains to be opposing environments. The beach is flat, sandy, and at sea level, while the mountains rise well above sea level, offering challenging steep slopes and towering trees. However, as one travels through the geologic history of Cloudland Canyon, it becomes clear that without the beach, the mountains that we know would never have been formed. 

             Cloudland Canyon is part of the Cumberland Plateau which contains rocks that date from the Paleozoic Era, 340 to 280 million years ago. These rocks were originally deposited in open sea and coastal environments when shifting tides, rain, and wind deposited layers of sand and sediment. Over several million years the sediment was compressed and hardened into solid rock. This rock has been folded and shaped by erosion and countless earthquakes.   

           The canyon itself is in the shape of a“Y”rotated 90 degrees to the right. The west canyon has been created by Daniel Creek, while the east canyon has been formed by the rushing waters of Bear Creek. These two creeks merge together to form Gulch creek, which flows through Sitton Gulch. At some parts of the canyon, the walls of the canyon plunge 1000 feet deep. As one travels down through the canyon, over 300 million years of geologic history can be seen and studied. The youngest rock is hard sandstone found on the top of the canyon walls. As one travels down into the canyon, the canyon walls consist of rock that becomes older and older. The rock at the bottom of the canyon consists of soft, porous limestone that was created from the remains of sea plants and creatures that lived 340 million years ago. 

 Cultural History 

Today, one travels throughout Northwest Georgia over ribbons of asphalt that connect small mountain towns. These asphalt ribbons have taken the place of the trade routes of the Cherokee Indians who lived and traveled on the land over 2,000 years ago. Few Cherokees made permanent homes in rugged northwest Georgia due to its harsh terrain. However, the Indians hunted throughout the land and set up trade routes that connected many river villages. These Indians were forced out of the area by President Andrew Jackson during the winter of 1838 in what would later be known as the Trail of Tears.            

           During the 1830’s, white settlers began to establish themselves on small, remote farms. However, the land near current day Rising Fawn remained extremely isolated from the rest of Georgia . In fact, Trenton, the County Seat of Dade County, which encompasses the area of Cloudland Canyon State Park, was only accessible from Tennessee or Alabama until the completion of US136 in 1939. This isolation from the rest of the state made the mountain people of Dade County fiercely independent. In fact, in 1860 Dade County seceded from the Union weeks before the rest of the state. It was not until July 4, 1945, 80 years after the end of the Civil War, that Dade County formally rejoined the Union. From the 1880’s to late 1940’s, mining was one of the major industries in the area. Many of the mining companies were aided by prison labor provided by the state. In 1938, the state acquired the 2,100 acres that became Cloudland Canyon State Park. 


 C. Caving 

           Caving provides a unique experience that is unlike any that most of our students have ever experienced. The opportunity to enter into the womb of mother earth and explore the underground passageways of these caves is a tremendous occasion. Caving allows us to teach about cave formation and local geology. It is the definition of experiential learning because students get to see firsthand what stalactites, columns, and rim stone dams are, and watch the slow drip of water which creates them over the eons. Students develop a real appreciation for the fragile nature of this environment and how humans can destroy in an instant what nature has taken millions of years to build.

           Caving also provides personal challenges as well. Students are immediately faced with fears of complete darkness and tight spaces as they crawl through passages that are just barely larger than their body size or enter into rooms the size of the basketball arenas in the Turner Gymnasium.

           As an instructor, it is your responsibility to help interpret this experience with the students. First, you must provide a thorough briefing at the beginning of the activity. This sets the tone for the experience. It is also the time to set up safety systems like counting off and the buddy system, which not only provides for physical safety but also reassures students and supports their emotional safety. Once you are inside the cave, you should teach cave genesis and discuss the various cave fauna (see below). You should also make time for activities such as silent“lights out,”“blind crawls,”choice readings, and cave naps. After you have returned to the earth’s surface, it is important that you debrief the student’s activity. This provides the students with the chance to verbalize their personal experience in the cave and hear the experiences of others. By weaving these personal reflections into this activity, you amplify the caving experience and extract all the possible learning that our students can take away from it.

 Safety Policies and Procedures 

 The faculty in charge of a caving party must be personally familiar with the cave system to be used. Two staff will accompany each group, one leading and one sweeping. One Discovery faculty member may take groups into caves which have been approved by the Director to be led by one faculty. Each group member will wear an approved helmet which has been properly adjusted to fit. Participants will also wear whistles and carry at least one extra source of dependable light. Caving parties will take emergency lighting, extra batteries, matches, first-aid equipment, and a safety rope. Equipment will be checked by the Discovery faculty person prior to entering the cave. Students will be briefed prior to entry on environmental hazards and proper procedures for moving as a group through the cave. Groups will count off periodically to insure that everyone is still with the group. It is especially important to count off after leaving an area where a group has stopped to rest. All headlamps will have an extra bulb, and students will carry extra AA batteries. In vertical caves all existing ropes and ladders will be checked by a Discovery faculty member prior to student use. 

10.     Staff to student ratio will be 2 student staff and one adult per group of 10 maximum.

 Procedures/Flow 

 Cave Briefing : (I through III must be covered prior to entering the cave)

I.   Name of Cave

II.  Type of Cave–A solution cave, typical of the majority of caves found in the Eastern U.S. Formed by weakly acidic ground water slowly dissolving the calcium or sulfate in rocks such as limestone, gypsum, dolomite, and marble. This dissolving process eventually creates passages, tunnels, and sometimes very large caverns.

III. Safety

      A. Numerical sequence

      B. Responsible of person ahead and behind of you

      C. First Aid pack is always with the last person (sweep)

      D. Backup light sources (check)–demonstrate head lamp use

      E. Helmets at all times

      F. Don’t get spread out as a group

      G. Review spotting procedures

IV. Cave Formations and Life

      A. Features of Solution Caves

1. Dripstone features –formally called“speleotherms”(Greek for“cave deposit”). These formations are created when water containing a large amount of“dissolved”minerals (such as calcite or gypsum), flows through the ground in the absence of air and eventually enters an air filled cavern and thus permits the deposition of the minerals with every passing“drip”of water. (Note: Not all caves have formations. Their presence is due in part to the amount of mineral concentrations found in the upper layers of the rock that is being dissolved.)

2. Types of Dripstone Features 

                    a. Stalactites - hang down from the ceiling.

                    b. Stalagmites - built up from the floor.

                    c. Column - connection of stalactite and stalagmite.

d. Curtains or Draperies - thin sheets formed along sloping ceiling or wall.

e. Flowstone - successive sheets of deposited minerals on the flow caused by flowing water.

f. Rim stone Dams - raised deposits found around pools or former pools of water. Deposits build up as water laps over the edges.

g. Cave Coral - small clusters or knobs formed by slow seepage of water.

3. Other Features –usually the result of mechanical forces of erosion

                    a. Cave Fill - material that has been washed into and deposited in the passages of a cave.

b. Breakdown - deposited from the collapse of the walls and/or ceiling of the cave, ranging in size from small flakes and chips to enormous blocks. This occurrence is generally prevalent in the early history of the cave.

B. Ecological Characteristics

1. Environmental Zones (3)–found from entrance to interior.           

                    a. Twilight - outermost zone that is lighted by entrance opening to the outside and in which the temperature and humidity are affected by the outside environment.

                    b. Middle - no presence of light, but the temperature fluctuates due to the presence of an air current flowing in and out of the interior portions of the cave to and from the entrance(s).

                    c. Deep Inner - characterized by a relatively low temperature that reflects the average temperature of the geographic area (in this area around 50°F. to 52°). Also, there is a very high relative humidity (near 100%) that remains constant.

2. Cave Fauna –3 categories of life within the cave

           a. Trogloxenes - animals that may use the“twilight”portions of the cave, but complete the majority of their life cycle outside of the cave (i.e. bears, foxes, raccoons, etc.)

           b. Troglophyles - inhabit the middle and deeper zones and although they may migrate out of the cave to find food, they nevertheless return to complete their life cycle within the cave, (i.e. bats, some spiders, crickets, etc.)

           c. Trilobites - inhabit the“deep inner zone”for the duration of their life cycle and are dependent upon the limited amount of food available. Since they spend their entire life in total darkness, these creatures many times develop these common characteristics:

                                 1. Loss of sight - development of other sensory structures is necessary for survival         

                                 2. Loss of pigmentation - cave creatures often have bodies that appear white or translucent (i.e.“blind”fish, crickets, crayfish, etc.)

                                                                                               (Virginia Cave Survey 1985)    

 Cave Travel Considerations 

           Remember that the mouths of caves are frequently littered with debris washed in during rain. The most dangerous items for us to be on the lookout for are broken glass and rusty items. Alert students to these hazards before entering the cave. Remind students to avoid crawling on their knees whenever possible–crab walking or duck walking work well and save a lot of wear and tear on the knee cap. In vertical caves all existing ropes or ladders must be checked thoroughly by the Discovery faculty member prior to student use. Proper instruction will be provided at the top and proper spotting at the bottom of all ropes or ladders. 

           Be careful of all cave formations, and remember to tell students to leave everything as they found it. Do not remove any rock pieces or fauna from the cave! Do not disturb the bats. Shine your light to the side of any bats you spot to point them out, rather than shining a light directly on them. A quick flash of light could be enough to disturb them and send them into flight.

           Hypothermia is a major medical concern in cave travel. Because of the high humidity, frequently wet conditions, and physical exertion of caving, we need to be especially alert to the possible onset of hypothermia. Never push to go deeper or further in if you see students are beginning to get cold. Remember, you still have the return trip out and in many cases uncertain weather when you emerge from the cave. At the end of the caving experience, have students remove the batteries from their headlamps, clean off any excess dirt, and turn the headlamps in to the assistant instructor. Get students into warm, dry clothes ASAP. Each bus should have a water jug for drinking and washing up. Make sure that students get re-hydrated.


 D. Rock Climbing/Bouldering/Rappelling 

           Climbing, bouldering, and rappelling provide a rich experience for our students. The opportunity to climb the pristine sandstone found on Pigeon Mountain is both unique and exciting for our students. These three activities allow students to face fears of heights while also developing trust in each other. It also allows us to teach the ninth graders about movement, balance, and breathing. Climbing should not be taught as some sort of extreme sport, but instead as an activity that is safe, methodical, and thoughtful.

           Like caving, you should take advantage of the environmental educational opportunities that are available. Teach your students the geology of where they are climbing; through these sports they become face to face with rock types, folds, and plate tectonics that occurred millions of years ago. Unfortunately, these climbing sites also usually provide an opportunity to teach about the human imprint, whether it be development or graffiti. Take the time to talk about what you see around you ecologically.

 Safety Policies and Procedures 

 1. Equipment 

a. Climbing ropes will be meet UIAA standards.

b. Climbing ropes will be of kernmantle construction with a diameter of at least 10.5 mm or 7/16 inches. Rescue ropes will be of at least a 9 mm diameter. All belay ropes will be retired 5 years from the date they go into service.

c. One inch tubular nylon webbing will be used for emergency climbing seats, runners, and anchor material. Commercial climbing harness will be used during rock climbing and rappelling.

d. All anchors will be made of one inch tubular nylon or 11 mm kernmantle static rope.

e. Only approved climbing helmets may be worn. Use of helmets will be determined by the Session Director.

f.  A mechanical belay device (i.e. ATC or similar device) will be used on all belays.

g. All carabiners will have a minimum strength of 22 Kn. longitudinally.

h. First-aid and rescue equipment appropriate to the site will be accessible.

 2. Procedures 

a.      All climbing and rappelling sites will be cleaned prior to use by a qualified staff member.

b.     Purchase, usage, and condition logs will be kept of on all climbing equipment and be readily accessible at all times for inspection.

c.      All sites will be checked by the Session Director prior to use by students.

d.     A safety briefing will be given by the Session Director to staff and students prior to commencement of activity.

e.      Natural anchors will be used whenever possible with at least one back-up anchor (two point system).

f.       All rock climbing activities will be supervised by technically competent staff.

g.      Equipment will be checked before and after use each day.

h.      All rock climbing activities will be belayed using the two person belay system, with a primary belayer and a secondary belayer. The primary belayer will be anchored either to a stationary anchor or will be anchored by a third person.

i.        Climbers will climb no faster than the belayer is able to take up rope safely. 

j.       Climbing areas will not be overcrowded. There will be an adequate student/instructor ratio no larger than 2 student staff and 1 faculty to 10 students.

k.     A hands-on check of the harness will be performed on each student by a Discovery staff member prior to climbing.

l.        All belays will be supervised by a trained Discovery staff person.

m.    A safety belay will be used on all climbing, rappelling, and jumaring activities, except for bouldering (see below).

n.      When bouldering, spotters will be used if appropriate. If spotters cannot provide adequate safety, a belay will be used. Spotting specific to bouldering will be taught.

o.     Bouldering will be limited to the height of the spotters’shoulders except for friction slab work.

p.     Jewelry and sharp objects will be removed prior to participation in all climbing activities.

 3. Tie-Ins 

a. Approved sewn harnesses will be used for all rock climbing activities. 

b. All tie-ins and/or harness systems will get a hands-on check by an assigned, qualified staff prior to use by student.

 4. Knots 

a. Participants Attachment Point

Participants will be attached using a figure 8 follow through knot tied off with a single overhand knot. A figure 8 knot is tied in the standing part of the belay rope about 30 inches from the end of the rope. The end is then passed under the waistband and crotch loop at which point it is woven back through the figure 8 knot to parallel the original knot. This is then locked off with the single overhand knot.

b. Attachment of ropes to anchor material

Ropes will be attached to anchor material using a figure 8 on a bight knot tied off with a double overhand locking knot. This loop is attached to the anchor via a Locking“D”carabiner with the gate locked. Only one rope is attached to each carabiner. Webbing anchors will be tied off with a water knot.

c. Attachment of anchor material to natural anchors–Usually use webbing with water knot.

  Static Rope Anchors 

a. A figure 8 follow through knot tied off with a double overhand knot will be used after the rope has passed around the anchor at least one time.

b. A bowline is also approved for anchor tie off.

         Webbing or mixed material anchor 

The sling will be tied into a loop using a water (grapevine) knot tied off with double overhand locking knots. The loop is attached to the anchor using a girth hitch or by double loops. A water knot will be used for all anchors which have mixed cordage (i.e. rope and webbing).

 5. Bouldering 

Bouldering usually takes place in Discovery as a warm-up activity prior to top rope climbing. However, bouldering is a valuable activity all unto itself and should be used in teaching climbing movement, spotting, trust and judgment. Often students get the opportunity to try harder climbing problems that you might not have set up at a top roping site.

This is a good chance to teach a climbing movement class at the beginning of a climbing course. Then have your students’practice that movement while they are unencumbered by ropes, harnesses and belaying.

Before beginning the activity, students will be taught the importance of spotting and spotting techniques. Good spotting is important for this activity to be run safely. It also helps students to develop trust in their fellow teammates. Teach the climbers to be spotted by no less than one spotter while bouldering. Instruct your students not to boulder higher than the spotters shoulders unless the top out terrain is 3 rd class or easier.

 Other things to remember: 

-        Before letting your students boulder on a new problem, be sure to clear any objects (i.e. sticks, logs, loose rock, bees, poison ivy, etc.) on the boulder or around the landing zone before students attempt a boulder problem. If you are unable to move the object, then you should make students aware of hazard and should take steps to minimize the risk (i.e. use crash pads to cover bad landings, spot in a way the keeps climber off hazard or choose new bouldering problem!).

-        You should consider the ability level of their student group and choose boulder problems that are appropriate for their climbing ability.

-        You should keep in mind the value of progressing from easy problems to more difficulty ones in order for students to warm up before pulling strenuous moves. This also allows students to gain confidence and learn good technique.

 6. Lead Climbing 

 There will be no lead climbing during a 9 th grade Discovery expedition. 

 Procedures/Flow 

           A few Discovery staff members and a faculty member should precede the main group of students to the climbing area. These staff members will be responsible for setting up the climbs. When the group arrives at the climbing area, the Session Director or appointed Discovery faculty member will be in charge of crowd control and help organize gear and food so as to minimize visual impact. Students will be shown safe places to sit, and will be reminded about the importance of never stepping on ropes. 

           While the set-up crew is completing their work, instruction in basic bouldering technique will be given by a qualified staff member. Students will then go bouldering with a qualified staff person for a specified amount of time. When they return, they will be taught the proper way to put on a Fudge harness. Depending on time, it’s either time to begin climbing instruction or its time for lunch. 

           Belaying will be taught by a qualified member of the Discovery staff. Only approved belay devices will be allowed (an ATC or a similar device). The primary belayer will always have his/her brake hand on the rope. Instruction will focus on smoothly sliding the brake hand back to the beginning position while the opposite hand pinches the rope. A staff member will then accompany groups of climbers to the climbs which have been set up. Close supervision of all belays is the most important responsibility of this day . A ratio no larger than one adult and 2 student staff to 10 9 th graders will be maintained for all climbing activities except bouldering where student staff can instruct a group of up to 6 . Keep an eye on all equipment for safe use and care. At the end of the day all climbing equipment will be put back into the climbing packs in which they were carried to the site. Do a double check for any carabiners, belay devices, or runners which could be left behind.

 E. The Experiential Process and Integration 

           Discovery is an“outdoor, adventure-based, experiential education”program. By the time 9 th graders arrive to work with us in the required program, all have been involved in a day of discovery in the 7 th grade, and¾of the class have also been part of 2 days of programming in the 6 th grade. Those students who have been here since pre-first (about¼the class) have been actively involved in experiential programs on a regular basis for 8 years. Discovery faculty also work with classroom teachers in the Junior High (in Bible, English, and Science) and in all 9 th grade English classes.

           So what does all of that mean for us? Well, first of all, it means that most of our students arrive on the first day with a sophisticated understanding of our expectations and an appreciation for the experiential process from having already been participants in experiential programs. This means that we have the challenge of designing and running a more complex, articulated, powerful program in order to meet their heightened expectations.

           Secondly, it means that we have an opportunity to re-define the classic“experiential education”process. We talk a lot about the basic“action-reflection”experiential model of the process in Discovery. The“action”part is comprised of the games, initiatives, ropes courses, and expedition.“Reflection”through de-briefings, journals, and solo complete this basic model.

           A more complete model involves the idea of the“focus”that the participants bring to the program. The“focus”is the mindset that the participants begin the program with. This is followed by the action phase, the de-brief, and finally helping the students“transfer”what they’ve learned back to other parts of their lives (Joplin).

           Because you, as student staff, come from the same situation as the participants, you have a unique opportunity to establish a“focus”based on your previous experiences in the 9 th grade and familiarity with current goings-on at the school. Having a good sense of where the 9 th graders are at (in school and developmentally) and an overview of the Discovery Program, you should be able to“frame”each exercise in ways that are unique to that particular group.

           Finally, because experiential programming permeates the 9 th grade academic program, we define our last step as“integration”rather than“transference.”Your job is to help the 9 th graders make the connection between classroom-based“experiential learning”and what we do in the outdoors, and help them integrate the two. We are not looking for ways in which they can transfer what they have learned as much as we are helping them find ways to integrated what they’ve learned within the broader context of learning at Westminster. Your intimate knowledge of the school, the teachers (and their unique styles), and the rhythm of the school year can help bridge that gap in a way that the faculty can’t. This insight and your ability to add this extra dimension to Discovery is what makes the student leadership part of Discovery such an important part of everything we do.


 QUOTES 

 Living in the Present 

Look to this day,

For it is the very life of life.

In its brief course lie all the verities and realities of your existence:

The bliss of growth, the glory of action, the splendor of beauty.

For yesterday is but a dream and tomorrow is only a vision, but

Today well lived makes yesterday a dream of happiness and every tomorrow

A vision of hope.

Look well therefore to this day,

Such is the salutation of the dawn.

           The SUFI (1200 BC)

This is the beginning of a new day.

God has given me this day to sue as I will.

I can waste it or use if for good.

What I do today is very important because I am exchanging a day of my life for it.

When tomorrow comes, this day will be gone forever, leaving something in its place I

           I have traded for it.

I want it to be a gain, not a loss, a good, not an evil. Success, not failure, in order that I shall not forget the price I paid for it.

           Woodrow Wilson

to be nobody-but myself-in a world which is doing its best, night and day, to make you everybody else-means to fight the hardest battle which any human can fight, and never stop fighting.

           ee cummings

Choose life-only that and always, and at whatever risk. To let life leak out, to let it wear away by the mere passage of time, to withhold giving it and spreading it is to choose nothing.

           Sr. Helen Kelly

 Self Reliance 

So why do we do it?

What good is it?

Does it teach us anything?

Like determination? Invention? Improvisation?

Forsight? Hindsight?

Love?

Art? Music? Religion?

Strength or patience or accuracy or quickness or tolerance or

Which wood will burn and how long is a day and how far is a mile and how delicious is water and smoky green pea soup?

And how to rely

On your

Self?

           Terry and Kenny Russel

            On the Loose 

 Compassion 

It is better to light a candle than to curse the darkness.

           Eleanor Roosevelt

It is the weak who are cruel. Gentleness can only be expected from the strong.

           Leo Rosten

 Teamwork 

This is the story about four persons named Everybody, Somebody, Anybody and Nobody. There was an important job that needed to be done and Everybody was asked to do it. Everybody was sure that Somebody would do it. Anybody could have done it but Nobody did it. Somebody got angry about that because it was Everybody’s job. Everybody thought Nobody realized that Everybody wouldn’t do it. It ended up that Everybody blamed Somebody when actually Anybody should have known that Everybody was so blame.

           Anonymous

 Solo 

It’s surprising how many people go through life without ever recognizing that their feelings toward other people are largely determined by their feelings towards themselves, and if you’re not comfortable within yourself, you can’t be comfortable with others.

           Sydney Harris

It is in solitude that we realize that being is more important having and that we are worth more than the result of our efforts. In our solitude we discover that our life is not a possession, but a gift to be shared.

           William Faulkner

 Courage 

Do not follow where the path may lead, go instead where there is no path and leave a trail.

           Unknown

“Come to the edge.”

“It’s too high.”

“Come to the edge.”

“We might fall.”

“Come to the edge.”

And they came.

And he pushed them.

And they flew.

           Oscar Wilde

I believe that courage is all to often mistakenly seen as the absence of fear. If you descend a rope from a cliff and are not fearful to some degree, you are either crazy or unaware. Courage is seeing your fear, in a realistic perspective, defining it, considering alternatives, and choosing to function in spire of risks.

           Leonard Zunin

            Contact: the First Four Minutes 

Ask yourself for one moment what your feelings have been on the eve of some act involving courage, whether it has been physical courage as it is commonly called, or moral or intellectual…what has happened to you?  If it has really called fourth courage, has it not felt something like this?

           I cannot do this. This is too much for me. I shall ruin myself

           if I take this risk. I cannot take the leap, its impossible. All of

           of me will be gone if I do this and I cling to myself.

And then supposing the Spirit has conquered and you have done this impossible thing , do you not find afterwards that you possess yourself in a sense that you never had before? That there is more of you?...So it is throughout life...you know,“nothing ventured noting won”is true in every hour, it is the fiber of every experience that signs itself into the memory.

           J.N. Figgis

 Expedition 

Efficiency is intelligent laziness.

           David Dunham

We do not receive wisdom; we must discover it for ourselves after a journey that no one can make for us or spare us.

           Marcel Proust

It is not down on any map, true places never are.

           Herman Melville

I’d rather wake in the middle of nowhere than in any city on earth.

           Steve McQueen

Adventure is not in the guidebook and beauty is not on the map. Seek and ye shall find.

           Terry and Kenny Russel

            On the Loose 

For me there is only traveling on paths that have heart. There I travel, and the only worthwhile challenge is to traverse its full length. And there I travel, looking, looking breathlessly.

           Carlos Iastandu

Was it worthwhile? For us who took part in the venture it was so beyond. We have shared a high endeavor. We have witnessed scenes of beauty and grandeur. We have built a lasting comradeship amoung ourselves and we have seen the fruits of that comradeship ripen into achievement. We shall not forget those moments of great living upon that mountain.

           Sir John Hunt

 Environment 

Compared to the rest of the world, the developed nations consume 12 times more energy, 10 times more steel , and 15 times more paper.

           Stead and Stead, 1992

About four of every five miles traveled by Americans is by car.

           Makower, 1992

Americans send enough aluminum to landfills every year three months to rebuild the U.S. commercial air fleet.

           Stead and Stead, 1992

Despite perceived feelings of superiority over nature, humanity remains fully and totally dependent upon the natural world. We need the bounty of nature to survive on this planet. We need fresh air to breathe, the clean water to drink, the fertile soil to provide our sustenance.

           Daniel Sitarz

You shall enter the living shelter of the forest.

You shall walk where only wind has walked before.

You shall know immensity and see continuing the primeval forces of the world.

You shall know not one small segment but the whole of life: strange, miraculous, living

           Dying, changing.

You shall dare delighting to pit your skill, courage and wisdom against colossal facts.

You shall live, lifted up in light.

You shall move among clouds.

You shall see storms arise and drenched and deafened shall exalt in them.

You shall top a rise and behold a creation.

And you shall need the tongues of angels to tell what you have seen.

           Ansel Adams and Nancy Newhall (edited)

My help is in the mountains

Where I take myself to heal

The earthly wounds

That people give me.

I find a rock with sun on it.

And a stream where the water runs gentle

And the trees, which one by one give me company.

So I must stay for a long time

Until I have grown from the rock

And the stream is running through me

And I cannot tell myself from one small tree.

Then I know that nothing touches me

Nor makes me run away.

My help is in the mountains

That I take away with me.

           Nancy Wood

Climb the mountains and get their good tidings.

Nature’s peace will flow into you as sunshine flows into trees.

The winds will blow their own freshness into you, and storms their energy.

And cares will drop off like autumn leaves.

           John Muir

 Striving/Endurance 

Giving up is a final solution to a temporary problem.

           Holocaust Survivor

When you get into a tight space and everything goes against you, till it seems as though you could not hand on a minute longer. Never give up then, for that is just the place and time that the tide will turn.

           Harriet Beecher Stowe

When the morning’s freshness has been replaced by the weariness of midday, when the leg muscles quiver under the strain, the climb seems endless and suddenly nothing will go quite as you wish, it is then that you must not hesitate.

           Dag Hammerskjold

            Markings 


 V. Appendix 

 Accidents/ Incidents 

 Emergency Procedures 

1. Survey the Scene. Plan what will be done prior to action if victim is inaccessible.

2. Make sure injured, you, and other personnel are not exposed to further risk.

3. Do a primary Survey as soon as injured is reached.

4. Perform life sustaining first-aid. Do a secondary survey. Stabilize injured by maintaining airway and body temperature.

5. Evaluate whether or not an evacuation can be accomplished with available resources. If so, go to paragraph 7.

6. Send a messenger party

a. Three person minimum

b. Leave at least two people with victim

c. Send complete written information, to include a map with location of injured, with the messenger party. Include money for telephone. The Patients Report form should also go out with the messenger party.

d. Party should take essential equipment and be prepared to spend night out, (on long backpacking trips).

e. Party should mark their route to prevent them from getting lost.

f. Party should not split up

7. Group with Injured/ or walking evacuation

a. Monitor vital signs.

b. Set up temporary camp if needed.

c. Assure group members are cared for by assigning one person to look after the group.

d. Assign one person to look after the injured at all times.

e. Keep a log of all symptoms, treatment, and medication being sure to record observations and time.


 Accident/Incident Reporting 

 Types of Reportable Accidents/Incidents 

• Accident resulting in death, serious injury, or severe property damage.

• Near miss in which accident or injury did not result because of fortuitous circumstances.

• Injury which requires hospitalization.

• Injury which may have repercussions from the injured or parents.

• Injury which requires observation by injured, parents, or medical personnel because of possible future complications.

• Incident such as assault, stealing, or other illegal or grossly immoral behavior.

• Incident or illness resulting in student being removed from remainder of program.

• Any incident where a student is lost or missing will be reported immediately to the Discovery Director.

 Accident/Incident Reporting Procedures 

1. Accidents/Incidents described above should be reported to the Discovery Director as soon as is practical. In his absence the Assistant Director should be notified.

2. The person reporting should have: WHO? WHAT? WHEN? WHERE? HOW? and WHY? information to relay to the Director. Notification should not be delayed because of incomplete information.

3. Additional reports should be made when necessary to report change in status. An abundance of information is better than not enough.

4. A complete written accident/incident report should be submitted as soon as practical to the Discovery Director who will submit it to the appropriate Dean and the High School Principal.

5. Accidents or Illness not described above will be reported within 24 hours of the program&apos;s end.

 Review 

 The Session Director will review all accident reports. S/he will insure completeness. The report will then be submitted to the Director who will then approve the report or require further action. 

 Reports 

 Instructor&apos;s Session Report 

           At the end of each session Instructors will submit a brief summative report on the session to the Session Director. The report will include:

           a. A short narrative description of how the session went, the flow, any problems, etc.

           b. A list of any exceptional students.

           c. A list of any problem students

           d. Logistics evaluation - transportation, food, equipment; any recommendations.

           e. A short self-assessment, to be reviewed during the evaluation time with the Session            Director.

 Accident/Incident Report 

           The Session Director is responsible for filling out any Accident/Incident reports which will be submitted to the Director of Discovery, the High School Principal, and the School Nurse. Your responsibility is to provide a short narrative description from you point of view about what happened. Your perception and insight on safety issues is crucial to running safe, fun programs, so it is important that we hear from you any time there is an incident or accident.
	</body>
</document>
