<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004985" url="http://www.restaurantshudsonvalley.com/htm/Dutchess/Link0182.html" time="2012-07-12-21:30" support="2" score="0.003104538072035033" bingtitle="Restaurants - Japanese &amp; Sushi Dutchess County" webtitle="Restaurants - Japanese&amp;Sushi Dutchess County">
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>Sushi Condiments The important seasonings are soy ... This is a kind of sushi &quot;fast-food&quot; restaurant in Japan and is ... - Hold your chopsticks towards their end, and not ...</description>
	<body>
		Sailing on the Hudson River  
 
 

 
Restaurants - Japanese&amp;Sushi

Dutchess County
 

 
 
 Advertise Your Business Here 
     Promote your business by advertising at Shopping in Dutchess, NY. Find the best Shopping in Dutchess County ; including outlets, department stores, discount clothing stores, women&apos;s and men&apos;s clothing stores and more great places to shop. 
 
 
 
 

 
Restaurants - Japanese&amp;Sushi

Dutchess County
 Select by Name Akari Sushi&amp;Japanese Bull&amp;Buddha Edo Sushi Hana Sushi Momiji Sushi Steak House&amp;Bar Osaka Osaka Japanese Restaurant Select by Town Poughkeepsie Red Hook Rhinebeck Tivoli 

 
 
  All Poughkeepsie Listings   
Poughkeepsie Restaurants
 
 - Japanese&amp;Sushi
 
 
 Akari Sushi&amp;Japanese 
 845-471-1773    Akari Sushi&amp;Japanese Food is located at 35 Main Street, Poughkeepsie NY 12601, in one of the River Towns of the Hudson Valley.
 Restaurant Features 
BYO
Outdoor Dining


 The word is This small and quaint restaurant is &quot;a local favorite among Culinary Institute of America students&quot;. Locals agree that Akari is absolutely the best sushi restaurant in our area&quot;; Akari is &quot;amazing&quot; serving &quot;incredibly fresh fish&quot;, all offered at a &quot;good value.
   Also in Category:   Outdoor Dining 
 
 Bull&amp;Buddha 
 845-337-4848    Bull and Buddha, serving Asian Fusion cuisine, is located at 319 Main Street, Poughkeepsie, NY 12601, Dutchess County in the mid-Hudson Valley. The restaurant is located in a newly restored building in the heart of Poughkeepsie&apos;s revitalized Main Street.
 Restaurant Features 
Night life
Outdoor Dining


 The word is The decor is attractive and chic with a great bar and cozy booth seating; the food and service need to improve, especially the service, but you can go for the great night life scene in Poughkeepsie.
   Also in Categories: 
 Outdoor Dining 
 Restaurants - Asian - Pan Asian&amp;Asian Fusion 
 
 
 
  All Red Hook Listings   
Red Hook Restaurants
 
 - Japanese&amp;Sushi
 
 
 Hana Sushi 
 845-758-4333    Hana Sushi, serving Traditional Japanese food and sushi, is located at 7270 South Broadway, Red Hook NY 12571, Dutchess County in the Hudson Valley. 
 
 
  All Rhinebeck Listings   
Rhinebeck Restaurants
 
 - Japanese&amp;Sushi
 
 
 Edo Sushi 
 845-835-8402    Edo Sushi, serving Traditional Japanese food and sushi, is located at 1094 Route 308, Rhinebeck, NY 12572 in Dutchess County.
 The word is Locals say Edo is the best sushi in the area, serving &quot;excellent super fresh sushi and sashimi&quot; and the &quot;Edo Roll is delicious&quot;.
	</body>
</document>
