<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004841" url="http://dailyserving.com/2010/10/superflex-flooded-mcdonalds/" time="2012-07-12-21:21" support="2" score="0.0018930669142164745" bingtitle="DAILY SERVING » SUPERFLEX: Flooded McDonald’s" webtitle="DAILY SERVINGSUPERFLEX:  Flooded McDonalds">
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>Contributors test; Partners; Sponsor Us; Store; Submit ... life-sized replica of a McDonald’s fast-food restaurant. ... It lifts and moves chairs, trays, food and drinks ...</description>
	<body>
		With over 30 writers contributing globally, DailyServing scours the earth to bring you groundbreaking visual art everyday.
 SAN FRANCISCO LONDON NEW YORK BERLIN LOS ANGELES SINGAPORE CHICAGO AMSTERDAM PERTH GLASGOW 
 ELSEWHERE 
 Boston Portland São Paulo Toronto 
 
 
 Home About Us Contributors Contributors test Partners Sponsor Us Store Submit 
 

 October 7, 2010 Written by Kelly Nosari 
 SUPERFLEX: Flooded McDonald’s 
 
Flooded McDonald&apos;s Still of&quot;Flooded McDonald&apos;s&quot;(2009), courtesy of the artists and Peter Blum Gallery, New York. Produced by the Propeller Group in cooperation with The South London Gallery, Louisiana Museum of Modern Art, the Oriel Mostyn Gallery and the Danish Film Institute.
 
 Flooded McDonald’s , by art collective Superflex , is currently on view at the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden in Washington D.C.  For this recent film, Superflex painstakingly created a life-sized replica of a McDonald’s fast-food restaurant.  Their deliberate choice to employ one of the most recognizable brands in the world offers a familiar point-of-departure for the viewer, while also evoking related issues of consumerism and corporate ascendancy.

As the Hirshhorn asserts, the artists‘borrow the cinematic vocabulary of documentaries, ads, and disaster movies’.  This approach is accessible and appropriately complements the main-stream setting.  As the film begins, one instantly recognizes the yellow, red and otherwise neutral, utilitarian interior of the fast food chain.  The counter, menu, partially eaten food and Ronald McDonald figure are all to-be-expected.  Yet, the realism of the space is made strange by the absence of the typically crowded human presence.  The restaurant seems to have been abandoned–creating a sense of the uncanny and imbuing the film with visual ambiguity that engages the viewer’s curiosity.
 
Flooded McDonald&apos;s Still of&quot;Flooded McDonald&apos;s&quot;(2009), courtesy of the artists and Peter Blum Gallery, New York. Produced by the Propeller Group in cooperation with The South London Gallery, Louisiana Museum of Modern Art, the Oriel Mostyn Gallery and the Danish Film Institute.
 
 Flooded McDonald’s is exhibited as a looped digital video projection, 21 minutes in length.  The film unfolds in real time and begins as it surveys the still (and empty) McDonald’s.  Water then begins to fill the space, entering from under a door.  Water, a powerful natural force, wreaks havoc without substantial visual obstruction.  It lifts and moves chairs, trays, food and drinks around the room.  It shorts the electrical circuit and becomes murky in all of the refuse.  The film concludes when the fast food restaurant is finally and completely submerged.

On the one hand a filmic quip, Flooded McDonald’s open-ended nature lends itself to deeper interpretation.  The film creates an artificial and concentrated natural disaster–an event which always points to the fragility of human existence.  (One can’t help but think of recent flooding disasters).  Furthermore, the work confronts the viewer with images of trash and destruction–highlighting over consumption and the associated waste it generates.  This waste, coupled with recognizable corporate imagery, unarguably critiques capitalist excess.  By destroying a fabricated prototype of the American way of life, the film seems to suggest a departure from the status quo.
 
Flooded McDonald&apos;s Still of&quot;Flooded McDonald&apos;s&quot;(2009), courtesy of the artists and Peter Blum Gallery, New York. Produced by the Propeller Group in cooperation with The South London Gallery, Louisiana Museum of Modern Art, the Oriel Mostyn Gallery and the Danish Film Institute.
 
 Superflex , a Danish art collective founded in 1993, exhibits internationally.  The collective engages viewers and participants in issues surrounding globalization.  They work in film and multi-media projects that are typically realized in the real world through social intervention.  Members Jakob Fenger (b. Roskilde, 1968), Rasmus Nielsen (b. Hjørring, 1969), and Bjørnstjerne Reuter Christiansen (b. Copenhagen, 1969) live and work in Copenhagen and Rio de Janeiro.

 Flooded McDonald’s was on view, from January to March of this year, at Peter Blum Gallery in New York.  It has also recently shown at Oriel Mostyn gallery in Wales and South London Gallery , London, UK.

 Flooded McDonald’s remains at the Hirshhorn through November 28th.  It is presented in conjunction with the fifth anniversary of the museum’s Black Box space, which is dedicated to new and recent work in film and video.
 Tweet permalink Tags: film , Hirshhorn , Oriel Mostyn gallery , Peter Blum Gallery , South London Gallery , Superflex , Washington D.C. 
Leave a Reply
 
SERIES
 
 Categories 
Categories

 Articles Artist Videos Collage Conceptual Conference craft Curators Design Digital Media Drawing Fashion Fiber arts Illustration Installation Interviews L.A. Expanded Column Mixed Media Neon New Media Painting Performance Photography Print Reviews Sculpture Sound Art Street Art / Public Art Text Uncategorized Video / Film 
 Archives 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 
 Follow @dailyserving 
 Copyright 2009-2012 DailyServing.com. All rights reserved. Site by Something in the Universe
	</body>
</document>
