<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004113" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indian_fast_food" time="2012-07-12-20:21" support="3" score="0.01619349627320336" bingtitle="Indian fast food - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia" webtitle="Indian fast food - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="32"/>
	<description>Main dishes; Desserts; Bread; Drinks; Snacks; Spices; Condiments ... serving counter, visible to the customers, and one has to eat while standing by placing the food on ...</description>
	<body>
		Indian fast food 
 From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Jump to: navigation , search 
 This article does not cite any references or sources . Please help improve this article by adding citations to reliable sources . Unsourced material may be challenged and removed . (September 2009) 

 This article is part of the series Indian cuisine Regional cuisines North India 
 Main article 

 Awadhi Punjabi Kumauni Mughlai Kashmiri Rajasthani Uttar Pradeshi 
 North-East India 
 Assamese Meghalayan Manipuri Naga Sikkimese Tripuri Arunachalese 
 South India 
 Main article Andhra Karnataka Kerala Tamil Hyderabadi Udupi Mangalorean Saraswat Mangalorean Catholic 
 East India 
 Bengali Oriya Bihari Bhojpuri 
 West India 
 Goan Gujarati Marathi Malvani&amp;Konkani Sindhi Parsi 
 Other 
 Indian Chinese Nepali Jain (Satvika) Anglo-Indian Chettinad Fast food Malaysian Indian Cuisine 
 Ingredients and types of food 
 Main dishes Desserts Bread Drinks Snacks Spices Condiments 
 Preparation and cooking 
 Handi Karahi Tava Uruli Other 
 See also 
 History Etiquette Indian chefs Cookbook: Cuisine of India 
   
 India portal 
 
 v t e 
 

The fast food industry in India has evolved with the changing lifestyles of the young Indian population. The sheer variety of gastronomic preferences across the regions, hereditary or acquired, has brought about different modules across the country. It may take some time for the local enterprise to mature to the level of international players in the field.

Many of the traditional dishes have been adapted to suit the emerging fast food outlets. The basic adaptation is to decrease the processing and serving time. For example, the typical meal which called for being served by an ever alert attendant is now offered as a Mini-Meal across the counter. In its traditional version, a plate or a banana leaf was first laid down on the floor or table. Several helpers then waited on the diner, doling out different dishes and refilling as they got over in the plate.

In the fast food version, a plate already arranged with a variety of cooked vegetables and curries along with a fixed quantity of rice and Indian flatbreads is handed out across the counter against a prepaid coupon. The curries and breads vary depending on the region and local preferences. The higher priced ones may add a sweet to the combination. Refills are generally not offered.

The diversity of Indian cuisine poses logistical problems when it comes to handling. Hence it is common to serve different cuisines at different counters within the same premises. Presence of a large vegetarian population, who eschew non-vegetarian food, has given rise to outlets which exclusively serve vegetarian fast food. Also, different variety of food may be served depending on the times of the day. Beverages such coffee, tea, soft drinks and fruit juices may also be served in such outlets. Some outlets may additionally have specially designed counters for ice-cream , chaats etc.

Popular formats of fast food business in India have the following features in common:

 Wide opening on the road side Easy to maintain and durable décor A cash counter where food coupons are sold A food delivery counter which invariably is granite topped Additional counters for Ice Creams, Chaats, Beverages etc. A well fitted kitchen located so as to be visible to the customers Tall tables, usually of stainless steel, where one can eat while standing A drinking water fountain adorned with a water filter Rust-proof and non-breakable crockery 

Most of the fast food outlets in India are stand alone establishment, few of them having more than one branch.

 
Contents
 
 1 Darshini 2 Food courts 3 Varieties of food offered 
 3.1 South Indian 3.2 Others 3.3 Beverages 
 4 Indian Associations related to food 
 

 [ edit ] Darshini 

One of Bangalore &apos;s restaurateurs, Mr Prabhakar, opened an outlet called Upahara Darshini in mid-1980s. The novelty was that the food is cooked just behind the serving counter, visible to the customers, and one has to eat while standing by placing the food on tall tables. It is a self service place where one has to buy a coupon before eating. It offered typical south Indian snacks at highly affordable prices resulting in an instant hit with the office goers as well as students. The size and the enclosed design of the eating space and consequent spilling over of the eaters onto the footpath during the busy hours indicates that he did not anticipate the level of success. This issue is addressed by those who copied the module by keeping the entire face of the outlet open to the road. It would not be wrong to say that this was a trend setter and its format, described earlier, is even to this day replicated by other across south India. The popularity of this business module can be gauged from the fact that many restaurants which adopt this format have &quot;Darshini&quot; as suffix in their names.

 [ edit ] Food courts 

Another concept of fast food that is becoming popular is that of Food Courts. It is like putting together a number of Darshinis serving different cuisines under one roof. Here also one has to purchase coupons and collect the food from one of the several counters. Each one of these counters serves specific variety of food and may be owned by different individuals or caterers. Food Courts are normally located on much bigger premises and may provide seating facility in addition to the stand and eat arrangement. Typically one entrepreneur owns or takes on lease the entire premises and promotes the place under one name. He then lets out individual counters to different independent operators to offer different menu. Internal competition is avoided by not allowing more than one counter to offer similar food.

Several international fast food chains like Kentucky Fried Chicken , McDonald&apos;s , and Barista Coffee have their outlets in major cities. Café Coffee Day , again a brainchild of Bangalore based businessman, is the only Indian chain which boasts of hundreds of outlets and is present across India. But then it is classified more as a coffee shop than a fast food place.

 [ edit ] Varieties of food offered 

The kind of fare they offer as of date could be just anything and everything. Preference of the local population and the location of the outlet influence the menu more than anything else. Some of the popular dishes offered at Indian fast food outlets are:

 The embedded lists in this article may contain items that are not encyclopedic . Please help out by removing such elements and incorporating appropriate items into the main body of the article. (February 2010) 

 [ edit ] South Indian 

 Idli – Rice Idli, Rava Idli Vada – Uddina Vada, Rava Vada, Masala Vada, Maddur Vada Dosa - Masala Dosa, Set Dosa, Rava Dosa Upma , Kesaribhath Puliyogere Pongal Vangibhath Vegetable Bonda 

 [ edit ] Others 

 Bonda Soup Bajji – Banana Bajji, Green Chili Bajji Pakora – Onion Pakora, Vegetable Pakora Thali - vegetable, chicken, mutton Rajma rice Omelette bread Chinese food Pasta Burgers (chicken, mutton, veg) Wraps&amp;rolls Grilled chicken Samosa , patties, bread pakoda Milkshake Dabeli Doner kebab Dum biryani Fish and chips Salads Momo Fruit beer Chicken wings Grilled Sandwich Mutar kulcha Pao bhaji Stuffed paratha Fruit salad Idli sambar Vada sambar Dahi wada Fried rice Noodles Mini Meals Pizza 

 [ edit ] Beverages 

 Coffee Tea Lassi Aerated drinks Fresh fruit juice Milkshake Mock tails Soup (Hot Beverage) 

 [ edit ] Indian Associations related to food 

 INCATA - Indian Caterers Association 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Indian_fast_food&amp;oldid=484802340 &quot; Categories :
 Fast food Indian cuisine 
 Hidden categories:
 Articles lacking sources from September 2009 All articles lacking sources Articles needing cleanup from February 2010 All pages needing cleanup Wikipedia laundry list cleanup from February 2010 
 
Personal tools

 Log in Create account 
 
Namespaces

 Article Talk 
 


 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to Wikipedia 
 
Interaction
 
 Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact Wikipedia 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Cite this page 
 
Print/export
 
 Create a book Download as PDF Printable version 
 
Languages
 
 മലയാളം 
 
 This page was last modified on 31 March 2012 at 05:03.
 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License ;
additional terms may apply.
See Terms of use for details.
Wikipedia®is a registered trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc. , a non-profit organization.
 Contact us 

 Privacy policy About Wikipedia Disclaimers Mobile view
	</body>
</document>
