<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004787" url="http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/saras-secrets/red-gold-white-and-candy-striped-beets-with-beet-juice-reduction-recipe/index.html" time="2012-07-12-21:18" support="7" score="0.00792801670183527" bingtitle="Red, Gold, White, and Candy-Striped Beets with Beet Juice ..." webtitle="Red, Gold, White, and Candy-Striped Beets with Beet Juice Reduction Recipe :   : Recipes : Food Network">
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001402" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001150" bing-rank="165"/>
	<description>I serve this in a small paper cup, like the ones you might find at a fast food restaurant for ketchup or relish ... Sign up for My Food Network to share photos, show off your ...</description>
	<body>
		Food Network Magazine Blog Social Videos Full Episodes 
 Food Network 
 Recipes&amp;Cooking Shows Chefs Restaurants Shop Food Network 
Shop by Chef

 Rachael Ray Guy Fieri Alton Brown 

 Paula Deen Anne Burrell Bobby Flay 

 More in: Shop All Chefs&amp;Shows Recipes&amp;Cooking 
 
Shop by Department

 Specials Clearance Cookbooks Cutlery Cookware Grocery Coupons Shop All Departments 
 
 
 Food Network Star Grilling Central Quick&amp;Easy 
Inside Quick&amp;Easy

 Grilling Easy Entertaining Breakfast Recipes Kid Friendly 
 Healthy&amp;Fast Shortcut Recipes 

 Weeknight Dinners Summer Salads Chicken Smart Shopping Tacos Cooking Tips 

 More in: Quick&amp;Easy Recipes&amp;Cooking 
 
Shows

 30 Minute Meals with Rachael Ray Cooking for Real More Shows 
 
Shop Our Store
 
 Rachael Ray Products Cookbooks 

 Cook&apos;s Tools Cutlery 
 Healthy Eating 
Inside Healthy Eating

 Healthy Every Week Light Summer Meals Dinner Recipes Light Desserts Healthy Blog 

 Quick Recipes Meal Makeovers Vegetarian Wallet Friendly Hero Foods 

 More in: Healthy Eating Recipes&amp;Cooking 
 
Shows

 Healthy Appetite with Ellie Krieger More Shows 
 
Shop Our Store
 
 Ellie Krieger Products Cookbooks 

 Cookware Small Appliances 
 Holidays&amp;Parties 
Inside Holidays&amp;Parties

 Grilling Central Burgers Hot Dogs In-Season Faves Cocktails Thanksgiving Prep
 

 Everyday Celebrations Barbecue Picnic Ready Family Weekends Summer Parties Appetizers 

 More in: Holidays&amp;Parties Recipes&amp;Cooking 
 
Shows

 Down Home with the Neelys Paula&apos;s Party More Shows 

 
 
Shop Our Store
 
 The Neelys&apos; Products Cookbooks 

 Cookware Gourmet Foods 
 In Season Now 
Inside In Season Now

 Grilling Vegetable Favorites Summer Salads Weeknight Meals Produce Picks 

 Summer Parties Appetizers Desserts Everyday Celebrations Entertaining Ideas 

 More in: In Season Now Recipes&amp;Cooking 
 
Shows

 The Cooking Loft Jamie at Home More Shows 
 
Shop Our Store
 
 Alton Brown&apos;s Products Cookbooks 

 Gift Ideas Bakeware 
 Recipes on TV 
Inside Recipes on TV

 Paula Deen Rachael Ray The Neelys Sandra Lee 

 Giada De Laurentiis Bobby Flay Ina Garten Guy Fieri 
 
Shows

 Barefoot Contessa Paula&apos;s Home Cooking More Shows 
 
Shop Our Store
 
 Chef&apos;s Products Cookbooks 

 Bakeware Grocery Coupons 
 Chef Recipes 
Inside Chef Recipes

 Paula Deen Rachael Ray The Neelys Sandra Lee 

 Giada De Laurentiis Bobby Flay Ina Garten Guy Fieri 
 
Shows

 Good Eats with Alton Brown Secrets of a Restaurant Chef More Shows 
 
Shop Our Store
 
 Chef&apos;s Products Cookbooks 

 Cookware Grocery Coupons 
 

 Food Network Star Restaurant: Impossible Giada at Home Best Thing I Ever Made Restaurant Guide Shows A-Z 
Shows A-Z Close 

 $40 a Day 24 Hour Restaurant Battle 3 Days to Open with Bobby Flay 30 Minute Meals 5 Ingredient Fix Aarti Party Ace of Cakes Alex&apos;s Day Off All-American Festivals Ask Aida Barefoot Contessa BBQ with Bobby Flay Behind the Bash Big Daddy&apos;s House Bobby Flay&apos;s Barbecue Addiction Boy Meets Grill Chef Hunter Chef Wanted with Anne Burrell Chefs vs. City Chic&amp;Easy Chopped Cooking for Real Crave Cupcake Wars Dear Food Network Dessert First Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives Dinner: Impossible Down Home With the Neelys Easy Entertaining with Michael Chiarello Emeril Live Everyday Italian Extreme Chef Extreme Cuisine with Jeff Corwin Fat Chef Feasting on Asphalt/Waves Food Detectives Food Feuds Food Network Challenge Food Network Specials Food Network Star FoodNation With Bobby Flay Giada at Home Giada&apos;s Weekend Getaways Glutton for Punishment Good Deal with Dave Lieberman Good Eats Grill It! with Bobby Flay Guy Off the Hook Guy&apos;s Big Bite Ham on the Street Have Cake, Will Travel Have Fork, Will Travel Healthy Appetite with Ellie Krieger Heat Seekers Heavyweights Home for Dinner With Jamie Deen How To Boil Water How&apos;d That Get On My Plate? Hungry Detective Hungry Girl Ice Brigade Inside Dish Invention Hunters Iron Chef America Jamie at Home Kid in a Candy Store Last Cake Standing Meat&amp;Potatoes Meat Men Mexican Made Easy Molto Mario My Life in Food Mystery Diners Nigella Bites Nigella Express Nigella Feasts Nigella Kitchen Not My Mama&apos;s Meals Outrageous Food Party Line with the Hearty Boys Paula&apos;s Best Dishes Paula&apos;s Home Cooking Paula&apos;s Party Private Chefs of Beverly Hills Quick Fix Meals with Robin Miller Rachael Ray&apos;s Tasty Travels Rachael vs. Guy: Celebrity Cook-Off Rachael&apos;s Vacation Recipe for Success Rescue Chef Restaurant Stakeout Restaurant: Impossible Road Tasted Road Tasted with the Neelys Roker on the Road Sandra&apos;s Money Saving Meals Sandwich King Secrets of a Restaurant Chef Semi-Homemade Cooking Simply Delicioso with Ingrid Hoffmann Spice&amp;Easy Sugar High Sugar Rush Sweet Genius Tailgate Warriors Ten Dollar Dinners The Best Thing I Ever Ate The Best Thing I Ever Made The Chef Jeff Project The Cooking Loft The Essence of Emeril The Great Food Truck Race The Next Iron Chef The Pioneer Woman The Secret Life Of Throwdown With Bobby Flay Tough Cookies Trisha&apos;s Southern Kitchen Tyler&apos;s Ultimate Ultimate Recipe Showdown Unwrapped Viva Daisy! What Would Brian Boitano Make? Will Work for Food Worst Cooks in America 
 

 Alton Brown Giada De Laurentiis Bobby Flay Melissa d’Arabian Ree Drummond Guy Fieri The Neelys Chefs A-Z 
Chefs A-Z Close 

 Aaron McCargo, Jr. Aaron Sanchez Aarti Sequeira Adam Gertler Aida Mollenkamp Alexandra Guarnaschelli Alton Brown Anne Burrell Anne Thornton Bob Blumer Bobby Deen Bobby Flay Bobby and Jamie Deen Brian Boitano Cat Cora Chris Cognac Claire Robinson Daisy Martinez Danny Boome Dave Lieberman Duff Goldman Ellie Krieger Emeril Lagasse Food Network Kitchens Geoffrey Zakarian George Duran Giada De Laurentiis Guy Fieri Ina Garten Ingrid Hoffmann Jack Hourigan Jamie Deen Jamie Oliver Janet Johnston Jeff Corwin Jeff Henderson Jeff Mauro Jim O&apos;Connor Jose Garces Keegan Gerhard Kevin Brauch Marc Forgione Marc Summers Marcela Valladolid Mario Batali Mark Dacascos Mary Nolan Masaharu Morimoto Melissa d&apos;Arabian Michael Chiarello Michael Symon Nigella Lawson Patrick and Gina Neely Paula Deen Rachael Ray Rahm Fama Ree Drummond Robert Irvine Robin Miller Ron Ben-Israel Sandra Lee Scott Conant Sunny Anderson Ted Allen The Hearty Boys Tom Pizzica Trisha Yearwood Tyler Florence Warren Brown 
 

 By Show By Host By Destination By Location 
 
 My Recipe Box 
 Entire Site Recipes Products Search Home &gt; Recipes &gt; Seasonal &gt; Red, Gold, White, and Candy-Striped Beets with Beet Juice Reduction Recipe 
Red, Gold, White, and Candy-Striped Beets with Beet Juice Reduction

Recipe courtesy Rick Tramonto, Amuse-Bouche: Little Bites That Delight Before the Meal Begins, Random House, October 2002

Show: Sara&apos;s Secrets Episode: Superbly Spectacular Serving 

 Recipe categories: Vegetables , Beets , more 
 Cuisine : American Technique : Simmer , Roasting Nutrition : Vegetarian , Low Fat , Low Calorie Occasion : Holiday , New Year , Holiday , Christmas , Holiday Season : Fall , Spring , Summer , Winter Cookware Used : Saucepan 
 
 
 recipe ratings&amp;reviews (0) 
 Be the first to rate this recipe Total Time: 1 hr 15 min Prep 5 min Cook 1 hr 10 min Yield: 6 servings Level: Easy 
 Print Recipe Full-Page View Save to My Recipe Box Review Recipe 

 
 x 
Save To My Recipe Box
 Save To Select Folder: All My Recipes Or Create New Folder 
Please limit to 20 characters
 
Saving Recipe
 
 Add Or Do Not Add 
 
 Success 

This recipe was saved to your Folder_Name folder.

 Do not show this message again 
 Close x 
Save To My Recipe Box

 Please sign in to save this recipe to your Recipe Box!! 
 
 Sign In or Create Your Recipe Box 
 

 Add Timer Timer Name: 25 Characters Max 
Enter Time:
 : : Start 
You can create up to five timers
 
 
 
©Television Food Network G.P. 
All Rights Reserved.
 
If you don&apos;t have fun with this dish, you&apos;re not doing it right! Go wild with the many different beets out there. I took all I could find at a local farmer&apos;s market and made an extraordinary and colorful salad, which I later pared down for an amuse, using colorful beets supplied by Ton Cornille and Sons, my produce vendor, with whom I have worked for more than a dozen years. I serve this in a small paper cup, like the ones you might find at a fast food restaurant for ketchup or relish, and arrange the beets according to color and shape: This amuse is very much about visual appeal. The beet juice reduction provides a little extra kick. Because this holds well, you can make it ahead of time, or you can increase the amounts and take it along on your next picnic.

Ingredients

 2 cups red beet juice (see note) Kosher salt 3 baby red beets 3 baby gold beets 3 baby white beets 3 baby candy-striped beets 1/2 cup olive oil Freshly ground black pepper Fresh thyme leaves, for garnishing 

Directions
 
Put the beet juice in a small, heavy-bottomed saucepan and bring to a boil over medium-high heat. Reduce the heat to maintain a simmer and simmer for about 25 minutes or until the juice is reduced to a syrup. Remove from the heat.

 Strain the reduction through a chinois or fine-mesh sieve into a small bowl. Cover and refrigerate until needed.

Preheat the oven to 375 degrees F. Lay out a large piece of aluminum foil. Make a 1/2-inch thick bed of kosher salt on a jellyroll pan.

Rinse and dry the beets. Remove all but 1 inch of the stems (leaving the roots and part of the stems prevents the beets from bleeding). Coat the beets with 1 tablespoon of the olive oil and place them on the jelly-roll pan. Wrap the beets with the foil to form a package and set it on the bed of salt.

 Roast the beets for 30 to 40 minutes or until tender. To test for tenderness, insert a skewer or paring knife into 1 of the beets. If the skewer meets with no resistance, the beets are done.

When the beets are cool enough to handle, cut off the roots and stems. If you wish, keep the stems on a few beets for presentation. Slip the skins off the beets with your fingers.

Cut the beets into quarters and put them in a medium-sized bowl. Toss with the remaining olive oil and season, to taste, with salt and pepper.

To serve, place a few assorted beet quarters inside a small cup, positioning the ones with stems near the top. Drizzle with the red beet juice reduction and garnish with thyme leaves. Repeat to make 5 more servings.

Note: 12 ounces of beets make about 3/4 cup juice.
 
 Print Recipe 
 
Browse Similar Recipes

 
Beet Gratin
 By: Emeril Lagasse 
White Chocolate Rice Pudding...
 By: Bobby Flay 
White Chocolate Valentines
 
Duck Beets
 
 
 View All 8 Healthy Collections 

Healthy Recipe Collections

 Low Cholesterol Recipes (159) High Fiber Recipes (88) 

 Heart Healthy Recipes (220) Low Sodium Recipes (107) 

 Diabetic Recipes (199) Low Calorie Recipes (1544) 
 
COMMENT ON THIS PROJECT
      
Sign in

All fields are required.
 
E-mail Address:
 
Password:
 
 Forgot Password? 
 
 Remember me on this computer
 
 Sign In 
 
Signing in

 
 
Sending Password

 
 
Please enter your email address and we will send your password
 
E-mail Address
 
 Request Password 
 
or Cancel 
 
Your password has been sent and should arrive in your mailbox very soon.
 
 Sign In 
 
Not a member?

Sign up for My Food Network to share photos, show off your style, and connect to an enthusiastic and helpful community.

It&apos;s free and easy.
 
 Register Now 
 
Review This Recipe

You must be signed in to review this recipe.
 
 Sign in 

or Register to Review 
 
Review This Recipe

Your review has been submitted for approval and will appear shortly. Thanks!
 
Next Recipe
 
Buttered Beets and Peas with Onions: Two UK-favorite sides in...
 By: Rachael Ray Rated 4 stars out of 5 Advertisement 
On TV

 Full Schedule · Shows A-Z 
 
 What&apos;s Hot 
 
 Diners, Drive-ins and Dives 
 Hosted by: Guy Fieri 
Most Popular Right Now
 
Recipes

 See More Recipes» 
 
 Pappardelle With Corn 
 Rated 5 stars out of 5 45 Reviews 
 Broccoli Salad 
 Rated 5 stars out of 5 313 Reviews 
 Peach Cobbler 
 Rated 4 stars out of 5 1480 Reviews 
Photo Galleries
 
 Summer Cookout Salad Recipes 
 
 Things to Grill in Foil 
 
Videos

 Watch More Videos» 
 
 Yummy Bacon Wrapped Appetizers 
 8524 views 04:27 
 Deliciously Unpredictable Demo 
 8079 views 00:42:00 
Today&apos;s Deal

 Browse More Products» 
 
 Top Chips Maker Set by Mastrad 
 $19.95 
See More Recipes Like This From Food.com
 
 Seasonal Recipes Seasonal Vegetables Seasonal Fruit Seasonal Grilling Seasonal Party Recipes 
 
Free Recipe of the Day Newsletter
 
Let Food Network chefs plan what&apos;s for dinner, with quick and easy recipes delivered to your inbox daily.


 E-Mail Address: CONTINUE 
Ads by Google
 
Ideas From Food Network

 Planting a Food Lover’s Garden Melissa d’Arabian Extras 

 Our Best Grill-Out Recipes Pantry-Raid Recipes 

 Recipes for Fresh Produce Great Grape Recipes 

 Black Bean Hummus Recipe Grow Your Own Desserts 

 Meet the FN Star Finalists Contests and Promotions 
 
More From Food Network

 Social: Facebook and More Sweepstakes and Contests iTunes and Mobile Food Network Everywhere Share Our Strength Recipes A-Z Topics A-Z 
 
Food Network Family
 
 HGTV 
 See the finalists compete! Tuesdays 9/8c 
 Food.com 

 Summer Corn, 10 Ways 15 Easy Party Snacks Food Holidays Newsletter 
 
 Cooking Channel 

 Healthy Summer Recipes Top Summer Side Dishes Best Burger Recipes 
 
 Food Network Everywhere 

 NYC Wine&amp;Food Fest Sweeps Pre-Order $10 Dinners Cookbook Get Food Network Magazine 
 Food Network 
 FoodNetwork.com Home Recipes&amp;Cooking Quick&amp;Easy Healthy Eating Holidays&amp;Parties Shows Chefs Video Shop 
 Search 
Scripps Networks Digital

 Cooking Channel Food.com CityEats.com HGTV DIY Network FrontDoor.com HGTVRemodels.com HGTVGardens.com Travel Channel GAC 
 x 
 See All of Scripps Networks Digital   

 Site Map Terms of Use Privacy Policy Ad Choices Infringements About Advertise With Us Help Contact Us 
 ©2012 Television Food Network G.P. All rights reserved. 
International Editions

 United States   United Kingdom   Asia   Europe, Middle East&amp;Africa   
 x International Editions
	</body>
</document>
