<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004187" url="http://www.amazon.ca/Fast-Food-Nation-Greg-Kinnear/dp/B000MEYKAU" time="2012-07-12-20:25" support="1" score="0.005929432535969981" bingtitle="Fast Food Nation: Amazon.ca: Greg Kinnear, Bruce Willis, Catalina ..." webtitle="Fast Food Nation: Amazon.ca: Greg Kinnear, Bruce Willis, Catalina Sandino Moreno, Wilmer Valderrama, Ana Claudia Talancn, Juan Carlos Serrn, Armando Hernndez, Frank Ertl, Michael D. Conway, Mitch Baker, Ellar Coltrane, Dakota Edwards, Richard Linklater, Alexandra Stone, Ann Carli, Chris Salvaterra, David M. Thompson, Edward Saxon, Eric Schlosser: DVD">
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>Only 1 left in stock--order soon (more on the ... as Brian, a kid who spits in the food routinely and dreams up schemes to steal money from the fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		amazon.ca 
 Hello. Sign in to get personalized recommendations . New Customer? Start here .   
 FREE shipping on orders over $25 
 
 
 Your Store  |  Deals Store  |  Gift Certificates   Your Account  |  Help  |  en franais 
 Shop All Departments 
 
 Search 
 All Departments Baby Books Classical Electronics Home&amp;Garden Movies&amp;TV Music Software Sports&amp;Outdoors Tools&amp;Building Supplies VHS Video Games Watches   
   
 Cart Cart Wish List 
 
 Movies&amp;TV Advanced Search Browse Genres New Releases Bestsellers Deals TV Shows Blu-ray En franais 
 
 
 Books 
 All Books Textbooks Children&apos;s Books 
 Music 
 All Music Canadian Music 
 Movies&amp;TV Shows 
 All Movies&amp;TV Shows Blu-ray New&amp;Future Releases 
 Electronics 
 All Electronics Camera, Photo&amp;Video Computers&amp;Accessories GPS&amp;Navigation 
 Software 
 All Software Business&amp;Office Software 
 Video Games 
 All Video Games Game Hardware 
 Home&amp;Garden 
 All Home&amp;Garden Kitchen&amp;Dining Furniture&amp;Dcor Bedding&amp;Bath Home Appliances Patio, Lawn&amp;Garden Pet Supplies 
 Tools&amp;Building Supplies 
 All Tools&amp;Building Supplies Power Tools&amp;Accessories Hand Tools Hardware Building Supplies 
 Baby 
 All Baby Nursery Strollers Car Seats Baby&amp;Toddler Toys 
 Watches 
 Watches 
 Sports&amp;Outdoors 
 All Sports&amp;Outdoors Exercise&amp;Fitness Outdoor Recreation Team Sports 
 Boutiques Francophones 
 Toutes nos boutiques francophones Livres Musique Films et Sries tlvises Logiciels 
 
 
 
 
Vous voulez voir cette page en franais ? Cliquez ici .
 25 used&amp;new from CDN$ 1.92 See All Buying Options Have one to sell? Sell yours here Share 

 
   Click for larger image and other views   
 
 
 
 
 
  
 Share your own related images 
 
 Fast Food Nation 
 Greg Kinnear (Actor) , Bruce Willis (Actor) , Richard Linklater (Director)   |   Rated:  R (Restricted)  |   Format: DVD
 1.0 out of 5 stars     See all reviews   ( 1 customer review ) 
 1 Review 
 5 star :    (0) 4 star :    (0) 3 star :    (0) 2 star :    (0) 1 star :  (1) 

 ›   See the customer review... 
 
 
 Available from these sellers . 


 7 new  from  CDN$ 9.99 18 used  from  CDN$ 1.92 
 
What Other Items Do Customers Buy After Viewing This Item?

 Food Inc / Les alimenteurs (Bilingual Edition)   ~ Michael Pollan  DVD 
 4.8 out of 5 stars   ( 20 ) 
 CDN$ 10.28 Forks Over Knives  DVD 
 4.9 out of 5 stars   ( 18 ) 
 CDN$ 14.99 The Future of Food   ~ Charles Benbrook  DVD 
 5.0 out of 5 stars   ( 4 ) 
 CDN$ 15.24 Foodmatters   ~ Vicky Blewitt  DVD 
 4.4 out of 5 stars   ( 7 ) 
 CDN$ 18.04 
 › Explore similar items 
 
Product Details
 
 Actors: Greg Kinnear , Bruce Willis , Catalina Sandino Moreno , Wilmer Valderrama , Ana Claudia Talancn Directors: Richard Linklater Writers: Richard Linklater , Eric Schlosser Alexandra Stone , Ann Carli , Chris Salvaterra , David M. Thompson , Edward Saxon Format: AC-3, Color, Dolby, Dubbed, DVD-Video, Subtitled, Widescreen, NTSC Language: English, Spanish Subtitles: English, Spanish, French Region: ( US and Canada This DVD will probably NOT be viewable in other countries. Read more about DVD formats. )
 Aspect Ratio: 1.85:1 Number of discs: 1 MPAA Rating: Studio: Fox Video Release Date: Mar 6 2007 Run Time: 116 minutes Average Customer Review: 1.0 out of 5 stars     See all reviews   ( 1 customer review ) 
 1 Review 
 5 star :    (0) 4 star :    (0) 3 star :    (0) 2 star :    (0) 1 star :  (1) 

 ›   See the customer review... 
 ASIN: B000MEYKAU Amazon Bestsellers Rank: #13,473 in DVD ( See Top 100 in DVD )
 #72 in  DVD &gt; Art House&amp;International &gt; British Cinema &gt; Comedy 
 
  Would you like to update product info , give feedback on images , or tell us about a lower price ?
 

 

 
 
 
Suggested Tags from Similar Products
   ( What&apos;s this? ) Be the first one to add a relevant tag (keyword that&apos;s strongly related to this product) Check a corresponding box or enter your own tags in the field below   
 documentary (8) food industry (8) environmentalis m (4) agribusiness (3) factory farming (3) health (2) michael pollan (1) organic food (1) anderson cooper (1) sanjay gupta (1) 

 
 Your tags: Add your first tag 
 Search Products Tagged with   See most popular tags 
 Like 1342117535 false -1 0 0 0 ( 0 ) 
Customers Who Bought This Item Also Bought
   Page of ( Start over ) Back 
 Food Inc / Les alimenteurs (Bilingual Edition) DVD ~ Michael Pollan 4.8 out of 5 stars   ( 20 ) CDN$ 10.28 The Future of Food DVD ~ Charles Benbrook 5.0 out of 5 stars   ( 4 ) CDN$ 15.24 Super Size Me DVD ~ Morgan Spurlock 4.7 out of 5 stars   ( 9 ) CDN$ 9.99 Wal-Mart: The High Cost of Low Price DVD ~ Lee Scott 2.7 out of 5 stars   ( 6 ) CDN$ 13.99 King Corn DVD ~ Bob Bledsoe 5.0 out of 5 stars   ( 2 ) CDN$ 21.24 The 11th Hour DVD ~ Leonardo DiCaprio 4.6 out of 5 stars   ( 11 ) CDN$ 9.93 
 Next 
Customer Reviews
 5 star 0 4 star 0 3 star 0 2 star 0 1 star 1 1 review 1.0 out of 5 stars Write a customer review Most helpful customer reviews 4 of 5 people found the following review helpful NOT a documentary July 28 2010 By Derek Satnik Format: DVD THIS IS NOT A DOCUMENTARY. This film is an anecdotal story. It has a point, but it is absolutely not a documentary. There are no interviewed experts, no stats, and no solutions explored. It has an inappropriate amount of sexual content, and offers little constructive recourse about any of the realities in the industry. Don&apos;t waste your money on this film - instead, consider &quot;FOOD, Inc&quot; and &quot;The Future of Food&quot;. Was this review helpful to you? Yes No › See the customer review Write a customer review Most Helpful Customer Reviews on Amazon.com (beta) Amazon.com:  128 reviews 38 of 41 people found the following review helpful fine exposé---even if the company in the film is fictional Jun 16 2008 By Matthew G. Sherwin - Published on Amazon.com Format: DVD Fast Food Nation is an excellent film about the very real and highly disturbing flaws that exist in a meat packing plant that provides the beef for Mickey&apos;s, a fictional fast food chain that doesn&apos;t exactly have its act together. Not only do we see how American lives are affected by this mess, we also see how desperate and sometimes frustrated, angry young people and illegal immigrants are drawn into this situation. The movie moves along at a good pace and the acting is terrific. The casting is excellent and this is one movie I must highly recommend even with a few hard to swallow (pardon the pun) scenes at the end of the &quot;kill floor&quot; at the meat processing plant.

When the action begins, we meet Don Anderson (Greg Kinnear) who is a high level executive at a fast food chain company. One day Don&apos;s boss informs him that some students at a university have found that there is waste matter in the meat. Don&apos;s boss orders him to the Colorado packing plant to investigate and try to find a way out of this mess.

We also meet desperate, frightened, yet sometimes angry Mexican immigrants who were so desperate for money that they illegally crossed the border from Mexico into the US. Two or three of them wind up working at the meat packing plant in Cody, Colorado. There is Raul (Wilmer Valderrama) and Sylvia (Catalina Sandino Moreno) and we also meet Coco (Ana Claudia Talancón). There are even young kids involved in the overall plot. There is Ashley Johnson who plays Amber, a cashier at Mickey&apos;s whose conscience bothers her about working there; and there is Paul Dano who turns in a stunning performance as Brian, a kid who spits in the food routinely and dreams up schemes to steal money from the fast food restaurant.

Of course, from here the plot can go almost anywhere. What happens when one of the Mexican men is injured--badly injured at the meat processing plant? How do Silvia and Coco get along when they get into the United States? What about Don Anderson--will he be able to find a graceful way out of this mess and make everything all right after all for Mickey&apos;s, the fast food chain? Watch the movie and find out!

We also get great smaller performances from highly talented actors including Kris Kristofferson and Bruce Willis. They make the movie all the more interesting and their acting is excellent, too.

The DVD comes with a documentary entitled &quot;The Manufacturing of Fast Food Nation;&quot; and there are four animated shorts as well. There is a commentary by director and co-author Richard Linklater and co-author Eric Schlosser as well.

Overall, I would recommend this film for grown ups--and those of them with strong stomachs at that. There is the issue of drug use in this film; and the scenes from the &quot;kill floor&quot; are not exactly going to help you sleep well tonight. However, if you can handle it, Fast Food Nation is a brilliant film that even allows its viewers to draw their own conclusions and opinions about these complicated topics. 54 of 64 people found the following review helpful Loved the message...but needed something more... Nov 18 2006 By Diane Moore - Published on Amazon.com The movie follows three groups of people who are all affected by the fast food industry in some way: teenagers working at &quot;Mickey&apos;s, illegal immigrants crossing into the United States and working at a meatpacking plant, and a man who works for the Mickey&apos;s company, in advertising. Though their paths only cross briefly if at all, the premise seems interesting. It shows the way the workers are treated, how someone can lose an arm or a leg in one of the machines, the &quot;kill floor&quot; and the graphic nature of cattle being slaughtered. Though it appears sanitary, there is a lot of &quot;talk&quot; from those that are connected to the place. Don Anderson ventures out to find the true story when his boss tells him that there was &quot;fecal matter&quot; discovered in the Mickey&apos;s meat. (Yet he still continues to eat it.)

All of this presented to you in an entertaining way makes the audience think. Yet there is something missing. Maybe it would have been better as a documentary. I think the reason that this movie was made as fiction, is so that it would reach more of an audience. Documentaries aren&apos;t viewed as often...though I would have loved to see it filmed that way.

I enjoyed the small parts by Ethan Hawke, Patricia Arquette, Avril Lavigne, and Bruce Willis. The message comes through loud and clear: big business doesn&apos;t care about customers, it cares about the almighty dollar. The only thing that can be done is, you have to stop buying their food. Until then, I hope to see more movies like this opening our eyes about the fast food industry.

I think it could have been done a little bit better. It&apos;s almost as if there is too much ground to cover, and a 2 hour film just doesn&apos;t do it. With that said, it may still put you off of fast food for a while. Pass the organic beef, please. 10 of 10 people found the following review helpful Brutal, Probing, Embarrassingly Honest Examination of the Fast Food Industry Mar 7 2007 By Grady Harp - Published on Amazon.com Format: DVD FAST FOOD NATION got such minimal response in the theater run that it seemed to go straight to DVD. The PR for the film was such that it appeared to be &apos;hilariously funny&apos; (according to the DVD box cover) and as such might just provide a bit of humor after a tumultuous day of work. WRONG! This little film adapted by Richard Linklater from Eric Schlosser&apos;s frightening book is agonizingly biting and insightful: if you elect to watch it, be prepared for some ugly facts that may just produce insomnia.

Don Henderson (Greg Kinnear) is a marketing strategist for &apos;Mickey&apos;s&apos;, a fast food chain that is highly successful in selling millions of &apos;The Big One&apos; (the comparisons to the McDonald&apos;s Big Mac are not subtle!) and discovers that the meat patties have been found to grow E. coli in the lab! On an expedition to explore the validity of this problem he travels to Cody, Colorado to visit the plant that produces the meat patties for the entire national chain. And so the plethora of storylines begin: the film examines the illegal immigrants from south of the border brought in by coyotes, treated like dirt, and given jobs &apos;cleaning&apos; the meat plant and working the food chopping lines and eventually the killing and slaughtering of the cattle whose housing conditions are filth personified; the teenage workers who people the Mickey&apos;s chain are shown to be discontent and equally capable of planning robberies as they are of attempting to free the soon-to-be-burgers cattle; the callous corporate types who cover the facts in favor of increasing monetary gain; the plant workers who abuse the immigrant workers in every way possible; the utter boredom of the populace of Cody and the resultant pacified response to the &apos;big problems&apos; that seethe through their town. Yes, it is an expose of corruption on many levels, but the film doesn&apos;t stop there.

Linklater and Schlosser are careful to include the individuals caught up in the mess and those individuals run the gamut from the immigrants who only want to find a better way of life and will subject themselves to horrors both in their trek across the border and the mistreatment in the factories to find it, to the honest men of the corporations, the ranchers, and the teenagers who try to make a stand against the many problems that overwhelm them. And that is what makes the film so moving: it personalizes rather than generalizing.

The cast is huge and without exception excellent: Greg Kinnear, Kris Kristofferson, Bruce Willis, Bobby Cannavale, Ashley Johnson, Paul Dano, Patricia Arquette, Luis Guzmán, Wilmer Valderrama, Catalina Sandino Moreno, Ana Claudia Talancón, Juan Carlos Serrán, Armando Hernández, Esai Morales, Ethan Hawke, Avril Lavigne...the cast just goes on and on. Be ready for some horrendously brutal scenes not only in the killing and cutting lines but in the sexual abuses equally as tragic. This is a film that should affect the viewer, and while it is overly long at almost two hours, it is as pungent a social comment as has been made. Grady Harp, March 07 › Go to Amazon.com to see all 128 reviews Search Customer Reviews Only search this product&apos;s reviews 
Listmania!
 
 
 
   Documentary films you need to watch : A list by El Hombre 
 
   My favorite documentaries : A list by Tim Donnelly 
 
   Give Your Life an Green Make-Over : A list by Brittney Kroiss 
 
 Create a Listmania! list 
 Search Listmania! 
 
 
Look for similar items by category
 
 Movies&amp;TV &gt; Art House&amp;International &gt; By Country &gt; British Cinema &gt; Comedy Movies&amp;TV &gt; Comedy &gt; British Movies&amp;TV &gt; Drama Movies&amp;TV &gt; Mystery&amp;Suspense 
 
Look for similar items by subject
 Movie 
 Adult Humor 
 Adult Situations 
 Americana 
 Comedy 
 Comedy Drama 
 Drama 
 Drug Content 
 English 
 Ensemble Film 
 Feature 
 Gore 
 Nudity 
 Profanity 
 Sexual Situations 
 Strong Sexual Content 
 Thriller 
 UK 
 USA 
 Workplace Comedy 

 
i.e., each DVD must be in subject 1 AND subject 2 AND ...
 
Feedback
 Would you like to update product info or give feedback on images ? 



 Your Recent History   ( What&apos;s this? ) 
 
 
 
After viewing product detail pages or search results, look here to find an easy way to navigate back to pages you are interested in.
 › Visit the Page You Made 
 
 
After viewing product detail pages or search results, look here to find an easy way to navigate back to pages you are interested in.
 › Visit the Page You Made 
 
 
 
 Get to Know Us 
 Careers Amazon and Our Planet Investor Relations Press Releases 
 Make Money with Us 
 Sell on Amazon Amazon Associates Self-publish with Us 
 Let Us Help You 
 Shipping Rates&amp;Policies Returns Are Easy Customer Service 
 
 China | France | Germany | Italy | Japan | Spain | United Kingdom | United States  And don&apos;t forget: Book Depository | IMDb | Shopbop Conditions of Use | Privacy Notice | Interest-Based Ads  2008-2012, Amazon.com, Inc. or its affiliates
	</body>
</document>
