<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004864" url="http://bestof.voiceplaces.com/new-york/w/best-veggie-burger-2011-50500" time="2012-07-12-21:23" support="1" score="0.00254380002396039" bingtitle="Best Veggie Burger in New York: 5 Napkin Burger" webtitle="Best Veggie Burger in New York:
  5 Napkin Burger">
			<query id="000129" bing-rank="14"/>
	<description>5 Napkin Burger, the Best Veggie Burger in New York. Vote for your favorite spots ... absolutely everything about this burger -- patty, bun, vegetal accessories, condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		New York Login 
 Atlanta Austin Baltimore Boston / Providence Broward / Palm Beach Chicago 

 Cleveland Dallas / Ft. Worth Denver / Boulder Detroit Houston Kansas City 

 Las Vegas Los Angeles Miami Minneapolis / St. Paul Nashville 

 New York Orange County Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix 

 Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh / Durham Sacramento San Diego 

 San Francisco / Bay Area Seattle St. Louis Tampa Bay / St. Petersburg Washington DC 
 
 Food&amp;Drink Arts&amp;Entertainment Sports&amp;Recreation Shopping&amp;Services 
 
Best Veggie Burger
 2011
 Winner ‘Best Veggie Burger’ in other markets » Tweet 
5 Napkin Burger
 630 Ninth Ave., New York, NY 10036 (212) 757-2277 Last year, we chose this as our favorite burger for the Voice&apos;s annual &quot;Best Of&quot; issue. And despite the fact that it has some serious competition this time around, its ranking stands for the simple fact that absolutely everything about this burger -- patty, bun, vegetal accessories, condiments -- works in perfect harmony. The bun: sturdy but pliant multigrain. Tomatoes, lettuce, bread and butter pickles: generous, fresh. Patty: Conjured from black beans, barley, brown rice, carrots, beets, jalapeños, and sesame seeds, it&apos;s crunchy on the outside, moist on the inside, and flavorful and satisfying as hell. 5N sauce: like a hybrid of Russian dressing and tartar sauce, and thus delicious. Meat eaters, your loss is our considerable gain. Source: The Village Voice Comments on 5 Napkin Burger Add a Comment Connect with facebook to post a comment.  Login Submit Saving your comment... Places Near: ★ 5 Napkin Burger 1 Best Veggie Burger 5 Napkin Burger 0.0 miles 2 Best Jazz/Blues Jukebox Rudy&apos;s Bar&amp;Grill 0.0 miles 3 Best Bar Mascot Rudy&apos;s Bar&amp;Grill 0.0 miles 4 Best Fish Palace In The Theater District Esca Restaurant 0.1 miles 5 Best Chilean Pomaire 0.1 miles 6 Best Room To Hear Cabaret FireBird Cafe 0.1 miles Vote Now 5 Napkin Burger 630 Ninth Ave. Veselka 144 2nd Ave. The V Spot 156 5th Ave. Remedy Diner 245 E. Houston Tiny&apos;s Giant Sandwich Shop 129 Rivington St. Shake Shack 23rd&amp;Madison Ave. Make another choice Current Standings Your vote: Change your vote ▶ GET MOBILE Find the best things to do wherever you are Download Free Finalists Veselka 144 2nd Ave. The V Spot 156 5th Ave. Remedy Diner 245 E. Houston Tiny&apos;s Giant Sandwich Shop 129 Rivington St. Shake Shack 23rd&amp;Madison Ave. Rabbithole Bakery&amp;Bistro 352 Bedford Ave. Westville East 173 Ave. A Hillstone 378 Park Ave. S. Suggestions Best Chinese (sichuan) Best BBQ Best Ramen Best Istrian Best Place To Take Your Mom Badges Check-in here on your mobile phone to earn the following badges: Veggie Burger Fan Feed Prettie wants to do this 3 months ago Michael wants to do this 5 months ago Do you own or manage this business? Click here to promote your award 
To create the award badge below, copy the HTML on the right and paste it into your website.
 2011 Winner Best Veggie Burger 
 Terms of Service Privacy Policy Contact Us 

 Brought to you by © 2011 Village Voice Media Holdings ,
 LLC all rights reserved. Powered by GoTime 
 
Sorry, you need to be logged in to do that

 Login with Facebook By submitting your e-mail you also agree to be added to the My Voice Nation database and receive the Best Of e-mail newsletter, unless you have chosen to opt out. 
 First name Last name Email 
 
Or login with Facebook

 Login with Facebook
	</body>
</document>
