<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004002" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100702150515AAfJVOB" time="2012-07-12-20:13" support="2" score="0.011048311476996609" bingtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Does the fast food restaurant Wendy&apos;s drug test ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Does the fast food restaurant Wendys drug test for employment?">
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Cars &amp; Transportation; Computers &amp; Internet; Consumer Electronics; Dining Out ... Does the fast food restaurant Wendy&apos;s drug test for employment?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Chiz, who else? Member since: December 18, 2007 Total points: 918 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Does the fast food restaurant Wendy&apos;s drug test for employment?
 Do they drug test, if so urine, blood, or saliva? Also, how long does it take for marijuana or its byproducts to exit your system? (I am 6 ft 1 in and underweight) 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by christie Member since: November 18, 2006 Total points: 2,282 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 the one i work at does not drug test. also weed takes at least 3 weeks to leave ur system sometimes more depending on how often u toke. if u get hurt on the job u do have to drug test tho. 
Source(s):
 while companies can take a hair sample, it is much cheaper to urine test so more then likely if u do test that is probably what u would get 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 75% 3 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Does the fast food r… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by ClassicR... Member since: June 30, 2009 Total points: 645 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 ok, well thats why they call it dope, because you all are dopes! if they take a hair sample it could last 6-7 years!!! not many people no that bc its very uncommon to test tht way bc its harder and inconvenient. anyways, if you have to ask, and over yahoo answers especially then i hope you are blessed with wendys work for the endurance of your life :] 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 25% 1 Vote by Celeste Member since: June 25, 2010 Total points: 223 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yea i am sure they drug test and more than likely it is either urine or blood! usually mj takes about 1 week to be completely out of your system. i wish you the best of luck with that! 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Patches the Dog 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
