<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004042" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080424104409AA82JMn" time="2012-07-12-20:15" support="1" score="0.00033682117793997033" bingtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Is hardees a good place to work?" webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - Is hardees a good place to work?">
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>Select &quot;Yes&quot; from the pop up window. Nothing, you ... cars but i need 1 right away is it a good place ... How long does it take for a fast food restaurant to call you…</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 buck Member since: April 01, 2008 Total points: 205 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Is hardees a good place to work?
 i got to get another job but im good with workn on cars but i need 1 right away is it a good place to work are give me some good places to try???? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Finally a Mrs.!! Member since: July 13, 2007 Total points: 7,986 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 I wouldnt do fast food if its at all possible, try another car place if thats what your good at 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 5 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Is hardees a good pl… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (1)
 
 by guitar_d... Member since: January 09, 2008 Total points: 408 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 yeah! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Related Questions

 How long does it take for a fast food restaurant to call you… What is the best fast food resturant to work at? Like… Why do you have to sign when using debit card at hardees? Dose the food at carl jr&apos;s ( AKA Hardee&apos;s) disturb you? What is the training period for a crew member at Hardees? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
