<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004209" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20101117213512AAE3cEh" time="2012-07-12-20:26" support="1" score="0.00253516095803169" bingtitle="Why the majority of fast food restaurant employees are mostly non ..." webtitle="Why the majority of fast food restaurant employees are mostly non whites? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="68"/>
	<description>Why the majority of fast food restaurant employees are mostly ... wealthier side.however, there is a great number ... alright, I don&apos;t want them handling my food anyway.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Society&amp;Culture &gt; Cultures&amp;Groups &gt; Other - Cultures&amp;Groups &gt; Resolved Question 
 The Melancholy of a Yahoo User Member since: June 25, 2010 Total points: 1,929 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Why the majority of fast food restaurant employees are mostly non whites?
 This is disturbing to me. Can the boss hire more whites? This is stupid and racist. Mostly you see whites in restaurants like TGI Friday or Oliver and Garden or any fancy restaurant.

But mostly blacks are in restaurants like McDonald&apos;s or Wendy. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 if you have an opininated answer, please share. 
 2 years ago 
 you guys are missing the point.

I never said that white people are racist.

I said that if boss hire mostly blacks in fast food resturants and white in fancy resturants, the boss is mainly racist because he complete hire people with skills but based on color. 
 2 years ago 
 by Leila Member since: January 11, 2009 Total points: 26,479 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Can I just start by saying that TGI Fridays and Olive Garden are NOT fancy restaurants? They are mid-level dining, at best. TGI Fridays and Olive Garden are cheap chain restaurants. No rich person eats at those places, I&apos;m just keeping it real girl. Those are kind of cheap seated-dining restaurants. Think about it. An average meal at McDonalds is like 7 dollars after tax, and an average meal at TGI Fridays is like 14 bucks after tax. Fourteen dollars really isn&apos;t a lot to pay for a meal. Rich restaurants are charging at least 25/30 dollars a plate.
And I have worked in a mid-level dining restaurant before, and VERY FEW people there where White, I&apos;m just being honest. I worked at a Ruby Tuesday as a bartender, and all of the cooks were Hispanic or Black, the food-runners were Hispanic, the servers were African (from Africa) and Middle Eastern and Black and there was a couple White girls but they were from overseas somewhere like Ukraine. I worked at a local mid-level dining restaurant too, and it was the same situation almost to a tee. The ONLY White people I ever encountered in either restaurant was the customers and the managers. Seriously.

I&apos;ll let you know what the&quot;difference&quot;is, though. The difference is that in fast food restaurants, the workers don&apos;t actually have to ever really hold an in-depth conversation with the customers. The customers ask for a #1, and the workers know what to do. In a sit-down restaurant like TGI Fridays, the workers have to talk to the customers in-depth. They have to explain things and they also have to be charming. Fast food workers aren&apos;t trying to earn tips so they don&apos;t need to be able to speak English well. They also aren&apos;t considered as true representatives of the company the way waiters and waitresses are.

The reason why you see non-Whites in fast food jobs is because they don&apos;t pay enough. So unless the person is under 18, it&apos;s unlikely they would get a fast food job when they could just get a waitressing job and actually pay the bills / tuition. A lot of White people are not underprivileged so they don&apos;t have to take fast food jobs. Some are, so they do. But anyway, it also really probably depends on where you live. I live in a major metro area, and most TGI Fridays and Olive Garden workers I see are Hispanic or Black, with some Whites mixed in. The majority in my area is non-White, though. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 33% 2 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (23)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Sarah Member since: November 15, 2009 Total points: 697 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 they aren&apos;t white because whites dont apply to work there! where i live mostly mexicans and hispanics work at fast-food places, and i dont have a problem with different races or anything, but i havent applied to those jobs because most of them cant speak english very well and i cant speak spanish so i dont think i would be able to communicate with them for socializing OR getting a customers order correct. if somebody of a different race applied to places like tgi fridays im sure they would have as good of a chance of getting a job as a white person. oh, and your acting like ONLY whites are racist! LOTS of the black/hispanic/mexicans i know are COMPLETYELY racist towards white people! its like they think we arent good enough to hang out with them :P i mean, not all of them are like that. i mean, my best friend is black AND mexican and she is not racist in the least bit....sorry if that sounded racist..which im sure it will to some people :( 
Source(s):
 im as white as it gets. 
 Edited 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by goodnuse... Member since: December 28, 2009 Total points: 6,097 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It is correct that a Caucasian has to apply, but most Fast Food jobs are entry level employment with no experience necessary. So many minority&apos;s and non english speaking people apply for work at these locations. If you show up and can be trained to perform repetitive tasks, then you can earn money to help your future.
I will only say this with out any racial bias. (EDUCATION IS KEY) If you study hard in school...learn to read and write and do mathematics, and today&apos;s computer skills...you will be able to find good employment. All bosses are suppose to be equal opportunity employers. And being bilingual or affluent with the racial profile in your area helps encourage good customer relations. But will always say English should be the primary language of the United States. JMHO Good Luck. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Kassandr... Member since: November 11, 2010 Total points: 189 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 because even though we are so past those antebellum days, white ppl still pass on their $$ and power(??) on to their children. since white ppl started off being the richest, white ppl are still the majority of the wealthier side.however, there is a great number of non-white ppl that are making it into the wealthier side. its a work in progress. also, poverty contributes to violence and failure to move forward, sooo when families are in poverty, the children&apos;s (the future&apos;s) being slowed down. 
Source(s):
 i have to live in this complicated world 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Mario Lavatory Member since: July 18, 2010 Total points: 2,998 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I don&apos;t know where you live, but here in Chicago where I live, you absolutely WILL see plenty of blacks as servers in the sit-down restaurants (Olive Garden, Chili&apos;s, etc.) as well as in fast-food restaurants. You will see whites, blacks&amp;Hispanics working in all the restaurants. However, you will NOT see a lot of Asians. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by jennn. Member since: October 18, 2008 Total points: 4,002 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Hmm, I don&apos;t seem to notice that in my area. I think you may be thinking into it too hard. It is possible that more non-white people apply to McDonald&apos;s or Wendy&apos;s and more white people want to work at TGI Friday, etc as well. You just cannot assume that they are racist for that reason. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Lever Member since: July 07, 2010 Total points: 4,970 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 That has to do with where you live. If I go out into the countryside, eveyrone working at McDonald and Walmart is White, if I go into the city, they&apos;re minorities.

Olive Garden where I live is multiracial. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by PGDN Member since: October 17, 2010 Total points: 836 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Funny you should say that because I was in KFC the other day and there were mainly white girls asking for orders.

Thumb me down if you think I&apos;m being somewhat racist, but that&apos;s what I seen. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Giovanni... Member since: November 17, 2010 Total points: 68 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I noticed the same thing. It does bother me.
Wendy&apos;s: Mexican, guatamalan
Mc Donalds: African Americans, mexicans, guatamalans
Dunkin Donuts: Pakistanians 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by CPOT Member since: September 01, 2010 Total points: 2,301 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 They want to continue the plantation life in the 21st century. Whites in the office making orders, and Black people out front doing the strenuous work. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by COTTON Member since: November 05, 2010 Total points: 930 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Because blacks voluntarily apply for those jobs, and whites voluntarily apply for the other jobs.

btw u a girl or boi 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Tyler Reks Member since: October 16, 2010 Total points: 6 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Fast food restuarants are low skilled jobs, and most illegal immigrants in the U.S can only do low skilled jobs because most of them are not very smart in the I.Q department. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Lynn Member since: October 31, 2010 Total points: 12,773 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Open your own restaurant and you will know the answer (and hopefully stop complaining). 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Shadowpl... Member since: June 10, 2010 Total points: 330 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I see teens mostly of any race, your questions is dumb, people get hired where they apply. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Sharnett... Member since: September 23, 2010 Total points: 2,068 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Whites mostly work in the back so that they cant be seen. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by ? Member since: November 11, 2010 Total points: 710 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Well, aren&apos;t the blacks are applying for the jobs? Are you saying they shouldn&apos;t be hired? 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 4 people rated this as good 
 by Fiona Member since: May 25, 2009 Total points: 2,320 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 &quot;Its a dirty job, but someones gotta do it.&quot; 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by The Rog Meister Member since: June 29, 2008 Total points: 1,721 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I don&apos;t see that where I live. Perhaps it&apos;s your imagination. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Dr Noah Boddy Member since: November 07, 2009 Total points: 21,637 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 That&apos;s alright, I don&apos;t want them handling my food anyway. They&apos;re too d@mn nasty. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by shizzle Member since: October 30, 2007 Total points: 71,483 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 sure, the boss can hire more whites...but only if they apply. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 5 people rated this as good 
 by Charles P Member since: October 31, 2010 Total points: 269 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Most whites go where the money is and that doesn&apos;t seem to be at a fast food joint. When I was a child all you seen were teenage whites at fast food joints. Now they have moved on up to TGI Friday and Oliver Garden..... LOL. No seriously though, they seem to be out for the&quot;mighty dollar&quot;and don&apos;t feel like a fast food joint that pays minimum wage is good enough. (Plus Mommy and Daddy wouldn&apos;t let them work there. Kills their social image) 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 

 by Anonymou... Member since: November 08, 2010 Total points: 352 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Answer hidden due to its low rating
 LMAO! You have to be a troll. Please tell me you&apos;re a troll. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Chandra Member since: March 21, 2010 Total points: 1,771 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Answer hidden due to its low rating
 i want to have sex with a black girl once in my life 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Ecstasy Member since: October 07, 2010 Total points: 5,395 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Answer hidden due to its low rating
 they own it. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Cultures&amp;Groups 

 Why don&apos;t white people use umbrellas when it rains? Do you think judges discriminate? Why or why not? In general, do you prefer the typical British English, Australian or American accent? Why do white people like to raw eggs and runny eggs? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Society&amp;Culture 
 Cultures&amp;Groups 
 Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgendered Other - Cultures&amp;Groups People with Disabilities Senior Citizens 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
