<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004503" url="http://www.dezeen.com/2011/11/21/mcdonalds-by-patrick-norguet/" time="2012-07-12-20:55" support="4" score="0.0040212270260694405" bingtitle="Dezeen » Blog Archive » McDonalds by Patrick Norguet" webtitle="McDonalds by Patrick Norguet - Dezeen">
			<query id="000766" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000781" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000515" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>Mc Donald’s has put Patrick Norguet in charge of ... oily smell and traces of ketchup on old trays… ... flagship design in the UK is great for this fast food &apos;restaurant&apos;.</description>
	<body>
		Home About Submit a story Advertise Contact Newsletter Cookies policy 
 
 Dezeen 
 
 « Older story Newer story » 
 
 McDonalds by Patrick Norguet 
 Pin It Tweet 21 November 2011 174845 50 comments http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dezeen.com%2F2011%2F11%2F21%2Fmcdonalds-by-patrick-norguet%2F McDonalds+by+Patrick+Norguet 2011-11-21+11%3A11%3A48 Rose+Etherington http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dezeen.com%2F%3Fp%3D174845 More:
 Interiors Restaurants and bars 
 
 

Fast-food giant McDonalds have commissioned designer Patrick Norguet to redesign their restaurant interiors across France. 

 

While the chain has come to appeal primarily to teenagers, Norguet wants to rebrand it as a place for families.

 

The space is divided by plywood cabinets, shelving and booths, and furnished with his own Still metal chair for Lapalma.

 

Customers can order at the counter or from digital terminals in family booths.

 

The neutral pallette is highlighted with orange and yellow metal storage boxes, plus red and dark green upholstery.

 

Other designer updates to fast-food restaurants include a Little Chef outlet by Ab Rogers and a chicken shop in Munich by Ippolito Fleitz Group .

 

Here are some more details from Patrick Norguet:
 
New interior design for McDonald’s restaurants in France by Patrick Norguet

Mc Donald’s has put Patrick Norguet in charge of designing the new architectural identity for its restaurants in France. A project which is exciting in terms of its scope as well as in its technical and sociological constraints since it concerned McDonald’s returning to its founding myth: familial fast food. If the brand was originally founded on the family, its image has little by little slid towards a more urban and adolescent tone. A return therefore to McDo’s DNA with this new interior design that Patrick Norguet, literally and figuratively, matches with getting back to roots.

 

The plant metaphor, with its branching development, this root common to the brand and to the family, is transformed here into an architecture which is transversal and expansive: birch plywood takes root and branches out in the restaurant in order to create areas, functions and moods for different social requirements without compartmentalising.

 

This organic and functional furniture/architecture offers several possibilities, several eating choices from eating standing up for lone teenagers, alcoves providing privacy to family table service, a small revolution at Mc Donald’s with digital control terminals integrated into the base and distributed throughout the restaurant. Henceforth, a mother can settle with her offspring at a table, order from a nearby terminal and wait for the meals to be brought to the table.

 

Patrick Norguet’s design, which as always hits the spot, uses contemporary white which he counterbalances with fun colours without falling for“toy”conventions like for example the storage elements with the painted metal boxes included in the base template. The luminous ambiance and the quality of the acoustics are exceptionally meticulous and offer customers a comfort which is rare today, whilst the quest for a certain radical nature is revealed through the choice of materials (plywood, sheet metal, concrete, etc.), tested in conditions of heavy passage to respond to the constraints of such a popular restaurant.

 

The designer is using his“Still”metal chair for Lapalma for the seats with a new high stool version specially designed for the occasion. The ceramic floor also designed by Patrick Norguet for Lea Ceramica immediately lends a distinctive tone to the venue. These huge, ultra-slim 2 metre slabs break with usual visual conventions: warm and graphic without being carpet, they change our habits in terms of flooring to create a brand new typology.

 

Piloted at the start of the year in the Villefranche-de-Lauragais restaurant 40 km from Toulouse, the concept was immediately appealing and spoke volumes. 6 restaurants are currently in the pipeline throughout France.
 
See also:

 Cocoro by Gascoigne Associates Cantina de Comida Mexicana by Taller Til… Sketch by Martin Creed Dezeen archive: restaurants and bars Dude Cigar Bar by Studiomake Hel Yes! temporary restaurant Spiegel Kantine by Ippolito Fleitz Group… Wienerwald restaurant by Ippolito Fleitz… RGB by Carnovsky at DreamBags-JaguarShoe… 
 
 « Older story Newer story » 
 Pin It Tweet 21 November 2011 174845 50 comments http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dezeen.com%2F2011%2F11%2F21%2Fmcdonalds-by-patrick-norguet%2F McDonalds+by+Patrick+Norguet 2011-11-21+11%3A11%3A48 Rose+Etherington http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dezeen.com%2F%3Fp%3D174845 More:
 Interiors Restaurants and bars Chain restaurants France Patrick Norguet Restaurants 
 
Posted on Monday, November 21st, 2011 at 11:11 am by Rose Etherington.
 See our copyright policy .
 
One Response to McDonalds by Patrick Norguet 

 arthurmani says: at 11:54 am 
Seeing these images, I can&apos;t help but thinking of Mac Donald&apos;s typical oily smell and traces of ketchup on old trays…
 Reply George Pepper says: at 12:22 pm 
I&apos;m not the biggest fan of McDonalds, but this design is great–I really like how the neutrals have been augmented with the toned down reds and yellows. Very classy.
 Reply Stefan Tervoort says: at 12:48 pm 
Maybe someone should redesign the food they serve…
 Reply AliB says: at 12:58 pm 
I would prefer to see McDonalds investing money in the quality of their food than the interior of their so called&apos;restaurants&apos;…
 Reply Howard P Mock says: at 1:32 pm 
this is for my friend june. wow, quite a mcdonalds.
 Reply urbanizr says: at 1:38 pm 
a strategy! now, will they also hire a french chef to rethink their menu?
 Reply Sixpense says: at 1:40 pm 
Don&apos;t all McDonalds already look like this ?
 Reply 
 Xit says: at 7:35 pm 
my favourite comment lol
 Reply 
 alis says: at 1:49 pm 
Looks good, however it still won&apos;t be a restaurant experience when the food is cheap, fabricated garbage…
 Reply Andrew says: at 2:21 pm 
If the product is not good, the packaging cannot do much to make it better.
 Reply Johnny says: at 2:29 pm 
lipstick on a pig!
 Reply eve says: at 3:22 pm 
the geometric shapes reminds me of Piet Mondrian&apos;s paintings
 Reply 
 Joe Lendvai says: at 2:17 pm 
Exactly. That is one reason why it comes across as visual noise, jumbled and fragmented. You ask yourself&quot;why?&quot;Looks like change for change&apos;s sake. The redesign adds little of value to customers and makes each&quot;restaurant&quot;more costly to furnish and maintain. Thumbs down.
 Reply 
 Shmuck says: at 3:31 pm 
Lovely…, and as for the product, it does no more then it sets out to achieve…so with that, a food that you eat that is ridden with guilt, but fills your rumbling belly, and now to enjoy this&quot;guilty plessure&quot;in a hospitable and charming enviroment.
 Reply Nino says: at 3:31 pm 
It looks sterile and grey and cold and flimsy.
 Reply Peni says: at 3:58 pm 
Must have been a good earner for his studio, plus he wedged his own chairs in there (and removed the DSWs that normally sit in&apos;design&apos;MacDonalds.)

A business man&apos;s project.
 Reply Marmaduke Wilture says: at 4:05 pm 
polishing a turd!
 Reply x77 says: at 4:33 pm 
everyone of you are a bunch snobs…..
 Reply 
 Stefan Tervoort says: at 11:11 am 
Well, that maybe true, but in my defense I didn&apos;t say they shouldn&apos;t sell hamburgers anymore, but there is a huge different between the hamburgers they sell, or what you could get in an average bar, paying the same.
And the bar isn&apos;t so called specialized in selling them, McDonalds is…

But I guess that the answer, McDonalds doesn&apos;t serve hamburgers, it tries to sell you one.
 Reply 
 dandid says: at 5:29 pm 
&quot;While the chain has come to appeal primarily to teenagers, Norguet wants to rebrand it as a place for families.&quot;

this guy obviously doesn&apos;t have kids then.
it&apos;s a great looking place and I like a lot of the details, but it certainly doesn&apos;t look like it fits his own brief. it looks like the design is just the usual mix of material and design detailing that appeals to designer eeedjits like us lot that read dezeen, but I don&apos;t think it would score much with a bunch of children. and as anyone with kids knows , if they are happy we are happy!
 Reply 
 Amandine says: at 3:30 pm 
You&apos;re universalizing American kids&apos;tastes with so much confidence…
Their toys look entirely different, their outfits look different, even the graphic and illustration styles on their favorite bed time stories are different, why would they be sensitive to the same design aesthetic?
 Reply 
 Marmaduke Wilture says: at 5:51 pm 
Just to help explane

definition of&quot;polishing a turd&quot;

The act of trying to make something hopelessly weak and unattractive appear strong and appealing. An impossible process that usually results in a larger, uglier turd.
 Reply Fiona Mathie says: at 10:04 pm 
It would never happen in Oz. Perhaps France can afford Norguet as they sell bier with their fries?
 Reply 
 martini-girl says: at 5:24 am 
You think? You obviously aren&apos;t a macca&apos;s customer. All of them are having an&apos;interior designers&apos;stamp being put on them now as they go through a&apos;revitilisation program&apos;. Quite a few architectural companies are involved and are being asked to deliver a different type of experience to the average user. The results have been quite interesting.
 Reply 
 jamiego says: at 12:59 am 
Design some independent cafes who sell products that don&apos;t rape the planet or exploit their employees or the supply chain, and then I&apos;ll listen. And that&apos;s not snobbery–it&apos;s ETHICS. Norguet should get some.
 Reply JeffK says: at 5:53 am 
Anyone know the grey cafe chairs( the ones with a real backrest)? Were they designed by Patrick Norguet, if so who for?
Thanks!
 Reply ANNA MARK says: at 7:35 am 
Looks good, however it still won&apos;t be a restaurant experience when the food is cheap, fabricated garbage…
 Reply Paul Lagerberg says: at 1:18 pm 
Bring back the disabled-/babycare toilets ! They&quot;went missing&quot;in the Netherlands !
 Reply davidgadd says: at 1:25 pm 
This mondrian esq style looks like its going to date quickly! Also solid colour bright upholstery–hope its not fabric
 Reply john says: at 2:53 pm 
Star Trek meets 50s diner–too sophisticated for kids to appreciate. I doubt the designer had any input to the food they sell–likely not much into the kitchen operation either–Clean and clinical, so as a retail environment it works for fast food service but it apprears to be a little off brand for McDs. Perhaps the designer thought he could be influential on the company……
 Reply Zane Baker says: at 3:27 pm 
Looks like the interior of IKEA
 Reply 
 Scribbs says: at 9:33 am 
I agree there is an Ikea vibe going on in there, he just forgot the ball park for kids to play in.
 Reply 
 Daniel Pecotic says: at 5:08 am 
I&apos;ve noticed how fancy McDonalds has been getting. There&apos;s one in Montreal on rue St. Catherine that this made me think of.
 Reply Adri Neuper says: at 8:40 am 
I see a lot of spaces for art to be displayed. Pottery etc. I like that.
 Reply Graeme Kennedy says: at 11:35 am 
McDonald&apos;s isn&apos;t exactly a concept which encourages you to stay and enjoy the cool surroundings. The hint is in the words&apos;fast food&apos;. People want to eat their food and get out as soon as they can.

Sure, they&apos;ve tarted up a few restaurants but this is proof as to how many billions the megacorp makes on an annual basis. They can afford to make a greasy spoon look like Pizza Express……
 Reply Chantal Verniest says: at 8:48 am 
Looks nice, like a MacDo schould look like but the ugly green logo does not match this interior……..BTW who was asking something about the food ?
 Reply Christopher says: at 11:39 am 
Interesting comments from people who probably know nothing about preparing meals for a fast food market..however that makes the comments all the more valid.

As A Designer I like the vibe and flow…almost a bit too upscale but clean. Maybe Mac should explore am alternative menu that would address the soybean crowd
could be interesting…form follows function with flair..and the menu usually follows what will sell…challenging! much Love!
 Reply Graphiste says: at 1:35 pm 
Amazing design but for McDo ! It will be better for slow food restaurant.
 Reply Joann says: at 4:49 pm 
I agree it does not look kid friendly. As to the food, estimates are now at over 247 billion served, they must be doing something right.
 Reply efj says: at 5:30 am 
I wonder what the designers first thoughts where when Micky dees first approached him. I&apos;m sure $ came into the picture but one can not help wonder how does one feel comfortably represent really bad food. Besides these thoughts Im happy to see his work though yet saddened to see who it is for.
 Reply Peter says: at 3:03 pm 
I really like the design of the order counter area but the rest seems like a grid nightmare to keep clean and misses out on the McDonald&apos;s brand–especially the attraction to families.
The McDonald&apos;s flagship design in the UK is great for this fast food&apos;restaurant&apos;. http://www.archithings.com/interior-designs-for-m …

Until the food gets better I wouldn&apos;t want the lighting reduced.
 Reply Rajesh says: at 6:24 am 
look is good but this is not good for Mc D, make a new design which is good for Mc D,
 Reply Mohammad Ismail says: at 6:18 am 
The dark confused cubbies have no clear function except to collect dust over time!
The finishes selection is fit for a Cafeteria and would not attract mature customers.
 Reply Sorin says: at 1:09 pm 
The food is still and will always be garbage.
 Reply john kretschmer says: at 12:02 am 
very pretty maintance nightmare! good industrial design should be pratical, and relate to the public it serves. The space is anything but family oriented…is starbucks next? I am an industrial designer
 Reply hilda says: at 3:17 pm 
i don&apos;t understand the&quot;storage&quot;elements (what are they storing in the dining area?) and the shelves throughout are going to be dirt/trash collectors…the calm colors are nice vs the usual vibrant/gaudy reds, oranges covering every surface.
 Reply Kimberly says: at 8:08 pm 
This doesn&apos;t read&quot;families&quot;at all. It reads&quot;business luncheon.&quot;Don&apos;t get me wrong, I actually think the design is really neat–sophisticated even, which is a strange word to associate with McDonald&apos;s. But nothing about it makes me want to bring my kids.
 Reply t says: at 5:11 am 
it’s time for the MCD food to evolve.
 Reply rock says: at 1:00 pm 
if the design doesn&apos;t kill ya, the food will!
 Reply John says: at 3:34 am 
Gorgeous designs, would love to see this guys work on a home interior rather than just commercial!
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
 Magazine Screen Jobs Wire Watch Store Book of Ideas 
 
Newsletter
 
 Magazine feed Screen feed Jobs feed @Dezeen on Twitter Dezeen on Facebook 
 
 Dezeen latest 


 
 Jobs latest 


 
 @Dezeen 


 
Ads by Google
 
 One of the leading B2B portals with millions of quality China suppliers (Swiss SGS certified).and their products listed online for global buyers to visit frequently.
Find construction products on Made-in-China.com. 
 
 ECVV.com is a product directory of qualified manufacturers, factories and suppliers. Search for targeted building and construction products on ECVV.com. 
 
 Buy high quality China wholesale cell phones , wedding dresses, baby clothes and other wholesale products directly from reliable Chinese wholesale suppliers on DHgate, and get worldwide delivery plus free escrow service. 
 
 
 
 Architecture Interiors Design 
 
 Featured city:
Paris 
 
 Featured architects:
MVRDV 
 
 Architecture categories 

 Skyscrapers Residential Public and leisure Cultural Offices Industrial Education Infrastructure Landscape/urbanism Hotels Health Pavilions 
 
 Interiors categories 

 Retail Residential Office interiors Restaurants and bars Exhibitions Salons and spas Hotels Health 
 
 Design categories 

 Furniture Products Homeware Fashion Watches Lighting Transport Graphics Installations 
 
 News: Kickstarter to launch
in the UK 
 
 News: Stonehenge Visitor
Centre under construction 
 
Features

 Slideshows Interviews Movies Podcasts Competitions Books Photography Green Media 
 
Events

 2012 
 Clerkenwell Design Week 2012 Cologne 2012 DMY Berlin 2012 London 2012 Milan 2012 Paris 2012 Stockholm 2012 World Architecture Festival 2012 
 2011 
 Beijing Design Week 2011 Cologne 2011 Design Miami/Basel 2011 Dezeen Space DMY Berlin 2011 Dutch Design Week 2011 Inside 2011 London Design Festival 2011 Milan 2011 Qubique 2011 Stockholm 2011 The Temporium 2011 Vienna Design Week 2011 
 2010 
 Cologne 2010 Design Miami/Basel 2010 DesignMarch 2010 DMY Berlin 2010 Graduate shows 2010 London Design Festival 2010 Maison&amp;Objet 2010 Milan 2010 Shanghai Expo 2010 Stockholm 2010 Tokyo 2010 Venice Arch Biennale 2010 Vienna Design Week 2010 
 2009 
 Cologne 2009 Design Indaba 09 DMY Berlin 09 Dutch Design Week 09 London Design Festival 09 Milan 2009 New Designers 09 RCA show 09 Shenzhen/Hong Kong 09 Stockholm 2009 Tokyo 2009 
 2008 
 Design Indaba 08 Design Miami 08 Design Miami Basel 08 Dutch Design Week 08 London architecture festival 08 London Design Festival 08 Milan 2008 New Designers 08 Stockholm 2008 Tokyo 2008 Venice Architecture Biennale 08 
 2007 
 Belgrade 2007 Cologne 2007 Design Miami Basel 07 Design Indaba 07 Design Miami 07 Dutch Design Week 07 Int. Design Forum 07 London Design Festival 07 Milan 2007 New Designers 07 RCA summer show 07 Stockholm 2007 Tokyo 2007 
 2006 
 Design Miami 2006 
 
 
Archive

 2012 
 January 2012 February 2012 March 2012 April 2012 May 2012 June 2012 July 2012 
 2011 
 January 2011 February 2011 March 2011 April 2011 May 2011 June 2011 July 2011 August 2011 September 2011 October 2011 November 2011 December 2011 
 2010 
 January 2010 February 2010 March 2010 April 2010 May 2010 June 2010 July 2010 August 2010 September 2010 October 2010 November 2010 December 2010 
 2009 
 January 2009 February 2009 March 2009 April 2009 May 2009 June 2009 July 2009 August 2009 September 2009 October 2009 November 2009 December 2009 
 2008 
 January 2008 February 2008 March 2008 April 2008 May 2008 June 2008 July 2008 August 2008 September 2008 October 2008 November 2008 December 2008 
 2007 
 January 2007 February 2007 March 2007 April 2007 May 2007 June 2007 July 2007 August 2007 September 2007 October 2007 November 2007 December 2007 
 2006 
 November 2006 December 2006 
 
 
 Dezeen Screen 

 Architecture movies Design movies Interiors movies Interviews Talks 
 
 Dezeen Jobs 


 
 Dezeen Watch Store 

 Shin Azumi Yves Behar Achille Castiglioni David Ericsson/VOID Naoto Fukasawa Denis Guidone Crispin Jones Ross Lovegrove Ross McBride/Normal Denis Guidone Industrial Facility Karim Rashid SANAA Uniform Wares Scott Wilson Michael Young 
 
 Movie: Design Products at Show
RCA 2012 with Tord Boontje 
 
 Movie: Ross Lovegrove at
Clerkenwell Design Week 
 
Recommended on Facebook
 Follow @dezeen 
 Dezeen Music Project:
featured track 
 
 Listen to all the tracks here » 
 
 Follow us 
 
 
 
 Dezeen Mail #109 
 
The latest issue of Dezeen Mail includes the best stories and comments from readers plus new jobs, competitions, movies and more.
 . 
 Read Dezeen Mail issue 109 | Subscribe to Dezeen Mail 
 
 Home About Submit a story Advertise Contact Newsletter Twitter Facebook RSS Data protection Copyright info 
 
 
 Are you looking for a job in architecture or design? Visit our recruitment site Dezeen Jobs 
 
 Dezeen Watch Store 
 
 Out now! Dezeen Book of Ideas
	</body>
</document>
