<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004418" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/walmart-employees-suck-one-of-them-scratched-my-car-gave-me-a-dirty-look-and-walked-away/" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="1" score="0.0018247501479957077" bingtitle="Walmart employees suck! One of them scratched my car, gave me a ..." webtitle="Walmart employees suck! One of them scratched my car, gave me a dirty look and walked away! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>So I walked to my car with my groceries to my car ... not bode well for those people who want to park ... Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Walmart - Bad customer service at Wally World! 3N2 Sports- Athletic apparel with excellent customer service! Glaceau VitaminWater review – does it taste better than Gatorade or Powerade and is it healthier for you? LASIKPlus Vision Center Tampa Florida review - a terrible experience and I have double vision in both eyes and constant migraines! Best Buy Geek Squad Accidental Warranty Complaint - Is It Worth The Extra Money To Purchase The Accidental Warranty? Hendrick Honda - Bad service and feeling ripped off! 5 Star Shine is slime! Turtle Wax works better and gives a better shine for a fraction of the price! New Lite headlight cleaning kit review - it really did restore my ugly, cloudy headlight lenses to new again! Comet Company Complaint - Purhased a Vaccum Cleaner And Didn&apos;t Recieve What They Stated In The Product Details Garmin Nuvi 1690 Compliment - Accurate and Dependable Garmin GPS System 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Walmart employees suck! One of them scratched my car, gave me a dirty look and walked away!
 By DenverChick 
I never knew the staff could be so rude at my local Wal-Mart! An employee scratched my car and no one cared!
 



I went to Wal-Mart today to go and pick up some groceries. I like Wal-Mart because it has low prices and it’s also very convenient to where I work. The only problems I usually have with Wal-Mart is its usually kind of hard to find a parking spot. It’s especially hard if it either rained or it’s going to rain or there is storm brewing of some sort.

I don’t what it is, but when it rains or there’s a storm everyone and their mother is out at the local Wal-Mart here in Denver Colorado. While something like that must’ve been going on today because the parking lot was packed full. There were also shopping carts everywhere. So I took one into Wal-Mart to use because I figured there wouldn’t be any inside available.

I went in and did my shopping and when I came out I saw an employee that pushed a shopping cart right into my car. As the employee approached me on their way back into the store they look down and ignored me. When I covered them about what I saw and that the shopping cart had hit my car they gave me a dirty look, muttered something under their breath and then proceeded to walk rate on past me and kept on going on into the Wal-Mart front entrance.

That was very rude right there. They just walked right on past me and didn’t care that they had pushed a Wal-Mart shopping cart into my car right in front of me. So I walked to my car with my groceries to my car to check it out and see if there was any damage. There was–there were two dings, some nicks and scratches. You could definitely tell when the shopping cart hit my car it must’ve been moving with some pretty good force when it hit it.

I put my groceries in my trunk and I won’t back into the Wal-Mart to talk to the manager. Here’s were I got upset. I was told that the manager was not in and that they would get the assistant manager for me. I waited and I waited. I must’ve waited for a good 45 minutes and no one came out to talk to me. So I went and asked around from several employees if I could speak to a manager or assistant manager.


 Your Ad Here 


I then overheard some employees say,“uh oh, that’s that bitch that thinks somebody hit her car.”I shouldn’t have to hear language like that in a grocery store from employees. All I was trying to do was talk to a manager because one of their employees had ran a shopping cart into my car. If you were a mistake on the employee’s part and Wal-Mart was willing to foot the bill for the repair I would have been perfectly fine with that.

But it didn’t look like that was going to happen here.  The managers are keeping themselves busy and trying to avoid me.  The employee that hit my car with a shopping cart avoided me and gave me a dirty look.  And the employees were snickering and talking behind my back calling or referring to me as a bitch.  This place is ridiculous.

 Looking to download the latest movie torrents safely? You need the best in VPN’s. You need to read this post! 

After about two hours I finally got to speak to someone whom claim they were an assistant manager and that they were extremely busy.  This person told me that Wal-Mart is not responsible for anything that occurs in the parking lot.  They then questioned me as to how I knew it was one of their employees that supposedly hit my car with a shopping cart and that it wasn’t a random shopping cart or another car or similar.

I told him I saw it with my own eyes.  They asked if I had in the witnesses to this and I said I saw it and the employee knows they did it.  At this the manager said they would be back and they never did come back.  What classy treatment I got today from the entire staff at Wal-Mart #3566 here in Denver Colorado.  What a classy place this Wal-Mart is.



 
Posts Related to Walmart employees suck! One of them scratched my car, gave me a dirty look and walked away!

 
 Walmart–Employees that suck!, Rude Customer Service and Untrustworthy Employees! 

// Everytime I have to go into Walmart I cringe.  The only reason I shop here is because its the only store in town.   I ...
 
 Wal-Mart Christmas trees review and complaint–their christmas trees suck! 

// I happen to be going to my local Wal-Mart for some groceries When I happened to notice that they had Christmas trees for sale ...
 
 Walmart cashier and customer service complaint–customer service at Walmart downright sucks! 

// I went to the Walmart the other day and saw that there was only a very few cash registers open and the lines were ...
 
 Wal-Mart employees selling and doing drugs while on the job! 

I went to my local Wal-Mart recently and saw several Wal-Mart employees out front on the left side of this store. There was a number ...
 
 Victoria’s Secret–A Store Filled with Rude, Ruthless, and Fashionless Employees 

// When I need to go clothes shopping, I usually head to the mall because there are so many different places.  Last week I went ...
 
 
 Tags: automotive , car , complaint , parking lot , rude , rude customer service , rude employees , rude managers , shopping cart , sucks , Terrible , unfair business practices , untrustworthy , Wal-Mart , Walmart , Walmart sucks 
 
One Response to Walmart employees suck! One of them scratched my car, gave me a dirty look and walked away! 

 wally on September 8, 2010 at 9:55 PM 

My philosophy on parking whether it be at Walmart or any store, you are better off parking away from the store itself. This saves your car from possible damage from other vehicles car doors or as we had, a bump in the rear panel. It has been my experience that Walmart has plenty of parking spaces and its developers always seem to have a good plan for parking.

I suspect your inability to get a close spot is the success of the company. Walmart is constantly busy and I am sure that does not bode well for those people who want to park close. I would hope that if you have a handicap or need for handicap parking, you would take advantage of applying for a tag. I have seen plenty of spaces in Walmart for Handicap parkers.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
