<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004136" url="http://jobs.oodle.com/careers/cleveland-area/restaurant-food-service-jobs/" time="2012-07-12-20:22" support="8" score="0.006276966689621711" bingtitle="Restaurant &amp; Food Service Jobs in Cleveland | Job Listings on ..." webtitle="RestaurantFood Service Jobs in Cleveland | Job Listings on Oodle Marketplace">
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001513" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000571" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000039" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000728" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001262" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>Consider joining our team at the Brookdale Place ... HAVE A DESIRE TO FURTHER THEIR CAREER IN FAST FOOD Restaurant ... Serve food in proper portions onto proper receptacles..</description>
	<body>
		Cleveland Area 
 
 Browse 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Post Sign In 
 Jobs 
 Home Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs More 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Login Ask Search Post Search Job &gt; USA &gt; OH &gt; Cleveland Area &gt; Restaurant/Food Service Find a Job in Cleveland Cleveland Accounting&amp;Finance Jobs Jobs Cleveland Advertising, Marketing&amp;Public Relations Jobs Jobs Cleveland Construction&amp;Skilled Labor Jobs Jobs Cleveland Engineering&amp;Product Development Jobs Jobs Cleveland Healthcare&amp;Nurse Jobs Jobs Cleveland Management&amp;Executive Jobs Jobs Cleveland Retail, Grocery&amp;Wholesale Jobs Jobs Cleveland Sales&amp;Business Development Jobs Jobs Cleveland Information Technology Jobs Jobs Cleveland Work from Home&amp;Self Employed Jobs Jobs Best Match 
 Best Match Posted Date 
 
Restaurant&amp;Food Service Jobs in Cleveland
 (1 - 25 of 265) 
 
 Bartender 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Sylvesters North End Grille · Canton, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Bartender Details Bartender exprienced only. SYLVESTERS North End Grill 4305 Portage Rd NW., N. Canton. See more Bartender Jobs in Canton …exprienced only. SYLVESTERS North End Grill 4305 Portage Rd NW., N. Canton Tools 
 X Tools Bartender Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 day ago on Monster 
 Convenient Food Mart 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Consun Food · Elyria, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Convenient Food Mart Details Convenient Food Mart CONVENIENT FOOD MART IS NOW HIRING Looking for Deli Managers, Shift Leaders, Cashiers and Deli Associates. Must be dependable, honest, and friendly. Some retail/restaurant background wanted. Drug Free Environment. Good Starting Rate. Must Be Able to Work Weekends/Holidays /Days/Evenings. Paid Vacations/Store Discounts. Part-time. Apply at: 5375 W. Erie Ave., Lorain 7580 Leavitt Rd., Amherst 42163 N. Ridge Rd., Elyria. See more Convenient Food Mart Jobs in Cleveland …CONVENIENT FOOD MART IS NOW HIRING Looking for Deli Managers, Shift Leaders, Cashiers and Deli Associates. Must be d... Tools 
 X Tools Convenient Food Mart Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 day ago on Monster 
 Cook 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Life Care Centers Of America · Westlake, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Cook Details COOK Life Care Center of Westlake, Ohio Full time cook position is available. Will work 3 day shifts, six a.m.-1:30 p.m. and 2 evening shifts, twelve p.m.-7:30 p.m. (EOE/M/F/V/D) Qualifications Food preparation background in a longterm care setting is preferred. Professional development We understand that you want to succeed not only as a person but also as a professional. This is why we are excited to grant requests for our associates to continue their education. Professional growth opportunities are available for you to advance your career. Benefits. See more Cook Jobs in Cleveland COOK Life Care Center of Westlake, Ohio Full time cook position is available. Will work 3 day shifts, six a.m.-1:30 p.m. and 2 evening sh... Tools 
 X Tools Cook Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 day ago on Monster 
 Food Services Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Central (Cleveland, OH) Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Food Service Worker Details About Trinity Cathedral: Trinity Cathedral is a church for all comers, a center for arts and music, a gathering place for those devoted to Cleveland and its future. Trinity Cathedral is a thriving urban community of faith. Our diverse congregation is committed to inspiring worship, thought-provoking education, dedicated service and determined advocacy. We invite newcomers to learn that when we say everyone is welcome, we really mean it.
The mission of Trinity Cathedral is to proclaim in word and action God’s justice, love and mercy for all creation. Trinity Cathedral is an Equal Opportunity Employer.
Position Description: Trinity Cathedral seeks an experienced and motivated individual for the position of Food Services Manager. The Food Services Manager position is a unique opportunity to showcase culinary and business skills within the environment of an outstanding facility and institution.. See more Food Service Worker Jobs in Cleveland About Trinity Cathedral: Trinity Cathedral is a church for all comers, a center for arts and music, a gathering place for those devoted t... eBay Classifieds User Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 1 day ago Tools 
 X Tools Food Services Manager Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Corporate Chef 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Chef Details Fine Corporate Chef needed now! 
 
We are growing and looking for a strong Corporate Chef. 
 
Are you that experienced, guest-oriented, cost controlling chef who has that ownership mentality? If you run a great kitchen, can achieve results through your people, care about the customer and know how to run numbers and build sales in a high energy environment, we want to recognize and reward you for your results! 
 
You will have the opportunity to use your 5+ years of multi-unit regional chef experience to lead and develop your team in a fun culture. This could be your big break!
 
Are you qualified to impact our concept as a heavy-hitting Manager with your strong leadership and management skills? If you can “bring it” to your store everyday and love to deliver excellent food and service, send your resume today!
 
Competitive salary ranging from $90-100k depending on experience, plus a great bonus program potential to an additional $10k! You get paid training and excellent benefits as well.. See more Chef Jobs in Cleveland Fine Corporate Chef needed now! 
 
We are growing and looking for a strong Corporate Chef. 
 
Are you that experienced, guest-oriente... 
Find out if you and Kim C. have mutual friends.
 Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 5 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Corporate Chef Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Applebee&apos;s Restaurant Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Applebee&apos;s · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Restaurant Manager Details WE ARE ALL ON THE JOURNEY TO LEADERSHIP! COME JOIN US! We’re looking for managers to staff our Cleveland and Akron area locations. Apple American Group LLC owns and operates approx 338 Applebee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar restaurants in Ohio, Indiana, New Jersey, Delaware, Pennsylvania, West Virginia, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Washington State, Nevada, California and most recently, New England. We have 38 restaurants in Ohio, many of them being remodeled inside and out. Coupling local empowerment with deep resources and high standards, Apple American Group strives to be the premier franchise group in the Applebee’s system. We offer. See more Restaurant Manager Jobs in Cleveland WE ARE ALL ON THE JOURNEY TO LEADERSHIP! COME JOIN US! We’re looking for managers to staff our Cleveland and Akron area locations. Apple ... Tools 
 X Tools Applebee&apos;s Restaurant ... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 day ago on Monster 
 Cook-Prep - Cleveland Airport Marriott (12000UFU) 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Jefferson (Cleveland, OH) Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Cook Details Are you ready to explore new challenges?
At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, co-workers who share your enthusiasm and clear career paths that offer experiences for growth and promotion. Whether you are a seasoned hospitality professional or just beginning to plan your career, we invite you to discover Marriott. 
Position: Cook-Prep - Cleveland Airport Marriott
Location: Cleveland, OH, 44135
Job Description
Cleveland Airport Marriott, located at 4277 West 150th Street seeks a Cook-Prep to join their staff. 
 Job Summary
 
 Prepare ingredients for cooking, including portioning, chopping, and storing food. Wash and peel fresh fruits and vegetables. Weigh, measure, and mix ingredients. Prepare and cook food according to recipes, quality standards, presentation standards, and food preparation checklist. Prepare cold foods. Operate ovens, stoves, grills, microwaves, and fryers. Test foods to determine if they have been cooked sufficiently.. See more Cook Jobs in Cleveland Are you ready to explore new challenges?
At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, co-workers... Marriott International Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 1 week ago Tools 
 X Tools Cook-Prep - Cleveland ... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Fast Track General Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | General Manager Details Immediate Restaurant Management Opportunities If you have 2+ years of full service background, we are currently seeking a results-driven manager with a passion for excellence for an exciting career opportunity. Growing National Restaurant Group (Fortune 500) *Opening 20+Units per year *General Manager Average $100k per year *Excellent Paid Training Program *Luctrative Bonus plan *5 Day Work Week *Medical/Dental/Prescription Drug Plan/Life Insurance, Starts immediately *Employee Discount *Paid Vacation *401(K) Savings Plan *Flexible schedules *No Late Nights Min requirement: -2+ years of Recent corporate or franchise restaurant background. -Salaried Management Only -Preference of no more than. See more General Manager Jobs in Cleveland Immediate Restaurant Management Opportunities If you have 2+ years of full service background, we are currently seeking a results-driven ... Tools 
 X Tools Fast Track General Man... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 21 hours ago on Monster 
 Restaurant Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Restaurant Manager Details Restaurant General Manager Opportunities 
RESTAURANT GENERAL MANAGER POSITION
Be part of the Evolution! 
There is something to be said about being part of something that continues to get better and better each day. Join our exciting, aggressive growing company. Our people are our greatest assets. This is an excellent opportunity for Restaurant Managers looking for a stable company with continuous growth, performance based advancement, and a balance between work and family life.
If this sounds like you and you have 1 years of restaurant and management experience, we want to hear from you!
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 
Email your resume to: (email removed)
Job Requirements
Minimum of 1 years (current) salaried Restaurant Management 
Stable work history with no more than 3 jobs in the past 5 years 
High volume experience (minimum $1MM/year) 
Strong operational background and ability to provide quality food and guest service 
Budget and cost control ability. See more Restaurant Manager Jobs in Cleveland Restaurant General Manager Opportunities 
RESTAURANT GENERAL MANAGER POSITION
Be part of the Evolution! 
There is something to be said ... eBay Classifieds User Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 2 weeks ago Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Manager Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Assistant Dining Director/Sous Chef 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Willoughby, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Sous Chef Details BRECKENRIDGE VILLAGE-GRACE WOODS-FOR A CAREER WHERE YOU CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE! ASSISTANT DINING DIRECTOR/SOUS CHEF Breckenridge Village, a leading retirement community in Lake Cty, is seeking a FT Assistant Dining Director/ Sous Chef for Grace Woods. Duties incl. assisting and overseeing the daily production&amp;service for our white tablecloth restaurant&amp;various catering events.Must possess a culinary degree with 5 years related experience, w/at least two years supervisory background. Applicant should possess a strong work ethic with an emphasis on customer service&amp;a desire to meet and exceed our residents needs and expectations. Technical skills a. See more Sous Chef Jobs in Cleveland BRECKENRIDGE VILLAGE-GRACE WOODS-FOR A CAREER WHERE YOU CAN MAKE A DIFFERENCE! ASSISTANT DINING DIRECTOR/SOUS CHEF Breckenridge Village, ... Tools 
 X Tools Assistant Dining Direc... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 day ago on Monster 
 Instantly Post Your Resume on 85 Top Sites! 

In about 5 minutes you&apos;ll be on all of the top sites like: Career Builder, Beyond, Job.com, and Dice. Post your resume today. 
 
 PartyLite Hostess needed 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Akron, OH Sales | Host/Hostess Details I need 5-10 PartyLite hosts/consultants for the Cleveland area. Hosts receive awesome perks like free product. If you choose to move up to the consultant level you earn great commission, amazing bonuses, paid vacations, and free product. If you are interested please contact me as soon as possible, my calendar fills up quickly with appointments.
Andrea C 
330-814-1648
www.partylite.biz/missandi. See more Host/Hostess Jobs in Akron I need 5-10 PartyLite hosts/consultants for the Cleveland area. Hosts receive awesome perks like free product. If you choose to move up t... Andréa C. · 211 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 3 weeks ago Tools 
 X Tools PartyLite Hostess needed Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Cook 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Louisville Eagles · Louisville, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Cook Details BREAKFAST&amp;LUNCH COOK NEEDED. Apply within Louisville Eagles, 306 W. Main St. See more Cook Jobs in Canton BREAKFAST&amp;LUNCH COOK NEEDED. Apply within Louisville Eagles, 306 W. Main St Tools 
 X Tools Cook Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 day ago on Monster 
 Experienced Servers and Bartenders 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Bartender Details Looking to hire experienced servers and bartenders immediately to work high-end events in the Cleveland area. Please have your own transportation and be professional as we are looking to meet the needs of very important clients. We need individuals who are able to pass a drug test and basic criminal background check. If you meet our high expectations then please submit your resume as soon as possible. Thank you and we look to hear from you soon!. See more Bartender Jobs in Cleveland Looking to hire experienced servers and bartenders immediately to work high-end events in the Cleveland area. Please have your own transp... eBay Classifieds User Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 4 weeks ago Tools 
 X Tools Experienced Servers an... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Kitchen Coordinator 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Laurel Lake · Hudson, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Kitchen Coordinator Details Kitchen Coordinator Laurel Lake is a beautiful retirement community nestled on 150 acres in historical Hudson. We are seeking a Kitchen Coordinator with 5 yrs background in Finer Dining cooking and 5 yrs background in a Kitchen Supervisory role. Years of background above required may be substituted for educational qualifications. In this leadership position, you will manage our Cooks&amp;Utility Workers and ensure high-quality operations through implementing your proven systems and hands-on staff development. Must be Serv-Safe certified. We provide a nicotine-free workplace environment with engaging staff and wonderful residents. If you share our core values. See more Kitchen Coordinator Jobs in Akron …Laurel Lake is a beautiful retirement community nestled on 150 acres in historical Hudson. We are seeking a Kitchen C... Tools 
 X Tools Kitchen Coordinator Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 2 days ago on Monster 
 Restaurant Managers------- 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Solon, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Restaurant Manager Details **** SEEKING EXPERIENCED FAST FOOD GM&apos;S and ASSISTANT MANAGERS FOR IMMEDIATE OPPORTUNITY ******
 * Looking for more stability?
 * Growth?
 * Better quality of life?
 Established Fast Food franchisee for proven fast food GM&apos;s for their new and existing stores in Cleveland, OH.
 Looking for candidates with 2-4 yrs of FAST FOOD GM experience or any other restaurant Management exp. 
FAST FOOD MGMT EXP HIGHLY PREFERRED!!!! Knowledge of P&amp;L, running shifts, food cost / inventory, a major must. Will also consider individuals with a combination of restaurant management and / or food / retail management background. 
Great benefits: Health and Dental insurance, 401K with co. match, and paid vacation).
 Local, paid training (8 weeks). OUTSTANDING QUALITY OF LIFE. 
GM&apos;s: 35-40K base + bonus (8K per year). 
Asst. Mgrs: 30-34K
 Local candidates ONLY. 
LOOKING FOR INDIVIDUALS WHO HAVE A DESIRE TO FURTHER THEIR CAREER IN FAST FOOD Restaurant Management.. See more Restaurant Manager Jobs in Cleveland **** SEEKING EXPERIENCED FAST FOOD GM&apos;S and ASSISTANT MANAGERS FOR IMMEDIATE OPPORTUNITY ******
 * Looking for more stability?
 * Growth... RestBizSol Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · Over 4 weeks ago Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Managers---... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Cook, Full Time 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Nas Recruitment Communications · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Cook Details HEALTH CARE Heartland of Holly Glen is now hiring and we need you to join our team! Cook Full time 2 Yrs as a cook in a large scale cooking operation and skilled/long term care or hospital experience desired. High-school degree or GED We offer great benefits including medical, dental and 401(k)! For more details please contact: Heartland of Holly Glen 4293 Monroe St. Toledo, OH 43606 Ph: 419-474-XXXX Fax: 419-475-XXXX E-mail: XXXX@hcr-manorcare.com Apply on-line athttp://www.hcr-manorcare.com/Careers.aspx EEO/Drug-Free Employer. See more Cook Jobs in Cleveland HEALTH CARE Heartland of Holly Glen is now hiring and we need you to join our team! Cook Full time 2 Yrs as a cook in a large scale cooki... Tools 
 X Tools Cook, Full Time Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 2 days ago on Monster 
 Restaurant Kitchen Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Kitchen Manager Details Restaurant Kitchen Manager Outstanding opportunity for career progression to include partnership programs! Generous benefits Package for Employee + Dependents- Health / Dental / Vision - Several plans to choose from Flexible Spending Accounts for Employee&amp;Dependents Retirement Savings Disability&amp;Life Insurance two weeks vacation to start Lots of extras -- Auto Insurance, Pet Insurance, Employee Assistance&amp;Hardship programs, and much more!
About the opportunity:
Patrice&amp;Associates has partnered with a dynamic, nationwide casual dining chain whose not just the exception - they are the rule! Their high-volume restaurants are famous for signature scratch-made foods. With employees, they are famous for treating people well, providing outstanding opportunities for career growth with generous benefits that are practically unmatched by any other company.. See more Kitchen Manager Jobs in Cleveland …Outstanding opportunity for career progression to include partnership programs! Generous benefits Package for ... Bret K. · 78 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · Over 4 weeks ago Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Kitchen Man... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Line Cook&amp;Housekeeper 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Lake House Inn · Geneva, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Housekeeper, Line Cook Details The Lake House Inn is accepting applications for a Line Cook&amp;Housekeeper. Please complete an application at 5653 Lake Rd, Geneva-on-the-Lake This job listing brought to you by The Star Beacon. See more Housekeeper, Line Cook Jobs in Ashtabula The Lake House Inn is accepting applications for a Line Cook&amp;Housekeeper. Please complete an application at 5653 Lake Rd, Geneva-on-the... Tools 
 X Tools Line Cook&amp;Housekeeper Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 3 days ago on Monster 
 Restaurant 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Lakefront Restaurant · Geneva, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Restaurant Details Lakefront Restaurant needs Experienced Day Cook, Prep Cook&amp;Waitresses Apply 2-5pm. Monday Thru Friday at 5243 Lake Rd., Geneva on the Lake, Oh This job listing brought to you by The Star Beacon. See more Restaurant Jobs in Ashtabula Lakefront Restaurant needs Experienced Day Cook, Prep Cook&amp;Waitresses Apply 2-5pm. Monday Thru Friday at 5243 Lake Rd., Geneva on the L... Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 3 days ago on Monster 
 Cooks and Servers 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Jefferson Diner · Jefferson, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Cook Details background wanted. Apply at Jefferson Diner, twenty N. Chestnut St. No Phone Calls. This job listing brought to you by The Star Beacon. See more Cook Jobs in Ashtabula background wanted. Apply at Jefferson Diner, twenty N. Chestnut St. No Phone Calls. This job listing brought to you by The Star Beacon Tools 
 X Tools Cooks and Servers Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 4 days ago on Monster What are your friends and neighbors
doing on Marketplace? 

 
 Porter 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Klaben Auto Stores · Kent, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Porter Details Porter – Full-time Klaben Ford Lincoln (Kent) is seeking a Porter – 40 Hour Work Week Summary of Essential Duties Transport customers, pickup up and deliver fleet vehicles to companies, clean service shop, remove trash, keep lot clean, maintain landscape, wash cars, inspect and receive new vehicles, perform other miscellaneous duties as needed. Job responsibilities Must have valid driver’s license and clean driving history; must obey all traffic laws while operating company vehicles. Must maintain neat and clean appearance; should be personable and properly represent Klaben Auto Stores due to direct contact with customers. Prior background desirable but not required. See more Porter Jobs in Akron …– Full-time Klaben Ford Lincoln (Kent) is seeking a Porter – 40 Hour Work Week Summary of Essential Duties Transport customers, pi... Tools 
 X Tools Porter Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 4 days ago on Monster 
 Restaurant Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Dave And Buster&apos;s · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Restaurant Manager Details Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s Westlake is hiring for an experienced Restaurant Operations Manager. All Managers will provide overall leadership, supervision and direction on shift operations along with specific department duties. Must have a min of three years of high volume Full Service Restaurant Operations Managerial background! $100,000 days. Multiple revenue streams. 300 employees. Performance-based bonuses. And countless ways to reach your most important career goals - with 1 twist: you&apos;ll actually love being a part of a worldclass restaurant and entertainment leader - Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s. Join a true pioneering company in redefining how great dining blends with fantastic gaming. See more Restaurant Manager Jobs in Cleveland Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s Westlake is hiring for an experienced Restaurant Operations Manager. All Managers will provide overall leadership, superv... Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Manager Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 4 days ago on Monster 
 OPEN INTERVIEWS! Associates 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Panera Bread/ Covelli Enterprises · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Open Interviews Associates Details *PANERA BREAD IS NOW HIRING* *HOURLY ASSOCIATES* Flexible Schedule Fun&amp;Positive Work atmosphere Room For Advancement! JOIN US FOR ON THE SPOT OPEN INTERVIEWS!!! *Tuesday July 10th&amp;Wednesday July 11th at Harvard Park From 9-12&amp;2-4 4103 Richmond Rd., Warrensville Hts., Oh 44122 *Thursday July 12th at Shaker Hts. From 9-11&amp;2-4 20060 Van Aken Blvd., Shaker Hts., Oh 44122 *Friday July 13th at Westlake From 9-12&amp;2-4 26137 Detroit Rd., Westlake, Oh 44145 *Monday July 16th at 7 Hills From 9-12&amp;2-4 7337 Broadview Rd., 7 Hills, Oh 44131 *Tuesday July 17th at Towpath From 9-12&amp;2-4 10037 Broadview Rd., Broadview Hts., Oh 44147 *Wednesday July 18th at Great Lakes From 9-12&amp;2-4 2000 Edgerton Rd., Broadview Hts., Oh 44147 *Thursday July 19th at Brecksville From 9-12&amp;2-4 8447 Chippewa Dr., Brecksville, Oh 44141 *Monday July 23rd&amp;Tuesday July 24th at Willoughby From 9-12&amp;2-4 36099 Euclid Ave., Willloughby, Oh 44094 APPLY IN PERSON OR FILL OUT AN APPLICATION ON-LINE AT WWW.p. See more Open Interviews Associates Jobs in Cleveland *PANERA BREAD IS NOW HIRING* *HOURLY ASSOCIATES* Flexible Schedule Fun&amp;Positive Work atmosphere Room For Advancement! JOIN US FOR ON TH... Tools 
 X Tools OPEN INTERVIEWS! Assoc... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 4 days ago on Monster 
 Restaurant Manager 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Rascal House Pizza · Cleveland, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Restaurant Manager Details Rascal House Pizza Company Description The Rascal House Pizza Café was established in 1980 opposite Cleveland State University in downtown Cleveland. From our beginnings as a place for Cleveland State Students to get a quick, tasty and affordable lunch, the Rascal House has, become the favorite lunchtime habit throughout the Cleveland corporate community. Over the years, the Rascal House has become a landmark - both&quot;geographically&quot;and as&quot;the place&quot;for great food and fun! Job Overview Company: Rascal House Pizza Location: Cleveland, OH (Downtown) Base Pay: commensurate w/background Position description Restaurant Shift Manager Looking to identify a strong Shift. See more Restaurant Manager Jobs in Cleveland Rascal House Pizza Company Description The Rascal House Pizza Café was established in 1980 opposite Cleveland State University in downtow... Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Manager Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 6 days ago on Monster 
 Food Service Specialist 
 Restaurant/Food Service · Army National Guard · North Canton, OH Restaurant&amp;Food Service Job | Food Service Worker Details Food Service SpecialistIts said that an army marches on its stomach. If thats the case, you can be the Soldier who keeps the Army National Guard marching on. In the Army National Guard, the Food Service Specialist takes care of the dietary and nutritional needs of fellow Soldiers, ensuring their expertise to meet the challenges before them. Youll learn how to plan and prep menus, how to prepare and serve food, and how to ensure food safety and facility sanitation, whether youre feeding 25 Soldiers or 2,500, in the field or in a fixed facility. And when your training. See more Food Service Worker Jobs in Canton …Its said that an army marches on its stomach. If thats the case, you can be the Soldier who keeps the Army Nationa... Tools 
 X Tools Food Service Specialist Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Marketplace User · 1 week ago on Monster 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 …of 11 pages Next 
 Find Listings on Oodle Marketplace Baltimore Jobs | Cincinnati Jobs | Colorado Springs Jobs | Dallas Jobs | Denver Jobs | Detroit Jobs | Fort Myers Jobs | Fresno Jobs | Grand Rapids Jobs | Indianapolis Jobs | Orlando Jobs | Phoenix Jobs | Sarasota Jobs | Winter Haven Jobs | Woodbridge Jobs .

Oodle Marketplace is a great place to find used cars , used motorcycles , used RVs , used boats , apartments for rent , homes for sale , job listings , and local businesses . 
SET LOCATION
 Cleveland Area [change location] 
Posted By

 Everyone My Connections 
 
Category 
 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets 

 All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals 

 All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Jobs Restaurant/Food Service 
 

 
Job Title

 Cook (53) Restaurant Manager (34) Food Service Worker (26) Bartender (16) Line Cook (16) Chef (12) Barista (11) Restaurant Worker (11) Host/Hostess (8) Executive Chef (7) General Manager (5) Dishwasher (5) Sous Chef (5) Kitchen Manager (4) Baker (2) Baker|Cook (2) Server - Cleveland Airport (2) Waiter/Waitress (2) Administrative Specialist (1) Bartender|Chef (1) Bartender|Line Cook|Shift Supervisor (1) Catering Coordinator (1) Catering Coordinator-Cleveland (1) Chef|Cook (1) Chef|Restaurant Manager (1) Contract Server (1) Convenient Food Mart (1) Cook|District Manager (1) Culinary Professional (1) Executive Chef|Production Manager (1) Food Runner - Cleveland (1) Food Service Worker|Outside Sales Representative (1) Food Service Worker|Production Coordinator (1) Food Service Worker|Truck Driver (1) Hourly Associates (1) Housekeeper|Line Cook (1) In-Seat Food Beer Vendor (1) Kitchen Coordinator (1) Kitchen Lead (1) Kitchen Manager|Restaurant Manager (1) Now Accepting Applications For (1) Open Interviews Associates (1) Panera Bread Associate (1) Panera Bread Hourly Associate (1) Porter (1) Restaurant (1) Sales (1) Server - Cleveland Marriott (1) Pizza Hut Team Member Restaurant Team Member Utility Server Banquet Assistant General Manager Carver Backup more choices ... 
 
Company

 Longhorn Steakhouse (10) Sodexo (10) Aramark (9) McDonald&apos;s (7) Army National Guard (6) Chipotle Mexican Grill (5) Marriott (5) Starbucks Coffee Company (6) National Guard (5) Panera Bread Covelli Enterprises (5) Brookdale Senior Living (4) Carlson Companies (4) Cleveland Clinic (4) HCR Manorcare (4) KFC (4) Knowledge Learning (4) Marriott International (4) University Hospitals (4) Gecko Hospitality (3) Job Chit Chat (3) Wyndham Worldwide (2) Applebee&apos;s (2) Brunswick Bowling&amp;Billiards (2) Caesars Entertainment (2) Embassy Suites Cleveland Rockside (2) Emeritus (2) IHG (2) Kindred Healthcare (2) LGC Hospitality Staffing (2) Robinson Memorial Hospital (2) Sage Hospitality Resources (2) Sylvesters North End Grille (2) Wine Tasting In Home (2) Akron Children&apos;s Hospital (1) Benihana (1) Bravo Brio Restaurant Group (1) Buffalo Wild Wings Grill&amp;Bar (1) Carrols (1) Catholic Charities Health And Human Services (1) Chili&apos;s (1) Chops Grille&amp;Tap House (1) Compass Group USA (1) Compass Group, North America (1) Consun Food (1) Cook Medical (1) Cuyahoga Community College (1) DCM (1) DNC Sportservice (1) Dairy Queen (1) Dave And Buster&apos;s (1) Pizza Hut Casting Boston Market HMSHost Red Lobster Olive Garden LocumTenens.com Giant Eagle Red Robin Restaurants more choices ... 
 Show all options 
Job Type

 Full Time (46) Employee (25) Part Time (23) Contractor Or Temp (7) more choices ... 
 
Refine By Keyword
 
Work Experience

 Less Than 1 Year (4) 2 To 5 Years (1) 
 
Required Education

 High School (11) None (3) 2 Year Degree (1) 4 Year Degree (1) more choices ... 
 Related Searches facilities and maintenance fairview park ohio job full time management executive near cleveland cleveland ohio job tv film musician cleveland ohio job counseling gates mills ohio job facilities maintenance strongsville ohio job Important
Safety Tips 
 Always meet the employer in person. Avoid sharing sensitive personal and financial information. Avoid employment offers that require a deposit or investment. 
 
To learn more, visit the Safety Center .
Report suspicious listings by clicking on .
 
 About Us Blog Help Safety Center Privacy Policy Terms of Use Send us Feedback 

 Add my listings to a Facebook Page Get Marketplace on your Phone 
 ©Copyright 2012 Oodle, Inc. All rights reserved.
 Job Search Enhanced by
	</body>
</document>
