<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004614" url="http://credit.org/blog/increase-your-personal-cash-flow-with-these-simple-tips/" time="2012-07-12-21:06" support="2" score="0.0026110547604280745" bingtitle="Increase Your Personal Cash Flow With These Simple Tips | Credit.org" webtitle="Increase Your Personal Cash Flow With These Simple Tips | Credit.org">
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>... did you eat a meal from a fast-food restaurant or convenience store? ... you use on any over-the-counter product. Then find the store’s ... Leave a Reply Click here to cancel ...</description>
	<body>
		QUESTIONS? CALL 1(800) 431-8456 
 
M-F 9am-6pm, Sat 8am-3pm PT
 
 Home Our Services Blog Contact Us Client Login › 
 
 Get Assistance Start Here About Us FAQ Services 
 Credit Counseling Debt Management Plan 
 Learning Center 
 Personal Finance Blog Online Courses Events and Seminars Guides and Downloads Videos 
 Tools 
 Financial Calculators Consumer Resources Email Newsletters Financial Terms Glossary Online Coupon Codes 
 
 Home / Credit.org Personal Finance Blog / Increase Your Personal Cash Flow With These Simple Tips 
Increase Your Personal Cash Flow With These Simple Tips

 Posted Jul 19 2011 by Melinda Opperman in  Money 
 
One of the biggest problems we see in financially distressed consumers is that people waste a lot of money on the little things. Naturally, most consumers, when buying a big-ticket item such as a car or appliance, are pretty good at getting quality for their money. They look at several different models and compare prices and features before making an informed and thoughtful decision.

Then, they go out and spend much more than they need to on items like clothes, food and entertainment – the less expensive, day-to-day purchases. And that really makes no sense because most of us spend the vast majority of our cash after our bills are paid on the little things. Imagine how much better you could do financially if you applied the same consumer skills to all your purchases as you did to the big ones.

For example, let’s start with food. How many times last week did you eat a meal from a fast-food restaurant or convenience store? Many people regularly eat all of their meals that way. Although each meal seems small, usually under five dollars, if you add it all up, you’re talking about ten to fifteen dollars a day. If you eat at a sit-down restaurant, you can add even more to that.

Now suppose we take just two days worth of these high-cost meals, approximately $20 to $30 in cost, and take that money to a grocery store. With that same money, you could easily buy enough food to feed yourself for more than a week. Sure, it’s a little less convenient, especially if you make your lunch at home and take it to work. But you can easily save $50 a week, just by eating out less often.  That’s over $2500 a year!

How about items around the house? The average consumer spends a lot of money on typical household items, so if you really analyze what you’re spending that money on, you can make a huge addition to your personal cash flow. For example, why spend up to 50 percent more on name-brand products when the generic store brand will do just fine?

Here’s a little experiment. Next time you’re at the grocery store, go to the pharmacy department and pick up the name brand you use on any over-the-counter product. Then find the store’s generic version of the same product and compare the ingredients. Chances are, they are exactly the same. So if you choose the name brand, you are in effect paying up to 50 percent more to help cover the costs for the marketing that helped you recognize the brand name in the first place.

The best way to save money around the house is to develop a vigilant attitude toward cutting costs, no matter how small. Turn lights out when you leave a room. Keep the thermostat higher in the summer and lower in the winter. Make long-distance phone calls during off-peak times, if you have to make them at all. And learn to do minor repairs yourself, instead of using a professional. Individually, these may not save you a lot, but if you add it all together, you’ll be amazed.

Overall, the best way to increase your personal cash flow is to be conscious of how much money you spend and why. Think about what you’re doing as a consumer, instead of simply reacting to impulses. You’ll see results immediately, as soon as you get serious about it.  And don’t forget to establish an emergency savings fund and contribute to it regularly.

Related articles:

 Tips to Increase Your Personal Cash Flow Why Pay Cash If You Can Barter? 5 Tips to Making Pet Ownership More Affordable Give Personal Finance Peace of Mind This Valentines Day Cash-Back Credit Cards Have Loopholes 
 
 Tags:   Blog Categories:   Money 
 
About the Author
 
 Melinda Opperman Melinda Opperman is an exceptional educator who lives and breathes the creation and implementation of innovative ways to motivate and educate community members and students about financial literacy. Melinda joined the Springboard team in 2003 and has over 19 years experience in the industry. Learn more about Melinda. View all posts by Melinda Opperman→ 
 Search for: 
 Help is a Phone Call Away 
 1(800) 431-8157 
 Credit.org offers credit counseling that can help you pay off your credit card debt faster. By calling us, a credit counselor can help you by first reviewing your income, all of your expenses, and debts you owe. After reviewing your budget situation and financial needs, your counselor will present you with your options and solutions to help you reach financial freedom.

 Get Started Now ›› 
 
Popular Blog Articles

 Should I get a loan to consolidate my credit card debt? Are You Addicted To Your Bad Financial Habits? HUD&apos;s Emergency Home Loan Program #infographic How to Get Your Free Annual Credit Report 
 

 
 Promoting Financial Literacy Since 1974 Search for: 
 
Credit.org
 
 Home How It Works Get Started FAQ’s Testimonials Site Map 
 Need Help? Call 1(800) 431-8157 



 
Our Services
 
 Credit Counseling Credit Card Debt Consolidation Debt Management Plan 
 
Free Resources
 
 Personal Finance Blog FIT Academy–Online Courses Financial Calculators Events and Seminars Downloads and Free Guides Video Gallery Financial Literacy Links Financial Terms Glossary Online Coupon Codes Email Newsletters 
 
Company
 
 About Us Contact Us Privacy Policy Terms of Use State Licensing Press Center 
 Additional Services: Bankruptcy Education and Certificates Foreclosure Assistance Reverse Mortgage Counseling 
 ©2012 Springboard Nonprofit Consumer Credit Management, Inc. All rights reserved. A 501(c)(3) Nonprofit Personal Finance Education and Counseling Organization founded in 1974.
	</body>
</document>
