<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004422" url="http://www.startupbizhub.com/how-to-start-a-halal-butcher-shop.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="1" score="0.002121454636253155" bingtitle="How to Start a Halal Butcher Shop - Startup Business - Innovative ..." webtitle="How to Start a Halal Butcher Shop">
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="88"/>
	<description>... and printing facility if possible) a till, counter ... i leave in Gaborone, Botswana. i would like to ... Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant; Starting a Hostel Business</description>
	<body>
		News   Franchise 
 68   
How to Start a Halal Butcher Shop


 Are you seriously dreaming and planning to start a halal butcher shop? Would you want to turn this dream into reality? Do you want to know how to plot and start a halal butcher biz? 

Let this article give you further insight and help as you start a halal butcher shop.

 

Who will be Your Halal Butcher Biz Clients?

Halal butchers primarily cater to people loyal to their Islamic beliefs. They sell meat specifically and meticulously prepared for compliance with Muslim practices and beliefs. By the word halal, the meat comes from slaughter houses which honor Allah. The slaughter is always swift and done once. The cut is made to the neck for full blood drain. Every animal and slaughter is made sure to be disease-free. An increase in the number of Muslims in various countries can be observed. Muslims are traveling and settling almost everywhere. This definitely means that halal butcher shop clients are many and prospects for this business are great and promising.

Muslim clients seek halal butchers specifically in their locality. It is because Halal butchers offer products not regularly found in common supermarkets and grocery stores. Even schools are one of the common halal butcher business clients since they are careful enough to make sure to have on their campus acceptable and reliable halal products for their Muslim students. Both government and private establishments have Muslims on their staff or work force. Expect well established companies (even the not so well established ones) to come to your door for halal products. Common halal products your buyers will get are samosas, burger patties, and various finger foods. Note also that having a halal butcher business License attracts more customers and clients.

What would be Part of the Startup Cost for Halal Butcher Shop?

The startup cost for halal butcher biz will vary depending on your budget. Know what the scale you would want your business to start with. Know this by first weighing your financial limits and constraints. Explore various sources of capital. After getting a good estimate of your seed money you can now work on developing a good and useful Halal Butcher Business Plan. Many items would be included in the computation of a startup cost for halal butcher business. Firstly, your product line must be decided. Determine the number and kind of products you want to offer for sale. If you have limited funds, begin a small scale business. Offer a few products initially. Offering too much too soon may cause you problems. Stick to items and products which you can actually deliver and supply to clients.

Determine your business location. Would you like to be located in a high end, middle end, or low end area? In deciding this, you need to know where the bulk of your consumers will be. Make sure the shop will be located in an accessible area. Keep the location visible. Dont be tempted to settle for the cheapest place to rent or own. The place must be an advertisement in itself. If people cant easily find you, your business will be at a disadvantage.



 &lt;&lt; How to Start a Fireplace Shop     How to Open a Hat Shop  &gt;&gt; 

68 Responses to &quot;How to Start a Halal Butcher Shop&quot;.
 1. gary smith on 11/8/2008 i would like to start my own small butcher shop here in bellevue, tn. do i have to hire a butcher to cut the meat or can i learn on the job myself? 2. JP on 11/8/2008 gary smith, it depends. if you are running with a limited budget then doing it yourself will get you more money. If you are also having less time to divert here then get it done by an expert is advised. At the end of everything, to have the detail knowledge on your business is always advised. If some day you are needed then you can simply jump to action if you ever learned how to cut the meat. 3. Tim Nolz on 3/2/2009 11:16:04 PM There is a vacant butcher shop close by that was closed down a couple of years ago and we had the idea of setting up a butcher shop there for the Muslim and Jewish people in Houston. My friend is a Muslim and knows a few Muslims that is encouraging to set up a shop. 4. kashif on 8/1/2009 4:27:34 PM Hi, i want to open a butcher shop in Manchester. i have 20000 to start with. just to make sure that, is this a reasonable money to start a butcher shop. i&apos;m these days finding a butchers shop on rent to start my business. Reply me soon. thank you. 5. karabo on 8/24/2009 9:32:10 AM Hi, i want to open a butcher shop. How do i go about doing that? money, license etc. please respond ASAP. 6. Mervyn Harris on 9/8/2009 5:13:18 AM Can you please advise what the average waste is in percentage terms from the preparation of the following :- Whole Lambs, Whole Pigs, and Sides of Beef, any information on what the average waste is from a typical Butchers Shop Cutting Room would be useful. Many Thanks 7. Gabe Smith on 9/11/2009 9:29:02 PM hello, i want to open a halal butcher shop and really don&apos;t know how to go about doing it. I have the vision and know what I want, but can you tell me where to start. I need to know how much money I need to start the shop, what I will need to start, and anything else I need to know to start. 8. Jahangir Shah on 11/6/2009 1:12:20 PM To start a Butcher shop you need at least the following items: 

1. a Cold room of a reasonable standard and size, enough to hang lamb, sides of mutton, carton of chickens etc. The smallest I&apos;ve seen is 4x6ft, costing around 4000 including fitting. Expect to pay up to 1000 for fitting if it&apos;s three phase and needs a board wired up, a lot less if you already have the circuitry.

2. You also need chopping blocks, knives, choppers, cutting saw, a mincing machine (or two) a set of weighing scales (with computer and printing facility if possible) a till, counter, display fridges, etc. Total costs for that depends on whether the items are new or used, expect to pay up to 12000 used, 30k + new. If you want be a pro butcher shop, sell frozen meat products and prepackaged meat products such as salami etc. you&apos;ll need a display fridge and display chest freezers, a couple grand each there. Then decorate your shop to your own taste/budget (remember, meat gets messy!!) and be prepared to work hard.

I&apos;m in the market to open a butcher shop and am looking for a location/reliable partner, so if anyone in Manchester/Northwest area (UK) is looking for a partner to get something set up on a budget, email me, jahangir_shah@hotmail.com 9. KHODOREL NATOUR on 2/17/2010 10:02:17 AM WE ARE LOOKING TO START UP OUR BUTCHER SHOP HALAL&amp;GRILL;, NEED INFORMATION AND DRAWINGS ETC. 10. sara on 2/18/2010 7:14:23 AM Hi, I would like to open a hallal butchery in mozambique, I&apos;ve no experience in this area and I would like to have some advise, which type of equipment can I use, for start the business. First I need to build the place, so how many compartments will need? Thanx in advance, Sara 11. dude on 3/15/2010 12:21:50 PM can you tell me how to start it better i need a little time to remember how to slaughter chickens and also learn how to kill cows with my machete 12. nima on 3/27/2010 5:03:26 PM hi i want to start a butchery business and i&apos;m searching a good muslim name please help. i&apos;m in kenya 13. Kali on 4/8/2010 2:15:18 PM we own a general/asian grocery store and would like to expand in selling halal meat to local asian and carribean community. We would probably buy used equipment. The size of the store is approx 25 ft x 15 ft with 2 storage areas. there is no access to the back just the front entrance. One which can be converted into walk in fridge and sink area. Do we have enough room to do this and is our shop suitable for this. Approx how much will it cost. How much profit is there in this and how much wastage will we have. Only looking to sell lamb and poultry and fish. Not sure about pork. Thank you and look forward to your response. 14. Masaemo on 4/22/2010 2:18:44 PM My business location will be in the city of st.louis, Missouri, USA. Well my question is if open a Halal butcher shop, where i would be able to get my raw products like sheeps, cows, and chickens? 15. lapologang molemele on 5/14/2010 10:30:17 AM i leave in Gaborone, Botswana. i would like to start up a butchery in my country. i have applied for funding to a tune of $12000. so i want to have the equipment and all necessary to start-up. quote me for all the required tools. i thank you in advance. hope to here from you soon 16. jalal on 6/7/2010 11:35:20 PM hello i want to know on how to start a beef slaughter house in sydney (avartwar) thank u 17. kimathi on 6/8/2010 8:53:36 AM Hi, I want to start a halal butchery within a medium town in kenya specifically for chicken. Please do advise on the viability and how to go about it. Best of regards. 18. esther on 6/16/2010 10:14:06 AM I would like to start a halal shop in Kenya, how much do I need? 19. oumaima on 6/19/2010 6:42:43 PM i have a halal butcher and grocery buisness in the uk. i would like to expand and enhance the premises...what do u advise to make it more attractive please? 20. Amanat Khan on 7/7/2010 11:41:02 AM I want to open a medium size Halal Butchers and a grocery shop in Stafford and would like to know what exactly equipment is required for me to start with as I can raise about 20000 to start if that is enough. I will want a 6ft x 4ft cold room. Thank you. 21. mpoki am on 7/13/2010 8:26:12 AM I want to open a medium size Halal Butchers in mbeya tanzania and I have only $1500 to start how I can go about 22. mubarak khan on 7/14/2010 6:34:05 PM Hello, I am planning on starting a halal butcher shop in Stockton, CA. I would be starting from scratch so would like to know what I would need to start this business. 23. md abu salek on 7/29/2010 10:46:35 PM i want to open a halal butcher in melbourne, victoria, australia close to railway station could you tell me is it right place for business 24. farid on 8/4/2010 4:41:01 PM hi, can anyone tel me how much roughly it cost to open a halal butcher in paris. many thanks 25. Khalid on 8/8/2010 10:23:44 AM HALAL BUTCHER SHOP IN CZECH REPUBLIC?? CAN ANYONE TELL ME WOULD IT WORK? I MEAN DOING BUSINESS IN PRAGUE? 26. Kh on 8/24/2010 12:08:20 PM I want to open Halal meat shop with asian groceries in Texas. I need to know what equipments are required? How to set-up the store? List of suppliers, distributors, and merchandising? Please respond... Many Thanks... Have a Blessed Day. Contact me... winback@gmx.com 27. bassam on 8/30/2010 4:06:04 PM My dad has a halal butcher shop and grocery. He is retiring and looking to sell the business asap. Very low price - Just asking for cost of equipment and setup costs + inventory. Located in Houston, Texas near Galleria, Stafford, etc. You can contact speeddemonforever at gmail dot com 28. Arifa on 9/14/2010 2:01:30 PM I would like to find out about how to go about starting a butcher shop in Richards Bay, Kwa Zulu Natal. Interested to know about the cost involved. Thanks 29. Jack Wanker on 10/4/2010 11:09:29 AM i&apos;m from india.. i&apos;ve plan to open butcher shop, to over come this how to plan to sell all meat and where to get orders and all.. 30. bilal on 10/13/2010 2:27:17 PM i have a butchers in manchester at the moment, i&apos;m having trouble keeping track of stock. I think someone has already asked about waste, but how much waste should i expect to get from a 3kg chicken if i&apos;m using breast, thigh and wings. how much would the carcus, fat and skin weigh? 31. mohammad hadayat on 12/3/2010 7:44:19 PM want to open halal meat market in sacramento,ca 32. Kaz Hussain on 12/4/2010 5:27:56 PM Hi all, Im looking to add a butchers section to my grocery shop, the problem is I have no idea how to start it and I have no clue about running a butchers, can anyone point me the right direction or is anyone interested in becoming a partner. The shop is based in Ilford, London you can email me on Kaz1_hussain@hotmail.com 33. Shaibu on 12/13/2010 2:30:10 PM hello my name is Shaibu i am here for helping the company of Halal as a butcher. I am from Ghana,Greater Accra Region.i will be very happy to be served as a butcher in your company and i hope u will give me the chance of working with u and i promise i will not regret when i am employed in your company thank u....this is my number if u are interested in me call me or mail me on yussif_shaibu2003@yahoo.com the number is 0260505011 or 0277795792.. 34. Abdul Sattar on 12/28/2010 7:10:35 AM Assalam walekum, i want to open a Halal butchery shop in Darwin, Australia. can you please guide me in setting up 35. hajira on 1/5/2011 12:26:11 AM I am interested in starting a butcher in The North of Johannesburg,South Africa, I do not have the funds but there is a great demand for Halaal meat, the Muslim community is growing in this area.Please advice on how do I go about it, and who should I contact. 36. nabeel riaz on 1/25/2011 1:51:09 PM hi, i want to open new meat shop in nelson at the moment i&apos;m working in meat shop. 37. Azz on 1/30/2011 3:51:34 PM Experienced Halal Butcher required. To start first week of FEB 2010
Based in, Stockton-on-Tees,UK azznaeem@hotmail.com 38. Jack on 2/4/2011 6:05:47 PM We are looking forward to exporting some halal meat from nz, at lease 1-3 container per week, anyone have any clue? Please email me: J.Li.2@massey.ac.nz Thanks in advance. 39. karim on 2/17/2011 8:07:07 AM salam, i am opening a halal butcher shop, but only i need a meet cutter, i cant buy a new one right now, any one know where i can find a used one 40. Syed on 3/4/2011 1:23:59 AM My Business Location is Brampton, ON Canada. I am looking for Installers to set up a Halal Butcher shop. Could some one guide in this regard? Thank you and Jazzakallah 41. Al on 3/21/2011 6:19:45 PM My company is based in Seattle, Washington US and seeking suppliers of organic halal meat and poultry. I am planning to open an organic/halal business - any guide is helpful. Thanks in advance. e.mansor@q.com 42. Sam on 3/27/2011 5:59:56 AM I am researching starting up a butchery in West Africa, I have been gathering resourcing needed to perfect the business plan and would be glad if I could be pointed to all I need in this regards, equipments, website, how to run butchery etc, looking forwards to responses 43. Razz on 3/27/2011 8:39:44 AM Hi, I would like to open halal meat shop in geelong, victoria, Australia. May I know how much do I need and how to prepare the business plan? 44. Laly Diab on 4/17/2011 12:16:31 PM We want to start a butchery in The Gambia and combine it with fresh vegetables and produce from our farm. We would like to produce sausages too. Predominantly though we want to provide affordable meat to the masses and the hotels. Please guide us on equipment, coldroom facilities and where we can find a fantastic halal butcher.. 45. ackson musakabantu on 5/9/2011 5:30:15 AM i want to start a butchery in lusaka garden compound, and i need free ideas on how to run this same business. so please you can send these good ideas to my e-mail 46. saleem khan on 7/13/2011 4:11:45 AM i want to start a halal butchery shop in canberra this year i want to no how can i do it and fresh vegetables and how can i get help to open one up 47. Ghazi on 7/16/2011 3:40:53 PM Hi. I am looking for an Arabic speaking business Partner to open up a Halal Meat/Food Shop in Church St area, Edgeware Rd, London. Email me on gpmgowan@gmail.com 48. Nawahl on 8/17/2011 5:26:01 AM I would like to start a Halaal butcher in the Greymont are in Johannesburg. There is a vacant shop available and i would like to know what i need to start this business please? Money, license ect. Thanks 49. christine on 9/12/2011 5:23:44 PM I&apos;m looking to open a halal meat shop in brampton, ontario canada. Do you have to be a male to open the shop, also do you have to be muslim? Please let me know where I can get more resources. Thanks 50. sarwar on 9/15/2011 8:48:18 AM To open Halal meat shop its not necessary that you should be Muslim but HALAL meat is that meat that butcher as per islam guide line and to do so butcher must be Muslim other wise that wont be HALAL
Sarwar (Dubai UAE ) sarwardar@gmail.com 51. Ishar Khalid on 9/22/2011 11:32:34 AM I am looking for Halal meat supplier in Darwin, Australia to supply to Singapore and also opening up a Halal Butchery in Darwin. I have a 3 years Provisional Visa to work/stay in Darwin starting Dec 2011. Need help/advice - my email : shirinishar@yahoo.com 52. anna m on 10/6/2011 12:13:25 AM HI I&apos;m interested in opening a butchery in barrie, ontarion canada. I have no knowledge in the business but know that there is a demand for what i have in mind. Could you please help me with how much you think I would need to get set up, where I can find more resources that my help me achieve my dream. I also probably would not afford to hire a butcher in the beginning so i would also like to know if there is somewhere i could learn to cut meat. thank you 53. khalid on 10/18/2011 6:42:28 AM Hello I&apos;m interested in opening a butcher, asian grocery and vegetable shop in pinner harrow london. I have no knowledge in the business but know that there is a demand for what i have in mind. Could you please help me how much do i need to get set up, where I can find more resources that my help me achieve my dream. Also need some help how to find out wholesale price of meat or some one know pricing of halal meat lamb, mutton chicken please email me. Thank you email. kmughal62@hotmail.com 54. Polly on 11/7/2011 1:43:58 AM Hi, I&apos;m interested to open a halal restaurant, but i don&apos;t have any idea before i start the business because i&apos;m not a Muslim. Does it a matter if i&apos;m not a Muslim? What do i need to qualify opening a halal restaurant in Korea? I heard it&apos;s not easy to open a halal restaurant compare with others. Is it true? Please reply me. Thank you!! 55. ismail on 1/11/2012 4:20:15 PM salam alaykom, Hello everyone,me and my wife are interested in opening a Halal butchery in Norwich England but we are new in this field so we will appreciate any information and advices please reply me : ismail_idissour_34@hotmail.com . jazakom allah khayran :) ismail . 56. Salah Elkhdar on 1/28/2012 4:57:27 AM I am a professional Head Butcher, Looking for halal job in U.S.A OR Canada, if possible. 57. ashfaq ahmed on 2/5/2012 1:05:32 AM Hi, i want to open a butcher shop in Auckland (New- Zealand). I have NZ$40000 to start with. just to make sure that, is this a reasonable money to start a butcher shop or I have to arrange more and how? i&apos;m these days finding a butchers shop on rent to start my business. Reply me soon. thank you. 58. Rashid Farred on 2/20/2012 2:39:58 AM Asalam alaikom, I am from South Africa, Johannesburg and are interested in opening a business, but I am new to this field so I would appreciate any information and advice. 59. ayesha on 2/20/2012 9:09:05 AM what are the risk of starting a halaal business in a non-halaal area? in this area there are no butchers at all...am i going in the right direction...cause i have a limited time to submit my business plan ..do you have any tips concerning the business plan? 60. cabdi fataax on 2/25/2012 4:21:16 AM I am interested in opening up a halal butcher in mn usa as we have big muslim community how do i go by opening one? what do i need as far as permit and licensing and also where do one get the live stock? is it possible to slaughter in town or does it have to be done in the farm area. what will be the cost of starting up such business? i am eager to know as i am sure there is profit in it because of the large muslim community thank you. any info will appreciate 61. francis richard on 3/2/2012 9:17:55 AM I m looking for cheap butcher equipment i don&apos;t mind second hard( butcher Saw, cold room, freezer and more...) please any help let me know..Thank you 62. General Manager on 3/5/2012 7:11:56 PM I&apos;m in a process of buying a running halal meat&amp;grocery store in a suburban city east of New York. I&apos;m aware of much of the paper work required by the town or county, but I still look forward for some tips. Please feel free to email me for any info at ashcorp@hotmail.com. Thanks 63. Asif on 3/21/2012 11:52:55 AM Hi, I am looking for a halal meat shop in east London to setup and I have 15,000-20,000 to invest in the business do you think it is enough ? also do you think it would be in my interest to open a meat shop nearby the muslim community area but they already have few halal meat shop doing very good business. thank you in advance my email address is arsel4been@hotmail.com 64. Nadir on 3/22/2012 2:30:04 PM I am planning to open halal meat shop/general food item store at the place has 2800 sqft. area. Could you give me the information where i can get used equipment like, cold room, cooler, freezers, cutting saw, machine for beef to ground. thanks Nz 65. James on 3/23/2012 4:22:48 AM 
@Nadir, you haven&apos;t mentioned about the place of this business. No matter which country you belongs to try ebay and craigslist for buying pre-owned equipments. You can also try some of your country specific websites for buying these.
 
Jestin James
Startup Biz Hub - Senior Advisor (Staff)
 66. ABDUL on 3/27/2012 1:41:46 PM I have already taken a shop on rent in Indranagar, Bangalore state of Karnataka in INDIA. The shop is located on the main road in a market place and the area has mixed population consisting of High, Middle, lower middle and lower category people. I have almost completed the interiors such as granite flooring,rectified wall tiles false cealing of plaster of paris and fittings etc.,Wherein i have planned to start fresh chicken, sea food sheep meat and chicken eggs. Pl advise me on how to place all items and where i can get good butcher equipments at a reasonable price in my city of Bangalore-India. The shop is &apos;L&apos; shaped with a road face of 10 feet and depth of 22feet and on the right it has an opening of 2.5feet and approx. an area of 110sqft which i have reserved for cutting and cleaning of chicken, and the chicken area has an opening of 2.5feet from the side lane too. The shop is due to open in about 5 days. Pl. advise me with ur valuable comments at the earliest including advise on the design and view of the name board. For ur Information i have registered the name of the shop as FRESH FARMERS CATCH IMPEX LLP. Awaiting ur valued comments.
Thanks&amp;Regards! Abdul Raqueeb Jaleel bangaloreproperties@in.com
+919448382524 67. Rahzak on 4/24/2012 4:39:57 AM salaam i want to open a halaal butcher ,dont no anything about the industry ,but there is a demand in the area,can anyone help with info 68. Anuar on 4/25/2012 3:06:32 PM Hi all... my name is anuar n from Malaysia (well known as halal hub)
I was reading and hope this explanation will help you all.
1. the butcher must be Islam, or else it won&apos;t be halal food. that all.
2. you don&apos;t have to be Muslim to open shop or restaurant or else that meet criteria of halal. Christian, budha, Hindu, or else also can..
3. you cannot mix halal and non halal food together in your cook. for example:
- pork (non halal) with chicken (halal) cook together in same cooking pots/plate. = non halal.
-alcohol ((non halal) wain, bear or else that contain alcohol) cook together with chicken (halal) = non halal.
-chicken ( non halal) cook together with chicken (halal) = non halal.
conclusions is every non halal food that mix together with halal food they will be non halal food..
there should be more.. I just can&apos;t think right now.. so for more info or Q .. just mail me at kuzie_ggr@yahoo.com fb
super.afro@hotmail.com 
kuzie_ggr@yahoo.com || Halal Butcher Shop Business Consultant
 
 Name: 
 Email: 
 Comment: 
 Write your business location to help you better. Exp: City, State, Country 
 ( All the above fields are required. ) 
 

 Sign up for Newsletter 
Restaurant Business

 How to Start an Indian Restaurant Business Juice and Smoothie Bar Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant Starting a Hostel Business Startup Sushi Restaurant 

Mobile Business Ideas

 How to Start Mobile Catering How to Start Your Own Charter Fishing Business How to Start a Mobile Spa Business Mobile Detailing Business Startup Kit How to Start Mobile Notary Business 

Farming Business Ideas

 How to Start a Poultry Farm Starting Chicken Farm Business Starting a Dairy Farm Business How to Start a Fish Farming Business Start a Rabbit Farm 

Service Business Ideas

 Starting a Recruitment Agency How to Start a Courier Business Starting Your Own Money Lending Business Starting Your Own Guest House Business Starting Your Own Computer Training Center 
 
 Advice for Small Business Business Insurance Information Business Marketing and Advertising Entrepreneur Business Idea Farming Business Ideas Financing a Small Business Free Business Ideas Home Based Business Opportunity Ideas for Small Business Instructor Guides Internet Business Ideas Professional Career Opportunities Repair Business Opportunity Restaurant Business Opportunities Retail Store Ideas Rural Business Opportunities Service Business Ideas Shop Business Ideas Small Business Articles Small Business Opportunities Small Manufacturing Business Starting Rental Business Startup Company Ideas Store Business Opportunities Tips for Buying and Selling Unique Business Opportunities Wholesale Business Opportunities 

Small Business Ideas

 How to Start a Towing Business How to Start a Trucking Business Starting a Taxi Business How to Start a Movie Theater How to Start a Shoe Business 

Small Business Articles

 How to Start a Gas Station How Much Does it Cost to Charter a Private Jet Starting a Night Club How Do You Calculate The Mark Up Price 

Home Based Business

 Starting a Home Health Agency How to Start a Home Baking Business Starting a Funeral Home Business Ideas for Home Based Business Starting a Woodworking Business 

Shop Business Ideas

 Starting a Pawn Shop Business How to Start a Meat Shop How to Start a Donut Shop How to Open a Sandwich Shop How to Start Auto Body Shop 

Store Business Opportunities

 Starting a Grocery Store Business Starting a Fashion Clothing Store How to Open a Liquor Store How to Start a Beauty Supply Store How to Start a Drug Store Business 

Startup Company Ideas

 How to Start a Tour Company How to Start a Security Company Start a Cosmetics Company How to Start a Skateboard Company Starting Your Own Repossession Company 
 Copyright©2007 - 2012 StartupBizHub.com. All Rights Reserved.
 About Us | Privacy | Contact Us 
 Site Map
	</body>
</document>
