<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004292" url="http://www.freepatentsonline.com/7349871.html" time="2012-07-12-20:32" support="9" score="0.012141821553048915" bingtitle="Methods for purchasing of goods and services - Fujitsu Limited" webtitle="Methods for purchasing of goods and services - Fujitsu Limited">
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>Each bank that issues a credit card will issue it&apos;s own ... the device 102 displays a message to the user to put ... These receipts do not contain actual account numbers and ...</description>
	<body>
		A SumoBrain Solutions Company 
 GO TO ADVANCED SEARCH 
 Home | Search | Communities | Products&amp;Services | About Us | Help 

 Login Sign Up 
 Title: Methods for purchasing of goods and services United States Patent 7349871 Abstract: A method for conducting a purchasing agreement for goods and services between a consumer and a merchant through a trusted a third party and using a wireless network includes generating, by the consumer, a first view of the agreement and transmitting the first view of the agreement to the third party, generating, independently by the merchant, a second view of the agreement and transmitting the second view of the agreement to the third party, and receiving, by the third party the consumer view of the agreement and the merchant view of the agreement, verifying identities of the merchant and the consumer and that the details of the independently generated views of the agreements are consistent and taking action to execute the purchasing agreement if the conditions are satisfied. The third party includes a Secure Transaction Server. 
 
 Inventors: Labrou, Yannis (Baltimore, MD, US)
Ji, Lusheng (Silver Spring, MD, US)
Agre, Jonathan Russell (Brinklow, MD, US)
 Application Number: 10/628584 Publication Date: 03/25/2008 Filing Date: 07/29/2003 Export Citation: Click for automatic bibliography generation Assignee: Fujitsu Limited (Kawasaki, JP)
 Primary Class: 705/26.35 Other Classes: 705/26.44, 705/26.8, 705/27.1, 705/75, 705/76, 705/80 International Classes: G06Q20/00 Field of Search: 235/379, 705/75, 713/170, 705/26, 705/76, 235/380, 380/277, 705/27, 705/80, 713/150, 705/1, 380/28, 705/50 View Patent Images: Download PDF 7349871         PDF help US Patent References: 
 7239346 System and architecture that supports a multi-function semiconductor device between networks and portable wireless communications products July, 2007 Priddy 7167844 Electronic menu document creator in a virtual financial environment January, 2007 Leong et al. 20060266823 Authentication method and system for use in vending a restricted product or service November, 2006 Passen et al. 20060229988 Card settlement method using portable electronic device having fingerprint sensor October, 2006 Oshima et al. 7003499 Service activation by virtual prepaid card February, 2006 Arditti et al. 705/67 6957334 Method and system for secure guaranteed transactions over a computer network October, 2005 Goldstein et al. 713/170 20050194452 Credit card and a secured data activation system September, 2005 Nordentoft et al. 6931431 Agreement and atomic broadcast in asynchronous networks August, 2005 Cachin et al. 6926200 Electronic cashless system August, 2005 Hayashida 6915951 Electronic cashless system July, 2005 Hayashida 20050122209 Security authentication method and system June, 2005 Black 20040234117 Electronic transaction verification system November, 2004 Tibor 6817521 Credit card application automation system November, 2004 Matada 6775777 Secure system using images of only part of a body as the key where the part has continuously-changing features August, 2004 Bailey 6766453 Authenticated diffie-hellman key agreement protocol where the communicating parties share a secret key with a third party July, 2004 Nessett et al. 20040104268 Plug in credit card reader module for wireless cellular phone verifications June, 2004 Bailey 6715679 Universal magnetic stripe card April, 2004 Infosino 6687375 Generating user-dependent keys and random numbers February, 2004 Matyas et al. 20030174049 Wearable identification appliance that communicates with a wireless communications network such as bluetooth September, 2003 Beigel et al. 20030123667 Method for encryption key generation July, 2003 Weber et al. 20030061486 Electronic commerce information processing system and method March, 2003 Shibuya et al. 713/170 6529885 Methods and systems for carrying out directory-authenticated electronic transactions including contingency-dependent payments via secure electronic bank drafts March, 2003 Johnson 705/64 6512919 Electronic shopping system utilizing a program downloadable wireless videophone January, 2003 Ogasawara 20020196944 Systems and methods for licensing and providing selective access to network applications December, 2002 Davis et al. 380/277 20020176579 Location-based services using wireless hotspot technology November, 2002 Deshpande et al. 20020163421 Personal fingerprint authentication method of bank card and credit card November, 2002 Wang et al. 6470448 Apparatus and method for proving transaction between users in network environment October, 2002 Kuroda et al. 20020107791 Method and apparatus for performing a credit based transaction between a user of a wireless communications device and a provider of a product or service August, 2002 Nobrega 20020107007 Method for wireless telephony payment and an apparatus therefor August, 2002 Gerson 6435406 Remote ordering device August, 2002 Pentel 20020097867 Communication system July, 2002 Bartram 20020095296 Technique for improved audio compression July, 2002 Hind et al. 20020087869 System and method of authenticating a credit card using a fingerprint July, 2002 Kim 20020087534 Agreement management system and method July, 2002 Blackman et al. 20020082925 Method and apparatus for utilizing a smart card to maintain a retail application on a number of portable, wireless hand-held computing devices June, 2002 Herwig 20020077993 Method and system for conducting wireless payments June, 2002 Immonen et al. 20020077974 Wireless point of sale June, 2002 Ortiz 20020073024 System and methods of using wireless communication devices to conduct financial transactions June, 2002 Gilchrist 6405314 Secure system using images of only part of a body as the key where the part has continuously-changing features June, 2002 Bailey 6378775 Electronic cashless system April, 2002 Hayashida 6378073 Single account portable wireless financial messaging unit April, 2002 Davis 6377692 Method and system for controlling key for electronic signature April, 2002 Takahashi et al. 380/277 6366893 System, a method and an apparatus for performing an electric payment transaction in a telecommunication network April, 2002 Hannula et al. 6356752 Wireless telephone as a transaction device March, 2002 Griffith 20020018585 System and method for cardless secure credit transaction processing February, 2002 Kim 20020017561 Electronic payment system using accounting function in a mobile communication network February, 2002 Tomoike 6334575 Safety transaction method January, 2002 Su-Hui 20010053239 Credit card fraud elimination system December, 2001 Takhar 20010045458 BIOMETERIC SYSTEM FOR VERIFYING THE USER OF A CREDIT/IDENTIFICATION CARD BY A MINIATURE AUTONOMOUS FINGERPRINT CAPTURE AND VERIFICATION SYSTEM November, 2001 Polansky 20010037264 Payment for network-based commercial transactions using a mobile phone November, 2001 Husemann et al. 20010034670 Direct point of presence distribution system and method October, 2001 Blair 20010010723 KEY RECOVERY PROCESS USED FOR STRONG ENCRYPTION OF MESSAGES August, 2001 Pinkas 6270011 Remote credit card authentication system August, 2001 Gottfried 6263436 Method and apparatus for simultaneous electronic exchange using a semi-trusted third party July, 2001 Franklin et al. 6257487 Electronic cashless system July, 2001 Hayashida 20010005840 Authentication in a telecommunications network June, 2001 Verkama 20010004231 Secure system using images of only part of a body as the key where the part has continuously-changing features June, 2001 Bailey 6226752 Method and apparatus for authenticating users May, 2001 Gupta et al. 6212290 Non-minutiae automatic fingerprint identification system and methods April, 2001 Gagne et al. 6199099 System, method and article of manufacture for a mobile communication network utilizing a distributed communication network March, 2001 Gershman et al. 6182892 Smart card with fingerprint image pass-through February, 2001 Angelo et al. 6175923 Secure system using images of only part of a body as the key where the part has continuously-changing features January, 2001 Bailey 6175922 Electronic transaction systems and methods therefor January, 2001 Wang 6137884 Simultaneous electronic transactions with visible trusted parties October, 2000 Micali 6115601 Payment scheme for a mobile communication service September, 2000 Ferreira 6098053 System and method for performing an electronic financial transaction August, 2000 Slater 6069969 Apparatus and method for electronically acquiring fingerprint images May, 2000 Keagy et al. 6067621 User authentication system for authenticating an authorized user of an IC card May, 2000 Yu et al. 6044388 Pseudorandom number generator March, 2000 DeBellis et al. 6010068 Credit document connected to a document or customized card, independent customized credit card and associated issuance and validation equipment January, 2000 Bozzo 6006328 Computer software authentication, protection, and security system December, 1999 Drake 6003767 Cashless medium for an electronic cashless system December, 1999 Hayashida 6003762 Transaction terminal for an electronic cashless system December, 1999 Hayashida 5949043 Electronic cashless system September, 1999 Hayashida 5917168 System and method for revaluation of stored tokens in IC cards June, 1999 Nakamura et al. 5869822 Automated fingerprint identification system February, 1999 Meadows, II et al. 5790677 System and method for secure electronic commerce transactions August, 1998 Fox et al. 5732148 Apparatus and method for electronically acquiring fingerprint images with low cost removable platen and separate imaging device March, 1998 Keagy et al. 5666420 Simultaneous electronic transactions September, 1997 Micali 5644118 Electronic cashless system July, 1997 Hayashida 5631961 Device for and method of cryptography that allows third party access May, 1997 Mills et al. 5598474 Process for encrypting a fingerprint onto an I.D. card January, 1997 Johnson 5485312 Optical pattern recognition system and method for verifying the authenticity of a person, product or thing January, 1996 Horner et al. 5465328 Fault-tolerant transaction-oriented data processing November, 1995 Dievendorff et al. 5363453 Non-minutiae automatic fingerprint identification system and methods November, 1994 Gagne et al. 5256863 In-store universal control system October, 1993 Ferguson et al. 5239166 Secure data interchange system erasing a card memory upon an invalid response August, 1993 Graves 5194289 Method for labeling an object for its verification March, 1993 Butland 5095194 Holographic credit card with automatical authentication and verification March, 1992 Barbanell 4882195 Method for labeling an object for its verification November, 1989 Butland 4636622 Card user identification system January, 1987 Clark 4582985 Data carrier April, 1986 Lofberg 4253086 Process and apparatus for positive identification of customers February, 1981 Szwarcbier 4182261 Credit card printer for fingerprints and solutions January, 1980 Smith, III et al. 
 Foreign References: 
 EP1120761 August, 2001 Payment execution device for cashless payment and method for executing a cashless payment EP1178444 February, 2002 Electronic payment using SMS EP1237132 September, 2002 Electronic transactions EP1237133 September, 2002 Electronic transactions by means of a wireless interface EP1237134 September, 2002 Electronic transactions EP1388797 February, 2004 Methods, apparatus and framework for purchasing of goods and services GB2386236 September, 2003 JP2000207483 July, 2000 JP2000269957 September, 2000 JP2002259621 September, 2002 KR2000-0068758 November, 2000 97 November, 1997 WO/1998/025371 June, 1998 PORTABLE ELECTRONIC AUTHORIZATION DEVICES AND METHODS THEREFOR WO/1998/037524 August, 1998 TRANSACTION METHOD USING A MOBILE DEVICE WO/2000/046959 August, 2000 SERVICE CARD TRANSACTIONS OVER A WIRELESS LAN WO/2001/001361 January, 2001 SECURE TRANSACTION SYSTEM 01 May, 2001 WO/2001/080133 October, 2001 SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR WIRELESS PURCHASES OF GOODS AND SERVICES WO/2001/098854 December, 2001 SYSTEM TO SUPPORT MOBILE VISUAL COMMUNICATIONS WO/2002/007117 January, 2002 METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR FACILITATION OF WIRELESS E-COMMERCE TRANSACTIONS WO/2002/011082 February, 2002 ELECTRONIC PAYMENT TRANSACTION VIA SMS WO/2002/013151 February, 2002 ELECTRONIC PAYMENT DEVICE USING A CONSUMER APPARATUS AND A TRADER APPARATUS COMMUNICATING THROUGH WIRELESS LINK WO/2002/027421 April, 2002 GLOBAL DATA NETWORK USING EXISTING WIRELESS INFRASTRUCTURES WO/2002/027439 April, 2002 METHOD FOR SIMPLIFIED ONE-TOUCH ORDERING OF GOODS AND SERVICES FROM A WIRED OR WIRELESS PHONE OR TERMINAL WO/2002/029708 April, 2002 WIRELESS REMOTE ORDERING DEVICE WO/2002/029739 April, 2002 METHOD AND APPARATUS FOR PERFORMING A CREDIT BASED TRANSACTION BETWEEN A USER OF A WIRELESS COMMUNICATIONS DEVICE AND A PROVIDER OF A PRODUCT OR SERVICE WO/2002/041271 May, 2002 ELECTRONIC PAYMENT AND ASSOCIATED SYSTEMS WO/2002/043020 May, 2002 METHOD AND DEVICE FOR THE TRANSMISSION OF DATA BY MOBILE TELEPHONE IN CASHLESS ELECTRONIC PAYMENTS WO/2002/054655 July, 2002 WIRELESS FINANCIAL TRANSACTIONS 02 August, 2002 WO/2002/067534 August, 2002 REMOTE ELECTRONIC PAYMENT SYSTEM 
 Other References: Deborah Bach, “CIBC Makes Long-Term Case for Wireless” [online], American Banker, vol. 167, No. 65, Apr. 5, 2002 (2 pages) [retrieved on Aug. 2, 2002]. Retrieved from the Internet:
	</body>
</document>
