<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004749" url="http://jacksonville.citysearch.com/profile/35744240/st_augustine_fl/chick_fil_a.html" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="5" score="0.005759657785089059" bingtitle="Chick-Fil-A - St. Augustine, FL, 32084 - Citysearch" webtitle="Chick-Fil-A - St. Augustine, FL, 32084 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>In Short – This fast-food restaurant lures diners with the promise of ... Even on their &quot;free food day&quot; (save the receipt to receive the same order any day ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Jacksonville, FL Metro &gt; Restaurants &gt; Chick-Fil-A 
Chick-Fil-A
 (904) 810-2201 
 1752 US 1 South , St. Augustine , FL | Directions  
 32084 29.865701 -81.322801 View Website 
 Menu Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 50 % 100 2 2 Votes Add a Photo Cuisine: Fast Food , Chicken Price: $ Categories: Restaurants 
 View More 
 Restaurant Special Features: Cheap Eats , Carry Out , Lunch Spot Payment Methods: MasterCard, Discover, Visa, American Express 
 View Less 
 Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (2) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Chick-Fil-A 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Chick-Fil-A
 Recommends CrssaFox Joined 3 years ago 5.0 November 07, 2009 
 Wonderful Service. This Chick-Fil-A location is always well-staffed. Even on their&quot;free food day&quot;(save the receipt to receive the same order any day that month) they had plenty of help to handle the insane crowds. We always get our food in a timely manner, and the dining room is always well-kept and clean.

A great location with friendly service - the only&quot;down side&quot;is that there can be large crowds any night of the week. But that just goes to show how great this restaurant is! :) … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend Contributor Joined 9 years ago July 29, 2005 
 No bones about it: crispy chicken sandwiches, buttered biscuits and signature waffle fries.. In Short 
This fast-food restaurant lures diners with the promise of fresh ingredients and a dependable menu. The marquee Chick-fil-A chicken sandwich is a fried breast served on a toasted bun with sliced dill pickles; other items include nuggets, strips, salads and wraps, all featuring the beloved bird. Health-conscious customers avoiding fried food can order the char-grilled chicken sandwich--same concept, one third the fat. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 Steak &apos;n Shake 1760 Us Highway 1 S 
 St Augustine, FL 
0.2 mi away Sonic Drive-In 704 East Geoffrey Street 
 Saint Augustine, FL 
0.5 mi away Mc Donald&apos;s 2431 Us Highway 1 S 
 St Augustine, FL 
0.9 mi away 
 
Things to do near Chick-Fil-A
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
