<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004475" url="http://www.jobsonline.net/food-preparation-serving-related-firstlinesupervisorsmanagersoffoodpreparationandservingworkers-n71202400/" time="2012-07-12-20:54" support="3" score="0.0039777965815515895" bingtitle="First-Line Supervisors of Food Preparation and Serving Workers ..." webtitle="First-Line Supervisors of Food Preparation and Serving Workers - Find Jobs - JobsOnline">
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>Compile and balance cash receipts at the end of the ... Fast Food Restaurant Manager; Fast Food Services Manager ... Lunch Counter Manager; Luncheonette Manager; Lunchroom ...</description>
	<body>
		JobsOnline 
 Already have an account? Login 
 
 Job you&apos;re looking for? job title, keywords or company Zip where you live? zip code     
 
First-Line Supervisors of Food Preparation and Serving Workers
 Jobs » Food Preparation and Serving Related »First-Line Supervisors of Food Preparation and Serving Workers 
Description:

Directly supervise and coordinate activities of workers engaged in preparing and serving food.

Tasks

 Train workers in food preparation, and in service, sanitation, and safety procedures. Compile and balance cash receipts at the end of the day or shift. Perform various financial activities such as cash handling, deposit preparation, and payroll. Supervise and participate in kitchen and dining area cleaning activities. Estimate ingredients and supplies required to prepare a recipe. Resolve customer complaints regarding food service. Control inventories of food, equipment, smallware, and liquor, and report shortages to designated personnel. Purchase or requisition supplies and equipment needed to ensure quality and timely delivery of services. Observe and evaluate workers and work procedures to ensure quality standards and service, and complete disciplinary write-ups. Specify food portions and courses, production and time sequences, and workstation and equipment arrangements. 

Knowledge
 Administration and Management Knowledge of business and management principles involved in strategic planning, resource allocation, human resources modeling, leadership technique, production methods, and coordination of people and resources. Customer and Personal Service Knowledge of principles and processes for providing customer and personal services. This includes customer needs assessment, meeting quality standards for services, and evaluation of customer satisfaction. Food Production Knowledge of techniques and equipment for planting, growing, and harvesting food products (both plant and animal) for consumption, including storage/handling techniques. Mathematics Knowledge of arithmetic, algebra, geometry, calculus, statistics, and their applications. Education and Training Knowledge of principles and methods for curriculum and training design, teaching and instruction for individuals and groups, and the measurement of training effects. Personnel and Human Resources Knowledge of principles and procedures for personnel recruitment, selection, training, compensation and benefits, labor relations and negotiation, and personnel information systems. English Language Knowledge of the structure and content of the English language including the meaning and spelling of words, rules of composition, and grammar. Production and Processing Knowledge of raw materials, production processes, quality control, costs, and other techniques for maximizing the effective manufacture and distribution of goods. Clerical Knowledge of administrative and clerical procedures and systems such as word processing, managing files and records, stenography and transcription, designing forms, and other office procedures and terminology. Sales and Marketing Knowledge of principles and methods for showing, promoting, and selling products or services. This includes marketing strategy and tactics, product demonstration, sales techniques, and sales control systems. 
Skills
 Speaking Talking to others to convey information effectively. Service Orientation Actively looking for ways to help people. Active Listening Giving full attention to what other people are saying, taking time to understand the points being made, asking questions as appropriate, and not interrupting at inappropriate times. Coordination Adjusting actions in relation to others&apos; actions. Management of Personnel Resources Motivating, developing, and directing people as they work, identifying the best people for the job. Monitoring Monitoring/Assessing performance of yourself, other individuals, or organizations to make improvements or take corrective action. Instructing Teaching others how to do something. Social Perceptiveness Being aware of others&apos; reactions and understanding why they react as they do. Reading Comprehension Understanding written sentences and paragraphs in work related documents. Time Management Managing one&apos;s own time and the time of others. 
Abilities
 Oral Expression The ability to communicate information and ideas in speaking so others will understand. Oral Comprehension The ability to listen to and understand information and ideas presented through spoken words and sentences. Problem Sensitivity The ability to tell when something is wrong or is likely to go wrong. It does not involve solving the problem, only recognizing there is a problem. Deductive Reasoning The ability to apply general rules to specific problems to produce answers that make sense. Speech Recognition The ability to identify and understand the speech of another person. Speech Clarity The ability to speak clearly so others can understand you. Written Comprehension The ability to read and understand information and ideas presented in writing. Information Ordering The ability to arrange things or actions in a certain order or pattern according to a specific rule or set of rules (e.g., patterns of numbers, letters, words, pictures, mathematical operations). Near Vision The ability to see details at close range (within a few feet of the observer). Inductive Reasoning The ability to combine pieces of information to form general rules or conclusions (includes finding a relationship among seemingly unrelated events). 
Work Activities
 Getting Information Observing, receiving, and otherwise obtaining information from all relevant sources. Judging the Qualities of Things, Services, or People Assessing the value, importance, or quality of things or people. Guiding, Directing, and Motivating Subordinates Providing guidance and direction to subordinates, including setting performance standards and monitoring performance. Making Decisions and Solving Problems Analyzing information and evaluating results to choose the best solution and solve problems. Identifying Objects, Actions, and Events Identifying information by categorizing, estimating, recognizing differences or similarities, and detecting changes in circumstances or events. Training and Teaching Others Identifying the educational needs of others, developing formal educational or training programs or classes, and teaching or instructing others. Coordinating the Work and Activities of Others Getting members of a group to work together to accomplish tasks. Coaching and Developing Others Identifying the developmental needs of others and coaching, mentoring, or otherwise helping others to improve their knowledge or skills. Performing for or Working Directly with the Public Performing for people or dealing directly with the public. This includes serving customers in restaurants and stores, and receiving clients or guests. Organizing, Planning, and Prioritizing Work Developing specific goals and plans to prioritize, organize, and accomplish your work. 
Work Context
 Contact With Others How much does this job require the worker to be in contact with others (face-to-face, by telephone, or otherwise) in order to perform it? Face-to-Face Discussions How often do you have to have face-to-face discussions with individuals or teams in this job? Work With Work Group or Team How important is it to work with others in a group or team in this job? Spend Time Standing How much does this job require standing? Coordinate or Lead Others How important is it to coordinate or lead others in accomplishing work activities in this job? Telephone How often do you have telephone conversations in this job? Physical Proximity To what extent does this job require the worker to perform job tasks in close physical proximity to other people? Deal With External Customers How important is it to work with external customers or the public in this job? Responsibility for Outcomes and Results How responsible is the worker for work outcomes and results of other workers? Time Pressure How often does this job require the worker to meet strict deadlines? 
Interests
 Enterprising Enterprising occupations frequently involve starting up and carrying out projects. These occupations can involve leading people and making many decisions. Sometimes they require risk taking and often deal with business. Conventional Conventional occupations frequently involve following set procedures and routines. These occupations can include working with data and details more than with ideas. Usually there is a clear line of authority to follow. Realistic Realistic occupations frequently involve work activities that include practical, hands-on problems and solutions. They often deal with plants, animals, and real-world materials like wood, tools, and machinery. Many of the occupations require working outside, and do not involve a lot of paperwork or working closely with others. Social Social occupations frequently involve working with, communicating with, and teaching people. These occupations often involve helping or providing service to others. Artistic Artistic occupations frequently involve working with forms, designs and patterns. They often require self-expression and the work can be done without following a clear set of rules. Investigative Investigative occupations frequently involve working with ideas, and require an extensive amount of thinking. These occupations can involve searching for facts and figuring out problems mentally. 
Work Style
 Stress Tolerance Job requires accepting criticism and dealing calmly and effectively with high stress situations. Cooperation Job requires being pleasant with others on the job and displaying a good-natured, cooperative attitude. Self Control Job requires maintaining composure, keeping emotions in check, controlling anger, and avoiding aggressive behavior, even in very difficult situations. Dependability Job requires being reliable, responsible, and dependable, and fulfilling obligations. Leadership Job requires a willingness to lead, take charge, and offer opinions and direction. Concern for Others Job requires being sensitive to others&apos; needs and feelings and being understanding and helpful on the job. Adaptability/Flexibility Job requires being open to change (positive or negative) and to considerable variety in the workplace. Integrity Job requires being honest and ethical. Attention to Detail Job requires being careful about detail and thorough in completing work tasks. Initiative Job requires a willingness to take on responsibilities and challenges. 
Work Value
 Relationships Occupations that satisfy this work value allow employees to provide service to others and work with co-workers in a friendly non-competitive environment. Corresponding needs are Co-workers, Moral Values and Social Service. Support Occupations that satisfy this work value offer supportive management that stands behind employees. Corresponding needs are Company Policies, Supervision: Human Relations and Supervision: Technical. Independence Occupations that satisfy this work value allow employees to work on their own and make decisions. Corresponding needs are Creativity, Responsibility and Autonomy. Achievement Occupations that satisfy this work value are results oriented and allow employees to use their strongest abilities, giving them a feeling of accomplishment. Corresponding needs are Ability Utilization and Achievement. Recognition Occupations that satisfy this work value offer advancement, potential for leadership, and are often considered prestigious. Corresponding needs are Advancement, Authority, Recognition and Social Status. Working Conditions Occupations that satisfy this work value offer job security and good working conditions. Corresponding needs are Activity, Compensation, Independence, Security, Variety and Working Conditions. 
Related Occupations

 Food Service Managers Farm and Home Management Advisors Dietitians and Nutritionists Dietetic Technicians Chefs and Head Cooks First-Line Supervisors of Housekeeping and Janitorial Workers First-Line Supervisors of Landscaping, Lawn Service, and Groundskeeping Workers First-Line Supervisors of Personal Service Workers Recreation Workers First-Line Supervisors of Animal Husbandry and Animal Care Workers 

Common Lay Titles

 Assistant Manager Banquet Captain Banquet Steward/Stewardess Banquet Supervisor Bar Manager Bartender Manager Cafeteria Manager Cafeteria Supervisor Canteen Manager Captain Caterer Catering Supervisor Chef Chief Cargo Vessel Steward/Stewardess Child Nutrition Manager Cocktail Lounge Manager Commissary Production Supervisor Cook Manager Cook Supervisor Counter Supervisor Crew Chief Crew Leader Culinary Specialist Dairy Bar Manager Diet Supervisor Dietary Manager Dietary Supervisor Dining Room Captain Dining Room Manager Dining Room Supervisor Director of Food and Beverage Director of Food and Nutrition Services Executive Chef Executive Sous Chef Fast Food Restaurant Manager Fast Food Services Manager Fast Food Supervisor First Cook Flight Kitchen Manager Floor Supervisor Food and Beverage Manager Food and Beverage Supervisor Food Beverage Supervisor Food Concession Manager Food Expeditor Food Production Manager Food Production Supervisor Food Service Director Food Service Manager Food Service Supervisor Food Service Worker Food Supervisor Fountain Manager Fountain Supervisor Head Banquet Waiter/Waitress Head Cook Head Silverman Head Waiter Head Waiter/Waitress Head Waitress Headwaiter/Headwaitress Hotel or Motel Food Service Supervisor Kitchen Manager Kitchen Steward/Stewardess Kitchen Supervisor Kitchen Work Supervisor Kosher Dietary Service Manager Kosher Dietary Service Supervisor Lunch Counter Manager Luncheonette Manager Lunchroom Food Service Supervisor Lunchroom Manager Lunchroom Supervisor Railroad Dining Car Steward/Stewardess Restaurant Manager Restaurant Supervisor Room Service Supervisor School Lunch Manager Shift Manager Snack Bar Manager Soda Fountain Manager Sous Chef Steward/Stewardess Store Manager Supervisor Supervisor of Food and Nutrition Services Supervisor, Diet, Kitchen Tea Room Manager Waiter/Waitress, Captain 
 
Personalize Your Job Search!
Use the form at the top of the page to begin your job search now! 
Not an existing member?
 Create a FREE account right now! 
Already Registered?
 Login now! 
Local Job Search Results for First-Line Supervisors of Food Preparation and Serving Workers Jobs

 Alabama Jobs 
 Birmingham Jobs Montgomery Jobs 
 

 Alaska Jobs 
 Anchorage Jobs Juneau Jobs 
 

 Arizona Jobs 
 Chandler Jobs Glendale Jobs Mesa Jobs Phoenix Jobs Phoenix Jobs Scottsdale Jobs Tucson Jobs 
 

 Arkansas Jobs 
 Little Rock Jobs 
 

 California Jobs 
 Anaheim Jobs Bakersfield Jobs Chula Vista Jobs Fresno Jobs Long Beach Jobs Los Angeles Jobs Oakland Jobs Riverside Jobs Sacramento Jobs Sacramento Jobs San Diego Jobs San Francisco Jobs San Jose Jobs Santa Ana Jobs Stockton Jobs 
 

 Colorado Jobs 
 Aurora Jobs Colorado Springs Jobs Denver Jobs 
 

 Connecticut Jobs 
 Hartford Jobs 
 

 Delaware Jobs 
 Dover Jobs 
 

 District of Columbia Jobs 
 Washington Jobs 
 

 Florida Jobs 
 Hialeah Jobs Jacksonville Jobs Miami Jobs Orlando Jobs St. Petersburg Jobs Tallahassee Jobs Tampa Jobs 
 

 Georgia Jobs 
 Atlanta Jobs 
 

 Hawaii Jobs 
 Honolulu Jobs 
 

 Idaho Jobs 
 Boise Jobs 
 

 Illinois Jobs 
 Chicago Jobs Springfield Jobs 
 

 Indiana Jobs 
 Fort Wayne Jobs Indianapolis Jobs 
 

 Iowa Jobs 
 Des Moines Jobs 
 

 Kansas Jobs 
 Topeka Jobs Wichita Jobs 
 

 Kentucky Jobs 
 Frankfort Jobs Lexington Jobs 
 

 Louisiana Jobs 
 Baton Rouge Jobs New Orleans Jobs 
 

 Maine Jobs 
 Augusta Jobs 
 

 Maryland Jobs 
 Annapolis Jobs Baltimore Jobs 
 

 Massachusetts Jobs 
 Boston Jobs 
 

 Michigan Jobs 
 Detroit Jobs Lansing Jobs 
 

 Minnesota Jobs 
 Minneapolis Jobs St. Paul Jobs 
 

 Mississippi Jobs 
 Jackson Jobs 
 

 Missouri Jobs 
 Jefferson City Jobs Kansas City Jobs St. Louis Jobs 
 

 Montana Jobs 
 Helena Jobs 
 

 Nebraska Jobs 
 Lincoln Jobs Omaha Jobs 
 

 Nevada Jobs 
 Carson City Jobs Henderson Jobs Las Vegas Jobs Reno Jobs 
 

 New Hampshire Jobs 
 Concord Jobs 
 

 New Jersey Jobs 
 Jersey City Jobs Newark Jobs Trenton Jobs 
 

 New Mexico Jobs 
 Albuquerque Jobs Santa Fe Jobs 
 

 New York Jobs 
 Albany Jobs Babylon Jobs Brookhaven Jobs Buffalo Jobs Hempstead Jobs Islip Jobs New York Jobs North Hempstead Jobs Oyster Bay Jobs Rochester Jobs 
 

 North Carolina Jobs 
 Charlotte Jobs Durham Jobs Greensboro Jobs Raleigh Jobs Winston-Salem Jobs 
 

 North Dakota Jobs 
 Bismarck Jobs 
 

 Ohio Jobs 
 Akron Jobs Cincinnati Jobs Cleveland Jobs Columbus Jobs Toledo Jobs 
 

 Oklahoma Jobs 
 Oklahoma City Jobs Tulsa Jobs 
 

 Oregon Jobs 
 Portland Jobs Salem Jobs 
 

 Pennsylvania Jobs 
 Harrisburg Jobs Philadelphia Jobs Pittsburgh Jobs 
 

 Rhode Island Jobs 
 Providence Jobs 
 

 South Carolina Jobs 
 Columbia Jobs 
 

 South Dakota Jobs 
 Pierre Jobs 
 

 Tennessee Jobs 
 Memphis Jobs Nashville Jobs 
 

 Texas Jobs 
 Arlington Jobs Austin Jobs Corpus Christi Jobs Dallas Jobs El Paso Jobs Fort Worth Jobs Garland Jobs Houston Jobs Laredo Jobs Lubbock Jobs Plano Jobs San Antonio Jobs 
 

 Utah Jobs 
 Salt Lake City Jobs 
 

 Vermont Jobs 
 Montpelier Jobs 
 

 Virginia Jobs 
 Chesapeake Jobs Norfolk Jobs Richmond Jobs Virginia Beach Jobs 
 

 Washington Jobs 
 Olympia Jobs Seattle Jobs 
 

 West Virginia Jobs 
 Charleston Jobs 
 

 Wisconsin Jobs 
 Madison Jobs Milwaukee Jobs 
 

 Wyoming Jobs 
 Cheyenne Jobs 
 
 Advertisers | Affiliates | About Us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use JobsOnline©2012
	</body>
</document>
