<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004558" url="http://duhnuz.com/" time="2012-07-12-20:58" support="1" score="0.0005048041183939272" bingtitle="DUH News - June 6th" webtitle="DUH News - June 6th">
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>A friend and I were standing in line at a fast-food restaurant ... Believe me, if I HAD a bill larger ... speed, and in general began to throw ...</description>
	<body>
		ARCHIVES
 May 
 29th 
 May 21st 
 May 15th 
 Medical IDIOTS    
 JOKES   
 CARTOONS   
 STUFF  
 ADULTS    
 
 
 She&apos;s 
 tired of waiting 
Marlene Anne Bagnall had Best Buy come to her house to repair her 
 TV. Not very good at their trade, the repairmen had to make several 
 trips to her house to try and fix the broken TV. Unfortunately when 
 the repairman said he couldn&apos;t fix it and attempted to leave, Marlene 
 had reached her limit. She went to the garage, grabbed her .38-caliber 
 weapon, pointed it at the repairman and said,&quot;You&apos;re not leaving 
 here until the TV is fixed.&quot;

The man pleaded with Bagnall to let him go and convinced her he 
 would get her a new TV. Bagnall told him she would kill him and 
 herself if he called police. After calling the store and getting 
 another employee to tell her he would get her a new TV, Bagnall 
 let the repairman go. After leaving the house the man called the 
 sheriff&apos;s office.

The police arrested Bagnall and charged her with aggravated assault 
 and unlawful imprisonment. Bagnall said she didn&apos;t point the gun 
 at the guy, just waived it around. Bagnall&apos;&apos;s husband told the police 
 she was on medication for a bipolar disorder. 
 

 

 
 Gracious 
 Hostess 
Lucy, ever the gracious hostess, was serving drinks at one of her 
 parties over the Holidays. A friend of hers brought his brother 
 who had just been ordained a Priest. She offered the friend a drink 
 from the
tray and said,&quot;I&apos;m sorry Father, I&apos;ll go right back to the 
 kitchen and bring you a coke.&quot;

The Priest smiled and said,&quot;No need to. I may have alcohol. 
 Priests abstain from sex, not the grape.&quot;

&quot;Oh!&quot;said Lucy blushing,&quot;I knew it was one or the 
 other that I wasn&apos;t supposed to offer you.&quot;

 Three Cent Tip 
One day a bachelor who was a poor tipper walked into his favorite 
 restaurant and ordered lunch.

A new waitress served his meal and received a three cent tip.

When he came in the next day, she thanked him for his&quot;generosity&quot;and she said she could tell the character of a diner by the way 
 he tipped.

&quot;Well, what could you tell about me?&quot;he asked.

&quot;You put three pennies in a neat row,&quot;said the waitress,&quot;and that shows you are a very tidy person. The first penny 
 tells me you are a frugal, and the second tells me that you are 
 a bachelor.&quot;

&quot;That&apos;s true,&quot;he agreed.&quot;But what does the third 
 penny tell you?&quot;

&quot;The third penny tells me your Father was a bachelor, too.&quot;

 Take that fast food resturants 
A friend and I were standing in line at a fast-food restaurant, 
 waiting to place our order. There was a big sign posted.&quot;No 
 bills larger than $20 will be accepted.&quot;
The woman in front of us, pointing to the sign, remarked,&quot;Believe 
 me, if I HAD a bill larger than $20, I wouldn&apos;t be eating here.&quot;

 Circle flies 
A farmer got pulled over by a NC State Trooper for speeding.
The Trooper started to lecture the farmer about his speed, and in 
 general began to throw his weight around to try to make the farmer 
 uncomfortable. Finally, the trooper got around to writing out the 
 ticket. As he was doing that, he kept swatting at some flies that 
 were buzzing around his head.
The farmer said,&quot;Having some problems with circle flies there, 
 are ya?&quot;
The Trooper stopped writing the ticket and said,&quot;Well yeah, 
 if that&apos;s what they are. I never heard of circle flies.&quot;
So the farmer says,&quot;Well, circle flies are common on farms. 
 See, they&apos;re called circle flies because they&apos;re almost always found 
 circling around the back end of a horse.&quot;
The Trooper says,&quot;Oh,&quot;and goes back to writing the ticket. 
 Then after a minute he stops and says,&quot;Are you trying to call 
 me a horse&apos;s ass?&quot;
The farmer says,&quot;Oh no, officer. I have too much respect for 
 law enforcement and police officers to even think about calling 
 you a horse&apos;s ass.&quot;
The Trooper says,&quot;Well, that&apos;s a good thing,&quot;and goes 
 back to writing the ticket.
After a long pause, the farmer says,&quot;Hard to fool them flies 
 though.&quot; 






 
 Milton 
 Berle is an inspiration to every young person that wants to get 
 into show business. Hard work, perseverance, and discipline: all 
 the things you need...when you have no talent.
-- Dean Martin

If life were fair, Dan Quayle would be making a living
asking &apos;Do you want fries with that?&apos;
-- John Cleese

She&apos;s so pure, Moses couldn&apos;t even part her knees.
-- Joan Rivers (on Marie Osmond)

I once shook hands with Pat Boone and my whole right side sobered 
 up.
-- Dean Martin 

 

 
 Congressman 
 Pete Sessions (R-Tex.) has introduced a bill in Congress to prohibit 
 state and local governments from offering telecommunications, telecommunications 
 services, information services, or cable services in an area where 
 there is a private concern offering the same service. It doesn&apos;t 
 matter how crappy the service, it doesn&apos;t matter how overpriced, 
 and it doesn&apos;t matter that the cities are willing to provide the 
 service in public areas where the private businesses would not. 
 Did I fail to mention that Sessions used to be a Southwestern Bell 
 district manager in Texas? 

 

 
 Martha 
 Stewart is ready to begin her new reality show . . .&quot;Confining 
 Spaces.&quot;

If my memory gets any worse, I will only be able to live in the 
 present.

If you find something you like, buy a lifetime
supply, because they will stop making it.

By the time you can make ends meet, they move the ends.
 
 
 
 The 
 older they are, the meaner they get. 
Ninety-one-year-old Katherine Woodworth thought she heard the man 
 behind her say he wanted her purse. But without her hearing aid 
 in, she wasn&apos;t sure. But when he said it a second time she said&quot;No, you&apos;re not.&quot;She started clobbering the would-be 
 attacker with the purse. She continued to beat on him until the 
 man ran out of the parking lot and into the Toledo streets.
Police arrested a 20-year-old suspect and charged him with robbery, 
 felony theft, assault, aggravated menacing, and possession of drug 
 paraphernalia
Sgt. Tim Hanus said women of Woodworth&apos;s age shouldn&apos;t try to fight 
 attackers. Woodworth said she didn&apos;t think her age was much of a 
 factor.
&quot;I&apos;ll be 92 in August and I guess I&apos;ve got more nerve now than 
 when I was younger,&quot;she said. 

 

 
 Do 
 you ever get frustrated by people who send emails that are emails 
 inside emails inside other emails. So you drill through six sets 
 of forwarded emails to get to the one that has the content. After 
 you finally read it you like what it says or want to send it to 
 friends but don&apos;t want to put them through the agony of the mouse 
 click parade to get to the email with content.
Open the email message that you want to keep/send. In either Outlook 
 or Outlook Express goto File/Copy to Folder or File/Move to Folder. 
 Now save the copy of the email that has the content instead of the 
 original one in whatever folder you desire. Now when you send it 
 to your friends or open it to read it again it will be the first, 
 not the sixth email in your message .

 

 
 Barry 
 Colbert, 38, says he let his 7-year-old drive as a reward for finishing 
 his homework and cleaning his room. He set his son up sohe could 
 reach the pedals, and Colbert sat in the passenger seat as they 
 hit the road. That&apos;s not all they hit: police said the boy ran a 
 stop sign and crashed into another car outside New Port Richey, 
 Fla. After the crash, Colbert took over the wheel just as officers 
 arrived.
Police say they will cite the boy for driving without a license, 
 driving without headlights and running a stop sign, and Colbert 
 for driving while intoxicated, habitually driving with a suspended 
 license and letting an unlicensed person drive.&quot;I&apos;m not irresponsible,&quot;Colbert explains.&quot;I just had a few beers.&quot;(St. Petersburg 
 Times) March 2002 

 

 
 There 
 are men in Guam whose full-time job is to travel the countryside 
 and deflower young virgins, who pay them for the privilege of having 
 sex for the first time...Reason: under Guam law, it is expressly 
 forbidden for virgins to marry. 

 

 
 Soapbox 
 time again 
Have you noticed how screwed up our priorities are? If you read 
 the press or turn on the news, everyday you hear about US soldiers 
 who are on trial for abusing the enemy, or in the heat of battle, 
 make an error and shot an Iraqi who is lying in the same position 
 as was a suicide bomber the day before who was lying there with 
 a grenade under him, waiting for a Marine to turn him over.
We persecute and prosecute our own troops for embarrassing the enemy, 
 but have done nothing to find the perpetrators who beat, shot, and 
 burned three Americans and hung them off a bridge over the Tigris 
 River.
We investigate to find out who&apos;s at fault for the death of an Italian 
 who died (acting like the enemy) during an attempt to rescue an 
 Italian reporter, and have not done a thing to find and prosecute 
 her captors.
Maybe another day I&apos;ll expound on working with the detainees. Today 
 I want to talk about how we punish officers for doing their job 
 and saving lives.
Major Catherine Kaus was the commander of an Army Reserve unit from 
 Ohio, and Chief Warrant Officer Darrell E. Birt her senior NCO. 
 The unit was activated before the start of the war and sent to Iraq 
 to provide the vital fuel necessary to support troops as they rushed 
 to Baghdad.
While her troops were motivated, their equipment was not and it 
 broke down leaving the fighting force without the 300,000 gallons 
 of fuel they would need to force the enemy to surrender. Then just 
 days before they were to make the&quot;jump&quot;into Iraq, higher-ups 
 told the soldiers they would have to go without most of their tools, 
 spare parts, machine guns, chemical protective gear, night-vision 
 goggles, tents, computers and personal belongings. The reason: None 
 of the vehicles belonging to the unit was capable of towing shipping 
 containers that held their gear.
Major Kaus and Chief Brit must have watched Heartbreak Ridge fifty 
 times like I did and listened to Clint Eastwood explain in his gravely 
 voice that they used the phone card of one of his Marines to call 
 in an air strike and take the hill that was crawling with Cuban 
 troops. When the general asked how he did it, Eastwood&apos;s reply was 
 that Marines were taught to improvise, adapt, and overcome. That&apos;s 
 exactly what Major Kaus taught her soldiers to do. In previous wars 
 from Hannable&apos;s elephants to Vietnam it was called adapting to the 
 situation and scrounging to survive. And that&apos;s what Major Kaus 
 and Chief Warrant Officer Birt directed their troops to do. They 
 commandeered unclaimed vehicles from units that had already pushed 
 into Iraq and broken trucks along side the road. They threw their 
 gear in the good trucks and cannibalized the parts off the bad as 
 they chased the troops to ensure they had enough fuel to continue 
 to fight the war.
For their efforts the commanders in the field rewarded them with 
 the Bronze Star, Then when the&quot;war&quot;was over and we sent 
 troops and commanders over there to&quot;preserve the peace&quot;, 
 those in charge decided their actions weren&apos;t heroic, they were 
 criminal and Court Marshaled them both. Both spent six months in 
 the Brig. Finally, Lt. Gen. Thomas Metz, the theater commander when 
 Kaus was in Iraq, overruled the court-martial in their cases and 
 granted partial clemency to both. He disapproved Major Kaus&apos;s dismissal 
 from the Army. He also disapproved&quot;contingent confinement,&quot;which could have landed Kaus in jail again if she failed to pay 
 the $5,000 fine on time. The six-month confinement, already served, 
 was approved.
The real criminals, here are the commanders who would send their 
 troops into battle without the proper equipment and then prosecute 
 them for making up for their own shortcomings. The classic line 
 from Heartbreak Ridge came from the general who landed his helicopter 
 on the top of the ridge that Eastwood and his men had just taken. 
 He was met by Eastwood&apos;s commander, a major who proceeded to tell 
 the general how Eastwood violated orders and should be punished. 
 The general looked at him and said,&quot;Major what did you do 
 before getting into the infantry?&quot;
&quot;Sir, I was a supply officer.&quot;The major replied.
The general chewed on his cigar and then asked,&quot;Were you good 
 at it?&quot;
&quot;Yes, Sir!&quot;the major said proudly.
&quot;Then I suggest you go back to Supply, because as an infantry 
 officer, you suck.&quot;
It&apos;s time we removed the&quot;supply officers&quot;(from the Pentagon 
 and front lines) and let those who know how to fight the war do 
 their job without the fear they might be court marshaled for every 
 decision they make. 

 
 
     DUHNUZ@EARTHLINK.NET
	</body>
</document>
