<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004440" url="http://eastgreensboro.myfox8.com/news/news/67253-suspect-sought-after-fast-food-restaurant-greensboro-robbed" time="2012-07-12-20:51" support="3" score="0.006362965105554475" bingtitle="Suspect Sought After Fast Food Restaurant in Greensboro Robbed ..." webtitle="Suspect Sought After Fast Food Restaurant in Greensboro Robbed | News | East Greensboro News">
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>... are looking for a suspect after a Bojangles fast food ... Teen dead, another hurt in single-car wreck in ... Sign me up to receive all station emails</description>
	<body>
		Our network
 
 MyFox8.com 
 
 
 
 Twitter RSS Facebook 
 More MyFox8 Sites 
 Alamance County Asheboro Burlington Davie County Eden Greensboro - West Greensboro - East 

 Guilford Co. - North Guilford Co. - South High Point - North High Point - South Kernersville Lewisville-Clemmons Lexington 

 Madison-Mayodan Mebane Mocksville Mount Airy Reidsville Rockingham County Stokes County 

 Surry County Thomasville Winston-Salem - North Winston-Salem - South 
 
Search
 
Welcome Menu
 
 Log in Contact us 
 
 Home Schools Crime Families Pets Events Restaurants Businesses Real Estate Deals! 
 
 
 News Overall crime reported in NC lowest since ... News Police reopen multiple intersections ... News Greensboro Police arrest bank robbery suspect News Harris Teeter ups reward to $75K for info ... 
Suspect Sought After Fast Food Restaurant in Greensboro Robbed | News
 
Title (Max 100 Charaters)
 Suspect Sought After Fast Food Restaurant in Greensboro Robbed Submitted by MyFox8_Web_Staff Monday, January 9th, 2012, 2:15pm Topics: News Print E-mail 
Police are looking for a suspect after a Bojangles fast food restaurant was robbed at gunpoint Sunday in Greensboro.

Police said the robbery happened around 3 p.m. at 2011 E. Cone Blvd. A silent alarm went off and police were there within minutes, authorities said.

The suspect allegedly entered the building through the east side door and went behind the counter and with a silver handgun.

Police said he demanded money from employees at the drive thru window and then from the main counter register.

Police said he suspect fled through the east side door on foot and then headed north past the Lowes hardware store.

A search led police to the Hunters Glens apartments area, authorities said. Police said they lost the suspect after tracking him to 3114 McKnight Mill Road.

The suspect is described as light skinned black male about 5&apos;2&quot;-5&apos;5.&quot; Police said he is thin, clean shaven, has short hair and is full faced.

He wore a pink or fuchsia colored shirt, a black hooded sweatshirt, dark jeans and shoes with white on them, police said.

No reported injuries were reported. Further details were not provided.
 Topics: News 
Top East Greensboro Stories
 News Overall crime reported in NC lowest since ... News Police reopen multiple intersections ... News Greensboro Police arrest bank robbery suspect News Harris Teeter ups reward to $75K for info ... 
Upcoming Events near East Greensboro
 
 
 Fred Hammond - Live 

Jul 15, 6:00PM

 Destiny Christian Center 
 
 Tigress 

Jul 12, 6:45PM

 Downtown Greensboro 
 
 Greensboro vs. Kannapolis 

Jul 15, 4:00PM

 NewBridge Bank Park 
 Add an Event 
 See more local events 
 East Greensboro Deals 
 20% Off For All Repairs | PC Solutions 15% Off! | Premier Hardwood Flooring $100 Off Tuition&amp;Free Books! | Professional Bartending Institute of Greensboro $25 OFF all over color an | Hair by Melissa Rivera 1st Session Free! | Greensboro Movement Specialists 10% Off Any Rental! | Monarch Auto Sales, LLC $25 OFF all over color an | Hair by Melissa Rivera 20% Off For All Repairs | PC Solutions 10% Off Any Rental! | Monarch Auto Sales, LLC 2 Free 8x10 Prints | Adrienne Fletcher Weddings 15% Off! | Premier Hardwood Flooring $25 OFF all over color an | Hair by Melissa Rivera $100 Off Tax Preparation! | Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA $25 OFF all over color an | Hair by Melissa Rivera 20% Off For All Repairs | PC Solutions $25 OFF all over color an | Hair by Melissa Rivera $25 Off Per Unit | Triad Inflatables $100 Off Tax Preparation! | Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA 10% Off Any Rental! | Monarch Auto Sales, LLC 10% Off | Cleansboro 15% Off Labor! | Honda Transmission Specialist 10% Off First Month | The Pooch Nanny $25 OFF all over color an | Hair by Melissa Rivera $100 Off Tax Preparation! | Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA 15% Off Labor! | Honda Transmission Specialist More Deals | Advertise with us 
 East Greensboro Businesses 
 Talley Water Treatment Company Adrienne Fletcher Weddings 2 Free 8x10 Prints Living by Design Padgett Construction&amp;Remodeling LLC Fuzzy&apos;s Bar-B-Que Greensboro Movement Specialists 1st Session Free! PC Solutions 20% Off For All Repairs Triad Inflatables $25 Off Per Unit Sage Detox System LLC All Community Sponsors 
Most popular stories from nearby communities
 
 Northern Guilford News 

 Family goes on vacation, returns to foreclosed home Businesses targeted in Oak Ridge break-ins, suspects sought Family faces $7,000 power bill after meter ‘malfunctioned’ Fun Fourth Festival in Greensboro High temperatures, warm water keeps crowds away from Belews Lake 
 
 Southern Guilford News 

 Forest Oaks Country Club to host Big Brothers Big Sisters Golf Classic Seventh case of rabies this year reported in Guilford Co. 3 dogs killed in house fire in Guilford Co. Students concerned about possible interest rate increase New I-85 lane labels meant to ease confusion 
 
 West Greensboro News 

 Jerry Seinfeld to perform in Greensboro One taken to hospital after shooting in Greensboro Man carries cross down busy Greensboro street Greensboro elementary school students build popsicle bridges UNCG volunteers landscaping neighborhood near Glenwood project 
 
Do you have a story to tell? Become a community blogger! 
 
Community Sponsors
 Graham D Farless, DDS Family, Cosmetic&amp;Implant Dentistry Pets you Love Inc. Where Grooming is Magic! GreenDay Waste and Recycling Multiple Solutions From One Local Source. Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA Offering a Broad Range of Services To Help You Secure A Sound Financial Future $100 Off Tax Preparation! Honda Transmission Specialist Home of the One Price Guarantee! 15% Off Labor! Triad Auto Parts Shop With US! All Community Sponsors 
 East Greensboro Real Estate Listings 
 
 7 Dunnberry Ct., Greensboro, NC $133,900 Contact: Janie Henderson Courtesy of: Allen Tate Realtors 311 Mendenhall, Greensboro, NC $287,900 Contact: Janie Henderson Courtesy of: Allen Tate Realtors 
 see more local real estate 
The Big Deal
 20% Off For All Repairs PC Solutions Computer Repair Professionals 
 View This Deal 
 10% Off Any Rental! Monarch Auto Sales, LLC Dependable vehicles at a reasonable price 
 View This Deal 
 20% Off For All Repairs PC Solutions Computer Repair Professionals 
 View This Deal 
 $100 Off Tax Preparation! Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA Offering a Broad Range of Services To Help You Secure A Sound Financial Future 
 View This Deal 
 $100 Off Tax Preparation! Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA Offering a Broad Range of Services To Help You Secure A Sound Financial Future 
 View This Deal 
 10% Off Any Rental! Monarch Auto Sales, LLC Dependable vehicles at a reasonable price 
 View This Deal 
 10% Off Any Rental! Monarch Auto Sales, LLC Dependable vehicles at a reasonable price 
 View This Deal 
 $100 Off Tax Preparation! Robert Charles Kirnard, CPA Offering a Broad Range of Services To Help You Secure A Sound Financial Future 
 View This Deal 
 20% Off For All Repairs PC Solutions Computer Repair Professionals 
 View This Deal 
 15% Off Labor! Honda Transmission Specialist Home of the One Price Guarantee! 
 View This Deal 
 See More East Greensboro Coupons 
Community Sponsors
 PC Solutions Computer Repair Professionals 20% Off For All Repairs Monarch Auto Sales, LLC Dependable vehicles at a reasonable price 10% Off Any Rental! The Pooch Nanny Professionals Serving Professionals 10% Off First Month Greensboro Plumbing&amp;Heating Your Source for Plumbing&amp;Heating. Graham Marine Sales&amp;Services Serving boaters in the heart of Graham for over 40 years! Cleansboro 10% Off Watch video Orrell Design Experience The Whole Body 8 More Fitness The Pulse of Personal Training! Watch video Two Men And A Truck We treat everyone the way you would want your Grandma to be treated. Watch video All Community Sponsors 
Local Business Spotlight
 Cleansboro more details 10% Off 8 More Fitness 616 D Guilford College Road, Greensboro, NC more details Two Men And A Truck more details 
Local Real Estate Agents
 Featured agent Janie Henderson Website | Contact Janie Henderson 
Local Service Providers
 PrimeCare Remarkable People. Remarkable Medicine. Premier Hardwood Flooring Your Premier Local Hardwood Flooring Company! 15% Off! Central Chiropractic Greensboro Chiropractor in the longest standing clinic in town...Walk-Ins Welcome! 
Get Local News
 Receive weekly local news&amp;deals. Email address: Sign me up to receive all station emails Your privacy is important to us. See our Privacy Policy . 
Stay up to date with your community!
Get news&amp;deals from East Greensboro for free! Close (X) Subscribe to our Newsletter Email address: Sign me up to receive all station emails Your privacy is important to us. See our Privacy Policy 
News Files
 
 Arts&amp;Culture Business Community Spirit Crime Environment Events Families Health Home&amp;Garden News People Pets Politics Public Spaces Real Estate Restaurants Schools Shopping&amp;Services Sports&amp;Recreation Style Transportation Urban Wildlife Weather 
 Article Archives 
 Northern Guilford News 

 Family goes on vacation, returns to foreclosed home Businesses targeted in Oak Ridge break-ins, suspects sought Family faces $7,000 power bill after meter ‘malfunctioned’ Fun Fourth Festival in Greensboro High temperatures, warm water keeps crowds away from Belews Lake 
 
 Southern Guilford News 

 Forest Oaks Country Club to host Big Brothers Big Sisters Golf Classic Seventh case of rabies this year reported in Guilford Co. 3 dogs killed in house fire in Guilford Co. Students concerned about possible interest rate increase New I-85 lane labels meant to ease confusion 
 
 West Greensboro News 

 Jerry Seinfeld to perform in Greensboro One taken to hospital after shooting in Greensboro Man carries cross down busy Greensboro street Greensboro elementary school students build popsicle bridges UNCG volunteers landscaping neighborhood near Glenwood project 
 
 MyFox8.com 

MyFox 8, 2005 Francis St., High Point, NC 27263

 Contact Us Watch our TV Ads Advertise With Us Privacy Policy Terms of Use 

Powered by Datasphere 
Copyright 2012
	</body>
</document>
