<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004830" url="http://www.middletownpress.com/articles/2012/04/12/news/doc4f8796406ed0e566412563.txt" time="2012-07-12-21:20" support="5" score="0.010086279456997436" bingtitle="New Britain man accused of stealing pregnant woman&apos;s cell phone at ..." webtitle="New Britain man accused of stealing pregnant woman&apos;s cell phone at local fast food restaurant - The Middletown Press : Serving Middletown, CT">
			<query id="001017" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="180"/>
	<description>... stealing pregnant woman&apos;s cell phone at local fast food restaurant ... woman’s cell phone that she had left on a table. ... Politics blog covers all the news from the seat of ...</description>
	<body>
		RSS | Contact Us | Submit Announcements | Place A Classified Ad | Subscribe | Manage Your Subscription | E-Paper | Advertise With Us 
 Our Network: New Haven Register The Register Citizen Middletown Press West Hartford News Connecticut Magazine 
 
 
 Serving Middletown, CT 
 
 Home | News 
 CT Senate 2012 5th District Election National News Honor Rolls Announcements Corrections Gas Buddy School Closings Traffic Blogs Video 
 | Sports 
 Athletes of the Week National Sports Video Blogs Video 
 | Obits | Business 
 Blogs Video 
 | Opinion | Entertainment 
 Events Games Numbrix Restaurants Blogs Video 
 | Health 
 Health TV 
 | Blogs 
 News Sports Business Entertainment Life 
 | Video 
 Autos News Sports Health TV Entertainment Technology Athletes of the Week Restaurants 
 
 
 Jobs | Real Estate | Cars 
 Video 
 | Classifieds | Marketplace 
 Directories Got Daily Deals Today&apos;s Ads Special Sections 
 
 SEARCH The Web Middletown Press 
 News 
 
New Britain man accused of stealing pregnant woman&apos;s cell phone at local fast food restaurant
 
Published: Thursday, April 12, 2012; Last Updated:Thursday, April 12, 2012 11:02 PM EDT
 
By LAUREN SIEVERT
Press Staff
@LaurenSievertMP

MIDDLETOWN—A New Britain man was charged with larceny after allegedly stealing a pregnant women’s cell phone at Five Guys restaurant, police report.

Hasan Harris, 18, 477 Stanley St., was issued a summons for sixth-degree larceny on March 30. He was due in court April 12, but did not appear and a bail commissioner’s letter was sent. If he does not appear on the next court date, he may be charged with failure to appear, officials said.

According to police, Harris was seen on the Five Guys Burgers and Fries security cameras taking a pregnant woman’s cell phone that she had left on a table. The cell phone was reportedly worth $150, and Harris allegedly admitted taking the phone but claimed it was not stealing because the victim“left it on the table,”according to police.




 


 1 2 
 


 1 2 3 
 


 1 2 3 4 See Full Story 

 Return to Paging Mode 
 
 
 See inaccurate information in a story? Other feedback and/or ideas for us to consider? Tell us here. 
 Reader Comments 
Comments are held for review before posting, per our Online Comments Policy . If you believe your comment was wrongly removed or not approved, email comments@nhregister.com 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. comments powered by Disqus 
 ADVERTISEMENT 

 
Talk of the Web
 


 
 
 
Your browser does not support iframes.
 
 View More 

 Place a Classified 
 
National News Videos
 
 See, Click, Fix 

 
 Photo Galleries 

 View All Galleries 

 Order Photo Reprints 

 Share Your Photos 
 
 Most Popular Hot Stories Most Shared 
 

 
 LETTER: THANKS TO YMCA MENTOR PROGRAM (7) Centenarian recalls trolley cars, old clock tower during Middletown birthday bash (5) Durham&apos;s adopted Morin brothers find home, family in America (5) Eileen Daily endorses Jim Crawford for state Senate (4) Vacant Colchester paper mill up in flames early Sunday (4) WTIC (Fox CT) hires Al Terzi (3) OpSail 2012CT brings tall ships to Connecticut despite delay (2) 
 
Recent Activity on Facebook

 
 
 Blog Center 
 
 

 From the Editor 

Editor Viktoria Sundqvist will share what&apos;s going on behind the scenes at The Middletown Press and what goes into making a small daily newspaper work in today&apos;s society.
 
 

 Connecticut Newsroom 

Reports from Connecticut Group Editor Matt DeRienzo.
 
 

 CT State Politics 

The Connecticut State Politics blog covers all the news from the seat of Connecticut&apos;s government and the state&apos;s elected leaders with original reporting from Journal Register Connecticut staff, links to stories from other media and blogs, press releases, statements and more.
 
 

 MP Book Club 

Our staff will comment on what they are reading or have read, and invite community members to tell us what they are reading and recommending.
 
 

 The Photo Club 

Middletown Press Staff Photographer Catherine Avalone blogs here about photography, her photo club and her day-to-day experiences in Middlesex County.
 
 More Blogs 
 
National AP Headlines



 View all AP National Headlines 
 
 
Middletown News, Middletown CT News:
 The Middletown Press is the leading source for local Middletown news. Powered by one of the most innovative news-gathering teams in Connecticut, MiddletownPress.com delivers you the local Middletown CT news you care about, as it happens. From 24-hour breaking news to compelling award-winning coverage of community, education, business, politics and more, MiddletownPress.com has all the Middletown CT news you&apos;re looking for, and beyond. Readers can easily use MiddletownPress.com to browse local Middletown news stories alongside original news reporting from other area towns, including Cromwell, Portland, Middlefield, Durham, East Hampton, Haddam, Chester, Killingworth, Deep River, Essex and East Haddam. Readers can use MiddletownPress.com&apos;s powerful search function to browse through years of award-winning Middletown news coverage. Readers can participate and engage in the Middletown Press&apos;s Open Newsroom by using the Fact Check story tool to flag inaccurate information reported in any article. Also enjoy Middletown restaurant reviews, Middletown obituaries, Connecticut real estate, and international news. No matter what Middletown CT news you&apos;re looking for, it&apos;s all in one place at MiddletownPress.com. 
 
 
Sections:
 Home | News | Sports | Obituaries | Business | Opinion | Entertainment | Health | Blogs | Video | 
 Marketplace 
 | Jobs | Real Estate | Cars | Classifieds 
 
 
Services:
 Advertise With Us | Subscribe | Manage Your Subscription | Place A Classified Ad | Submit Announcements | E-Paper | Newspapers In Education | Contact Us | Public Notices | RSS Feeds 
 
 
Our Network:
 New Haven Register | Register Citizen | West Hartford News | Connecticut Bride | Connecticut Magazine 
 
 
Foothills Media Group:
 The Avon News | The Canton News | The Simsbury News | The Granby News | The Litchfield News | Thomaston Express | The Foothills Trader | LitchfieldCountyMom.Com 
 
 ©Copyright 2012 The Middletown Press , a Journal Register Property &amp;part of Journal Register CT -- All rights reserved | Our Publications | About Our Ads | Privacy Policy/Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
