<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004677" url="http://www.oregonlive.com/washingtoncounty/index.ssf/2009/05/aloha_man_calls_911_over_botch.html" time="2012-07-12-21:10" support="10" score="0.0744814101608912" bingtitle="Aloha man calls 9-1-1 over botched fast-food order | OregonLive.com" webtitle="Aloha man calls 9-1-1 over botched fast-food order | 						OregonLive.com">
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Aloha man calls 9-1-1 over botched fast-food order Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2009, 3:30 PM Updated: Wednesday, November 04, 2009, 4:23 PM</description>
	<body>
		OregonLive.com 5-day | Satellite 
 


 
 Sign in | Register for free 
 OregonLive.com 
 
 Sign in 
 
 News 
 News 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 News Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All News Topics» | All News Forums» 
 
More ...

 Education Pacific Northwest Environment Photos Local News Politics Obituaries Road Conditions Opinion US&amp;World The Hillsboro Argus Videos The Oregonian Weather 
 Business 
 Business 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Business Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All Business Topics» 
 
More ...

 Business News Playbooks&amp;Profits Complaint Desk Silicon Forest Front Porch Small Business News It&apos;s Only Money Window Shop My Economy Stock Market Report Business Newsletters Tax Q&amp;A Blog Business Public Blog US&amp;World 
 Sports 
 Sports 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Sports Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All Sports Topics» | All Sports Forums» 
 
More ...

 Blazers NCAA Canzano Pac-12 Beavers Pilots Ducks Timbers MLB Track&amp;Field NBA Vikings NFL Winterhawks 
 H.S. Sports 
 High School Sports 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 High School Sports Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All High School Topics» 
 All High School Forums» 
 
More ...

 Scores&amp;schedules Football Find your school Boys Basketball Latest news Girls Basketball Forums Boys Soccer Photos Girls Soccer Recruiting Track&amp;Field Videos Volleyball 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Entertainment Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 Entertainment Topics» | Entertainment Forums» 
 
More ...

 Books Food&amp;Recipes Comics Health&amp;Fitness Dining Homes&amp;Gardens Events Outdoors Music Parenting Performance Pets TV&amp;Movies Travel 
 Local 
 Local 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Clackamas County Happy Valley West Linn Lake Oswego Wilsonville Milwaukie Oregon City 
 
 Portland Downtown Portland Southeast Portland North Portland Southwest Portland Northeast Portland Gresham Northwest Portland Clark County, Wash. 
 
 Washington County Aloha North of 26 Beaverton Sherwood Forest Grove Tigard Hillsboro Tualatin 
 
 
 Jobs 
 Jobs Home Find a Job Job Seeker Tools Employer Tools Post a Job More» 
 Autos 
 Autos Home Advanced Search New Car Pricing Used Cars Research Motorcycles Classic Cars Find A Dealer Place An Ad More» 
 Real Estate 
 Real Estate Home Homes New Homes Rent Foreclosures Commercial Place An Ad More» 
 Rentals 
 Rentals Home Apartments&amp;Communities Commercial Leases Place An Ad More» 
 Classifieds 
 Classifieds Obits Rentals Pets For Sale Garage Sales Fraud Prevention Manage Your Ad Place An Ad More» 
 Obituaries 
 Obituaries Home 
 Find N Save Local Businesses 
 Local Businesses Home Food&amp;Dining Retail Shopping Health&amp;Medicine Personal Care Entertainment Real Estate Automotive Personal Care Claim Your Business 
 
 Local news the way you want it: 
Sign in to OregonLive.com
 Username Password Remember me 
 Forgot your username or password ? 
 
Don’t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 Home &gt; Washington County News &gt; Hot Topic 
Aloha man calls 9-1-1 over botched fast-food order

Published: Wednesday, May 27, 2009, 3:30 PM   Updated: Wednesday, November 04, 2009, 4:23 PM 
 By John Snell, The Oregonian The Oregonian 
 Follow 118 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print Raibin Raof Osman 
ALOHA - For most folks it&apos;s not a dilemma. Given a choice between &quot;a day without sunshine&quot; and a day without jail time, most people will skip the orange juice and stay out of jail.

But Raibin Raof Osman isn&apos;t most people. The 20-year-old Aloha man had a sleep-over at the Washington County Jail on Memorial Day after calling 9-1-1 to complain that McDonald&apos;s left out a box of orange juice from his drive-thru order.

Osman was booked Monday night on accusations of improper use of 9-1-1. He bailed out Tuesday. The offense is a Class B misdemeanor punishable in Oregon by up to six months in jail and a fine of $2,500.
 
 The 9-1-1 call 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

&quot;We ordered some food,&quot; Osman told dispatchers at 11:41 p.m., calling on his cell phone from the restaurant at 19525 S.W. TV Highway in Aloha.

Osman told dispatchers the drive-thru attendant was laughing at his brother because he could not speak English very well.

&quot;That&apos;s why I called,&quot; he said. &quot;She (the employee who waited on him at the drive-thru window) was being rude.&quot;

A restaurant employee later called 9-1-1 to report that Osman and others who were with him were blocking the drive-thru lane, knocking on restaurant windows and intimidating employees.

Osman could not be reached for comment.

When sheriff&apos;s deputies arrived at the McDonald&apos;s, Osman was unwilling to listen to deputies explain that 9-1-1 wasn&apos;t in the business of straightening out fast food orders, said Sgt. David Thompson, spokesman for the Washington County Sheriff&apos;s Office.

&quot;The deputy basically said, &apos;You can&apos;t use 9-1-1 for that reason,&apos;&quot; Thompson explained. &quot;It&apos;s not an emergency. (Osman) said he didn&apos;t know how to get the non-emergency number. The guy had a Blackberry. He could have dialed 4-1-1 or got it off the Internet. There are payphones all over the parking lot, with phonebooks hanging from them.

&quot;He could have come up with the non-emergency number just like everyone else does.&quot;

Thompson said Osman tried to argue that he had the legal right to call the police.

&quot;He said it was a &apos;freedom of speech&apos; issue,&quot; Thompson said. &quot;He was not open to having the deputy educate him.&quot;

So Osman was taken to jail. His education will continue with an appearance in court, set to be scheduled at a later date.

 -- John Snell; johnsnell@news.oregonian.com 
 Inappropriate post?  Alert us. Related topics: 9-1-1 , Aloha , McDonald&apos;s , Raibin Raof Osman 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in Washington County News
 Previous story
 Hillsboro school board member will step down to apply for job with district Next story
 Aloha man accused of killing 2-month-old daughter Copyright 2012 OregonLive.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
More Washington County News

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 Washington County News stories with the most comments in the last 7 days. 74 When Oregon kids miss too much school, officials try hauling their parents into court 66 Do TriMet&apos;s board members ride their buses and trains? Yes, no comment and sometimes (if Portland Streetcar counts) 55 Matt Wingard hosted party where minors drank alcohol, witness says 54 TriMet driver orders Cornelius family off bus; TriMet investigates Forest Grove confrontation 49 Matt Wingard&apos;s potential replacement in the House is &apos;not currently dating&apos; him 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most OregonLive.com comments in the last 7 days 97 Ziggy Ratzhield 95 StronzoB 81 Enoch Root 78 Seriously . . . 75 nwokie 
 

Users We Love
 Oregon high school football fan, &apos;chadicus01&apos; 
OregonLive.com contributor is part of our vibrant and diverse high school sports community. More Users We Love 
Connect with OregonLive.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
About Us

 About OregonLive.com Advertise with us Contact Us 

 Jobs at OregonLive.com FAQ 
 
Subscriptions

 Newsletters Text Alerts RSS Mix Magazine The Oregonian The Hillsboro Argus 
 
OregonLive.com Sections

 News Business Sports High School Sports Entertainment Living Travel Opinion 

 Obituaries Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Local Deals Local Businesses 
 
Your Regional News Pages

 Clackamas County Clark County Gresham 

 Portland Washington County More Local News 
 
Mobile

 Mobile site | iPhone, Android apps | Tablet Apps 
 
More on OregonLive.com

 Forums Videos Photos Interact with us Weather 

 Post a job Post a classified ad Sell your car Sell/rent your home Sitemap&amp;search 
 
Follow Us

 Twitter | Facebook | Google+ 
 
Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 Oregon Live LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of Oregon Live LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management. 

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
