<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004252" url="http://www.ebay.com/itm/PEETS-Coffee-20-oz-Venti-Go-Tumbler-Starbucks-Card-/360354717113" time="2012-07-12-20:30" support="3" score="0.0023504983452323925" bingtitle="eBay - New &amp; used electronics, cars, apparel, collectibles ..." webtitle="PEET&apos;S Coffee 20oz Venti RETIRED ToGo Cup Tumbler Old Brown Logo +Starbucks Card | eBay">
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001150" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001402" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>Buy and sell electronics, cars, clothing, apparel ... their origins and treat you like you are at a fast food restaurant ... will depend on shipping service selected and receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content 
 eBay Welcome, ( Sign in to bid or buy) 

 My eBay Sell Community Customer Support Cart 
 
 CATEGORIES   ELECTRONICS FASHION MOTORS TICKETS DEALS CLASSIFIEDS eBay Buyer Protection -- Learn more 
 
 Back to home page  |  
 Bread Crumb Link 
 Collectibles &gt; Advertising &gt; Food&amp;Beverage &gt; Coffee&amp;Tea &gt; Merchandise&amp;Memorabilia 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Click to view larger image 
 Zoom Enlarge 
 Mouse here to zoom in 
 
 
 Zoom Start of Layer End of Layer Have one to sell? Sell it yourself Avg Average price before paying applicable eBay and/or Paypal fees, calculated by determining the average selling price on eBay over the last 14 days for this used item in all conditions offered as buy it now or auction, excluding outlier selling prices as determined by eBay and does not include shipping and handling costs. No representation is made that a particular item will sell for a particular price. Start of Layer End of Layer 
PEET&apos;S Coffee 20oz Venti RETIRED ToGo Cup Tumbler Old Brown Logo +Starbucks Card
 
 
 Item condition: New US $21.95 Buy It Now Buy It Now Buy It Now Add to cart Add to cart Add to cart Add to Watch list Start of panel 
 Add to Watch list Add to Wish list 
 Sign in for more lists End of panel Add to a new list Please enter a valid name (Separate multiple list names with a comma.) Cancel Start of Layer End of Layer
	</body>
</document>
