<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004112" url="http://www.bizbuysell.com/eating-and-drinking-place-businesses-for-sale/" time="2012-07-12-20:21" support="3" score="0.004098081201052366" bingtitle="Eating &amp; Drinking Places For Sale - BizBuySell.com" webtitle="Eating&amp;Drinking Places For Sale - BizBuySell.com">
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="58"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Great opportunity to take over ... because of its great location and high-end ... These subs have a main meat condiment and vegetables ...</description>
	<body>
		Already a BizBuySell Member?

Log In to Continue
 


Invalid log in. Check your user name and password.
 Email Address (Member ID): Password: 
 Verifying... 
 
 Forgot Your Password? 

 Note : The email address you provided matches an existing account. Please log in using this email address and your original password. If you don&apos;t recall your password, click the &apos;Forgot Your Password?&apos; link.
 
 Are you new to BizBuySell? 
 
 
BizBuySell - The Internet&apos;s Largest Business for Sale&amp;Franchise for Sale Marketplace
 
 Welcome! Sign In Register For Brokers 

 My BizBuySell BrokerWorks 
 My Listings My Watch List My Saved Searches My BizAlerts My Ad Responses My Ad Inquiries My Valuation Reports My Community Questions My Community Answers My Profile 
 Sign Out For Brokers 
 
 
 
 

 Properly valuing small, family owned businesses and larger companies. Determining which businesses offer the greatest financial return. How to value a business and negotiate the price. And much more... 

 Enter email address: 
 Please note that you can opt out of the BizBuySell Bulletin at any time. 


 Eating&amp;Drinking Places For Sale 
 500+ Eating&amp;Drinking Place Businesses for Sale Found. 

Looking to buy a Eating&amp;Drinking Place business? There&apos;s a Coffee Shop, Catering Business or other Eating&amp;Drinking Places to meet your needs on BizBuySell. To ensure you are seeing all potential listings, click &quot;Business Categories&quot; in the search filters below to see other categories that may contain additional Eating&amp;Drinking Place related businesses. 
 
 
 1 2 ... 10 
 Save this Search 
Search Saved
 Get BizAlerts Start Search Over 
Refine Your Search

 Price Range to Gross Income Range to Cash Flow Range to Business Categories City or Keyword Business Location 
 State -Search ALL of US- Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming U.S. Territories Africa Asia/Pacific Australia/New Zealand Canada Caribbean Mexico/Central America Europe South America Hold CTRL to mutli-select 

 County Select one state above Hold CTRL to mutli-select 
 Show Only Seller Financed Listings with Disclosed Prices Show Businesses Listed 
 Anytime Last 3 Days Last 7 Days Last 30 Days 
 Home Based 
 Include Home-based Exclude Home-based Only Home-based 
 Relocatable Include Relocatable Businesses Broker Membership Exclude from Search IBBA M&amp;A Source OBBA NYABB MABIA Broker Certification Exclude from Search CBI M&amp;AMI 
 
Select Business Categories
 
RETAILING BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Apparel and Accessory Stores Automotive Dealers Bars/Taverns Blding Mat., Hardware, Garden Convenience Stores Florists Gasoline Service Stations General Merchandise Stores Home Furniture&amp;Furnishings 

 Liquor Stores Marine Dealers&amp;Equipment Miscellaneous Retail Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places Other Food Stores Pet Shops&amp;Supplies Restaurants Supermarkets Vending Machines 
 
SERVICE BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Agents&amp;Brokers Amusement&amp;Recreation Auto Repair, Parts&amp;Services Beauty Salons, Barber Shops Computer&amp;Software Services Drycleaning/Laundry Services Educational Services Engineering&amp;Accounting Svcs Finance, Banking, Loans, etc. Freight, Moving/Delivery Health, Medical&amp;Dental Hotels&amp;Other Lodging Places Landscaping&amp;Yard Services Legal Services 

 Marine Repair, Parts&amp;Services Membership Organizations Miscellaneous Repair Services Miscellaneous Services Motion Pictures Museums, Art Galleries, Zoos Other Business Services Other Personal Services Other Travel&amp;Transportation Passenger Transportation Pet Care&amp;Grooming Social Services Storage&amp;Warehousing Travel Agencies 
 
INTERNET BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Business Services (B2B) Consumer Services (B2C) Domain Name/Basic Site General Internet 

 ISP/ASP Services Software Web Design/Tech Services 
 
MANUFACTURING BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Apparel&amp;finished fabrics Chemicals&amp;Allied Products Electronic&amp;Electrical Equip. Fabricated Metal Products Food and Kindred Products Furniture and Fixtures Industrial&amp;Comm. Machinery Leather and Leather Products Lumber and Wood Products Measuring&amp;Analyzing Instr. 

 Miscellaneous Paper&amp;Allied Products Petroleum Refining Primary Metal Industries Printing, Publishing Rubber and Plastic Products Stone, Clay, Glass, Concrete Textile Mill Products Tobacco Products Transportation Equipment 
 
WHOLESALE/DIST. BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Durable Goods Nondurable Goods 
 
CONSTRUCTION BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Building Heavy Special Trades 
 
BUSINESS REAL ESTATE - Select All 

 For Lease For Sale 
 
 - Select All 

 Agriculture Communications Electric, Gas, Water, Sanitary Svcs Mining Non-classifiable Establishments 
 Cancel close 
Name Your Search
 Name: 
 cancel 
 close 
Your search has been saved
 
At any time, you may access all of your saved searches by going to My Saved Searches .

 
 
   Established Businesses for Sale Asking Price Cash Flow Location Hot Tex-Mex Restaurant with Loyal Customer... $200,000 $125,000 New York,... Burritoville Tex-Mex Restaurants for Sale   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This Tex-Mex Restaurant is part of a new breed of Tex-Mex with low operating costs,minimal staffing and easy operations criterion.Restaurant is in the heart of the Chelsea District in NYC. 7 day a week operation with both great on site and delivery business through both telephonic and internet ordering. Our customers are almost all repeat customers who rave about our... Established Bar and Grill $159,000 $61,227 Clark... Established Bar and Grill  

 Well established, profitable bar and grill in the Sioux Falls area. Restaurant has seating for 125, and comes complete with a remodeled and expanded kitchen, and great parking. Set on a busy corridor with good traffic, business has been growing the last few years. Good opportunity to acquire a successful restaurant!! Interactive Sports Bar&amp;Grill Franchise $45,000 Caddo... Interactive Sports Bar&amp;Grill Franchise  

 This interactive sports bar&amp;grill venue was created more than 22 years ago to meet a need that was missing as the time. This venue is a unique. They offer the best in sports programming on high definition televisions with pool, darts, video games, and food. They believe in active sports. They want their customers to participate in pool, darts or other activities to give... Neighborhood Bar and Grill $204,000 $77,460 Jackson... Neighborhood Bar and Grill  

 Neighborhood Sports Bar and Grill located near fast growing residential area. Full service menu (price range $$). 30+ Demographic. Current owners run a Texas Hold&apos;um tournament on Wednesdays, a trivia tournament on Fridays and live music on weekends. Enclosed and heated deck keeps smokers happy. Mexican style grill, sales growing, only $... $139,500 Carlsbad,Laj... Mexican style fast food grill,La Jolla, only $139k, $95k down   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Use your 401k or IRA with No Penalty. No experience is required to own this very well known, popular food grill. Seller very motivated, this is a beautiful Mexican cafe in the southern part of carlsbad/lajolla. A well known and established caribbean and mexican style grill. The finest and high quality foods include: tortas, tacos, burritos (includes, salmon, mahi-mahi,...   Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places $100,000 - $200,000 Lake Mary, FL Run a BizBuySell Valuation Report to view details of this business and other recently for sale and sold Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places .


   New Blimpie Sub Shop! Easy Terms $49,000 Northeast... NEW Blimpie Sub Shop! Easy Terms / Busy Location  

 Think you don&apos;t have enough to invest in / own your own business ? Think Again! Take Advantage of this existing Franchise Owner who spent over $200,000 to build out a new Blimpie Sub Shop 2 years ago and now has some family issues and must sell! Located in a SUPER location, extremely busy area, on main highway, 1/4 mile off a major interstate containing lake traffic... Pizza Delivery Restaurant (1608 $110,000 Dallas, TX... Pizza Delivery Business for Sale (1608)  

 Excellent Pizza Inn delivery business. This location has been established for more than 30 years and owned by the same owner for the last 10 years! Completely updated with new equipment. Average sales are approximately $30,000 per month with a low rent of $2,200. The business only offers pickup or delivery and there are more than 1,000 apartments in a 1 mile... Thai Restaurant. Great lease. Great Hell&apos;s... $249,000 $50,000 New York,... Thai Restaurant. Great lease. Great Hell&apos;s Kitchen Location!  

 This small Thai restaurant in Hell&apos;s Kitchen has 36 seats in 900 Square Feet (plus basement). The restaurant has an attractive lease with 6 years remaining. The landlord will probably extend this to a 10 year lease for the right buyer. Busy Smoothie Cafe $175,000 $94,176 Kendall, FL... Busy Smoothie Cafe  

 Reason for Sale:New business opportunity. Busy Smoothie Cafe next to a Nat&apos;l gym. Great lifestyle mall with many National anchors. Cafe serves, healthy smothies,salads,wraps&amp;more. Seating for 6 customers outside&amp;6 inside. Simple to run. Lease extends 2019.Owner benefit for an owner working 60 hours/wk. Ample parking. New owner can sell supplements. Ask for video tour... Popular Upscale Breakfast Restaurant For S... $51,000 $19,216 Bristol... Popular Upscale Breakfast Restaurant For Sale  

 Well established upscale breakfast restaurant. Breakfast, simply at its best. This restaurant is a well-known breakfast location and has a strong local community presence due to being in business at the same location for many years. Repeat customers are the norm and come in every week to experience high quality, fresh and healthy food that isn t over-priced. This...   Office Building Cafe $74,000 $34,330 Broward... Office Building Cafe  

 Reason for Sale:Opening larger restaurant. Office Building Cafe located in Coral Springs. Open M-F 7:30-4PM. No weekends. 5 story office bldg in the lobby in the heart of Coral Springs. Seating for 15 customers. Fully equipped kitchen with hood. Store Avg $377/day in sales. Catering /delivery. Ask for video tour. Simple to run/low overhead. $1708/mth rent includes... Fine Dining Midsized Italian Restaurant- 1... $465,000 $183,861 Coconut... Fine Dining Midsized Italian Restaurant- 17010  

 This restaurant enjoys a reputation for possibly the best midsize fine dining &apos;ristorante&apos; in S. FL. No expense spared buildout featuring the finest in decor, design&amp;equipment. Dinner only: 5-10PM. Seats 70 in main dining room, 30 in private room, 30 outside. Full liquor bar. Owner enjoys short hours but huge upside in opening for lunch, catering, or expanding next... Catering Company $349,000 $98,405 AR Catering Company  

 Family owned and operated business founded in 1980. This business was purchased by its current owners in 2008 and converted from a manually run mom and pop business to a fully computerized business with the ownership working more to grow the business than to participate in the daily operations. This business is not only a full service catering company. In addition, they... Mrs fields cookies $155,000 Orange... cookie store   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Mrs Fields Franchise , Profitable, Good Records, Employee Run, Newly Remodeled, Mall Location, includes Webstite , 25 years in same location buyer to vertify.. Old Mexico Grille $40,000 Keizer, OR... Old Mexico Grille   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Old Mexico Grille is located in the Keizer Village shopping center. The restaurant features excellent Mexican food in the cleanest restaurant one could eat in. The restaurant is most comfortable and does a very nice carry out business. Th lease amount is $ 2,400 per month and consists of 3,400 sq.ft. Hours are 11:00 am -9:00 pm 6 days closed on mondays. Dishwasher and ice...   Pizza Italian Restaurant Excellent Locatio... $199,000 $117,000 Palm Beach... Prime Location! Solid Customer Base! Growing Area! Financing!   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This is a busy, established restaurant with a secure, loyal customer base and it is a unique opportunity to purchase a restaurant in a geographic area that has major investment funds flowing into it. The area that this restaurant serves is drawing developers who feel that this area is the next investment hot spot, including a major outlet shopping center, with national... Upscale Deli, Music Venue&amp;Coffee Shop $7,500 Vineland,... Turnkey Deil/Coffee shop/Music Venue Needs Owner  

 ** TURNKEY OPERATION. MOVE IN AND OPEN IMMEDIATELY. USE OF ALL F&amp;F;INCLUDED IN LEASE. LEASE FOR ONLY $1,600 NNN PER MONTH !! ** Business is not operating at present time, but could be reopened immediately. This is a very interesting business opportunity for the right entrepreneur. If you have a background in Food Services, this is your chance to operate an upscale... Breakfast Lunch Restaurant Est 18 Yrs on M... $50,000 $50,000 Martin... Strong Customer Base! Main Highway!  

 Long established breakfast and lunch restaurant with a strong, repeat customer base. Same owner 18 years is turning 70 years old and no longer wishes to operate the business. Located on a main highway in a Publix Supermarket Shopping Center. The asking price is on a &quot;or best cash offer&quot; basis. No commission co-brokerage for brokers. Blimpie.Conyers Location.,.REDUCED for qui... $75,000 Conyers, GA... Reduced for quick sale  

 BE YOUR OWN BOSS.Well maintained Blimpie Franchise. CONYERS location.Upscale neighborhood.high profit margins.Good for family business. MONEY MAKER. $75,000 includes all equipments,furniture and fixtures.Call agent :Husain A Charaniya 678 637 5089.Great Atlanta Realty.SERIUS INQUIRES PLEASE.Please do not talk to employees. Well Presented Locally Recognized Restaura... $125,000 $33,475 Kent... Well Presented Locally Recognized Restaurant/Bakery For Sale   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This restaurant is an ideal purchase for someone who is looking to build on a well-established and locally recognized restaurant/bakery that has a strong potential for growth. They are known for their made-to-order high quality specialty sandwiches, fresh hot brick oven pizza/calzones, fresh made bakery goods and local coffee. Their main source of revenue is from... Put $175,000 in Your Retirement Account in... $325,000 $72,000 Mullica... Put $175,000 in Your Retirement Account in 3 Years  

 This is a great opportunity for the right buyer to earn some extra retirement money.This is a nicely positioned pretzel store franchise in an established and upscale suburban community. The store is located on a maor thoroughfare in town and is situated in a clean strip mall. This isa a neat, clean well-kept building with excellent signage and road visability. Turn-key Pizzeria $250,000 Sicklerville... Profitable Pizzeria  

 Well established, turn-key Pizzeria Business. Take out and delivery only. Great opportunity to walk right in and take over this family owned bueinss. Operating Deli with Catering Business and ... $349,000 Camden... Prifitable deli business with growth potential  

 Great Opportunity to own and operate your own business. This is a full service deli serving sandwiches, sliced lunchmeats and salads along with a very profitable catering business.The property includes an apartment with $580/month income, 2 car garage and on site parking for 10-12 cars. Popular Bar in Waikiki, Honolulu,HI $320,000 $76,000 Honolulu,... Popular Bar in Waikiki for sale  

 Popular Neighborhood bar in the heart of Waikiki. Great clientele mix of local residents and tourists who return year after year. Two owned condo units with 24+ years left on very low land lease. Full bar and small kitchen serving hoagies and pupus (appetizers). Also featuring darts and nightly Karaoke. Owner must move to the mainland for family reasons or I&apos;d never... The Harrison Building - One Shot Charlie&apos;s $845,000 Harrison,... The Harrison Building - One Shot Charlie&apos;s Tavern&amp;More!  

 One Shot Charlie&apos;s, housed in the Harrison Building (circa 1917), is well known over a large geographic area for their great family atmosphere, super food in their cafe restaurant, and great bands that book there during the summer. And it doesn&apos;t hurt that they have a view of Lake Coeur d&apos;Alene, being positioned just above the &quot;Trail of the Coeur d&apos;Alenes&quot; bicycle trail... Restaurant-bar-banquets-catering $2,649,000 $600,000 Media, PA... Restaurant-Bar-Banquets-Catering (Property w/wo Business 4 sale)  

 Property&amp;Business for sale. RE only purchase is also available. 10,000 square feet of recently renovated (2008) restaurant, bar and banquet facilities complete with outdoor patio, over 100 parking spaces, 2 full commercial kitchens (perfect for Catering operations), and 1000sq ft of offices space! Rt 1&amp;Rt 252... 1 turn off of 476 or Baltimore pike. Densely... Coffee House/Cafe located in historic buil... $25,000 Winsted, CT... Adorable Cafe and Coffee House   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Adorable cafe with organic coffee and espresso bar located at a busy intersection near town green and community college in Winsted, CT. We have a vegetarian menu, home made Italian sodas, frappes, and smoothies. Outdoor seating, indoor lounging...someone with a creative mind could do a lot with this space. We are currently in business, and would be happy to train if... Tower Deli $120,000 $96,000 Century... Tower Deli   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Annual Discretionary Earnings of $96,000 and revenue of $228,000 for a 5 Days Deli&amp;Sandwiches offering 1800+/- Sq. Ft. of Space with 32 seats inside a tower building at 90% Occupancy, in the middle of walking ... High-rise office towers on Century Park Boulevard is NOW available for sale. The Business is positioned to be a significant primarily from repeat business and... Restaurant - Mediterranean style-4-cop-srx... $395,000 Dunedin, FL... Restaurant - Mediterranean style-4-cop-srx/2 patio&apos;s Hot Loc.   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Great Location for a CHEF owner operator to have his Dream. Hot Location Free standing Building Low rent. of only $2,400 per month with 8 Years left on lease. There is about 4,000 Sqft of newly remodeled space. with ample parking, this is a free standing building in a very prime location. They have nightly entertainment live Jazz- etc This is fully turn key and if you... Authentic Greek Restaurant with Low Rent $139,000 $81,000 Mid-Suffolk,... RENT $1,656 MONTH   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This Attractive Greek Restaurant /Take-out has an Authentic Greek Specialty Menu and a RIDICULOUSLY LOW MONTHLY RENT. It is located on a busy Main Street in the Heart of Town in Mid-Suffolk County. The Seller will finance with 60% down. ***A GREAT CHEF / OWNER OPPORTUNITY*** *** For more info, call John Stefan of JS Business Brokers at 631-473-2973 ***For the Exact... Three Hot RED MANGO Yogurt Franchise Store... $375,000 FL Three Hot Red Mango Yogurt Franchise Stores   $ Seller Financing Available 

 College town USA . Own three hot and in demand RED MANGO yogurt franchise stores. Open over two years. Fully staffed and operational. 180 franchise stores already open across the nation. Voted by Zagat as Best Smoothie/Frozen Yogurt. Three open stores and doing business are included in the price.Three franchise rights are also included in the price. Pictures are available... Torys Cafe serving breakfast&amp;lunch 7 day... $75,000 $50,000 Clearwater,... Torys Cafe serving breakfast&amp;lunch 7 days a week   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Torys cafe seats 40 location excellent 25 years in business great business for husband&amp;wife team. well established loyal following. money maker. Family restaurant $295,000 Pinellas... Family restaurant   $ Seller Financing Available 

 GREAT FAMILY RESTAURANT NEAR MANY CONDO&apos;S AND HOMES. GREAT CONCEPT ON HIGHLY TRAVELED ROAD. NEEDS A FAMILY OR GREAT COOK TO KEEP IT GOING. Call me 24/7 for an appointment to see this great location at 727-461-9899 ask for A. J. Della Monica Broker Pizza! Two Shops Available $170,000 $120,000 Crystal... $  

 That s right two great pizza shops available in Crystal Lake area. Shops can be purchased individually or together. Asking price for each shop is $170K. Best pizza in town. Pickup, Delivery or Pizza by the slice with a Pop . Looking for established profitable business with well known name and excellent reputation in community . This is it! Serious buyers only. Owner has... High Volume/Very Profitable Classic All-Am... $550,000 $225,000 Downtown... Very Profitable - Cash flow 2011 = $225k!   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Serving simple, great-tasting food from a menu of all-American favorites including hamburgers, hotdogs, Italian beef, classic sandwiches, fries and rich, delicious hand-dipped shakes&amp;malts. Counter service dine in or take out. Turn key operation! Prime retail space A+. In the heart of the theater district in downtown Chicago next to the famous Chicago Theater,... High Volume/Very Profitable Local Deli Fra... $550,000 $245,000 Downtown... Extremely Profitable ! easy to run   $ Seller Financing Available 

 A highly successful local deli offering a wide selection of fresh breads, hand-sliced meats&amp;cheeses combined with unique ingredients to create over sixteen incredible sandwiches, along with Chicago style hotdogs, chili&amp;soups. Everything from deli classics, delicious salads and desserts to gourmet coffee and fresh juices. Also serving breakfast, which includes a... Very Successful Fast Food Chicken Restaura... $779,000 $240,000 Somerset... Very Successful Fast Food Chicken Restaurant Franchise   $ Seller Financing Available 

 **STEADY PROFIT**LOCATION**SIMPLE MENU**FINANCING**TURN KEY WITH FRANCHISE SUPPORT** This HOT concept started in 1971 and has been in the United States since 2002. An instant favorite among locals, there are over 300 stores worldwide and 50 locations across the Country. Get in early with opportunities to open multiple units or just run the one location. This successful... Pizzeria Take Out and Delivery-Big Profits $175,000 $80,000 Middlesex... Pizzeria Take Out and Delivery-Big Profits   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Brand New Small Pizzeria. Everything looks great inside. Very easy to operate and making BIG PROFITS. 70% of this Business is Delivery and 30% is Take Out. Equipment includes Double Decker Pizza Oven, Large Dough Mixer, Hood Vent with Grill, Fryer, Stove and Stand Up Refrigerator and Freezer. LOW LOW RENT of only $800 per month. Located near a lot of residential and... Italian Restaurant in Santa Monica $160,000 $70,000 Santa... Italian Restaurant in Santa Monica  

 A casual Italian restaurant uniquely located on Santa Monica Blvd a few blocks from “3rd street promenade” is available For sale. 1000 sq. ft. of space/ Monthly RENT of ONLY $1,200/mo. Including utility bill. (Gas bill) 7 Days operation, Fully equipped, Fully Staffed, Great chef, Seats 25 people inside and 8 outside. 10 Parking spaces In addition to the valet... Restaurant - Commissary For Sale $275,000 Rye Brook,... Restaurant - Commissary For Sale   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This 3,135 square foot family operated country market/restaurant is located in an upscale Rye Brook, NY community surrounded by 261 luxury single family homes. Serving breakfast, lunch and dinner, the space consists of a 1,500 square foot main dining area, an approximately 1,600 square foot kitchen and an additional 1,000 square foot outdoor patio dining area. The kitchen... Hilton Head&apos;s Best Restaurant $150,000 $130,000 Hilton... Hilton Head&apos;s Best Restaurant  

 Restaurant is famous for its bread (baked fresh to order) and food. Has been a locals favorite for years most dinning weekly. Great reputation with 22 years in business. Great lease 3,608 per mo. for 1,968 sq ft. 40-50 seats outside, 60 seats main room, 28 seat back room. Owner suggest new ower split restaurant in half (28 seats in back) and do pasta/pizza with delivery... Five Star BBQ $250,000 $80,000 Winston-Sale... Five Star BBQ  

 This is a busy Lexington-style BBQ spot on a busy highway in Forsyth County thousands of cars a day pass right by the door. It currently has sales of $650,000. split between dine-in, take-out and catering. The current owners have been working it for twenty plus years and have made a very comfortable living from it. Now it s time to throttle back and take it easy. With new... Hottest Thing in the Ice Cream Biz-Liquid ... $149,000 $69,459 Orlando... Hottest Thing in the Ice Cream Biz-Liquid Nitrogen!   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Hottest thing in the ice cream biz-Liquid Nitrogen! This mobile N2 system produces premium ice creams, sorbets, gelatos&amp;more. Chef inspired recipes, dazzling smoke&amp;sound show make this EXTREMELY PROFITABLE, turnkey biz the center of any event! Solid client base produces steady cash flow-needs a marketing savvy new owner to tap new markets. Sideline opportunity selling... High Volume/Profitable Red Mango Yogurt Fr... $395,000 $164,000 Bellevue,... Extremely Profitable Yogurt Franchise !  

 A hot new franchise, which offers award winning all natural non-fat frozen yogurt paired with fresh delicious toppings. The perfect venue for today s health-conscious consumers serving a variety of frozen yogurts, parfaits, smoothies, iced beverages and now serving hot chocolate. Simple operation, small footprint, and rapidly growing product category. Prime retail... Self-Serve Frozen Yogurt Store. *No Franch... $179,000 $105,000 Somerset... Self-Serve Frozen Yogurt in NJ! Complete turn key operation  

 Great Self-Serve Yogurt Shop for sale in Somerset county, NJ. **Lucrative cash business** Complete turn key operation. An absolute must see! You will become part of a recession-resistant business as the Frozen Yogurt Industry continues to grow at an amazing pace! Baskin Robbins Franchise $139,000 $55,000 Frederick... Great oppotunity  

 This successful business is the franchisee of the most popular ice cream chain with over 6,000 stores in 35 countries. All remodeling and update has been done and current owner has been running the business for almost 5 years. Franchisor provide training and support in all aspect of business operation including HR, Marketing, Financial report, cost control, sales and... Cold Stone - Top Performing Ice Cream Busi... $297,800 $92,000 Centennial,... Cold Stone - Top Performing Ice Cream Business in Colorado   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This is one of the most profitable Ice Cream stores in Colorado. With over $400k in Gross Sales and nearly $100k in Cash Flow, this business is a solid investment and is pre qualified for SBA financing with around $60k downpayment. The mission of this business is simple, they offer only the best tasting Ice Cream, Smoothies, Shakes, and Cakes for the best price with... Downtown Spokane Profitable Wine Bar and S... $115,000 $55,000 Spokane, WA... Beautiful Spokane Wine Bar and Small Plat Biz 4 Sale. Profits!  

 Nice Profits. Beautiful Buildouts and Furniture. Turnkey. - 1,113 SF± Seats 49 Monthly Rent: $2,116 All Inclusive Full Service Lease (Landlord Pays NNN&amp;CAM Expenses) All Furniture, Fixtures&amp;Equipment Included in the Sale Beautiful downtown Spokane wine bar&amp;small plate restaurant located in a well known historic building in the heart of downtown The owner’s... Classic Neighborhood bar over 60 years Ful... $199,000 $80,100 Tampa, FL... Downtown Liquor Bar Cash Flow 80K Only 99K Down!  

 An extremely rare opportunity to own a classic full liquor bar with a (4 COP license) with over a 60 year history in the downtown area. Positioned well for this years 2012 Republican convention with it&apos;s ample parking and courtyard. Excellent books and records as well as fully staffed and run semi-absentee as all tools are in place for off site owner. Favorable lease... Pizza Restaurant - 21798 $185,000 $132,260 New Haven... Pizza Restaurant - 21798   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Busy Pizza store located next to a Dunkin Donuts and across from a Subway. Location gets foot traffic all day long. Located in a busy downtown area very close to a city Hospital and near a university. There is NO local Pizza competition and the menu is varied. The store is 1800 sq ft with an incredibly low rent and long lease. Great opportunity will go fast!   
 Related Franchises View all Franchise Opportunities that match your search criteria. 
 $207,000 - $587,000 Capital Required 

 Joey Bag a Donuts 

 Joey Bag a Donuts is your way to own one of the most competitive donut shop franchises in the business! We will provide you with an efficient system that allows you to bring the nostalgia... 
 
 $1,995 Capital Required 

 Boozelator™ Breathalyzer Vending Business 

 The Boozelator™ 3001 is a much needed safety product for any alcohol-serving establishment. Awesome growth potential and LOW start-up cost! 
 
 $80,000 Capital Required 

 Bella Pita 

 Fresh and Healthy Mediterranean Cuisine! 
 
 
 List your Business for Sale on BizBuySell 
 Page: 1 2 3 4 5 ... 10 
 
Browse Popular Retail Businesses
 
 Apparel Stores Auto Dealerships Bars&amp;Taverns Convenience Stores Flower Shops Food Companies 

 Furniture&amp;Home Decorating Gas Stations General Merchandise Stores Liquor Stores Marine Dealers and Services 

 Pet Shops for Sale Restaurants Retail Businesses Supermarkets Vending Machines 
 
Browse Popular Service Businesses
 
 Auto Parts Businesses Auto Repair Businesses Banks&amp;Mortgage Lenders Beauty Salons Brokerage Firms Business Services Computer&amp;Software Services Day Care Centers 

 Dry Cleaners Education Companies Entertainment and Recreation Financial Companies Health Care Companies Hotels and Motels Landscaping&amp;Gardening 

 Laundromats Medical&amp;Dental Businesses Passenger Transportation Companies Personal Services Pre-Schools Storage&amp;Warehousing Travel&amp;Transportation 
 
Browse Popular Franchises
 
 Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Child Related Cleaning And Maintenance 

 Computer And Internet Food And Restaurant Health, Beauty, and Fitness High Capital Franchises Home Based Businesses 

 Home Services Low Cost Franchises Retail Franchises Sports And Recreation Travel And Lodging 
 
 About BizBuySell 

BizBuySell is the leading online marketplace for both finding and selling businesses available for sale. Due to our industry leading traffic, more business sellers choose BizBuySell as their marketplace of choice. That means if you are looking for new Eating&amp;Drinking Place business opportunities, you can find the best selection of what&apos;s available right here, including Pizzeria, Catering Business, Coffee Shop and other great Eating&amp;Drinking Place businesses.

If you don&apos;t find what you are looking for, don&apos;t fret. Consider setting an email alert and we&apos;ll notify you each time a business matching your criteria becomes available, or better yet, try contacting a business broker with experience in the Eating&amp;Drinking Place industry. 
Search for Eating&amp;Drinking Place Businesses For Sale

Browse by State

 Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
   x 
Be First to Know with BizAlerts
 

Get free alerts via email when new businesses are listed matching your Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places search criteria.

BizAlert Email Frequency
 Daily Alerts Summary Emails 
 Weekly Alerts 
 Realtime Alerts Individual Emails 
Save This Search
 Save Search to MyBizBuySell 
 Submit cancel 
 OK 
 Retry 
Name Your Search
 
 Name: 
 OK cancel 
 
 
 
 
 advertise terms&amp;conditions privacy policy about us contact us careers site map mobile 
 
 
 
©1996 - 2012 BizBuySell.com®   |
	</body>
</document>
