<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004361" url="http://www.my3cents.com/showReview.cgi?id=69583" time="2012-07-12-20:36" support="5" score="0.016545134366357135" bingtitle="My3cents.com - Burger King Informative - False Advertising ..." webtitle="Burger King Informative - False Advertising: Misrepresentation of Product - All Sandwiches">
			<query id="000815" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001290" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000838" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000842" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000843" bing-rank="31"/>
	<description>They have professional &apos;food artists&apos; who work for ... Close examination shows it to be made of plastic and who ... Meal did not look like the Happy Meal on the menu board.</description>
	<body>
		Write a Review  
 
 Consumer News, Tips&amp;Recalls Newsletter 

 Email: 
 
 

 
 Home &gt; Food Services &gt; Restaurants &gt; Burger King &gt; 
 Burger King Informative

 False Advertising: Misrepresentation of Product - All Sandwiches 

Review by The Lorbz on 2010-01-04 
 1 
 Helpful Votes 
 
   

 Does anyone else notice, at least here in the New York City area, how the actual products (Burgers, Fish, Chicken) never look like the picture above the cash registers or drive throughs? If you look at the pictures of, say, their hamburgers, they always appear almost higher than they are wider. That would mean, based on the current diameter, burgers should be no less than 3 inches high. Why is this variance between what you see prior to purchase and what you get become an accepted norm? As much as I would love for Burger King (or any restaurant)to change the product to truly represent the advertised items, (They look so much better) I would accept some honesty and wish they were required to display a true representation of their products based on production facts.

Anybody with me on this. How&apos;s about a class action suit! 


 Comments (19) Next Burger King Review &gt;&gt; 


 


 Did you find this review helpful?    Yes     No 


 Got something to say?
Help other consumers by sharing
your experiences on My3cents. 

 
 
 

 
 
 
M3C User Discussion
 


 Posted by Tennboy1981 on 2010-01-04 
Oh lord. They have been doing that for as long as Ive been alive. And I&apos;m 28. Yeah you go ahead and file a lawsuit. Let&apos;s see which lawyer is wacky enough to take the case....The burgers on TV that they show, Ive heard arent even actually REAL. They are made of clay or plastic. They can&apos;t even make a REAL burger look like that. If you want that kind of burger, youre going to spend more than $3.99 for it. give me a break. 

 Posted by goduke on 2010-01-04 
And yet you keep going back. Hmmm. 

 Posted by Inat on 2010-01-04 
well, they go back b/c the food perfume that makes them taste &apos;flame broiled&apos; is just too delicious... 

 Posted by Class Advocate on 2010-01-04 
You think BK is bad, you should the variance between what I look like and my pictures on match.com! 

 Posted by Ytropious on 2010-01-04 
Tenn, the burgers are indeed real, but the fries and drink can be fake. If they are advertising a burger it must be made of actual food product. Whether or not it&apos;s made of a real hamburger is up for debate, but whatever they make it out of must be edible. 

 Posted by goduke on 2010-01-04 
I&apos;ll bet they cover it in that breakfast cereal preservative that Clark Griswold invented..... 

 Posted by justthefaxx on 2010-01-04 
It&apos;s called &quot;Marketing&quot; and it works since you keep going there. 

 Posted by bearkatkitten on 2010-01-04 
&quot;How&apos;s about a class action suit!&quot;

And what would you sue for exactly?
 

 Posted by Slimjim on 2010-01-04 
Who exactly would be the injured class? Those maliciously harmed by a burger they happily ate anyway that didn&apos;t look like a picture? 

 Posted by zzrokk on 2010-01-04 
Outside of an impending dry cleaning bill, I see nothing misleading about the sandwich shown below.
It&apos;s fast food not a work of ART!

http://danhaberkorn.files.wordpress.com/2009/03/mcdonalds-fillet-o-fish.jpg 

 Posted by Face to Face on 2010-01-04 
what are you,new?

the pix never look like what you end up slopping down 

 Posted by Starlord on 2010-01-04 
They have professional &apos;food artists&apos; who work for hours to get those photographs of perfect food. It is absolutely correct that the food they are showing in the menu photo is real, as per the Federal Trade Commission. Campbell&apos;s soup got fined an obscene amount of money one time for putting clear marbles in soup bowls to make it appear there were more noodles and chicken chunks in their soup than there really was. They are allowed to use tricks like painting a turkey with a common kitchen food additive to make it look much better than if it were really roasted. or using electrical charcoal starters to give meat those nice grill marks. Check out your local Subway. Many of them have a sandwich under a plastic cover. Close examination shows it to be made of plastic and who knows what. As pointed out, it is called &apos;Marketing,&apos; and is perfectly legal, as long as they follow the rules. Any attorney you ask about a class action suit based on this will laugh you out of his office. 

 Posted by redmx3racer on 2010-01-04 
I first noticed that in 1983. I was 5 at the time, and upset that my Happy Meal did not look like the Happy Meal on the menu board. My Dad told me to eat it and shut up. :) 

 Posted by LadyScot on 2010-01-04 
Red, sounds like my dad. Though today&apos;s parents would be screaming at the cashier about it.

I saw a documentary once on how cereal commercials are done...the actual consumed version uses milk, the &apos;sitting and photographing&apos; bowl uses GLUE on the cereal instead of milk. It sits better and won&apos;t soggy up the flakes. 

 Posted by littleyaya on 2010-01-04 
I hate to break this to you as well, but the girls in those commercials for the chat lines aren&apos;t the same girls you talk to on the phone. 

 Posted by redmx3racer on 2010-01-04 
Ladyscot-tell me about it. These days telling a kid to shut up might get you reported to child services for abuse! 

 Posted by Crown Jules on 2010-01-04 
BA, Starlord. OP, I&apos;m sure you can have a burger that looks like the ones in the commercials and pictures if you&apos;re willing to wait a few hours but this is fast food we&apos;re talking about here. Why do people get so up in arms about the way food looks at a fast food place, anyway? If I were at a high-end restaurant and paying $50 for an entree, then presentation counts, not so much for a $2-$3 burger. 

 Posted by Class Advocate on 2010-01-04 
I once paid $124.95 for a burger in Vegas. (Actually the casino bought me a meal so I did not pay for it.) Actually a very good burger. Even that one though does not look as good as the ones on BK&apos;s signs. 

 Posted by azspots on 2010-01-04 
With all the really great food in NYC, why in God&apos;s green earth would you eat at BK? 

 

   Login/Register to Add Your 3 Cents!  |  Or Add a Comment Without Registering 

 
 
 

 Burger King Tools&amp;Resources: Company Rating: 
 Rate this company: 
 Read our Burger King consumer report featuring reviews, contact info and more Compare ratings of other companies in this industry 

 

 Burger King Reviews By Product: 

 Reviews by product/service Food (62) Drive Thru (27) 



 Community Tools: 

 Read comments (19) Consumers: Add your 3 cents to this review! Business Owner? Post your company response! Write a review on this company 
 


 

 
 More Reviews on Burger King: 
 Unprofessional Service - Fast Food Filthy Establishment - Eating Area Poor Service and Unprofessional Staff - Custumer Service Company Not Answering Phone 25 Minute Wait at Drive Thru 
 

 

 

 Consumer Tools | My Account | Write a Review | Compare Company Ratings Businesses: Respond to Consumers HOME | FAQ | Advertise | About Us | Site Rules | Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy | RSS 


 Copyright 2000-2012 My3cents, LLC  Browse in another language
	</body>
</document>
