<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004992" url="http://jupiterfox.deviantart.com/art/fifi-la-fume-meets-a-bully-108783588" time="2012-07-12-21:31" support="1" score="0.0015001951187496314" bingtitle="fifi la fume meets a bully by ~jupiterfox on deviantART" webtitle="fifi la fume meets a bully by ~jupiterfox on deviantART">
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>Sarah:damn,aint got no real food in this place ... Babs,Shirley and Fifi decide to go to a fast food restaurant after ... Joker:yeh,just get me my food Punk Ass. Babs Bunny ...</description>
	<body>
		deviantART 
 Browse Art Prints Shop T-Shirts&amp;Gear Groups Deviants 
 Sta.sh dA muro Chat Journals Today Forum Find More Art 
 Daily Deviations Discover beta Critiques Critiqueable Wallpaper Random 
 Random Deviant Random Deviation Random Group 
 
 Search Username or Email 

 Password 
 Stay logged in 
 Login 
 Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour Lost Password? Deviant Login Buy Art Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear Buy adCast Buy Premium Upgrade Shop   Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour 
 Add to Favourites Download File 
 HTML download, 14.8 KB [x] 
 More from ~ jupiterfox 
 View Gallery 
Featured in Groups:
 Not currently featured in any groups. 
Details
 Submitted: January 7, 2009 
 File Size: 14.8 KB
 Thumb 
 
Statistics
 Comments: 0
 Favourites: 3 [ who? ]
 Views: 434 (0 today) 
 Downloads: 11 (0 today) 
 To [friends] Message fifi la fume meets a bully Fifi La Fume Meets A Girl Skunk

This is a fanfiction about fifi la fume meeting a new girl skunk at school.Fifi is happy to see another girl skunk at her school.But the skunk causes trouble at the school and even gets fifi into trouble.read more to find out.

.note:i dont own fifi la fume or any other tiny toon characters.All belong to warner brothers.

Its a beautiful day at acme looniversity. People are hanging out near the campus and relaxing.Classes were about to begin.
not far away a male skunk and a female skunk walk towards the school.the male skunk is the father with his daugher.he is a slim and meek middle class red skunk with gla 
      [x] 
 
fifi la fume meets a bully
 by ~ jupiterfox 

Fifi La Fume Meets A Girl Skunk


This is a fanfiction about fifi la fume meeting a new girl skunk at school.Fifi is happy to see another girl skunk at her school.But the skunk causes trouble at the school and even gets fifi into trouble.read more to find out.

.note:i dont own fifi la fume or any other tiny toon characters.All belong to warner brothers.

Its a beautiful day at acme looniversity. People are hanging out near the campus and relaxing.Classes were about to begin.
not far away a male skunk and a female skunk walk towards the school.the male skunk is the father with his daugher.he is a slim and meek middle class red skunk with glasses,short hair and a dress suit with a tie and a mustache.he is about 35 years old.His daughter is also red and a slighly plump tomboy skunk with black sunglasses,a red bandana,long straight hair,and  a baseball jersey and earrings on her ears and nose.she is 15 years old.

father:now sarah,I want you to make a good impression on your first day here.It was difficult to transfer you from supertoon university.
sarah:whatever pops.
father:no,im serious.be a good girl.please stay out of trouble.

Fifi La Fume  and shirley the loon watch the two skunks in curiosity.

The girl Skunk and her father enter the school building and enter the principal&apos;s office.The principal is Bugs Bunny.

Bugs Bunny:Oh good.Ive been expecting the both of you. Simon Rose and Sarah Rose.Please,make yourselfs at home.Im bugs bunny,the principal
Simon;thank you Mr.Bugs
Bugs Bunny:Now I understand your daughter is a transfer student.i just want to understand, why did she transfer
Simon:Well,its my new job.You see im an architect and ive been relocated at work.I had to tranfeer by daughter because her old school is too far away now.
Bugs:Okay,well your child will be taken care of at acme looniverity.Its a nice shcool with a great learning enviornment and lots of clubs and sports.oh forget my manners.he looks at sarah.its nice to meet you sarah.he holds out his hand to her.
Sarah:whaterver.
Simon:thats no way to introduce yourself,young lady
Sarah:whats up bugs.she gives him a handshake.
Bugs:are you excited about your new school.
Sarah:i guess.i mean, its different.i miss my old school
Bugs:dont worry,youll get along just fine.are you a good student.
Simon;well she had some behavior problems in her old school.fights,disrespect for teachers.but I think it was because of the negative enviornent of the school.peer pressure.she certainly didnt learn that behavior from me.
Bugs:well i assure you,Mr. Rose,we dont tolerate any of that here.She will behave.And the kids are generally good.no real trouble makers.so no negative peer pressure.
Simon:well,im happy to know that.
Bugs:Sarah,here is your planner,your class schedule.your teachers will give out your books in class.And Im gonna need the tuition.He nods to Simon
Simon:Here you go sir.He gives bugs a big stack of cash.
Bugs:Have a nice day.He gives Simon and Sarah a handshake.Good luck sarah.

Simon and Sarah both leave his office and Simon begins to walk out from the school.

Simon:please do well,sarah.okay.
Sarah:whateva,pops.
It was lunchtime at acme looniversity so sarah went to the cafeteria.she went up to the lunchlady and got a lunch tray.
lunchlady gets out a wad of nasty old meatloaf and puts it on her tray.
Sarah:What is this shit.i aint eatin that.
The Lunchlady just frowns and tells her to move along
Sarah:damn,aint got no real food in this place.theres better food in jail.she gets a milk and an apple

Fifi,Babs Bunny and Shirley are sitting at a table and watches Sarah get her lunch.
Fifi:A new skunk. Its nice to have another female skunk at school.I wonder wahts she like???
Babs:she looks pretty cool.Invite her over.
Fifi waves her hand at the skunk.She walks over.
Fifi:bonjour,Im fifi la fume what is your name.
Sarah:Joker.
Fifi:your name eezz Joker.okay.zat eeez a weird name
Sarah:man you talk funny.mocks fifi:bonjour,i am fifi la fume.acts girlish
Babs and shirely just just laugh.
Fifi:eets not funny.i talk like zat because i am french.
Joker:chill i was just playin.you are oversensitve sista.we cool right.gives her a hand pound..
Babs:Joker,why is your name Joker.is that your nickname.are you the class clown or something.i goof off in class myself.
Joker:you can say its my nickname.see this large black mark around my eye. i painted it.she takes off her sunglasses.i cant remember when i exaclty thought the name joker up.i guess i was thinking of joker from batman.his facepaint  expresses himself as a  villain. my facepaint is like war paint that soldiers wear.it expresses that im a strong woman.im not the girl you want to mess with.
Fifi:I like zat.I think its good to be a strong woman.to have a positive personallity.
Joker:did yall try this cafeteria food.its disgusting.it makes me want to barf
Shirley:yeh, i think the meat is alive.her mealoaf walks up and moves from her tray.

Joker looks around.she seems hampton j pig eating a large lunch.he has a feast.the food looks really tasty.he has enough to feed 30 people.

Joker walks over to hampton&apos;s table

Joker:what you eatin fat boy.
Hampton:oh, just the usual.hey i havent seen you around here before.are you new.
Joker:yup,let me have your lunch.
Hampton;well, i could share it with you.just take what you want
Joker:naw, i want all of it.
Hampton:i think its better to share.
Joker:you think im playing dont you fat boy.
Hampton:please, dont call me fat boy.im sensitive about my weight.
Joker:I SAID GIVE ME YOUR LUNCH!!!!
Hampton:look if you are gonna be mean like that you cant have any.i wont share any of it with you.
Joker:oh you think you tough now.you think you a big man.She begins to push hampton.
Hampton:yeh, stop that.thats not nice.he gets out of his seat.he begins to walk away.Joker grabs him by his shirt and pulls him close to her.She then beings to beat him up.She is much bigger than him so he is defenseless.Fifi and babs sees whats happening to hampton
Fifi:What eezz happening.shes attacking poor Hampton.
Babs:damn.hampton is getting his ass wooped .

Fifi walks over to where Joker and Hampton are,.she pushes Joker.
Joker:what are you doing.who do you think you are pushing me.
Fifi:stop picking on hampton.he didnt do anything to you
Joker:that fat ass wont give me his lunch like i asked him. i asked nice.hey why dont you help me beat him up.its fun.Joker is about to punch hampton again when yosmete sam comes over.

Yosemete Sam:what are you varments doing
Fifi breaks Hampton and Joker up.Fifi:Oh nothing,We were just playing with each other.
Yosemete Sam:looks like fightin to me
Fifi:Oh no,She was just giving hampton friendly punches.you know.friends have different handshakes and everything.
Joker;oh yes,she helps hampton up.me and him are good freinds.he puts her arm around hampton in a friendly way.
Yosemete Sam:well you varments have strange ways of playin with each other.well i guess i wouldnt understand sense its been awhile ive been a youngster.sorry ive bothered you.he walks away.
Joker lets go of Hampton.Joker:well.lunch is almost over.so ill let you get away fat boy.she pushes him away.
Fifi:zat was close.ive hoped you learned your lesson.
Joker:thanks fifi,you got me out of trouble.you are down with me.Puts her hand around fifi&apos;s shoulder.from now on we are friends,sistas.
Fifi:well,okay.but eet was wrong of you to be so mean to hampton.i want you to be nice to him from now on
Joker:hey,look i promise,i will be nice to fat boy.i swear, i will be a sweet skunk.
Fifi:well,lets get to class soon or we will be late.They both go to daffy ducks class.
After all the classes the students leave the building.Porky Pig gave out tons of homework
Joker and Fifi walk out of class together.
Joker:hey,fifi,i think im gonna have trouble wit this homework.do you think you can mabeye,um do it for me.
Fifi:why cant you do it yourself.
Joker:i got shit to do.hey friends do stuff for each other.you are my friend arent you.
Fifi:well,yes but.
Joker:come on fifi.please.pleasse.here i got something for you.gives Fifi her sunglasses.its a token of our freindship.im gonna let you have these.these are my special sunglasses.and you are my special friend.my soul sista
Fifi:fifi gets emotional from Joker&apos;s gift.she hugs her.thank you Joker.okay,okay,i will do your homework for you.but just this once okay.
Joker:I knew i could count on you.
the next day all the students go to class.Babs has the same classes with fifi and Joker.They go to Porky Pig&apos;s Class.Fifi is nowhere to be seen.
Babs:hey,joker have you seen fifi.
Joker:nope,i wonder where she could be.In her mind(I hope she gets here soon with my homework.)
Porky:okay kids let me take the class roll. Plucky duck
Plucky:here.
Fifi walks into class.
Porky:um fifi you are five minutes late.im gonna let you slide this time but next time,im gonna have to give you a late slip.
Fifi:okay monsiour pig.Fifi looks terrible.She has bags under her eyes and her hair is messed up.she barely got any sleep from doing her and Joker&apos;s homework.she sits next to Joker and Babs
Fifi:here.she hands joker her homework.You are lucky.Porky Pig barely checks the homework.he glances at it so he wont notice my handwriting.
Joker:thanks sista.
Porky checks everyones homework and like fifi said he barely checks the kids homework.After all the classes are done,the students get a big test from elmer fudd.its about advanced algebra.
Babs,Shirley and Fifi decide to go to a fast food restaurant after class.Fifi asks Joker to go with them so she wont feel left out.
In the restaurant the girls all start talking.
Babs:that test elmer fudd gave is gonna be hard.you gotta study a lot for that.
Fifi:yeh,i dont wanna fail it.its the most important test of the semester.
They walk up to the cashier guy to order who is montana max
Babs:so what you gonna order fifi.
Fifi:im just gonna get a cheesburger
Shilrey:im gonna get the veggie burger.
Babs:yeh, i think im just gonna get a cheesburger.got that richie rich. she talks to montana max
Joker:let me get 5 jumbo burgers,3 jumbo milkshakes and 4 large fries and 2 apple pies
Babs:wow,that is a lot of food Joker
Joker:Im a girl who likes to eat.
Montana Max:you gonna eat all that at once.you are a pig.hahahaha
Joker:say that again, punk. i dare you.
Montana:I said,you are a greedy  pi-------Before he can finish, Joker punches him and gives him a black eye.
Montana is now scared of her.he starts crying.okay okay,im sorry,i  dont want any trouble.
Joker:yeh,just get me my food Punk Ass.
Babs Bunny gives Joker a high five.nice punch.that jackass Montana Max got what he deserved.
Shirley:yeh,that black eye looks like its gonna be there for a month.nice hit.
Joker:nobody insults Joker and gets away with it.they will get knocked the fuck out.
Soon montana max brings them thier food and they all sit down in the booths.also at the restuarant are Plucky Duck and Buster Bunny.
Buster:hey,its that new girl at school.you see her.she sure has an appetite
Plucky:yeh,she eats as much as hampton.well anyway have you seen that new Samurai Slug movie
Buster:its alright.
Babs and the other girls eat thier food.Joker eats like a slob.She eats really fast and is messy
Fifi:look at her go.she tries to imitate her by also eating fast and messy
Babs:let me try that.that looks fun.she does the same as fifi.
Shirley:uhh, i think i lost my appetite.
They all finish and Joker manages to eat everything she ordered.She belches loudly and rubs her belly which is now swollen from all the food.
Babs:thats disgusting..the other girls laugh
Fifi:well, im about to leave.ive got to study for zat difficult test.
Babs:me too.
Plucky and Buster are talking in the other booth.
Plucky:look buster, i am the king of street figher.nobody can touch me..
Buster:oh yeh,ill challenge you,lets go to the arcade.
Joker hears them talking about streeet figher.Joker:I will beat the shit out of both of you in street figher.
Plucky:hahahaha girls cant play video games.
Buster:no,no plucky ,lets give  her a chance.come on .why dont you go to the arcade with us.whats your name
Joker:joker
Buster:well im buster bunny and this green duck next to me is Plucky Duck
Fifi:well,Ill see you later Joker.dont forget to study.Fifi leaves the restarueant.Joker goes to the arcade with the Plucky and Buster.
The next day of school approaches.It is the day of the big test.Fifi walks to school happily.She studyed pretty hard and feels good about herself
Fifi:I am going to pass zat test easily.Fifi sees Joker near the school and greets her
Fifi:Bonjour,Joker.do you think you are going to pass zeee test.
Joker:Um fifi, i need your help girl.I didnt study.
Fifi:What,WHY!!!!!!
Joker:last night,me and plucky duck played street fighter all night and I forgot to study.I did beat the shit out of him though.
Fifi:it looks like you are going to fail.
Joker:naw,with your help, I can pass.Help me cheat
Fifi:no,cheating is wrong
Joker:come on fifi,you gotta help a sista out.look just write the answers all down and pass it to me while the teacher aint lookin.ill sit close to you.
Fifi:no,i refuse to cheat.look Joker,you have to pay for your mistakes.
Joker:come, on,please,if i fail my pops is gonna kill me.i would cheat for you
Fifi:i said NOOOOO.
Joker:ohh, i see,you arrnt a true friend.forget you.our friendship is OVER!!!!!.

Fifi didnt want to let the friendship die.She felt really connected with another girl skunk in the school.Somebody who stunk as much as she did.even though she felt cheating was wrong she felt sorry for Joker and didnt want her to get into trouble.This was just her first test

Fifi:look,Joker,wait,I will cheat, okay.but i really want you to learn your lesson and study zee next time
Joker:see, i knew you was my sista.i knew you was my true friend.she gives fifi a hug

Fifi has a big decision ahead of her.,she could get her and joker into serious trouble.but she dosnet want Joker to fail the test

To be continued...........in part 2. 
 
 fifi la fume meets a bully by ~ jupiterfox
	</body>
</document>
