<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004849" url="http://www.goenc.com/records/record_generator.asp?encnum=016805" time="2012-07-12-21:21" support="2" score="0.003375524485406432" bingtitle="goENC.com : Record for ENC#016805 (Math extension units. Book 1 ..." webtitle="goENC.com : Record for ENC#016805 (Math extension units. Book 1. Grades 2-3.)">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001169" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>... data and to compare prices in a fast food restaurant. ... Understanding place value Different ways Number pyramid ... ISBN: 978-1-883055-18-9 : Order#: DL 110</description>
	<body>
		Subscribe to goENC.com About goENC.com ENC Focus Magazine Contact goENC.com 

    You are here: Home / Record for ENC#016805 (Math extension units. Book 1. Grades 2-3.) 
 
 Email Address 
 
 Password 
 
   
 Forgot your Password? 

[ Tell Me More | Join Now ] 


 Recommended Resources Teaching Degrees 
 Online Schools 
 Online Degrees 
 
 
 
 
 
Math extension units. Book 1. Grades 2-3.

 Series:  Math extension units.
 Grades:  2 3
 ENC#:  ENC-016805
 Publisher:  Dandy Lion Publications
 Date:  1996
 Ordering Information 

 
 
 Subjects: 

 Mathematics 
Applied mathematics. Arithmetic. Measurement. Money. Place value. Problem solving. Process skills. Real world applications. Time. 


 Resource Type: 
Lessons and activities.
 
 Abstract: 
This book for grades 2 and 3, part of the MATH EXTENSION UNITS series, contains reproducible activities for four units: place value, problem solving, money, and time, designed to extend the learning of math students who have mastered the basic concepts. The two book series offers able math students extra challenges and learning opportunities while working on the same units as the rest of the class. Each unit includes twelve to fourteen illustrated worksheets with activities requiring higher level thinking and problem solving.

In a sample activity, students, working independently or in small groups, read a simple map showing the possible routes among five cities and calculate mileages for the Speedy Deliver Service. The Service picks up and delivers packages within a 50 mile radius, always trying to take the shortest route to get from town to town. Students answer questions related to their calculations. In later activities, students apply the concepts of more and less to analyze field day data and to compare prices in a fast food restaurant. All answers are included. (Author/JRS)
 
 Table of Contents: 
Place value
     Assignment sheet
     Importance of place
     Understanding place value
     Different ways
     Number pyramid
     Place value scramble
     Finding mystery numbers
     What&apos;s my mystery number (1 to 20)
     What&apos;s my mystery number (20 to 99)
     What&apos;s my mystery number (100 to 999)
     Really big numbers
     More or less
     Largest to smallest
Problem solving and computational application
     Assignment sheet
     Jessie&apos;s Valentine party
     The amusement park
     Trip to the farm
     A day at the beach
     George&apos;s birthday party
     Playing darts
     Reading club
     Book store sale
     Collection fair
     Fast food
     School store
     Speedy delivery
     Field day
Money
     Assignment sheet
     Counting money
     Using money symbols
     Trading coins
     Different ways
     Ways to make 25 cents
     Ways to make 30 cents
     Ways to make 35 cents
     Making change
     Piggy bank logic
     More piggy bank problems
     Ten coins in the bank
     Problem solving
     Money pictures
Time and measurement
     Assignment sheet
     Digital and analog clocks
     Minutes before and after the hour
     Timely problems
     Play time
     Monthly calendar
     Yearly calendar
     Temperatures above zero
     Temperatures below zero
     Liquid measurements
     Ways to make a gallon
     Container capers
     Party punch
Answers
 
 
 Vendor: 
Dandy Lion Publications/Prufrock Press
PO Box 8813
Waco TX 76714
 dandy@dandylionbooks.com 
(800) 998-2208
Fax: (805) 544-2823
 http://www.prufrock.com/ 

 

 Pricing Information: 

 
 Description: 1 activity book (paperback) 
 Cost:  $11.95  
 ISBN: 978-1-883055-18-9  
 Order#: DL 110  

 Publisher: 
Dandy Lion Publications

 Notes: 
Terms governing use and reproduction: Purchase of this book includes the permission to reproduce in limited quantities all pages bearing the copyright notice. The reproduction rights are extended to the purchaser of this book and entitle him or her to duplicate the reproducible pages for his or her students. The permission is limited to a single teacher and does not extend to other teachers, to entire schools, or to school systems. Institutions purchasing the book should pass the permission on to a single teacher.

 Contributor(s): 

 Authors: Mary Lou Johnson; Sharo Eckert; Judy Leimbach. 



 Specifications: 
1 activity book (65 pages : illustrations ; 28 cm.)
 
 Record Created: 03/16/2000 Last Modified: 06/13/2005

 
    

     ©ENC Learning Inc. 2012
	</body>
</document>
