<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004326" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/03/the_fins_are_typically_hacked.php" time="2012-07-12-20:34" support="3" score="0.001999421407999067" bingtitle="Controversial Shark Fin Soup Served at King Palace Chinese Bar B-Q ..." webtitle="Controversial Shark Fin Soup Served at King Palace Chinese Bar B-Q - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000277" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>I left my number but haven&apos;t heard back yet. It ... Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short ... Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   The Critic 
Controversial Shark Fin Soup Served at King Palace Chinese Bar B-Q
 By Lee Klein Wed., Mar. 9 2011 at 7:00 AM Categories: The Critic 
 Pin It 
 
 
​ &quot;The fins are typically hacked off a live shark, leaving it to die slowly as it sinks to the bottom of the sea.&quot; Seventy-three million sharks a year are being killed this way. &quot;As many as 90 percent of sharks in the world&apos;s open oceans have disappeared.&quot;

That info comes from an article by Patricia Leigh Brown in Saturday&apos;s edition of the New York Times that sheds light on the controversy surrounding a bill in the California Legislature that would ban the sale and possession of shark fins, including the serving of shark fin soup.

Most of the two dozen menus from Miami&apos;s Chinese restaurants that I perused showed no shark fin items. Hakkasan, Miss Yip, Tony Chan&apos;s Water Club, China Palace, South Seas... fin free. Philippe Restaurant used to sell it but stopped doing so in May 2009. Mr. Chow serves &quot;imitation&quot; shark fin (crab). Tropical Chinese had likewise featured fin -- and its online menu still lists the delicacy (shark fin crabmeat soup $30 for two; braised imperial shark fin $40 per person). But May Hensley, Tropical&apos;s manager, says, &quot;We took it off the menu a long time ago.&quot; Asked why, she says, &quot;Because people complained.&quot;

 King Palace Chinese Bar-B-Q , on the other hand, still serves shark fin soup (with chicken, for $18.95).
 
Thing is, this soup is not even eaten because of any particularly fetching flavor, but merely as a status symbol denoting wealth and power. And on the other end, those who sell the fins make huge profits; they come in varying grades, the tail fin being most expensive and netting up to $800 for a 1.6-pound bag.

Defenders of shark finning like to use &quot;cultural significance&quot; as their rationale. &quot;It&apos;s been part of our heritage for centuries,&quot; they say. OK. Let shark fin soup grace the wedding tables of pretentious fat cats in China. But these practices have no significance in American culture. Immigrants should surely be free to retain any parts of their indigenous lifestyle when they come here. But it doesn&apos;t strike me as unreasonable to make an exception to that rule when it involves the senseless taking of life that offends the values of the host country. And I find the act of horrifically killing 73 million sharks a year so people can ostentatiously flaunt their wealth extremely offensive.

Restaurants in Hawaii have until June 30 to clear out their shark inventories or face fines of $5,000 to $15,000 for a first offense. Similar bills have been introduced in Oregon, Washington State, and now California. I don&apos;t know whether shark fin is being sold much in other Florida cities, but Miami seems to have cleaned up its act voluntarily -- or in some cases, with a little prodding from the public. I called King Palace to do a little prodding of my own, but the woman answering the phone could say only that she &quot;thought&quot; it was real shark fin being sold, and that the manager didn&apos;t come in often. I left my number but haven&apos;t heard back yet.

It wouldn&apos;t be a bad idea if readers would give King Palace a call and leave a message for the manager/owner, politely saying you&apos;d be more apt to come in for dinner if shark fin soup was removed from the menu. The number is 305-949-2339. And if you know of any other local places that still sell shark fin, let us know and we&apos;ll give them a call too.

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 King Palace Bar-B-Q , Mr. Chow , Philippe Chow , Tropical Chinese Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Thank you, Lee, for your article calling attention to the problem with shark fin soup. I LOVE Asian food but whenever my family goes to a new restaurant the first thing we do is check what is on the menu. If a restaurant serves shark fin soup, we leave. We won’t ever patronize any restaurant that shows such a lack of stewardship for the ocean. Isn’t there some kind of decal or notice that a restaurant can place on its window so that people that feel as we do don’t waste our time even going into restaurants that serve shark fin soup?
 
Thanks, Lee, for this great article. For the past several years a few of us in South Florida (all members of the national Shark Research Institute, www.sharks.org) have been calling/visiting local Chinese restaurants and have been told regularly that they still were serving shark fin soup - although it rarely is included on the printed menus (for a variety of reasons). We, of course, would politely explain that we then would not give them our business because of the damaging effect on the environment of this barbaric practice. (Removing the apex predator from the ocean affects everything down the food chain.) It is great to know that you were able to speak with managers directly to get confirmation that most of them (but unfortunately not yet all) have stopped serving this off-menu item. Having someone of your professional standing take an interest in this topic and make a few phone calls has done more for shark conservation than our many hours of volunteer efforts as potential customers, so thank you!!!
 
Annoyed employees tell their bosses. If you don&apos;t think phone calls work, talk to the folks at Philippe, and Tropical, and all the other restaurants who removed the menu items solely because...people complained.

As for the price: maybe it&apos;s just crab, maybe a mix of crab and shark&apos;s fin -- although if it&apos;s only crab, that&apos;s a serious scam in itself.
 
Apparently you&apos;re a member of the&quot;don&apos;t criticize anything unless you&apos;re prepared to criticize everything&quot;school of thought. Don&apos;t write about foie gras because chickens have it bad too! Don&apos;t write about alcohol because prescription pills are bad too! Don&apos;t criticize Mubarak because Gadafi is worse! 

This is just a petty way of trying to stifle any criticism at all. And please Chris: Don&apos;t criticize Peta unless you&apos;re also willing to call out the tea party!
 
Way to go Lee!
 
Hey, Chris -

FYI, here in the U.S. we annually eat an approximate EIGHT BILLION animals (not including fish), most of whom never see the light of day, nor set foot to earth.

As Wendell Berry has written,&quot;The designers of animal factories appear to have had in mind the example of concentration camps or prisons, the aim of which is to house and feed the greatest numbers in the smallest space at the least expense of money, labor, and attention.&quot;The key to most, perhaps all of the planet&apos;s problems is to take a serious look at the gross human overpopulation, then do whatever it takes to fix it.

As the bumperstrip says,&quot;We are not the only species on the planet, we just act like it.&quot;
 
You mean the one place that may or may not actually serve it, where the manager doesn&apos;t come in often? For $18.95 a bowl, what do you think the odds are that they&apos;re even using real shark&apos;s fin? Seems more like a way to annoy some employees who have absolutely no control or discretion over what may not even be an issue, rather than any kind of fix, short or long term.
 
I think its a little over the line to give out the phone and say take it off the menu and me may (or may not) come in. You know how crazy these Peta people are. 

And when did you become such a conservationist. How about a post calling out Nobu and Matsurai for having blue fin tuna. Or an article with places that serve Chilean sea bass, or conch. Oh wait, their extinction didn&apos;t stop you from ordering them last month when you reviewed Rickenbacker Fish Company Restaurant and Market.
 
I agree that calling a legislator is a better big, long-term fix; calling the one place that serves it and asking them not to is for the small, short term fix.
 
Good. Next up foie gras.
 
Agree that restaurants should stop serving sharks&apos; fin, if they are doing so. But it should be no more acceptable in China than it should be here, if it is endangering species populations and is needlessly wasteful and cruel (like whaling, another industry where&quot;cultural significance&quot;is often raised).

But I hardly think the appropriate course of action is a telephonic harassment campaign of a restaurant that may, or may not, even be serving actual shark&apos;s fin. Instead, if you feel like picking up the phone, why not call your legislator and ask them to support a law like the California one that would make sure no restaurant is serving it?
 
I wonder how many cows, chickens, etc are killed each year. If we start mass producing sharks like we do cows, chickens, etc, then would it be ok to eat shark fin soup?!? I&apos;ve never actually had the soup, but I planned on trying it in my lifetime. I guess that won&apos;t happen. If we as humans are beginning to wipe out the shark population, then we should definitely cut back on shark fin soup.

Chris H.
 

TotalComments: 12
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Fratelli Milano
 View Ad | View Site 
Montes de Oca Original Pizza Cubana
 View Ad | View Site 
High Steaks BBQ
 View Ad | View Site 
Kings County Pizza
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
