<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004310" url="http://www.yelp.co.uk/search?find_desc=restaurants+halal&amp;find_loc=London" time="2012-07-12-20:34" support="1" score="0.0014540993819491205" bingtitle="Restaurants halal London" webtitle="Restaurants halal London">
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>a fast food restaurant Halal Bite is nice, clean with a welcoming ... in Camden has become my own kitchen table. I make ... for the growing Asian community in the Mile End ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Search for (e.g. pizza, pub, greasy spoon) 

 Near (Address, Area , City or Postcode) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk Events 

 Member Search 
   
restaurants halal London 
 Skip to search results 1 to 10 of 486 - Results per page: 10 20 30 40 Hide Filters 
Sort By

 Best Match Highest Rated Most Reviewed 
 
Areas

 Bethnal Green Bayswater Camden Town Soho 
 …More Areas» 
More Areas»
 
 
 London 
 Select all Deselect all 
 Abbey Wood Abbotts Langley Abridge Acton Addington Addlestone Alderstead Heath Aldgate Alexandra Palace Alperton Anerley Angel Archway Arnos Grove Arsenal Ashford Ashtead Aveley Avery Hill Badgers Mount Balham Banstead Banstead Heath Barbican Barking Barnes Barnet Barnsbury Barons Court Battersea Bayswater Beacontree Beckenham Beckton Belgravia Bellingham Belmont Belsize Park Belvedere Bermondsey Berrys Green Bethnal Green Bexley Bexleyheath Bickley Biggin Hill Blackfriars Blackheath Bloomsbury Borehamwood Borough Botany Bay Bounds Green Bow Bow Common Bowes Park Brent Cross Brentford Brick Lane Bricket Wood Brixton Brixton Hill Broadway Market Brockley Bromley Bromley-By-Bow Brondesbury Buckhurst Hill Buckingham Palace Burgess Park Burgh Heath Bush Hill Park Bushey Byfleet Camberwell Camden Town Canada Water Canary Wharf Canning Town Canonbury Canons Park Carshalton Caterham Catford Chadwell Heath Chalk Farm Charlton Chase Cross Cheam Chelsea Chelsfield Chertsey Chessington Chigwell Chinatown Chingford Chipstead Chislehurst Chiswick Church End Clapham Clapham Common Clapham Junction Clapham Park Clapton Claygate Clerkenwell Cobham Cockfosters Coldblow Coldharbour Lane/ Herne Hill Colindale Collier Row Colliers Wood Coulsdon Covent Garden Cranham Crayford Crayford Ness Cricklewood Crockenhill Crouch End Croxley Green Croydon Crystal Palace Cudham Custom House Dagenham Dalston Dartford De Beauvoir Denham Denmark Hill Deptford Derry Downs Dollis Hill Downe Dulwich Ealing Earls Court Earlsfield East Dulwich East Finchley East Ham East India Dock East Molesey Eastcote Eden Park Edgware Edmonton Elephant&amp;Castle Elm Park Elmers End Elmstead Eltham Emerson Park Enfield Enfield Chase Epping Forest Epsom Erith Esher Euston Ewell Excel Fairlop Farleigh Farnborough Farringdon Feltham Finchley Finchley Central Finchley Road Finsbury Park Fitzrovia Foots Cray Forest Gate Forest Hill 

 Friern Barnet Fulham Fulham Broadway Fulwell Gants Hill Gidea Park Goddington Golders Green Goodmayes Grange Hill Grange Park Green Park Greenford Greenwich Gunnersbury Hackbridge Hackney Central Hackney Downs Hackney Wick Hadley Wood Haggerston Hainault Ham Hammersmith Hampstead Hampstead Garden Suburb Hampstead Heath Hampstead Village Hampton Hangar Lane Harefield Harlesden Harold Hill Harold Wood Harringay Harrow&amp;Wealdstone Harrow on the Hill Hatch End Havering-atte-Bower Havering Park Hawley Hayes Hayes (Kent) Heathrow Hendon Heston Hextable Highams Park Highbury Highgate Hillingdon Hinchley Wood Holborn Holland Park Holloway Homerton Honor Oak Park Hornchurch Hornsey Horton Hounslow Hoxton Hoxton Square Hyde Park Ilford Isle of Dogs Isleworth Islington Iver Joyden&apos;s Wood Kenley Kennington Kensal Green Kensal Rise Kensal Town Kensington Kensington Gardens Kensington Olympia Kentish Town Kenton Keston Kew Kew Gardens Kidbrooke Kilburn King&apos;s Cross Kingsbury Kingsland Kingston Upon Thames Kingswood Knightsbridge Knockholt Ladbroke Grove Ladywell Laleham Lambourne Lee Leicester Square Lewisham Leyton Leytonstone Limehouse Lisson Grove Little Venice Liverpool Street / Broadgate London Bridge London City Airport London Fields Long Ditton Loughton Lower Holloway Maida Hill Maida Vale Malden Manor House Marylebone Mayfair Merton Mile End / Globe Town Mile End (South) Mill Hill Millwall Mitcham Monks Orchard Morden Mortlake Motspur Park Mottingham Mudchute/Cubitt Town Muswell Hill Neasden New Cross New Cross Gate New Southgate Newbury Park Newington Newington Green Nine Elms Noak Hill Noel Park Norbury North Acton North Cray North Finchley North Kensington North Woolwich Northolt Northumberland Heath Northwick Park Northwood Norwood (West&amp;Upper) Notting Hill Nunhead Oakwood Old Kent Road Olympic Village Orpington Osterley Oval Oxshott Paddington Palmers Green Park Langley Park Royal Parliament Hill/Dartmouth Park Parsons Green Peckham Peckham Rye Penge Perivale Petticoat Lane Petts Wood Piccadilly Pimlico Pinner Plaistow Plaistow (South) Plumstead 

 Poplar Potters Bar Pratts Bottom Preston Primrose Hill Purfleet Purley Putney Putney Heath Queen&apos;s Park Queensbury Radlett Rainham Ramsden Ravenscourt Park Raynes Park Regent&apos;s Park Richmond Park Richmond Upon Thames Rickmansworth Riddlesdown Roehampton Romford Rotherhithe Ruislip Rush Green Sanderstead Selhurst Selsdon Seven Kings Seven Sisters Sewardstone Shad Thames Shadwell Shepherd&apos;s Bush Shepperton Shoreditch Shortlands Sidcup Silvertown Slade Green Sloane Square Snaresbrook Soho South Acton South Bank South Harrow South Hornchurch South Kensington South Lambeth South Norwood South Ockendon South Woodford Southall Southfields Southgate Southwark Spitalfields St Helier St James&apos;s St Johns St John&apos;s Wood St Katherines Dock St Mary Cray St Paul Cray Staines Stamford Hill Stanmore Stapleford Abbotts Stepney Stepney Green Stockwell Stoke Newington Stoke Newington Central Stoke Newington Church Street Stonebridge Park Stoneleigh Strand Stratford Streatham Streatham Hill Stroud Green Sudbury Summerstown Sunbury Sundridge Surbiton Surrey Quays Sutton Swanley Swiss Cottage Sydenham Tadworth Tatsfield Tattenham Corner Teddington Temple Fortune Thames Ditton Thamesmead The City The Hyde Theydon Bois Thornton Heath Thorpe Titsey Tolworth Tooting Tooting Bec Tooting Broadway Tooting Graveney Tottenham Tottenham Hale Totteridge Tower Hill Trafalgar Square Tufnell Park Tulse Hill Turnpike Lane Twickenham Upminster Upper Clapton Upper Holloway Upper Tooting Upton Park Uxbridge Vauxhall Victoria Victoria Park Waddon Wallington Walthamstow Walton Heath Walton-on-Thames Walworth Wandsworth Wandsworth Common Wanstead Wapping Warlingham Waterloo Watford Well Hill Welling Wembley Wennington West Acton West Brompton West Drayton West Dulwich West Green West Ham West Hampstead West India Docks West Kensington West Molesey West Wickham Westerham Westminster Weybridge Whetstone White City Whitechapel Whitton Whyteleafe Willesden Wilmington Wimbledon Wimbledon Common Winchmore Hill Woldingham Wood Green Woodford Woolwich Worcester Park Worlds End Yeading Yiewsley 
 
 Search Cancel 
Distance

 Bird&apos;s-eye View Within 5 miles Within 2 miles Within 1 mile Within¼mile 
 
Features

 Open Now Good for Groups Good for Children Take Away …More features» 
 
More Features
 
 General Features 
 
 Open At: Mon Tue Wed Thu Fri Sat Sun Open Now Accepts Credit Cards Waiter Service Wheelchair Accessible 
 
 Alcohol 
 
 Full Bar Beer&amp;Wine Only Happy Hour 
 
 Meals Served 
 
 Breakfast Brunch Lunch Dinner Dessert Late Night 
 
 Music 
 
 DJ Juke Box Karaoke Live 
 
 Parking 
 
 Street Garage Valet On-Site 
 
 Smoking 
 
 No Outdoor Area/ Patio Only Yes 
 
 Wi-Fi 
 
 Free Paid 
 = No results Search Cancel 
Price

 ££££ £££ ££ £ 
 
Category

 Fast Food&amp;Takeaways Halal Chinese Steakhouses …More categories» 
 
More Categories
 
 African Bars Caribbean Coffee&amp;Tea Delis Fish&amp;Chips Food Indian Malaysian Middle Eastern Nightlife Pakistani Restaurants Seafood 
 Search Cancel 
 1. Halal Bite 
 Category: Fast Food&amp;Takeaways Area: Bethnal Green 2 reviews 169 Mile End Road
London E1 4AQ 020 7791 0405 a fast food restaurant Halal Bite is nice, clean with a welcoming atmosphere. I honestly cannot fault this place. With great tasting, cheap fresh food, that is perfect for a filling late lunch, I have to bestow 5*s. 
 2. North Sea Fish Restaurant 
 Categories: Seafood , Fish&amp;Chips Area: Bloomsbury 46 reviews 7-8 Leigh Street
London WC1H 9EW 020 7387 5892 North Sea is the place where I was introduced to a proper Fish and Chips.   We managed to catch North Sea minutes before the restaurant opens, which meant a trip right next door to their takeaway. If you&apos;re looking 
 3. Chutney Mary 
 Categories: Indian , Halal Area: West Brompton 16 reviews 535 Kings Road
London SW10 0SZ 020 7351 7694 I went to Chutney Mary with a friend during restaurant week earlier this year and it was an absolutely lovely experience.  It was pretty quiet for a week night - I believe we went on a Wednesday.  The restaurant 
 4. Rasa Sayang 
 Categories: Malaysian , Chinese Areas: Chinatown , Soho 33 reviews 5 Macclesfield Street
London W1D 6AY 020 7734 1382 is a plethora of Thai, Cantonese, Japanese and Vietnamese restaurants around, Malaysian restaurants are comparatively few and scattered around. I used to like Kiasu in Bayswater before it got closed down for reasons… 
 5. Blue Elephant 
 Category: Thai Areas: West Brompton , Fulham , Fulham Broadway 25 reviews 4-6 Fulham Broadway
London SW6 1AA 020 7385 6595 This is one of my favourite restaurants in the UK, certainly my favourite Thai restaurant .  The decor here is just stunning, walking into the restaurant over a little footbridge with a pool of koi carp swimming around 
 6. Guanabana 
 Categories: Caribbean , Halal , Steakhouses Area: Camden Town 6 reviews 85 Kentish Town Road
London NW1 8NY 020 7485 1166 thought!   I went for dinner there that night and I wasn&apos;t disappointed...I even ended up booking my 30th Birthday party there straight away.  I love this venue, a cosy, comfortable and friendly restaurant with a great 
 7. Tayyabs 
 Categories: Indian , Pakistani Area: Whitechapel 153 reviews 83-89 Fieldgate Street
London E1 1JU 020 7247 9543 Make a reservation. Otherwise, your experience at Tayyabs will be tainted. The line to get a table is a bit ridiculous--you queue inside the restaurant while miserably watching plates of food being served to seated 
 8. Noodle Oodle 
 Category: Halal Area: Bayswater 9 reviews 106-110 Queensway
London W2 3RR 020 7792 8833 unless you are actually looking for halal food, go to one of the &quot;real&quot; Chinese restaurants down the street. 
 9. Bosphorus Kebabs 
 Category: Middle Eastern Area: South Kensington 23 reviews 59 Old Brompton Road
London SW7 3JS 020 7584 4048 Whenever we visit London we rent an apartment in a different residential neighborhood, and the biggest advantage is discovering restaurants we never would have found if we were staying in a hotel in the heart 
 10. Satay House 
 Categories: Chinese , Malaysian Area: Paddington 14 reviews 13 Sale Place
London W2 1PX 020 7723 6763 This is my favourite &quot;Malay&quot; Malaysian restaurant in London (compared to others e.g. Mawar (now Melur), Naha (now Bonda), Jom Makan, etc). These are different to the &quot;Chinese&quot; Malaysian restaurants (e.g. C&amp;R, Kopitiam 
 1 to 10 of 486 Go to Page 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... Previous | Next 
 Got search feedback? Help us improve. 
Related Lists

 
 Good Cheap Grub 

A good hearty meal for a small price
 
 My 5* Hotspots 

The best of the best.
 

 See more lists» 
 
Not here? Tell us what we&apos;re missing.

If the business you&apos;re looking for isn&apos;t here, add it!
 Add A Business Redo search when map moved Draw Search Area «Mo&apos; Map Less Map» Loading... Please zoom in to get updated search results. Yowza, that is one large search area. Draw something a bit smaller for us, eh? 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Italy Norway Republic of Ireland Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United States 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 London Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Belfast | Birmingham | Bristol | Cardiff | Coventry | Edinburgh | Hull | Leeds | Leicester | Liverpool | London | Manchester | Sheffield 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp
	</body>
</document>
