<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004709" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/33770781/Nutrition-For-Canadians-For-Dummies" time="2012-07-12-21:13" support="7" score="0.009262457667001345" bingtitle="Nutrition For Canadians For Dummies - Scribd" webtitle="Nutrition For Canadians For Dummies">
			<query id="001151" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000647" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000459" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000148" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>Contains the latest information from Canada&apos;s Food GuideGet the facts on good nutrition, slim down, and feel greatGood nutrition is the key to a healthy weight and ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Buy Now You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 13 to 27 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 40 to 105 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 118 to 276 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 289 to 405 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Page 418 is not shown in this preview. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Nutrition For Canadians For Dummies
 Contains the latest information from Canada&apos;s Food GuideGet the facts on good nutrition, slim down, and feel greatGood nutrition is the key to a healthy weight and lifelong good... ( More ) Contains the latest information from Canada&apos;s Food GuideGet the facts on good nutrition, slim down, and feel greatGood nutrition is the key to a healthy weight and lifelong good health. But with more and more food choices available in today&apos;s grocery stores and restaurants, how do you make sure you and your family are eating right? With information from the latest guidelines and research, this friendly guide is just what you need to make the right food choices every day.Discover how to:Interpret nutrition labelsPrepare delicious, healthy mealsKeep portion sizes under controlEat smart when eating outEvaluate natural health supplementsCarol Ann Rinzler is a noted authority on health and nutrition and holds an MA from Columbia University. She is the author of more than 20 health-related books. Doug Cook is a Registered Dietitian/Nutritionist and Certified Diabetes Educator working at St. Michael&apos;s Hospital in Toronto and in private practice. ( Less ) 1,371 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 07/01/2010 Copyright: Traditional Copyright: All rights reserved Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
