<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004579" url="http://blog.doha-delivery.com/" time="2012-07-12-21:03" support="4" score="0.013830367690965356" bingtitle="Doha Delivery - Easy Online Ordering" webtitle="Doha Delivery - Easy Online Ordering">
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>With a vast library of delivery menus just a click away, it&apos;s easy to order ... Fast Food; Restaurant Locations; Media. Doha Delivery on BBC World; Doha Tweetup – Doha 101</description>
	<body>
		Doha&apos;s Delivery Menus Online 
 Home About Us 
 About Doha Delivery Announcements Cuisines Our Restaurants Fast Food Restaurant Locations Media 
 Doha Delivery on BBC World Doha Tweetup–Doha 101 
 Statistics 
 July 2011 Stats August 2011 Stats September 2011 Stats 
 Legal Notices 
 Privacy Policy Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 Restaurant Managers 
 Get your Menu Online Add your Menu the EASY way Manage Your Menus Set-Up Online Ordering 
 Manage Your Orders Manage Your Emails Customer Orders–What Happens 
 
 How to Order Food 
 How to Find a Restaurant Menu How to Create an Account Ordering Food Online 
 Order Food Now 
 Order American Grill Online Order Bread&amp;Bagels Online Order Kabab-ji Grill Online 
 Contact Us 
 Jun 22, 2012 Order from Noodle House Onli... Doha Delivery spoke to Noodle House Managers a few weeks ago…They are great people, but Noodle House is taking its time to decide over whether they... read more May 27, 2012 Know your Zone! Planning Zon... Hello Doha!!
A lot is changing at Doha Delivery over this summer with more restaurants being added and new website enhancements.
One aspect, I hope everyone... read more Sep 13, 2011 Caravan Bukhara–Upda... Caravan Bukhara has updated their Menu.
One of Doha’s most popular Indian restaurants has updated its menu.
Check out the new changes on Doha... read more Aug 1, 2011 Bread&amp;Bagels Ramadan ... Bread&amp;Bagels in West Bay has new operating hours for the Holy Month of Ramadan:

Delivery&amp;Take-away:
Daily 9:00 am till midnight,
Fridays... read more Jun 20, 2012 Posted by Webmaster 
 Giving Directions in Doha 
 How do you give directions to Food Delivery Drivers in Doha?
One of the biggest challenges in Doha, despite its small size, is giving directions.
Everyone fears... read more Mar 21, 2012 Posted by Webmaster 
 December 2011 Stats 
 In December Doha Delivery kept climbing despite the holidays
Thanks again to everyone who visited Doha Delivery this December, it was another record breaking... read more Feb 19, 2012 Posted by Webmaster 
 November 2011 Stats 
 In November Doha Delivery really launched…Thanks again to everyone who visited Doha Delivery this November, it was another record breaking month. We... read more Nov 20, 2011 Posted by Webmaster 
 KFC Dominates Doha 
 Is KFC the most popular delivery choice in Doha?
There must be something in the Colonel’s secret recipe of 7 herbs and spices, because it seems like... read more Oct 25, 2011 Posted by Webmaster 
 McDelivery in Doha 
 McDonald’s Delivery in Doha
McDonald’s seems to be everywhere in the greater Doha area.
Every time you turn your head, there’s another... read more 
 «Previous Entries 
 popular articles 
 July 2011 Stats (1) Order from Noodle House Online...maybe? (1) 
 random articles 
 August 2011 Stats Indian Cuisine–A brief Burger King in Doha Eid Mubarak from Doha Delivery Domino’s and Isfahan X-Press ... Order from Noodle House Online̷... Bread&amp;Bagels Ramadan Timings Caravan Bukhara–Updated Men... 
 Created by Salsabil Ventures, LLC | Copyright Maendeleo Ventures Qatar, LLC 2011
	</body>
</document>
