<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004439" url="http://www.jobisjob.ca/high+prairie/jobs/l" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="2" score="0.00547259826389046" bingtitle="High Prairie Jobs, Top Career Opportunities in High Prairie ..." webtitle="High Prairie Jobs, Top High Prairie Career Opportunities - JobisJob Canada">
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>Cashier Add to shortlist. SSC Enterprise Ltd., O/a Mohawk ... total payment for goods or services required, Receive ... Fast food restaurant manager Add to shortlist. A &amp; W ...</description>
	<body>
		FREE Job Posting 
 Sign In - Post a Job 
 My Network My jobs (0) Sign In 
 Search jobs: 
 What: Job title, keywords or company name Where: Town, County, Region (Optional) 
 
Jobs in High Prairie
 
Sort by:  Date | Relevance 
 Distance: Exact location only Within 10 km Within 25 km Within 50 km Within 75 km Within 100 km 
 1 to 10 of 25 vacancies 
 
Related Jobs
 Mining Truck Alberta 
Top locations near High Prairie hiring now:

 High Prairie (25) Valleyview (13) 

 McLennan (6) Falher (5) 

 Brownvale (1) 
 
 Nursing Attendant Add to shortlist 

 Alberta Health Services -
High Prairie, Canada

The Nursing Attendant provides personal care to residents under the direction of a Staff Nurse or Licensed Practical Nurse in accordance with established care plans, and provides encouragement and emotional support, ensuring the dignity of the resident...
high prairie job bank…

 2 days ago from: peoplemenders.ca
 
 Client Service Representative-High Prairie, AB (5437) Add to shortlist 

 RBC -
High Prairie, Alberta, CANADA

This role is a professional career opportunity in a highly visible client service oriented position within the High Prairie branch of RBC Royal Bank. This role will be attractive to individuals interested in working in a full time work arrangement while...
job in high prairie alberta…

 7 days ago from: workopolis.com
 
 
People you know

who work at this company
 
 You 

 know 
 Your Friend 
 Facebook Off LinkedIn Off 
 
 
 Registered Nurse/Staff Nurse Add to shortlist 

 Alberta Health Services -
High Prairie, Canada

The Staff Nurse provides professional nursing care using the nursing process, contributes to the nursing unit team, and performs other related...
some one to cultivate garden in high prairie…

 5 days ago from: peoplemenders.ca
 
 Records Manager Add to shortlist 

 High Prairie School Division No.48 -
High Prairie, AB

 High Prairie School Division No.48 currently has an opening for a skilled Records Manager (electronic data) based out of beautiful High Prairie , Alberta. In this specialized role, your main responsibility will be to develop and implement the electronic...

 13 days ago from: linkedin.com
 
 Administrative assistant Add to shortlist 

 W J Stelmaschuk and Associates Ltd. -
High Prairie

Specific Skills: Type and proofread correspondence, forms and other documents, Receive and forward telephone or electronic enquiries, Maintain and prepare reports from manual or electronic files, inventories, mailing lists and databases, Process incoming...

 Today from: jobbank.gc.ca
 
 Cleaning supervisor Add to shortlist 

 PICHAY JANITORIAL SERVICES INC. -
High Prairie

Specific Skills: Supervise and co-ordinate activities of workers, Inspect sites or facilities to ensure safety and cleanliness standards, Recommend or arrange for additional maintenance services, Prepare work schedules, Assist cleaners in performing duties...

 3 days ago from: jobbank.gc.ca
 
 Cashier Add to shortlist 

 Max Fuel Distributors Ltd. -
HIGH PRAIRIE

Specific Skills: Customer service oriented, Operate cash register, Process money, cheques and credit/debit card payments, Scan items, Tabulate total payment for goods or services required, Receive payment for goods or services, Calculate daily/shift payments...

 3 days ago from: jobbank.gc.ca
 
 Cashier supervisor - retail Add to shortlist 

 Max Fuel Distributors Ltd. -
high prairie

Specific Skills: Supervise and co-ordinate sales staff and cashiers, Assign sales workers to duties, Sell merchandise, Resolve customer complaints and supply shortages, Maintain specified inventory, Prepare reports on sales volumes, merchandising and...

 3 days ago from: jobbank.gc.ca
 
 Truck driver Add to shortlist 

 Max Fuel Distributors Ltd. -
high prairie

Education: Completion of high school... Credentials (certificates, licences, memberships, courses, etc.): Driver&apos;s Licence (Class 1 or A), Air Brake (Z) Endorsement... Experience: 1 year to less than 2 years... Languages: Speak English, Read English,...

 3 days ago from: jobbank.gc.ca
 
 
People you know

who work at this company
 
 You 

 know 
 Your Friend 
 Facebook Off LinkedIn Off 
 
 
 Automotive service technician Add to shortlist 

 Recruiting Room -
High Prairie

Education: Not applicable, Not required... Credentials (certificates, licences, memberships, courses, etc.): Automotive Service Technician Trade Certification, 4th Period Apprentice, Automotive Service Technician Red Seal Endorsement... Experience: No...

 3 days ago from: jobbank.gc.ca
 
 1 2 3 Next 
 
 Get email alerts for the latest
Jobs in High Prairie 
 
 My email 
You can cancel email alerts at anytime. We will not share your email address with anyone.
 
 
Share Options

 
 
Filter jobs by
 Job Title All Live-in Caregiver (3) Food Service Supervisor (2) Records Manager (2) Administrative Assistant (1) Administrative Secretary (1) Automotive Service Technician (1) Cashier (1) Cashier Supervisor - Retail (1) Cleaning Supervisor (1) See More… Company All Freson Market Ltd/freson Market-iga/freson Bros.-iga (3) Max Fuel Distributors (3) A&amp;W Restaurant (2) Alberta Health Services (2) Pratt Ranches (2) Blaze Marketing Solutions (1) Brandt Tractor (1) David Curran (1) Employment Office (1) High Prairie School Division No.48 (1) See More… Job Type All Permanent, Full Time (9) Permanent, Shifts (9) Full Time (2) Permanent, Part-time (1) Temporary, Full Time (1) Date Posted Last 24 hours (1) Last week (11) Last 2 weeks (20) Last month (25) 
Related sections
 My recent searches You have no recent searches at the moment.
Use our  Job Search  to find your new job.   Create email alert My email 
 Search jobs: 
 What: Job title, keywords or company name Where: Town, County, Region (Optional) 
 
Refine your search
 Job Title All Live-in Caregiver (3) Food Service Supervisor (2) Records Manager (2) Administrative Assistant (1) Administrative Secretary (1) Automotive Service Technician (1) Cashier (1) Cashier Supervisor - Retail (1) Cleaning Supervisor (1) See More… Company All Freson Market Ltd/freson Market-iga/freson Bros.-iga (3) Max Fuel Distributors (3) A&amp;W Restaurant (2) Alberta Health Services (2) Pratt Ranches (2) Blaze Marketing Solutions (1) Brandt Tractor (1) David Curran (1) Employment Office (1) High Prairie School Division No.48 (1) See More… Job Type All Permanent, Full Time (9) Permanent, Shifts (9) Full Time (2) Permanent, Part-time (1) Temporary, Full Time (1) My recent searches High Prairie 
 JobisJob: About us Legal information Contact us Help Top job searches Top locations Resume Review ©JobisJob, SL
	</body>
</document>
