<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004831" url="http://www.thriftyfun.com/tf83998027.tip.html" time="2012-07-12-21:20" support="2" score="0.005500864890384705" bingtitle="Where Do You Get Senior Discounts? | ThriftyFun" webtitle="Where Do You Get Senior Discounts? | ThriftyFun">
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="35"/>
	<description>... anyone want to share with me where they usually get ... I even heard of a fast food chain that does, but I haven ... occassionaly you&apos;ll find one that will give free drinks.</description>
	<body>
		Join ThriftyFun User/Email Password Login Forgot My Account Logout   
 Home Ask Answer 
 Recent Questions Lonely Questions Recent Feedback 
 Share 
 Crafts for Fun and Money Contests Seed Swap Coupon Swap 
 Contests 
 Current Contests Tips My Frugal Life Recipes Pets Photos Results 
 Guides Browse 
 Featured Posts By Date By Topic Recent Feedback Search ThriftyFun Search With Google 
 Account 
 Main Profile Bookmarks Newsletters Questions Feedback Ratings 
 About 
 About ThriftyFun Staff Spotlights Newsletters Contact Us Media Inquiries Advertising Privacy Statement Disclaimer 
 
 Budget&amp;Finance &gt; Tips for Seniors May 14, 2006 
 
 
Where Do You Get Senior Discounts?
 I was surprised to learn of some business&apos;s that give senior citizens discounts. Quite often, all you need to do is ask. I only know of a couple though, does anyone want to share with me where they usually get senior citizens discounts? The pharmacy I go to is one I know of, and a grocery store gives seniors a discount on tuesdays, where i live (10%). There are probably a lot more. I even heard of a fast food chain that does, but I haven&apos;t checked it out to know for sure. Thanks for all replies!

P.J. from delaware 1 Variations 1 Question 26 Answers Share Print Follow 0 0 
 Previous: Estate Planning is Important Next: Estate Planning is Important 
 
Answers
 Answer this Question Read answers for this post below. 
 By dl274 02/05/2011 
The Pizza Hut in Palm Harbor FL., has a&quot;30% off menu senior discount&quot;. You have to ask for it. I don&apos;t know if it&apos;s available at all Pizza Hut restaurants, but it&apos;s a large discount and worth asking for. Good on delivery orders too. McDonald&apos;s used to have a widely available&quot;senior Coke&quot;discount. Small Coke for about 30 cents and free refills I think. Haven&apos;t used it in a while and don&apos;t know if it&apos;s still around.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By alberto.elliott 01/31/2011 
Denny&apos;s gives a 20% discount between 4pm-10pm to AARP members. Tanger and Walgreens give AARP discounts too as does The Hartford for home and auto insurance ( http://aarp.thehartford.com/ ).
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Raeb22 01/23/2010 
I get a discount at Taco Bell and a clothing store here
in downtown Denver,CO. I love it! :)
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By redhatterb 07/13/2009 
In SD, KMart and Joann Fabric used to give senior discounts on a given day. I haven&apos;t been to either one of them for seveal years, because they are both so congested with merchandize that it is hard for me to get around in them and is actually annoying. I think Kohls gives a senior discount, at times. Anyway in their ads, it will say something to the effect that a special senior discount will be applied on a certain day.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By John (Guest Post) 01/06/2009 
Thanks for this forum to get more ideas of who is giving Senior Discounts. I get one at Burger King but it does vary by store. Most fast food places will give you something. Chick-fila gives a Senior Drink and free refills. Captain D&apos;s gives 10% as does Fuddruckers. You do have to ask as it is not advertised as tall. Good Hunting!
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By ELLIE B (Guest Post) 12/01/2008 
I live in Valley Stream, New York. Anyone know of senior discounts at supermarkets?
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Jvan228 (Guest Post) 08/27/2008 
Lots of the Campgrounds we go to give discounts to AARP members.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Carl (Guest Post) 08/27/2008 
Boston Market gives a 10% discount for seniors. Have a great day...filled with mystery and enchantment! And remember, blessed is he who expects nothing, for he shall never be disappointed .
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Fiftysumthin (Guest Post) 09/19/2007 
Strange to me how some stores in a national chain provide senior discounts while some do absolutely NOTHING! My KROGER does NOTHING! Another reason to move elsewhere? LOL
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By crys7881 05/16/2006 
I would call your favorite places to visit and just ask over the phone!
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Marylin (Guest Post) 05/16/2006 
Most fast food places give some kind of discount, But you have to ask!! McDonalds and Burger King give discounted drinks. Taco Bell gives free drinks. Pizza Hut and many other restaurants give 10% off. Wendy&apos;s usually gives 10% off but occassionaly you&apos;ll find one that will give free drinks. Ages vary, but usually it&apos;s 55. ASK, ASK!!
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By dameemag (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
Hi..In Michigan Goodwill even gives a senior discount..It is on Tuesday and it is 20% which really adds up...Now with all the new and good things you can really save a lot there....You just have to be 55....
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Charlotte (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
Debbie, the senior discount age varies anywhere from 50 - 65. You simply will have to ask if it is not posted.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Charlotte (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
At age 61 I don&apos;t feel old either but eagerly seek and use all the senior discounts I can. So far I use these:
Wendy&apos;s
Golden Corral
Ponderosa
Bob Evans ~ senior menu
Kroger 5% on Tuesday
One of our banks has a senior program providing free checking and the checks as well. Each bank varies in what it offers.
We will use the senior discount a La Quinta hotel in CA this week for the first time.
Our county offers a property tax discount at age 65 as well.

Check with your pharmacy and car repair/maintenance dealer.

Tips
Don&apos;t hesitate to ask since the worst anyone can say is&quot;we have none&quot;.
Many places that have discounts don&apos;t give them unless the customer asks for the discount each time.&lt;frown&gt;

 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Glinda (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
My husband always gets Senior discount at McDonalds, he is 48.
I get a discount at Goodies Dept. store on Wednesdays, and I will be 50 in June.
Senior discounts don&apos;t ever insult me! I love it!
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By syd (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
Ask&amp;you will receive.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By hwalz (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
McDonald&apos;s has a reduced price for coffee for seniors. Bob Evans, Denny&apos;s, and Ponderosa have a senior discount or reduced prices (for reduced portion size). Some are effective at age 50, others age 55. State Parks also have a Golden Passport. You might check with AARP for other discounts.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Carol in PA (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
I am 60. I&apos;ve found that you need to ask what the age might be for the senior discount. Different grocery stores have different ages.

Long John Silvers seafood is one reastaurant that has a discount for seniors..

The best discount, I hear, is at the senior center where you can get a meal for not much money. Also, ours here in PA give coupons for $20 worth of produce at the farmer&apos;s market.

Dont be afraid to ask. I recently learned that Rite Aid has senior discount (age 60) on Tuesdays. It is 10% off anything you buy.

Best of luck
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Debbie52 05/15/2006 
What I would like to know is when does one qualify to get a Sr discount. I am turning 54 soon and certainly don&apos;t think of myself as a Senior yet....but my husband is older than me and just wondered when he can take advantage of discounts.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Debbie52 05/15/2006 
What I would like to know is when does one qualify to get a Sr discount. I am turning 54 soon and certainly don&apos;t think of myself as a Senior yet....but my husband is older than me and just wondered when he can take advantage of discounts.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By wendee (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
How old do you need to be to get the Ross discount?Thanks
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By Memere (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
Krogers grocery store gives their plus card with a 10% discount to seniors everyday, even sale items on all Kroger products. I save a bundle. The Dress Barn gives 10% on Tuesdays.
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
thanks for your replies, but i generally don&apos;t buy much on line. i basically was looking for places that give senior discounts like retail places, etc, but not online. thanks
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By camo_angels 05/15/2006 
I would ask over the phone before you try it online.....as with any company. It is hard to verify age online!
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By camo_angels 05/15/2006 
It&apos;s sad that you can only get them once a week! You all deserve it, IMO! Check out All I Saw Cookware online; they are a small specialty kitchen/coffee/tea/gift store in Wasilla AK. They ALWAYS give a senior 10% discount. Not all inventory is online because they get SO MUCH stuff, but carry kitchen items from Le Creuset, Heinkel (knives and cookware) Spode China, Progressive, Norpro, April Cornell Clothing and Linens, WONDERFUL bulk coffee and teas, Villaware and Krups appliances, Capresso Machines, YOU NAME IT! And ask about their candy too.....toll Free Line: 1-866-376-3177 or check out www.allisawcookware.com; PS I used to work there, and everyone is great! You can tell them Kelly sent you!
 Report Spam or Abuse 

 By smartshopper (Guest Post) 05/15/2006 
Ross department store also gived 10% discount on Tuesdays.
 Report Spam or Abuse 
 
Questions
 Ask a Question Here are questions related to this page. Click &quot;Ask a Question&quot; if you have a question to ask about this topic. 
 Finding Stores That Offer Senior Citizen Discounts 
Do Best Buy stores give senior citizen discounts?
By DG

 View this Question 3 Answers   Share Print Follow 
Most Recent Answer
 By chef4u 11/15/2011 
You could probably actually call them and ask.
 Report Spam or Abuse 
Related
 
 Teacher Discounts Remember Your Membership Discounts Homeowners Insurance Discounts 
 
 Check for Senior Discounts Find Special Discounts Ideas for Senior Class Activities 
 
Variations
 Add a Variation Here are variations of this Tip. Rate the variation that you like the best. Click here add your variation. 
 Link: List of Senior Discounts 
I think that there are enough seniors on Thriftyfun to make use of the following list of discounts you could receive.
 http://www.giftcardgranny.com/blog/senior-discounts/ 

By Elaine from Belle Plaine, IA
 Was this helpful? 5 0 2 Feedbacks Share Print 
 Shared on: 05/11/2011 
 Once you try the above variations, be sure to come back and give a &quot;thumbs up&quot; to the one that worked the best for you. Do you have a better variation? Click here to share it! 
 Answer this Question
 Your thoughts are welcomed and appreciated.
Enter your answer here! 
 Answer: 
 

 Image Upload: 

Add an image to your post! Click the &quot;Browse&quot; button above and select an image from your hard drive. Please only select gifs or jpegs. If you have any problems, please contact us .

    
 Like ThriftyFun on Facebook 
Browse Topics
 
Over 80,000 tips, recipes, questions&amp;crafts.

 Select a Topic... Back To School Beauty Better Living Budget&amp;Finance Business Cars Christmas Cleaning Clothing Collectibles College Life Computers Consumer Advice Coupons Craft Projects Craft Tips Easter Education Emergency Entertainment Father&apos;s Day Food Tips&amp;Info For Educators Fourth of July Freebies Garage Sales Gardening Gifts Green Living Halloween Health&amp;Body Home Improvement Homework Help Legal Links Make Your Own Memorial Day Mothers Day Organizing Parenting Parties Pest Control Pets Photos Product Reviews Recipes Recreation Repair Shopping Thanksgiving Travel Travel Guides Valentine&apos;s Day Weddings for Less Columnists Glossary Printables 
 
Popular Now
 
 Christmas Weddings for Less Beauty Budget and Finance Cleaning Craft Projects Craft Tips Food Tips Garage Sales Gardening Gifts Green Living Home Improvement Organizing Parenting Parties Pest Control Pets Recipes Repair 
 
Ask a Question
 Submit a question to the TF community.
 

 
 
Subscribe to ThriftyFun Newsletters!
 Email: 
 
©1997-2012 by Cumuli, Inc. - All Rights Reserved.
Page generated on March 23, 2012 at 11:26:02 PM on 216.168.63.21 in 1 seconds.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of ThriftyFun&apos;s Disclaimer and Privacy Policy .
  
 Login with Facebook 
 
If you are a Facebook user you can login here to post comments on ThriftyFun.
 
 Login to ThriftyFun 



 Username or Email Address 

 Password 

Not a Member? Click here to Register. 

Forgot your password? Click here for help. 
 
http://www.thriftyfun.com/tf83998027.tip.html

 Where Do You Get Senior Discounts? | ThriftyFun 
 [x]
	</body>
</document>
