<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004781" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Burger-King-11135.html" time="2012-07-12-21:17" support="1" score="0.0013045147024390053" bingtitle="Burger King #11135, 2270 Hunters Woods Plz, Reston, VA ..." webtitle="Burger King #11135, 2270 Hunters Woods Plz, Reston, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="000084" bing-rank="8"/>
	<description>3-304.12(A)-(F) - Corrected During Inspection Dispensing ... Receipt from last service obtained on 7/31/06 ... This is a routine inspection at this fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Burger King #11135, 2270 Hunters Woods Plz, Reston, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: Burger King #11135 
Address: 2270 Hunters Woods Plz, Reston, Virginia 
Total inspections: 19 
Last inspection: Sep 11, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 No violation noted during this evaluation. September 11, 2009 Routine 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. May 28, 2009 Critical Procedures 0 0 Details / Comments 
 3-304.12(A)-(F) - Corrected During Inspection Dispensing and/or in-use utensils improperly stored between use as follows: a plastic container is used to dispense the pickles. 4-903.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Repeat Clean equipment was found stored in a dirty container. 5-103.11(B) - Critical The water water heater serving the food service establishment is no longer operable.The hot water at the hand sink is 80F and at the 3-vat sink 82F. 6-202.11(A) - Repeat Light bulbs in the ceiling in the dry storage area are not covered by a protective shielding. 6-301.12(A) - Corrected During Inspection Observed that paper towels were not provided at each handwashing sink. By the drive-thru window. 7-201.11(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Observed that poisonous and toxic material, bottle of rubbing alcohol on the first aid kit, is not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food, buns, below. Also, bottles of windex and degreaser are on the wall above the buns on a cart below. 
 July 03, 2008 Routine - - Details / Comments 7-201.11(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed that poisonous and toxic materials, 2 buckets of sanitizer, are not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food. On a shelf next to container of ketchup bottles. January 09, 2008 Critical Procedures 1 0 Details / Comments 
 4-903.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Clean equipment were found stored in a dirty container. 4-904.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Paper cups were found dispensed with the food or lip-contact surface facing upward. 5-205.15(B) - Plumbing connections at the hot water faucet at the 3-vat sink is leaking. 6-101.11(A) - Repeat One ceiling tile located above the 3-vat sink is absorbent and not easily cleaned. 6-202.11(A) - Light bulbs in the ceiling in the dry storage area are covered by a broken protective shielding. 6-501.11 - Observed that there are several holes in the wall by the prep sink. 
 July 03, 2007 Routine 0 6 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. January 04, 2007 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 4-402.11(A) - The three-compartment sink is not installed in a manner that allows accessibility for cleaning, nor is it installed with closely abutting surfaces to minimize the need for cleaning. Observed the sink pulled-away from the caulking. 4-602.13 - The nonfood contact surfaces of the following equipment had accumulations of grime and debris: 1. non-food contact surfaces of the bottom of sheet pans on the clean equipment storage shelf near the three-compartment sink. 6-101.11(A) - One ceiling tile located above the three-compartment sink is absorbent and not easily cleaned. 
 January 04, 2007 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments 
 3-302.11A1 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Raw animal food stored over ready-to-eat (RTE) food in the refrigeration unit. Observed raw chicken stored over single service juice containers in the walk-in refrigerator. The chicken had dripped onto the exterior of the juice box. 3-501.19A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Sliced tomatoes, for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control, was not labeled or otherwise marked with a 4 hour cook, serve or discard by time. Observed the food item at 72F and labeled with a six hour discard time. 4-101.111 - The nonfood contact surface of the bottom chemical storage shelf is lined with cardboard and therefore is not corrosion resistant, nonabsorbent, and/or smooth. 4-501.11A - The rusted and peeling equipment storage shelf was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged. 
 August 23, 2006 Routine 2 2 Details / Comments 
 4-501.11B - The door gasket of the walkin is ripped 6-403.11B - The few hooks provided for employee storage of jackets, pocketbooks, etc are inadequate 6-501.110B - Corrected During Inspection Employee clothing and other possessions have been found stored in areas that may contaminate food, food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items.(jackets stored on soda syrup containers) 
 March 03, 2006 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments 
 4-501.11B - The door gasket of the walkin is ripped 6-403.11B - The few hooks provided for employee storage of jackets, pocketbooks, etc are inadequate 6-501.110B - Corrected During Inspection Employee clothing and other possessions have been found stored in areas that may contaminate food, food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items.(jackets stored on soda syrup containers) 
 March 03, 2006 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments 
 4-402.11A - The prep sink in the rear area is not caulked to the wall. 4-501.11B - One light fixture in ceiling has a burned out light tube 4-901.11A - pans stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 
 October 25, 2005 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments 
 4-402.11A - The prep sink in the rear area is not caulked to the wall. 4-501.11B - one light fixture in ceiling has a burned out light tube. 4-901.11A - pans stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitation. 
 October 25, 2005 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. June 17, 2005 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 3-304.14B2 - Corrected During Inspection Level of sanitizer in wiping cloth container was low 4-802.11A - Corrected During Inspection Ripped and soiled oven mitt was noted in kitchen 6-301.12A - Corrected During Inspection Observed that no paper towels were available for handsink at the mens&apos; room 6-501.11 - one tile is missing from the ceiling; manager says it was stained by a leak 
 January 10, 2005 Routine 0 4 Details / Comments 
 4-904.11A - The french fry containers were found handled, displayed or dispensed with the food or lip-contact surface facing upward. Employees must take them from the dispenser by the top edge because the holder will not allow them to be pulled out by the bottom, as they should be 2-402.11A - Employees observed working in the food service area without proper hair restraints. The managers are not wearing hats; one manager is scooping fries. In addition, although the employees have caps and hair pulled back, their hair is not covered. 
 December 22, 2004 Complaint 0 2 Details / Comments 
 6-501.11 - ceiling tile is stained in area of three vat sink 7-201.11A - container of cleaner stored next to soda syrup 3-304.14B2 - Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. 4-204.112B - could not find thermometer in small freezer 6-501.12A - noted dead flies in fly traps and soiled caulk at rear prep sink 6-303.11A - one light out in ceiling in rear storage area 4-901.11A - pans in storage near three vat wsink found stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 4-501.11B - there is a leak at the faucet of the mop sink 
 July 08, 2004 Routine 0 8 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. March 10, 2004 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 3-305.12F - Single service straws and cups observed under water lines of hand sink. 4-501.114A - Critical Chlorine sanitizing solution was not at an acceptable concentration. Chlorine detected less than 50ppm in sanitizing buckets. 4-602.11E - 1. Ice machine interior and 2. soda nozzles observed soiled with accumulations of grime and debris. 6-501.114A - Observed broken refrigerator and unused lockers outside establishment in refuse area. Facility is storing unnecessary items to the operation or maintenance of the establishment. 4-501.11B - 1. The door gasket of the Silver King refrigerator observed soiled with mildew and other soil build-up. 2. The door gasket to the walk-in freezer observed damaged. 
 November 26, 2003 Routine 1 4 Details / Comments 
 6-101.11A - Repeat The ceiling tile over the 3-vat sink is moved to the side due to work being done. 6-303.11A - Inadequate lighting was noted in the walk-in freezer. 4-602.11E - Surfaces of the ice machine are in contact with non-potentially hazardous food items that were observed soiled with accumulations of grime and debris. 
 April 08, 2003 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
