<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004106" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Knoxville/Louis-Original-Drive-in-Restaurant" time="2012-07-12-20:20" support="1" score="0.0017427640685868575" bingtitle="Louis Original Drive in Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant ..." webtitle="Louis Original Drive in Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant  Knoxville, TN">
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Louis Original Drive in Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant ... One of the small tables is next to the order window, so anyone coming in to pick up a to-go order will be ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Louis Original Drive in
Restaurant

 
Average User Rating
 
10
 
Perfect

 2 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(865) 688-4121

 
 TN &gt; Knoxville &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Louis Original Drive in Restaurant listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Louis Original Drive in Restaurant to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Louis Original Drive in Restaurant
 Louis Original Drive in Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located at 4624 N Broadway St in Knoxville, TN . Louis Original Drive in Restaurant has been described as an Perfect Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 10 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Pizza, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Louis Original Drive in Restaurant
 
 
 
All Reviews for Louis Original Drive in Restaurant

 
 Lauren 
 


September 02, 2008
 
Food
 
10
 
Decor
 
10
 
Service
 
10
 
Louis restaurant has been around for a long time and has many fans. Expect the parking lot to be packed during dinner time or on the weekends. If you are looking for the best comfort food in Knoxville, try Louis spaghetti. The sauce is so good. They load up the plates too so you get a lot of food. The prices are good for as much food as you get.
 
Overall Rating
 
10
 
&quot;Perfect&quot;
 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
10
 
Decor
 
10
 
Service
 
10
 
Someone had recommended that I try Beijing II. The first time I tried to go there, they were closed. I believe they close at 8PM or even before on weeknights. This place is extremely small. One of the small tables is next to the order window, so anyone coming in to pick up a to-go order will be right on top of your food. Don&apos;t let them seat you there! The place is really TOO small for the tables they have there.The menu is moderately varied although not as much as I have seen elsewhere. The pric
 
Overall Rating
 
10
 
&quot;Perfect&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Louis Original Drive in Restaurant:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   2

 
Comments
 
 
Louis Original Drive in Restaurant News
 The mystery of China’s big spenders My friend runs an import-export business and was thinking about opening a sideline in exporting the fragrant nuggets of black gold to Shanghai restaurants ... of the country building a city the size of New York on an annual basis. China’s communist ... The 50 best hotels in the world There is a lovely restaurant and bar (featuring the original ceiling fan from Apocalypse Now), and ... s hospitality landscape and is one of the places to be seen in New York. The concierges are walking encyclopedias, the location on 57th and Park is ... CDs of the week: The Maccabees, Louis Armstrong and East of Underground His renown was such that he dined in the best restaurants ... as well. Louis Armstrong was not, as is often claimed, a Freemason. Although he is usually listed as being a member of Montgomery Lodge No. 18 (Prince Hall) in New York, no such lodge has ... Fred Hayman Recounts Wild Ride on Rodeo Drive BEVERLY HILLS — At the height of Giorgio Beverly Hills, in 1981, when the Rodeo Drive ... original address. “Those were the main thoroughbreds that drove Rodeo Drive to new heights, which then other designers followed — Prada, Dolce&amp;Gabbana, Chanel ... Fox&apos;s Fraudulent Defense Of South Carolina&apos;s Voter ID Law Airlines, restaurants, federal buildings have ... including the Justice Department, and to drive, buy liquor or cigarettes, even to collect welfare in many states. [Fox News, Fox&amp;Friends, 1/3/12] A dozen nuns and an unknown number of students were ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Best Deals and Discounts on the Best Local Restaurants – Save ... Saving money on dining out is easy with Restaurant.com gift certificates. Find restaurants in your area and get $25 restaurant gift certificates for only $10! Start ... NYC.com | New York Hotels - Broadway Tickets - New York ... Save more with NYC.com, the trusted New York City experts. Book New York hotels and lodging, buy New York Broadway tickets and event tickets, reserve New York ... Guy Fieri in Diners, Drive-Ins, and Disasters - Page 1 ... &quot;We&apos;ve had to lay people off,&quot; Page booms. He tears past walls lined with advertisements for the Dari-Ette Drive-In, Rosie&apos;s Diner, and Pop&apos;s Greasy Spoon. The rotund ... Guy Fieri in Diners, Drive-Ins, and Disasters - - Restaurants ... &quot;We&apos;ve had to lay people off,&quot; Page booms. He tears past walls lined with advertisements for the Dari-Ette Drive-In, Rosie&apos;s Diner, and Pop&apos;s Greasy Spoon. Travel - Guides and Deals for Hotels, Restaurants and Vacations ... Expert travel advice for destinations around the world from The New York Times, including hotel, restaurant, and vacation tips and deals. 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 73° 
Fri
 
 70° - 90° 
Sat
 
 68° - 88° 
Sun
 
 70° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Louis Original Drive in Restaurant

4624 N Broadway St

Knoxville, TN 
 

 
Telephone
 (865) 688-4121 
Louis Original Drive in Restaurant
 
 Rating :  10 out of 10 based on 2 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Louis Original Drive in Restaurant Photos
 
 Fast Food Pizza American 
 
 Local Places
 
 China City Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dragon Den Chinese Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pizza Cafe 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Lotus Garden Chinese Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Krystal 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pizza Palace Restrnt 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Long John Silvers 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food China Inn Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Krystal 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wendy&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food New China Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Barnstone Farms 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Ac Moore Arts Crafts Store 
Cuisine: Art Craft Supplies Hanson Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Monsarrat Artisan Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Picture Frames Barn 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Knoxville Art Museums Galleries 
See all Knoxville Art Craft Supplies 
See all Knoxville Hotels Motels 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Louis Original Drive in Restaurant Coupons 

 Louis Original Drive in Restaurant Knoxville 

 Louis Original Drive in Restaurant Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Knoxville Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P R | S | T | V | W | Y 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
