<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004997" url="http://www.astrologyzine.com/health/holy-tea-testimonials.shtml" time="2012-07-12-21:31" support="20" score="0.03154302566899509" bingtitle="Holy Tea Testimonials - Astrology Zine - Astrology and Tarot" webtitle="Holy Tea Testimonials">
			<query id="000387" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001170" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000794" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000857" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000730" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000105" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000920" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001045" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000668" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001140" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000355" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000574" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001297" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000231" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000542" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000982" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="148"/>
	<description>... just one regular tea or coffee per day at a fast-food restaurant. ... There&apos;s also a US/Canada toll-free order number where ... A cathartic stimulates faster elimination of waste ...</description>
	<body>
		Holy Tea
Testimonials 
 

 Holy Tea 
is a good-tasting, gentle, safe, all-natural tea 
with medicinal herb ingredients and enzymes which help remove toxins 
and provide relief from many health issues. 

 Thousands of users achieved weight loss and removed inches from their belly simply by drinking
 Dr. Miller&apos;s
Holy Tea 
 
 
 Holy Tea Testimonials 

 
 &quot;Based on a Medicinal Herb Called Holy Thistle  Used For 2000 Years, 
This Colon-Cleansing Detox Tea Has Been Used Successfully For Over 20 Years.&quot; 
 

Holy Tea Tastes Great and is Easy To Use. Just Drink Two 8-ounce Cups per Day.

| Testimonials | FAQ | Ingredients | Directions | BUY Holy Tea |
 Who Uses Holy Tea? | Contact 
 Holy Tea Movie with Testimonials 
 
 Drink
 Dr. Miller&apos;s
Holy Tea 
if you have:
Allergies, Skin Ailments, 
Heartburn, Acid Reflux, Gas, Bloated Belly, Cramps, Flatulence, Indigestion, IBS, Chronic Constipation.
Or need:
Laxatives, Colon Cleanse, a Detox, 
Weight Loss, More Energy. 

 BUY Holy Tea 
Sample Pack $12.49 
 
 
 

 Holy Tea User 
 Testimonials 

 Weight Loss 

 All-Natural 
 Ingredients 

 Frequently Asked 
 Questions 

 Directions 
 For Brewing and Using Holy Tea 

 Uses for 
 Holy Tea 

 Health 
 Benefits 

 Constipation 

 Diarrhea 

 Flatulence 

 Irritable Bowel 

 Heartburn 

 Parasites and Worms 

 Yeast Infections 

 How to Get 
 Holy Tea for FREE 


 
 Holy Tea 
Ingredients 
contain NONE of these: stimulants, caffeine, harsh laxatives like cascara or cassia senna, sugar, salt, harmful chemicals, or pesticides.
It is made from the finest quality herbal ingredients grown in the USA.
Holy Tea is gentle, easy to use, proven to work, and very affordable. 
 

 
 Holy Tea Benefits 

 Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea was formulated by Dr. Bill Miller (Ph.D. Nutritional Science) of Tennessee, USA. It is a unique blend of safe, edible, all-natural, pesticide-free, USA grown, herbal ingredients designed to gently cleanse the digestive tract and detoxify the body. Holy Tea is a colon cleansing tea, a detox tea, a weight loss tea, and a great-tasting herbal tea - all wrapped up in each unbleached tea bag.

But, most of all, Holy Tea is a healing tea . Remarkable things happen when you drink Holy Tea every day. It is gentle, yet surprisingly powerful as a colon cleanse, liver cleanse, kidney cleanse, Candida cleanse, parasite cleanse, and whole body detoxifier. You probably won&apos;t need any more antacids, laxatives, stool softeners, allergy pills, acne creams and many other potions and lotions after you start drinking Holy Tea each day.

See the testimonials below - they are truly inspiring!

The name&quot;Holy Tea&quot;is taken from the traditional name of one of its effective ingredients, a widely-used and scientifically studied medicinal herb known as Holy Thistle ( Silybum marianum ), and is not intended to imply any religious significance - although grateful users who experienced remarkable health improvements after taking Holy Tea often thank God for this gift of healing! Some want to call it a &quot;miracle tea&quot;, but this cleansing tea is really just a special blend of high-quality USA-grown herbal ingredients, tested and refined over 20 years of use in Dr. Miller&apos;s health clinics. This secret blend of safe, natural ingredients produces fast and effective results that no imitator has been able to copy.

With continued use of Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea one may experience clearer, healthier, and younger-looking skin; increased energy; increased mental clarity and focus; better memory; more resistance to diseases; better overall health and vitality; more comfort with the body; and a happier outlook on life.
 
 Holy Tea Testimonials 

 Dr. Miller and his wife operate two health clinics in Jackson, Tennessee, and for over 20 years have been using Holy Tea to improve the health of thousands of clients. He has hundreds of written and videotaped testimonials from grateful users of Holy Tea, and a sampling of these testimonials are reproduced below.

 Watch the Holy Tea online movie and listen to the personal messages from Dr. Miller and his grateful users. 

 
 Here&apos;s what some users have said about Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea... 

 &quot;Since I began taking Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea I no longer need to take Nexium, and my Acid Reflux is totally cleared up. I dropped from 240 to 185 lbs., and even though I smoke 2 packs of cigarettes a day the doctor said he could not believe how clear my lungs are, as if I did not smoke. The Tea is the best health product I have ever taken!&quot;
 - William Griffen, Jackson, TN 

 &quot;I have been on Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea for 12 years, both my husband and I. I had Crohn&apos;s Disease, Irritable Bowel Syndrome and terrible acid reflux. I won&apos;t miss a day without drinking my tea. I used to have terrible knife-like sharp pains in my stomach from the Crohn&apos;s and IBS, and a great deal of discomfort from the acid reflux. Dr. Miller&apos;s tea has cleared all of this up, and I lost almost 30 pounds as well. My husband lost more weight than I did. I swear by the tea and would not be without it.&quot;
 - Ruth and Billy Hurt, Cedar Grove, TN 

 &quot;Not only did the Tea make me look years younger, I feel years younger too, and have more energy than ever. I tell everyone this is a &apos;must have&apos; product.&quot;
 - Sally May, Jackson, TN (she lost 60+ pounds) 

 &quot;As a member of the medical community, I was quite familiar with the causes, symptoms, and treatments available for Crohn&apos;s. I became much more knowledgeable in this regard as I became a victim of this so-called incurable disorder. There is absolutely no doubt in my mind as to the effectiveness and medical principles behind Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea. I have experienced personally the pain and discomfort that results from Crohn&apos;s and I have also done exhaustive research into the possible treatments and cures. Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea is the only viable solution I am aware of for treating and clearing up this dreaded disease.&quot;
 - Dr. Dennis Read, Jackson, TN 
 
 
 Holy Tea helps people restore their natural state of optimum health and wellness by stimulating the body to rid itself of stored toxins, drug residues, parasites, yeast and fungus - things that cause disease and make us feel less than healthy. But we become so used to feeling bad that we don&apos;t realize we should be feeling better!

Just try drinking Holy Tea for a week or more to start detoxifying your body and you will soon start feeling better than before. Some users see and feel results within a few days to a week, which is why the Holy Tea Club is confident in offering a one-week trial pack of Holy Tea. Seven or eight out of ten users notice positive results within the first week of use.

Keep drinking Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea and your &quot;Quality of Life&quot; will gradually get better, and you won&apos;t ever want to go back to that old life of low energy, lack of focus, annoying ailments, or serious suffering. Here are some Holy Tea testimonials that refer to improving the quality of life of some suffering seniors...

 
 Holy Tea Improves Quality of Life... 
 
&quot;I have been drinking Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea for almost 5 years. It has helped me lose over 50 pounds and keep it off, and keep me healthier than I had been for 40 years. I can now travel and enjoy my retirement, where before I did not feel well enough to do so. I am amazed by the results of the Tea for both me and friends I have told about it. One friend of mine, who is 70 years old, has had terrible migraines for the past 10 years, which were about to drive him crazy. After a couple of months drinking Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea, he no longer has the migraines. Some of the results I see with the Tea just baffle me.&quot;
 - Nancy Moy, Chicago, IL

&quot;I own and operate an Assisted Living Facility that houses 15 residents. I began drinking Dr. Miller&apos;s Tea about six years ago due to my high blood pressure and blood sugar problems, both of which are health issues that run in my family. I now have no problems with either of those issues, and I have no doubt that the Tea is the reason.

After I had been taking the Tea personally for a couple of years, I began to serve it to the residents of the ALF, every one of them. They all won&apos;t be without it now. I&apos;ve personally seen it correct a multitude of health issues in people from their mid 50s to over 90 years old. I have a 90 year old resident who I believe the Tea is the only thing that provides her any hope of a quality of life. If she doesn&apos;t drink the Tea, she is like a sack of bricks. It&apos;s as if the Tea erases 20 years of aging from her.

Also, my sister was having health problems and had been told that she needed to schedule surgery for intestinal problems. As soon as she told me, I made sure she was drinking the Tea. She has not had surgery and now has none of the health issues that were prompting the surgery. Her husband was literally dumbfounded by the results. Needless to say, they are avid Dr. Miller Tea drinkers.

The Tea works wonders.&quot;

 - Wanda Grady, Cedar Grove, TN
 

 Holy Tea is a both a colon cleansing tea and whole body detoxifier. Medical experts say that 85 to 95 percent of all ailments begin with an unhealthy colon, so you can see how important it is to keep our colons healthy and free of the impacted fecal matter (i.e. mucoid plaque ) that is constantly poisoning us with toxins being absorbed into the bloodstream (i.e. autointoxification or &quot;self-poisoning&quot;) - and serving as a breeding ground for hundreds of varieties of pathogenic bacteria, yeast and fungi , parasites and worms .

Here is a Holy Tea testimonial that refers to improvements in colon health...
 
 
 Holy Tea for a Healthy Colon... 
 
&quot;It was about eight years ago that I started drinking Dr. Millers tea. Since then I have had two colonoscopies done by two different physicians. After each procedure the doctor has remarked to me how clean my colon has been. During this eight year period I have not had so much as a common cold. Working in the health field, I have learned that the body must get rid of toxins or else they will be absorbed back into the blood stream and cause many different problems. I have no doubt whatsoever that Dr. Millers tea is the key to detoxification of the body.

Also, during this time I have noticed that my skin has a much smoother look and feel and my primary care physician has even remarked that I have the skin of a much younger man. I am a Vietnam veteran and will turn sixty on my next birthday. Many of my comrades-in-arms have either died or have some really serious health problems. Again, I am totally convinced that Dr. Millers tea is the primary reason I am still around and kicking.&quot;
 - Dan Record, Henderson, TN
 

Click here to view a web page with detailed Instructions for using Holy Tea and a list of Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ).

Click here to view a web page with answers to Frequently Asked Questions About Holy Tea (FAQ page).

Click here to view a web page with detailed descriptions of the Ingredients of Holy Tea .
 
 ORDER Holy Tea Online 

| Testimonials | Holy Tea Benefits | Holy Tea Ingredients | FAQ | Directions |
 Holy Tea Movie with Testimonials 
 
 Holy Tea may also be used as an element in any Weight Loss Program and is much more effective than Chinese Tea, Oolong Tea, Wu Yi Tea, Red Rooibos Tea, or Green Tea. Just drinking Holy Tea regularly often results in a reduction in the amount of stored fat in the body as toxins stored in fat cells are releases, and a significant reduction in the size of the abdomen or belly as the impacted fecal matter in the colon is gradually cleaned out. For some people, the weight loss has been achieved quickly and rather dramatically (see the Testimonials), but individual results will vary.

 When the excess weight is actually from pounds of impacted fecal matter stuck to the inside wall of the colon and small intestine, no amount of dieting or fat loss or exercise can reduce the size of the belly.   But Holy Tea can! 
If you have bloat, midriff bulge, a &quot;beer belly&quot;, a &quot;pot belly&quot;, or a protruding abdomen, then drinking Holy Tea can help you shed pounds and lose inches around your waist, without dieting or changing your eating habits. (See Bulging Bellies .)

 Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea is a safe, mild, all-natural, detoxifying health tea. It is gentle in its action, yet more effective than most other colon cleansing products, laxatives, and detoxifiers. It&apos;s also a very good-tasting herbal detox tea which is simple to use - you just drink 8 ounces twice per day with meals!

No restrictive detox diet, no fasting, no diet pills, no harsh laxatives, and no complicated procedures. Just drink your Holy Tea every day. You don&apos;t even have to drink it with meals, but doing so could help provide heartburn relief or stop acid reflux.

Holy Tea LOOKS like any other herbal tea, but don&apos;t be fooled. Just two of those Holy Tea bags make ONE U.S. GALLON or 4 litres of Holy Tea - an 8-DAY supply! And this is a HEALING TEA. Most people feel positive effects within a week, and often within a day or two!

See for yourself! Order a one-week Sample Pack of Holy Tea for USD $12.49 plus a shipping fee of $2.51 to USA, Canada, Mexico, South America, Europe, Asia, Australia, Africa, or any country in the world! Click here to visit the Holy Tea online store.
 
 Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea - The Bottom Line 

 Holy Tea contains only safe, natural ingredients and is made from the finest quality edible herbs grown in the USA. Holy Tea is made in the USA and ALL of the high-quality herbal ingredients are grown in the southeastern U.S. states of Georgia and Florida.

 Holy Tea contains NO caffeine, ephedra, hoodia, stimulants, drugs, cascara, cassia, senna, harsh laxatives, pesticides, harmful chemicals, sugar, salt, or fillers. It does not create any bowel dependency and does not irritate the intestines.

 Holy Tea has no harmful side effects. There is no discomfort, and no constant running to the bathroom. It softens hard stools, but does not cause diarrhea . It helps you get back to having two to three quick and easy bowel movements per day, the way you are supposed to.

 Holy Tea ingredients are all well-known herbs which have been used safely for hundreds of years, and have been the subject of various scientific research studies in recent years. It is the quality and the precise combination of these herbal ingredients which makes Holy Tea unique and effective. The secret formula has been imitated, but no one has been able to produce a product as effective as Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea .

 Holy Tea helps you lose weight, reduce fat, and lose inches off your waist without any change in diet or depriving yourself of foods you like to eat. It can be used alone, or along with another weight loss program. Much of the weight and inch loss is due to cleaning out pounds of impacted fecal matter and parasites from inside your colon, something which no fat loss diet can achieve.

 Holy Tea provides the very best colon cleanse and body detox available today.  And it helps remove toxins from every place in your body - organs, tissues, blood, fat cells, and your entire digestive tract. It is also a gentle yet effective parasite cleanse, Candida cleanse, worm remedy, and herbal home remedy for acid reflux, heartburn, gas, bloating, food allergies, constipation and various colon ailments.

 Holy Tea supports the body in detoxifying and healing itself of all kinds of ailments caused by:
(1) toxic build-up of decaying impacted fecal matter in the intestines ( mucoid plaque ) and the resulting autointoxification;
(2) bacteria, yeast, microbial parasites, amoebae, worms and flukes; and
(3) the poisons and toxic compounds released by some of these bacteria and other microbes. 
Restoring the colon, liver and kidneys to a healthy state reduces the risk of many painful and potentially fatal diseases.

 Holy Tea is made by a hands-on expert in Nutritional Science who actually cares about your health . Dr. Miller has devoted his entire professional life to researching, formulating, testing, and perfecting this remarkable healing tea while working with clients at his two health clinics. He uses the finest quality herbal ingredients from sources in the southeastern USA (not China).

 Holy Tea has been used successfully for over 20 years at Dr. Miller&apos;s two health clinics in Tennessee.

 Holy Tea has been proven to work. Just ask his thousands of happy clients!

 Dr. Miller has hundreds of testimonials from grateful users of his Holy Tea. You can read some of their testimonies on this page, or hear them in the online video.

 Holy Tea is convenient and easy to use. It&apos;s as simple as making a gallon of tea, then drinking two glasses per day.

 Holy Tea tastes very good. It is clear and flavorful, just like any good herbal tea. And you can mix it with herbal teas, decaf teas, or juices to suit your taste. You can vary the strength, and you can drink it hot or cold. You can even open the dried used tea bags and add the edible herbal ingredients to foods like salads, sauces, soups, stews, or chili.

 Holy Tea is very affordable. It costs less than over-the-counter remedies or prescription drugs that do less for your overall health. Two daily servings of Holy Tea cost about the same as buying just one regular tea or coffee per day at a fast-food restaurant. When you see and feel the results, you will realize Holy Tea is worth a lot more than you pay for it.


 For information on buying Holy Tea contact Michael Star at 905-891-7436  (11 AM to 11 PM Eastern Time).

Click here to BUY Holy Tea on-line at USD $49.95 retail price for a one-month supply (8 bags make 4 gallons or 16 litres). For 1 to 12 packages S&amp;H is $5 to USA (including Alaska, Hawaii, US Virgin Islands, Puerto Rico), S&amp;H $9 to Canada and Mexico, and S&amp;H $11 to Central America, the Caribbean, South America, the U.K., Europe, Asia, Africa, Australia and all other countries. (See Holy Tea Club info below to buy at wholesale price with discounted or free shipping - and how to get your Holy Tea for FREE.)
 
 ORDER Holy Tea Online 

| Testimonials | FAQ | Benefits of Holy Tea | Ingredients | Directions |
 Holy Tea Movie with Testimonials 
 
Medical professionals tell us that 85% to 95% of all human diseases start with an unhealthy colon.

 Doesn&apos;t it make more sense to take steps to restore the colon to a healthy state and PREVENT disease, than to ignore it and wait until the pain caused by a new disease prompts a person to seek medical treatment? 
And doesn&apos;t it make more sense to restore the colon to health and avoid disease than to just keep taking another expensive drug to treat each new disease that occurs as a result of an unhealthy colon?

 Healthy people don&apos;t need expensive medical treatments or prescription drugs. 

Frankly, we take better care of our automobiles than we do our own bodies. You know that not replacing a dirty oil filter with a clean one on a regular basis is going to cause your engine to break down. Well, not cleaning out a dirty colon is going to cause your body to break down. But in either case, a little bit of relatively inexpensive &quot;preventive maintenance&quot; can avoid the problems.

 If you&apos;re sick and tired of being sick and tired , it&apos;s time to try Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea !
 
Click here to see the Holy Tea Online Video with Testimonials (requires Windows Media Player) 

 For information on buying Holy Tea contact Michael Star at 905-891-7436  (11 AM to 11 PM Eastern Time).
Or contact Michael on Skype for free from anywhere in the world.
SKYPE ID: michaelstar2

Click here to ORDER Holy Tea online at USD $49.95 retail price for a one-month supply, or $12.49 for a one-week Trial Pack. Shipped from the USA to most countries by U.S. Post. The one-week Trial Pack is shipped anywhere in world for a total cost of $15 including shipping.

 ORDER Holy Tea Online 

| Testimonials | FAQ | Benefits | Holy Tea Ingredients | Instructions |
 Holy Tea Movie with Testimonials 
 
 For information on buying or selling Holy Tea, or becoming a Member of the Holy Tea Club, contact Michael Star at 905-891-7436  (11 AM to 11 PM Eastern Time, GMT-5).

Or contact Michael on Skype for free from anywhere in the world.
SKYPE ID: michaelstar2

Click here to BUY Holy Tea online now at the retail price of $12.49 for a one-week trial package or $49.95 for a one-month supply. (Or use the link below to buy at wholesale price as a Holy Tea Club Member and save up to $14.95 per month. Members have the opportunity to get their Holy Tea for FREE by referring just a few new customers or other Members.)

Click here to learn more about the Holy Tea Club and reserve your position as a Full Member with a free web site and the ability to earn monthly commissions from the wholesale purchases and retail web site orders of Holy Tea by people you refer to the Club.

When you start drinking Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea you soon may have a testimonial of your own! If you have been helped by the Holy Tea, then you have a story to tell to the people you know. If it helped you, why wouldn&apos;t you want to share your story with the people you care about?

The Holy Tea Club motto is:  Sharing Is Caring - Pass It On! 

There are so many people suffering needlessly from uncomfortable to downright painful ailments that could be relieved by drinking Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea. Once you have seen how it helped you relieve some discomfort or pain, you&apos;d naturally want to help your family and friends get some relief from their pain too.

If you are willing and able to share your own Holy Tea &quot;testimony&quot; with others you care about, then the Holy Tea Club is willing to give you TWO FREE WEB SITES where you can send people to learn about Holy Tea and purchase it online if they decide it could help them too. It&apos;s FREE to join. There is no cost and no obligation whatsoever. It&apos;s almost &quot;too good to be true&quot; - but it&apos;s true!

Every time someone orders a one-month supply of Holy Tea for $49.95 from your free web site store, your Club account is immediately credited with $9.95. Every time someone orders a one-week Trial Pack for $12.49 your account is credited with $2.49. As a Holy Tea Club Member, you can buy your own Holy Tea at the discount price of $40, so you can see how each $9.95 credit will soon bring the cost of your Holy Tea down to $0 with four sales or more.

 Just referring five people who order a month&apos;s supply of Holy Tea online earns you more than enough to &quot; Get Your Holy Tea For FREE! &quot; - including the cost of shipping to anywhere in the world. When your earnings exceed the cost of the Holy Tea you use yourself, you can have the money sent to you by U.S. check or credited to your international debit card.

Even if you don&apos;t earn enough to &quot;get your Holy Tea for free&quot; right away, you can immediately get it for $9.95 less ($40) just by joing the Holy Tea Club for free. Then each $49.95 sale made on your free web site further reduces your cost by another $9.95. Just two sales would mean your cost goes down to $20.10 (because $40 - $19.90 = $20.10). You can get your Holy Tea at less than half price simply by referring two new users of Holy Tea.

How hard would that be? All you have to do is ask people to visit your free web site. You don&apos;t have to &quot;sell&quot; - you just have to &quot;tell&quot; them how Holy Tea helped you. Then tell them the web address of YOUR Holy Tea web site and ask them to visit to learn all about Holy Tea.

 Your web site does all the selling, order-taking, payment processing, invoicing, and shihpping. Everything is done for you automatically, and at NO cost to you.

Simply join the Club for free and order a one-month supply of Holy Tea at the $40 wholesale price from your own FREE Holy Tea Club member web site and that will qualify you for the first month. After that, you remain qualified simply by drinking Holy Tea and purchasing $40 per month yourself - OR - by making just ONE $49.95 retail sale per month from your free retail web site.

You do NOT have to keep purchasing Holy Tea if you qualify by making just ONE sale from your free web site each month. There is no required &quot;auto shipment&quot; - it&apos;s just an option that can save you money on shipping costs. In fact, you can keep your free web sites and earn money even if you don&apos;t keep buying Holy Tea for yourself - as long as at least ONE $49.95 purchase is made from your web site by any retail customer in each month. Or you can just quit anytime you want, and your customers can order from another Holy Tea Club member instead.

It&apos;s not very difficult to find customers for this much-needed health product - my free Holy Tea web site store sells over $2,500 per month of Holy Tea to retail customers.

 And most of them just order online without even calling me to ask any questions. The web site provides all the information they need, such as benefits, testimonials, ingredients, and directions for use. So you don&apos;t have to be an expert or a &quot;sales person&quot;. Just TELL people about your Holy Tea web site and invite them to visit.

Wouldn&apos;t a friend or co-worker be willing to at least look at your new web site? You can tell them it&apos;s a professionally-designed e-commerce web site and you got it for free! Actually, you get TWO free web sites - one is your Retail site that has a shopping cart to take retail orders; and the other is your Member site where you can order Holy Tea at the wholesale price, check your current sales and earnings &quot;in real time&quot;, and choose the way to send you the money in your Holy Tea Club account.

 My Holy Tea Club web store is like an automatic &quot;money machine&quot; that works 24/7 without any effort on my part. And you can get one like it for FREE! All you have to do is find ways to get people to visit your own web site, and the rest is done for you automatically. Send a few emails, give out a few business cards, post a few notices on bulletin boards. Place some small classified ads in your local newspaper.

Better yet, just tell the people you know how Holy Tea helped you, and how it could help them solve their health problems and improve their lives.

Click here to see an example of your own free Holy Tea Club retail web site - or to order a Holy Tea sample pack on-line for the retail price of USD $12.49 plus $2.51 shipping to any country in the world. (Don&apos;t place an order there if you plan to become a Holy Tea Club member. You could order at the discount price from your own web site!)

We ship a one to twelve-month supply of Holy Tea to any country at low rates ($5 to $11), and Members from almost every country are welcome. If they wish, Members can choose an auto ship option and also save $4 to $5 on the shipping fee so it&apos;s only $0 to $7 for any quantity up to 12 one-month supplies.

 Do you think you &quot;don&apos;t have the time&quot; to refer people? If you have time to tell people about that restaurant you loved or a good movie you have seen, then wouldn&apos;t you have a little time to tell people about a product that helped you feel healthier, or relieved you of some chronic pain or discomfort?

 If you feel that the Holy Tea is good for you, why wouldn&apos;t you want to tell your family and friends about it? 

 You just have to &quot;tell&quot; - not &quot;sell&quot;. Just ask them to visit your free Holy Tea Club web site and let it tell the story, show the testimonials, and sell the product for you! Your free e-commence web store takes credit card orders (and some debit cards) and ships the products for you, so you don&apos;t have to! There&apos;s also a US/Canada toll-free order number where your customers can order by phone and pay by check or money order. (They will need to tell the order desk person your HTC Member ID (mine is &quot;freetea&quot;) for you to get credit for the sale.)

Cleansing the colon and detoxing the whole body can eliminate so much unneccessary pain and suffering - and literally change someone&apos;s life for the better.

 Who wouldn&apos;t want to share that helpful information with the people they care about? Honestly, if you were one of the first to hear about a health product like Aspirin that could relieve headaches and pains, would you NOT tell your friends and family about it?

 Holy Tea can help people in many more ways. But billions of people don&apos;t even know about it yet. You could be someone who helps &quot;spread the word&quot; about this life-changing health product.

Instead of paying millions of dollars to the rich owners of television and radio stations and magazines and newspapers for advertising, the Holy Tea Club is willing to pay YOU to do &quot;word of mouth&quot; advertising to the people you know. And &quot;word of mouth&quot; is the BEST advertising, because people would rather hear about a product from someone they know and trust.

Just share your personal story or &quot;testimoniaL&quot; about Holy Tea and invite people to visit your Holy Tea Club web site to see some more testimonials and learn about Holy Tea and the many ways it can help people with many more health conditions than you might have yourself. I don&apos;t have colon cancer and don&apos;t ever want to die that way - but I knew someone who had a belly full of impacted fecal matter and died of colon cancer, so I tell people about that too. I won&apos;t mention my own testimonial here, but you can ask me when we talk.

You can listen in on the Holy Tea Club Conference Calls almost any day of the week and hear many other people giving their personal testimonies about Holy Tea and how it helped them.

Each person who buys a one-month supply of Holy Tea from your free Holy Tea Club web site for $49.95 will generate a $9.95 commission which is put into your HTC Member Account. So each time such a sale is made, the cost of your own Holy Tea goes down by $9.95 because you can use the money in your account when you order Holy Tea for yourself at the Member price. Or you could have it mailed to you by check when it grows to $20 or more.

 All it takes is four customers to earn you almost enough to pay for your own monthly supply of Holy Tea - which you get at the $40 wholesale price as a Holy Tea Club Member. Five customers will cover the cost of your Holy Tea and any fees for shipping to anywhere in the world, and still leave a little money in your account.

Why pay the $49.95 retail price when you can simply refer a few new users and get your Tea for FREE ?

By the way, some of my retail customers save on shipping by ordering $99 to $199 worth of Holy Tea at a time, not just $49.95. A family of two will order $99.90 to provide for two users. You might need only two or three of those customers to get your Holy Tea for free.

And some of those retail customers will tell others who could also become your retail customers.

When you have more than enough customers buying the Holy Tea each month to pay for your own supply, you can start earning a nice monthly income that can grow from about $10 per month to $100 per month to a $1,000 per month or more. Already, some Members are earning $2,000 to $3,000 per month* just by telling people about Holy Tea.

And who couldn&apos;t use even an extra $50 to $500 per month to cover the ever-increasing cost of food, gas, electricity, and prescription drugs? Or the next interest rate increase on one of those adjustable-rate home mortgages? For some Americans, getting a little business going on the side might make them enough extra money to save them from being one of the million who may soon lose their homes through a mortgage default and a bank foreclosure.

* Your personal income will depend solely on your efforts and the amount of Holy Tea sold. These income figures are shown as examples only.

 Click here to learn more about the Holy Tea Club 
 or click here to sign up today for your own free Holy Tea Club web site store and order Holy Tea at the $40 member price for a one-month supply. (A monthly auto shipment is NOT required, but you will save an extra $4 to $5 per month on shipping if you choose to set one up. It can be changed or cancelled anytime.)

If you sign up and do not order any Holy Tea, you are a &quot;Free Member&quot; but still get the free web site store where you can send people and make online sales and earn the same $9.95 commission per $49.95 retail sale, or $2.49 commission per $12.49 sample pack sale. Making just one $49.95 sale will permanently qualify you as a Full Member even if you do not purchase any Holy Tea yourself.

So without spending any money yourself, you can &quot;earn&quot; your way to Full Member simply by sending people to your free web site. As a Free Member you can earn commissions on retail sales from your web store. As a Full Member you can ALSO earn a percentage of the monthly wholesale purchases AND retail sales made by other Free Members and Full Members who join through your own web site. (You can even earn a percentage of the purchases and sales of Full Members who were NOT referred by you - but were placed under you by other Full Members above you OR were referred by Members whom you did personally refer.)

Please don&apos;t sign up for free and expect to just sit there doing nothing. You DO have to do something to get people to VISIT your free web store, or nothing is going to happen. But you really don&apos;t have to do much more than that!

Just sending the URL of your new web store to your friends is an easy way to get started. Why wouldn&apos;t a friend or relative be willing to take a look at your new web site? Some might decide to &quot;Try the Tea&quot; themselves, and then you will have some new customers! Some might want to keep ordering Holy Tea every month, and then you will be building yourself an ongoing monthly income!

 Click here to see an example of your own free Holy Tea Club retail web site - or to order a Holy Tea one-week &quot;trial pack&quot; on-line for the retail price of USD $12.49 plus $2.51 S&amp;H.

It would make sense to actually &quot;Try the Tea&quot; yourself before deciding if you want to get a free web store and recommend Holy Tea to others, but you are NOT required to. If just reading about Holy Tea and the user testimonials has convinced you to &quot;try the tea&quot; then maybe others will too! Just tell people about your own web site so they can visit and read about Holy Tea, and some will want to try it.

It would be even better if you could tell them how the Holy Tea helped YOU personally, but did you notice that I haven&apos;t told you how it helped me? I will if you want to phone me. But it&apos;s not always necessary to have a great personal testimony when there are lots of other testimonials available like the ones on this web page - and the ones on your own free Holy Tea Club web site.

Even if the Holy Tea had not been such a help to me personally (it did help me a lot!), if I knew that it had really helped some other people I know, then I could still recommend it to others. I don&apos;t need to take pain pills, but I could still recommend some places to get good pain medications.

We have found that about 7 or 8 out of 10 people who buy the $12.49 Holy Tea one-week trial pack see or feel results within a few days to a week and then come back to order a full month&apos;s supply. If you just tell enough people about your free web site, you could earn a very nice income every month - $2.49 for each one-week trial pack ordered, and $9.95 for each retail customer who buys enough Holy Tea for one month. How many would you need to earn an extra $100 or $1000 next month from your free web store?

Just referring 4 or 5 people who order a month&apos;s supply is enough to &quot;get your Holy Tea for free&quot; - and then any more than that starts earning you a nice income with no investment and very little expenses, if any.

When you see how well this works, you might want to put a little money into some local advertising or world-wide web promotion to get more people to visit your free Holy Tea on-line store. More visitors means more income for you. My web store gets orders from all over the world every day, even from countries which don&apos;t use the English language!

 Click here to order a one-week trial pack from my Holy Tea Club retail web site for the total price of USD $15.00 including shipping world-wide, and see how YOUR OWN free web site could be making sales for YOU! Then give me a call if you have any questions - I am very user-friendly!
 
 ORDER Holy Tea Online 

| Testimonials | FAQ | Holy Tea Ingredients | Directions |
 Who Needs Holy Tea? | Bulging Bellies | Colon Health | Digestive Tract | Liver&amp;Kidneys | Dr Miller 
 Holy Tea Movie with Testimonials 
 
 This article about Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea user testimonials is©2007 Michael Star Co. Portions were reproduced with permission.
The text and images on this copyrighted web page may not be published on another web site or in any media without the consent of the author or copyright owner. Permission is given to copy portions of this web page for personal, non-commercial use only.

 Contact: Michael Star 905-891-7436 (11 AM to 11 PM Eastern Time, GMT -5 hours)

The content of this Holy Tea article is intended &quot;for educational purposes only&quot; and should not be construed as medical advice. Holy Tea is a natural food, not a drug, and this general information is not intended to provide any diagnosis, treatment, or cure. If you have a medical condition, consult your personal physician or health care practitioner.
 

 This product contains natural herbal ingredients which act as a cathartic . A cathartic stimulates faster elimination of waste products from the body, which may not be appropriate under some conditions.

Women who are pregnant or nursing, elderly persons, young children, and individuals suffering from any illness or health condition should consult with their personal physician prior to using this or any herbal supplement.

Holy Tea stimulates your body to detoxify itself by eliminating all toxins and foreign substances, which may include drug residues and even the pharmaceutical drug medications you use today. If you are taking medications, we suggest you do not drink Holy Tea for two hours before and after you take your medicine, to avoid reducing the effectiveness of your medications. 

The Holy Tea user testimonials quoted in this article and recorded testimonies from Holy Tea users shown in the online video are anecdotal and may not represent typical results. Individual results will vary.

The U.S. FDA does not review health products which are sold as a dietary supplement. (Holy Tea is a natural food, not a drug.)
As required by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA):
&quot;These statements have not been evaluated by the FDA. This product is not intended to diagnose, treat, cure or prevent any disease.&quot;

 Disclaimer: Do not take Dr. Miller&apos;s Holy Tea as a substitute for medical treatment. Always follow the advice of your doctor, personal physician, or professional health care consultant. 

 Some common alternate spellings and misspellings: Chron&apos;s Disease = Crohn&apos;s Disease; haemorrhoids = hemorrhoids; hemhorroids = hemorrhoids; faeces = feces; diarrea = diarrhea; diarrhoea = diarrhea; laxitive = laxative; mucous = mucus; large bowel = large intestine = colon; irratable bowel = irritable bowel; irritible bowel = irritable bowel; syndrom = syndrome; iratable = irritable; iratible = irritable; irrital bowel = irritable bowel; irrritable = irritable; irritated bowel syndrome = irritable bowel syndrome; bowel cleanse = colon cleanse; bowel cleansing = colon cleansing; bowel cancer = colon cancer; impacted bowel = impacted colon; leaky gut = leaky bowel; Dr. Millers = Dr. Miller&apos;s; Holly Tea = Holy Tea; Wholy Tea = Holy Tea; testimonies = testimonials; ingredent = ingredient; persimon = persimmon; virginia = virginiana; marshmallow = marsh mallow; holly thistle = holy thistle; milk thistle = holy thistle; Sillybum = Silybum; Sillymarin = Silymarin; Cardus = Carduus; ingedients = ingredients 
 
 
 Dr. Miller&apos;s
Holy Tea
is distributed world-wide by
the Holy Tea Club 
 
 
 
 Dr. Miller&apos;s
Holy Tea
is made in the U.S.A. from safe, pesticide-free, natural ingredients grown in Georgia and Florida, USA.
Beware of unauthorized imitations which use cheap, low-quality ingredients. 
 
 
 
 
 Testimonials 
are from
Holy Tea users who were clients of
Dr. Miller&apos;s
health clinics in Tennessee, USA. 
 
 

 BUY Holy Tea 
Sample Pack $12.49
Shipped world-wide for $2.51 S&amp;H.
	</body>
</document>
