<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004456" url="http://www.cheatcc.com/xb/gtasa.html" time="2012-07-12-20:53" support="11" score="0.017311136594618012" bingtitle="Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas Cheats, Codes, Cheat Codes for Xbox (XB)" webtitle="Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas Cheats, Codes, Cheat Codes for Xbox (XB)">
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000676" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>Go to the Ganton gym and park a car in the doorway, with the hood touching the door. ... When at a fast food restaurant (such as Cluckin&apos; Bell or Well Stacked Pizza), have a ...</description>
	<body>
		Hottest Games: 
 Zombi U DmC: Devil May Cry Batman: Arkham City Armored Edition God of War: Ascension 
 
 E3 &apos;12 Awards Videos Newsletter Facebook Special Features Game News 
 
 Home Xbox 360 PS3 PC Wii 3DS NEW 
Vita DS PSP PS2 Xbox GameCube PSOne Other Systems 
 N64 GBA Game Boy Dreamcast DVD 
 
 
 
 Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas 
 Strategy Guide 
 100% Completion Guide 
 Car Locations Guide 
 Girlfriend Guide 
 Horseshoes Location Guide 
 Property Guide 
 Tag Locations Guide 
 Map: Vehicles 
 Map: Weapons 
 Map: Properties 
 Map: Tags, Oysters, Horseshoes, Photos 

 

 Review 

 
 Top 10 Games You&apos;re Embarrassed to Play Top 10 Things That Would Have Made E3 Better Why Do You Never Finish Games? Top 10 Worst Games To Emerge From Development Hell Top 10 Most Inspirational Games Games Need Multiplayer Or You Won&apos;t Play Them The Wii U&apos;s Success Depends On More Than Mario Video Game Propaganda Is Ruining The Industry Best and Worst Of E3 2012 Best and Worst Video Game Dads Top 10 Video Game Sidekicks Top 10 Games That Are Cool To Watch But Not Play More Special Features... New Stuff You Should Check Out! 
 Final Fantasy VII Releasing Once More China Gets Call Of Duty Free To Play The Least Popular Zelda Getting A Remake? Halo 4 Requires 8GB Of Free Space For Multiplayer Resident Evil 6 Demo Live Budokai HD Collection Confirmed 
 
 ESRB Lists GTA3 And Vice City For PS3 Playstation All-Stars: Battle Royale Smashes The Competition Resident Evil 6&apos;s Gameplay Has More Surprises Darksiders 2 Displays A Different Side In The New Trailer Okami Returns In Gorgeous HD
	</body>
</document>
