<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004459" url="http://nutritionunplugged.com/2010/10/predicting-2011-food-and-dining-trends/" time="2012-07-12-20:53" support="2" score="0.003145174221761491" bingtitle="Predicting 2011 Food and Dining Trends | Nutrition Unplugged" webtitle="Predicting 2011 Food and Dining Trends | Nutrition Unplugged">
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>Korean spicing and condiments. Kogi, the LA food truck that launched a thousand wheels, has ... Words to Eat By; Global Food Blogs. A Life (Time) of Cooking – India; A Wee Bit of ...</description>
	<body>
		Nutrition Unplugged 

Serving up food news and views
 
 Home About Buzz Favorites Articles #RDchat Links Contact Subscribe 
 
Predicting 2011 Food and Dining Trends

by Janet on October 30, 2010 
 Share 
 

Photo:  Rhubarb&amp;Raspberry Yogurt by Flickr user La Tartine Gourmande .

I recently wrote about 2011 food and restaurant trends based on the predictions from Andrew Freeman&amp;Co. This time the forecasting comes from Joseph Baum&amp;Michael Whiteman Co. Inc ., international restaurant consultants based in Brooklyn.  I found myself comparing the two lists—there were some similarities (including the popsicle trend) as well as some contradictions.  For example, Freeman predicts big things for hot dogs, yet Baum&amp;Whiteman think they’re on the downside.  They both agree that cupcakes have probably peaked, Meatless Mondays have gone mainstream, and ethnic influences are stronger than ever.

Here’s a summary of Baum&amp;Whiteman’s food and dining trends in restaurants and hotels for 2011:

 Artisan ice pops: Popsicles are taking on an upscale, global vibe bursting with exotic flavors.  In New York, La Newyorkina sells flavors like tamarind and passionfruit,  People’s Pops creates treats-on-a-stick like roasted red plum, blackberry-black tea and pear-ginger, and you can find pomegranate-tangerine, Mexican chocolate and orange-mango-ancho at Locopops in Raleigh and surrounding towns. Meatballs. Old Italian is getting new respect . Meatballs are gaining momentum, along with other old-school Italian classics like eggplant parm and lasagna. The Meatball Shop in New York (five kinds, four gravies) has endless lines, and Disney opened a Meatball and Beer Bar (also four kinds). Korean spicing and condiments. Kogi, the LA food truck that launched a thousand wheels, has propelled Korean cuisine into the big time. Bulgogi, bibmibap and kimchee will enter America’s gastronomic lexicon. Publicity around the Momofuko chain will also give Korean a push. Tacos with global and wacky fillings. Look for an outburst of outrageously creative mult-culti tacos, soft and hard, from fast food to haute cuisineries. Grits are the hot new grain .  Expect grits to leap from morning food to an all-purpose starch.  It’s part of another trendlet: down-home southern cooking.  Shrimp and grits could be the dish of the year.  Grits are also gaining popularity because of its gluten-free status.  Look for more gluten-replacing starches like grits, quinoa and chickpeas on menus. New-fangled sandwiches. Last year it was gussied up hot dogs and gourmet hamburgers, next year it’ll be sandwiches over the moon but they’ll be called something else.  There are Mexican cemitas , Vietnamese banh mi , baos (traditionally yeasty steamed buns with savory fillings that are now being formed as fluffy flatbreads to wrap around banh mi -like ingredients, tartines, and regional American sandwiches.  To me, it seems Banh mi (pronounced“bun me”) will be the sandwich that really breaks through. This Vietnamese street food that unites the flavors of France and Vietnam has sparked the site BattleoftheBanhmi.com that allows visitors to search for and nominate their favorite banh mi shops by states, and includes recipes so you can make your own at home. 

 Photo:  Banh mi by Flickr user Ric_W 

 Convenience store cuisine. Drug stores and convenience stores are ramping up their food departments with newly conceived fresh“grab-and-go”departments. Popup restaurants. The recession created lots of empty restaurants and lots of chefs with no kitchens.  Now we have popup restaurants (like food trucks) with no location at all.  Impromptu  food places are popping up and customers are finding them via Twitter and word of mouth. Many popups are now treated in the media alongside major restaurant openings. Food trucks 2.0. Expect to see more food truck“rodeos”where a dozen or more vendors turn an empty field or parking lot into a food fair on wheels. Look for more restaurant operators and big-name chefs to supplement their businesses by chasing after customers with their own trucks. Snacks and multiple snacks replacing meals . Breakfast all the time. More restaurants and chains are entering the breakfast biz, and soft slow-cooked eggs are appearing all over upscale restaurant menus.  They’re comforting, turning fancy dishes into homey offerings—runny eggs on pasta, pizza, braised meats and grits. Going collaborative. Group couponing and location-based restaurant promotions—Groupon, Village Vines, Open Table. A couple of nutrition trends: “Free-from”foods, especially gluten-free items on restaurant menus, and“gross is good.”Baum&amp;Whiteman say the recession has everyone so stressed that they’re finding refuge in the massive“calorie bombs”that are showing up on menus. 

 Buzz-worthy foods and ingredients: 
 

 Coconut water, awash in a mythology of good health Bourbon, for people who actually like booze Cucumbers, lavender and  hibiscus, especially in cocktails Burrata cheese Umami along with stealth use of miso Sangria with new twists Peppadew Macarons, not macaroons Whoopee pie Fregola, a pasta from Sardinia Designer donuts imitating froufrou cupcakes Pesto variations Greek yogurt, even larger 

Photo:  Kiwi Cucumber Cocktail, Flickr user Zespri Kiwifruit 
 
 Tweet This Post 
 
Tagged as: 2011 restaurant trends , dining trends , food trends , food trends 2011 
 
 { 10 trackbacks } 
 TWEETS THAT MENTION PREDICTING 2011 FOOD AND DINING TRENDS | NUTRITION UNPLUGGED -- TOPSY.COM 10.30.10 at 9:46 am BY: TWEETS THAT MENTION PREDICTING 2011 FOOD AND DINING TRENDS | NUTRITION UNPLUGGED -- TOPSY.COM | COOKINGPLANET 10.30.10 at 11:26 am HEALTH, NUTRITION AND MEDICAL CARE INFORMATION - PREDICTING 2011 FOOD AND DINING TRENDS | NUTRITION UNPLUGGED 10.31.10 at 7:46 pm TOP TEN PROJECTED RESTAURANT TRENDS FOR 2011 | NUTRITION UNPLUGGED 12.01.10 at 3:13 pm FOOD TRENDS FOR 2011 | SANTA ROSA&amp;AMP;WINE COUNTRY DINING AND RESTAURANTS 01.04.11 at 2:01 pm CULINARY TRENDS FOR 2011&amp;LAQUO;MELISSA KAY ALLEN 01.14.11 at 1:31 pm 2011 FOOD TRENDS TO LOOK OUT FOR IN SACRAMENTO! | SACFOODIES 01.19.11 at 12:21 pm MELANI ROLLWAGE – TREND&amp;AMP;STRATEGY&amp;RAQUO;2011 FOOD PREDICTIONS 01.24.11 at 4:11 pm DISCOMFORT FOOD | NHữNG VấN đề MớI TRONG CôNG NGHệ THựC PHẩM 02.21.11 at 9:56 am DISCOMFORT FOOD(THựC PHẩM MớI, Lạ )- NHóM9-ĐHTP3 | NHữNG VấN đề MớI TRONG CôNG NGHệ THựC PHẩM 03.15.11 at 9:56 pm 
 { 6 comments…read them below or add one } 
 1 JIM MATORIN 11.02.10 at 6:05 am 
Good stuff. What about a Philly Taco? http://n.pr/cjRDX3 Sounds real healthy!
 2 ADRIENNE 11.03.10 at 9:19 am 
This post makes me excited for 2011 (particularly for the new-fangled sandwiches…)!

I’m representing Eating Healthy NYC, and we’re looking for food bloggers to join our online community to help educate our fans about nutrition. We’d love for you to visit our page (facebook.com/eatinghealthynyc) and either join a conversation about healthy eating, or just encourage our fans to check out your blog.

Stay healthy =)
 3 RIC 11.05.10 at 6:50 pm 
I definitely agree with you about banh mi being the sandwich that really breaks through. It’s certainly become one of my favorite sandwiches. And I’m glad you like my photo of our homemade banh mi…it tasted even better than it looks. 
 4 FITANDGO 07.11.11 at 6:06 am 
Food is about always reinventing to satisfy the pallet to excite customers and restaurant goers.
 5 LIANNE 09.04.11 at 5:17 pm 
Awesome. People are really into tasty yet nutritious foods, yes? Best of both worlds. 
 6 BOILX 03.29.12 at 1:48 pm 
Very yummy information, I look foward to any future updates to this blog.
 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name * 

 E-mail * 

 Website 

 

 You can use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 * 
 
 
Welcome to Nutrition Unplugged
 Thoughts, opinions, musings and discussion about nutrition, food trends, diet myths, new products and fad-free healthy eating. 
About Janet Helm
 I’m a writer, registered dietitian and mom of twins. My passion is translating nutrition science into intelligible words – and healthy food choices. I want to help people make sense of nutrition news. I don’t think it needs to be complicated or confusing. l believe food should be enjoyed, not feared. And I think taste and health can happily co-exist. 
Connect With Me
 
 
 
Food&amp;Nutrition News

 360 Eats All We Can Eat–Washington Post Alltop Food News Alltop Nutrition News Corby’s Fresh Feeds–The Atlantic Diner’s Journal–New York Times Fast Food News Food Media–Chow Food Section–New York Times Huffington Post Food Morning News Beat NPR’s Kitchen WIndow Obama Foodorama Progressive Grocer Topix Food Wire Well–New York Times 
 
Food Blogs I Like

 101 Cookbooks Alice Q. Foodie Amateur Gourmet Anthony Bourdain Arugula Files Chez Pim Chocolate and Zucchini Chow Coconut and Lime Cookbook Chronicles Cookie + Kate Cooking With Amy Cookthink Cookus Interruptus Culinate Curious Cook Daily Blender David Lebovitz Delicious Days Dinner with Julie Dorie Greenspan Eat Me Daily eGullet Epicurious Food Blogga Food Gawker Food52 Gastronomy Gluten-Free Girl Good Bite Happyolks Hedonia Herbivoracious Homesick Texan Hungry Mouse Joy the Baker Kalyn’s Kitchen Kitchenist Kitchn La Tartine Gourmande Leite’s Culinaria Mark Bittman Matt Bites Michael Ruhlman My Gourmet Connection My New Roots Naturally Ella One Tribe Gourmet Orangette Pen and Fork Pioneer Woman Cooks Sassy Radish Serious Eats Shutterbean Simply Recipes Skinny Gourmet Slashfood Smitten Kitchen Snails View Spoon Fork Bacon Sprouted Kitchen Steamy Kitchen Sweet Beet Tastespotting Tasty Kitchen Three Many Cooks Vanilla Garlic Wednesday Chef When Harry Met Salad White On Rice Couple Words to Eat By 
 
Global Food Blogs

 A Life (Time) of Cooking–India A Wee Bit of Cooking–UK Abstract Gourmet–Australia Anissa Helou–Lebanese At My Table–Australia Cafe Fernando–Turkey Cafe Liz–Tel Aviv Chocolate and Zucchini Chubby Hubby–Singapore Food and Thoughts–Denmark Food Blog–Lebanese From Argentina With Love Istanbul Eats Limes and Lycopene–Australia Milk and Cookies—U.K. Mouneh: Exploring the Lebanese Pantry My Culinary Journey Through Lebanon Nami Nami–Estonia Nifty Noshing–UK Nordljus–UK Nourish Me–Australia Passionate Cook–UK Phoenician Gourmet–Lebanese Rambling Spoon–Asia Rosewater&amp;Orange Blossoms–Lebanese ShowShanti–China Taste of Beirut–Lebanese Walima–Arabic 
 
Nutrition Links

 A Weight Lifted Academy of Nutrition and Dietetics–Eat Right Balanced Health and Nutrition Carrots&apos;n Cake Cheryl Forberg Consumer Reports Health David Grotto&apos;s Nutrition Housecall Diary of a Dieting Dietitian Diet Blog Diet Detective Diet Dish Dieting Dietitian Dietitian Mom Dish on Dieting Eating Well Anywhere Edible Nutrition eNourishment Expect the Best Pregnancy Feed Between the Lines Food Insight Food Think Foodtrainers Fooducate Healthy Eats Junkfood Science Kath Eats Real Food Little Stomaks Lynn Grieger Meal Makeover Moms’Kitchen Mostly Eating MyPyramid Nutrient Rich Foods Coalition Nutrition Blog Network Nutrition Data Nutrition Diva Nutrition for Slackers Nutrition Info 411 Nutrition To Kitchen Nutrition Viewpoint RDs Weigh In Real Mom Nutrition Robin Plotkin Scoop on Nutrition USA Today–Blog Squad WebMD–Healthy Eating&amp;Diet What I’m Eating Now (and What’s Eating Me) World’s Healthiest Foods Zied Guide 
 
Other Blogs I Read

 Apartment Therapy Boing Boing Daily Beast Food Jobs Huffington Post Impulsive Buy Ladies Who Launch Not Martha Things I Bought That I Love Twitip 
 
Resources - Blogging, Food Writing

 Blogging Without a Blog Chris Brogan Copyblogger Digging Into WordPress Don Fry Food Blog Alliance Food Blog Forum Food Blog S&apos;cool Food Bloggers Unite! Google Webmaster Central How To Make My Blog Problogger Seth Godin Will Write For Food Wordpress 
 
Restaurant Sites

 Chicago Menu Pages Chicago Reader’s Food Chain Chowhound Daily Eats Diner’s Journal–New York Times Eater Grub Street In Praise of Sardines LTH Forum Luxeat Open Table Restaurant Girl Savory New York Tasting Table 
 
Tools To Analyze Recipes and Foods

 CalorieLab Nutrition Data 
 
Tracking What You Eat and Drink

 MyPyramid Tracker Nutrition Data–My Tracking 
 
Trends

 Bite of the Best Center for Culinary Development Food Channel Sparkblog by The Hartman Group Supermarket Guru The Nibble 
 
Ways You Can Check Out Diet Fads and Frauds

 Better Business Bureau Consumer Lab Diet Scam National Council Against Health Fraud Quack Watch Skeptoid Snopes
	</body>
</document>
