<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004117" url="http://community.sephora.com/t5/Makeup/Money-saving-tips-for-makeup-skincare-and-hair-products/qaq-p/174579" time="2012-07-12-20:21" support="3" score="0.001986143927724627" bingtitle="Money saving tips for makeup, skincare, ... - BEAUTY TALK" webtitle="Money saving tips for makeup, skincare, ... - BEAUTY TALK">
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>... blotting sheets, the next time you’re at a fast-food restaurant get a small stack to carry in your purse. Napkins ... Combine 1 cup coarse sea salt with 1/2 cup baby oil ...</description>
	<body>
		beauty advice home : BEAUTY TALK : Makeup... : Makeup : Q&amp;A; : Money saving tips for mak… 
 
 Makeup 
 Go To 
 BEAUTY TALK Welcome / Getting Started Ask The Experts Ask The Experts Ask The Experts Lips Lips Lips Q&amp;A; Eye Makeup Eyes Q&amp;A; Face Makeup Face Q&amp;A; Nails Nails Q&amp;A; Makeup Makeup Makeup Combo / Normal Skin Combo / Normal Combo / Normal Skin Oily Skin Oily Oily Skin Dry Skin Dry Q&amp;A; Natural&amp;Organic Natural&amp;Organic Q&amp;A; Acne Acne Q&amp;A; Antiaging Antiaging Q&amp;A; Other Skin Concerns All Other Concerns Q&amp;A; Skincare Stories Skincare Stories Q&amp;A; Fragrance Fragrance Fragrance Hair Hair Hair Bright Ideas Sephora Asks BeautyTalk Feedback Products Beauty Insider Stores&amp;Services Sephora.com The Lounge Off-Topic Hauls Beauty Confessions The Swatch Board BeautyTalk Support BeautyTalk Support BT Support Customer Support Customer Support Customer Support 
 Question Options 
 Subscribe to RSS Feed Mark Question as New Mark Question as Read Bookmark Subscribe Email to a Friend Printer Friendly Page Report Inappropriate Content 
 readyfreddie IT GIRL (17) 
Money saving tips for makeup, skincare, and hair products
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
I&apos;ve gotten used to just splurging on whatever makeup, skincare, and hair products I want/need but I&apos;m going back to college this fall and won&apos;t be able to afford to do that anymore. Anyone got any awesome money saving ideas for makeup or skincare or hair stuff?
 Answer on 06-30-2011 02:13 (476 Views) ( 4 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 Accepted Solution tiffanybt BEAUTY ADVISOR (1208) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
Hi readyfreddie. Here are some of my favorite tips for SAVING on makeup, skincare and haircare products:

 

1. If it&apos;s not on sale wait until it is! Check out our SALE section which has amazing and affordable deals.

 

2. See if the product you want to purchase has a luxury or jumbo size so you get more product at a cheaper price. If you put the word &quot;luxury&quot; in our search field it will pull up all the luxury sizes we carry. Check it out here: LUXURY 

 

 3. Search for value and combination sets that will complete your look so you get more for your money and an AWESOME deal. 

 

 4. Last, but definitely not least shop through your old products and see what new looks you could come up with. 

 

 I hope this helps and GOOD LUCK in all your endeavors!
 
 Comments (0) Permalink on 06-30-2011 06:13 (205 Views) ( 2 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 Other Answers: 7 Sorted by: Most Kudos 
 Least Kudos Newest First 
 corrin99 BEAUTY GURU (567) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
 I would recommend buying Revlon Colorstay foundation, it&apos;s really good and about $12. Tresemme and Dove are good for shampoo, if you&apos;re in love with a special shampoo short hair only needs about a nickle size amount of shampoo and same with conditioner. I love Aveda and buy the economic size of camomile it&apos;s a liter for $30, it lasts forever. Instead of expensive primer chafing gel works great, it&apos;s said to be so similar to Smashbox primer. Pick a budget for the month and pick a few things you can&apos;t live without, $25 for splurge items a month seems to fit most budgets and you can save up for things for a month or 2 if you must, it depends how tight your budget will be. I can&apos;t live without Clinique Dramatically Different Gel and Smashbox eyeshadow in shell. I also really like Clinique exfoliating scrub. I use Purpose cleanser, it&apos;s gentle and takes makeup off well, and it&apos;s $5 at target. For treating dry patches or broken skin I use vitamin e oil. Revlon also makes good liquid eyeliner.  Drugstore brands of eyeshadows are pretty ok, Loreal is my favorite. Covergirl professional mascara is good and $4, but it doesn&apos;t last more than 8 weeks.   
 Comments (0) Permalink on 06-30-2011 02:57 (200 Views) ( 1 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 thecaramelapple BEAUTY BOSS (387) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
Hey hun,

 

        I&apos;m in college too, so I know it&apos;s a pain when over the summer your working and can spend frivolously and then go back to school and have to buy books, food, etc. it all adds up. One thing I do to save on hair products is I switch to Biotera..I usually use the big liters of Biolage, but its so expensive. Biotera is the generic version of Biolage and it can be found at Sally&apos;s. They are usually on sale, 2 big liters for 14 dollars, and let me tell you they are like the exact same thing. Fantastic! I also get the One and Only brand of Argan Oil available there, the consistency isn&apos;t as nice a Moroccan Oil, but its way cheaper has the same smell, and leaves my hair just as soft. As for leave in conditioner, I use Soma, which is a high end brand and costs around 16 dollars, but it&apos;s the only hair product I use besides the oil and I figure its way cheaper than hoarding drugstore serums and creams like I used to. As for makeup products, I don&apos;t need any but during the year I still get the itch to buy them, so I just switch what I buy. I go to CVS a lot to buy Revlon because I have a major thing for Revlon. If it was a high end brand Id still buy them. I just like to check out what new products they have and things like that. I don&apos;t go into Sephora as often because I always spend a crazy amount of money.but if I do I definitely focus on the Sephora brand because the quality of the makeup is just as good if not beter than the other brands such as Makeup Forever, Too Faced, Kat Von D, etc. The quality really is superior, which is rare for store brands. Have you tried the Sephora Mono Blushes? Amazing. They are half the price of some of the other blushes such as Nars and Illamasqua. Also, the new foundation they just came out with is great too. The Body Shop has a great makeup line for a lower price point as well. Clinique usually has a lower price point. I usually visit the MAC counter during school to get a lipstick here, an eyeshadow there...they are generally 14.50 each, so if you buy a couple products you arent totally overdoing it. Sallys Beauty Supply has makeup lines such as Femme Couture and Palladio who makes a great eyeshadow primer. Check out the Cosmetics Company Outlet store too, high end makeup for way cheaper, I got a MAC blush for 13 dollars, and a Bobbi Brown lipstick for 14. Good luck hun!
 Comments (0) Permalink on 07-01-2011 05:36 (200 Views) ( 1 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 kimmi1115 HALL OF FAMER (3008) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
Sally&apos;s has the Generic Brand for many high end hair brands. I use the Generic Anti Snap which is based on Redkin&apos;s Anti Snap for my curly hair. It works exactly like Redkin does, but a LOT cheaper. Sally&apos;s Beauty discount card is one of my new friends lol. It&apos;s 5 bucks a year, but as soon as you buy it, it pays for itself because you&apos;ll get a 5 dollar off coupon to use on a purchase of 5 dollars or more. With the card, you get a slightly cheaper price on everything in the store, and the register will print you a 15% of coupon of 20 or 25 dollars or more on a purchase. The card quickly pays for itself.
 Comments (0) Permalink on 07-01-2011 05:22 (200 Views) ( 1 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 brookie673 BEAUTY GURU (404) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
1. Wait for a big sale and stock up on faves. 
2. Ask for gift cards to whatever (Sephora, MAC, etc.) as a gift. 

3. Go to retailmenot (dot) com often and look for coupon codes for whatever you need, or for the stores that sell it. They usually have atleast one or two good coupons that work when you check.

 4. As far as makeup goes, definitely take a look at ELF, or Eyes Lips Face (eyeslipsface dot com). Most products are between one and five dollars, and I think they&apos;re pretty high quality. Their products are featured often in style magazines and even compared to Stila, MAC, Sephora, etc. This is my best recommendation- they&apos;re not that well known, but I love them a ton. Go take a look at their website, maybe try some products. I&apos;d recommend the $3 brushes in the Studio Line, the $1 Brightening Eye Color Quads, the cream eyeliner, and the Studio Line eyeshadows. 

 

Good luck!!!
 Comments (2) Permalink on 06-30-2011 09:36 (210 Views) ( 1 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 View More Comments 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 tenngal HALL OF FAMER (3663) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
Hi, readyfreddie. Here’s a few suggestions on how to save on your beauty products that I hope will help:

- Check Sephora’s website “Sale” section for great deals.

- Post-holiday and seasonal shopping can be a huge, less expensive way to build your makeup collection. Gift sets (which are discounted deeply at the end of the season) don&apos;t just have to be just for gifts! Check out Sephora’s “Gift” section on their website for excellent deals.


- Combine to save: If you&apos;re like me, you have several bottles of half-full conditioner in your shower. There&apos;s nothing wrong with these formulas per se, but none of them qualify for the &apos;good to the last drop&apos; category. Instead of tossing them in the garbage, squeeze all of the conditioners into one big bottle to create a “super-conditioner” or save to use as a “shaving cream” for your legs.

- Conserve your product: If you use a sponge when applying foundation, wet your makeup sponge slightly before you dip it into your foundation or before you dab to do touchups. The dampness will cause the sponge to absorb less product, thus leaving more in the bottle or on your face.

- If you use cotton rounds to apply your toner and take off nail polish, since they provide more surface area than you usually need, try cutting them in half to save product and money.

- At-Home Hair Treatment: Instead of purchasing expensive hair treatments, try an at-home avocado mask. All you&apos;ll need is a fully ripened avocado mixed in with one egg yolk and a teaspoon of olive oil. After stirring well, apply the mixture to your hair in sections and leave on for 30 minutes or so. Afterward, your hair will feel soft and healthy.

- Run damage control on your blemishes before they get out of hand. If you feel a big blemish coming on, take an aspirin and make a paste of it with water. Apply it to the pimple before you go to bed and the next day the swelling should be gone.

- Use double-duty products: Invest in some multi-tasking makeup. For instance, the Jillian Dempsey for Avon Professional Multi-Pencil functions as a lipstick, eyeshadow and blush and costs only $8. Not only will you save money, but also space in your makeup bag and you&apos;ll also save time in your routine.

- Vaseline: Vaseline is another mega-multiuse beauty tool. Use it as a lip balm, a lip exfoliator (along with an old toothbrush), to soften heels or as a makeup remover.

- Invest in an all-in-one palette such as the Sephora Collection combination sets that include lipstick, blush, eyeshadow, eyeliner, etc., which come at an affordable price.

- Olive oil is actually an excellent beauty secret that not everyone knows about. It&apos;s great for taking off makeup, calming frizzy hair in the summer and for moisturizing your skin.

- Instead of buying expensive oil-blotting sheets, the next time you’re at a fast-food restaurant get a small stack to carry in your purse. Napkins work very well and the brown napkins like the ones from Starbucks work really well.

- Get a few more uses out of an almost-gone mascara by standing it in a glass of warm water or heating it up with a hair dryer.

- Make your own exfoliating body scrub. Combine 1 cup coarse sea salt with 1/2 cup baby oil. Stir the ingredients together in a bowl and put into a screw-top jar. Leave for 24 hours, then stir the mixture and apply to any areas of the body you wish to smooth out. Massage into the skin for a few minutes, then shower off and pat your skin dry. (Makes multiple applications.)

- If you use an expensive cellulite cream, stop buying it. You can make your own by mixing dry coffee grounds with your body lotion and rubbing into your problem areas. This stimulates circulation, making it easier for trapped fat to surface and be broken down. Plus, the caffeine tightens skin. Leave this coffee-lotion combo on your skin for about 30 minutes, then wash off.

- Inexpensive blemish-fighter: Honey has powerful antioxidant and antibacterial properties, making it perfect for curing dry or acne-prone skin. Make sure you start out with clean skin, then spread some honey on and let it sit for up to 15 minutes. Rinse thoroughly with warm water.

- Instead of spending money on de-puffing eye creams, if you wake up in the morning with under-eye bags, apply two chamomile tea bags, chilled spoons, or cucumber slices to your lids. Expedite the process by sitting up with your head back; this will help drain the fluids around your eyes more quickly.

- You can save money by using any eye shadow as an eyeliner instead of buying a separate eyeliner. Use an eyeliner brush with short, stiff, angled bristles and mist the tip of the brush rather than soaking it. For a smudgy, nighttime look, try applying with a damp Q-tip.
|
- Use a lip brush. Slathering on your lipstick may cause you to over-apply, which you&apos;ll only blot off onto a tissue and waste. Use a lip brush and you&apos;ll save product, plus get a more even, precise color.

- Instead of spending money on a facial, do an at-home facial using bananas and honey. Fruit is the best ingredient for your skin. The vitamins and minerals help clear up blemishes and leave you feeling soft and smooth. Each fruit has its own benefits, but for a quickie do-it-yourself facial, try this recipe: Mash a ripe, medium-sized banana and mix with 2 tablespoons honey. For a thicker consistency, add 2 tablespoons plain yogurt. Apply to your face and neck for 10 to 15 minutes and rinse off.

- Although this last one isn&apos;t entirely beauty-related, it can save you a ton on your laundry bill. Instead of taking your clothes to the dry cleaner, use a hand-held, portable steamer that heats up to at least 212°F, which sanitizes and kills odor-causing bacteria.

Hope this helps and have a great day!
tenngal 

 
 Comments (0) Permalink on 07-01-2011 08:24 (200 Views) ( 1 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 jbyrne BEAUTY BOSS (96) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
Being in college is hard and still wanted to splurge on the nice makeup that you can use when you are making your own money.   I was just in college and finished so, I know how it feels to not be able to spend as much as you usually can.

 

If you have the extra money buy things that can be used as multiples such as the nars multiple, buying it in a color that suits your eyes lips and cheeks, really helps a lot and it also saves a lot of time in the morning when you are rushing off to class.

Buying products that aren&apos;t really necessary to buy in full price such as mascara and nail polish and lip sticks/glosses are all things that you can get at like CVS.  Mascara is my favorite thing to buy from pharmacies because I sometimes agree that the cheaper ones are better anyway and some better brands of mascara are sometimes not even that great. My favorite is Maybelline Colossal cause it has collagen in it and helps to really lengthen your lashes (in non waterproof).   Nail Polishes are fun to get at the pharmacy because you can get so many and still stick within your budget. I have really sensitive skin when it comes to skincare products and need products that aren&apos;t harsh on my skin. The face wash that I use is called Cetaphil, it is very light an non-drying.  It only costs like 10 bucks and the cleanser lasts forever. I also buy the daily moisturizer with spf in it just cause it is always good to get some spf in there ... These can be found at any pharmacy- so again (within your budget and each product lasts for a while so its worth your buck).

In terms of Haircare, I usually just use Pantene Pro-v because it is the most luxurious of all the shampoos, or if I am looking to switch up I usually use Herbal Essences because their conditioners smell really good and they are nice and thick which means then are conditioning close enough to a salon brand.   You can usually get sponges and cotton pads if you use them at the pharmacy for cheap and keep an eye out for specials on things that you use cause that&apos;s the best time to buy especially if you are on a budget 
 Comments (0) Permalink on 07-01-2011 12:03 (143 Views) ( 0 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 puekam IT GIRL (33) 
Answered
 Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
get sample sizes of things before you buy products. also value sets are great!
 Comments (0) Permalink on 06-30-2011 04:42 (208 Views) ( 0 ) Options 
 Mark as New Bookmark Subscribe Subscribe to RSS Feed Print Email to a Friend Report Inappropriate Content 
 
You must be a registered user to add a comment here. If you&apos;ve already registered, please log in. If you haven&apos;t registered yet, please register and log in.

 Post a Comment 
 
Ask a beauty question
 type question or keywords 
 
 view all 
Welcome,
 sign in or register
	</body>
</document>
