<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004195" url="http://www.ksl.com/?nid=960&amp;sid=15712305" time="2012-07-12-20:26" support="1" score="0.0003479752810186152" bingtitle="Police looking for Spice, bath salts make &apos;substantial find&apos; | ksl.com" webtitle="Police looking for Spice, bath salts make &apos;substantial find&apos; | ksl.com">
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="203"/>
	<description>... this year, Gov. Gary Herbert signed a bill ... An employee of a fast-food restaurant next door said he ... on several occasions, but would never leave with any copies. The store ...</description>
	<body>
		Login    Feedback    Contact Us KSL TV       KSL Newsradio       iWitness    » Utah all of KSL Classifieds Local Web Keyword 
 Utah Page Two U.S. World Sports Weather Traffic Biz Entertainment Shows More 
 
 Deals Local Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds 
 
 Local Stories KSL 5 News Investigations Tough Times Survival Bank Staying Safe Statecraft: Government&amp;Politics Sunday Edition 
 About this ad Police looking for Spice, bath salts make &apos;substantial find&apos; By Pat Reavy May 26th, 2011 @ 9:59pm 

To view this video, you need to download the latest version of Adobe Flash Player . 19 Comments Post or read comments Related Stories 
 
 South Salt Lake Police raid smoke shops for Spice, Ivory Wave 
 

 
 Bath salt creates a high when snorted, and it&apos;s legal 
 
 Photo Gallery» 9 pics » 
MILLCREEK—An undercover police investigation into a local tobacco shop suspected of selling illegal Spice and bath salts resulted in more than detectives were expecting this week.


&quot;We knew he was selling it. We had no idea he was such a prolific seller,&quot; said Unified Police Sgt. Scott VanWagoner. &quot;It&apos;s a substantial find.&quot;


Members of the Unified police narcotics squad served search warrants at two adjacent businesses owned by the same person on Tuesday, The Tobacco Outlet and Smith&apos;s Copy and Print shop, both on the corner of 900 East and 4500 South.
 We have intelligence on other shops. We know who you are and we know what you&apos;re doing. We&apos;re not asking, we&apos;re telling: &apos;Stop selling this stuff.&apos; –Sgt. Scott VanWagoner 

Earlier this year, Gov. Gary Herbert signed a bill
	</body>
</document>
