<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004429" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/291168-low-calorie-fast-food/" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="2" score="0.0013018034173050016" bingtitle="Low Calorie Fast Food | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Low Calorie Fast Food | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="180"/>
	<description>Watching your calorie intake while eating at a fast-food restaurant ... easiest ways to limit your portion size is to order ... the meal with a small green salad or cup of broth ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Calories in Food Brands Calories in Fast Food Low Calorie Fast Food 
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food 
 Jun 14, 2011 | By Katie Leigh Photo Credit James And James/Brand X Pictures/Getty Images 
Watching your calorie intake while eating at a fast-food restaurant can be tricky. Though fast food is often quick and relatively inexpensive, the American Heart Association says that it is best reserved for an occasional meal. However, if you must dine out at a fast-food establishment, there are some common menu options that you can generally select safely.
 
Benefits

Many options at fast-food restaurants, such as deep-fried french fries and chicken nuggets, contain quite a bit of artery-clogging fat and are high in calories. However, knowing the low-calorie options at fast-food restaurants can help you keep your calorie intake in check, even on the go. If you eat fast food often, choosing low-calorie items can also help you maintain your weight and overall health, particularly when these foods are paired with frequent exercise and a generally heart-healthy diet.
 
Lean Choices

Look for lean choices on the fast-food restaurant&apos;s menu. Grilled chicken breast sandwiches, entree salads and deli sandwiches on whole-grain bread can all be low-calorie items. If needed, adjust the toppings and ingredients in the dishes to reduce the calories. For example, if you order a grilled chicken sandwich, get it without mayonnaise or cheese and discard half of the bun. Ask for no cheese on your entree salad, and opt for a low-calorie dressing. Leave the cheese and bacon off of deli sandwiches in favor of piled-up veggies.
 
Sides

Susan McQuillan, author of &quot;Low-Calorie Dieting for Dummies,&quot; says that if you&apos;re looking for low-calorie foods at fast-food joints, check out the sides menu. Small green salads, plain baked potatoes and broth-based soups are often listed there. These side items tend to contain few calories, are packed with vitamins and nutrients, and can be a filling way to round out your meal.
 
Portion Size

Portion size is a big reason that so many fast-food meals are high in calories. McQuillan suggests that you adjust your expectations in this area. For example, if you want a hamburger, get the thin, single-patty version with no cheese or creamy sauces. Stick to a small order of french fries or chicken nuggets, as opposed to the huge servings that are included in most value meals. One of the easiest ways to limit your portion size is to order a meal from the children&apos;s menu. If it isn&apos;t enough food, supplement the meal with a small green salad or cup of broth-based soup.
 
Considerations

Keep in mind that not all fast-food restaurants are alike. For example, while one chain&apos;s plain hamburger may have only 150 calories, another&apos;s might contain 300 calories or more. The best way to make sure your fast-food dining choices fit neatly into your diet is to request a nutritional information booklet at the counter or look up the calorie amounts in specific items on the restaurant&apos;s website.
 
References

 &quot;American Heart Association Low-Calorie Cookbook&quot;; American Heart Association; 2004 &quot;Low-Calorie Dieting for Dummies&quot;; Susan McQuillan; 2005 
 
Article reviewed by Eric Lochridge Last updated on: Jun 14, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Low Fat Fast Food Lunch Options 
 
 Nutrition Facts for Wendy&apos;s Fast Food 
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Fast Food Menu for Diabetics 
 
 Low-Calorie Meals at Restaurants 
 
 Low Carb Fast Food Choices 
 
 Information on McDonalds Food 
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food Options 
 
 4 Ways to Eat Fast Food on a Diet 
 
 Low-Calorie Quick Meals 
 
 Duchess Restaurant Nutrition Information 
 
 Nutrition Data on Fast Food 
 
 What are the Lowest Calorie Fast Food Items? 
 
 Information on Fast Food Nutrition 
 
 Low Calorie Meals&amp;Snacks 
 
 Healthy Fast-Food Nutrition 
 
 Fast Food Nutrition for Children 
 
 Fast Food Restaurant Nutrition 
 
 Healthy Fast Food Solutions 
 
 Healthy Meals at Fast Food Restaurants 
 more Calories In Fast Food advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 Low Fat&amp;Low Sodium Meals 
 
 Low-Calorie Diet Menu Plans 
 
 Lowest Calorie Fast Foods 
 
 Restaurant Pasta Meals With the Lowest Calories 
 
 Simple Low-Fat&amp;Low-Calorie Crockpot Meals 
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Restaurants 
 
 Low-Fat&amp;Low-Calorie Diet Menu 
 
 Lowest Calorie Foods List 
 
 What Are Some Low-Fat, Low-Cholesterol Meals? 
 
 Low-Calorie Restaurant Guide 
 
 1,200 Calorie Low Carb Diet Menu Tips 
 
 A Low Calorie Fast Food List 
 
 300 Calorie Fast Food Meals 
 
 Fast Food Choices for Low Sodium Diets 
 
 Subway Menu With Calories 
 
 Meal Plans for Low Fat&amp;Low Cholesterol 
 
 Low-Calorie Menu Options at Your Corner Bakery 
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food Ideas 
 
 Lowest Calorie Snack Foods 
 
 Beer With the Lowest Calories 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
