<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004698" url="http://www.cashregisterdepot.com/showaccess.asp?pid=4" time="2012-07-12-21:12" support="1" score="0.0010862053246452996" bingtitle="Cash Register Depot - [Accessories Listing]" webtitle="Cash Register Depot - [Accessories Listing]">
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>Free Shipping On All Orders Over $300 (Continental U.S. Only) ... Credit Card Equip: Copyright © 2002,2003 Information Systems Services, LLC.</description>
	<body>
		Free Shipping On All Orders Over $300 (Continental U.S. Only) 

 
   Welcome Guest User ( Login/Create Account ) 
 
 Home FAQ/Support Register Wizard Cash Registers Samsung TEC Casio Sharp DataSym Refurbished Cash Drawers Touchscreen Printers Scanners Scales Package Deals Camera Systems Software Pole Displays Paper/Ribbons Credit Card Equip Copyright©2002,2003 Information Systems Services, LLC. All Rights Reserved 
 
 Samsung ER-650 Accessory List To save the brochures to your computer, Right Click on the &apos;Download/View 
 Brochure&apos; link and choose &apos;Save Target As..&apos; Otherwise you may view the 
 brochures online. 

 VIDEO SYSTEMS Text Inserter Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $799.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $599.00 
    View Details 
 
  Sure looks like they scanned that item.

 Features 
 View items as they are scanned Select Color Of Specific Items Position Text on Screen to Fit Specific Needs 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure 


 ACCESSORIES Cable 50 Ft. Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $45.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $20.00 

   


 Memory Expansion Module, 4MB Suggested 
 Retail: 
 N/A Our 
 Price: 
 $40.00 

   


 Samsung Second Cash Drawer Kit Suggested 
 Retail: 
 N/A Our 
 Price: 
 $135.00 
    View Details 
    Model 53 Drawer w/Cable. Adds second cash drawer to most Samsung model cash registers. 
 
   


 Datacap LT Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $600.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $495.00 
    View Details 
 
  Datacap Credit Card Authorization System

 Features 
 Integrate Credit Card Authorization Automatic Close Batch Eliminates The Need For Additional Credit Card Hardware Uses Printer in Cash Register for Credit Card Slips (Wireless Option Available) 
 
 
   


 Coin Dispenser Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $1,475.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $1,100.00 
    View Details 
 
  Automatic Coin Dispenser

 Features 
 Sleek Design and Small Footprint Removable coin canister has substantial capacity. RS 232 Interface Built to withstand the punishment of continuous high volume operations. 
 
 
   


 SCANNERS Metrologic MS9540 Voyager Scanner Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $399.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $200.00 
    View Details 
 
 VoyagerCG is an advanced auto-trigger, single line laser bar code scanner that is equally effective hand held or in the stand for presentation scanning.

 Features 
 Automatic trigger PowerLink, user-replaceable cables Adjustable stand Firmware updates via Flash ROM Custom edit the bar code data Short-range and long-range activation RSS-14 decoding capability Features CodeGate Technology 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure White Keyboard Wedge White Serial White USB Black Keyboard Wedge Black Serial Black USB 


 Symbol LS 2208 Barcode Scanner Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $475.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $220.00 
    View Details 
 
 Investment Protection and Maximum Productivity at an Affordable Price

 Features 
 Durable Scan Element Design Working Range is Contact to 17&quot; Multiple Interfaces On-Board Aggressive on Poorly Printed or Long Barcodes Hands Free Stand Ergonomic Design Easy programming using the 123Scan Setup Utility 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure White Keyboard Wedge White Serial Black Keyboard Wedge Black Serial 


 Symbol LS 9208 Omnidirectional Projection Scanner Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $740.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $395.00 
    View Details 
 
 Speed and Versatility Combine for Increased Productivity at Checkout

 Features 
 Small Footprint Built-In Shock Absorption Innovative 100-Line Rastering Omnidirectional Scan Pattern or Single Line Mode Supports 123Scan for Easy Programming Multiple Onboard Interfaces Universal Cables Reduce Inventory Requirements Available in White or Black 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure White Keyboard Wedge White Serial Black Keyboard Wedge Black Serial 


 Metrologic MS7620 Horizon Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $1,130.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $475.00 
    View Details 
 
 Horizon is an in-counter laser bar code scanner. This compact, hands-free scanner is designed with a dense 20-line omnidirectional scan pattern that helps provide fast, efficient throughput with a high first-pass read rate.

 Features 
 Automatic Scanning Operation Decodes All Standard 1D, RSS-14, RSS Limited, and RSS Expanded Bar Codes Durable Die-Cast Construction Firmware Updates via Flash ROM EAS Deactivation Antenna is Standard Custom Edit Barcode Data User-Replaceable, Single Cable Interface to Host RS232 Auxiliary Port for Adding Peripherals Field Replaceable Window 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure 


 Metrologic MS9535 Voyager Wireless Scanner Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $895.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $495.00 
    View Details 
 
  Wireless Scanning up to 33 Feet Away

 Features 
 Cable Free Scanning Using BlueTooth Wireless Standard CodeGate Data Transmission Technology Firmware Updates Via Flash Rom Shipping as Kit; Power Supply,Cable,Manuals and Stand Included 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure Keyboard Wedge Serial 


 PRINTERS Samsung SRP-275A Receipt Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $295.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $215.00 
    View Details 
 
 The SRP-275A series two-color dot-matrix printer combines high reliability with a low cost of ownership.

 Features 
 Very fast dot-matrix printing speed of 4.6 lines per second High quality easy to read print High reliability at 18,000,000 lines MCBF Compatible with competitors emulations including Epson, Star, Citizen Compact design Easy to use 
 Plug&amp;play Auto paper loading for paper replacement 
 Near-end sensor and paper-end sensor 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure Ivory-Serial Ivory-Parallel Gray-Serial Grey Parallel 


 Citizen iDP-3551 Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $400.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $245.00 
    View Details 
 
 High-speed printers for bankcard, POS, fast food, restaurant and convenience store use.

 Features 
 9 Pin Dot Matrix Printing High Speed Print (Bi-Directional) 2-Color Printing (Black&amp;Red) 3 Emulations in 1 Paper Auto Load and Paper Auto Cutter Built-In Power Supply 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure White-Serial White-Parallel Black-Serial Black-Parallel 


 Samsung SRP-275C Receipt Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $350.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $265.00 
    View Details 
 
 The SRP-275C series two-color dot-matrix printer combines high reliability with a low cost of ownership.

 Features 
 Auto Paper Cutter Very fast dot-matrix printing speed of 4.6 lines per second High quality easy to read print High reliability at 18,000,000 lines MCBF Compatible with competitors emulations including Epson, Star, Citizen Compact design Easy to use 
 Plug&amp;play Auto paper loading for paper replacement 
 Near-end sensor and paper-end sensor 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure Ivory-Serial Ivory-Parallel Gray-Serial Grey Parallel 


 CBM-1000II Thermal Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $600.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $300.00 
    View Details 
 
 Two-Color, High Speed Thermal POS Printer. Includes barcode printing and flash memory for storing logos.

 Features 
 Two-Color and Monochrome Thermal Printing High Speed Printing (150mm/sec) Multiple interface options: Serial/Parallel/USB/Ethernet Interface Boards Drop-In Paper Loading Barcode Printing Internal/External Power Supply Configuration Spill Resistant Top 2 Drawer Kick-Out Auto-Cutter and Tear Bar Paper Low/Paper Out Sensors ESC/POS Emulation, OPOS, and Windows Drivers 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure WHite-Serial White-Parallel White-USB Black-Serial White-Parallel White-USB 


 Epson TM-U200B Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $368.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $325.00 
    View Details 
 
 The TM-U200B printer is in wide use as the POS standard printer for the general retail, restaurant kitchen and hospitality markets.

 Features 
 9 Pin Dot Matrix Printing 2-Color Printing (Black&amp;Red) Flexible, and With a Multitude of Applications Easy Paper Loading with Tear-Bar and Autocutter Ease-of-use features including Auto Status Back (ASB) messages 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure Ivory-Serial Ivory-Parallel Gray-Serial Gray-Parallel 


 Samsung SRP-370 Receipt Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $450.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $345.00 
    View Details 
 
 With speed, quality and value, the Samsung SRP-370 thermal receipt printer is clearly first in it?s class.

 Features 
 Fast 150mm/second (47.2 lps) print speed Multiple interface (standard RS-232C/IEEE-1284, option RS-485/USB) Compatible with competitors emulations including Epson, Star, Citizen Saves installation space (compact size, wall mount option) Easy to use 
 Drop and print paper supply Simple to eliminate paper jam Compact design 
 Auto cutter Near-end sensor and paper-end sensor 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure Ivory-Serial Ivory-Parallel Gray-Serial Grey Parallel 


 Epson TM-T88III Receipt Printer Suggested 
 Retail: 
 $457.00 Our 
 Price: 
 $425.00 
    View Details 
 
 Epsons TM-T88III thermal printer has all the benefits of the best-selling TM-T88II with faster printing.

 Features 
 Thermal Printing Technology Fast print speed, up to 5.9/sec. 25% faster than the TM-T88II Easy Drop-In Paper Loading with Tear-Bar and Autocutter Ease-of-use features including Auto Status Back (ASB) messages 
 
 
 Download/View Brochure Ivory-Serial Ivory-Parellel Gray-Serial Gray-Parallel 

 
 Samsung Cash Registers Casio Cash Registers Sharp Cash Registers Printers Cash Drawers
	</body>
</document>
