<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004599" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/15250536088/rdg-bar-annie-houston" time="2012-07-12-21:05" support="2" score="0.002752759197335196" bingtitle="Rdg Bar Annie - Houston - Insider Pages - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="Rdg Bar Annie - Houston">
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>The last thing one would expect would ... he wanted to quickly &quot;turn our table. We felt extremely pressured to order ... This place is not your local fast food restaurant!</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Houston, TX &gt; Food &gt; Restaurants &gt;Rdg Bar Annie 

 

 

 

 
Rdg Bar Annie
 ★★★★☆ 49 Reviews Write a Review 
713-840-1111
 1800 Post Oak Blvd Houston , TX 77056 rdgbarannie.com 

 
 Add Photo Edit Business Claim Business 
 
About Rdg Bar Annie
 Categories 
 Restaurants 
 
Food
 More choices in Houston: 
 Barnaby&apos;s Cafe 
604 Fairview St Houston, TX
 
 Americas 
1800 Post Oak Blvd # 164 Houston, TX
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for Rdg Bar Annie

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★★★★★ Cafe Annie is quiet and romantic atmosphere 
 Ruth G. | Insider Guru
| Rank: 2,036 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 
A place I go for a special occasion. The atmosphere is nice romantic and quiet. The portions are small for the price but the presentation of the food is beautiful.
 October 09, 2009 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 
Latest reviews from Citysearch .
 ★☆☆☆☆ Seriously Overrated - 
by carrieg at Citysearch 1 Rdg Bar Annie 
 May 16, 2009 
We ordered a $120 bottle of wine, the decanter was chipped at the mouth, which isnt something you dont expect when you spend $300+ for a meal. We tried the fried shrimp appetizer which was fried on a skewer then topped on a dry slaw with bits of lobster. I ordered my NY Strip steak medium, it arrived rare. My husbands ribeye was not even an inch thick and very bland. The grits were undercooked and not warm. We tried to salvage the dinner with the warm chocolate cobbler, it tasted like a day old cookie thrown in the microwave. The service was worse than the food we had to ask for the wine list after sitting at the table for 15 minutes. The server would fill 1 glass 3/4 full of wine, and the other 1/4 full. not high end at all! Such a waste of money we literally called Marks on the way home for a reservation the next weekend. HORRIBLE

Cons: service, food


 ★★☆☆☆ where was I 
by frustratedone at Citysearch 2 Rdg Bar Annie 
 January 28, 2009 
We had dinner last week and was so embarrassed by the down home feel of the owners. Let me explain, when someone dines out at Cafe Annie, it is usually to enjoy a quiet dinner with a loved one, a personal celebration, or some other significant occasion. The last thing one would expect would be for the owner to sit down next to you and carry on a LOUD conversation with whomever. How do I know she was the owner? Everyone was calling her Mimi and she was making it a point that everyone knew who she was. I understand that owners&amp;managers need to talk with their guests from time to time, but please don&apos;t sit down on a chair next to someone unless you are invited, one should stand at the table for a brief time. We are here to dine and spend money in your establishment, not to hear how bad sales are or what other companies are having a rough time, or how your family is doing. Let us enjoy our time. Even with this we did manage to enjoy the food. We are eagerly waiting the opening of their new restaurant, it is time for a change for this restaurant.


 ★☆☆☆☆ Had high expectations 
by LilMitty3 at Citysearch 1 Rdg Bar Annie 
 January 13, 2009 
My fiane and I moved to Houston just over a year ago and are avid eaters. We love to get around the city and try out all the restaurants so we were excited to finally try Cafe Annie with a friend of ours. I viewed the menu online before we went and thought it looked great, but soon learned that the descriptions are creative ways to describe just regular, boring food. I was so disappointed by this restaurant. The chicken fried gulf shrimp were just fried shrimp that I could have gotten from a street vendor and the lobster crepe just tasted like eggs. For entrees the tuna was high quality but it was bland and the red fish was boring as well. It says it comes with shrimp and there was no shrimp to be found and the fish itself was dry and fishy tasting. Our friend had the ribeye, which seems safe but after eating part of it, he put down his fork and was finished because the flavor was bad. For dessert we had the berry cobbler which was good but essentially a berry muffin and when we ordered the grilled pound cake it was basically Sara Lee pound cake with some Hershey syrup drizzled over. I will not be going back to Cafe Annie.

Pros: service was decent

Cons: food bad


 ★☆☆☆☆ Great wine list, but that is all. 
by mrnuckles at Citysearch 1 Rdg Bar Annie 
 November 10, 2008 
My wife and I decided to celebrate our birthdays at Cafe Annie this year, after hearing many good things about the establishment. Unfortunately, this will be our last celebration at the establishment.

We made early reservations so that we could get home to tuck in the little one. Our reservations were for 6:30. We were out of the place by 7:45. Our waiter dropped off our cocktails and pressured us for our dinner order at the same time. Before we had even finished our first drink, the appetizers had arrived, as I was still looking through the wine list.

The appetizers were acceptable, but nothing spectacular. I thought the flavor somewhat bland.

Our dinner arrived just as we were finishing the appetizers. Again, the food was acceptable, but nothing spectacular.

The dessert was probably the best part of the meal, aside from the wine. However, bringing the check while we are still eating leaves much to be desired, especially considering the price level.

Bottom line is this place would be an acceptable lunch location if the prices were significantly lower and it was conveniently located near the office. Otherwise I would not go out of my way to go back. If there were a company function there, I would plan on drinking my dinner, but would definitely prefer some of the other upscale locations in Houston (Mark&apos;s, Damien&apos;s, etc.) if I wanted to actually eat.



Pros: Wine list

Cons: Overpriced. Rushed service.


 ★☆☆☆☆ Terrible food and Services 
by jafe11 at Citysearch 1 Rdg Bar Annie 
 November 09, 2008 
The service was timely, however, does not allow guest to relax and take time to enjoy the meal, the waiter seem to be in a hurry to turn the table, for the price you pay, we feel that the service is almost like a fast food place. We did not like the food we ordered. After I came back from the meal, I was having some issues with my stomach. The price of this place is comparable to Mark&apos;s, but compare to the service and the food, I would never go back to Cafe Annie again.


 ★★★★★ Great as always 
by jenny4pres at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 20, 2008 
Me and my husband have been to Cafe Annie for years! I&apos;m glad to hear that the new location will create a larger area for the bar which is more affordable than most people think. I had dinner there the other night and was floored by the great bar service, be sure to make reservations in advance though because it can get quite packed during weekends. The music is getting better than what I remember. The food was great as always, my favorite is the rare tuna salad with roasted beets....delicious. I&apos;ve never noticed what the hostess wear since we are regulars but they seemed lovely to me. Another must try is the Bar&apos;s Annie Burger, the bread is perfection and the fries are wonderful as well. I also noticed that the lunch menu has been updated with new exciting salads and entrees, and the prices are reasonable compared to other places like Tony&apos;s. I only wish though that the people there would dress a little more formal. I understand the complaint about the shorts of the person below but I guess they are trying to be more casual then usual. Either way, great job Cafe Annie.

Pros: Bar Annie is both affordable and chic

Cons: Too casual attire?


 ★★★★★ Impeccable Service 
by lucky720 at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 20, 2008 
What can I say? Hands down one of the best dining experiences I&apos;ve had. I&apos;m not a regular so I wasn&apos;t expecting VIP treatment; however, the waitstaff and owner were very gracious to our party. I came in to celebrate my birthday with a few girlfriends and we were all very impressed with the attentitiveness of the staff. The food was fabulous, if you go for dinner you must try the grilled shrimp with the enchiladas or the filet mignon with grits, to die for!!!! I will definitely be back for more, and I can&apos;t wait for the new location to open...oh and try the valet, the etxra $3 is worth it.

Pros: Service and Cheap Valet

Cons: none!


 ★★☆☆☆ standards 
by msangel at Citysearch 2 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 16, 2008 
double standards abound. When I called I was told that shorts were not approariate but what is the hostess wearing when I arrive? You guessed it, now I understand these were not walking shorts, they were almost what used to be terrmed as short shorts. It seems like Cafe Annie is losing its edge when it comes to first impressions. Went back the next day and there was so much cleveage showing, its a wonder the gentlemen didn&apos;t dine in the bar just to stare. What has happened to the good old days, when genmtlement wore jackets, ladies wore dresses? I know this is Houston and times are changing but when we go out to eat, we want to admire the decor, the food, the atmoshphere not the lack of clothing on the hostesses


 ★★★☆☆ The usual 
by darrinstreet at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 June 24, 2008 
This restaurant is not what it used to be. The service is just what one would expect from a first rate restaurant but the food is lacking. How many different ways can you do salmon, filet of beef and chicken? It seems like the chefs (or Robert) are no longer being creative. Wouldn&apos;t it be nice to see some pasta dishes, maybe some new fish on the menu not just as a special and let&apos;s not mention the desserts. I don&apos;t think I have seen a creative and new dessert since Ben Berryhill left the kitchen. I am hoping with the opening of the new restaurant, new ideas will also come.


 ★★★★★ Annie loved Cafe Annie 
by CoolDan at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 May 24, 2008 
I&apos;ve always heard good things about this place and I was not disappointed. I knew the price would be high but it was only a $150.00 for two of us. Thats with a 65.00 bottle of wine. Well worth it in my opionion. It was a memorerable experience with my new (that night) Fiance. Well done Cafe Annie - Keep it up. The shrimp and enchilada&apos;s were too die for.

Pros: Great food - Good service

Cons: Nothing was free


 ★★★☆☆ Rep is stronger than experience 
by Houstone at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 April 16, 2008 
Can&apos;t really say anything that bad about the place. Service from my waiter was impeccable, but the menu, particularly the desserts, are just flat.
Probably would eat at the bar next time; better menu, and less expensive.

Pros: Bar menu, waitstaff

Cons: See review


 ★★★★☆ Reputation stronger than my experiences 
by z_man1025 at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 January 01, 2008 
My wife and I have been to Cafe Annies now on a number of occasions, purely based in the strength of recommendations from Houston natives. Although a gewat restaurant, and one of the better ones in Houston, it doesn&apos;t deserve the world class accoldaes we&apos;ve seen heaped on it recently.

Our most recent experience was in Sep 07 when we dined with business colleagues. I had Sea Bass and my wife tried the veal. Both were very good and well prepared, but not spectacular. The prices charged demand a little more than was delivered here. The wine list was great though and we were helped to select a benchmark bordeaux.


 ★★★☆☆ Nyeh! 
by sst9929 at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 November 05, 2007 
I had a meal here in 1998, every bite a symphony. My meal on 11/3/07, a Saturday night, was also a disappointment. There was no magic at all. I had the chicken-fried shrimp and foie gras appetizers and the toasted pound cake dessert. The pound cake had an unpleasant bitter/tangy taste. My friend and I were dressed down in an Austin kinda way, and I had the feeling we were being rushed along.

Pros: service, parking

Cons: the carriage has changed back to a pumpkin again


 ★☆☆☆☆ Huge disappointment! 
by azilet at Citysearch 1 Rdg Bar Annie 
 September 25, 2007 
My husband and I come to Houston on a regular basis, most of the time to enjoy the restaurants. We have some favorites (Da Marco&apos;s and Tony&apos;s specifically) but like to try out new spots. We had resisted trying Cafe Annie mainly because we thought it was probably just a trendy place with no substance. I hate to say we could not have been more correct. After visiting this past Saturday night, we walked out wondering how it manages to stay in business if that was a typical night. The food was bland and, in the case of the shrimp dish I tried, too hard to eat. I expected fresh seafood and knock your socks off flavors. The tables were situated too close. Da Marcos manages to pull off a similar seating arrangement without making you feel like you are sitting on top of the neighboring tables. I will say the margaritas and the caramel custard (aka flan) were good but not worth a second trip.


 ★★★☆☆ 1st time the last. 
by dacosta at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 June 03, 2007 
Last night was our first time to Cafe Annie and I&apos;m sorry to say we were both disappointed. Absolutely, no comparison to Mark&apos;s or Ruggles. The food was bland, seating close, service &quot;snooty&quot;, and all of this for $200! I definitely expect A LOT better for a supposedly upscale restaurant. Sorry Cafe Annie, but we won&apos;t be returning.


 ★★★★★ great food, great service 
by txmadame72 at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 December 31, 2006 
No complaints on our first visit. The service was great. Our food was great. The wood-grilled flavor took us by surprise and had us questioning it at first, but by the second bite all doubts were gone. The shrimp appetizer, the steaks, pecan pie, berry custard, wine...all was great. We will surely be back.

Pros: everything

Cons: none


 ★★★★★ Awsome 
by mrchef at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 December 19, 2006 
The food was great, the service was very good and the atmospher was relaxed/upscale. The flavors were well balanced of everything we ate exept the chilled avacado mango soup. The crab salad is a must have. I love lamb and the lamb was perfect. Desert my date and I shared the caramel custard with cinnamon churro along with our port. They had a nice wine list. Upscale with nicely blended southwest flavors done right will eat here again.

Pros: everything

Cons: none


 ★★★★★ My fav restaurant in Houston 
by adrianne77 at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 November 19, 2006 
The food is always exquisite and the service is always impecable. Definitely worth the trouble of making reservations and getting dressed up. Don&apos;t miss out on the people watching.


 ★★★★☆ Excellent Food, Faltering Service 
by bigdaddylynn at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 October 20, 2006 
Two of us went to Cafe Annie for lunch mid-week, with reservations made in advance. The tortilla soup, crab meat salad and fried chicken salad were wonderful. After delivering our order our waiter seemed to disappear. There were several bus boys, but no waiter. The manager finally came to check on us. When we ordered dessert (from the manager), I requested our check. The &quot;warm&quot; chocolate cake wasn&apos;t warm - it had a crusty re-heated taste. But the check was delivered with our dessert - again, from the manager. I wouldn&apos;t go back for lunch if I had time constraints.

Pros: Food, location

Cons: Service


 ★★★★☆ New Year&apos;s Eve 
by johnpeppers at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 January 09, 2006 
What an exciting start to 2006. A friend told me what Cafe Annie does when the clock strikes 12 and he was not wrong. The balloons ( the whole restruant was covered) party favors, champagne, hats, menu, etc. were just wonderful, they even had a few people outside with silly string. I will be there next year.


 ★★★★★ User review by wescobarm 
by wescobarm at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 September 29, 2005 
Why do people think Cafe Annie is closed? This concerns me, because it is my favorite restaurant in Houston, yet on my last several visits to the city. I heard that rumor from a concierge, a taxi driver and several Houston businessmen. Thankfully, it is just a rumor, and I was greeted at the door by Paco, who I&apos;ve known for 19 years. By the way, the crab meat tostada is still excellent.



 ★★★★★ The service was second to none 
by sparklez71 at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 26, 2005 
The service was phenomenal. The food was very delectable cocoa chicken. The flavors and textures were a party in my mouth. I actually left the restaurant happy. There is a waiter by the name of Ricardo; I have to say that his complimentary style will have me take my associates there time and time again. With the help of the scrumptious chicken and the timeless energy and smile of this Ricardo R I bagged a multi-million dollar account! Did I tip enough?? The entire ambiance of Cafe Annie has me hooked. I question the negative reviewers taste.

Pros: Service, Quality, Attention to detail

Cons: None


 ★★★☆☆ Change is good 
by rdbtx at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 12, 2005 
In the past weeks I have dined at 17, Shade, and T&apos;afia and was looking forward to revisiting Cafe Annie for the first time in years. I mention these other restaurants, because perhaps the owners of Cafe Annie should venture out and see how the competition has evolved while they&apos;ve been resting on their laurels.

The room is anything but luxurious - stark without being modern. The popular floral arrangements were pedestrian - nothing but palms and bromeliads. The food may have been interesting 25 years ago, but now it pales in comparison to the lighter, more inventive fare available around town. They should consider a dress code as the clientele were at best underdressed. Only the service was as one should expect from a restaurant with Cafe Annie&apos;s reputation. The staff were kind and attentive and my dinner companion charming. Otherwise, the evening and the restaurant were both forgettable.

Pros: staff

Cons: food, interior


 ★★★★★ Outsanding...! 
by dini77056 at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 July 31, 2005 
I&apos;ve heard so much about Cafe Annie, so my husband and I took some friends from out of town this last weekend. I have to admit that I was impressed about the whole experience. I see now why this restaurant is been in business for 25 years. I had to change my reservation a couple of times, and we even had a couple of special requests, and they were really nice about it. Food was absolutely outsanding, my steak was cooked to perfection, dessert was excellent. Not to mention the best wine, suggested by the manager. Our waiter was very hepful, considering that the restaurant was full. We even stayed at the bar for a couple of after dinner drinks, and the atmosphere was exceptional. We are coming back to check out the bar menu! Now I see what makes Cafe Annie different and a very unique experience... Congratulations!

Pros: Food, Ambience, Service


 ★★★★★ POSITIVE COMMENTS 
by jondavis at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 July 28, 2005 
I was amazed by the two last comments posted for this restaurant. I am a weekly costumer that comes in with my wife . She is always telling me how fashionable, pretty and nice the girls are. I think this comment was written by a women with a lot of envy and not a very fashion oriented mind. And to the other comment about the old china and scratched silverware, Cafe Annie is recognized by it&apos;s food not by the silverware or china, probably we are different but I mind what is on my plate not the type of plate that I am eating in.


 ★★★★☆ User review by sharonh 
by sharonh at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 July 26, 2005 
What can one person say, the food and service as always is above par. The subtle changes to the decor makes this resturant more relaxed and inviting. I am not sure about the hostesses at the front, you just never know what to expect. One is wearing something too tight while someone else is wearing see thru, not sure if they know the meaning of &quot;fine dining&quot;


 ★★★☆☆ Over rated 
by snowman1234 at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 June 15, 2005 
I enjoyed the restaurant and the food, but was expecting something outstanding. The China is old banquet china, silver old and scratched, food and service was solid, but not to the reputation that everyone talks about.

Time to work on updating the place.




 ★★★★★ Creme de la creme 
by JD at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 May 24, 2005 
Cafe Annie remains Houston&apos;s finest restaurant.
The cuisine&amp;service are unbeatable.


 ★★★★★ Exquisite 
by spopham at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 April 16, 2004 
I absolutely love this restaurant; everything was perfect from the food, to the service. I tell you for those of you that can afford to go this is the best dinning experience that you can ask for, even if its for prom night your wedding anniversary, business meeting or even if you have the bug to eat at a nice restaurant like I did. A friend who lives in the Houston area recommended me to Cafe Annie, and it was well worth the drive from San Antonio. I plan to make it a tradition among my friends and myself. My hats off to you all for making such a pleasant dinning experience.
Thank you,
Steven Popham

Pros: Romantic, Stylish


 ★★★★★ An Old Favorite 
by smithfree at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 April 04, 2004 
We forget sometimes in the heat of discovery that some old gems just keep performing. Our recent meal at Cafe Annie reminded us what a jewel this is. Elegant yet relaxed, informed and attentive waitstaff, very fair prices considering the quality and the levels charged by competitors - an absolute delightful evening in all regards. You know you have been in the hands of professionals when you are finished. And by the way, the covered entry way is a blessing on a rainy night.

Pros: Food, Service, Ambience


 ★★★★★ Still on top 
by thomasdd02 at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 February 14, 2004 
Visited Cafe Annie for the first time in many years, to sit at the bar and partake in the bar menu and just have some drinks. The wine selection was good, the martinis were great, and the bar menu was exceptional. The restaurant has that cozy atmosphere which was very pleasant, it was packed but you could still carry on a decent conversation without having to yell at your partner. We&apos;ll be back to have dinner sometime in the near future.

Pros: Bar Selection, Food, Service


 ★★★★☆ Still going strong... 
by josephngo at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 December 15, 2003 
Even without their famed Sommelier, the place still maintains a good wine list. Recently I noticed they have reduced wine prices but their selection is more limited to better know names. Their food is great. Not very imagainative but the flavors are basic and grounded. Great for business, nice to take a date.

Pros: Modern Decor


 ★★★★☆ Quintessential Favorite 
by jpclark65 at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 March 15, 2003 
If you&apos;re looking the incredible food in a polished, refined environment, with impeccable ultra-friendly service, then Cafe Annie is the place. For game lovers, the mixed grill of venison, buffalo and lamb is awesome - and I highly recommend the rabbit enchiladas to begin. Looking to read a novel just ask for the wine list. But, dont let its size scare you the wait staff stands ready to recommend the perfect wine to compliment your meal. In spite of the high prices and relatively small servings, Cafe Annie continues to top my list. As of my visit last night, I discovered the entire wait staff is studying to become sommeliers. Definitely make reservations, and to top off the evening, give them your credit card while making the reservation, so you dont need to have your check presented at the table.

Pros: incredible food, perfect service, exhaustive wine list

Cons: price, smaller servings, slightly crowded


 ★★☆☆☆ Tasteless Food, Rushed Service 
by konline at Citysearch 2 Rdg Bar Annie 
 February 15, 2003 
Our waiter was incredibly friendly, but made it quite obvious he wanted to quickly &quot;turn our table. We felt extremely pressured to order each course quickly and eat even quicker. We could not even have a conversation, as he interrupted us every few minutes to &quot;move us along.&quot; I wanted to stay and chat after our meal, but my husband felt so uncomfortable staying at the table we opted to leave. We arrived at 7:05pm, sat at 7:10 and left by 8:10. Unfortunately, the food was no help. It was bland&amp;tasteless. The trout was fishy and greasy, and our filet was Well-Done when we ordered it Medium. We expected what we get at other great restaurants, but instead felt like we wasted our money (which we&apos;re HAPPY to spend when we enjoy our meal). Next time, well go back to Marks!

Pros: Reservations accepted, Valet Parking, Master Sommelier

Cons: Tasteless, Bland food, You&apos;re rushed to eat, Cramped tables


 ★★★★★ Normal but Expensive 
by Silly_Mongoose at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 February 12, 2003 
The service is great. The food was okay - I had salmon. The restaurant is open and a bit crowded. Do not expect much privacy on the main floor. Do expect to pay alot.

Pros: You will feel rich.

Cons: You will leave poor.


 ★★★★★ best southwestern 
by loftonpm at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 November 27, 2002 
went with my family. food and serves was very good. the dessert was delicious. only thing missing was not meeting chef del grande.


 ★★★★☆ be willing to spend 
by t12ubeauty at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 November 22, 2002 
the food (crab meat tostadas, wood grilled shrimp&amp;NY strip) is good and the service is decent, but i still think it is overpriced. for such an upscale restaurant, i figured it would have much better decor. it looks really plain and drab on the outside. I think we&apos;re really paying for robert del grande&apos;s name. It&apos;s a good place to take someone that you&apos;re trying to impress by buying them an expensive meal. Be willing to spend. I think there are much better restaurants in houston.


 ★★★★★ Foolproof Entertaining 
by mary_kingston at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 October 11, 2002 
Great resturant, professional service and creative, quality food. Just make sure that you make reservations at least an hour before you plan to eat dinner. We had a great table, but were in the bar for at least an hour past our reservation time. Food was a bit on the heavy side for SW cuisine, and I would call it more French than Santa Fe. Terrific place to take out of town guests, or clients on an expense account.

Pros: Creative cuisine, Quality staffing, Ambiance

Cons: EXPENSIVE, Slow service


 ★★★☆☆ Overrated 
by Andy1111 at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 October 08, 2002 
The food was really good but the service was awful. I went back a second time to see if the service was a fluke but it was bad both times. The problem is the wait staff continually asks you if you&apos;re done with your meal. And they rush one dish after another.

The atmosphere isn&apos;t that nice either. My girlfriend commented it was cold and not that romantic.


 ★★☆☆☆ too pricy!!! 
by rlbundick at Citysearch 2 Rdg Bar Annie 
 September 17, 2002 
The food was good but way too expensive for the serving. There is better food that is not so expensive. I also thought the ambiance was cold and not comfortable.


 ★★★★★ Romantically Delicious 
by shanbritally at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 September 04, 2002 
I have dined at Cafe Annie several times and I have never been disappointed. This place is not your local fast food restaurant! The food is absolutely delicious and very well prepared. To add to the ambience this place displays, the service is top notched. Quiet as it may be kept, I notice some of the staff are former employees of Brennan&apos;s. The menu is a little more than expected but like I mentioned this is not your local fast restaurant. I recommend dining here for a special occasion, and I&apos;ll even recommend my favorite entree. Try the Wood Grilled New York Strip with the Enchilada of Potato and for dessert please have the Sugared Lemon Cake or the Fresh Summer Berry Shortcake. Enjoy!



Pros: Service, Quality, Great Parking

Cons: Expensive


 ★★★☆☆ Wow, is this place overrated!?! 
by sjgjess at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 September 01, 2002 
I have been consistently unimpressed by the too-expensive, quite tasteless food here at Cafe Annie. It isn&apos;t that I think the chef is uninventive or does not deserve praise. I fear that the complacence of Houston diners has contributed to the decline of Cafe Annie, a former benchmark in innovative cuisine. The food has lost its verve. The last time I ate there, I went with my father. Our dinner came out to over $200, and yet our potatoes were cold, our entrees were less than spectacular, and we barely ever saw a server. Houstonians have too long accepted Cafe Annie as top-of-the-line without questioning the integrity of its dishes or its service. All it would take is a bit of unbridled criticism, and this once-trusty standby would bolster its menu...

Pros: Interesting menu, Good desserts

Cons: Slow service, Not so good


 ★★★★☆ Waste of money 
by grans at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 22, 2002 
The only explanation I can offer for the lofty praise this restaurant has garnered is that it became popular when Houston was used to barbeque as fine dining. Anything described as &quot;essence&quot; or &quot;reduction&quot; seemingly meant culinary artwork. Far from the truth for Cafe Annie. If you want essence of poblano pepper, go to La Mexicana.

Pros: service

Cons: price, value, freshness


 ★★★☆☆ Move on 
by John108 at Citysearch 3 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 16, 2002 
This has to be the most overrated restaurant I&apos;ve ever been to in Houston. I&apos;ve had to go on business many times, and I&apos;ve never had a first class meal. Service is, frankly, not good, and the wine list may be the most overpriced in town. Why bother?


 ★★★★☆ Good 
by rivas at Citysearch 4 Rdg Bar Annie 
 August 11, 2002 
Expensive, romantic, and good! Outside is not so hot looking! ok!

Pros: good food, coat needed, romantic

Cons: ugly outside, expensive


 ★★☆☆☆ Good Food, Not so good service 
by lsinfuego at Citysearch 2 Rdg Bar Annie 
 July 11, 2002 
This was the second time my boyfriend took me to this restaurant. The first time was a wonderful experience. However, the second time was not as I had expected. The food is always excellent. However, the service suffers. My boyfriend was eating his food and was asked 3 times whether he was finished. In the meantime, the busboy lurked behind us waiting until he could ask once again. It seemed like they couldn&apos;t wait to hurry us through the meal. Also, when I was walking to the restroom, I heard a catcall from the kitchen area. You expect that from a construction site, not a nice restaurant. I wrote a letter to the company and got a mere reply that the staff would be informed of my dissatisfaction. When you spend more than $300, you expect a little more class and service.

Pros: consistent food

Cons: poor service, noisy


 ★★★★★ 10 
by chipsadi at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 July 03, 2002 
Its a catchy blend of mexican and american all made into a fine dinning resturant. It is elegant dinning and great food. Service is wonderful and friendly. If your thinking of going there you have to go. A 5 star resturant!!!

Pros: good food, not very crowded or l

Cons: expensive but worth


 ★★★★★ Restaurant Connoisseur 
by jyoungblood at Citysearch 5 Rdg Bar Annie 
 June 28, 2002 
Perfect for any special occasion, or if you&apos;re just loaded. Excellent service, not stuffy and snobby servers like some other nice restaurants. Food and wine selection was great. One of the best in Houston!

Pros: Excellent Service, Excellent Food

Cons: Pricey, but worth it


 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Restaurants - Houston, TX
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
