<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004190" url="http://aella.org/2011/01/the-beginning-of-the-end-for-disposable-plastic-the-great-pacific-garbage-patch/" time="2012-07-12-20:25" support="4" score="0.012259657868064171" bingtitle="The Great Pacific Garbage Patch &amp; the beginning of the end for ..." webtitle="The Great Pacific Garbage Patchthe beginning of the end for disposable plasticAELLA.ORG">
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>Let us not waste precious time in the belief that ... many of the plastic cups, Styrofoam cups, fast food restaurant ... A Bill Becomes A Law; Contact Us; Government Resources</description>
	<body>
		AELLA.ORG 
 
 All 
 
Featured
 Back Next 
The Great Pacific Garbage Patch&amp;the beginning of the end for disposable plastic
 Posted on January 13, 2011 under AELLA , Animal Rights , Anthony Damiano , brutality , constitution , Environment , factory farming , garbage , Marla Stormwolf Patty , ocean life , pacific ocean , plastic , pollution , sea life 
 

 

 SIGN THE PETITION TELLING CONGRESS TO PLACE A HEFTY ENVIRONMENTAL TAX ON EVERY PLASTIC BAG USED IN COMMERCE . 

 

We have many serious issues facing our society today, such as a severely struggling economy, elevated criminal activity, flawed health care, social security issues and lack of gainful employment, just to name a few. We do realize that environmental issues have set themselves on the“back-burner”for many law-makers, however, to some degree, everyone must realize that there will be no livable world if we do not begin to address our environmental concerns, even if we could repair all of these other issues.

One such pressing issue that we would like to bring to everyone’s attention is the plastic“soup”which currently resides in the middle of the Pacific Ocean, which is now roughly twice the size and width of Texas. In some areas, it is nearly 90 feet thick/deep at the surface, where the sun slowly breaks the plastic down into smaller parts. As we already know in regard to plastics/Styrofoam, it will virtually never“go away”or properly degrade, especially the bulk of the plastic that rests upon the ocean floor. As a point of fact, it simply keeps growing, and at an alarming rate. We are quite past the point of merely“promoting”communities and citizens to recycle. Any piece of floating trash, Styrofoam or plastic which finds its way to a river will eventually add itself to this environmentally detrimental“sludge”which is now commonly referred to as the“Great Pacific Garbage Patch”.

 

Let us not waste precious time in the belief that recycling is not incredibly flawed and far from universally employed. Although the amount of plastic bottles recycled in the United States has grown steadily since the year 1990, the recycling percentage rate remains at less than thirty. Even if we reached one hundred percent, how many of the plastic cups, Styrofoam cups, fast food restaurant, convenience store/gas station cup lids and straws, etc…are recycled after being utilized? The answer to that question is next to none and more than likely, a billion of these shreds of plastic are discarded by humans with no chance of recycle, every single day. According to the Environmental Protection Agency, almost four million tons of plastic bags alone, are produced on an annual basis, well over three and one half million tons of which, or some 90 percent, are discarded. This is an absolutely horrifying statistic.

I would like to expand on the plastic bag issue, if I may. According to several other sources, plastic bag consumption falls in between five hundred billion and one trillion bags annually. That amounts to nearly one million each and every minute. The Wall Street Journal reported that the United States uses roughly one hundred billion plastic shopping bags as retailers across the nation spent four billion dollars annually on the bags, alone. It takes the average American family only a few trips to the grocery store in order to come home with over fifty plastic bags.

 

When the United Nations came forward with a study in regard to this issue, they reported that each square mile of the ocean has roughly forty-six thousand“pieces”of floating plastic in it. This same study also states that at least ten percent of all plastic produced annually around the world finds its way into the ocean and to reiterate, seventy percent of that plastic will fall to the ocean floor, where it will more than likely never degrade. All of these plastics are noxious to ocean life, and in specific, consider the devastation these degrading chemicals are causing our coral reefs, the cradle of all life on Earth, which can not survive in an acidic environment. When coral reefs are gone, humanity will follow.

I do sympathize with the fact that this is a monumental problem to solve. It is a task which requires all citizens to fully recognize, understand and face the enormity of environmental impact in relation to the issue, then to knowingly sacrifice and act. It is time for us to“step up to the plate”in regard to the devastation we have inflicted upon our planet, for the sake of our children. We have to come to the realization that we are condemning our posterity, not ensuring their continuance. It will be our doing, our very fault and folly, that our grandchildren will suffer, without action and sacrifice from us, right now.

 

Environmentally conscious people from across the nation will have to stand together, calling for a specific draft in legislation that will, at the very least, propose serious strides toward the end of plastic/Styrofoam with the intent of disposable use, as well as very strict and serious recycling reform. If this must be achieved in steps, then we must take the first one. We can move toward a ban on the use of plastic shopping bags in the United States. We propose the idea that stores should be forced to charge as much or more, for a plastic bag at checkout, as they would for a cloth or“eco-friendly”bag. We find this to be a satisfactory beginning to the“out-phasing”of plastic bag usage in commerce. Our world and our children simply have absolutely no time left for us to delay any longer in regard to this matter.

Anthony Damiano
Founder of AELLA

Please sign the petition to Congress HERE .

 
 [Translate] 

 
 Posted by Anna on September 7th, 2011, 02:37 (Reply to this comment) 
i support this.
 Posted by Lada Marjanac on September 7th, 2011, 13:47 (Reply to this comment) 
 :-)
 Posted by RENATA MAKOWSKA on October 21st, 2011, 20:15 (Reply to this comment) 
stop !!!!!
 Posted by McKenna Fisher on March 15th, 2012, 17:39 (Reply to this comment) 
signed petition.. I believe that if we can send our soldiers to other countries to fight against the taliban, and we can send man to the moon, there is absolutely no reason this pile of plastic waste cannot be removed. There are enough engineers in this country alone that should be able to figure it out.. I have some ideas…and I don’t even have a masters in ecology…let’s get this handled and NOW! MGF
 Posted by Iveta Martinková on June 3rd, 2012, 18:31 (Reply to this comment) 
stop THIS make full change
 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 

 Name: E-mail: Website: Comment: 
 
 Feed facebook twitter youtube 
 
Please Donate Today
 
 
World Clock
 
Resources
 
 A Bill Becomes A Law Contact Us Government Resources Stop Buying Extinction STOPCRUSH.ORG About AELLA 
 
Social Networks
 

 
Educational Video!
 
 &quot;AG-GAG&quot;~ WHAT ARE FARMS HIDING? 33 FACTS ABOUT VIVISECTION A BLOODY BUSINESS: FOUR CORNERS A DELICATE BALANCE A LIFE CONNECTED A MOST INCONVENIENT TRUTH A STORY OF VIVISECTION ACCESS DENIED ON VIVISECTION BY NAVS ACID TEST: OCEAN ACIDIFICATION AG-GAG–KEEP CONSUMERS IN THE DARK AN INCONVENIENT TRUTH ANIMAL CRUSH VIDEO ANIMAL RIGHTS WITH TOM REGAN ANIMAL TESTING: POINTLESS CRUELTY ARE HUMANS NATURAL MEAT EATERS? ASK YOUR DOCTOR ABOUT MEAT BAD MEDICINE: VIVISECTION BEYOND FAST FOOD NATION BREAKING A BABY ELEPHANT BUAV ON PRIMATE TRADE&amp;VIVISECTION CADBURY INVESTIGATION CAFO THE BOOK: VIDEO TRAILER CAFO&apos;S&amp;WATER POLLUTION CARING ABOUT THE CONGO CHICKENS: LOST DREAMS CONGRESSMAN KUCINICH ON VEGANISM DEFENDING THE RIVERS OF THE AMAZON EARTHLINGS EGG FARM NIGHTMARE END OF THE LINE ETHOS EXTREME ICE FAST FOOD ADDICTION FAST FOOD NATION FAT, SICK&amp;NEARLY DEAD FOOD INC. FORKS OVER KNIVES FOWL PLAY: THE REAL EGG INDUSTRY FROM FARM TO FRIDGE FUEL GIRL WHO SILENCED THE WORLD GLOBAL WARMING 101 GO VEGAN FOR THE PLANET GO VEGAN: BY ANIMAL AID GOD&amp;GLOBAL WARMING GOT MILK? THE TRUTH ABOUT DAIRY! GREAT PACIFIC GARBAGE PATCH HOME HORSE SLAUGHTER IN THE U.S.A. HUNTING WOLVES, SAVING WOLVES INDIGENOUS PROPHECY INVESTIGATION AT HY-LINE HATCHERY ISRAEL EXPOSE ON HATCHERY CRUELTY JAPAN:ONE YEAR LATER KYMATICA LABS UNLOCKED LESS THAN HUMAN MAKING THE CONNECTION MEET YOUR MEAT MONKEY ISLAND MY MATE&apos;S A PRIMATE OCEAN TIPPING POINT ON THIN ICE PARADISE LOST PHILIP WOLLEN ON ANIMAL RIGHTS PHYSICAL ADDICTION TO FOOD PORK INDUSTRY ABUSE EXPOSED SEA CHANGE SEA THE TRUTH SHARKS:STEWARDS OF THE REEF SHARKWATER SHOCKING FACTS: THE BLUEFIN TUNA SKIN TRADE SLAUGHTERHOUSE MACHINE SPEAKING OUT ABOUT CLIMATE CHANGE SPECIESISM STOP CIRCUS SUFFERING SUPERSIZE ME TAPPED THE 11TH HOUR THE COVE THE MEATRIX THE PLANET THRIVE TOM REGAN: ON ANIMAL RIGHTS TURKEY HATCHERY INVESTIGATION UNITED NATIONS SAYS: BE VEGAN! VEAL: BABY COWS BORN INTO HELL VEGAN DOCUMENTARY: 1976 VEGANISM: THE SOLUTION VEGGIE PROPAGANDA WATER WORLD 
 
Visitor Map
 
Animal Kill Counter
 
 

Number of commonly-exploited land animals killed by the meat, dairy and egg industries, since you opened this webpage. 

 0 chickens 0 turkeys 0 ducks 0 pigs 0 cattle 0 sheep 0 0 
 
Pages:

Hosted by: The Mary T. and Frank L. Hoffman Family Foundation 

 Home  \  A Bill Becomes A Law  \  About AELLA  \  Contact Us  \  Government Resources  \  STOPCRUSH.ORG  \  Return to top 
 
 powered by
	</body>
</document>
