<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004706" url="http://www.snagajob.com/restaurant-jobs/fast-food/wendys/" time="2012-07-12-21:13" support="4" score="0.03681362444121994" bingtitle="Wendy&apos;s Job Applications | Wendy&apos;s Apply Online" webtitle="Wendys Job Applications | Wendys Apply Online">
			<query id="000110" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000905" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000893" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="131"/>
	<description>Wendy&apos;s Restaurant &amp; Food Service Jobs. Crew Member As a Crew member, you will be afforded ... Some of those positions may include: Runner/Frontline Coordinator, Order Taker ...</description>
	<body>
		Are you an employer? To post jobs or get hiring solutions, please visit our employer website . Hide this message x 
 Browse Jobs Job Tips Join Today Sign In 
 
 FIND LOCAL JOBS 
 Search with keywords BETA 
Help Wanted at Wendy&apos;s



 Find a Job 
See all Wendy&apos;s Jobs now hiring!
 
 
Wendy&apos;s Overview

 Headquarters: Dublin, OH Revenue (2010): $3.5 (billion) Industry: Restaurant Competitors: Burger King , Hardees McDonalds 
 
Wendy&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Food Service Jobs

 Crew Member 
As a Crew member, you will be afforded the opportunity to learn many different positions within the restaurant. Some of those positions may include: Runner/Frontline Coordinator, Order Taker/Dining Room Attendant, Grill Operator, Sandwich Maker, Drinks, and Register Operator.

 Assistant Manager 
As an Assistant Manager, you will support the GM in managing the operations and staff of a Wendy&apos;s restaurant, including execution of all Company policies, procedures, programs and systems; participate in the achievement of store objectives; ensure compliance with all laws and ethical business practices; and participate in creating and maintaining a customer-focused environment.

 Supervisor 
In this entry level management position, you will learn the business from the ground up with the safety net of great tools and processes to help you along. Supported by your General Manager and management team, you will be given the opportunity to train and supervise Crew members; train, monitor and reinforce food safety procedures; interact with our customers, and execute cost control systems.

 Manager 
The manager assists the General Manager in managing the operations and staff of a Wendy’s restaurant, including the execution of all Company policies, procedures, programs and systems.
 
Wendy&apos;s Fun Facts

 Wendy&apos;s was founded by Dave Thomas in 1969. Wendy&apos;s is based in Dublin, Ohio . Wendy&apos;s is the third largest hamburger fast food chain behind McDonald&apos;s and Burger King. Wendy&apos;s employs over 46,000 people. 
 
Restaurant Job Resource Center
 See all restaurant job articles » 
 
 Waiter / Waitress jobs 
 Want to be a Bartender? 
 Turn your restaurant job into a career 
 
 Sign up for email Job Alerts 
Get local jobs delivered to your inbox.
 See an example. Email Address
 ZIP Code
 
 Submit 
 Find us on Twitter 


 Snagajob Job Seeker Security Center Local Jobs Job Tips Job Seeker Blog My Job, My Health Coupons Right-Fit Degrees Help and FAQ Contact Us Employer Solutions Post Jobs Talent Sourcing Hiring Manager Training Manager Scheduling Manager Recruitment Ad Agency Advertise with Us Affiliate Program Contact Sales About Snagajob Careers Our Story Giving Back Life at Snagajob News ©2000-2012 SnagAJob.com, Inc. All rights reserved Privacy Terms of Use Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
