<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004956" url="http://www.gokis.net/self-service/archives/cat_technology_new.html" time="2012-07-12-21:28" support="2" score="0.001776430527134823" bingtitle="Gokis Kiosk Self-Service: Technology - New Archives" webtitle="Gokis Kiosk Self-Service: Technology - New Archives">
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>It accepts and dispenses change bills + the credit card ... WWAN solution to a customer that makes kiosks to dispense ... of the accomplishment, the company has tapped pop ...</description>
	<body>
		Gokis Kiosk Self-Service 
 GoKis - KIosk Self-service from industry perspective 
June 15, 2011
 
Hardware - Evolis unveils dual encoder

Evolis announced the launch of the Evolis Dual Encoder that supports both smart contact and contactless cards. This dual encoder is compliant with the Evolis range of card personalization systems.

 CR80News | Evolis unveils dual encoder 

Evolis has worked with technology from SCM Microsystems in collaboration with Elyctis, an expert in advanced card readers, to design the encoder.

This new encoder can be integrated in the Pebble, Dualys, Quantum and Securion printers. It also features fast-reading throughput and foolproof security for data. This add-on supports up to three SAM slots, which makes it a flexible encoder to serve any type of secured applications.

The new Evolis Dual Encoder uses PC/SC printer drivers for Windows XP&amp;7 and is capable of being used for instant issuance projects or large-scale card production environments.

“We realized that companies, governments and financial institutions were increasingly looking for sophisticated solutions to personalize their payment cards, transport passes or ID cards, to name just a few of the multifarious card-based applications,” said Eric Bouvard, product marketing manager at Evolis.

 CR80News | Evolis unveils dual encoder 
 Posted by staff at 12:12 PM 
April 22, 2011
 
Vantage Recycler from Vendapin

New all in one from Vendapin and Darrell Rademacher. It accepts and dispenses change bills + the credit card capability.

Hello everyone...

You have asked for a bill acceptor that would accept; $1-$5-$10&amp;$20 bills and pay back as change (recycle) $1.00 bills or $5.00 bills! We now have it!

You asked for a bill acceptor that would accept credit cards! We now have that also!

You asked to have the wireless credit card acceptor process through to your own bank clearance center! We now have this also!

We have for you today the hottest bill acceptor with bill recycler&amp;wireless credit card terminal product on the market!!! It is the Advantage Coinco Recycler Bill Acceptor&amp;In-One Credit Card Terminal! We can upgrade any of our coin-op products that have the Raptor II Vending Machine Controller as it&apos;s engine.

Please go to: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NFrKckXtaA4 to view a full length video presentation of this amazing break through in bill acceptor technology! Call us if you require more information and prices. Also...see what&apos;s new at: http://www.vendapin.com/press27.html
 Posted by staff at 02:07 PM 
December 22, 2010
 
Microsoft to Reveal New Version of Windows

Microsoft hints at new version of Windows. After all the other &quot;versions&quot; we have already we are not sure a new &quot;version&quot; does much for them. We wish they would throw away the current model and build a completely new one, but that might be too difficult?

 Microsoft to Reveal New Version of Windows - WSJ.com 

By DON CLARK And NICK WINGFIELD
Microsoft Corp., feeling pressure from hit products like Apple Inc.&apos;s iPad, is crafting a new operating system that deviates from the software giant&apos;s heavy reliance on chip technology pioneered by Intel Corp., according to people briefed on Microsoft&apos;s plans.

The company next month plans to demonstrate a new version of its widely used Windows operating system that targets low-power devices and adds support for chips based on designs from ARM Holdings PLC as well as the x86 chip technology offered by Intel and Advanced Micro Devices Inc., these people said. Microsoft will discuss the software at the Consumer Electronics Show in early January, though it isn&apos;t expected to be available for two years, they added.

A Microsoft spokesman declined to comment, as did an Intel spokesman. An ARM spokeswoman also declined to comment.

Microsoft, based in Redmond, Wash., has struggled to match its dominance in PC operating systems in markets such as smartphones and a new breed of consumer tablets that Apple has come to dominate since introducing the iPad last spring.

Chips based on designs licensed by ARM consume less power than most x86 chips, helping to make them an overwhelming favorite in smartphones. Microsoft already sells versions of Windows for cellphones that support the technology, but has remained firmly committed to x86 chips in the mainstream version of the product used in PCs and server systems.

The relationship between Microsoft and Intel has been so close since the early 1980s that it is sometimes abbreviated as &quot;Wintel.&quot;

On the other hand, Microsoft and Intel have worked with other partners outside of PCs. Intel, for example, has been supporting Google Inc.&apos;s Android operating system in tablet-style computers, as well as software called Meego that Intel developed with Nokia Corp.

According to two people close to Microsoft, the company has had a project for some time to create a version of Windows running on ARM-based microprocessors. One of those people said the effort is part of a broader push at Microsoft to make Windows more &quot;modular&quot; so that pieces of the operating system that are unnecessary for smaller, low-power devices like tablets can be easily stripped away to make the software perform snappily on the gadgets.

The strategy is similar to the one Apple has employed with iOS, the lightweight operating system for iPads, iPhones and other devices that is derived from Apple&apos;s full-blown Mac operating system for traditional computers.

Microsoft&apos;s plans for the new operating system were reported earlier by Bloomberg.

 read rest of article 

 Posted by staff at 01:07 PM 
November 05, 2010
 
Giant Interactive Vodka Bottle

From Thinclient - example of presence mats being used by Absolut vodka in conjunction with video website and social networks and mobile phones. Very good outcome. Thin Client 
 Posted by staff at 10:47 AM 
October 12, 2010
 
New Hardware - Dual Core 510 with Ion2 graphics

The nettop hits, they just keep on coming. This one&apos;s from Habey, who we&apos;ve seen delivering a number of microATX wunder-machines over the years. Its latest delivers Intel&apos;s latest 1.6GHz Atom, the dual-core D510, and pairs it with Ion 2 graphics to deliver a system capable of 2560 x 1600 output over HDMI

 Habey&apos;s ENT-6564 nettop packs Ion and Atom D510 power for potent playback -- Engadget 

easily handling 1080p or, as you can see in the video after the break, triple Flash video playback without much of a hiccup. There&apos;s gigabit Ethernet, 802.11 wireless, four USB ports, and 250GB of storage. Price? Well, that&apos;s up in the air. Like many of the company&apos;s products this is really meant to be bought in bulk, so we&apos;re guessing the cost is wholly dependent on how many of these you want for your business or man cave. But, if you&apos;re the DIY sort, you can just get the board itself, the MITX-6564, complete with graphics and processor and dual slots just waiting for your DIMMs. Again, though, no price for mere consumers.

Update: Ya&apos;ll never fail to impress. Moments after this post went live commenter Brent found these for sale (individually) at a reasonable $329.
 Posted by staff at 02:08 PM 
October 04, 2010
 
Next Wave -- Google TV: The Future of Interactive Television.

Google wants to get inside your TV (just like Apple). Turner, CNBC and HBO are getting onboard.

 Google TV: The Future of Interactive TV? 

Google Seeks to Bring the Best of the Web to Couch Potatoes

By NEAL KARLINSKY and CHRISTINE BROUWER
Oct. 4, 2010—

First, Google revolutionized web searches -- now it&apos;s trying to reinvent the way you watch TV.

Inside a top-secret lab in Silicon Valley, programmers are putting the finishing touches on a new product called Google TV. The company says this new device will take all the best features of watching television, surfing the web, playing online games, and connecting with friends on Twitter and Facebook, and combine them into a single experience.

It is &quot;a new way to think about television,&quot; said Google Senior Product Manager Rishi Chandra. &quot;Basically what we&apos;re trying to do here is take all that content that you already watch today on television, and add all that other content that you get on the web today, that you normally can&apos;t get on your TV.&quot;

Watch the full story on &quot;World News&quot; tonight at 6:30 p.m. ET and on &quot;Nightline&quot; at 11:35 p.m. ET

With Google TV, users can channel-surf between traditional TV shows, websites, online video, social media, and eventually programs recorded on a DVR, all with just a few clicks of the remote. (The DVR function has not yet been worked out with all major cable and satellite providers.)

&quot;You can bookmark all your favorite applications, all your favorite websites, and all your favorite channels in this one single interface,&quot; Chandra explained.

Google is betting that it will transform TV the same way smartphones transformed the telephone.

The device is expected to hit store shelves later this month. It will be marketed as a stand-alone unit that can be attached to an existing TV, and also as a built-in feature in Sony TVs and Blu-Ray DVD players.

Google TV already has competition from Apple, which markets a system called Apple TV. Apple&apos;s device -- a sleek little black box -- provides access to TV shows, movie downloads, online music, photos and more. Amazon and Netflix are also looking at new ways to provide immediate content for viewers to turn watching TV into a more interactive experience.

All of these systems use new technology to bring an old idea back to life -- the idea of the whole family gathering around the television to share hours of entertainment together. While mobile use has vastly increased in recent years, making it easy to watch a movie solo on a laptop or smart-phone, the average American still spends five hours a day in front of the TV. Google sees that as a big opportunity.

&quot;The ability to actually enhance [TV viewing], to give them more content, to give them more opportunity to create new experiences, I think is what&apos;s most exciting for us,&quot; Chandra said.


 rest of article 
 Posted by staff at 04:48 PM 
September 09, 2010
 
Solar Powered Kiosk meets German Engineering

Hoeft&amp;Wessel announces new generation of compact ticketing kiosks and a special solar-powered version.The new solar-powered ticketing kiosks are powered by solar energy so do not need to be connected to the electricity grid.

 Solar-powered Kiosk | KIOSK EUROPE 

The Group´s Almex business division will present the new product for the first time at InnoTrans in Berlin.

Known as almex.midi, the vending machine extends the successful almex.station series, of which more than 10,000 units are in operation across Europe on railway platforms and public transport stations. Whereas the almex.station has a width of 90cm, the new model measures only around 68cm. Although smaller, it offers the same functions as the larger model owing to the optimised arrangement of modules.

The almex.midi will be available in two versions: a conventional one powered by electricity and a version which is fitted with a solar panel and can therefore be operated independently of the electricity grid.

 

nergy savings

By using highly efficient components and heating only individual parts rather than the entire device, it has been possible to reduce energy consumption by up to 50% in the solar-powered version.

Further energy savings are achieved by shutting the terminal down overnight and when it is not in use. The utilisation of LEDs instead of neon lights also saves energy and, despite higher initial costs, pays off because of the lower energy costs. The illumination also appears better and has a longer life expectancy. They recently developed and integrated a new LED lighting system for the 1,100 ticket vending machines operated by London Bus at the bus stations in the UK capital.

In developing the solar-powered version of almex.midi, Almex was also able to rely on experience gained by their subsidiary Metric. Its car park ticketing kiosks are a good example of the role which alternative energies can have. Around 60% of the parking kiosks sold already include a solar module, with this figure set to rise in the future. As early as in the 1990s, more than 15,000 solar-power car park ticketing kiosks had been sold. As these machines do not have to be connected with the electricity grid, the cost-intensive infrastructure preparations can be avoided. At the same time, CO2 emissions are reduced.

Passengers can pay for tickets in cash, by card or with e-tickets complying with the ITSO or VDV-KA standard. A large touchscreen and language support make the kiosks easy to use. Transports Publics Genevois, Geneva´s public transport company, has already opted for the new almex.midi.


 Posted by staff at 03:24 PM 
August 31, 2010
 
New B-Series TouchComputers from Elo TouchSystems Announced

The new B-Series portfolio consists of three highly configurable, ruggedized and cost-effective AiO touch systems intended to support a wide range of Point-of-Service (POS) and Point-of-Information (POI) applications and environments. The B-Series is a compliment to our previous D-Series and R-Series AiO solutions.

FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE

TYCO ELECTRONICS INTRODUCES THE ELO TOUCHSYSTEMS B-SERIES TOUCHCOMPUTERS FOR POS AND POI ENVIRONMENTS

– Trio of Compact, Highly Configurable, All-in-One Touchcomputers Delivers Powerful Commercial Options in a Single Intelligent Design –

MENLO PARK, CA – July 27, 2010 – Elo TouchSystems, a Tyco Electronics business, today launched the new B-Series touchcomputer family: answering the industry need for a single compact and retail-hardened touchcomputer platform to support countertop, pole- and wall-mounted applications. The new B-Series portfolio consists of three highly configurable, ruggedized and cost-effective All-in-One (AiO) touch systems intended to support a wide range of Point-of-Service (POS) and Point-of-Information (POI) applications and environments.

Engineered for Flexibility and Efficiency

The B-Series offers System Integrators, Value-Added Resellers (VARs) and Software Developers a uniquely efficient, scalable AiO platform for the delivery of tailor-made solutions to the ever-changing retail market. With multiple connection ports and PCI-E (PCI Express) expansion slots for easy system configuration no matter what the installation environment – the B-Series fits almost any space constraint or in-store design demand. In addition,

Elo has constructed the system to provide tool-less access to internal components to minimize service and repair down-times.
“Until today, fully integrated AiO POS terminals have been expensive to purchase, configure and manage for the ever-changing retail market,” said John Nicewick, Worldwide Business Development Manager, Elo TouchSystems. “The compact size, cost and scalability of the B-Series are well-suited to support a diverse range of POS and POI touch computing requirements. Retailers with various touch computing needs -- from standard POS duties to new interactive signage -- will find a B-Series platform configuration to fit their needs”

B-Series Highlights: Compact, Integrated Commercial Touch Solutions

Until now, the majority of commercial touchcomputers featured limited connectivity ports and no expansion capabilities – greatly limiting system functionality. To increase configuration options, the new B-Series comes standardized with multiple connectivity ports including: six USB 2.0 ports, two RS-232 serial ports, Gigabit Ethernet and audio ports. PCI-E low-profile industry-standard option cards and others from Elo TouchSystems deliver enhanced performance and compatibility. Additionally, B-series peripherals support virtually any retail/POS application and include a 3-track magnetic stripe reader (MSR), a 2x20 VFD rear-facing customer display, and a biometric fingerprint reader, all of which can be customer installed on the top, bottom, left, or right side of the screen .

The B-Series also provides multiple memory and storage configurations and options, as well as scalable
computing power featuring three high-performance processor configurations:

• Cool and Quiet Fan-less ATOM
• Performance Fan-cooled Intel CeleronTM Dual-Core 2.2 G
• Performance Ultra Fan-cooled Intel CoreTM 2 Duo 3.0 GHz

Screen sizes include both 15-inch or 17-inch configurations. To provide a better application match, the
new B-Series also offers a variety of touch technology options including:

• IntelliTouch surface acoustic wave
• *Zero-Bezel AccuTouch resistive
• *Zero-Bezel APR acoustic pulse recognition

*Zero-Bezel touch technologies from Elo TouchSystems provide an unique seamless edge-to-edge surface design for a sleek, clean appearance that is easy to maintain.

Other options include RAID for continuous data protection and reduced downtime, as well as HDMI output (included in certain B-Series models) for true high-definition video and audio as well as secure transmission of protected information.

High-Grade, Long Life Cycle Components Deliver Peace of Mind

Elo TouchSystems has emphasized the importance of quality throughout its more than 40-year history, ensuring products that work reliably, in “rugged” commercial environments. The B-Series reflects Elo’s commitment to building dependable, flexible utility value for customers –- all from a single hardware platform that utilizes commercial-grade, high-performance embedded processors, boards and chipsets built for 24/7 usage.

“Consumer-grade components can change every 9 to 12 months, forcing software to be retested on
each new platform. The peripherals provided by Elo take the guesswork out of compatibility,” added Bill
Nulf, Director Channel Sales, Elo TouchSystems. “Our touch system functionality and product
consistency significantly exceeds consumer component lifecycles to help minimize a customer’s
software costs throughout an installment lifecycle. In addition, the B-Series is covered by a three year
warranty backed by a global service and support network for customer peace of mind.

The new B-Series is available immediately in North America and Canada, with availability to EMEA,
China and Japan starting late August.

Find more information online visit:

Tyco Electronics Website
Elo TouchSystems Website
Elo TouchSystems B-Series Press Kit
Elo TouchSystems Product Page
Follow Elo TouchSystems on Twitter @EloTouch

Technorati Tags: Elo TouchSystems, services, digital media, digital sign, digital content, DMS, creative
services, touchscreen, kiosk, POS, AiO

ABOUT TYCO ELECTRONICS
Tyco Electronics Ltd. is a leading global provider of engineered electronic components, network solutions, specialty products and undersea telecommunication systems, with fiscal 2009 sales of US$10.3 billion to customers in more than 150 countries. We design, manufacture and market products for customers in a broad array of industries including automotive; data communication systems and consumer electronics; telecommunications; aerospace, defense and marine; medical; energy; and lighting. With approximately 7,000 engineers and worldwide manufacturing, sales and customer service capabilities, Tyco Electronics&apos; commitment is our customers&apos; advantage. More information on Tyco Electronics can be found at http://www.tycoelectronics.com/.

ABOUT ELO TOUCHSYSTEMS
Tyco Electronics’ Elo TouchSystems is the global leading brand in touch technology. The Elo TouchSystems portfolio encompasses the largest selection of touchscreen technologies, touchmonitors, and all-in-one touchcomputers for the demanding requirements of diverse applications, such as industrial, medical, POS, kiosks, retail, hospitality, transportation, office automation and gaming. Elo founders invented the touchscreen over 35 years ago. Since then, Elo touchscreens have delivered one common, powerful result - advanced computer technology simplified for all users. For more information on Elo products and services, please contact 800-ELO-TOUCH (800-356-8682), or view Elo products website at www.elotouch.com or direct electronic mail inquiries to customerservice@elotouch.com.

AccuTouch, Elo TouchSystems, IntelliTouch, Tyco Electronics and TE (logo) are trademarks of the Tyco Electronics group of companies and its licensors. All other products and company names referred to herein may be trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective companies or mark holders.

###


Contacts:
Public Relations:
Jennifer Shanks
408-286-9899
jshanks@stephenz.com
Marketing Communications:
Gary Sadamori
(650)361-4669
gary.sadamori@tycoelectronics.com
 Posted by staff at 04:20 PM 
August 27, 2010
 
Paul Allen Sues Apple, Google, Others Over Patents

Paul Allen sues Apple, Google and more. A legacy of innovation seems headed towards the capital optimization pipe.

Excerpt:

Mr. Allen&apos;s firm had sent letters to the defendants telling them it held &quot;patents of interest&quot; to the company and that his firm would like to talk to the defendants about them.

The suit, filed by Mr. Allen&apos;s Interval Licensing LLC, lists violations of four patents for technology that appear to be key components of the operations of the companies—and that of e-commerce and Internet search companies in general. The suit does not estimate a damage amount.

The technology behind one patent allows a site to offer suggestions to consumers for items related to what they&apos;re currently viewing, or related to online activities of others in the case of social networking sites.

A second, among other things, allow readers of a news story to quickly locate stories related to a particular subject. Two others enable ads, stock quotes, news updates or video images to flash on a computer screen, peripherally to a user&apos;s main activity.

 Full story at WSJ.com 





 Posted by staff at 01:43 PM 
August 19, 2010
 
Technology - World&apos;s Smallest SSD

Size of a postage stamp, with support for SATA, now we can get 64GB SSDs. These can be soldered directly to motherboards.

18 August, 2010, by Desire Athow

Sandisk has just announced the arrival of the world&apos;s smallest SSD with storage capacities ranging from 4GB to 64GB and which will be part of the company&apos;s integrated SSD range of products.

The storage company said that the iSSD range will target the &quot;fast-growing&quot; mobile computing platforms such as tablet PCs and ultra-thin notebooks (and netbooks we presume); as expected, they won&apos;t be available to consumers directly but as an integral part of devices.

Weighing less than a paper clip and smaller than a postage stamp, the iSSD comes in a tiny Ball Grid Array and boost support for the SATA standard, which means that it can be soldered directly on motherboards.

Sandisk also says that it is &quot;fast enough&quot; to use with the latest operating systems with 160MB/sec sequential read and 100MB/sec sequential write speeds being quoted.

The advantages of having such an integrated technology are obvious and could pave the way for cheaper, more reliable and faster solid state storage as manufacturers start to integrate SSD straight on their products.

Read more: here 

 Posted by staff at 10:09 AM 
July 15, 2010
 
Company Profiles - Belprog iPad&amp;iPhone Development

New software development resource for iPhone and iPad development. Currently have app(s) on Appstore and have several &quot;kiosk&quot; apps in the works.


We are glad to inform that in addition to iPhone, Belprog has successfully started providing services in the area of software development for iPad platform.

Our first iPad project is titled as MixxMuse (http://mixxmuse.com). This iPad application was presented on the Grand Opening in the Appstore, on the 3rd of April 2010 and it has become one of the most popular apps in its category.

 Belprog - Main page 

 Posted by staff at 07:23 AM 
June 18, 2010
 
Forrester: Tablets Outselling Netbooks by 2012

Another report on computing hardware trends. By 2015 they have desktop PCs as close to 15% (down from current 50%). Tablets eating up that share.

Another analyst has gone bullish on tablet computing. Forrester Research is out with a report this morning projecting that tablets will start outselling netbooks by 2012.

The report goes on to predict that by 2015, tablets will make up 23% of all PC sales (which Forrester defines as desktops, laptops, netbooks and tablets).

Early signs already suggest this shift is happening; two million iPads were sold in its first two months of availability, and netbook sales –- not long ago the hottest growth area of the computing industry -– have slowed considerably.

Moreover, seemingly every hardware manufacturer is prepping a tablet of its own, and Google is set to enter the market with Verizon Wireless as its launch partner.


 Tablets Will Be Outselling Netbooks by 2012 [REPORT] 

 forecast image 
 Posted by staff at 01:31 PM 
NCR unveils the high-tech, self-serve future

NCR Whiz kids display and offer sneak peek into self-service future. Mark Grossi quoted. Gadgets include posters with RFID, photo recognition (variation of OCR/visual/pattern), devices in cards, and in-home medical services.



By Dan Chapman

The Atlanta Journal-Constitution
1:36 p.m. Friday, June 18, 2010

Posters at airports that speed hotel check-ins. Doctor visits via TV screen. Cars as personal assistants.

Duluth-based NCR Corp. offered a sneak peak Friday of the self-service future – quick, convenient and high-tech. A handful of Jetson-like features, including next-generation ATMs and grocery store scanners, were unveiled by company engineers and consultants.

Costs weren’t mentioned; the products won’t be on the market for a couple of years. But the NCR whiz kids eagerly discussed cloud-computing, near-field communication and other technologies geared to make easier shopping, driving and life.

“We’re looking to build out scenarios for what the future will look like for the next generation of consumers,” said Mark Grossi, an NCR vice president for product development. “The next generation is more technologically aware. They will have grown up with Nintendo and Play Stations and will have no fear of technology. They are our customers and we are anticipating their needs today.”

Some of the high-tech gadgets previewed:

• Posters embedded with radio-frequency tags to let travelers at airports make hotel reservations. Just tap the poster with your cell phone and a list of hotels, rooms and reservations can be made.

• A photo-based, self-service check-out system for grocery stores that easily scans fruit and other hard-to-tally products.

• Shop while you drive! Perhaps a spouse wants you to stop by the store on the way home. A blinking dashboard light alerts you to a voice message which is also sent ahead to grocery stores on the route home. The driver can chose the store based on distance and price. The groceries await your arrival.

In-home doctor visits. A web cam, finger pad for blood pressure, scales and other medical equipment link a home-bound patient with doctors and nurses via a TV screen.

“Technology changes so fast,” said Dan White, an NCR technology consultant. “We can’t predict what’s going to hit. But we can make bets on some of these trends.”


 NCR unveils the high-tech, self-serve future �| ajc.com 
 Posted by staff at 01:23 PM 
Technology - 4G/3G USB Modem from Clear for PC or Mac

Dual band (EVDO and WiMAX) USB Modem available now from CLEAR. 6Mb/s where available.

WiMAX provider Clearwire has expanded its device offering with a few new modems today. This set of new modems will help PC and Apple users connect to Clear&apos;s 4G wireless broadband service. The Clearwire CLEAR 4G+ Mobile USB 4G/3G Modem works for both Mac and PC users enabling 4G connects at up to 6Mb/s where available. Clear 4G coverage only extends to a few select cities so far but is expanding. The 2&quot; dongle is double jointed and can easily flex to fit any device or be out of the way.

Plans start at $40 per month, which is lower than most cellular carrier&apos;s add-on unlimited data plans. The surprising thing is that the S series adapter and a 4G+ is also able to connect to 3G networks when 4G isn&apos;t available. The devices can also be leased or bought outright with no long term contract. All this flexibility seems a little too good to be true. As you go in and out of range of 4G, the USB modem will switch over automatically to 3G. This is a great feature but we hear it&apos;s not quite instantaneous. They are available now at Clear&apos;s site if you are ready for 4G and are lucky enough to live in one of their select cities.


 CLEAR 4G Mobile USB Modem is Cross-platform&amp;Dual-band Friendly 
 Posted by staff at 07:09 AM 
May 03, 2010
 
Trends - Kraft and Coke machines Borrow From iPhone

See the impact of Apple as kids take to vending machines designed like giant iPhones with 42&quot; touchscreen menu&apos;s instead of clunky oldstyle. iPhone-like vending machines - chicagotribune.com 
 Posted by staff at 09:57 AM 
March 24, 2010
 
Cool Tech - First portable 13&quot; LCD

Not generally available but at show this week new portable LCD that runs off USB port shown off. Battery is five hours. Cool stuff.

 source link- 


MEDL Technology Launches at DEMO Unveiling First Portable 13&quot; LED Monitor


Download image

PALM SPRINGS, Calif., March 22 /PRNewswire/ -- MEDL Technology today announced the prototype of &apos;The Panel&apos;, the world&apos;s first fully functional, portable LED monitor, at IDG&apos;s DEMO conference in Palm Springs, CA. For updates on The Panel, visit www.medltech.com.

(Photo: http://www.newscom.com/cgi-bin/prnh/20100322/NE74006 )

&quot;The technology wasn&apos;t available previously to manufacture an elegant, lightweight and durable, portable display; but with The Panel, anyone can add a second or third monitor to their laptop and easily pack it up and go,&quot; said Eric Liao, CEO of MEDL Technology. &quot;Our vision is to make life easier for the laptop-toting public and we&apos;re thrilled to have the opportunity to launch our first product at DEMO.&quot;

A multi-purpose, LED display, the MEDL Panel offers both business and consumer audiences the very first portable 13&quot; display. Lightweight at 2.2 lbs., it can be used for work or play. Students, telecommuters and road warriors alike can add more screen real estate to their computer&apos;s desktop and enhance productivity at home. The battery-operated Panel is perfect for desks, conference rooms or for an impromptu presentation in any location.

The Panel connects easily to computers using either Mac OS or Windows operating systems via a common USB cable and is ready for use in fewer than 10 seconds. With WXGA resolution and a five-hour battery life, The Panel provides portability with incredible LED brightness, high definition and resolution. Not limiting itself to just laptops, The Panel can be used with portable video players, cameras, DVD players, iPhones, iPods and gaming platforms such as Xbox and PS3.

Last year over 160 million LCD monitors were sold and DisplaySearch forecasts growth to 197 million by 2012.

About DEMO

Produced by the IDG Enterprise events group, the worldwide DEMO conferences focus on emerging technologies and new products innovations, which are hand selected from across the spectrum of the technology marketplace. The DEMO conferences have earned their reputation for consistently identifying cutting-edge technologies and helping entrepreneurs secure venture funding and establish critical business. For more information on the DEMO conferences, visit http://www.demo.com/.

About MEDL Technology

Founded in 2008 and based in Hong Kong, MEDL Technology is an innovator in portable consumer electronics. Designer of the first fully functional, portable 13&quot; LED monitor, MEDL Technology is committed to bringing the next generation of portable devices to market. For more information, go to www.medltech.com.

SOURCE MEDL Technology
 Posted by staff at 08:06 AM 
March 04, 2010
 
3D - new rendering engine for PCs

3D is coming to a browser near you in near future. Both Firefox&amp;Webkit are about to be 3D enabled with new real-time ray tracing technology via XML3D spec. Native render.

&quot;A group of researchers plans to release a version of the Firefox browser that includes the built-in ability to view 3D graphics. They&apos;ve integrated real-time ray tracing technology, called RT Fact, into Firefox and Webkit. Images are described using XML3D, and the browser can natively render the 3D scene.&quot;

The browser will be released within a few weeks, the researchers say, and they are checking with the Mozilla Foundation about whether they can call it Firefox.
	</body>
</document>
