<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004386" url="http://www.coursehero.com/file/5833091/midterm-exam/" time="2012-07-12-20:38" support="1" score="0.0006987978231106732" bingtitle="California State Universit... : BUSINESS 168 : midterm exam" webtitle="California State Universit... : BUSINESS 168 : midterm exam">
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Dan earned $4,200 in 2009 working at a fast food restaurant and is ... The employer has offered to pay Turner a $720,000 ... counteroffer, Turner will be in constructive receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		Course Hero Sign up Log-in 
 Home Study Documents 
 Find Documents Textbook Help 
 Tutors 
 Ask a Question Browse Questions 
 Courses 
 Find Courses Create a Course Suggest a Course About Courses 
 Flashcards 
 Find Flashcards Create Flashcards About Flashcards 
 Support 
 Contact Us FAQ 
 
 
Why Course Hero?
 7 Million Study Materials From students who&apos;ve taken these classes before 24/7 Access to Tutors Personal attention for all your questions Learn 93% of our members earn better grades 
 Register now to access 7 million high quality study materials. midterm exam Course: BUSINESS 168, Winter 2010 
 School: California State Universit... 
 Rating:           
 Related: 
 Document Preview 
 NAME STUDENT ___________________________________ University of California, Riverside Bus 168A - Individual Federal Taxation - Midterm Exam - Winter 2010
Multiple Choice Identify the choice that best completes the statement or answers the question. ____ 1. Which, if any, of the following is a deduction for AGI? a. Alimony payments. b. Interest on home mortgage. c. Unreimbursed employee expenses. d. Charitable... 
 Register Now 
 
MOST POPULAR BUSINESS MATERIALS
 
 BUS168A - ... 
 California State Univer...
BUSINESS 1 
 Vol 01 Cha... 
 California State Univer...
BUSINESS 1 
 midterm 
 California State Univer...
BUSINESS 1 
MOST POPULAR California State Un... MATERIALS
 
 econ readi... 
 California State Univer...
ECON 3006 
 Trend&amp;amp...; 
 California State Univer...
STATISTICS 
 assessments 
 California State Univer...
ECON 3006 Ask a Tutor my question   * -- Select a subject -- Accounting Biology Business Chemistry Civil Engineering Computer Science Economics Electrical Engineering English Finance Math Mechanical Engineering Operations Management Other Subjects Physics Statistics and Probability Writing Help * Due Date: Time: Any 12 AM 1 AM 2 AM 3 AM 4 AM 5 AM 6 AM 7 AM 8 AM 9 AM 10 AM 11 AM 12 PM 1 PM 2 PM 3 PM 4 PM 5 PM 6 PM 7 PM 8 PM 9 PM 10 PM 11 PM morning afternoon evening Attachment (optional): Get help Now! Our current time in (CST) is     Unformatted Document Excerpt Coursehero &gt;&gt; California &gt;&gt; California State Universit... &gt;&gt; BUSINESS 168 Course Hero has millions of student submitted documents similar to the one
 below including study guides, practice problems, reference materials, practice exams, textbook help and tutor support. NAME STUDENT ___________________________________ University of California, Riverside Bus 168A - Individual Federal Taxation - Midterm Exam - Winter 2010
Multiple Choice Identify the choice that best completes the statement or answers the question. ____ 1. Which, if any, of the following is a deduction for AGI? a. Alimony payments. b. Interest on home mortgage. c. Unreimbursed employee expenses. d. Charitable contributions. e. None of the above. 2. During 2009, Marie had the following transactions: Salary Bank loan (proceeds used to buy personal auto) Alimony received Child support received Inheritance from deceased aunt Maries AGI is: a. $40,000. b. $46,000. c. $52,000. d. $96,000. e. None of the above. ____ 3. During 2009, Sam had the following transactions: Salary Interest income on General Electric Corporation bonds Gift from parents Contribution to traditional IRA Lottery winnings Sams AGI is: a. $59,000. b. $61,000. c. $65,000. d. $85,000. e. None of the above. ____ 4. Merle, age 17, is claimed by her parents as a dependent. During 2009, she had interest income from a bank savings account of $2,000 and income from a part-time job of $4,200. Merles taxable income is: a. $4,200 $4,500 = $0. b. $6,200 $5,700 = $500. c. $6,200 $4,500 = $1,700. d. $6,200 $950 = $5,250. e. None of the above. $60,000 2,000 24,000 5,000 3,000 $40,000 10,000 6,000 12,000 50,000
____
____
5. In which, if any, of the following situations may the individual not be claimed as a dependent of the taxpayer? a. A former spouse who lives with the taxpayer (divorce took place this year). b. A stepmother who does not live with the taxpayer. c. A married daughter who lives with the taxpayer. d. A half brother who does not live with the taxpayer and is a citizen and resident of Canada. e. A cousin who lives with the taxpayer. 6. Which of the following taxpayers may file as a head of household in 2009? Ron provides all the support for his mother, Betty, who lives by herself in an apartment in Fort Lauderdale. Ron pays the rent and other expenses for the apartment and properly claims his mother as a dependent. Tammy provides over one-half the support for her 18-year old brother, Dan. Dan earned $4,200 in 2009 working at a fast food restaurant and is saving his money to attend college in 2010. Dan lives in Tammys home. Joes wife left him late in December of 2008. No legal action was taken and Joe has not heard from her in 2009. Joe supported his 6-year-old son, who lived with him throughout 2009. a. Ron only. b. Tammy only. c. Joe only. d. Ron and Joe only. e. Ron, Tammy, and Joe.
____
____
7. For the current year, David has salary income of $80,000 and the following property transactions: Stock investment sales Long-term capital gain Short-term capital loss Loss on sale of camper (purchased 4 years ago and used for family vacations) What is Davids AGI for the current year? a. $76,000. b. $77,000. c. $78,000. d. $89,000. e. None of the above.
$ 9,000 (11,000) (2,000)
____
8. On a particular Saturday, Tom had planned to paint a room in his house, but his employer gave him the opportunity to work that day. If Tom works, he must hire a painter for $100. For Tom to have a positive cash flow from working and hiring the painter: a. Tom must earn at least $125 if Tom is in the 25% marginal tax bracket. b. Tom must earn at least $150 if Tom is in the 33% marginal tax bracket. c. Tom must earn at least $150 if he is in the 25% marginal tax bracket. d. Tom must earn at least $115 if he is in the 15% marginal tax bracket. e. None of the above. 9. Turner, a successful executive, is negotiating a compensation plan with his potential employer. The employer has offered to pay Turner a $720,000 annual salary, payable at the rate of $60,000 per month. Turner counteroffers to receive a monthly salary of $50,000 ($600,000 annually) and a $180,000 bonus in 5 years when Turner will be age 65.
____
a. If the employer accepts Turners counteroffer, Turner will recognize $65,000 ($780,000 12) each month. b. If the employer accepts Turners counteroffer, Turner will be in constructive receipt of $60,000 per month. c. If the employer accepts Turners counteroffer, Turner will be in constructive receipt of $60,000 per month and the $180,000 bonus. d. If the employer accepts Turners counteroffer, Turner will recognize as gross income $50,000 per month and $180,000 in year 5. e. None of the above.
____ 10. Dorothy purchased a certificate of deposit for $10,000 on January 1, 2009. The certificates maturity value in two years (December 31, 2010) is $10,816, yielding 4% before-tax interest. a. Dorothy must recognize $400 (.04 $10,000) gross income in 2009. b. Dorothy must recognize $816 gross income in 2010. c. Dorothy must recognize $816 gross income in 2009. d. Dorothy must recognize $408 ($816/2) gross income in 2009 and 2010. e. None of the above. ____ 11. Home Office, Inc., leased a copying machine to a new customer on December 27, 2009. The machine was to rent for $500 per month for a period of 36 months beginning January 1, 2010. The customer was required to pay the first and last months rent at the time the lease was signed. The customer also was required to pay an $800 damage deposit. Home Office must recognize as income for the lease: a. $1,000 in 2009, if Home Office is an accrual basis taxpayer. b. $1,000 in 2010, if Home Office is a cash basis taxpayer. c. $1,800 in 2009, if Home Office is a cash basis taxpayer. d. $0 in 2009, if Home Office is an accrual basis taxpayer. e. None of the above. ____ 12. With respect to the prepaid income from services, which of the following is true? a. The treatment of prepaid income is the same for tax and financial accounting. b. A cash basis taxpayer can spread the income over the period services are to be provided if all of the services will be completed by the end of the tax year following the year of receipt. c. An accrual basis taxpayer can spread the income over the period services are to be provided if all of the services will be completed by the end of the tax year following the year of receipt. d. An accrual basis taxpayer can spread the income over the period services are to be provided on a contract for three years or less. e. None of the above. ____ 13. Wayne owns a 25% interest in the capital and profits of Emerald Company (a calendar year partnership). For tax year 2009, the partnership earned revenue of $500,000 and had operating expenses of $200,000. During the year, Wayne withdrew from the partnership a total of $64,000. He also invested an additional $20,000 in the partnership. For 2009, Waynes gross income from the partnership is: a. $44,000. b. $55,000. c. $64,000. d. $75,000. e. None of the above. ____ 14. Under the terms of a divorce agreement, Kim was to pay her husband Tom $4,000 per month in alimony and $1,500 per month in child support. For a twelve-month period, Kim can deduct from gross income (and Tom must include in gross income): a. $0. b. $18,000. c. $48,000. d. $66,000. e. None of the above. ____ 15. The taxpayers marginal tax bracket is 35%. Which would the taxpayer prefer? a. $1.35 taxable income rather than $1.00 tax-exempt income.
b. c. d. e.
$.65 tax-exempt income rather than $1.00 taxable income. $1.50 taxable income rather than $1.00 tax-exempt income. $1.65 taxable income rather than $1.00 tax-exempt income. None of the above.
____ 16. A scholarship recipient at City University must include in gross income the scholarship proceeds used to pay for: a. Only tuition. b. Tuition, books, and supplies, but not meals and lodging. c. Books, supplies, meals, and lodging. d. Meals and lodging. e. None of the above. ____ 17. Roger, age 19, is a full-time graduate student at State College. During 2009, he received the following payments: State scholarship for ten months (tuition and books) $3,600 Loan from college financial aid office 1,500 Cash support from parents 3,000 Cash prize awarded in contest 500 $8,600 Roger served as a resident advisor in a dormitory and therefore the university waived the $2,400 charge for the room he occupied. What is Rogers adjusted gross income for 2009? a. $11,000. b. $4,100. c. $2,900. d. $500. e. None of the above. ____ 18. Barney, a full-time graduate student, receives a full tuition waiver ($5,500 during the year) and a monthly stipend for 9 months of $500 from State University for performing research for the university as a graduate assistant ($4,500 during the year). In addition, he receives a $2,000 research grant to pursue his own research and studies. Barneys gross income from the above is: a. $0. b. $4,500. c. $10,000. d. $12,000. e. None of the above. ____ 19. In 2009, Khalid was in an automobile accident and suffered physical injuries. The accident was caused by Rashads negligence. Khalid threatened to file a lawsuit against Amber Trucking Company, Rashads employer, claiming $50,000 for pain and suffering, $25,000 for loss of income, and $100,000 in punitive damages. Ambers insurance company will not pay punitive damages; therefore, Amber has offered to settle the case for $120,000 for pain and suffering, $25,000 for loss of income, and nothing for punitive damages. Khalid is in the 35% marginal tax bracket. What is the after-tax difference to Khalid between Khalids original claim and Ambers offer? a. Ambers offer is $30,000 less. ( $100,000 punitive damages + $70,000 increased and pain suffering.) b. Ambers offer is $10,500 less. [($30,000 .35) = $10,500]. c. Ambers offer is $19,500 less. [$30,000(1 .35) = $19,500]. d. Ambers offer is $5,000 more. [$70,000 (1 .35)($100,000) = $65,000]. e. None of the above.
____ 20. The First Chance Casino has gambling facilities, a bar, a restaurant, and a hotel. All employees are allowed to obtain food from the restaurant at no charge during working hours. In the case of the employees who operate the gambling facilities, bar, and restaurant, 60% of all of Casinos employees, the meals are provided for the convenience of the Casino. However, the hotel workers, demanded equal treatment and therefore were also allowed to eat in the restaurant at no charge while they are at work. Which of the following is correct? a. All the employees are required to include the value of the meals in their gross income. b. Only the restaurant employees may exclude the value of their meals from gross income. c. Only the employees who work in gambling, the bar, and the restaurant may exclude the meals from gross income. d. All of the employees may exclude the value of the meals from gross income. e. None of the above. ____ 21. Ridge is the manager of a motel. As a condition of his employment, Ridge is required to live in a room on the premises so that he would be there in case of emergencies. Ridge considered this a fringe benefit, since he would otherwise be required to pay $600 per month rent. The room that Ridge occupied normally rented for $60 per night, or $1,500 per month. On the average, 90% of the motel rooms were occupied. As a result of this rent-free use of a room, Ridge is required to include in gross income. a. $0. b. $600 per month. c. $1,500 per month. d. $1,350 ($1,500 .90 = $1,350). e. None of the above. ____ 22. Heather is a full-time employee of the Drake Company and participates in the companys flexible spending plan that is available to all employees. Which of the following is correct? a. Heather reduced her salary by $1,200, actually spent $1,500, and received only $1,200 as reimbursement for her medical expenses. Heathers gross income will be reduced by $1,500. b. Heather reduced her salary by $1,200, and received only $900 as reimbursement for her actual medical expenses. She is not refunded the $300 remaining balance, but her gross income is reduced by $1,200. c. Heather reduced her salary by $1,200, and received only $800 as reimbursement for her medical expenses. She is not refunded the $400. Her gross income is reduced by $800. d. Heather reduced her salary by $1,200, and received only $900 as reimbursement for her medical expenses. She forfeits the $300. Her gross income is reduced by $300. e. None of the above. ____ 23. Emily is in the 35% marginal tax bracket. She can purchase a York County school bond yielding 5% interest, but she is interested in earning a higher return for comparable risk. a. If she buys a corporate bond that pays 8% interest, her after-tax rate of return will be greater than if she purchased the York County school bond. b. If she buys a U.S. government bond paying 6%, her after-tax rate of return will be less than if she purchased the York County school bond. c. If she buys a common stock paying 6% dividend, her after-tax rate of return will be higher than if she purchased the York County school bond. d. All of the above are correct. e. None of the above are correct.
____ 24. Stuart owns 300 shares of Turquoise Corporation stock and 2,000 shares of Blue Corporation stock. During the year, Stuart received 150 shares of Turquoise as a result of a 1 for 2 stock split. The value of the shares received was $2,400. Stuart also received 100 shares of Blue Corporation stock as a result of a 5% stock dividend. Stuart did not have the option of receiving cash from Blue. The additional shares he received had a value of $3,600. Stuarts gross income from the receipt of the additional Turquoise and Blue shares is: a. $0. b. $2,400. c. $3,600. d. $6,000. e. None of the above. ____ 25. Trade and business expenses should be treated as: a. A deduction from AGI subject to the 2%-of-AGI floor. b. A deduction from AGI not subject to the 2%-of-AGI floor. c. Deductible for AGI. d. An itemized deduction if not reimbursed. e. None of the above.
____ 26. Janice is single, had gross income of $38,000, and incurred the following expenses: Charitable contribution Taxes and interest on home Legal fees incurred in a tax dispute Medical expenses Penalty on early withdrawal of savings Her AGI is: a. $21,300. b. $28,800. c. $32,800. d. $35,500. e. $37,800. ____ 27. Which of the following expenses is classified as a deduction for AGI? a. Alimony. b. Reimbursed employee business expense. c. Safe deposit box rental fee in which investment securities are stored. d. Only a. and b. e. a., b., and c. ____ 28. Benita incurred a business expense on December 10, 2009, which she charged on her bank credit card. She paid the credit card statement which included the charge on January 5, 2010. Which of the following is correct? a. If Benita is a cash method taxpayer, she cannot deduct the expense until 2010. b. If Benita is an accrual method taxpayer, she can deduct the expense in 2009. c. If Benita uses the accrual method, she can choose to deduct the expense in either 2009 or 2010. d. Only b. and c. are correct. e. a., b., and c. are correct. ____ 29. Angela, a real estate broker, had the following income and expenses in her business: Commissions income Expenses: Commissions paid to non-brokers for referrals (illegal under state law and subject to criminal penalties) Commissions paid to other real estate brokers for referrals (not illegal under state law) Travel and transportation Supplies Office and phone Parking tickets How much net income must Angela report from this business? a. $48,500. b. $49,000. c. $60,000. d. $68,500. e. $69,000. $100,000 $2,500 9,000 1,000 4,000 200
20,000 10,000 12,000 4,000 5,000 500
____ 30. Priscella pursued a hobby of making bedspreads in her spare time. Her AGI before considering the hobby is $40,000. During the year she sold the bedspreads for $10,000. She incurred expenses as follows: Supplies Interest on loan to get business started Advertising $4,000 500 6,500
Assuming that the activity is deemed a hobby, how should she report these items on her tax return? a. Include $10,000 in income and deduct $11,000 for AGI. b. Ignore both income and expenses since hobby losses are disallowed. c. Include $10,000 in income, deduct nothing for AGI, and claim $10,000 of the expenses as itemized deductions. d. Include $10,000 in income and deduct interest of $500 for AGI. e. None of the above. ____ 31. Cory incurred and paid the following expenses: Tax return preparation fee Moving expenses Investment expenses Expenses associated with rental property Interest expense associated with loan to finance tax-exempt bonds Calculate the amount that Cory can deduct (before any percentage limitations). a. $5,000. b. $4,600. c. $3,000. d. $1,500. e. None of the above. ____ 32. On January 2, 2009, Fran acquires a business from Chuck. Among the assets purchased are the following intangibles: patent with a 12-year remaining life, a covenant not to compete for 10 years, and goodwill. Of the purchase price, $120,000 was paid for the patent and $45,000 for the covenant. The amount of the excess of the purchase price over the identifiable assets was $90,000. What is the amount of the amortization deduction for 2009? a. $11,000. b. $17,000. c. $13,250. d. $18,500. e. None of the above. $ 600 2,000 500 1,500 400
Problems 33. Eva, single with a dependent child, had the following transactions during 2009: Salary Interest income on bonds Issued by City of Providence Issued by Dell Corporation Alimony received Child support received City and state income taxes paid Bank loan obtained to pay credit card debt a) What is Evas AGI for 2009? $80,000 $2,000 3,000
5,000 3,000 9,000 4,000 10,000
b) What is Evas federal income tax for 2009?
34. Robert, single with no dependents, had the following transactions for 2009: Salary Alimony paid Recovery from car accident Personal injury damages Punitive damages Gift from parents Property sales Loss on sale of camper (used for pleasure and owned 3 years) Gain on sale of Chevron stock (held for 8 months as an investment) a) What is Roberts AGI for 2009? $ 80,000 6,000 $60,000 30,000
90,000 26,000
($ 2,000) 3,000
1,000
b) What is Roberts federal income tax for 2009?
35. Amy incurs and pays the following expenses during the year: Alimony of $14,000 to her former spouse, Ted. Child support of $12,000 to Ted for the care of their son, Bobby. Medical expenses of $8,000 for herself. Charitable contributions of $3,000 to her church. Contribution to her traditional IRA of $5,000. Mortgage interest on her residence of $11,000. Property taxes on her residence of $1,200. State income taxes for herself of $4,000.
Amys only income is a $100,000 salary. Calculate Amys deductions for AGI and from AGI. 36. Kitty runs a brothel (illegal under state law) and has the following items of income and expense. What is the amount that she must include in taxable income from her operation? Income Expenses: Rent Utilities Bribes to police $200,000 8,000 2,000 10,000
Medical expense Legal fees Depreciation Illegal kickbacks
5,000 20,000 14,000 15,000 Find millions of documents on Course Hero - Study Guides, Lecture Notes, Reference Materials, Practice Exams and more.
 Course Hero has millions of course specific materials providing students with the best way to expand
 their education. 

Below is a small sample set of documents:

 ch01-flow_cl Hibbing CC - SUPCOM - 1 CNASSUPCOMEngineering of Engineering Telecommunication and Computer Networking ComputerMaster,SUPCOMF2006 1Summary1. 2. 3. 4. 5. 6. 7. 8.Traffic Control Error control Routing Multiple Access Control Traffic management Switching Signalling Transport ch02-error_cl Hibbing CC - SUPCOM - 1 CNASSupcomChapter IIError controlEngineering of Computer and telecommunication Engineering Networking NetworkingMaster MasterF 20061Summary Biterrors Packet and frame errors Packet insertion Packet detection Transmission control Control mechanis ch03-routing Hibbing CC - SUPCOM - 1 Chapter 3RoutingMaster,Supcom, F2004The ProblemProcess of finding a path from a source to a Process destination in the network destination Suppose That a customer wants to connect a Suppose the university server from his/her desktop while he/she is f ch04-mult_access Hibbing CC - SUPCOM - 1 Chapter 4:Multiple Access ControlSupcom Supcom Master F2006 MasterProblem StatementConsider an audioconference where if one person speaks, all can hear if more than one person speaks at the same time, both voices are garbled How should participants ch05-traffic_mgt Hibbing CC - SUPCOM - 1 Chapter 5Traffic managementMaster F2006An exampleA worldwide videoconference is organized. Different groups are participating. Proceedings are videotaped and stored in different archives Proceedings are edited and placed on web sites, which may be acc ch06-switching Hibbing CC - SUPCOM - 1 Chapter 6SwitchingMaster Supcom, Fall 2006What is it all aboutsHow do we move traffic from one part of the network to How another? another? Connect end-systems to switches, and switches to Connect each other each Data arriving to an input port of a s 1 Homework Bowling Green - ECON - 118 1.Refer to the above diagram. If society is currently producing 9 units of bicycles and 4 units of computers and it now decides to increase computer output to 6, the cost: A) will be 4 units of bicycles. B) will be 2 units of bicycles. C) will be zero be 1 Quiz Bowling Green - ECON - 118 1.TheoutputofMP3playersshouldbe: A)reducedifmarginalbenefitsexceedmarginalcosts. B)reducedifmarginalcostsexceedmarginalbenefits. C)increasedifmarginalcostsexceedmarginalbenefits. D)reducedtozeroiftheirunitcostsexceedtheunitcostsofalternativeproducts. 2.(L 012609%20Section%2003%20No%20Answer UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patrick Corpuz pcorpuz@ucsd.edu A01: Mon. 8-8:50 Center 207 01/26/09 OH: Fri. 8-8:50 Leichtag Lobby A04: Wed. 8-8:50 Center 220 WEEK 3 I. Neuromuscular Junction (NMJ) a. Receptors respond to _ =&gt;therefore referred to as _ i. Sensitive to nicotine =&gt;ther 020409 Section 04 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patrick Corpuz pcorpuz@ucsd.edu A01: Mon. 8-8:50 Center 207 02/04/09 OH: Fri. 8-8:50 Leichtag Lobby A04: Wed. 8-8:50 Center 220 WEEK 4 I. Sensory Receptors 1. Respond to particular sensations 2. Types of Receptors: i. Mechano 1. ion channels open under me 020909 Section 05 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patrick Corpuz pcorpuz@ucsd.edu A01: Mon. 8-8:50 Center 207 02/09/09 OH: Fri. 8-8:50 Leichtag Lobby A04: Wed. 8-8:50 Center 220 WEEK 5 I. Autonomic Neurotransmitters * Remember the autonomic division of the peripheral nervous system consists of pre-gangli 021809 Section 06 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patrick Corpuz pcorpuz@ucsd.edu A01: Mon. 8-8:50 Center 207 02/17/09 OH: Fri. 8-8:50 Leichtag Lobby A04: Wed. 8-8:50 Center 220 WEEK 6 I. Hormone Control Mechanisms 1. Neuronal reflex examples i. Mechano: oxytocin release during labor and suckling of nipp 022509 Section 07 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patrick Corpuz pcorpuz@ucsd.edu A01: Mon. 8-8:50 Center 207 02/23/09 OH: Fri. 8-8:50 Leichtag Lobby A04: Wed. 8-8:50 Center 220 WEEK 7 I. Muscle A. Skeletal muscle muscle usually attached to the bone via tendons and is responsible for movement of the skel BIPN100 Sheet 1 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday 11-1150AM Caf RomaB I P N 100: Handout 1 I. 3 TYPES OF D I F F US ION a. Simple Diffusion i . Diffuse directly across the phospholipids bilayer of cell ii. Lipid-soluble molecules pass 1. Examples a. _ iii. Ficks Law of Diffusion BIPN100 Sheet 1 Answers UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday 11-1150AM Caf RomaBIPN 100: Worksheet 1 I. 3 TYPES OF DIFFUSION a. Simple Diffusion i. Diffuse directly across the phospholipid bilayer of cell ii. Lipid-soluble molecules pass 1. Examples a. Gases (O2, CO2, NO), Hormones (Steroi BIPN100 Sheet 2 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday 11-11:50AM Caf Roma Handout 2 I. Graded vs. Action Potentials a. Graded Potentials i. How does the amplitude change with distance? _ ii. Is it proportional to stimulus? _ iii. Summation- 2 or more stimuli can be added together Tem BIPN100 Sheet 2 Answers0 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday 11-11:50AM Caf Roma Handout 2 I. Graded vs. Action Potentials a. Graded Potentials i. How does the amplitude change with distance? decays ii. Is it proportional to stimulus? yes iii. Summation- 2 or more stimuli can be added toget BIPN100 Sheet 3 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 PatriciaPepa OH:Friday111150AMCafRoma Handout3 I. 2Majortypesofpostsynapticreceptors a. Ionotropicreceptorthemselvesaretheionchannel b. Metabotropicactsthrough2ndmessengersystem i. _coupledreceptors 1. Offstate:GproteinhasG,G,andGsections.Gsectionis bound BIPN100 Sheet 3 Answers UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 PatriciaPepa OH:Friday111150AMCafRoma Handout3 2Majortypesofpostsynapticreceptors a. Ionotropicreceptorthemselvesaretheionchannel b. Metabotropicactsthrough2ndmessengersystem i. Gproteincoupledreceptors 1. Offstate:GproteinhasG,G,andGsections.Gsectionis b BIPN100 Sheet 4 answersss UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 H andout 4I. Sensory Receptors a. Mechanoreceptors -respond to mechanical stimulus i. Example-touch receptors in skin 1. Hair on arm-blow softly on arm, feel sensation b/c receptors at base. When hair moves, stimulates receptors ii. Also in muscles-respo BIPN100 Sheet 5 Answers UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Handout 5 w/ Answers I. Autonomic Nervous System Organs Sympathetic Fight or Flight Heart rate; contraction force (1) Why? Bring more O2 to tissues. Muscle Systemic arterioles Constricts or Dilates Why? Increase resistance for blood flow in certain areas BIPN100%20Handout%209 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday, Caf Roma 11-1150 Last Handout: Vasoconstriction/dilation, Capillary Exchange, Lymphatic System I. Arteriole Resistance a. R=8(length)(viscosity)/(r^4) b. Which part of the equation is the main cause of resistance change for resis BIPN100%20Sheet%201%20Answers UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday 11-1150AM Caf RomaBIPN 100: Worksheet 1 I. 3 TYPES OF DIFFUSION a. Simple Diffusion i. Diffuse directly across the phospholipid bilayer of cell ii. Lipid-soluble molecules pass 1. Examples a. Gases (O2, CO2, NO), Hormones (Steroi BIPN100%20Sheet%202%20Answers UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Friday 11-11:50AM Caf Roma Handout 2 I. Graded vs. Action Potentials a. Graded Potentials i. How does the amplitude change with distance? decays ii. Is it proportional to stimulus? yes iii. Summation- 2 or more stimuli can be added toget BIPN 100 Sheet 7 Answers0 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 PatriciaPepa OH:1111:50CafRoma Handout 7: Skeletal Muscles and Cardiac I. Skeletal Muscles a. A skeletal muscle is a collection of muscle fibers. b. Attached to bones via tendons or connective tissue c. Muscle Terminology 1. Muscle cell=muscle fiber 2. Ce BIPN%20HD%202%20master UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Minh Le m8le@ucsd.edu, OH M 11-11:50a; BIPN 100. Handout 2 More on Neuronsa. Schwann Cells- in Peripheral N.S., these cells myelinate a single axon by wrappingaround it and leaving space between each other. b. Oligodendrocytes- myelinate several axons, BIPN%20100%2c%20Wi09%2c%20Handout%20#1%20Answers%20Sheet0 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Jordan Sullivan Week 1, Winter 2009 BIPN 100 Section Friday 10:00am (Solis 109)HEY EVERYBODY HERES THE ANSWER SHEET FOR THIS PAST SECTIONS HANDOUT. HOPEFULLY YOU DID THE PROBLEMS THAT WE DIDNT FINISH ON YOUR OWN IF NOT THEN I RECOMMEND YOU DO THIS BEFORE BIPN%20100%20Handout%202_Wk3 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Handout 2 (Week 3) T.A. Marissa (Marlee) Caballes Section: Friday (9:00am - 9:50am) Solis 109 OH: (10:00am 11:00am) Old Student Center -I.II.Conduction is faster in myelinated axons (Figure 8-18) a. The myelin sheath creates a high resistance BIPN%20100%20Hd%201%20Student%20Version UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Minh Le, m8le@ucsd.edu BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes; Section: Thursday 7-7:50p Handout 1, Discussion 1 Diffusion: molecules have kinetic energy constantly moving; area of high concentration of molecules to area of low concentration of molecules. What are two facto BIPN%20100%20Hd%203 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Minh Le, m8le@ucsd.edu; BIPN 100 OH: 11-11:50a Mondays, Caf Roma Handout 3 Summation: - Temporal G.P. close enough together in time so APs could add up and pass threshold - Spatial G.P. from pre-synaptic cell, but not sufficient for depolarization. But if BIPN%20100%20Hd%204 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Minh Le, m8le@ucsd.edu; BIPN 100 OH: 11-11:50a Mon. @ Caf Roma Hand Out 4Sensory Receptors 1) Special Senses: sensory stimuli reaching the conscious level of perception - Vision, taste, smell, hearing, equilibrium/ posture - Sensory neurons project into BIPN%20100%20Midterm%201%20Review%20Session%20Outline UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN Midterm 1 Review Session Outline I. Post-synaptic events a. Two types of receptors: Ionotrophic vs. metabotrophic a. Ionotrophic: ligand gated ion channels i. Ion channel Receptor elicits a fast synaptic potential because it is quick and it lasts a s BIPN%20100%20Sheet%207%20Student%20Version0 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: 11-11:50 Caf Roma Handout 7: Skeletal Muscles and Cardiac I. Skeletal Muscles a. A skeletal muscle is a collection of muscle fibers. b. Attached to bones via tendons or connective tissue c. Muscle Terminology 1. Muscle cell=muscle fiber BIPN%20100%20Sheet%208 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Patricia Pepa OH: Caf Roma Friday 11-1150AM Handout 8: Heart, Heart, Heart I. Draw a P-V curve of the Left Ventricle of the heart and label all of the following: Stroke volume Where the mitral and aortic valves open and close. EDV, ESV, preload, afterload notes UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Axons carry outgoing signals to the target Axons are for chemical and electrical signals - cytoplasm is filled w/ many types of fibers and filaments but lacks ribosomes and endoplasmic reticulum o proteins must first be synthesized on rough endoplasmic re Practice%20Midterm%201%20Questions0 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Midterm 1 Practice Questions Part 1 1) At what membrane potential would prevent Na+ influx if the extracellular concentration is 100 mM and the intracellular concentration is 10 m M? (assuming Na-channels are open)?2) What would happen to the resting mem Practice%20Midterm%201%20Questions%20Answers UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Midterm 1 Practice Questions Part 1 1) At what membrane potential would prevent Na+ influx if the extracellular concentration is 100 mM and the intracellular concentration is 10 mM? (assuming Na-channels are open)? 58mV 2) What would happen to the resting Sensory Pathways Notes UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 SensoryPathwaysBookNotes Transducer:convertsstimulusintointracellularsignal,changeinmembranepotential Ifabovethreshold,APpassessensoryneurontoCNSallincomingsignalsare itnegrated Senseorgans:earandeye Somatosensoryreceptors:somaticsenses:consistofneuronw/n week3handoutanswerscorrections UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 TA: Eric Apaydin BIPN 100 Section: Thurs. 5-550, 6-650; Center 203 OH: Mon. 11, Weds. 1, Mandeville Coffee Cart BIPN 100 Week 3 (Lectures 1/16&amp;1/21) I. AP Conduction Larger axons conduct current well (they have a larger cross-sectional area and thus les week%201%20student%20version UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 sections: Tuesday 6-6:50pm Center 220&amp;Tuesday 7-7:50pm WLH 2113 TA: Jean Du email: jdu@ucsd.edu OH: Week 1 I. Diffusion molecules move due to thermal energy movement increases if _ channels aquaporin _-ion channels o select for a particular t Week%202%20-Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 1 January 5th Diffusion&amp;Transport Pathways Lecture 2 January 7th Na+/K+ ATPase Ion Concentrations Ohms Law Ficks Equation Nernst EquationChris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 3 - January 9th Nernst Cont Goldman-Hodgkin-Katz Membr Week%203%20-%20Student%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 B IPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 4 January 12th Graded Potentials Action Potentials Hodgkin&amp;Huxley Lecture 5 January 14th Action Potential Mechanism&amp;Gating Refractory Periods Action potential conductionChris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 6 - January 16 th M Week%203%20-%20Teacher UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 4 January 12th Graded Potentials Action Potentials Hodgkin&amp;Huxley Lecture 5 January 14th Action Potential Mechanism&amp;Gating Refractory Periods Action potential conductionChris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 6 - January 16th Mye week%203%20student%20version UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 sections: Tuesday 6-6:50pm Center 220&amp;Tuesday 7-7:50pm WLH 2113 TA: Jean Du email: jdu@ucsd.edu OH: Fri 2-3pm, outside of Sierra Summit Week 3 I. Transmission of Information from Neurons to Other Cells Neurotransmitters and neuromodulators (bot Week%204%20-%20Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 B IPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 7 January 21stChris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 8 January 23rdLecture 9 - January 26thLecture 10 - January 28 th Cerebral Cortex Phinease Gage Motor&amp;Sensory units Lateralization Language association areasIonotropic vs. Week%205%20-%20Teacher%20Edition0 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 11 February 2nd Sensory Receptors Tonic vs. Phasic Fine touch vs. pain receptors Rubbing a wound - Why does it feel good?Chris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 12 February 4th Sympathetic vs. Paraympathetic Nervous Systems Pre-gangl Week%206%20-%20Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 13 February 6th Reflexes mono and polysynaptic Muscle spindle and golgi tendon reflexes Lecture 14 February 9th Hormone categories Hormone receptors extracellular and intracellular G Protein Coupled Signal TransductionChris Ch Week%207%20-%20Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 B IPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 16 Prolactin + Prolactin Tumors Growth Hormone + Excess / Deficiency Muscle Anatomy&amp;HistologyChris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 17 Muscle Contraction Cytoplasmic Events (Ca2+, SR, Troponin Etc.) Summation, Tetanus Metabolic D Week%208%20-%20Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 18 February 20th Smooth Muscle Contraction Cardiovascular Anatomy Cardiac Muscle Contraction Cardiac Muscle Action Potential Smooth Muscle:Chris Childers Winter 09 Lecture 19 - February 23rd Autorhytmic Cells&amp;Pacemaker Poten Week%209%20-%20Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 20 February 25th ECG Cont Mechanical Events of Cardiac Cycle Wiggers Diagram Cardiac Output Starling Effect Lecture 21 March 2nd Starling Curve / Law of the Heart Venous Return Autonomic Regulation Poiseuilles LawChris Childer Week%2010%20-%20Teacher%20Edition UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 BIPN 100 Dr. Fortes Lecture 23 March 6th ADH Natriuretic Peptides RAAS System Hypertension drugs Venous Valves Capillary Exchange Lecture 24 March 9th Lymphatic System Homeostatic Functions Nephron Anatomy&amp;Histology Glomerular FiltrationChris Childers Weeks 1 and 2 Notes UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Diffussion, Ion Pumps Resting Potentials: Graded and Action Potentials I. Diffusion Exchange between intracellular and extracellular compartments is restricted by cell membrane. Selectively permeable: lipid and protein composition of cell membrane determi 7 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Special Seminars(see chem dept website for more info)Special Seminar Tuesday, February 02 4:00 PM Health Sciences Auditorium Professor Elizabeth Blackburn, Nobel Laureate Univerrsity of California, San Francisco Title: Telomeres and Telomerase in Health 8 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Molecular Techniques II Electrophoresis PCR SequencingElectrophoresis Separation of charged molecules based on migration in an electric field. Separation depends on: Electric force Mass and shape of molecule Matrix Separations are performed usually in 9 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Mobile DNA - transposable elements Discovery of transposons Transposable elements DNA transposons Retrotransposons viral-like (LTRs) poly-A (non-LTRs) ! LINES ! SINES Roles in evolutionTransposable elements (TEs) - non-functional DNA? TEs - long stretch 10 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Organelle DNAs -origin of organelles -mitochondrial DNA -chloroplast DNAEndosymbiotic origin of organellesOver evolutionary time, most of the bacterial genes were lost form organellar DNAs - some lost because their functions were provided by genes in ho 11 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Eukaryotic gene regulation Transcriptional control RNA Pol activity requires multiple subunits RNAP carboxy-terminaldomain (CTD) Control elements Reporter genes Txn activatorsEukaryotic gene regulation Transcriptional control : Gene expression in eukaryo 11.2 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 12 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Eukaryotic chromosome organization Chromatin - condensed / open Nucleosome structure Histones heterochromatin&amp;euchromatinPacking of DNA is crucial must prevent knotting or tangling of long DNA molecules must also permit specific DNA sequences to be ava 12.2 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Higher eukaryotes express proteins with domains (chromodomains) that bind to histone tails that are methylated at specific lysines Example: heterochromatin protein 1 (HP1) Many of these proteins also contain a second domain called a chromoshadow domain th 13 UCSD - BIMM - BIMM 100 Review: Transcription of protein coding genes:Review: Transcription of protein coding genes:mRNA-like strandReview: Transcription of protein coding genes: 1. Initiation 2. Elongation 3. TerminationReview: Maturation of mRNA : Pre-mRNA 5 capping 3 Poly 
Flashcards
 
 CPA REG 3 Term Definition offers, rejections,... received Types of endorsements -Blank... does a disclaimer of... no when are punitive... for fraud     
 
 Individual Income Tax - Part Term Definition 100,000 Investments: 5,70011,4008,350 65; $1,100,... Qualifying Relative... , seminars,... Investments:     
 
 Individual Income Tax - Part 2 Term Definition kiddie; Estate tax; 50; greater;... personal home; sudden and... greater; $5000; 50%; __________...     
 
 CFP Exam Prep Cards - Section 5 - Income Tax... Term Definition The Internal Revenue... the main... Taxpayer Relief Act... includes... The process of tax... 1) House... Treasury regulations... -the...     
 
 CFP Tax Planning - 2008 Term Definition What type of... dividends... Adjustments to... -the penalty... Taxpayers are allowed... $2,500 and... For single... $53,000 and...     
 
 Sitemap Tutors Educational Concepts Textbooks Blog Study Skills 
 Course Hero is not sponsored or endorsed by any college or university.
Copyright©2012. Course Hero, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
