<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004538" url="http://www.wikinvest.com/industry/Fast_Food_Restaurants_(QSR)" time="2012-07-12-20:57" support="33" score="0.1626945618757312" bingtitle="Industry:Fast Food Restaurants (QSR) - See your portfolio in a ..." webtitle="Industry:Fast Food Restaurants (QSR)">
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001490" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000110" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000890" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001018" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>Pershing Square Capital founder Bill Ackman appeared on CNBC and gave his ... After labor, food and beverage inputs are the single largest cost facing fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		New! Portfolio     Login / Sign Up Search 
 
 Industries 
 
 Technology Energy Media Finance Green Issues China All Concepts 
 
 Metals Energy Meats Grains Softs 
 
 ETFs Indices 
 
 Currencies Geographies Exchanges Rates 
 
 How To Invest Personal Finance Options 101 Definitions 
 
 
     

 close close close close 
 Send us Feedback 
 
Fast Food Restaurants (QSR)
 
 
 Neutral Bulls Bears Data 
 RECENT NEWS Oops! Unable to complete your request. Please refresh your browser. See more recent news Dickey&apos;s Barbecue Named 2012 Best Franchise Deal PR Newswire   2 hrs ago   Comment  
 DALLAS, July 12, 2012 /PRNewswire/ -- Dickey&apos;s Barbecue has always been known for big portions at reasonable prices and now owning a Dickey&apos;s franchise has never been a better deal. QSR Magazine recognized Dickey&apos;s Barbecue as a 2012 Best Franchise RANKED: The Most Popular Fast Food Restaurants In America Clusterstock   5 hrs ago   Comment  
 Americans love fast food.


The top 15 fast food chains in the nation raked in a combined $115 billion in sales last year, and their 105,000 total stores blanket the landscape.


We asked food industry research firm Technomic to put together a... Chip-hungry Olympic workers celebrate freedom from McDonald&apos;s monopoly guardian.co.uk   Jul 11   Comment  
 Staff working on opening and closing ceremonies allowed to eat chips served outside branches of fast food chain

The great London 2012 Olympic chip embargo has cracked. No longer will hungry workers at the games be denied pie and chips, chicken... &apos;End fast food Olympics links&apos; BBC News   Jul 11   Comment  
 Fast food and alcohol brands sponsorship of sporting events such as the Olympics is called into question by Wales&apos; chief medical officer. &apos;The Infographics Show&apos; Tackles Fast Food Forbes   Jul 10   Comment  
 Those who visit McDonalds at least ten times a month make up for more than 75 percent of sales.  People in the Congo ingest 1606 of calories a day, while people in Argentina eat 2959 calories.  248,000 Americans die prematurely due to obesity. VIDEO: Call to ban junk food Olympic sponsorship BBC News   Jul 10   Comment  
 London cardiologist Dr Aseem Malhotra believes we need to end the relationship between fast food company sponsorship and sport to save lives. Machete wielding thieves target take out joints Sydney Morning Herald   Jul 9   Comment  
 Two men attempted to rob two fast food outlets last night but walked away with nothing.

 Use of these RSS feeds and headlines is governed by our terms of use.
 Enquire about licensing these feeds here. Here On Biz: Real-Time Networking For Execs Forbes   Jul 6   Comment  
 Wouldn?t it be great if the next time you were stranded in an airport because your flight was delayed, you could actually spend your time at the bar with other like-minded professionals? A business trip would take on a whole new life -- from... Maccas in Mt Lawley: I&apos;m lovin&apos; it? Sydney Morning Herald   Jul 6   Comment  
 A poster claiming fast food restaurant McDonald&apos;s will open at a prominent Mt Lawley location has caused a flutter of concern this morning. Health Toll of Fast Food Spreads Eastward (CME/CE) MedPage Today   Jul 3   Comment  
 (MedPage Today) -- Eating Western-style fast food on a regular basis significantly increased the risk of diabetes and coronary heart disease in a large Asian cohort, investigators reported. Oops! Unable to complete your request. Please refresh your browser. See earlier news Suggest other news sources for this topic 
 Topic 
 

 Top news source/blog that we&apos;re missing 
 

 Why do you recommend this news source? 
 
 
 
Contents
 
 1 Spice and Favorings 2 Trends&amp;Forces 
 2.1 U.S. Spending Slowdown Negatively Impacts Fast Food Sales 2.2 Growing Global Middle Class and International Expansion are a Recipe for Profit 2.3 Health and Wellness Concerns are Bad for Fast Food 2.4 Fast Casual Restaurants are Growing Threat 
 3 References 
 
 RELATED WIKI ARTICLES 
Related Articles

 Yum! Brands (YUM) Commodities Triarc Companies (TRY) Investing in India Investing in China 
 more▼ 
 Industry Discussion History Bookmark Print 
 WIKI ANALYSIS   TOP CONTRIBUTORS Vincent McPhillip 
Fast food restaurants represent one of the largest segments of the food industry with over 200,000 restaurants and $120B in sales in the U.S. alone [1] . Fast food restaurants, also known as quick service restaurants (QSR) and regional players like Jack In The Box and Sonic .

Since late 2006, the fast food industry&apos;s growth has been slowed by soaring food and energy prices. [2] The high prices of commodities , combined with the housing slump [3] and a weakening job market [4] are taking a toll on restaurant spending in the U.S. (the world&apos;s largest fast food market, by far [5] ). The same food and energy inflation that is corroding consumer spending is also taking a bite out of company margins.

Fast food restaurants have navigated this difficult landscape with varying levels of success. International players such as McDonald&apos;s (MCD) and Yum! Brands (YUM) have had the most success as explosive growth in [[Emerging Markets|emergvation to boost growth and profitability.



 
 Spice and Favorings 

 McCormick&amp;Company (MKC) 
 
 Trends&amp;Forces 
 
 U.S. Spending Slowdown Negatively Impacts Fast Food Sales 

The U.S. accounts for the lion&apos;s share of fast food spending globally. Since the first half of 2007, several forces have put consumer spending in this critical market under intense pressure. The first of these is a plummeting housing market (especially in the overbuilt areas of Southern California, Nevada and Florida) which produces a negative wealth effect among consumers, discouraging spending. Second, rising food and energy prices have raised inflation to multi-decade highs- outpacing wage gains and shrinking spending power. Finally, the U.S. job market has deteriorated; in the first six months of 2008, the economy has shed 485,000 private sector jobs, while many have seen job hours reduced [6] . Although some industry players, such as McDonald&apos;s , have seen continued same store sales growth as consumers trade down to less costly food alternatives, overall the sector has struggled. According to the National Association of Restaurants, 55% of restaurant operators reported a same-store sales decline in March 2008 compared to just 28% who reported increases [7] 

 italic text ===Rising Food Prices Pressure Fast Food Margins===
 Historical and USDA forecasted Corn prices per bushel Wheat prices have since risen more dramatically- Data from USDA 
Several factors have contributed to a dramatic rise in food prices in recent years, including higher oil and energy prices; the growing global demand from rapidly developing economies such as China and India; a weak U.S. dollar; and a larger share of the grain market being diverted to ethanol production [8] . These trends have led to the rapidly rising prices of commodities such as corn and wheat (see graphs at right).

After labor, food and beverage inputs are the single largest cost facing fast food restaurant operators, accounting for 33 cents for every dollar of sales [9] . Because operating margins are already relatively low compared to other industries (typically in the single digits) a slight increase in these costs can have an outsized effect on profitability. For over a year now, wholesale food price inflation has been rising at multi-decade highs. In 2007, wholesale food prices rose 7.6%; as of March 2008 that number had increased to 8.5% on a year over year basis [10] . At the same time, intense competition limits the ability of fast food operators to pass along rising costs to customers. Increased costs have had a noticeable effect on fast food company earnings with operators such as Domino&apos;s , Wendy&apos;s and Jack In The Box have all reported consistent quarterly declines in operating margins since the second half of 2007.

Because franchisers capture a portion of revenue rather than profits, smaller fast food chains that have a lower portion of their restaurants franchised are most vulnerable to cost increases. Jack In The Box , Wendy&apos;s , and Sonic have particularly low franchised to owned restaurant rations.
 
 Growing Global Middle Class and International Expansion are a Recipe for Profit 

Fast food companies with exposure to international markets have most successfully overcome the twin hurdles of high prices and an anemic North American market. Yum! Brands and McDonald’s , with 50% and 60% of sales overseas respectively, are the best examples of the benefits of an international presence. Both companies have posted consistent same store sales growth driven by double digit gains overseas. Rising overseas sales are underpinned by strong economic growth in emerging markets like China , India , Russia , Latin America and Eastern Europe. As more people across the globe join the middle class many are enjoying the promise of a better diet.
 
 Health and Wellness Concerns are Bad for Fast Food 

Higher rates of heart disease, increases in the incidence of cancer, record numbers of clinically obese people, and various other health scares have all drawn attention to the need for healthy lifestyle choices. Rising concerns for ‘’ health and wellness ’’ are bad news for fast food which is generally perceived as fattening and unhealthy. Many QSRs have responded to this negative press by adding new, healthier offerings to their menus. Since the beginning of the decade many companies have also responded by removing trans-fats and other unhealthy ingredients from their offerings. Despite these efforts, fast food restaurants retain an unhealthy stigma
 
 Fast Casual Restaurants are Growing Threat 

Fast casual restaurants are a growing source of competition for the fast food industry. Fast casual restaurants like Chipotle , Cosi and Panera combine the convenience of fast food restaurants with the quality of casual dining. This new alternative to fast food and sit down restaurants threatens to steal market share from both. Still the fast food restaurant stands to benefit from a U.S. consumer slowdown as strapped consumers trade down from more costly fast casual restaurants.
 
 References 

 ↑ Hoover&apos;s Fast Food and Quickservice Restaurant Report ↑ The Boston Globe- Surging costs of groceries hit home ↑ Bloomberg Case-Shiller Index Falls ↑ NYTimes Unemployment Rising ↑ Bitter taste: Food costs, less consumer spending hurting restaurants ↑ New York Times- Uncomfortable Answers to Questions on the Economy ↑ How Spiking Food Prices Impact Restaurants ↑ How Spiking Food Prices Impact Restaurants ↑ How Spiking Food Prices Impact Restaurants ↑ How Spiking Food Prices Impact Restaurants 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.wikinvest.com/industry/Fast_Food_Restaurants_(QSR) &quot; 
Companies in the Fast Food Restaurants (QSR) Industry (21)

 
 A AFC Enterprises 

 B Brazil Fast Food Corp. Buffalo Wild Wings Burger King Holdings 

 C CKE Restaurants Caribou Coffee Company Chipotle Mexican Grill Cosi 

 D Denny&apos;s 
 
 G Good Times Restaurants 

 J Jack In The Box 

 K Krispy Kreme Doughnuts 

 L Luby&apos;s 

 M MTY Food Group McDonald&apos;s Corporation 

 N Nathan&apos;s Famous 
 
 P Papa John&apos;s International Pizza Inn 

 R Rubio&apos;s Restaurants 

 S Sonic 

 W Wendy&apos;s International 
 
 
 Categories : Mature | Food&amp;Beverage | WikiData Seeded 
 Bet you&apos;ve never seen portfolio analytics like these. Introducing SigFig—from the creators of Take Tour 
 
 
 
 Wikinvest©2006, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012. Use of this site is subject to express Terms of Service , Privacy Policy , and Disclaimer . By continuing past this page, you agree to abide by these terms. Any information provided by Wikinvest, including but not limited to company data, competitors, business analysis, market share, sales revenues and other operating metrics, earnings call analysis, conference call transcripts, industry information, or price targets should not be construed as research, trading tips or recommendations, or investment advice and is provided with no warrants as to its accuracy. Stock market data, including US and International equity symbols, stock quotes, share prices, earnings ratios, and other fundamental data is provided by data partners. Stock market quotes delayed at least 15 minutes for NASDAQ, 20 mins for NYSE and AMEX. Market data by Xignite . See data providers for more details. Company names, products, services and branding cited herein may be trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective owners. The use of trademarks or service marks of another is not a representation that the other is affiliated with, sponsors, is sponsored by, endorses, or is endorsed by Wikinvest. About | Blog | Press | Feedback | Help | Get involved Mobile | Advertise | Licensing&amp;Partnerships | Blogger Tools | Jobs
	</body>
</document>
