<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004327" url="http://www.touchdynamic.com/partners.aspx" time="2012-07-12-20:34" support="4" score="0.0032897596372204268" bingtitle="Touch Dynamic-Software Partners" webtitle="Touch Dynamic-Software Partners">
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>Store Manager is the award-winning Windows version ... of Sale Software for Retail, QSR, Fast Food Restaurant ... Validation of employee leave and other benefits ...</description>
	<body>
		888.508.6824 | Contact Sales | Software Partners | TD en español 
 
 HOME ABOUT US PRODUCTS 
 Products Flyer All In One Systems 
 Breeze Performance AIO Breeze AIO CS200 AIO Saturn AIO Pulse AIO 
 PC Product Line 
 Galaxy PC Saturn Atom PC Jupiter PC Orion Performance 
 Mobile POS 
 WF35 Mobile POS WF43 Mobile POS 
 Photo Kiosk 
 PK7000 
 Panel PC 
 QS300 QK Panel PC Series 
 Touch Screen LCD&apos;s 
 Breeze Touch Monitor 
 Printers 
 TP20 Mobile Printer Printer TP3000 Printer TB-650 Printer PR IM 
 Cash Drawers Discontinued Products 
 Global PC Apollo PC Saturn PC PLUS 15&quot;Touch Screen LCD 17&quot;Touch Screen LCD Orion PC FS100 CobraPOS 370 CobraPOS 478 Stinger Printer TB-700 Printer TP2000 15&quot;Pyramid Touch Screen LCD 
 
 RESOURCES 
 Drivers Spec Sheets Pictures Manuals Touch Dynamic MAPP 
 SUPPORT 
 Tech Support RMA Request Image Submission Remote Assistance FAQ 
 Touch Dynamic Restore to Original Factory Settings Breeze LCD Replacement Inst. Cobra FAQ Compact Flash Processing Tekserve Warranty SSHD Windows Server 2008 WF35 MOBILE POS FAQ 
 Sales Info Knowledge Base Configuration Tool Video Tutorials 
 NEWS CONTACT US 

 
Touch Dynamic Software Partners

 
 ABS Point of Sale Inc. specializes in the development of user friendly, visually enhanced and intelligent point of sales solutions. Its flagship software, WinRest Restaurant Management Software has revolutionized the hospitality industry. Built on Microsoft .NET technology, WinRest utilizes the industry&apos;s newest and most advanced software architecture and is wide in scope, managing anything from a small café to a nationwide restaurant chain. ABS Point of Sale Inc. has over 10,000 installations and an established re-seller network across North America, Europe, Asia and the Middle East. For more information on WinRest you may visit www.abspos.com Aldelo for Restaurant is the 
 Restaurant POS solution for all types of food service establishments.
This point of sale solution was designed to serve small to medium sized 
 restaurants, including fine dining establishments and franchise stores.
Aldelo for Restaurants is an easy to use, flexible and affordable software. It 
 is 100% multi-lingual and 100% Windows based. Your staff training will be 
 significantly simplified with our intuitive touch screen user interface. Alliance POS is a Windows based touch screen 
 restaurant management system, operating on the best hardware platforms in the 
 industry. ALLIANCE was developed by CYPLEX, Inc. (serving Southern California 
 and the U.S. dealer channel since 1983) and has been installed for over 10 
 years in various concept environments including quick service, drive through, 
 dispatch and delivery, family dining, fine dining, and high activity club 
 service. The ALLIANCE POS interface can be designed by the user to satisfy 
 color schemes, button shapes and sizes, screen interactivity, forced pop-up 
 screens, timed menus, logon by employee code, customer order history, and more. 
 ALLIANCE POS offers complex menu control - from maximum pizza pricing 
 strategies to multiple revenue center control and profit contribution 
 calculations. The ALLIANCE POS system was designed to provide speed, 
 flexibility, and ease of use together with thorough and complete system and 
 operator reporting. ALLIANCE offers Internet Reporting, an internal Gift Card 
 control center, integrated credit card processing, database search capability, 
 and much more. Phone#: 800-4CYPLEX (429-7539) StoreTender™ was developed by Aloha Data Systems for the Grocery, Liquor, C-Store markets. It’s compatible with just about any PC based 32 or 64 bit systems (XP or greater) and utilizes an SQL database for speed and reliability. With your OPOS for .Net compatible equipment and StoreTender; you’ll have the best possible solution for years to come and at a reasonable price. If you’ve been looking for a dependable, fast and affordable POS solution for these industries, you don’t need to look any further. And even better, StoreTender is about as full featured as you’d find on systems costing thousands more. Gas Pump interface for the C-Store industry releasing in the 1st quarter of 2011! ASI/Restaurant Manager POS System Designed, tested and proven in today&apos;s real-world restaurant environment, the Restaurant Manager POS System was created to fit the way you do business, not vice versa. With solutions for every type of restaurant business, from pizza delivery and quick service to fine dining and bars or clubs, Restaurant Manager goes beyond technology to focus on real business impacts and benefits that provide true ROI. BigEMouth Traditional retail business know they need to market to their customers and prospects by email but often find the collection and management of the email address list too laborious a task. BigEMouth.com solves that problem with simple and free kiosk based data collection software. In just minutes you can be collecting any information you want from your customers automatically! Biztracker is a leading developer of Retail 
 POS Software. We offer a complete suite of low cost solutions that will help 
 improve your customer’s business processes and improve their return on 
 investment.
Our services include:

 Uses a touch screen to speed transactions Customer tracking, Customer purchase history, Accounts receivable, Purchasing, 
 Barcode printing, E-Mail advertising, Direct mail Integrate sales information with accounting programs like QuickBooks, 
 Peachtree, Blackbaud, Great Plains and others Track work orders, quotes, backorders, gift cards and layaways Connect E-commerce shopping carts from third parties Electronic signage for customer rear displays standard Wireless windows mobiles assistance® handheld devices for receiving, customer 
 orders, purchasing, and inventory control Remote synchronizer allow off-site sales and ordering using a laptop, great for 
 tradeshows, route sales Powerful enterprise SQL multi-store software for complete control of remote 
 stores 
 BmssPOS is a Heavily Integrated, Very Flexible point of sale Application running on Windows Based Platforms.
Purchase orders, Remote poll, Kitchen video and printers, customer VGA screen,CC integration and more are free. Video surveilance with text optional. And BmssPos just received PA-DSS Certification which will be mandatory as of 7-1-2010 if you process Credit Cards.
The user interface is VB6 and the Database is SQLexpress2005.
BmssPos has been in the &quot;Register&quot; business since 1981 and POS since it&apos;s inception.
We started our development company in Y2K and on 3-1-2010 we released V4.2.3 &quot;BmssPos Retail Appliance&quot; which is an imaged platform and ships ready to use. (vitually no settings). Camaleon POS is a bi-lingual (English/Spanish) Windows based point of sales system for small businesses including restaurants, bars, grocery stores and more. Camaleon POS is innovative, versatile and international, used in Peru,Chile, Mexico, Japan and all over the United States. The Camaleon POS interface can be designed by the user to satisfy all the needs. Camaleon POS is tailored for every individual business in order to match perfectly. Camaleon POS features versatility, profitability, accuracy, efficiency, reporting, inventory analysis, secure data bases, inter-communication and customer support that rivals all competitors. Camaleon POS works along with Camaleon Services to provide the best customer support in the business. Call Camaleon POS at 1(800) 571 8370 CAP Software is the original retail Point-of-Sale and inventory control software system. Since 1978 we have been developing solid, stable POS software products based on the features required for real world retail businesses. CAP is an ideal fit for liquor stores, gift shops, boutiques and apparel stores, hardware and home good, lawn and garden, sporting goods stores, and many other store types. We know how important quality and consistency are to businesses, so we make it our primary goal to provide a reliable product. We were the first retail software package and we want to be the last one that you will ever need. Celerant Technologies 
Celerant&apos;s Retail Management system is the most flexible, powerful, and 
 advanced tool available to retailers who need to maintain a precisely managed 
 operation at store level through price-optimization, customer satisfaction, 
 employee management, and tight inventory-control. Celerant&apos;s POS sales are done 
 in real-time and are available at once throughout the enterprise.
Our services include:

 Point of sale Inventory management Employee management Customer relationship management Allocation/Distribution Integrated gift cards E-Commerce Admin/Reporting Open to buy 
 ConnectBeauty is a web-based (SaaS) POS software system built specifically for salons, spas, beauty schools and corporations around the world. Based on Microsoft technology, ConnectBeauty offers an intuitive user interface, with all of the nuances of the beauty industry sales processes built in. Online appointment booking, e-commerce and marketing campaigns are just a few of the features that enhance ConnectBeauty’s POS offering. Reseller inquiries are welcome. Diamond Scan is a Windows 95, 98, and NT 
 Compatible Point of Sale Software for Touch Screen Computer Systems.
Our services include:

 Optional fuel maintenance True windows environment Eliminate pricing&amp;clerk error Loaded with features&amp;functions Increase customer satisfaction Save on labor Year 2000 compliant 
 Diamond Touch is a leader in computerized 
 restaurant management systems, specializing in Pizza POS computer systems. 
 Because we focus exclusively on pizza, we have the experience necessary to 
 computerize your operation. Whether you are part of a large national chain or 
 an independent restaurant, we can custom tailor a pizza point-of-sale system to 
 fit your business and your budget. Digital Dining was originally developed and 
 installed in Australia in 1978. The product was introduced in the United States 
 in 1984 and the Virginia Corporation, Menusoft, was formed. Today Menusoft is 
 both recognized as a pioneer in the hospitality point-of-sale (POS) market and 
 as an innovator with regards to functionality and features. Digital Dining is 
 now in its 23rd year of production and development and has been installed at 
 more than 30,000 sites throughout North America. From quick service to table 
 service and everything in between, Menusoft’s software can be configured to 
 meet any environment using the same application and the same corporate 
 database. Menusoft continues to grow and develop the software, each year adding 
 more and more features and capabilities. Dinerware 2.7 is a revolutionary restaurant 
 touch screen system designed for independent restaurants. The latest technology 
 and easy user interface adds unprecedented work flow enhancement, and helps 
 increase business by allowing complete access to information - open data - and 
 a database that tracks customer history. Dinerware is the first intuitive 
 system available to the restaurant industry that allows customers to be in 
 control of their software without depending on expensive maintenance and 
 service contracts. DirecTouch Point of Sale has emerged as the 
 industry leader in “Do It Yourself” point of sale systems for restaurants. Our 
 software is easy to install, perfect for the first time user or a great 
 replacement for existing systems by using the hardware already in place. Visit 
 our main site at DirecTouch for more information and a free trial. Focus POS Systems creates point of sale 
 solutions for the restaurant and hospitality industries. This includes table 
 service, fine dining, delivery, counter service, cafeterias, bars, night clubs, 
 gentleman&apos;s clubs, fast food and drive thru. With over 20 years of POS 
 development experience and thousands of installations worldwide, Focus POS 
 Systems brings a rich heritage of delivering innovative software technology to 
 the hospitality industry. For more information please visit: Focus POS Future POS sell software and hardware to the 
 hospitality marketplace. The main difference between Future POS and all the 
 &quot;other companies&quot; is that we include everything you might need to effectively 
 run your restaurant--POS, timekeeping, employee scheduling, gift card tracking, 
 frequent diner, and much more. While others charge for these modules, we 
 include everything you need. InadwareSoft “Empresa dedicada al desarrollo de software administrativo empaquetado para el sector comercio y el sector salud.
Nuestro software punto de venta es Ideal para negocios de los giros de: Abarrotes, Ferreterías, Farmacias, Ropa, Zapaterías, Tlapalerías, Minisupers, Licorerías, , Papelerías, Línea blanca, Celulares, etc. Contamos también con Software para Control de Laboratorios de Análisis Clínicos el cuál está diseñado para automatizar los procesos administrativos y apoyar las operaciones del Laboratorio Clínico para una completa gestión de su Laboratorio” IKEY Mobile Software We Offer a full line of Data Collection Modules from Inventory Control, Asset Management, Sales, Route Sales, Line Busting and Purchasing&amp;Receiving Extend your current point of sale system to mobile devices
 IKEYMobile Software provides you with a complete, end-to-end solution for your data collection needs. We integrate to point of sale systems. We also have stand alone solutions.
 Inventory Control Sales Purchasing Line Busting Route Sales 
 Since 1986, InfoTouch Corporation has been the 
 recognized leader in providing touch screen POS software to Specialty 
 Retailers. Today, the InfoTouch product line has grown into a complete suite of 
 products that is meeting the ever increasing needs of independent retailers or 
 managing the complex requirements and operations of a multi store retail 
 operation. Store Manager is the award-winning Windows version of our touch 
 screen POS software. Store Manager puts a graphical user interface around the 
 most comprehensive POS software available. This native 32 bit Windows product 
 runs under Windows 98, Windows NT 4, Windows 2000, and Windows XP. Advanced POS is the most comprehensive offering in the Keystroke POS software line by Specialized Business Solutions. SBS is best known for the high-level support we provide our fast growing network of dedicated independent POS dealers who appreciate the robust capabilities of the Keystroke Advanced POS system.
 Fast&amp;flexible sales entry Powerful transaction scripts Built-in touch-screen editor Extensive databases PCI validated&amp;payment residuals 50%+ Generous dealer margins 50%+ 
 Logivision develops software for the retail industry with a particular focus on the operation system for the front-end terminals. Innovative and always at the forefront of new technological developments, Logivision is committed to improving the service and the products we provide to our customers. . Maitre&apos;D offers a complete solution that is 
 easy to use, including customizable POS, Back-Office, Corporate solutions and 
 ASP solutions for table service and quick service restaurants. The Maitre’D 
 Software Suite will provide you with the tools that you need to improve your 
 business operations and increase your profits. Whether you run one restaurant 
 or over one hundred, count on us for the service and reliability you need to 
 help your business grow Contact us today to for more information on the 
 flexibility, simplicity, and reliability that Maitre’D can offer you. Micro$ale is a fully-featured, easy-to-use 
 Food Service POS system.
Our services include:

 Developed for the industry by a long-time Restaurateur Installed and developed continuosly since 1991 As powerfull as you want, as simple as you need For use in full-service and quick-service dining 
 National Computer Corporation Reflection Embedded POS is a low cost, full featured point of sale application developed by NCC to run on the Touch Dynamic Breeze Terminal. Reflection runs on a CF Card eliminating the need for a hard drive and Windows.

For more than 20 years, NCC has been developing software solutions for the hospitality industry. We have over 20,000 systems installed in more than 30 countries around the world. NCC offers a full line of products including point of sale, time and attendance, back office and headquarters all developed and supported by NCC.

Point of Sale, Timekeeping, Labor Scheduling, Delivery with Customer Database, Integrated Electronic Payments, and much more all included in Reflection Embedded POS. onePos onePOSʼs streamlined architecture and nine years of real world enhancements means rock solid
dependability you can count on every day - all day. We constantly evolve our software to offer the latest
features when you need them. Automatic emailing of reports throughout the day, PCI compliant and
PABP certified, Full kitchen video display, hand held table side ordering and payment, Verifone hand held
table side and curb-side payments, Hotel room folio query and charge posting, Interfacing into a wide
variety of systems and peripherals, and Direct credit card processing to major processors. No third party
credit or gift card processing software is necessary since onePOS connects directly to your bank. Monthly
releases of our software continues to add to our ever expanding list of up to date features. PCAMERICA 

 
Our services include:
 ·Hospitality

·Fine dining

·Table service

·Quick service

·Retail ·Fast, easy Point-of-Sale software for any type of restaurant or retail store.
·Flexible and scalable for single-location businesses or chains with hundreds 
 of locations.
·Detailed reports, inventory and ingredient tracking, customer loyalty.
·Support for Dell POS hardware, office system and servers.
 
 Pixel 
 Point POS is a leading developer of 
 restaurant POS, Wireless, Web and Enterprise Software Suites for the restaurant 
 industry worldwide.
Since 1992, PixelPoint has been committed to providing reliable, flexible, and 
 easy-to-use point of sale software solutions for table service and quick 
 service restaurants. POS&amp;Touch es una Aplicación para el manejo de la facturación e inventarios en Comercios tales como: Restaurantes, Fast Food, Clubs, Bowling, Súper Marquet, Tiendas, Farmacias, Panaderías, Ferreterías, y todo lo referente al manejo y control del Negocio.....También podrás conectar cualquier tipo de periférico como balanzas de peso (en pasillo o mostrador ) lectores de banda, PDAs para tomas de inventarios, PDAs para meseros en Restaurantes, PDAs para el Manejo de Credit Card, KDS para mensajes en la Cocina y otros, ( Somos desarrolladores con 18 Años de Experiencia y 24 en el Area ) El SoftWare POS&amp;TOUCH Cuenta con Interface con Desarrollos de la calidad de SAP, JD EDWARS, LATISSE SOFT Y SAINT Enterprise, esto le da mayor robustez si se quiere contar con herramientas para mayores controles Administrativo Gerenciales que permiten tener un control seguro al tratarse de redes de Negocios que puedan estar ubicados en cualquier parte del mundo y quieran tener toda la información y movimientos del negocio a mano. Necesitamos Integradores para Sur America y Centro America….. Plexis Pos PosPlexis Pos specializes in Point 
 of Sale Software for Retail, QSR, Fast Food Restaurant, Convenience, Liquor, 
 Grocery, Tobacco and Pizza. Pointos Professional is a full featured, easy to use point of sale software
package, designed by In The Biz people for In The Biz people.
With simple-to-use as it&apos;s number one goal, we&apos;ve managed to pack in every
feature expensive point of sale software contains plus many more not found
anywhere else, at a price you can afford. With integrated credit card
processing, inventory control, customer tracking, full reporting, and an
easy to use interface, PointOS will save you time and money. Procare Child Care Software is the management tool of choice for more than 25,000 child-centered businesses. Procare simplifies management of child care centers, daycare providers, preschool and after school programs, school districts, enrichment programs, gymnastics clubs, child activity centers and similar facilities.
Procare has helped hundreds of thousands of early childhood professionals streamline child care management, administration, recordkeeping and automated Payment Processing at daycare centers and similar facilities around the globe. Queuent’s Wait List Manager is the complete restaurant guest paging system that lets popular restaurants manage their walk-in crowds by calling waiting parties on their mobile phones. Guests can then confirm, delay, or cancel seating. With Wait List Manager’s mobile phone paging technology, restaurants now know if and when parties will be returning. Restaurants with Wait List Manager will see fewer curb-side turn-aways because the waiting area will be less crowded and more inviting to passers by. Since Wait List Manager is completely web-based and only needs an internet connection, it is ideal for Touch Dynamic’s all-in-one systems. With Venue&apos;s Flexible design, complete theatre 
 management is always at your fingertips.
Our services include:

 Touch screen tickets sales Touch screen concession sales Inventory and cash control Movie scheduling Extensive access and data security Custom screen design Employee time clock and labor management Detailed management reports and More... 
 RPOWER Restaurant POS provides unmatched flexibility for today&apos;s
restaurants. RPOWER reaches far beyond traditional point-of-sale systems.
From off-site, real-time reporting and extensive customer relationship
programs, to the seamless integration with accounting software, RPOWER puts
you in control. Its reliability in the field and dedicated support staff
ensure your time is focused on your customers. SCANPlus POS Software Our solutions are for any size store, from a single store with a single register to large multi-store operations.
SCANPlus POS software is not hardware dependent. Unlike many solutions that run on proprietary platforms, SCANPlus software is truly open. You have a choice of a variety of peripherals such as receipt printers, scanner/scales, cash drawers, displays, etc. At SCANPlus we listen to our customers needs and are willing to adjust our software to meet their needs. SCANPlus POS software, incredibly capable but surprisingly affordable. Since 1986 PDQ POS software from Signature Systems, Inc. has offered complete hardware and software solutions for your restaurant. With over 35 years of experience in the industry, SSI has become the #1 POS system for delivery and quick service applications.
SSI’s development team continually works to integrate the newest technologies for your business. Our in-house 24/7/365 support team ensures that you will always have a live support connection.
Driver dispatch, driver mapping, caller ID features streamline your delivery operation. Drive-thru timers, line busters and automatic change machines accelerate your store’s traffic. Complete online ordering, payment processing integration, reporting and management tools for both single store owners and the multi-chain franchisees give you the tools to manage and expand your business. National Soft Soft Restaurant® is the ideal solution for Hispanic restaurants. Developed by National Soft®, Soft Restaurant® has a perfect combination of powerful system and intuitive way to use and control your business, it helps you maximize your sales, and improve the operation of your enterprise. Provide a better service to your costumers and invite them to come back after a good experience. Our System has been leading the Hispanic market around Mexico and Latin America, becoming the favorite Point of Sale because it has been developed to attend the needs of this market. The software and our technical support are in Spanish, making us a specialized engine for our target. Giving you full control of your business, Soft Restaurant® is your best choice. SunSofTouch Restaurant Point-Of-Sale Systems 
 is a state-of-the-art Touch Screen Windows POS and back office software for the 
 food service industry. SunSofTouch Restaurant is perfect for &quot;sit-down&quot; 
 restaurants including fine dining, bars, family style restaurants, cafes, 
 cafeterias, country clubs, membership clubs and fast food operations. For 25 years, Synchronics has developed 
 full-featured business software for serious retailers and wholesalers—just like 
 you.
We offer a suite of software solutions that work together to make your business 
 more successful:
Our services include:

 CounterPoint SQL enterprise is business management software that relies on the 
 power of SQL CounterPoint SQL Express is business management software designed for 
 single-store businesses that want an economical SQL solution CounterPoint V7 is feature-rich business management software that works with 
 whatever platform you do CPOnline lets you open your own online store CPGateway adds 2-second credit card authorizations 
 1TouchSoftware Solutions, Inc. , is a 
 full-service enterprise restaurant management systems and services provider. 
 Founded by a combined team of experienced industry professionals and seasoned 
 software technologists, 1TouchSoftware is delivering a new generation of 
 restaurant management and marketing solutions. The 1TouchSoftware Enterprise 
 Restaurant Management System (eRMS) helps restaurateurs manage operations, 
 resources, and the many touch points of the client relationship, all through a 
 single suite of integrated applications.
Our services include:

 Full featured point-of-sale (POS) Workforce management Customer relationship management (CRM) framework Customer loyalty management Gift card management Inventory Enterprise reporting 
 UpFront Software is a point of sale software program designed specifically for the grocery store industry. The software offers a wide variety of features that will meet the needs of any size grocery store, from a single lane to a large multi-lane grocery store. For over 15 years we have listened to our customers and have developed our software to offer solutions for every aspect of a grocery store’s operation. These include POS Touch Screen, or Keyboard, Pricing and Cost Controls, Receiving, Inventory Control, Accounts Receivable, Shelf Labeling, Frequent Shopper Tracking, Direct Store Delivery, Financial Reporting, on-line Credit/Debit/EBT/Gift Card processing and more. UpFront Software will continue the tradition of listening to the needs of our customers. We are committed to providing them with the most cutting edge grocery store features available in the marketplace. Work Tech&apos;s Time Suite software enables immediate savings on time and attendance data collection and reporting. Validation of employee leave and other benefits ensures compliance with company policy and government regulations. Its highly flexible configuration allows enterprises to collect complex time and attendance data efficiently. The end result is direct cost savings, fewer errors, and the information needed to allow facilities and operations management to increase departmental efficiency.

 WorkTech’s Contractor Cost Tracking System, Reduces Costs and Improve Decision Making 
Companies that outsource labor and contract labor, whether on an ongoing basis or for short-term projects such as turnarounds, know the importance and difficulties of the data collection, invoicing, review, and payment processes. Costs need to be assigned and tracked against purchase orders, work orders, and projects. These transactions can be complex and error prone with hundreds of workers, job orders, transactions, and pay rates. The information is required by multiple systems and, unfortunately, is often entered multiple times. 
 
 
Popular Links

 Contact Sales Where to Buy Software Partners Touch Dynamic MAPP 
 
Technical Sevices

 Tech Support Drivers Configuration Tool 
 
Customer Service

 RMA Spec Sheets OEM / Private Branding TD Warranty Terms 
 
Certifications

 GSA ISO 9001:2008 RSPA Certfied Microsoft Direct 
 
 Desinged by Awarecode 

Copyright 2001- 2012 All rights reserved - 17 Camptown Rd. Irvington, NJ 07111 - 888.508.6824 - sales@touchdynamic.com Widefly
	</body>
</document>
