<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004254" url="http://www.allthingspos.com/citizen/idp3550.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:30" support="1" score="0.0010605810588935002" bingtitle="Citizen iDP-3550 POS Printers - POS Experts, Same Day Shipping and ..." webtitle="Citizen iDP-3550 POS Printers 
				
				 - POS Experts, Same Day Shipping and Low Prices!">
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>... at the lowest price, guaranteed - order ... economy printer for bankcard, POS, fast food, restaurant and convenience store use.</description>
	<body>
		Expert Advice: 1-800-326-0393  ·  Same Day Shipping  ·  Low Prices Cart    

 
 Products 
· Barcode Scanners 
· Credit Card Swipers 
· Cash Drawers 
· POS Software 
· POS Systems 
· POS Printers 
· POS Touchscreens 
  More» 

 Brands 

 Services 

 Solutions 

 

 Customer Service 
· Contact Us 
· Delivery Options 
· Printer Drivers 


 

 About Us 
 
 POS Hardware › Point of Sale › POS Printers › Citizen POS Printers › Citizen iDP-3550 

 
Citizen iDP-3550 POS Printers

 High speed economy printer for bankcard, POS, fast food, restaurant and convenience store use. 

Designed for such applications as receipts, journals, kitchen, ticket, and credit/debit card transactions, the iDP-3550 series has a cash drawer kick out feature that can control two drawers. The iDP-3550 series also features a 6k-byte memory buffer, two color printing, and semi-automatic paper loading. It weighs six pounds and prints up to 3.6 lines per second.
 
 
 
 Related Links Email us Request a quote Spec Sheet 
 Citizen iDP-3550 Ribbons Citizen
Receipt Paper Citizen drivers Citizen&apos;s iDP-3550 Page Price match Connection Example Pictures 
 
 

 Top Model Options All Model Options Accessories Specifications 
 
 
 Part # Description Availability Price Order 3550F-40PF120V-CW IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , parallel interface. Includes power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: white. Ships Same Day $219.10 3550F-40PF120V-BK IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , parallel interface. Includes power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: black. Ships Same Day $222.70 3550F-40RF120V-BK IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , serial interface. Includes power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: black. Ships Same Day $219.70 3550F-40RF120V-CW IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , serial interface. Includes power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: white. Ships Same Day $222.20 IDP3550F40RF120 IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , serial interface. Includes power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: Ivory. Ships Same Day $229.50 3551F-40PF120V-BK IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , parallel interface. Includes auto-cutter&amp;power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: black. Ships Same Day $234.30 3551F-40RF120V-BK IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , serial interface. Includes auto-cutter&amp;power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: black. Ships Same Day $244.70 3551F-40PF120V-CW IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , parallel interface. Includes auto-cutter and power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: white. Ships Same Day $244.70 3551F-40RF120V-CW IDP-3550, Impact, two-color printing, 3.6 lps , serial interface. Includes auto-cutter&amp;power supply. Order cables separately. See accessories. Color: White. Ships Same Day $240.90 IDP3551F40RF120 IDP-3550, 76 mm (3&quot;) DOT MATRIX PRN AC, SERIAL, IVORY, POWER SUPPLY Ships Same Day $248.30 IDP3551F-40PF-120V IDP-3551, Receipt Printer (Parallel Interface and 120V) - Color: Ivory Ships Same Day $231.70 IDP3551F-40RF-230C IDP-3551, Receipt Printer (Serial Interface and 230 Volt) - Color: Cool White Ships Same Day $223.50 
 
Accessories
 
 Part # Description Availability Price Order 13172 Cables, 6 ft. USB cable (USB 2.0, A to B). Replaces Part# USB-5000-02M. Ships Same Day $12.20 03019 Cables, Serial printer cable, 9-pin to 25-pin, 6 ft. Replaces Part# PCM-1970-06. Ships Same Day $12.30 13400 Cables, 10 ft. USB cable (USB 2.0, A to B). Replaces Part# USB-5000-03M. Ships Same Day $12.90 02798 Cables, 6 ft. Parallel printer cable. Replaces Part# PCM-1100-06. Ships Same Day $12.90 JM14703-0 CLP-521, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $184.50 JE99694-00 CLP-72xxE, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $368.60 JE99427-0 CLP-7001, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $308.60 JE99234-0 CLP 1001, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $225.40 JH09701-00 CLP8301, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $966.20 JM14706-00F CLP-631, Replacement printhead, 305 dpi . Ships Same Day $313.00 IR-31RB-R Receipt Ribbons, CD-S500 Ribbon, Red/Black, single ribbon, priced per ribbon Ships Same Day $12.10 IR-31RB Receipt Ribbons, CD-S500 Ribbon, Red/Black, 10 ribbons/case Ships Same Day $34.10 OPT-789 Printer Accessories, Cutter (for the CLP521 and 621 Printers) Ships Same Day $193.80 OPT-788 Printer Accessories, Ethernet Card (for the CLP521, 621 and CLS700) Ships Same Day $238.90 AH37945-01 BLACK, RIBBON/GSX-190 (9-WIRE), DOT MATRIX RIBBON Ships Same Day $18.00 JN98909-0M Printer Accessories, Peeler (for the CLS700) Ships Same Day $225.20 OPT-784 Printer Accessories, 7200 Cutter (Includes Mounting Kit) Ships Same Day $538.10 OPT-794 Printer Accessories, Peeler Assembly (for the CLP-7202) Ships Same Day $108.00 31ADU Power supply for the 3210 Ships Same Day $71.20 AW-3 Auto-Winder for IDP-35XX Printers Ships Same Day $49.40 OPT-780 Printer Accessories, Ethernet Kit (Internal, 7200SER with Mounting, SEH IC102) Ships Same Day $266.80 35AD2-U Printer Accessories, Power supply (CEC Compliant) for the CBM820, CTS300/310 and PPU231/700 Ships Same Day $55.20 AM37901-00 Black Ribbon Cartridge, single ribbon, for the CI-620, CI-630, CI-650 printers. Ships Same Day $15.00 IC111-FAST-CBM-TX Removable Ethernet Interface (for the CBM-1000II) Ships Same Day $203.40 AH37901-0 Compatible black fabric ribbons, single cartridge, designed for the Citizen GSX 220 / 230 / 240 / 540, Swift 200 / 24 / 240 printers, 2 million characters per ribbon yield, Color: Black Ships Same Day $14.90 100115-00B CT-S300 POS Printer Accessories, Power Case for the CTS300 Black Internal Power supply for CTS300 Ships Same Day $17.70 PHU-332S PPU-700 Kiosk Printer Accessories, Paper Tray (Side Paper Install with 2 Near End Sensors) for the PPU-700 Ships Same Day $45.40 950034-00 Interface Board (RS-232 Serial) for the CTS300, CDS500 and PPU700 Ships Same Day $38.20 950028-00 Printer Accessories, CBM-1000II Interface (Removable) Ships Same Day $43.70 TA66811-0 Printer Accessories, Interface Board (Parallel) for the CTS310/2000/4000 Ships Same Day $32.20 28AD1-U CT-S280 Printer Accessories, Power supply (Not CEC Compliant) for the CT-S280 Ships Same Day $42.20 950025-00 Interface Card, Parallel, Interchangeable, For the CBM1000II printer Ships Same Day $32.10 AW-3-BK Paper Winder, For the IDP3550/3551 Printers Ships Same Day $41.50 PHU-131P.HOLDER PPU-231 Printer Accessories, Paper Holding Unit (for the PPU-231 Kiosk Printer) Ships Same Day $38.90 010761D Ethernet Interface (for the CTS300, CDS500, PPU 700, CTS310 and CTS2000/4000) Ships Same Day $117.50 950036-01 Interface Board (USB) for the CTS300/CDS500/PP and PPU700 Printers Ships Same Day $41.90 IR-41RB Receipt Ribbons, Red-Black Ribbon (for the IDP3400), Single Ribbon. Ships Same Day $14.40 TC56702-00F Power Case (Black, Rubber feet) for the CT-S310 Ships Same Day $17.70 JE98903-0 Printer Accessories, 521/621 Holder (8 Label Roll) Ships Same Day $54.00 JM14705-00F CLP-621, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $203.70 JN09802-00F CL-S700, Replacement printhead, 203 dpi . Ships Same Day $260.40 1C4P-6P Printer Accessories, Cable (Adapter Single Drawer 1 Molex to Single Drawer Modular) Ships Same Day $20.10 950035-00 Printer Accessories, Interface Board (Parallel) for the CTS300, CDS500 and PPU700 Ships Same Day $38.30 95002700 Printer Accessories, CBM1000 II Citizen Serial Interface ( DB-25 -Pin) Ships Same Day $32.10 JE99149-0 6001, 6002&amp;2001, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $344.00 JE99234-00 C4, Replacement printhead (for the C4 Barcode printer) Ships Same Day $333.10 JE99029-0 Printer Accessories, Platen Roller (CLP1001) Ships Same Day $60.10 JE99035-01 Printer Accessories, Platen Gear (CLP1001 Printer) Ships Same Day $11.30 JE99042-0 Printer Accessories, Platen Holder (CLP1001 Printer) Ships Same Day $11.30 JE99043-0 Printer Accessories, Platen Bearing (CLP1001 Printer) Ships Same Day $21.40 51AD-U Printer Accessories, Power supply (CEC Compliant) for the CD-S500 Ships Same Day $74.80 TA66814-0M Printer Accessories, SEH Ethernet Board (for the CTS310/2000/CTS4000) Ships Same Day $153.00 JE99711-0F Printer Accessories, Platen Roller (for the CLP7201/7202) Ships Same Day $85.20 JN98901-0M Printer Accessories, Cutter (for the CLS700) Ships Same Day $538.10 CIT-NJ76908-00F Printer Accessories, Master CTN/Box for CD-S500 Serial Ships Same Day $17.60 JM22701-00F Printer Accessories, Platen Roller (for the CLP521/621) Ships Same Day $26.10 ACC-230KIT Cutter (and Plate Kit) for the CBM1000 Ships Same Day $37.80 TB66832-00F Interface Board (Serial) for the CTS310/2000/4000 Ships Same Day $31.60 JA99272-00 CLP-4081, Replacement printhead, 203 dpi . Ships Same Day $483.70 IR-41RB-CASE Ribbons, Red-Black Ribbon (for the IDP3400), 10 ribbon pack. Ships Same Day $87.20 JE99482-0 CLP7401, Replacement printhead. Ships Same Day $767.80 
 
Citizen iDP-3550 Details
 
 
 iDP-3550 - High-speed printers for bankcard, POS, fast food, restaurant and convenience store use.
 3 Emulations in One Small size, light weight, and low price High-speed print (Bi-directional) Red and black print Auto load Paper end sensor Built in power supply Options: Special purpose winder AW-3-E (Option) that will be placed separately.
 
 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 
 Epson TM-U220: TM-U220A, TM-U220B, TM-U220D
POS Printers 
 $202.00 
 Epson TM-T88v
POS Printers 
 $282.70 
 Epson TM-T88v
POS Printers 
 $282.70 
 
The Citizen iDP-3550
 is also known as the
 
 
 
 Citizen America iDP-3550
 
 .
 

 ©2011 All Things POS
	</body>
</document>
