<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004424" url="http://www.hobartcorp.com/About-You/Food-Service/Restaurants/Independent/" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="2" score="0.0013627684874094807" bingtitle="Hobart Corporation | About You - Food Service - Restaurants ..." webtitle="Hobart Corporation | About You - Food Service - Restaurants - Independent Restaurants">
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>We can help make food safety easy. One of the most important issues facing ... While chemical cleaners could leave your glasses and cups with unsightly stains such ...</description>
	<body>
		Hobart Traulsen Baxter Sustainable Food Equipment SPEC SELECTOR Financing CAD&amp;Revit Libraries Sign In Search 
 Find us on: 
 Home About Us News&amp;Events Contact Us / Dealer Directory 
 Products 
 
 
 Baxter Baking » 

 Ovens Proofers Retarder/Proofers Specialty Products&amp;Accessories 

 
 
 Cooking » 

 Combi Ovens&amp;Barcode Scanners Convection Ovens Fryers Griddles Ranges Rotisseries Steamers Toasters 

 
 
 Food Prep » 

 Choppers/Grinders Cutter Mixers Food Cutters Food Processors Meat Saws Mixers Mixer/Grinders Peelers Power Drive Units Tenderizers Salad Dryers Slicers Accessories 

 
 
 Traulsen Refrigeration » 

 Blast Chillers Dual Temps Hot-Food Holding Cabinets Prep Tables Refrigerators and Freezers Special Application Products Undercounter and Equipment Stands 

 
 
 Warewashing » 

 Advansys Conveyor Type Door Type ENERGY STAR® Qualified FastRack Conveyor System Flight Type Glasswasher Pot, Pan and Utensil Washer Powered Sink Undercounters Waste Equipment Accessories 

 
 
 Weigh Wrap » 

 Scales Wrapping Equipment ITW Labels Networking/Retail Software USDA Mandatory Meat-Case Nutrition-Labeling Rule 

 
 
 Water Treatment » 

 Cooking Systems Baking Systems Warewash Systems Ice&amp;Beverage Systems 

 
 
 
 AboutYou 
 
 
Consultant Services

 Consultants 
 
Food Service

 Education
 K-12 Schools 

 SNA Contest 

 Higher Education 
 

 Healthcare
 Acute Care 

 Assisted Living 
 

 Restaurants
 Chain Restaurants 

 Independent 
 

 Lodging&amp;Casinos 

 Corrections 

 Military 

 Corporate Dining 

 Government 
 
Grocery

 Convenience Stores 

 Grocery Stores 
 
 
 ServiceParts SustainableDesign 
 
Independent Restaurants

We report to work faithfully at thousands of restaurants every day.

 Representing approximately seven out of 10 restaurants, the independent owner and operator is the backbone of the industry. We support you with the reliability and durability of our equipment for lower cost of operation.
 Food Service 
 
Education
 
 K-12 Schools SNA Contest Higher Education 
 
Healthcare
 
 Acute Care Assisted Living 
 
Restaurants
 
 Chain Restaurants Independent 
 Lodging&amp;Casinos Corrections Military Corporate Dining Government 
 
 
 
 Food Safety Cost of Ownership Productivity Resource Center 
 
 

 
 
We can help make food safety easy.

One of the most important issues facing independent restaurants, food safety requires the attention and cooperation of everyone on your staff. Good food safety is a lot more than your staff washing their hands thoroughly.

 Clean and sanitized ware is essential to any food-safety program. While chemical cleaners could leave your glasses and cups with unsightly stains such as lipstick, Hobart’s ENERGY STAR® qualified Advansys™ Ventless Door-Type Warewasher is NSF-certified to clean and sanitize dishes and delicate glasses, and pots and pans as well.

 Hobart’s 3000 Series Slicer is the industry’s easiest-to-clean slicer. The carriage is tiltable and removable for thorough washing. The base is a single unit that can be wiped clean and leaves no cracks or crevices for waste to accumulate.

The recent trend in serving “fresh foods,” including organics, has added to the complexity of food safety. Hobart food processors can help you meet this market demand with safe food practices. For example, our diwash™ aluminum plates remove in seconds and can be cleaned and sanitized in a warewasher without fear of discoloration.

To keep your food fresh and safe, there’s our full line of Traulsen undercounter refrigerators and freezers with their exclusive microprocessors for precise temperature control. 

 The Traulsen Undercounter Quick Chiller is a powerful tool for safe food storage. If you cook food ahead of the time
it’s served, it’s important to get it chilled fast through the Danger Zone of
temperatures (41°F to 135°F), where food can spoil. The Traulsen Quick Chiller
pulls down food temperatures well within the FDA-required time limit. 
 
 

 
Save energy, your water and your money, too.

Restaurants consume almost two and a half times more energy per square foot than any other commercial-type building. When you add in other utility costs, such as water, you have expenses that continue to erode the profitability of your restaurant.

 Hobart equipment and service can help reduce those expenses. Our ENERGY STAR® qualified CL e Warewasher —with Hobart’s exclusive Opti-Rinse™ technology—can save you as much as $9,192 a year because it uses less than half the water and energy, compared to previous models without Opti-Rinse.

 



 The ENERGY STAR ® qualified Hobart Advansys™ Ventless Door-Type Warewasher not only uses the least water per load in its
class—only.74 gallons—but its unique Energy Recovery feature saves energy, too.
It captures water vapor and condenses it to heat the incoming cold-water inlet
for the final rinse cycle, and saving up to $792 in energy costs per year.
Plus, its ventless design eliminates $776 in HVAC operation costs per year. Put
all that together, and the Advansys Ventless can save you $1,568* in energy
every year. 

 

 *Based on 200
cycles/day, 360 days/year at an energy cost of $.011 per cycle. 

 

With approximately 400 ENERGY STAR qualified appliances to choose from, we give you lots of way to save. For example, Traulsen ENERGY STAR qualified refrigerators and freezers can cut your refrigeration energy costs as much as 45%.

Hobart Service can help you get the highest level of performance from your equipment with preventive maintenance, service contracts, extended warranty contracts and other specialty programs.

 

 

 

 
 
 
 
 
Improving the productivity of your staff.

The largest private-sector employer in the country, the restaurant industry runs on people. For the independent restaurant, wages and benefits account for fully one-third of your costs. Compounding the cost is the high rate of turnover, resulting in the added expense of training and motivating new employees.

Hobart equipment is designed to help you deal with these dual issues by providing products that are easy to operate, require minimal training and increase productivity.

 The Hobart Legacy® Mixer is the only mixer with a swing-out bowl, making it simpler to add ingredients and take out product, to mount and change bowls. It has other features to improve productivity, too, such as Automatic Time Recall that remembers the last time set for each speed, making it ideal for mixing batches of the same product.

The Hobart Combi® Oven brings push-button convenience to cooking. You can preprogram up to 100 different recipes that your staff can execute at the touch of a finger. 

 The Baxter Hybrid Convection Oven combines the versatility of
convection and steam heat, but into a smaller footprint. Its attractive
hearth-shaped viewing window makes it perfect for front-of-house applications.
Plus, it has 100 programmable recipes, so you can get cooking at the touch of a
button. 

 

 
 
Resource Center

 
 
 
Case Studies
 
 David Chang 

 Red Stag Supper Club 
 
Literature
 
 Restaurants Segment Brochure 
 
Special Events/Trade Shows
 
 Show Date Location NRA Show May 5-8, 2012 Chicago, IL Greenbuild Expo 2012 November 14-16, 2012 San Francisco, CA NAFEM Show 2013 
 February 7-9, 2013 Orlando, FL 

 
Industry Links
 
 ACF (American Culinary Federation) 

 DineOriginals.com 

 DiRoNA (Distinguished Restaurants of North America) 

 StarChefs.com 


 Hobart© 2012
 All Rights Reserved 
Notice to all users: Carefully read the Terms of Use, International and Other Notices before using the Web site.  By using this Web site, you signify you assent to all terms of use, privacy, international and other notices.  If you do not agree, please disconnect from and do not use this Web site.
	</body>
</document>
