<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004518" url="http://www.hotfrog.com/Products/Restaurant/NV/Las-Vegas" time="2012-07-12-20:56" support="1" score="0.0007999148481321673" bingtitle="Restaurant in NV - Hotfrog - Your Business Directory" webtitle="Restaurant in Las Vegas">
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant American Restaurant Burger ... best deals on the web for cash registers, credit card ... Nevada, for fun slot machines, mixed drinks and ...</description>
	<body>
		Login 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Restaurant in Las Vegas
 Restaurant   NEVADA   Las Vegas (911) 1 - 40 of 911 businesses results King Of Clubs Las Vegas 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 837 2401 Email 
So, whether you are looking for transportation for corporate events, a special occasion, or the wildest bachelor/ette party in Las Vegas, The Ki…
 
Latest updates
 King Of Clubs - Gifts - 11/23/2011
 New to King of Clubs Las Vegas! The most luxurious Resort Towe… Read more: King Of Clubs - Sommalier - 11/23/2011
 The ultimate in elegance combined with some real fun. Our excl… Read more: 
 More info 
 
Related information
 Restaurant in Las Vegas NV Kung Fu Thai and Chinese 
Kung Fu Thai and Chinese Restaurant - 03/16/2012
 An authentic Thai and Chinese restaurant in Las Vegas. Open for lunch and dinner, we&apos;re located just 1/2 mile west of the Fashion Show Mall on the Las Vegas Strip. Las Vegas Restaurants Free WiFi offer to their Social Media followers 
Kung Fu Thai&amp;Chinese Restaurant - 03/31/2011
 Kung Fu Plaza might be the oldest and most authentic Chinese and Thai 
restaurant in Las Vegas, but it&apos;s also striving to take a step in the 
right direction. Starting in the first quarter of 2011, Kung Fu Thai&amp;Chinese Restaurant began offering free 
WiFi for patrons who enjoy keeping up with family and friends during 
lunch and dinner. &quot;We want to give something back to the new 
friends we&apos;re making on Facebook and Twitter,&quot; said Allen Wong, general 
manager of Kung Fu Plaza resta… American Beach Food 
Beach Cafe Las Vegas - 11/20/2010
 You might not catch a wave at Beach Cafe, but you will find a fun, sea-side like atmosphere featuring beach music and totally awesome island inspired grub at tubular prices. Chill out with a tasty tropical smoothie or dive into one of their delicious deli or grilled sandwiches, surfin&apos; salads and more. Hang loose with local faves like the South Shore sliders, Waikiki Teriyaki burger and Thai chicken wrap. Looking to catch the morning pipeline? Beach Cafe opens early, serving full b…   Kung Fu Thai and Chinese Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-247-4120 
An authentic Thai and Chinese restaurant in Las Vegas. Open for lunch and dinner, we&apos;re located just 1/2 mile west of the Fashion Show Mall on the Las Vegas Strip.
 
 Asian Restaurants Thai Food 
 Kung Fu Thai&amp;Chinese Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-247-4120 
Kungfu Plaza Restaurant has been the premier Thai and Chinese restaurant in Las Vegas, NV for over 35years, since 1973.  Kungfu Plaza serves authentic Thai and Chinese food, alongside Beer, Wine, Cocktails, with takeout…
 
 Restaurant Listings Restaurant Menus Thai Restaurant Gourmet Chinese Food 
 Smashburger 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-462-5503 
Smashburger is a great new burger place that offers a great tasting gourmet burger made with 100% Angus beef. &quot;Smashburger has the best burgers.&quot; Try a custom Smashburger today!
 
 Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant American Restaurant Burger 
 Smashburger 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-385-0043 
Smashburger is a great new new burger place that offers a great tasting gourmet burger made with 100% Angus beef. &quot;Smashburger has the best burgers.&quot; Try a custom Smashburger today!
 
 Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant American Restaurant Burger 
 Smashburger 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-462-5500 
Smashburger is a great new burger place that offers a great tasting gourmet burger made with 100% Angus beef. &quot;Smashbrurger has the best burgers.&quot; Try a custom Smashburger today!
 
 Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant American Restaurant Burger 
 Raising Cane&apos;s Chicken Fingers&quot;The Str… 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-434-3644 
Where the chicken is kickin&apos;, the sauce is the boss and the toast is the most! Raising Cane&apos;s Chicken Fingers is a unique restaurant chain serving high-quality chicken finger meals with few frills and extra attention pa…
 
 Fast Food Family Restaurant Casual Dining Fried Chicken 
 Insurmart Inc. 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-795-1777 
Auto Insurance -Home Insurance - Business Insurance -Commercial Insurance - Workers Compensation -Dealer Bonds - Restaurant Insurance - Truck Insurance ‎‎
 
 
 Smashburger 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-982-0009 
Smashburger is a great new burger place that offers a great tasting gourmet burger made with 100% Angus beef. &quot;Smashburger has the best burgers.&quot; Try a custom Smashburger today!
 
 Fast Food Fast Food Restaurant American Restaurant Burger 
 The Tillerman Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-731-4036 
The Tillerman Restaurant - the best place in Las Vegas, NV. Famous 
Restaurant, Private Dining, Seafood Restaurant, Steak Restaurant, Fine 
Dining Restaurant. For more details - (702) 731-4036
 
 Restaurant Listings Steakhouse Steak Restaurant Famous Restaurant 
 Sushi-Mon Las Vegas 
Las Vegas, NV
 7023040044 
We are the original Sushimon in Las Vegas since we started business in 2001 as one of the few restaurant s who had ALL YOU CAN EAT SUSHI We have established numerous royal customers and have shared the best Sush…
 
 Japanese Restaurants All You Can Eat Sushi Japanese Cuisine 
 Micatrotto Restaurant Group dba Raising… 
LAS VEGAS, NV
 702-365-9221 
MRG-llc. is the franchisee for Raising Cane&apos;s Chicken Fingers in the State of Nevada.  The Micatrotto Restarant Group is a Las Vegas based company.
 
 Cane Sauce Restaurant Group Crinkle Fries Raising Cane 
 Saffron - Flavors of India 
Las Vegas, NV
 7025175301 
Try something delightfully unique and exciting. Saffron - Flavors of India brings you authentic Indian cuisine to Northwest Las Vegas. Try traditional dishes of cooked in real Tandoor ovens marinated in homemade yogurt,…
 
 Chinese Restaurant Indian Restaurant Tandoori Halal 
 Tc4tc 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702)544 0840 
The Traveling Culinarist is in a category all its own. the customized compact design is ideal for traveling. The unique interior spaces keep everything securely in place when you arrive. No space is wasted in this trave…
 
 Chef Tools Chef PROFESSIONAL CHEF Gourmet Chef 
 NapkinNights 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 425-9399 
An interactive guide to popular nightlife focusing on Las Vegas, Los Angeles, Miami, Arizona, San Diego, San Francisco, Portland, Salt Lake City, Nashville, St Louis and Sacramento.
 
 Club Scene Drinking Nightclub Restaurants 
 Alexco Pos 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 878 8283 
We offer some of the best deals on the web for cash registers, credit card machines, pos, merchant services, paper and ribbons in Las Vegas
 
 Pub Accommodation Services Pos Hotel 
 Wings Restaurants 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 435-7222 
The Best hot Wings in Las Vegas. Wings Restaurant features unique wing flavors such as Hell Fire, Cajun Kickers, Hot Garlic, Buffalo Hot Wings and a lot more.Make sure you try the awesome homemade sides and sauces.Wings…
 
 Wings Restaurant Catering Services Chicken Food 
 Kung Fu Plaza Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 1-702-247-4120 
Las Vegas restaurant s cooking Authentic Thai food-Chinese food open for lunch and dinner with dining, delivery, takeout, catering services, Beer, Wine, and Cocktails
 
 Thai Food Restaurant Chinese Restaurant Chinese Takeout Caterers 
 Innovative Dining Group Sushi Roku&amp;Bo… 
LAS VEGAS, NV
 7027337373 
High above the lights of the famed Las Vegas Strip sit Sushi Roku and BOA Steakhouse. We are proud to offer complete catering, special event planning, wedding consulting, and event design for your next party or event. W…
 
 Steakhouse Dining Sushi Group Accommodation 
 Garfield&apos;s Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 702-925-8333 
Garfield&apos;s Restaurant - Great Bar, Fresh Seafood, NightlyEntertainment Garfield&apos;s invites you to join them for a comfortableDining experience on Lake Jacqueline nestled in the Summerlin/Desert ShoresCommunity. General M…
 
 Waterfront Restaurant Lunch Seafood Wedding Catering 
 Distinctive Cleanup&amp;Handyman Services 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 575 8644 
We are a full service janitorial company in Las Vegas, NV. We offer commercial cleaning, window cleaning, graffiti removal, floor maintenance and much more
 
 
 Aces Bar&amp;Grill 
Las Vegas, NV
 866 568 2613 
Enjoy gourmet food and for your excitement we have IGT&amp;Bally multi-poker gaming machines at our bar in Las Vegas, Nevada
 
 Bistro Tavern Bar&amp;Grill Bar 
 Dress The Drink 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 270 4346 
Dress the Drink brings cocktail mixology and unparrelled, creative and decadent products inspired for all your beverages and desert needs
 
 Dessert Catering Gourmet Desserts Mixologist 
 Tableside Hospitality Consulting 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 743 2883 
Drawing from years of experience in the Food and Beverage Industry our seasoned team members will help your venue succeed
 
 Restaurant Industry Hospitality Consulting Cooking Hospitality 
 Aaa Bar&amp;Restaurant Supply 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 678 6005 
Please Visit Our New Streamlined Webpage at:www.AAABarAnd Restaurant .comIn business locally for over 25 years, AAA Bar&amp;Restaurant Supply is your Low Cost Leader in New&amp;Used Restaurant and Bar Equipment
 
 Bar And Restaurant Used Restaurant Used Restaurant Equipment Restaurant Supply 
 Beach Cafe Las Vegas 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 898 5200 

 
 Breakfast Cafe Sandwiches Beach Cafe 
 AllPoints 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 876 0667 
These market leading companies combined to form AllPoints Foodservice Parts&amp;Supplies Most of this time AllPoints was two separate companies
 
 Commercial Foodservice Coffee Cooking Oven 
 Gm Monarch West 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 597 2230 
GM Monarch West is an architectural mill shop that creates custom architectural millwork for the casino, hospitality, restaurant and retail industries
 
 HOSPITALITY RESTAURANT Architectural Mill Hospitality Casino 
 Hash House Family Restaurants 
las vegas, NV
 (702) 873 9479 
We will, on occasion, reserve our separate dining room for special occasion parties All of our breakfast dishes are prepared to order
 
 American Food Family Restaurants Family Restaurant Restaurants 
 Big Dog&apos;s Hospitality Group 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 368 3715 
Where the best in food, homemade microbrews, gaming promotions and exceptional hospitality are served up at all times
 
 Kids Menu Dinner Menu Brew Pub Lunch Menu 
 Four Kegs 
Las Vegas, NV
 702 870 0255 
Four Kegs currently sponsors a host of local athletic talent, including two softball teams and two soccer teams Four Kegs Sports Pub, since 1977 the place for all seasons We hope you come down and join us…
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Pizza Cocktail Lounges Cocktails 
 Ceres Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 973 746 7811 
Richie Cecere&apos;s Restuarant and Superclub is the best restuarant in New Jersey, providing fine dinining and entertainment while you eat. Come book a table with friends here and enjoy what we offer. Richie&apos;s 18 piece orch…
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Restaurants Fine Dining Family Restaurants Dining Restaurant 
 The Broiler 
Las Vegas, NV
 (916) 444 3444 
Sacramento&apos;s steakhouse since 1950. Serving aged, cut to order beef, seafood, pastas, chicken&amp;lamb. Home of Gallagher&apos;s Irish Pub
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Restaurants Steak Houses Steakhouse Steak Restaurant 
 The Broiler 
Las Vegas, NV
 (916) 444 3444 
Sacramento&apos;s steakhouse since 1950. Serving aged, cut to order beef, seafood, pastas, chicken&amp;lamb. Home of Gallagher&apos;s Irish Pub
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Restaurants Steak Houses Steakhouse Steak Restaurant 
 Pinoy Express 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 616 0384 
Pinoy Express - serving ofw for morethan 20 years of fast, easy, convinient, and reliable Philippine remittance transfer and delivery service. Sending money to Philippines, faster than ever
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Full Service Restaurant Eating Places Restaurants 
 Dan Marinos 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 739 9000 
Dan Marino&apos;s restaurant s. Fine Dining in Florida. Miami, Orlando, Ft Lauderdale, St Petersburg, Coral Springs
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Full Service Restaurant Eating Places Restaurants 
 Cili Restaurant 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 856 1000 
Walters Golf offers 3 unique and challenging golf courses in Las Vegas, Nevada. Choose from Bali Hai, Royal Links, and Desert Pines
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Full Service Restaurant Family Restaurants Restaurant&amp;Bar 
 China Ginger 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 876 1889 
Buy direct ginger products from China. China-Direct-Buy.com provides made in china ginger products, china ginger manufacturers, suppliers, exporters, factories and companies
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Full Service Restaurant Chinese Restaurants Chinese Restaurant 
 Steiner&apos;s A Nevada Style Pub 
Las Vegas, NV
 (702) 395 8777 
Steiner&apos;s - A Nevada Style Pub. Steiner&apos;s is the place to get your game on., Steiner&apos;s - A Nevada style pub
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Full Service Restaurant Pub Lounges 
 Morning Star Trading Corp 
Las Vegas, NV
 512 476 1726 
We offer the best in massage oils, lotions, and creams from BIOTONE, Soothing Touch, Sacred Earth Botanicals, and Zen Organics
 
 Full-Service Restaurants Full Service Restaurant Eating Places Restaurants 
 First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (911) 
 Related keywords 
 Restaurants Eating Places Full-Service Restaurants Fast Food Sandwiches Web Site Salads Full Service Restaurant sandwich Deli 
 Restaurant by city 
 N Las Vegas, NV North Las Vegas, NV Henderson, NV Boulder City, NV Overton, NV Pahrump, NV 
 Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
No results available
 
 Kung Fu Thai and Chinese Rest… 
 Products (1) 
 Smashburger 

 Smashburger 

 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 Kung Fu Thai and Chinese Restaurant 03/16/2012 My Buddy&apos;s Greek Cafe 10/05/2011 Smashburger 06/27/2011 Smashburger 06/27/2011 Smashburger 06/27/2011 Smashburger 06/27/2011 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search inquiry 
Most popular
 
 Kung Fu Thai&amp;Chinese Restau… Micatrotto Restaurant Group d… Raising Cane&apos;s Chicken Finger… Saffron - Flavors of India Giuseppe&apos;s Bar&amp;Grille Innovative Dining Group Sushi… 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
Share on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how-tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.7fs9.002 )
	</body>
</document>
