<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004170" url="http://www.whattoexpect.com/forums/may-2011-babies/topic/sweet-vs-salt-boy-vs-girl" time="2012-07-12-20:24" support="1" score="0.0010659785547062982" bingtitle="Sweet vs Salt - Boy vs girl - May 2011 Babies - What to Expect.com" webtitle="Sweet vs Salt - Boy vs girl - May 2011 Babies - What to Expect.com">
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>What to Expect When Your Pregnancy is Unexpected ... could skip meals all together and just eat ice ... Taco Bell is the only fast food restaurant that ever sounds good.</description>
	<body>
		3 Things To Do Today » Save on baby accessories » Introduce new foods to your baby » Get prepared for childbirth 
 
Follow Us On
 Sign in Close Register 
Log-in to What To Expect with one click!
 
 OR 
 Log-in with your What To Expect Account: 
E-Mail Address:
 
Password:
 Forgot Your Password? That&apos;s ok, we can send you a new one. Click Here 
 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler 
 
 Community Groups 
 Community Find a Group Start a Group My Preferences 
 Blogs 
 Word of Mom 
 Members&amp;Friends 
 Meet Members 
 Photos 
 Recent Photos Popular Photos 
 Local Resources 
 New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Find Groups Near You 
 Contests&amp;Deals 
 Diaper Deals Feeding Deals Wipes Deals More Family Deals Photo Contests Group Giveaways The WTE Bookstore 
 
 
 
 Group Main Page Message Board Events Meet Group Members Email Group Members Group Settings Browse All Groups My Preferences 
Related Articles
 
 Our First Community Swimming Pool Experience Cool Mother and the Neighborhood Pool Party Toddlers and Swimming Pool Safety Toddler Water Safety- What To Do When They Hate The Pool Ways to Prevent Toddler Drowning 
 
 Get great deals up to 90% off 
 for mom, baby, and the whole family 
 
 Featured Deal 

 55% Off Comfy (and Cool) Baby Carriers 
Show off your baby and your sense of style with this adjustable baby carrier from Hotslings.

 Get This Deal 
 
 Advertisement 


 Find a Group Whether you&apos;re looking for support from other expecting moms, a playgroup in your hometown, or even a Glee fan club, WTE has groups you&apos;ll love. Find a group now or start your own group . Advertisement Community » Groups » May 2011 Babies » Archives »Sweet vs Salt - Boy vs girl Hide Signatures Share this discussion: 
Sweet vs Salt - Boy vs girl
 Next Discussion» From: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 09:55 AM (1 of 18) 

Hello all, I&apos;m curious to those that have already previous children if you remembered what you craved or some of the symptoms you had.. I know this is all old wives tale stuff but I think it&apos;s funny... I heard if you crave sweet, its a girl, if you crave salt, it&apos;s a boy. I have 3 other children (2 are twins) and I craved sweet with both pregnancies and had girls... I am now craving salt - mexican food - but no sweet at all..... so any other old wives tales out there?



 From: nicelysaid To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 11:14 AM (2 of 18) 
I wish I could remember with my daughter what it was I wanted. I was pregnant during this time so I am thinking I liked sweets (who doesn&apos;t during the fall, christmas season? ) LOL. But with this one Im craving SWEETS... Sweet veggies, fruit, candy- chocolate milk... ect. Everyone thinks I&apos;m having a boy though.... soooo I don&apos;t know. I have a hard time thinking my husband can produce a female (this is our first child together) so I guess we&apos;ll see. Sorry I can&apos;t be more help- but we&apos;ll find out soon!
 From: scarlettssib To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 11:20 AM via the iPhone app (3 of 18) 
I have a dd and all I wanted was sweets. I have a natural sweet tooth though. This time I crave everything (Mexican food with dessert!)
 From: MAC0511 To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 11:26 AM (4 of 18) 
This is my first pregnancy and I never used to have a sweet tooth. I also used to love red meat, steaks, hamburgers, now I can barely look at red meat and all I crave is sweets and dairy. From my ultrasound last week, I am having a boy!!!
 From: kddp To: MAC0511 Posted: Nov-22 11:28 AM (5 of 18) 
This is my first, and I don&apos;t know yet, but when I told my friend I wanted meat and sweets, she said that she had craved meat and sweets with both of her little boys.
 From: Jullifferth To: ALL Posted: Nov-22 11:29 AM via the iPhone app (6 of 18) 
I do remember that in the first trimester with my little boy that sweets repulsed me! But after that they were alright. In this pregnancy I have been able to eat sweets the whole time. I hope that means this one is a girl.

I&apos;ve also heard that you are sicker with girls than with boys. And I&apos;ve been sicker this time too!
 From: steffanie1214 To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 11:55 AM (7 of 18) 
All I want to eat right now is dessert...anything with sugar....I could skip meals all together and just eat ice cream. I am having a Boy, so the theory isnt working with me :)
 &gt; From: JJ613 To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 12:01 PM via the android app (8 of 18) 
This is my first and my cravings are all over the place, so not sure I could determine what I am having! Pineapple, &quot;everything&quot; bagels with cream cheese, disco fries, and mashed potatoes are the foods I crave the most often.
 From: jjbmama To: ALL Posted: Nov-22 12:22 PM via the iPhone app (9 of 18) 
With both of my girls, I craved sweets. I could barely look at meat! With these twins, I&apos;m craving meat, with only an occasional sweet craving. I can&apos;t wait until the 15th to see what we are having!
 From: sappy_sappington To: nicelysaid Posted: Nov-22 12:45 PM (10 of 18) 

this time i really havent been craving anything in particular, i craved sweet and salty together my first pregnancy, strawberry milk and chips, ice cream and popcorn....... first was a girl, so maybe this will be a boy?



 From: ejo_is_me To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 12:58 PM (11 of 18) 
With DS the biggest craving I had was cheeseburgers with extra onions. Then later I wanted peanut m&amp;ms, but not nearly as much as I wanted savory stuff, like the burgers and pizza. We were living in Nashville at the time so I ate a lot of bbq as well. This time I had a huge aversion to sweets until a few weeks ago, and even now I would rather have chips than ice cream, but sweets are good sometimes. Aside from being a little more sick this pregnancy is pretty much identical to the one with DS. 
 
 
 
 

 From: MontbriandAR To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 01:13 PM (12 of 18) 
I craved frosting, ketchup (because it is loaded with sugar i guess), and apples.  I had a baby girl. this time i want salty foods i wonder if it will be a boy.
 I also noticed that when i was pregnant with her my boobs got muge larger faster and never had morning sickness and gained a lot of weight in the beginning like 6 pounds in the first trimester. This pregnancy my boobs are a little bigger but not much and was sick all the time until about 11 weeks and have only gained 2-3 pounds so far.

two completely different pregnancies! I am guessing a boy but guess i will have to wait and see
 
 
36 weeks above pic
 
 Make a pregnancy ticker 
 From: BlessingsRain To: MontbriandAR Posted: Nov-22 01:25 PM (13 of 18) 
I&apos;ve been craving salty things, mexican food, and tomato-based foods. I hate real tomatoes, but I&apos;ve been going crazy for ketchup, tomato soup, etc. I eat ramen noodles (salt!) and chex mix (more salt!) all the time. Taco Bell is the only fast food restaurant that ever sounds good.

That being said, my sister has predicted that I&apos;m having a girl. We won&apos;t know until the birth day, though!
 Mommy to one beautiful daughter, born May 10, 2011
 Number 2 on the way! EDD March 16, 2013 From: To: jjbmama Posted: Nov-22 01:33 PM via the iPhone app (14 of 18) 
I find out on the 15th too!!! Can&apos;t wait
 From: mommyof2girls0509 To: MAC0511 Posted: Nov-22 03:48 PM (15 of 18) 
Wow That is me! lol.. I drink three gallons of milk a week! I just cant seem to get enough and I want sweets anything sweet tasting. I have a feeling boy! us not til dec18th tho. With both Previous pregnancies I wanted spicy I loved me some slim jims and taco bell with both and they were girls...no such urges this time...
 Chentel 
  
 
 Make a pregnancy ticker From: sandra0609 To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 04:03 PM (16 of 18) 
I craved sweets with both my kids and they both are boys, this time i am into both but i think i am having a girl this time. They are old wives tales but when they work for some people start believe them lol My mom swears by the needle and theard, me not so much..
 

 
 From: rmadd To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 05:47 PM (17 of 18) 

 From: CaitlinsMommy08 To: firstandlast72 Posted: Nov-22 06:24 PM (18 of 18) 
I craved sweets big time last time which sucked becaused I had GD. I had a girl. This time I am craving salty like popcorn, french fries and chips. I am predicted a boy so we will see......
 
 **Kelli** 
 

 

 

 

 

 
 
 
 
 
 Back to May 2011 Babies Archives 
 
 
Browse

 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler Community Family Deals 
 
About

 About What to Expect What to Expect Foundation What to Expect Bookstore Everyday Health Network Contact Us Word of Mom 

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Advertising/Editorial Policy Advertise With Us Partnerships Press Room 

 Facebook Twitter Pinterest Help Feedback Careers 
 The material on this website is provided for educational purposes only and is not to be used for medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment, or in place of therapy or medical care. See additional information . Use of this site is subject to our terms of use and privacy policy. Advertising Notice 
This Site and third parties who place advertisements on this Site may collect and use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like to obtain more information about these advertising practices and to make choices about online behavioral advertising, please click here
	</body>
</document>
