<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004865" url="http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/tir-na-nog/" time="2012-07-12-21:23" support="2" score="0.001214477706049159" bingtitle="Tir Na Nog - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Irish, Bar Food ..." webtitle="Tir Na Nog - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Irish, Bar Food Restaurant Search">
			<query id="000172" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>Terrific food, particularly the burgers, seafood and ... Bar itself is awkward, difficult to get a good seat as ... You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 11183 Menus for New York City Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Brooklyn East Village/ LES Midtown East Midtown South / Chelsea Midtown West Murray Hill / Gramercy Soho/Trbca/FinDist Upper East Side Upper West Side Uptown Village/ W Village All Neighborhoods Bath Beach Bay Ridge Bedford-Stuyvesant Bensonhurst Borough Park Brighton Beach / Manhattan Beach Brooklyn Hts / DUMBO Brownsville Bushwick Canarsie Central Village / Noho Chelsea / Midtown South Chinatown / Two Bridges Cobble Hill / Carroll Grdns Coney Island Crown Heights Ditmas Park Dyker Heights East 30&apos;s East 40&apos;s East 50&apos;s East 60&apos;s East 70&apos;s East 80&apos;s East 90&apos;s East Harlem East New York East Village Financial District Flatbush Flatiron / Union Square Flatlands Fort Hamilton Ft. Greene / Clinton Hill Gramercy / Kips Bay Gravesend Harlem Kings Highway / Homecrest Lefferts Gardens Lower East Side Marine Park / Gerritsen Beach Midwood Mill Basin / Bergen Beach Morningside Heights Park Slope / Prospect Hts Prospect Park South / Kensington Sheepshead Bay Soho / Little Italy Sunset Park Tribeca Washington Hts / Inwood West 30&apos;s West 40&apos;s West 50&apos;s West 60&apos;s West 70&apos;s West 80&apos;s West 90&apos;s&amp;100&apos;s West Village Williamsburg / Greenpoint Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Burmese Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan New England Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Portuguese Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Sri Lankan Steakhouses Sushi Swiss Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
Tir Na Nog
 + SHARE 


 $$$$ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Irish, Bar Food 5 Penn Plaza , New York   NY 10001 40.751951 -73.993843 (At 33rd St) Subway Directions 
 
 Make a Reservation Online» 
 
 
 
 Phone: (212) 630-0249 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/tir-na-nog/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
User Ratings (Based on 28 reviews) 
 3.98 5 
 Food 4.2 Value 3.8 Service 3.9 Atmosphere 3.8 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (212) 630-0249 Fax: fax (212) 630-0247 Website: www.tirnanognyc.com Notes: Major Credit Cards Hours: Lunch Mon-Fri: 11:30am-4pm Dinner Mon-Sat: 4pm-10:30pm Sun: 4pm-10pm Brunch Sat-Sun: 11am-3pm Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner,
 
 Brunch Features: Live Entertainment,
 
 Online Reservations,
 
 Wheelchair Friendly,
 
 Accepts Credit Cards,
 
 Private Parties 
User Reviews
 
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by Mickey on 02/28/2012 
 
Best Irish Pub in NYC
 
Somehow, beer just tastes better at Tir na nOg, and not just Guinness and Harp, as it now as a line of craft beers like Leffe, Lagunitas and Smuttynose. I love the brunch on weekends, especially the traditional Irish breakfast and the Irish Cheddar omelet with bacon rashers. The smoked salmon is the best I&apos;ve ever had. The service is usually marvelous, with two lovely lasses tending to your every need. Yes, it gets crowded before Garden events, but it&apos;s exciting to feel the buzz of the crowd. It&apos;s less crowded at other times, especially on weekends.
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by irish gurl in nyc on 02/11/2012 
 
Awesome
 
Myy meal was so good, i had to ask the chef&apos;s name. Great portion size, great service, great fun. I will be back!
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by Cal on 11/26/2011 
 
Best Irish Pub in NYC
 
One of my favorite places for any occasion. Terrific food, particularly the burgers, seafood and Shepherd&apos;s Pie., and a great beer list. I love the staff, and the decor is unsurpassed.
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by Sinead on 01/08/2010 
 
Not recommended
 
My boyfriend has been meeting his buddies here for years. Because they are creatures of habit. I have finally convinced him never to go back. This place has become stale. They are cruising on past reviews. Girls restroom is unclean and never has toilet paper. Garbage can overflowing with paper towels. Surly bartenders...there&apos;s only one, tall nice-looking young guy who treats customers with some respect. The turnover of the crowd here is not to be believed. Everyone from Penn Station/Madison Square Garden meeting for one or two and leaving. Not a good ambience at all. Kinda like a bar located WITHIN Penn. Bar itself is awkward, difficult to get a good seat as you&apos;ve always got your back to the front door and any musicians playing. I&apos;ve been here numerous times and food is pub-grub at best.
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by Butch Carlton on 01/06/2010 
 
Best Irish Food Ever
 
I&apos;ve eaten at a fair amount of Irish pubs in NYC and Tir Na Nog has got to be tops on my list.....I&apos;m telling you the Sheperds Pie is THE BEST I&apos;ve ever had anywhere......that dish alone would keep me coming back forever.....I reecommend this place to all who want a cozy, clean, friendly Irish pub with GREAT food......
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by Dennis on 10/23/2009 
 
Great Dining near Madison Square Garden
 
I searched the internet prior to making reservations for dinner at Tir Na Nog and had no idea how great this restaurant would be. The food and service were excellent and the maitre d&apos;has a great personality and honored our reservation even though we were 45 minutes late. Topping it off, we had a great view of the Garden from our table. Try Tir Na Nog, you won&apos;t be disappointed!
 Tir Na Nog 
 Posted by PPP on 02/11/2009 
 
Well worth a visit!
 
Very nice lunch spot. The grilled salmon is delicious, and the scallops are perfectly done as well. Great service. WIll certainly return!
 
 
 1 2 3 4 › » 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near Tir Na Nog
 Regal E-Walk Stadium 13&amp;RPX 
247 W. 42nd St.

New York
 The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Brave  (PG) Brave 3D  (PG) Seeking a Friend for the End of the World  (R) Rock of Ages  (PG-13) Show More [+] More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages NYC Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
