<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004679" url="http://www.tmz.com/2007/08/13/britney-wont-do-coke-will-do-fake-accent/" time="2012-07-12-21:10" support="6" score="0.005367558359727416" bingtitle="Britney Won&apos;t Do Coke, Will Do Fake Accent | TMZ.com" webtitle="Britney Wont Do Coke, Will Do Fake Accent | TMZ.com">
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="226"/>
	<description>The popwreck shambled up to the fast food restaurant&apos;s ... you&apos;ll be sent a link via email to confirm your ... problem with Mexicans getting my order wrong. You ...</description>
	<body>
		TMZ MY TMZ 
 SIGN IN 
SIGN IN / REGISTER
 What&apos;s your email address? 
 

 I&apos;m already a member I&apos;m already a member 
 I&apos;m new I &apos;m new 
Voice yourself on TMZ today, join in on the discussions and personalize your avatar!
 What&apos;s your password? Remember me    FORGOT YOUR PASSWORD? 
CREATE A TMZ
ACCOUNT TO:

 Chat with the TMZ community about the craziest stories. Create a profile and customize your avatar. Add stories to your link page. See your collection of comments and news. Share your experience on Facebook and many other networks. Sign up to the left and start customizing your TMZ experience. 
 
 CELEBS VIDEOS PHOTOS 
 Your name (required): -- Enter your name. Your email address (required): -- Enter your email address. Phone Number (required): -- Enter your phone number. Subject (required): -- Please write a subject. Your Tip -- Please write a tip. 
 
 Usher Wants to Settle w/ Tameka After Jet Ski Tragedy 
 
 Jennifer Lopez -- I Might Come Back to Idol, I Might Not
 
 
 Colin Farrell -- Shirtless&amp;Ripped in Rio 
 
 Kate Upton -- I Had NO Liquor at Tigers Game
 
 
 Sublime Bassist -- What I Got Is One Busted Shoulder 
 
 Home 
Britney Won&apos;t Do Coke, Will Do Fake Accent
 8/13/2007 2:37 PM PDT BY TMZ STAFF Britney Won&apos;t Do Coke, Will Do Fake Accent Who says Britney Spears doesn&apos;t love a diversity of cuisines? McDonald&apos;s? Of course. Taco Bell? Claro que si! Carl&apos;s Jr.? Mais oui, ya&apos;ll!


The popwreck shambled up to the fast food restaurant&apos;s drive-thru after filming her music video last Tuesday night, looking pretty good -- for her -- with a full face of make-up. There&apos;s no denying her love of greasy food, but girl definitely loves herself some Fanta too -- yelling at the speaker with a truly horrendous Spanish accent, trying to emphasize how crucial the fruity soda was to her. (Fanta is, of course, a product of the good ol&apos; US of A. And did we mention she was in L.A.? )

Spears even had her own bodyguard walk through the drive-thru next to her car to both keep the paps away and hand over her food when it was ready. She then sped off into the night, Fanta-fixed and everything.

 
 Related 

Articles

 Britney -- The Last Straw 
 &quot;Brainiac&quot; Brit Drops a Hit, Run
 
 Tweet   63 COMMENTS See More: Paparazzi Video ,  Britney Spears Hide these Add to My Links    63 COMMENTS 
 
 
 New Readers COMMENT 
 
SIGN UP AND COMMENT
 SIGN IN 
 Name: E-mail: Please check your inbox ... your comment will not appear until you have confirmed your identity via email. 
MEMBER SIGN IN
 I&apos;M NEW 
 E-mail: Password: 
 Your comments: 
When you enter your name and email address you&apos;ll be sent a link via email to confirm your comment. Please keep your comments relevant to this post. Email addresses are never displayed, but they are required to confirm your comments. 

To create a live link, simply type the URL (including http://) or email address and we will make the link live for you. You can put up to 3 URLs in your comments. Line breaks and paragraphs are automatically converted—no need to use&lt;p&gt;or&lt;br /&gt;tags.
 | 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Most Recent | Next 15 Comments 1. 

 
 Stan     
 
McDonalds is a classy restaurant y&apos;all
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 2. 

 
 Hop Off     
 
Get off her cl*t, TMZ. Kevin is already lunching down there.

Try McDonalds for a more enjoyable meal.
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 3. 

 
 Donna     
 
God, how ridiculous that this girl can&apos;t even order her dinner without the paps all up in her buisness!!! I&apos;m going to say it once again, no wonder she&apos;s out of her mind..can&apos;t the girl just eat in peace??????
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 4. 

 
 weneedtostop.com     
 
What&apos;s next? Can&apos;t wait...lol
Brit stops at a redlight....ooooooo LOL
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 5. 

 
 NYC     
 
This footage is OLD !!!!. MUST be a slow day !!!! .
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 6. 

 
 Tangie     
 
She&apos;s crazy, and looks like a real dolt ordering her food, but those camera&apos;s in your face at a frickin drive-thru are enough to drive someone to insanity.
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 7. 

 
 Carlos     
 
Fanta is a German drink. It might be owned by Coca Cola now but it started in Germany during WWII
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 8. 

 
 LRT     
 
GROW UP!
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 9. 

 
 Mikey     
 
BREAKING TMZ BRITTNEY SPEARS NEWS:

SHE ORDERED A SODA AT MCDONALDS! AND TMZ WAS FIRST TO FIND OUT WHAT BRAND!
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 10. 

 
 KWIllyVox     
 
FANTA&apos;S GERMAN YOU DOLTS....It was created in WW2 due to the embargo of western imports.
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 11. 

 
 tuna marie     
 
she is a pig, why can&apos;t she stay in her big mansion for once. if i had her home, i wouldn&apos;t be out trolliping all the time.
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 12. 

 
 Debbie     
 
It sounds like she was mocking the drive through employee, not the Fanta drink. She sounds prejudice to me or maybe she just enjoys making fun of the way people talk.
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 13. 

 
 Stan     
 
12. It sounds like she was mocking the drive through employee, not the Fanta drink. She sounds prejudice to me or maybe she just enjoys making fun of the way people talk.

Posted at 2:12PM on Aug 13th 2007 by Debbie
---------------------------------------------------------------------
How is that prejudiced ? I have the same problem with Mexicans getting my order wrong. You have to talk like them

 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 14. 

 
 angee     
 
Crazy.. and I am not talking about Britney. I mean come one.. take a &quot;few shots&quot; of her and then let her go to the Window to get her Food in Peace! You would think the Price of Britney Pictures would be going down considering there are SO MANY out there! These Photogs need to get a LIfe!
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote 15. 

 
 kygirll     
 
After watching this, I can&apos;t imagine what it would be like to have a hoard of photographers after you every minute of the day. No wonder she&apos;s nuts.
 1795 days ago Reply     0 0 Clear Vote | 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Most Recent | Next 15 Comments 
TMZ LIVE!
 RECENT EPISODES 
 Wednesday&apos;s 
 TMZ Live: Charlie Sheen ... Here Comes the&apos;Idol&apos;Judge? 
 
We&apos;re pretty sure it started as a joke ... but now that Charlie Sheen seems into it -- could he be the next &quot;American Idol&quot; judge? We think it&apos;s not the worst idea ever.Plus, Daniel Tosh apologizes for spewing rape jokes at a female heckler during a stand-up gig! Did Tosh cross…
 
 Tuesday&apos;s TMZ Live: Kris Humphries -- Off… 119 Monday&apos;s TMZ Live: Justin Bieber -- Too… 111 Friday&apos;s TMZ Live: Justin Bieber --… 60 
 Also Available on iTunes View All CANCEL AND CLOSE VIEW PAST EPISODES 
AROUND THE WEB
 
PHOTOS
 15 View Gallery Kristin Chenoweth Hospitalized After Accident on&apos;The Good Wife&apos; 

 
HOT VIDEOS
 RAW AND UNCUT 
 LUKE BRYAN 
 Yes, I Checked My Watch During National Anthem TMZ ON TV 
 TMZ TV Full Episode: 
 Wednesday 07/11/12 HOT STORY
	</body>
</document>
