<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004993" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/257730-nutritional-facts-on-restaurant-menus/" time="2012-07-12-21:31" support="3" score="0.012091303669477011" bingtitle="Nutritional Restaurant Menus | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Nutritional  Restaurant Menus | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001427" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Because of this significant lifestyle change ... estimates that an average meal at a fast food restaurant can top ... would let diners know how much fat or the number of ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Nutrition Information for Restaurants Nutrition for Restaurants Nutritional Facts on Restaurant Menus 
 
 Nutritional Facts on Restaurant Menus 
 Sep 24, 2010 | By Chris Dinesen Rogers Photo Credit RESTAURANT image by Com Evolution from Fotolia.com 
There&apos;s no denying the pleasure of eating out and being spared the cooking and cleaning time. The frequency with which people dine out has increased dramatically in the last 40 years, according to the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation. Because of this significant lifestyle change, concerns exist regarding the quality of food and whether these meals are healthy additions to consumers&apos; diets. Nutritional facts on restaurant menus could enlighten diners to exactly what they are consuming.
 
Significance

Most Americans do not realize how many calories or how much fat they consume when they eat out, according to a 2006 study in the American Journal of Public Health. This fact sets up a scenario for overeating. The American Diabetes Association estimates that an average meal at a fast food restaurant can top 1,000 calories or more. The recommended daily calorie intake for active adult women is 2,200 to 2,400 calories.
 
Considerations

Part of the problem is perception -- diners simply may not realize how much they are eating due to exaggerated portion sizes. A 2003 study in the Journal of the American Medical Association found that portion sizes increased significantly from 1977 to 1998, especially at fast food restaurants and in-home meals. Families are also eating out more frequently. A 2007 study in Public Health Nutrition found that most families dined out for one or more family meals each week.
 
Effects

Some restaurants may make nutritional information available at their businesses. Other establishments provide this information online. However, having the facts available at the time of purchase may help patrons make better food choices. A 2009 study in the Journal of Adolescent Health showed that if this information is present on menus, women are more likely to order lower calorie meals, but men&apos;s choices were unaffected by the availability of nutritional content.
 
Opposition

Restaurant owners may disagree with the need to print nutritional information, citing cost of printing new menus and educating their staff. With restaurants with frequently changing menus, these can be a valid concern. In addition to the menu, restaurant owners must determine calorie counts, perhaps using the services of a professional dietician.
 
Examples

Without nutritional information on menus, diners are oblivious to the staggering calorie counts of some menu items. For example, you may assume a salad is a healthy meal. However, add cheese, high-fat dressings and other additions, and the calorie count soars. Nutritional information on menus would let diners know how much fat or the number of calories their meals contain.
 
References

 Robert Wood Johnson Foundation: Menu Labeling: Does Providing Nutrition Information at the Point of Purchase Affect Consumer Behavior? &quot;American Journal of Public Health&quot;; Attacking the Obesity Epidemic: The Potential Health Benefits of Providing Nutrition Information in Restaurants; S. Burton et al.; September 2006 &quot;Journal of the American Medical Association&quot;; Patterns and Trends in Food Portion Sizes, 1977-1998; S. Nielsen and B. Popkin; January 2003 &quot;Public Health Nutrition&quot;; Fast Food for Family Meals: Relationships With Parent and Adolescent Food Intake, Home Food Availability and Weight Status; K. Boutelle et al.; January 2007 &quot;Journal of Adolescent Health&quot;; Does Calorie Information Promote Lower Calorie Fast Food Choices Among College Students?; M. Gerend; January 2009 
 
Article reviewed by Samantha Davidson Last updated on: Sep 24, 2010
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 T.G.I. Friday&apos;s Restaurant Nutritional Facts 
 
 Restaurants With Nutrition Information 
 
 How to Compare the Nutritional Value of Foods From Restaurants 
 
 Restaurants That Serve Heart-Healthy Foods 
 
 Fast Food Restaurant Nutrition 
 
 Restaurant Diet Facts 
 
 Cracker Barrel Restaurant Menus&amp;Fat Grams 
 
 About Bennigan&apos;s Restaurant Nutritional Facts 
 
 Food Safety Warnings on Restaurant Menus 
 
 Olive Garden Restaurant Nutrition Information 
 
 Fridays Restaurant Nutritional Facts 
 
 Applebee&apos;s Restaurant Nutrition 
 
 Eating Out Restaurant Weight Loss Guide 
 
 Dragon Chinese Restaurant Nutritional Information 
 
 Nutritional Labeling in Restaurants 
 
 Applebee&apos;s Low-Cholesterol Restaurant Meals 
 
 Nutritional Value for Applebee&apos;s Restaurant Menu 
 
 Weight Watchers Restaurant Nutrition Facts 
 
 Duchess Restaurant Nutrition Information 
 
 Nutrition Information for Restaurant Chains 
 more Nutrition For Restaurants advertisement 
 You May Also Be Interested In 
 Duchess Restaurant Nutrition Information Nutrition Facts on Menus Duchess Restaurant Nutrition Nutritional Information on Restaurant Menus Nutritional Information on Menus Restaurant Menus with Nutritional Information Nutritional Restaurant Nutritional Menus Nutrition and Menu for Restraunts Examples of Healthy Restaurant Menus Restaurant Nutrition Menus Restaurants&apos; Nutrition Menues Rrestaurant Healthy Food Menu Eamples Nutritional Restaurant Menus Livestrong Resturant Menus Duchess Menu Nutrition Nutritional Facts on Menus Health Facts About Reasturant Meals Restaurant Nutriional Menus Nutrition Information on Menus Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
