<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004160" url="http://laist.com/news/2012/01/" time="2012-07-12-20:24" support="12" score="0.005281601684346809" bingtitle="News: January 2012 Archives: LAist" webtitle="News: January 2012 Archives: LAist">
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000665" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001262" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="000259" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000384" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001294" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000165" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>... surprising as it is, Michael Jackson didn&apos;t leave ... The bandit responsible for a series of fast food restaurant ... American Apparel, with 18 stores in LA, you can look ...</description>
	<body>
		77° 
 our cities:
 Austin Chicago London Los Angeles New York City San Francisco Shanghai Toronto Washington DC 
 
 Adopt a Black Cat for $13 This Friday the 13th featured Why Angelenos Say Nay to the Bus, Yay to the Car Comedians Fire Back at Daniel Tosh&apos;s Heckler 
 
News
 
Tuesday, January 31, 2012
 
 Lakers and Ducks Get Lopsided Yet Ho-Hum Wins 
 
After a night where two of the three best teams in the NBA Western Conference matched up and featured a ferocious dunk, somehow Tuesday night was a bit of a breather on the excitement meter in Southern California. Hell, only the last two championship winning teams in Southern California played. more › 
 Jimmy Bramlett 
 Extra, Extra: Homeboy Shoutout, Madonna&apos;s Nervous,&amp;&quot;Death By Los Angeles&quot; 
 
In tonight&apos;s Extra, Extra we&apos;ve got Homeboy making headlines, why Madonna is nervous about a football game, an exploration of &quot;Death By Los Angeles&quot; and more news bites of the day. Plus: Keep up with us on Facebook , and follow us on Twitter: @LAist @LAistFood @LAistSports . more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Summer Touch Football Banned At Marina Del Rey Beaches: Who Knew? 
 
The Board of Supervisors approved a set of regulation changes governing Marina del Rey beaches and harbors today, one of them being a continuance of the ban on summer touch football. Did anyone out there know this ban existed? more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
Tuesday, January 31, 2012
 
 Teacher Accused of Blindfolding Kids and Feeding Them His Semen Said it Was a &quot;Tasting Game&quot; 
 
Miramonte Elementary School teacher Mark Berndt, 61, has been arrested and his highly questionable teaching methods are under scrutiny following an extensive investigation into accusations he blindfolded students and had them tasting his semen fed to them by spoon. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Ruh-Roh! PetSmart Plants New Billboard Atop Local Community Pet Store [UPDATED] 
 
A David versus Goliath struggle has erupted in West Hollywood, and the local pet-loving community is voicing its opinions loud and clear. Yesterday, a community pet shop with just two Los Angeles locations received an unexpected two-year anniversary present atop their Santa Monica Boulevard store. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Okay, Who Is Running the Fake Eric Garcetti Twitter Account? 
 
Here&apos;s one Twitter account that is definitely not going to earn that blue &quot;verified account&quot; checkmark: A fake Eric Garcetti has been Tweeting since January 22, spreading mostly dopey messages of eco-friendliness and love of KCRW. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Fighting To Save The Rare San Bernardino Flying Squirrel 
 
Californians, have you ever witnessed the beauty of a San Bernardino flying squirrel soaring above among the treetops? Yes? You&apos;re lucky, and we want photos. No? Sadly, you&apos;re not alone. The species has suffered a tremendous decline over the years, but the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service announced today that they will consider protecting the squirrel under the Endangered Species Act. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Wild Car Chase Ends With Suspect Shooting at Police Dog (And Getting Arrested) 
 
A wild car chase last night found California Highway Patrol and LAPD officers pursuing a man and a woman as they drove from Diamond Bar to South Los Angeles in a stolen car, and with one of the suspects allegedly firing shots at a police dog. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Former L.A. Times Employee Warns Of Impending Massive Writer Layoff 
 
A freshly fired Los Angeles Times pressman shared some shocking details about the publication&apos;s termination policies, recent employee suicides and impending layoff of writers with The Frying Pan editor Steven Mikulan . more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Obamajam, First Lady Edition? Michelle Obama in Town Today and Tomorrow 
 
Normally, when the President arrives in town, we cluck about it for days beforehand because we&apos;re all so terrified that we&apos;ll be the unlucky bastards stuck on Pico Blvd. for three hours. But we haven&apos;t heard much about traffic delays leading up to the arrival of Michelle Obama today, and we&apos;re hoping that it stays that way. more › 
 Jessica Pauline Ogilvie 
 LAPD Shuts Down Chatsworth&apos;s Last Medical Marijuana Dispensary 
 
It was the last medical marijuana dispensary standing. While a ban of all medical marijuana dispensaries operating in the City of Los Angeles is in the works, the LAPD continues to crack down and wrapped their storefront sweep in Chatsworth Monday afternoon. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 &quot;Sexually frustrated&quot; Meth-Smoking Man Busted for Driving Naked [UPDATED] 
 
A 34-year-old Glendale man was arrested last week on suspicion of driving while high on meth and naked from the waist down. Umar Kahn, a computer technician, told Glendale Police officers who pulled him over early last Thursday morning for running a stop sign that he had taken off his pants and underwear because he was &quot;sexually frustrated and hadn&apos;t had sex in a month.&quot; more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 South L.A. Teacher Accused of Performing Bondage Acts on Elementary School Students 
 
It&apos;s not every day that you come across a story so vile that it&apos;s difficult to write, but here we go: a South L.A. elementary school teacher is being accused of binding and gagging students, covering them with roaches, and possibly feeding some of them his semen from a spoon. more › 
 Jessica Pauline Ogilvie 
 Woman Shot&amp;Killed At Hollywood Thai Restaurant Identified 
 
The woman who was shot and killed at a Hollywood Thai restaurant Friday night was identified Monday by the coroner&apos;s office. Jitrujee Buatet, 44, was shot once and pronounced dead at a local hospital. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Kaiser Healthcare Workers Holding One of Largest Strikes in Hospital&apos;s History 
 
If you have an appointment at Kaiser today, you might want to call ahead -- one of the largest healthcare worker strikes in the hospital&apos;s history is happening today, reports NBC Los Angeles . more › 
 Jessica Pauline Ogilvie 
Monday, January 30, 2012
 
 Clippers and Blake Griffin Explode All Over the Thunder 
 
Brent Barry of NBA TV called it their signature win of the season, even more than their overtime win over the Miami Heat. The Clippers indeed put on a spectacular performance in their 112-100 thrashing over the Oklahoma City Thunder, owners of the best record in the NBA. more › 
 Jimmy Bramlett 
 Extra, Extra: Boston Comes to L.A., a Doughnut Shop is Compromised, and the Kardashians Reign Supreme 
 
In tonight&apos;s Extra, Extra, a Boston cable show comes to local TV, a woman drives into a doughnut shop, and Kourtney and Kim Kardashian kill it in their show&apos;s season finale. Plus: Keep up with us on Facebook , and follow us on Twitter: @LAist @LAistFood @LAistSports . more › 
 Jessica Pauline Ogilvie 
 Fire Destroys 70 Percent of South L.A. Furtinure Store&apos;s Inventory 
 
A fire in a South L.A. furniture store destroyed nearly 70 percent of the business&apos; inventory, reports NBC Los Angeles . The store, C and L Furniture, is located at 6245 S. Manhattan Place. more › 
 Jessica Pauline Ogilvie 
 Occupiers Attempt Citizen&apos;s Arrest of San Diego&apos;s Mayor 
 
Members of Occupy San Diego tried to make a citizen&apos;s arrest of their mayor, Jerry Sanders, but, alas, they were not successful. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Frizzies VS Formaldehyde: Brazilian Blowout Settlement Orders Honest Advertising 
 
A settlement requiring the Brazilian Blowout manufacturer to warn consumers and hair stylists of the health risks associated with its products was announced today, making it the first government enforceable action in the U.S. to address the exposures of formaldehyde gas associated with said products. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 CicLAvia&apos;s April 15, 2012 Route Announced! 
 
Get your bicycle bells tuned up, because CicLAvia is back on April 15, and today the route map makes its debut. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Man Struck&amp;Killed By Airplane Propeller 
 
A man died this morning at Gillespie Field in El Cajon after attempting to hand-crank a Piper Cherokee, a light aircraft designed for flight training, air taxi and personal use. During his attempt, the man was struck in the head by an airplane propeller around 8:30am. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Vegas-Bound? Legionnaires Disease Bacteria Found in Luxor&apos;s Water 
 
Is your destination Vegas? This story might gross you out. Health officials in Sin City confirm the presence of the bacteria that causes Legionnaires&apos; disease was recently found in water samples from the Egyptian-themed hotel-casino following the death of a guest from the form of pneumonia. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Loserville, USA: Are So Many Cities Seriously That Much Better Than L.A.? 
 
When it comes to the classic head-to-head comparison throwdown between Los Angeles and other major U.S. cities, we&apos;re bested by Boston, kicked to the curb by Kansas City, MO, and less preferable than both Portlands...just to name a few. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Pinkberry Co-Founder Pleads Not Guilty To Beating Transient, Granted One More International Business Trip 
 
Pinkberry co-founder Young Lee pleaded not guilty today to assaulting a transient and is currently free on $60,000 bail. On June 15, 2011, the 47-year-old allegedly chased and beat a homeless man with a tire iron, breaking the man&apos;s left forearm and cutting his head. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 WTF Is Going On With the Sunset Junction Sign and That Strange New Concrete Corner Wall? 
 
If you&apos;ve been along Sunset Boulevard in the well-known area of Sunset Junction, you might have noticed a few strange changes at the intersection. In case you were wondering WTF is happening with the Sunset Junction sign, and why on earth there&apos;s a concrete block wall up on the corner, the Eastsider LA has provided some much-needed answers. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 Oops: Southwest Flight From LA Knocks Over Light Pole On Its Way to the Gate in Denver 
 
Some passengers aboard a Southwest flight from Los Angeles had a less-than-smooth arrival this morning in Denver. Flight 792 managed to knock over a light pole on its way to the gate, say airport officials in the Mile-High City, reports TheDenverChannel.com . more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 7 Reasons to Love L.A.: Flamingos, Wilco, Picca&amp;More 
               
There are thousands of stories to tell in Los Angeles, but sometimes a picture says so much more. Thanks to our LAist Featured Photos Pool on Flickr, here are 7 moments worth taking a second look at in our 7 Reasons to Love L.A. series. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 South Pasadena Scores Burbank&apos;s Peacekeeper For $1 
 
Sometimes $1 can go a long way, as in the case of a recent Peacekeeper sale by Burbank to South Pasadena. Primarily used for rescues and barricades between a potential shooter and a resident or police, the Peacekeeper saw little action in Burbank, except during SWAT exercises. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Ex-LAPD Detective&apos;s Trial Begins Today for 1986 Murder of Her Former Boyfriend&apos;s New Bride 
 
The controversial case against former Los Angeles police detective Stephanie Lazarus has moved ahead to the trial phase today, with the start of jury selection. Lazarus is the accused in the 1986 murder of Sherri Rasmussen, a nursing director who had recently married Lazarus&apos; ex-boyfriend, John Ruetten. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 International Twitter Fail: British Tourists Arrested Over Tweets About Destroying America, Digging Up Marilyn Monroe 
 
Last Monday, two British tourists landed at Los Angeles International Airport (LAX) and were greeted with handcuffs. The reason for their detainment did not stem from inappropriate behavior during their flight to the U.S. Rather, Homeland Security had flagged two of the male tourists&apos; tweets leading up to his trip as potential threats to America. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Man Spends His 31st Birthday Stabbing Two Housemates To Death, Injuring A Third [UPDATED] 
 
A homicide investigation was underway this morning after a man allegedly stabbed two women to death and injured a man in a shared condominium in Torrance. Deputies received a call at 8:23pm on Sunday and responded to the scene of the murders: a complex in the 21800 block of South Vermont Avenue near Harbor-UCLA Medical Center. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
Sunday, January 29, 2012
 
 Extra, Extra: No Donkey Semen on &apos;Fear Factor,&apos; Conservatives Hate Miley&amp;South Pasadena&apos;s $1 Tank 
 
In tonight&apos;s Extra, Extra, Burbank sells a tank for $1, conservative groups aren&apos;t big on Miley Cyrus these days and Occupy Oakland. Plus: Keep up with us on Facebook , and follow us on Twitter: @LAist @LAistFood @LAistSports . more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Overheard in L.A.: Serial Killers—They&apos;re Just Like Us! 
 
There’s no predicting the shenanigans that can go down at L.A. after parties. One lucky lady has found a fail-proof method to stay safe at such events. This week’s Overheard in L.A. round-up includes overheard conversation on amateur astronomer night, Shiva and serial killers. more › 
 Guest Writer 
 Pet Store Forgives Remorseful Puppy-Nappers Who Sent &apos;I&apos;m Sorry&apos; Note and Restitution 
 
A pet store in Orange County relented and dropped the case against two thieves who snatched a chow puppy from the store last week. Previously, the puppy-nappers sent an &quot;I&apos;m sorry&quot; note and a wad with $600 in cash . more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Guy Caught Driving Without Pants Tells Police: &apos;My Thing is the Freedom&apos; 
 
A man was arrested in Glendale this week after police caught him driving pantsless. Police said that during their investigation of Khan, they discovered that he likes driving around at night pantsless, looking for a cul-de-sac or driveway to masturbate in. more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
Saturday, January 28, 2012
 
 Extra, Extra: Cynthia Nixon &apos;Gay By Choice,&apos; &apos;The Forest Of Disappearing Children&apos;&amp;Why California&apos;s Being Sued 
 
In tonight&apos;s Extra, Extra, tales of &quot;The Forest of Disappearing Children,&quot; coyote survival, California failing in free education and a LAX security scare. Plus: Keep up with us on Facebook , and follow us on Twitter: @LAist @LAistFood @LAistSports . more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 A Tree Branch Fell on a Guy in Brentwood, But Don&apos;t Worry He&apos;s Gonna Live 
 
A really big tree branch fell on a guy in Brentwood Park this afternoon. Although there aren&apos;t a whole lot of details about what happened, it seems safe to say that he&apos;s going to be making a full recovery. more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 History Lesson: Infographic Likens SOPA To The House Committee On Un-American Activities&apos; Hollywood Blacklist 
 
&quot; SOPA And The Film Industry ,&quot; an eye-opening infographic created by Anne Rhodes, shows Hollywood&apos;s longtime war on technology using censorship and legislation as weapons of choice. The visual timeline asks the question, &quot;Has Hollywood already forgotten the 1950s and the Hollywood blacklist?&quot; more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 How Walkable Is Your Metro Rail Station? 
 
 More Than Red Cars , a blog examining &quot;the obscure, offbeat and half-forgotten transportation history of Southern California,&quot; recently ranked L.A&apos;s Metro Rail stations by their Walk Score , a number assigned to a location illustrating its proximity to amenities like grocery stores, coffee shops and eateries. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Maritime Smugglers Busted In Malibu With Over 1,000 Pounds Of Pot 
 
Federal government officials seized over 1,000 pounds of marijuana from a Mexican panga boat beached at Malibu&apos;s Pirate&apos;s Cove on Friday night. Three male suspects were arrested, and sheriff&apos;s deputies are on the hunt for a fourth possible smuggler. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Police Investigate Connection Between Two Women Whose Bodies Were Dumped Near Freeways 
 
Police said they are investigating the very thing that has been worrying residents in Lincoln Heights : whether there&apos;s any connection between the cases of two women in the neighborhood who mysteriously disappeared before turning up dead on the side of the freeway. more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Woman Shot&amp;Killed At Hollywood Thai Restaurant 
 
A shooting at a Thai restaurant in Hollywood on Friday night leaves one woman dead and a man injured. The incident occurred at Pink Pepper on Hollywood Boulevard and was reported to police at 10:17pm. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
 Remorseful Puppy Thieves Send &apos;I&apos;m Sorry&apos; Note and $600 to Pet Store 
 
A pair of thieves wanted a pet store in Orange County to know that they were so sorry that they stole a chow puppy, so they sent the store a condolence letter and $600.

The couple&apos;s puppy heist last Thursday was caught on a surveillance tape. more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Gang Shooting Near Downtown L.A. Nightclub Leaves One Man Dead, Three Wounded [UPDATED] 
 
A gang shooting near the Mayan in Downtown Los Angeles early Saturday morning leaves one man dead and three others wounded. Police arrived on the scene around 2:45am following a report of an argument outside the nightclub at 1038 South Hill Street. A gang member had shot one of his rivals, who later died at a local hospital, in the head and wounded a trio of others. more › 
 Lauren Lloyd 
Friday, January 27, 2012
 
 Extra, Extra: 175 Pounds of Nicorette, Another Lap-Band Investigation&amp;Why Downtown Businesses Love CicLAvia 
 
In tonight&apos;s Extra, Extra, someone killed their neighbors&apos; chihuahua with a golf club, downtown business love CicLAvia and 175 pounds of Nicorette gum looks as disgusting as you might imagine. Plus: Keep up with us on Facebook , and follow us on Twitter: @LAist @LAistFood @LAistSports . more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Female UCLA Student Sexually Assaulted On Campus Near Residence Hall 
 
University police say that a UCLA student was sexually assaulted near a residence hall on campus early this morning.

A male suspect called out to a female student climbing what are called the Saxon Steps before he sexually assaulted her. more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Discovery of Bree&apos;Anna Guzman&apos;s Body Dumped Near Freeway Worries Lincoln Heights Community [UPDATED] 
 
The Lincoln Heights community where resident Bree&apos;Anna Guzman was last seen a month ago has been on high-alert since she left to go to the drug store on December and never returned. But that fear has only been heightened since her family identified her as the woman whose body was found near a freeway on-ramp in Silver Lake yesterday morning. more › 
 Emma G. Gallegos 
 Veteran LAPD Detective Busted For Allegedly Swiping Money From a Suspect 
 
The Los Angeles Police Department have announced the arrest of one of their veteran detectives on suspicion of stealing money from a suspect&apos;s house. 

Detective II Ramon Alvarez, who has 25 years with the force and is assigned to Gang and Narcotics Division, was arrested January 27 for violation of Penal Code 487, Grand Theft. more › 
 Lindsay William-Ross 
 L.A. Writer Abducted by Pirates While Researching Book About Pirates 
 
Michael Scott Moore, a writer from Manhattan Beach, was researching a book about pirates in Somalia when he was abducted by a group of 15 men, and he&apos;s currently being held hostage, reports the Huffington Post . more › 
 Jessica Pauline Ogilvie 
 Thanks to This Week&apos;s Advertisers 
 
We would like to take a moment to thank this week&apos;s advertisers on LAist.
	</body>
</document>
