<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004383" url="http://www.thailandlife.com/1997-2001/fast-food-restaurants-in-thailand.html" time="2012-07-12-20:37" support="1" score="0.002914681557474729" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurants in Thailand - Thailand Life" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurants in Thailand - Thailand Life">
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>Lots of teenagers in Thailand like to eat at a fast food restaurant becasue now it has ... The counter where you order foods inside a KFC</description>
	<body>
		You are here: (2) My Life Aged 12-15 Fast Food Restaurants in Thailand 
 Thailand Life 

Life of a Thai Teenager
 
 Home Press Room&amp;Contact 
 
 Skip to content 
 
Fast Food Restaurants in Thailand
 Wednesday, 07 February 2007 00:17 Panrit&quot;Gor&quot;Daoruang &quot;Can 
you guess what Thai people like eating the most?&quot;
Answer at the bottom. 
 I really like to eat fast food because it&apos;s quick, 
I don&apos;t have to wait long time. I like to eat Burger King, my favourite 
burger is Double Cheese Burger with Becon. The French Fries there are 
really good, not the same as KFC which is very dry but I think the Fries 
at McDonalds is best. 
 
 Lots of teenagers in Thailand like to eat at a fast 
food restaurant becasue now it has become fashionable for Thai teenagers. 
When Thai boys go out with their girlfriend, they always go to fast 
food restaurant because it is expensive and she will be impress. Older 
Thai people call fast food&quot;junk food&quot;, Thai peole say that 
they just put a piece of meat and vegetable in the roll which is not 
that useful for the body. They said Thai food has more nutrition. 
 I took the following prices from three popular fast 
food restaurants: KFC, McDonalds and Burger King. I did this at the 
end of January 2001. You can compare the prices with your own country 
($1 = 42 baht) or see how the menu varies. 
 
 
 McDONALDS 
 Burgers: Hamburger
 19 baht Cheese burger 27 baht Double cheese burger
 50 baht Big Mac 55 baht Pork burger 19 baht Samurai pork burger 45 baht Fillet-o-fish 45 baht 
 
 Others: McChicken
 45 baht Chicken McCrispy 2 pcs 55 baht Chicken McNutget 4 pcs
 45 baht Mac Fried s/m/l 22/30/35 baht 
 
 Beverages: Coke, Sprite, Fanta
 
 Reg. 22 baht
L. 26 baht 
 Pineapple juice Reg. 24 baht
L. 27 baht Hot coffee
 20 baht Iced coffee/Milo/Lemontea 26 baht Mineral water 12 baht Milk 10 baht 
 
 Deserts: Pies (Taro, Pineapple, 
 corn) 25 baht Ice cream cone 7 baht Sundaes (Chocolate, Strawberry, 
 Toddy palm) 29 baht 
 
 
 
 
 
 Outside of KFC at Siam 
 Square. 
 The counter where you 
 order foods inside a KFC 
 
 
 
 
 I really like eating 
 the Double cheeseburger with bacon here! 
 A big sign of McDonalds 
 by side the road. 
 
 KFC BURGER 
 KING 
 Burger: Colonel Burger 29 baht Nuggets (6/10 pcs) 45/65 baht Colonel&apos;s choice fillet Burger 45 baht Big Catch Fish Burger 39 baht 
 
 Chicken Selection: 1/2 pcs 28/55 baht 3/6 pcs 80/157 baht 10/15 pcs 260/379 baht 
 
 Others: Mashed potato (s/l)
 15/33 baht Coleslaw (s/l) 15/33 baht French Fries (s/l/jumbo) 22/30/35 baht 
 
 Drinks: Iced tea 25 baht Iced coffee 30 baht Hot tea 20 baht Hot coffee 20 baht Pepsi, 7up, Mirinda 20 baht 
 
 Burger: Whopper/cheese
 65/75 baht Whopper jr./cheese 45/55 baht Double cheeseburger/bacon 69/79 baht Hamburger 25 baht Cheeseburger 35 baht Chicken sandwich 59 baht Chicken&apos;n crisp 29 baht 
 
 Others: Chicken tenders 4/8 pcs
 35/55 baht BK fried chicken 1/2/3 pcs 29/55/75 baht BK big fish 45 baht French Fried s/m/l 22/30/39 baht Onion ring s/m 30/39 baht 
 
 Drinks: Coke, Fanta, Sprite s/l 20/24 baht Iced coffee s/l 25/28 baht Iced tea s/l
 25/28 baht Hot coffee 20 baht Hot tea 20 baht Mineral water 15 baht 
 
 Deserts: Apple pie 25 baht Smile Free! 
 
 Answer: Most fast food restaurants in Thailand (including
Pizza Hut) have changed their menu because of what the Thai people
like to eat. We don&apos;t like beef so much, but we do like chicken
and fish. 
 
 
 Main Menu 
 
 Home Press Room&amp;Contact 
 
 My Thailand Life 
 
 Samut Prakan Province (1) My Thai Childhood (2) My Life Aged 12-15 - My Secret Diary - Phuket with Leonardo (3) My Life Aged 15-19 - The Drug Interviews - Gor&apos;s World Column - My Baby Daughter - My Thai Wedding - My Life as a Thai Monk (4) My Life Aged 19-21 - Thai Prison Life 
 
 More About Thailand 
 
 All About Thailand Thai Culture Thai Festivals Songkran Festival Thai Buddhism Thai Food Thailand Forums Samut Prakan Province How to Find Best Hotel Deals 
 
 Extra Links 
 
 My First Website My Second Website Free Downloads Homework Helper Thailand Cyber Hunt 
 
 Top Thai Websites 
 
 LearningThai.com eThaimusic.com ThailandQA.com Thai-Blogs.com ThaiChatBox.com ThailandGuidebook.com ThaiHotelFinder.com EnjoyThaiFood.com ThaiBuddhist.com ThaiPhotoBlogs.com ThaiCultureBlogs.com Paknam.com 
 
 Administrator 
 
Did you know that your Internet Explorer 6 (IE6) is out of date?

This template is compatible with IE6, however your experience will be enhanced with a newer browser.

To get the best possible experience using our website we recommend that you upgrade to a newer version or other web browser. A list of the most popular web browsers can be found below

           
   Do not show this message again
	</body>
</document>
