<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004542" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Something_fast_food_rarely_comes_without" time="2012-07-12-20:57" support="1" score="0.000610436597225203" bingtitle="Something fast food rarely comes without - The Q&amp;A wiki" webtitle="Something fast food rarely comes withoutSomething fast food rarely comes without">
			<query id="000145" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>fries, ketchup, napkins, beverage, salt, grease, fat ... That&apos;s how people get money out of others. Get it right ... Cars &amp; Vehicles; Entertainment &amp; Arts; Food &amp; Cooking</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; Uncategorized &gt; Something fast food rarely comes without? 
Something fast food rarely comes without?
 In: Uncategorized [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: fries, ketchup, napkins, beverage, salt, grease, fat 

 First answer by ID1663377099 . Last edit by ID1663377099 . Question popularity : 2 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Can you answer these Uncategorized questions?
 
 How far from phoenix to Honolulu? Answer it! Do fight my monster member cards exist? Answer it! What are James Madison University GPA requirements? Answer it! What happens if you double both the current and the voltage in a circuit? Answer it! How does fascist government control society? Answer it! 
 
Relevant answers:
 
 Where did fast food come from? 
 Fast food came from America. America had decided that fancy food is not the best. They made a greecey and Delicious meal. That&apos;s how people get money out of others. Get it right pplz 
 Why did fast food come out? 
 because when people are on the go, they can&apos;t be bothered to make their own healthy type of food. and fast food is fast food when your on the go go go! 
 When did fast food come out? 
 April 28th 1989 
 Is there something wrong with you if you come without ejaculating? 
 No. Your body has probably not had time to reproduce sperm/semen yet or you have not reached that part of puberty yet if you have never ejaculated but you can still have an orgasm. 
 Why is fast food called fast food ? 
 Fast food is called fast food because they give it to you fast and it will make you fat fast. 
 
 
Related ads:
 

 Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 What is the scientific category of the time you were born? In: Science Answer it! How does it take to drive from Anthem AZ to Lake Mary flagstaff AZ? In: Driving Times Answer it! Do fight my monster member cards exist? In: Moshi Monsters Answer it! What are James Madison University GPA requirements? In: James Madison Answer it! » more 
Featured guides
 
 What Are The Benefits Of COQ10 How To Create Avery Label Templates What Is Susie&apos;s Coupons? Review Of Popular Colon Cleansers How To Build A Water Fountain Wall 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
