<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004304" url="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2008-11-02-fast-food-english-orders_N.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:33" support="2" score="0.07171767695187915" bingtitle="Fast-food order accuracy rises with English-fluent hiring pool ..." webtitle="Fast-food order accuracy rises with English-fluent hiring pool - USATODAY.com">
			<query id="000884" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="113"/>
	<description>If your next fast-food order at the drive-through has the right food in the right bag, you may have something surprising to thank: the bad economy. Andy ...</description>
	<body>
		Cars     Auto 
 Financing     Event 
 Tickets     Jobs     Real 
 Estate     Online 
 Degrees     Business Opportunities Shopping 
 Search How do I find it? Subscribe to paper   
 
 
 
 
 
 Home News Travel Money Sports Life Tech Weather 
 
 Money Markets 
 Markets Home Mutual Funds ETFs Most Active Stocks Commodities Currencies Key Interest Rates Internet 50 Stock Market Answers: Ask Matt World Stocks Free Annual Reports 
 Economy 
 Economy Home Economic Calendar Jobs 
 Companies/Execs 
 Executive Suite Company News Company Calendars Annual Reports Jobs 
 Personal Finance 
 Personal Finance Home Mutual Funds ETFs Retirement Taxes Mortgage Rates CD and Savings Rates Your Money: Sandra Block Investing: John Waggoner Your Portfolio Calculators Free Annual Reports 
 Mutual Funds ETFs Cars 
 Cars Home Drive On community Test Drive: James R. Healey Video Reviews Research a Car Buy a Car Sell a Car Incentives Recalls Other Reviews 
 Real Estate 
 Real Estate Home Find a Realtor Sell It Yourself Home Value Apartments Moving Home Improvement 
 Small Business 
 Small Business Home Ask an Expert: Steve Strauss Entrepreneurial Tightrope: Gladys Edmunds Strategies: Rhonda Abrams Franchises 
 
 
 GET A QUOTE: 
 
 
 
 
 
   What&apos;s 
 this? 
 
 

Search hundreds of franchises and business opportunities to find the one that is right for you. Find a franchise: 
 Select Category All Automotive Business Services Children&apos;s Services Cleaning Services Computer&amp;Internet Food&amp;Restaurants Health&amp;Beauty Home Services Onsite Services Retail Sports&amp;Leisure Travel&amp;Lodging 
 Select Investment Up to $10,000 Up to $25,000 Up to $50,000 Up to $100,000 Up to $150,000 Up to $200,000 Over $200,000 All Levels   
 
 Quick Request Form:
 Request information from your favorite 
 franchises and business opportunities.  Click here 
 
 
 Fast-food order accuracy rises with English-fluent hiring pool 

 Updated  |  Comment  |  Recommend E-mail | Print | 
 
 
 
   Enlarge PR Newswire Carl&apos;s Jr. Guacamole Bacon Six Dollar Burger. The chain&apos;s order accuracy has risen. 
 
 
 
  BEST, WORST FOR ACCURACY 
 Carl&apos;s ranked seventh with 93.6% in accuracy in 2008. Top five best and worst drive-throughs for order accuracy: Chick-fil-A 97.1% Church&apos;s 82.5% Culver&apos;s 95.2% Popeyes 84.2% Del Taco 95.1% Bojangles&apos; 85.6% Jack In The Box 94.8% Whataburger 87.0% Krystal 94.6% Dairy Queen 87.4% Source: QSR 
 
 
 
 By Bruce Horovitz, USA TODAY If your next fast-food order at the drive-through has the right food in the right bag, you may have something surprising to thank: the bad economy. 
Andy Puzder, CEO of CKE Restaurants (CKR) , which owns the Carl&apos;s Jr. and Hardee&apos;s fast-food chains, says that in the past six months, Carl&apos;s Jr.&apos;s 478 locations in Southern California in particular have been able to recruit crewmembers more fluent in English, and thus are able to process drive-through orders more accurately.

&quot;It&apos;s a no-brainer,&quot; Puzder says. &quot;Hiring people who are fluent in English has always been something we&apos;ve wanted to do. Now we can.&quot;
 
That&apos;s because, with layoffs on the rise—particularly in hard-hit Southern California—the chain can be more selective in hiring. The unemployment rate in California hit 7.7% in August vs. the national rate of 6.1%—the most recent month from the Bureau of Labor Statistics.

Bob Sandelman, a fast-food researcher, is not surprised order accuracy is up and puts the reason bluntly: &quot;When times are tough, people are willing to take jobs for which they&apos;re over-qualified.&quot;
 
For the fast-food world overall, order accuracy is a nagging problem. At drive-throughs, botched orders are the No. 1 problem, says, Sherri Daye Scott, editor at QSR Magazine , which does an annual ranking on order accuracy. &quot;Speed is less important to consumers than getting orders right.&quot;

 QSR &apos;s statistics show Carl&apos;s accuracy clearly is improving—up to 93.6% in the QSR study conducted this spring vs. 89.3% in the accuracy study it conducted in spring of 2007. When QSR did its research in 2007, &quot;language barrier&quot; was an issue for 3.8% of its drive-through purchases at Carl&apos;s vs. 1.2% this spring.

Carl&apos;s is not hiring fewer Latinos or other minorities—those numbers are the same, Puzder says. But it is hiring more crewmembers with more skills. &quot;I can&apos;t believe this is unique to Carl&apos;s,&quot; he adds. &quot;We&apos;re all hiring from the same labor pool.&quot;

Also, he notes, employee turnover is down as folks hang onto jobs.

Denny Lynch, a Wendy&apos;s (WEN) spokesman, says the chain &quot;intuitively&quot; sees what Puzder means. Wendy&apos;s turnover is down, and it is seeing &quot;an improved quantity and quality&quot; of job seekers.

&quot;With a larger labor pool of applicants to choose from, we are able to more efficiently fill positions with qualified candidates,&quot; says Deborah Martin, a rep for Burger King.

Executives at the League of United Latin American Citizens say they want to be sure Hispanics have fair opportunities, but they see the effects of the economy. &quot;The importance of language skills varies job to job,&quot; says Darryl Morin, a LULAC director. &quot;With the expanding labor pool, you&apos;re able to find candidates with better training.&quot;
 
 Posted Updated E-mail | Print | To report corrections and clarifications, contact Reader Editor Brent Jones . For publication consideration in the newspaper, send comments to letters@usatoday.com . Include name, phone number, city and state for verification. 
 Guidelines: You share in the USA TODAY community, so please keep your comments smart and civil. Don&apos;t attack other readers personally, and keep your language decent. Use the &quot;Report Abuse&quot; button to make a difference. Read more . Newspaper Home Delivery - Subscribe Today 
 Home • News • Travel • Money • Sports • Life • Tech • Weather 
 About USATODAY.com: Site Map | FAQ | Contact Us | Jobs with Us | Terms of Service 
 Privacy Policy/Your California Privacy Right | Advertise | Press Room | Developer | Media Lounge | Reprints and Permissions News Your Way:   Mobile News |   Email News |   Add USATODAY.com RSS feeds |   Twitter |   Podcasts |     Widgets Partners: USA WEEKEND | Sports Weekly | Education | Space.com | Travel Tips 
 Copyright 2011 USA TODAY, a division of Gannett Co. Inc.
	</body>
</document>
