<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004782" url="http://hudsonvalley.com/sp?aff=1&amp;catId=16032400&amp;wId=76748&amp;showTab=reviews" time="2012-07-12-21:17" support="7" score="0.038759562439140395" bingtitle="HudsonValley.com: Kentucky Fried Chicken - Fast Food Restaurant ..." webtitle="HudsonValley.com: Kentucky Fried Chicken - Fast Food Restaurant - Port Jervis, NY">
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="23"/>
	<description>... and more information about Kentucky Fried Chicken along with information on Fast Food ... people in line i know i have a 20 min wait no kiddding.and they mess up my order 20% ...</description>
	<body>
		BUSINESSES CLASSIFIEDS CARS JOBS HOMES DAILY DEAL COUPONS 
 Search Now&amp;Post a Review 
SEARCH FOR:
 
LOCATION:
 Current Category All Categories Advanced Search 
 X 

Where would you like to start your search?
 
 

Enter Zipcode or City, State
 
We&apos;re sorry, but we couldn&apos;t find &quot; &quot;. Please type in a different address, ZIP code, or city&amp;state
 

 Kentucky Fried Chicken ( 3 Reviews ) 
33 Main St, Port Jervis, NY 12771

 Phone: 845-856-1623

 Reviews | Rate It 

 Is this Your Business? Click here to enhance your listing 
 
 DETAILS MAP REVIEWS COUPONS PHOTOS 
 We didn&apos;t find any Details for this Business.

Would you like to update your Listing? 

 1.  
 Kentucky Fried Chicken 33 Main St 
 Port Jervis , NY 12771 
 GET DIRECTIONS: Starting Address:
 City:
 State:
 Zip:
 Ending Address:
 City:
 State:
 Zip:
 If you are unable to view this map, please clear your browser&apos;s cache or enable JavaScript. REVIEWER RATING: 
 rated on: 11/26/2008 The Colonel would be spinning.... Pros: None Cons: Slow help, food that&apos;s been sitting out, not clean &quot;This place is beyond slow... dirty... and the last (and I mean VERY LAST!) time I went there I got a nasty case of food poisoning... go ANYWHERE but here!&quot; REVIEWER RATING: 
 rated on: 11/09/2008 slow &quot;slow slow if a see more then three people in line i know i have a 20 min wait no kiddding.and they mess up my order 20% of the time&quot; REVIEWER RATING: 
 rated on: 07/16/2008 SLOW!!! &quot;icky, slow, but alas the only KFC in 25miles.&quot; We didn&apos;t find any Coupons for this Business.

Would you like to update your Listing? 

 
 
 We didn&apos;t find any Photos for this Business.

Would you like to update your Listing? 

 Manage Your Listing
	</body>
</document>
