<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004769" url="http://ecorporateoffices.com/PopeyesChickenBiscuits-1521" time="2012-07-12-21:16" support="1" score="0.0006681633304224112" bingtitle="Popeyes Chicken &amp; Biscuits Corporate Office | Headquarters Contact ..." webtitle="Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Corporate Office | Headquarters Contact Phone Number&amp;Address | Reviews">
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>... is also currently working at a store in Oak Park ... NEEDS TO CALL ME ASAP I WAS JUST CHASED IN MY CAR ... airport and received the best service for a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Corporate Office | Headquarters 
 Po Box 1181 Elsa, TX 78543
(956)262-4277 




 Reviews For Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Corporate Office 

 Wanda Patterson 6/4/12 
 I am unhappy with the service I receuved in Paducah, Kentucky. My first time to order chicken strips, I got to work and started to eat them and they were raw in the middke. On another occasion, I had to wait fifteen minutes for my order in the drive-thru, The nab said he got busy abd forgot about me. Yesterday I asked for a bag for my purchase and was given a little paper bag. When I asked for qa plastic vag that I could carry in to work I was told they could not give them for small boxes. I spent four dollqrs for nuggets and qa biscuit. How much does a plastic bag cost? 



 d janak 6/4/12 
 intelligence has never been an employment criteria at popeye s in victoria tx
 



 K. D. Robbins 6/5/12 
 While waiting in line to purchase a 12 and 16 mix I noticed a customer with the top of his shorts half way between his knees and feet. His green underwear was completely exposed. He had to hold his pants up to keep them from falling to his feet. I ask the manager to request him to get dressed but the manager replied he could not do any thing about it because they did not have a policy about it. There were women in the restaurant exposed to this. Do you have a policy and even if you don&apos;t why can&apos;t the manager request someone to pull his pants up? 



 kay Jennings 6/7/12 
 Can we get a Popeye&apos;s in cedar rapids Iowa please!!! 



 Lucy 6/9/12 
 Popeyes has had several campaigns where the outside advertisement quotes one price, yet the inside ad quotes something higher. For example, at my location in Co-op City, the pull-apart chicken is quoted at $3.99 with drink&amp;fries. I walked in the restaurant one day and noticed that the inside ad quotes the deal at $5+. That is blatant lying. I walked out of the store.

I actually saw something similar with Popeyes months before and sent corporate a message. I received no response. I know that many retailers use the ole&apos; &apos;bait and switch&apos; routine, so I know I have the choice to either frequent them or not. I appreciate that Popeyes makes really good chicken and you can find good coupons on the website, but that does not give Popeyes the right to deceive their customers.

 



 dana 6/14/12 
 to be Americas Favorite Chicken (what a joke) maybe those who voted have not eaten there more than once at store # 8215 in Madison TN. After reading all reviews, need i say anymore? Whats so funny to me, is they dont even offer a free meal to replace the old and nasty one they gave at first. Eat and Learn! 



 Richard A. 6/19/12 
 Sunday father&apos;s my wife and I decided to try the new chicken tenders being announced on the TV. When we get to the Popeye&apos;s located at 7130 San Pedro in San Antonio Tx., the girl behind the counter promptly informed us it would take thirty minutes to prepare both orders that if we wanted something else. We said we would wait eager to savor the new dish. A second woman then informed the girl to tell us that there was no such item in stock. We quietly walked out and took our business elsewhere. This same store on another occasion also lied about not having spicy chicken and that it would take 45 minutes to prepare another batch. Please if Popeye&apos;s is going to advertize something have the decency to provide what you are advertizing. This store will not see my business ever again that I promise you. Also your chicken has been getting scrawnier and scrawnier, soon you will be wanting to sell people fried baby chicks just out of the egg. People expect to get what they pay for. Bring back the healthy chicken and take away the sickly scrawny birds you are selling to the public. 



 ccp 6/20/12 
 Why does it say on their sign...&quot;Popeye&apos;s Chicken&amp;Bisquits&quot;?
I have tried repeatedly to get them to give me an order of just 2 or 3 pieces of chicken and a bisquit. They tell me that&apos;s not on the menu....but I can order it as separate side orders. Did that once....price was over what a meal would have been.
So...my point is....why not name their place &quot;Popeye&apos;s...if it ain&apos;t on the menu you don&apos;t get it&quot;?
Oh...and I tried to get them to just give me what&apos;s on the meal order but remove the drink and side at the menu price they are separately......Uh uh...can&apos;t do that.
 



 Daisy 6/25/12 
 The sad part about this site is that the Corporate office isn&apos;t doing anything about those piss poor establishments. Post after post go up and still the employees get worst along with service. I could tell some real hum-dinger stories about the stores in Chicago Illinois from the employees pocekting half the money to the GM being EXTRA stupid to the managers being on the take with some of the other employees.
Why bother to have the site when nothing is being done/ Do you people think consumers are going to continue to go to your stores when the food is getting as bad as the service. I always thogut Popeyes would be around for a long time. I don&apos;t see it lasting at the rate in which is going. I see more people in their competitors stores than theirs.
I have had Popeyes in so long I honestly couldn&apos;t tell you what it taste like. The service has gotten so bad QUITE a FEW of my friends and family stop going as well. We&apos;d rather drive way across town to buy chicken than go to Popeyes.This is the end result of trying to alert Corporate with no response. Their not going to respond until someone goes postal in one of the stores or sales start to real drop and they have to start closing stores.
I&apos;m not going to rate them because one star is to much. 



 Matt 6/25/12 
 I notice you display the disclaimer the posted remarks on this site. It also states you don&apos;t know the accuracy of the reviews. Now call me crazy but don&apos;t you think that is your cue to get off your behinds and check into some of these accusations? The majority of the reviews are saying the same thing. That alone should raise a red flag. Instead it seems as though things are swept under the rug as long as the money is still rolling in. Enjoy the ride because ALL good things eventually comes to an END!!!
I am planning on trying to get into that store. The one where I watched the cashier pocket the money. I asked one of the other employees did anyone tell the manager. I was told the manager knew yet the person is still employed there.
Hey I figure I could get a pay check and a bonus at the same time. It seems to be alright.
I&apos;m joking about working there but I&apos;m NOT joking about what goes on.
&quot;Sad isn&apos;t it!!!!!&quot;
I will not waste a star rating them. 



 Polly 6/25/12 
 I don&apos;t know if it&apos;s the company policy or unfortunate luck but a lot of the complaints is about the nasty attitude of the manager and GM. It seems as if the store is franchised out then employees can do what they want to do. I have grown so tired of Popeyes and their nasty employees I actually hand out coupons to my colleagues for your competitors. I use to take orders,3 times a week for Popeyes, now we ALL go to the competitors for lunch. We even have our office parties catered by competitors. I&apos;m trying to be nice and not say their name but I think you guys know who I&apos;m referring to.
I tried to hang in there with Popeyes but a person can only take so much.
Here&apos;s a review you may post....GO BACK TO THE BEGINNING AND TAKE PRIDE IN YOUR COMPANY!!!!!
I will rate you when you come up with ZERO stars as a choice. 



 Diane 5/7/12 
 I would like to know how you can justify charging $.99 for a biscuit? We don&apos;t eat out very much anymore because of the economy, but when we do,we enjoy popeyes chicken and feel your chicken is not priced unreasonably. But for what you charge for a single biscuit or six or a dozen, I can buy a loaf of bread or two or three! I make biscuits at home from scratch, so I know it doesn&apos;t cost that much to make. So please bring the price of your biscuits down, so that we can enjoy a whole meal with bread. Thanks 



 roy woodley 5/10/12 
 every time i go into the popeyes fast food store in deerfield beach. the service is very poor. i stand in lien and no one whant to take my order. with cause. maybe it&apos;s because they think that i am gay. those people: stand and debate on who would take my order. and what they do is go in the waist box and give me old chicken. i have on choise but to get my money back.... the last time i stopde in at popeyes. they actually took old chicken, put it in a basket; and droped it in the greese for the fries. i think my next step is to get an attorney. and take them to court. this has been going on far to long. i did get sick once, from some bad chicken... i use to love to go over to popeyes. and get some chicken. now popeyes is just a joke.. and i will go on facebook, and spred the news.... 



 A. Bell 4/8/12 
 Do not eat or buy from the Popeys on the corner of E. Houston and WW White Rd in San Antonio Texas. There is an employee there named Valarie who is very rude and disrespectful to customers of color. She has very low self-esteem and just plain dumb. When I go there and she is not there the staff is totally different, when she is there she mostly caters to mexican american customers, and rude to others. She likes to argue with customers and try to intimate other employees. 



 Faith&amp;Joe Schmidt 3/3/12 
 

We just visited your popeys location in Grand Prairie TX at Belt Line Rd and I30. We drove thru because we had been doing yard work all morning and we just wanted to pick up lunch and come home and eat lunch. This trip to popeyes became the worst fast food trip we have ever been on. We ordered a 21.99 family meal with red beans rice for one side and coleslaw for the other side, and one extra corn on the cob and 2 drinks easy right? gosh no. They charged us for the meal price and also charged for the two sides that was suppose to come with meal. We asked the drive thru guy if he understood we wanted the family meal with our 2 sides and he said yes. They also charged us for 3 corn on the cobb when we only ordered and received one. Our lunch came to over 34.00 and all we received was a 21,99 family meal with 2 drinks. I went inside to explain what they had done to our order and none of the 3employees understood what they did and needed to do to fix it. I finally got tired of explaining that they needed to refund our 2 sides because the family meal came with them, (they handed me one dollar and 75 cents-???????) at this point I realized that they could not understand this mistake if I stood there all day, so I left. Why do you put these employees in your popeye restaurants if they cant understand their mistakes much less fix them? If you do not have any competent people at this resturaunt I would be too afraid to go back there. This was such a easy mistake to fix and yet 3 employees never understood even what they had done wrong,with me spelling it out for them in detail 3 times. Please send someone who is competent to train the staff so that more customers wont go through what we went through. Joe&amp;Faith Schmidt







 



 Felipe 2/19/12 
 Popeyes in ny the Bronx very dirty false advertisement and no one behind the counter know how to speak English horrible for the area and location someone should look into it 



 X crew member 2/16/12 
 I use to work at the Popeyes in Warren,MI on 8mile for almost 6years as a crew member and have met a few members from the corporation. On Tuesday, January 31 the day after I got paid, I worked that day in the morning at 10am on the register as I always do. On that day more cashiers came in so I asked the morning shift manager if I could get a break from the register and cook instead and he said that was fine. When the General Manager appear from her GMs&apos; meeting she did a few did things in the computer. After she finished programming things in the computer she walked over to me and the kitchen area and ask me if I could help re- organize the walk-in cooler. I said that was fine because I love to multitask and help others. After me and the General Manager completed the task.nI went back in the kitchen because we were starting to run out of chicken. After I got the chicken back on board the GM asked me to filter. I havent filter for 2years and most of the time a replacement cook always come in filter after I leave the kitchen because I am always on the register most of the time. So I told the General manager,&quot; that I didnt remember&quot; so she said, &quot;I&apos;ll show you&quot;. After showing me how to set up the filtering machine she told me to pull the machine near the stolve. When I put the machine near the stolve she ask me, &quot;what stolve does the machine goes under&apos;? I said, &quot;I dont remember.&quot; So the General Manager called a crew member over and said, which stolve does the filtering machine goes under?&quot; The crew member pointed to the stolve that the machine goes under. Afterv that the General Manager told me to, &quot;clock out and go home&quot; with rage and anger on the floor in front of the while store. I was in shock because I didnt know why she got so angry and sent me home. After I clocked out she told me, &quot;Dont come back until you have some sense in your head&quot;, yelling and screaming in front of everyone with customers in the lobby instead of pulling me to the office like a General Manager is suppose to do. My main point is if I forgot how to do something and I ask for help from a manager they&apos;re suppose to guide me through directions, not yell and scream at me and sent me home in front of everyone because I ask for directions. I&apos;ve never had any problems with any manager for the while years I&apos;ve been working thier until now.The next day I came in to work and the assistant manager said that, the GM took you off the schedule&quot;,.I&apos;ve called the store for 3weeks and all the managers&apos; told me that I wasnt on the schedule. I called the GM several times but didnt get a response or a return phone call. So 2day which is february 16, 2012 I called and spoke with assistant manager and she said, &quot;that the GM laid you and another worker off.&quot; I ask the assistant manager if she could see if I had any write up. She said, &quot;yes&quot;. She said, I was written up for,&quot; failure to complete duty.&quot; In my opinion the GENERAL MANAGER failed to complete her duty when she didnt finish showing how to filter the stolve anf got a nasty attitude and told me not to come back until I got some since in my head. A lot of people has lost thier jobs since the GM arrived at our store for no good reasons at all. This General Manager is also currently working at a store in Oak Park and Warren,MI at the same time. In my opinion in the future if a new crew member ask her for directions she might get mad in fire them as well and its already hd to find a job these days. If she didnt want to do her job and show me how to do something she should be the one that should be fired and not others that asks for simple instructions. I will rate the store with 4stars because I know what each crew member is capable of and how hard they work but I give the General Manager no stars at all for poor lack of commmunication skills,poor attitude, and failure to complete duty. 



 Freddie Scott 1/31/12 
 I am writing to express my disappointment in the service and discrimmation that is displayed at the Popeyes located in Denver, Colorado at 47th and chambers. It is operated by a staff of all hispanics and when myself as a black customer place an order I have to clearly explain to them that I do not want a miniture piece of chicken that is served to us while the hispanices and whites receive a normal size piece of chicken. I placed an order for wicked chicken and had to drive back up to the restaurant because I was give crumbs and 4 half pieces of strips. Needless to say I will not return to this location and I will tell all that I know to not use this location. 



 Virginia 1/31/12 
 I went to a Popeyes chicken to purchase the mixed deal offered. I asked for two deals, one regular and one spicy. They asked me if I would accept spicy breast in the mild deal. I said OK, but not only did they not put what they said they didn&apos;t give me any breast at all in either deals. Now you can get leg&amp;thigh deals all the time so why would I want legs&amp;thighs if I went for a mixed deal. when I tried to call and tell them the phone was on fax mode so I called Corporate. They took my info and said I would get a call back. I has been about three (3) months or more already and I am still waiting for that call. Not only are the stores poor business but so is Corporate. 



 york 1/20/12 
 I am writing this to let everyone know that Popeye&apos;s chicken 15468821 in Romeoville Illinois is not a good place to buy chicken I order a 10pc all spicey When I got home I had grease not spicey chicken I called and ask to speak to the superviser he said bring it back but it was to late. It was 8pm at the time I order the chicken there were no other customers. I Called the manager she gave me a number to replace my order, at my convince. when I tried to used the number 3 days later she said the order was picked up the next day around 6pm. She lied. This manger need help. I hope the owner know whats happening before the business goes under. I will tell every that I know that the chicken is not what Popeye&apos;s is All about 

 

 dre 12/29/11 
 I work for popeyes on kingshigh way in brooklyn and they no hours they and u only work 2 or 3 days in a week and got a sign sayin help wanted an can&apos;t give umore hours,shame,shame,shame, 



 How disapointed...... 12/29/11 
 Customer Service was bad at my local Popyes, as much as I don&apos;t like admitting to this I will not be going back. How sad is it when you can&apos;t even order an extra biscuit at the drive up window even though no one was waiting behind me? Oh Well. 



 jess 12/15/11 
 My husband said i hasd to try this chicken sandwich so we went to centre mall in hamilton and thats what i ordered. with three kids under seven hungry and waiting to eat , we waited and waited and waited until finally my husband asked the girl he ordered from what was happening... oh were stll waiting yeah i get that said my husband but why... the girl says well i yelled it back but he didnt hear so the order just got started.. well shouldnt there be better communication instaed of five people standing around doing nothing except making fun of people in the food court my husband said.... well i told him he didnt hear thats not my fault said the girl and wow my husbands face went red and he asked for his money back and we left... we will not return .. 



 NoLonger Acustomer 12/11/11 
 Went to Popeye&apos;s Chicken in Spring Texas b/c I had a craven to some good ole fried chicken. I haven&apos;t been there in well over a year as the last visit was not the best experience dealing w/ their give a shi&amp;&amp;T;attitude employees. I purchased a 3 pc dinner w/ mash potatoes and 1 biscuit at a price of $7.99. I&apos;m sorry folks but the cost to value ratio for this food just doesn&apos;t cut any more for me. I guess the employees must have got a raise and are making $50 grand a year now b/c the taste and quality of the food doesn&apos;t qualify that price for me. I guess the Colonel will have to satisfy my chicken fix as it has for the last 40 years. Bye bye to the no longer America&apos;s Favorite Chicken Company, Popeye&apos;s.

Regards,

No Longer A Popeye&apos;s Fried Chicken Customer 



 LEAH BUGGS 11/22/11 
 I&apos;m a resident of Troy Michigan and I was in Pontiac/Waterford Michigan. I ordered and did not receive my Large Mashed Potatoes. When I got home I called and told them and they told me the next time I came in I could get it, I told them I didn&apos;t know when because I didn&apos;t live in the area. 30 days later I went to Popeyes an ordered a 12pc meal and asked if I could also get my Mashed Potatoes that was never given to me and gave her my name because supposingly they were keeping my name written down. They told me that after 30 days they get rid of names. It couldn&apos;t have been more than 30 days that I was there. I left there without my Mashed Potatoes and I was not about to argue over $2 but fair is fair. They gained my $2 and I lost food that was paid for. Not happy at all. Email me back at leahbuggs@hotmail.com Management please. 



 B. Reeves 11/17/11 
 I visited popeyes chicken in oakpark mi on greenfield an linclon st. It was late I was starving . I ordered a few chicken raps and a sm side of red beans with a sm mash a 2 pc special an a few peppers customer service seemed to b great at first. I got hm wth my order an my red beans an rice was spoiled. My chicken in my raps was old . My sm sides didn&apos;t even have a time on them so who knws when they were made. An worst of it all when I call the manager didn&apos;t even apologize I told her I threw up an she still had nothin to say. Didn&apos;t. Even ask me if I wanted to be acomodated for the mishap. I&apos;m tired of all the lazy people wrkin for these fast food comp. Careless folks. Food safety should number one otherwise how would u stay in business. I wouldn&apos;t visit the same one or maybe even none I have gotten spoiled redbeans an rice twice frm same location. 



 Dean R 11/15/11 
 No receipt. Says tell manager you didn&apos;t get a receipt and get $5. I asked for a receipt. He said computer is down. Did not give me $5. Mash potatos and gravy dumped in the box. Lid not secured. No utensils. Chicken super greasy. At least he under billed me! What a racket! $2.99 plus $1.59 X 3 is not gonna be $6.35. Way to go! Make that pocket money while you can. I bet the Sherman TX Popeyes won&apos;t be open long at this rate! 



 s. gismondi 10/29/11 
 I am a contractor that was asked by the store manager to do some work for them. Since it wasn&apos;t a lot, I did it without getting paid right there and then. I was assured by the managerthat I&apos;d get paid as oon as they got the invoice. That was three (3) months ago. He keeps coming up with new excuses as to why he hasn&apos;t paid up yet. Now he&apos;s gone as far as no responding to my calls and has his staff lie for him. His cell phone is constantly turned off. I tried calling Customer Service to report the matter and they are just as worthless as the store manager. I asked to talk to someone higher up but they refused and claimed that they had no access to phone numbers to managerial staff. THEY ARE A WORTHLESS PIECE OF CRAP JUST LIKE THEIR FOOD. 



 Kenya Cobb 10/18/11 
 It really angers me that I have to give this review a star at all! The Popeyes in Eddystone PA has been out of Dip&apos;n Chick&apos;n since they came out! I was only able to try it once out of the 10 times I came to the location and even then there was no sauce! There has been a sign sayin they have been out of the chicken but when I asked to be sure.........they did have it?!?!?!?!? I find it kind of ridiculous that it&apos;s a chicken shortage considering all the other chicken pieces you have! I would actually appreciate if I would stop airing the commercial for items you DO NOT HAVE! 



 Star 10/17/11 
 I&apos;ve just came from the Tulsa Ok store number 5716, I believe with this experience I will not be back to Popeyes . I ordered the new dip n chicken and got everything but that in my box. I had shrimp, popcorn chicken, and I spicy chicken strip in it. And a few pieces of what I wanted. But to top everything off my chicken was OLD AND COLD! Not sure where they do that at, but I won&apos;t be going back. 



 Marvis Murphy, BS Nutrition 10/16/11 
 Called a Nashville Popeyes Chicken with a complaint, and the manager was so damn smart, did not want to hear nothing that I had to say, curse me and hang up in my face. What a way to do business.....Have lost me and my business for ever. 



 Tina Hoff 10/7/11 
 my family and myself have been to popeyes chicken alot and we use to love going but here the last few times we have been there sevice and product was very poor, service was very poor. One day we went and ordered our food and drinks,we got our drinks and my youngest grandson iam raiseing took a drink and it tasted like pure salt, it made him very sick, he has serious helth problems and when this terrible taste went in his mouth he throwed up, i tasted the drink to see what was wrong and it tasted like salt, i went inside the resturant due to we got our order thru the drive thru, when i went inside and i exsplaned to the cashier what had happened at first he acted like i was crazy I then told him to taste it, well then i found out some one who worked there dumped five pounds of salt into the tea. I was upset that this had even happened the employees thought this was funny. A few days ago my husband desided he wanted to try the same popeyes again needless to say I will not go back they messed up our order we didnt get part of the order had to go back after we had left to get it then what we had ordered they didnt have. Popeyes use to be very good I really dont know what has happed 



 Kim 10/1/11 
 Terrible customer service!! Tried to order from the Memorial Blvd., Murfreesboro, TN location today and was treated terribly. We wanted to substitute the wings in our order for any other kind of chicken and was told that they absolutely would not do it. We have no problem doing this at KFC. But when we told her this, she just shrugged her shoulders and had rather lose a sale than to replace 3 lousy pieces of chicken wings for legs! Ridiculous! Needless to say she lost the sale and KFC received our $30. Poor Management, poor service, poor attitudes = no business from my family. 



 X 10/1/11 
 I was in Rochester NY and I went to popeyes. I order mild chicken when I got home it was spicy
chicken my child could not eat if I did live in the next county over I would have return it. When I called them to tell them about it. They picked up the phone and put it down. I could hear them talking but they would talk on the phone. I love their chicken but I was very disappoint :( 



 X 10/1/11 
 I was in Rochester NY and I went to popeyes. I order mild chicken when I got home it was spicy
chicken my child could not eat if I didn&apos;t live in the next county over I would have return it. When I called them to tell them about it. They picked up the phone and put it down. I could hear them talking but they would talk on the phone. I love their chicken but I was very disappoint :( 



 Repeater Customer 8/9/11 
 I have gone several of times to Popeyes chicken location at 457 W Broadway in Tempe Az. Let me tell you a couple of things about this restuarant. 1. Very bad customer service in the evening hours. 2. They tend to close early before closing hours. 3. I always see employees smoking in the back of the store, but one day i went to order in the evening I did see an employee smoking and the smell was Marijuana. To be honest the manager should be carefull in who they hire as employees or managers. To be honest something major could happen in the store while employees are under the influence. I surely appreciat that this concern should be an alert for the business OWNER of that restuarant. This hasnt been the first time I witness this situation at this location ONLY!!!!! 



 Yvette 8/14/11 
 I visited the Popeye&apos;s on Gravois in St. Louis, MO today. The sign in the drive-thru quoted one price. I asked the cashier why was I charged another price. She stated the price went up. I spoke to the manager. She said the price went up and the advertised price has not been changed yet. She also stated I would have to pay the new price. I told her this was fraudulent pricing. She insisted that I pay the new price. I asked for my money back. She was very rude. I wonder if Popeye&apos;s offer customer service training to their employees. 



 Beachball54 8/16/11 
 
I have been going to Popeye&apos;s for years, the one in Neptune
Beach, FL, however they really to pay closer attention to being
consistent. The last several times I have ordered LARGE
sides they are about 2/3 full. At a cost of over $4 with tax it
should be FULL! I have also gotten dry chicken, like it sat on
the warmer tray too long. I am not going back anymore as it
is not worth the price. So sad, they used to be awesome.
 



 Dave Lee 8/16/11 
 I requested and waited for fresh chicken and Ilsie sneakily placed the dried-up drumsticks on the bottom. She strategically covered the old drumsticks with the freshly cooked thighs. I said to her the chicken is for my dad who has no teeth. When I got home and talked to her, she was DEFIANT and COMBATIVE. I will not be returning to Popeyes any time soon! 



 jay 8/21/11 
 Just paid six dollars f
or 3pc dinner with no biscuit and plenty of honey. I called back at 1230am no one answered phone. I just wanted my biscuit. Store # 31 Marietta windy hill. Email: authorajordan@AOL.com
 

 

 mee 8/25/11 
 i wrk at popeyes in st.louisnn my check bounce inn it was my very frist check if yall cnt pay on a 30 dollar check wat about my next one 



 B&amp;R Taylor 8/29/11 
 I HATE TO GIVE THIS LOCATION A STAR...fRENSO, CA. 559-276-8688..NOT ONLY ARE THEY RUDE..THEY MADE 2 MISTAKES ON AN ORDER OF 3 DINNERS...ORDERED MILD AND GOT SPICY CHICKEN..WHICH NO ONE CAN EAT IN THIS HOUSE. SO I CALLED AND WAS TOLD THEY WOULD MAKE GOOD ON MY NEXT VISIT...I WAS TO GET 2 WHITE 3 PIECE MEALS REPLACED..
I GOT A TOTAL OF 4 PIECES OF CHICKEN...WHEN I CALLED SHE SAID SHE WAS SORRY AND SO WHAT... SO WHAT IS THAT CUSTOMER SERVICE..

THIS LOCATION MAKES MISTAKES ON THEIR MISTAKES...THANK GOODNESS KFC IS ACROSS AS THAT IS WHERE WE WILL GO...

PRICES ARE BETTER AT KFC WHEN YOU ORDER A 3 PIECE WHITE MEAL AT KFC, YOU GET 1 WING AND 2 BREASTS....AT POPEYE YOU GET 2 WINGS AND 1 BREAST...THAT IS ONLY ON A DAY WHEN THE CLERKS CAN READ THEIR TICKETS...
 



 Maria 9/14/11 
 I had a bad experience with the Popeyes in Jersey Village (Houston TX). My order was short 4 peices of chicken and I received no biscuits. When they finally answered the phone, the manager was very apologetic and asked me my name so he could add it to &quot;the list&quot; and I could come back at my convenience to get it. I went today, the manager on duty was rude, and said my name was not on the list, and to come back when the other &quot;dude&quot; was there. I replied that I am not here to get a free meal, and that I was insulted that he implied I was lying. I will not go back to that Popeyes ever. His name is Miguel. He&apos;s a real ass hole! 



 Howard B. 9/8/11 
 I love Popeye&apos;s chicken. My local restaurant is disadvantaged. I have tried to eat there many times. Sometimes the chicken is old, sometimes they do not have the pieces I want. ( spicy legs ). Last night I saw your ad for 2 legs and a biscuit for $2.50. The last time I was there they charged me $2.50 for 1 leg with no biscuit. I walked out. Today I thought I would call to make sure they would have the legs.
They told me they could not honor that ad. They wanted to charge me $4.44 for the same thing, what kind o;f crap is that? don&apos;t all your franchises honor your ads? For many years I lived near your Vallejo CA store. Consistently good, hot, and fresh. You need to close that shithouse on Knighten road near Anderson and open in another location in Anderson or Redding.
Thanks, Howard
e mail me back with managements thinking about this situation. It sounds like false advertising to me!
hbinsr@sonic.net 



 Kimberly Jones 7/10/11 
 Popeyes Chicken in Los Angels, on 103rd Street and Compton Avenue is so far the worse location I have visited. I have gone and ordered egg biscuits and had to return because the egg was old. I have had this problem three times and then vowed not to bother again. Because it is down the street from my home, I have gone back because my daughter has insisted and it quite consistent in having problelms. Today, 7/10/11, we went through the drive through and ordered what said firecracker shimp,comes with reqular side order - the picture shows fries but when ordered a regular side of beans, they said look at the picture we can only order fries. I could not convince them to honor the advertisement. I even suggested that it comes down if they were not going to allow customers to order what the sign says. They refused to allow any other sides but fries because of the picture. I was furious. I now refuse to take it quitely, it is so sad that in our area this is what we tolerate - I will not any longer. 



 Sandra 7/18/11 
 OMG...Popeye&apos;s has not so many locations close by...but is worth driving a couple more miles for that chicken! Is the best!!
 



 Mary Lee Taylor 8/1/11 
 I use to love Popeyes Chicken actually all your food and I still love it but the service just isn&apos;t worth the trip to go pick it up.

I live in North Richland Hills, TX, there use to be a Popeyes restaurant on Rufe Snow in my city, it closed a few years ago and it is no wonder, the service was terrible, it wasn&apos;t unusual to go in and find the staff standing around speaking in Mexican, laughing and carring on. Half the time they would be out of something be it chicken or the slaw, the wait was way to long, the last time I was in that particular restaurant another customer was getting fed up and we both talked about how poor the service had gotten and that we probably wouldn&apos;t go back after this trip.

Well, I am sorry to say the only Popeyes left in my area is going down hill in the exact same manner. The last time I went, I placed my order at the drive-up window, I was the only customer in sight, and was asked to please move to the parking lot. I was shocked, so I parked and went inside, a couple of men were leaving with their order, there was a grandmother and grandson waiting to pick up their order, there was a young woman sitting at a table by herself and a young man sitting by himself at another table. I was asked for my order and I told the person I was waiting for my order already and was told it would be about 5 minutes, that was fine. In the mean time the young woman that was sitting by herself came up and tried to get some tea, when she found the container empty she asked someone behind to counter for some tea and was told it was right there, she informed the person there wasn&apos;t any left and was told it would take a 5 minutes. Now all this time again like at the other restaurant the employees were standing around speaking in Mexican and acting like they had no cares in the world as far as seeing that there was food prepared and ready for customers. I have no problems with with employees enjoying themselves on the job as long as they are curtious and see that they have enough food prepared to serve customers. It is very aggravating to listen to people carring on like there is no reason to be busy, speaking in a foreign language, barely able understand them because their accent in so strong and try to ask for service or help.
Just because people will work cheap doesn&apos;t get the job done and it is proof in the product and so far the result I have seen in my town is a perfect example of poor service. It saddens me greatly that your company is suffering because of poor service. I have to drive twice as far to get to your restaurant now and I can tell you after the last time I&apos;m not sure it is worth it. I had already told my husband quite awhile before this latest incident that that restaurant was heading in the same direction and sorry to say I was right. I am sorry to have to send this but I think you should know what your customers concerns are.

 



 Otha Love 8/2/11 
 I visited your popeyes store # 2710 and the service was very poor. No custormer sevice. I stood at the counter for five minutes before someone could help me. I WAS THE ONLY COUSTOMER IN LINE. I waited forever to get my food. 



 T KILLGORE 7/1/11 
 SOMEONE NEEDS TO CALL ME ASAP I WAS JUST CHASED IN MY CAR BY AN EMPLOYEE /S DATE WITH A BASEBALL BAT .


I WANT JUSTICE ASAPPPPPP.....


 



 thomas killgore 7/1/11 
 i was in line and was threatened by one of your employees, date. at 8 oclock in the drive in . i want he pulled out a baseball bat to threathen me. i want someone to talk to asap. im going to sue you quick. i cant even sit in the drive up being WHITE and be threatined, he chased me in his car. i will get a lawyer and pull your films, i mean the film from 745 to 815 july 1 2001 , im calling a lawyer right now . someone needs to call me asapppppppp. i will own your chicken house.

tk

i will not have this . he pulled a baseball bat out on me.

i will sue you for all you have./..

cause im WHITE...... 



 thomas killgore 7/1/11 
 I WILL OWN YOUR FRANCHISE , I WAS CHASED BY AN EMPLOYEE,S DATE WITH A BASEBALL BAT . IM JUST TRYING TO BUY CHICKEN. YOU NEED SOME PEOPLE THAT ARE NOT RACIST...... HE WAS GOING TO ROB ME IN YOUR PARKING LOT.... HE CHASED ME WITH A BASEBALL BAT .


SOMEONE NEEDS TO CONTACT ME SO I CAN GIVE IT TO MY LAWYERRRRR///

YOUR RACIST...

 



 William Howell 6/25/11 
 Odered chicken at the drive up window. They rang up $1,218 dollars instead of $12.18. They had me sign a receipt for $1,218, because they said they entered it in wrong, then thay had me sign a receipt for $12.18 the actual cost and then they had me sign a receipt for a credit for $1,218. Guess what? The only two that came through and charge against my card were $1,218 and $12.18. I called the store (Pinellas Park, FL) and they said oh well you will just have to go to your bank! Really, I&apos;ve got to take time off work to go to the bank (losing money) because of there mistake. Anybody else want to go to Popeyes Chicken! 



 Q.T 6/28/11 
 Dallas TX on Plano road the staff is very stand offices and has a nasty attitude like theyre ready to fight or want something for free. They are not worry about you get utensil to eat with or napkins to wipe your hands and the killer is you buy chicken and do not get a biscuits because the meal is only 99cent. Get it together and get the order right then people will not get upset and your day will go smoother 



 Ms.Scottie Gray 6/29/11 
 To Whom It May Concern,




On Saturday 20 August 2011 the Los Angeles County Sheriffs Multi-Faith Clergy Council and the H.O.P.E. for Life Foundation will host its Second Annual Multi-Faith Unity Celebration at Whittier Narrows Park, El Monte, California.



The Multi-Faith Clergy Council is a group of dedicated leaders from the faith-based community who volunteer their time and service by partnering with various Sheriffs Department personnel in order to identify and understand the unique needs of the community. The Los Angeles County Multi-Faith Clergy Council is an invaluable resource: it draws from its community members, which have a significant amount of influence towards improving quality of life. They also serve as a source of comfort for individuals who have endured hardship, trauma or distress, such as: the aftermath of violent crimes, death notifications, and so forth.



It is anticipated that well over 2,000 people will attend this event from all regions of Los Angeles County, as their family, friends and constituents will represent each council member invited. This Unity Celebration will provide an opportunity for all council members and their families to enjoy each other in a friendly, fun and wholesome environment. In addition, the Unity Celebration will serve as recognition and reward for the many hours of hard work, dedication and unselfish commitment they have made to their community.



We need your help. We are requesting local organizations and vendors to assist with the purchase and/or supply of much needed items to ensure our Unity Celebration is a total success. We are asking you to help provide us with resources that could assist us in this worthy endeavor. If you prefer, you can provide a monetary donation to help cover the cost. This is a 501 (C) (3) Organization. Your donation is tax deductible.



Please note that all major credit cards and debit cards are accepted and all donations made by check or money order should be made payable to:





H.O.P.E. for Life Foundation

1426 West Manchester Avenue

Los Angeles, CA 90047



As a special way of saying thank you, we would like to offer the following benefits for sponsorship:



Your banner may be hung in the designated area of the Unity Celebration

Your logo will appear on our literature as event sponsors for the remainder of the year

You will be recognized at one of our major events as a sponsor for the Multi-Faith Clergy Unity Celebration

You will receive a formal letter and certificate of appreciation

You may use our Unity Celebration venue for distributing literature or product samples

Following the event, you will receive a brief recap and photos.

I thank you in advance for your support. Please feel free to call my office if you have any questions and/or comments. I can be reached at (323) 753-4673.

Sincerely,





Scottie Gray, Executive Director

H.O.P.E. For Life Foundation
 



 charlene Howard 6/14/11 
 I went to Popeyes Chicken on the Northwest Fwy yesterday to order a jug of Sweet Tea the Sweet Tea had a foul smell to it. 



 Leslie R. 6/20/11 
 I WENT TO THE ELKTON MARYLAND POPEYES FOR CHICKEN FOR MY HUSBAND ON FATHER&apos;S DAY AND GUESS WHAT....THEY MESSED UP MY ORDER. I HAD ORDERED FROM THE DRIVE THRU AND THE WINDOW WAS FILTHY AND CRACKED.I DONT DARE GO INSIDE BECAUSE THE LAST TIME I WENT THERE (YEARS AGO) THERE WERE TOO MANY FLIES AND IT SEEMS AS THO THE STORE HADN&apos;T BEEN CLEANED SINCE IT OPENED...I DIDNT NOTICE THAT MY ORDER WASNT CORRECT UNTIL I GOT HOME SO I CALLED TO SPEAK TO THE MANAGER. AFTER TALKING TO HER AND NOT ACCOMPLISHING ANYTHING I INFORMED HER THAT I WILL NEVER EAT AT POPEYE&apos;S AGAIN AND SHE SAID ...ARE YOU READY???...THAT &apos;S FINE WITH HER IF I NEVER CAME BACK..WOW I WANT TO SPEAK W/ SOMEONE HIGHER UP THAT HER BUT THEY WONT GET BACK TO ME.. ALL MY FRIENDS AND ASSOCIATES WILL GET A COPY OF THIS REVIEW AS WELL AS ALL THE OTHER REVIEWS - (ALL NEGATIVE) SHAME ON POPEYE&apos;S FOR HIRING SUCH NASTY INCOMPETENT WORKERS. HOW DO THEY EXPECT TO STAY IN BIZ? 



 No name 5/24/11 
 I was in Popeye Chicken in Clarksdale Ms today an that sold me some no good chicken today. I call them and told them that the chicken was no good that told to come back to get a discount on more chicken. I think she was told me to come and get my money back. 



 Vern Law 6/2/11 
 visited POPEYES (3) times this week. I know I spent over $50. Yesterday I purchased a coke. I went back to work and it tasted like water. I told Zaesar Rojas at the POPEYES ON ROUTE 1 IN LAUREL, MD. THEIR PHONE NUMBER IS 301-725-0041. He asked me if I had the receipt I told him I accidentally threw it away with the bag. He told me he couldn&apos;t give me a replacement. I thought that was the worst customer service I have every seen. I have my bank receipt showing how many times I went to POPEYES this week. I am very upset. He is not a good manager. I would appreciate if you would have a word with him. Thank you
Disgruntled custer 



 Don Brown 6/5/11 
 I have done quality assurance for thirty years. Salem OR was a 4.6 but today i stopped at the Aurora OR store on I-5 and it didn&apos;t taste like Popeyes 1.0.

Don Brown
503-990-8197 



 joan keller 5/17/11 
 went to the popeye on 76 and good hope,milwaukee,wis. will never go back. cannot here workers talk as they face the cooking area with their backs to you. wanted chicken wings, hardkly listed on their menu. from now on, kentucky feied chicken gets my business. 

 

 T. Bec 5/18/11 
 I contacted Popeyes to complain about their advertisement on television commerical is misleading. They claim if you buy one bonafide three piece dinner you&apos;ll get a two peice free. I did the offer but instead of getting my usual two thighs and a leg with the three peice dinner I got a mix of one leg, one thigh, one wing. I asked the check out girl about this and she said that&apos;s what you get with the special. I told the Popeyes representative and she said the commerical states that the deal says it&apos;s a mix. Not true. I recorded the commerical and no where does it say anything a bout a mix. The representative lied to me to get me off the telephone. When I called back a few days later to advise her to watch the commerical before lying to your customers but they would not answer the telephone. They must have an automatic reference to legitimate callers being kicked out of their system. It&apos;s clearly false advertising and extremely bad customer service. They should be ashamed of misleading the public. No more Popeye&apos;s Churches is better anyway 



 omekia jones 5/18/11 
 The last 4 years I have visited your location on Lake Ave. in Rochester, NY. I have continued to visit your franchise thru the years because I like your food. However I have become tired of the never ending advertisments of discounts that are never honored at this location. The cost is much too high for a fast food place. Each time I ask about an advertised discount I am treated as if I have done something wrong.I sat ther for 30 minutes and they would not honor the sdvertisment that was on tv, so please stop the advertisments if all of the franchises will not honor it. I will just say, you have lost a really good customer. Please Imail me at dude3282231@yahoo.com

 



 Maurice 5/10/11 
 For the last 3 years I have visited your location on Morgan Rd. in Oklahoma City, OK. I have continued to visit your franchise thru the years because I like your product. However I have become tired of the never ending advertisments of discounts that are never honored at this location. The cost is much too high for a fast food place. Each time I ask about an advertised discount I am treated as if I have done something wrong. Training is greatly needed. I have read the other comments on this page and it seems that comments are falling on deaf ears. I will just say you have lost a really good customer. You have a product; get your act together.

Maurice Smith
405-317-3767 



 sam loveless 4/11/11 
 PLEASE BRING A POPEYE&apos;S TO LASALLE/PERU ILLINOIS.
WE ALL EAT CHICKEN DOWN HERE AND WE ARE ALL SICK OF KFC AND WALMART CHICKEN.


WE NEED POPEYE&apos;S WE NEED POPEYE&apos;S WE NEED POPEYE&apos;S
IN LASALLE/PERU ILLINOIS

THANK YOU
SAM LOVELESS 



 kenny chambers 4/21/11 
 OHH, NO NO this place is rediculous. I dont know where to start with this old shak. they sell biuscuts, but no honey. My very good friend and i went to eat there bought 10 pieces nd three side orders to go with our meal.Well we asked for barbecue sauce and got charged for it. the guy employee was on his phone and didnt seem to give me my change back. no matter what that place took all my money and the worst thing about it is that i will NOt return there. I will not let any of my friends or family go there and get treated like a fool.terrible experiences in the past 



 carol wooten 4/17/11 
 I was recently in your drive-thru in leesburg Va. I ordered the 499 shimp special. I was charged 699 the regular price. My biggest complaint is that they charged my debit card twice. The only reason I caught this is I just happened to checkn my bank account that night. I feel this is going to be a problem, because when I talked to the manager, he told me yes we charged you twice, but I would have to go through my bank to fix it. No apology at all. I called the 866 no. to complain. She took my name, e-mail, phone number, but I have heard nothing from you!! 



 pissed off in el paso 4/17/11 
 I just came from popeyes on alemeda, and chelsea, or the fox plaza store. First off let me say I wanted to give them no stars but one is the least u can do apparently. This was a terrible experience, I bought food so I could park there and went to nearby store, in the half hour I was gone my car was towed away. I had my wife an 8 month old baby and three little girls left there with no ride. I went to retrieve my car and while my family was waiting they were very rude, and the b#tch manager &quot;silvia de la rosa garza&quot;. Wouldn&apos;t give me the # to corporate and the # she did give me, no one answered. I would like to know what kind of establishment is this place? Horrible experience I vow never to eat there and to bad mouth popeyes to everyone I know. 



 Jon and Mary McQuarters 4/7/11 
 I went to the Thomson, Georgia Popeyes to eat with my wife and found that one of the Managers had been working some
Long hours. My wife said that Is that the same manager that was here last night when we stopped by I looked and said yes
She is the same one why is she still working. I asked one of the employees who is the manager on duty tonight and she told me
That her name is Pam. I am very concerned with the direction Popeyes is going in with the way they work the people that work
for them. She (Pam) have been working some long hours (5:30 am to 10pm for over two days back to back and from what we
found out Pam have been working all week. Is this how your company takes care of its people? Why do Popeye need to work
them like that? Is it because Popeye do not care what happens to people when they work like that. Do they think that maybe Pam have a family at home and would like to spend some time with them?

My wife told me that if it was me, she would call and report this so that something could be done because this is not the way that I feel that Popeyes need to work the employees (managers or non managers). I hope Popeyes doesn&apos;t just throw this email away but use it to improve the way that some of the managers work. I love to eat at Popeyes but after look at this I am not sure if we should stand by and see that Popeyes is not taking care of its employees. I trued calling back to the store by I did not get an answer. I should have call or try to call Popeyes Headquarters but I needed to talk to Pam first maybe shes okay with working like this but Im not.

It will make one think that Popeye do not care and that the Corporate Office must condone this because its no way that someone
have not called in telling you how this one manager is doing all of this work, you should just see how she look, she looks
as if she have not gotten any rest in a few days. There are too many people who are unemployed who would love to get a job
and this way Pam would not have to work like this. Why or how does the Corporate Office put up with this? If the store is
suffering because they need more managers, you have no one to blame but yourselves.

I still love your food but I do not like the way that your managers work. Some one need to find out whos her boss and get to the bottom of this.....Because of this I have to give a rating of POOR. 



 Fed - Trenton, NJ 4/2/11 
 Location - Nottingham Way Mercerville, NJ - We tried a few things and were generally disapointed. We asked for the spicy white and received the plain chicken and the fries were dripping in grease. The prices were definetely too high for the quality of the food. Would not recomend. 



 OTTO R. 3/29/11 
 THOUGH I ENJOY THEIR CHICKEN FROM TIME TO TIME,I FIND THE SERVICE LACKING.I HAVE BEEN GIVEN LESS THAN WHAT I ORDERED ON MULTIPLE OCCASSIONS.THE PARKING LOT IS NOT VERY WELL CARED FOR,AND THE GREETING AND THE RESPONSE AFTER BEING SERVED IS OFTEN NONEXISTANT.THIS IS THE YOUNGSTOWN,OHIO STORE.TODAY I HAD TO RETURN A PURCHASE BECAUSE AGAIN IT WAS LESS THAN I ORDERED.I ASKED FOR MY MONEY BACK AND RECEIVED IT.I AM DONE WITH THE YOUNGSTOWN STORE. 



 joy nichols 3/30/11 
 pine bluff ,ar. on 270 last week,chickin on sale and everyone an there momma was there and by the time I tryed to order,I would had to waited 2 frikkin hours for a box of 5 dollor chickin.Now what kinda biz is that?Fast food go figure. 



 alexis hughes 3/25/11 
 The popeyes on Fletcher ave in Tampa Fl is disgusting and the service is awful to say the least. The drive thru person is very rude. I will never go there nor will i encourage anyone else to. Im absoloutly stunned how people can hold their jobs being so damn rude and nasty! 



 Ms. Govain 3/17/11 
 I see Popeyes chicken all over but there isn&apos;t one in the Quad City area. We would like to have a Popeyes chicken here too. We like chicken, beans, rice and biscuits. Most of us don&apos;t even like KFC so please bless up with a Popeyes chicken restraunt. I&apos;m sure it will get lots of business. 



 3/20/11 
 Hi my name is Howard Hill , I have been working in Hinesville Ga for about 6 months. I have no complaint with the headquarters , however I do have one with the Hinesville branch. Before I get started , let me just say. I am a huge fan of the shrimp po boy sandwich. Have been for years. Not taking away from the chicken , but I always perfered the shrimp sandwich over everything. I have been frequenting the branch in Hinesville GA in hopes of getting a po boy. I was successfull once , but every other time , they say &quot;we are all out of popcorn shrimp&quot; and yesterday after whoever was supposedly in charge explained to the cashier they were out of shrimp. The cashier exclaimed &quot;I&apos;m glad , now I dont have to make it....
Now as a fan of the po boy , I was already disappointed , but her remark was tantum out to a slap in the face , as far as I&apos;m concerned.
Now I&apos;m not certain what the reason behind this &quot;conspiracy&quot; against me is , but I&apos;m quite positive its not due to lack of shrimp.


Faithful Popeyes fan
Howard Hill
email hillh57@yahoo.com 



 Store#4015 3/23/11 
 When to Popeye&apos; on Markham Street in Little Rock, Arkansas s for lunch&amp;saw 15-20 customers waiting on their orders, when I noticed several workers waiting on one customer who had come to get chicken for Whole Hogg Cafe&amp;bought all the chicken that was cooked, mild&amp;spicey.;He also bought allof the potatoes&amp;gravy to take to his restaurant to sell at an increased rate. This was during the lunch hour rush, causing some customers to get a refund on their orders, after spending their whole lunch time waiting,leaving w/o any food to eat. The Asst , Mgr, Miracle Stewart, had the nerve to get an attitude;body language, when the other restaurant should have been deferred until their cudtomers were satisfied seeing we are there all the time and they were there for GREED&amp;to make a profit off of someone else. Something needs to be done about this or forfeit the loss of customers, 



 Dr. Campbell 3/23/11 
 Little Rock&apos;s Store#4015, Mgr Miracle Stewart, saw fit to take a large order from Whole Hogg Restaurant than to take care of the 17 regular lunch customers who stood by having to wait 15-20 minutes, some requesting refunds. What is happening? This is a managerial decision and should have been deferred until after the lunch hour. All knowing the chicken would be served to their customers at an increased rate
Sorry for their customers. 



 i love popeyes. very good,. we have experience great food and service fro 3/24/11 
 i love popeyes. very good,. we have experience great food and service from the staff at the hwy249 and veterans memorial for many years. Only one exception, mr Loyd the mgr. He treat his team members like animals most of the time. we are in that store 3 or 4 times every week. we love popeyes food. there in the past mr Loyd have had some food safety issues but, the team members let us know whats safe, and whats not. But theres a lot of mr Loyd&apos;s in the food industry. But there are also good team mates. My name is Dominick. 8322587527. Thanks 



 Bob Gillespie 3/8/11 
 I just stopped in at Popeyes chicken for lunch, had a coupon for 8 pc. chicken. 4 legs and 4 thighs. I asked if I could get all legs, not liking thighs. Answer. Not without paying a .15 upcharge on all 8 legs. I said well, I get 4 legs with the order, so I should have to only pay upcharge on other 4 legs. NO!!! You have to pay upcharge on all 8 legs. Ok , said no to that deal. So I asked about the Boneafide 3 pc meal for $6.99. What do you get you ask, 1 leg, 1 thigh and 1 wing, as far as the chicken goes. I asked, you mean for $7.00 I can&apos;t even get a breast. No!!! Wow, that&apos;s like pretty steep for those meally pieces of chicken. Needless to say, I left, a hungry and disappointed chicken lover. My reason for telling this is not for everyone to fry me up some chicken and send it to me, but rather to see if I couldn&apos;t persuade all the standup people out there to stand up and support me. I will not eat at Popeyes again until they change this pricing. Somewhere we have to quit letting these places walk all over us. They forget that without us they are non exisistant. If you don&apos;t believe in standing up for what&apos;s right, and you choose to go to Popeyes anyway, would you mind spending some extra and bring me a bucket of breasts and legs. Thanks
 



 glinda giles 2/15/11 
 this is the concern of the buiness of the popeyes store # 3696 they are to slow they do not give you any friendly welcome just can i help you,and you can not go there on a lunch break because you will not be able to eat your lunch they do not say anything to you if you ask a question they may answer you or look at you like you are the crazy one please ,please help them so that we can received some better service in that area no friendlyness at all, just send in a secrete shopper and you can see for yourself most the customer are going to churchie cause they are to slow again this is the store #3696 in chicago il located on Roosevelt Rd please help them or they are going to put you guys out of buiness, cause of the service that we are getting please,please help! 



 Ms. N 2/18/11 
 I went to Popeye&apos;s (located in Mishawaka, IN) on my lunch break and ordered the special of popcorn chicken and fries. But, much to my surprise the chicken was raw. Can you believe that? As small as the pieces are, how is it that the chicken was not done. Even after I had waited on them to cook some more. So, I had no lunch and now my lunch break was over.
After multiple attempts of calling, I finally got through. And, when I did, the MANAGER had no sympathy. All she said when I explained what happened was. &quot;I would like to see that&quot;. Like I had nothing to do better that to call and let her know of there mishap. She wanted me to bring it back. But, as I said before, my lunch was over. I had to wait until I got off from work, pick up my kids, run take of other business, before I could resolve this issue. She didn&apos;t seem to be concerned that I just consumed RAW ASS chicken.
Customer Service I Think NOTTTTTTTTTTTTT!!!!!!
Thanks for the SIMONELLA lunch! 

 

 fed up 1/13/11 
 every time i got to the Popeyes chicken on Grand and Michigan in downtown chicago IL. the owner is very cheap and will not give you a Breast with any order larger than 2 pieces. i ordered 15pc of chicken and he wanted to give me 5-wings 5-legs 5-thighs, another friend ordered 30pcs and out of all of that chicken not one breast.
he says that the order dont come with breast.
he wouldn&apos;t let me change my side with a 2pc to red beans and rice because the coupon picture had fries in the picture. i will never patronage this business ever again. 



 1/4/11 
 Sir(Madame); I purchased your great chicken today, took it home set my table and feed the family. I noticed the amount of salt in the chicken. I hope you will take a look into this. So many are suffering with kidney,diabetes and high blood pressure diseases, attacking various races in america. A little less salt will not bother your great chicken. Please take this under consideration. We want to eat more of your chicken. But if you keep this up more will began to stop purchasing the chicken. Becase it has the ability to make a person sick. I have eaten at many Popeyes restaurant, sad to say all of them are so salty, I would hate to stop eating you delicious chicken, but the salt content is getting to be too much. Please find an find an alternative. Try and change, change is good Mary Cottrell 



 TimeOut 1/7/11 
 I love our food from your store here in Ocean Springs, MS. However, each time I order I am asked to move forward while my food is prepared and they will bring my order to the car. Many people are aware that they must be on a timer!! At my last visit, I decided that I would NOT move forward again. When I did not, the cashier was pretty nasty. I moved forward to avoid conflict. However, this store (I am sure as many others are as well) is on a heavily traveled road especially during rush hours. Due to the other SUV in front of me I had a difficult time maneuvering around and was almost into traffic where I awaited a 10 minute arrival of my food. Now, I understand the wait time. However, there is a local chicken place as well as KFC that do not share these same practices. The local restaurant actually has homemade yeast rolls. As great as your food is people will choose to go other restaurants if they are mistreated. I would advise that READ AND TAKE ACTION of all of the comments that you are receiving around the nation!! BAD BUSINESS!! 



 Joe Baker 12/25/10 
 I ordered and paid for 8 pieces of chicken at Kingman,AZ. received 6 pieces. It was Christmas Day and I believe that the employees were trying to send a message. Message received. FUCK Popeyes Chicken, VIVA KFC!!! 



 Cat 12/3/10 
 Didnt get complete order called back once I realized it at home they answered hung up I was very polite and still they refused to pick up the phone when
I tried clling again. I wanted to know if I actually paid for what was missing they never picked up. Whats fast sefvice fior if they cannot get the order correct. Rude people are unexcuseable especially if you run a business that depends on it..... 



 Angela C. 12/4/10 
 Why is the popeyes chicken on west 38th street closed? I really miss my wing, breast meal... 



 Terry from Liberty 11/17/10 
 I go to lunch at least once a week in Houston at your store on N. Shepherd. 3 out of 5 times my order is wrong. I buy the same thing and the amount I am charged is always different. Popeye&apos;s has gotten expensive on their chicken. I paid $6.70 for a 2 piece meal today, too much to pay. The store&apos;e employees are very rude, they look at you like it&apos;s my fault they screwed up and got my order wrong. I hate the policy of having a customer pull around to the front to wait on their order. I didn&apos;t sit in line to order just to have to pull around to the front. The interior of the store is filthy. So, someone needs to get out in the field and check on the stores and get people in the stores who actually are their to please the customer instead of just interested in getting a pay check. Popeye&apos;s needs to wake up, you may not have many customers to even worry about if changes aren&apos;t made. 



 grumpu913 11/13/10 
 I have beenwatching your commercials for quite a while and that black woman spoksperson does not impress me at all the way she keeps comming across is she owns Popeye&apos;s all by her self and this calling people HONEY is disquesting that is one of the main rerasons I would not bue evev a cup of water from your restaurants. Tell that woman to clean up her presentation a lot fo people DO NOT liked to be called HONEY 



 Randy E 11/6/10 
 I&apos;m wondering can the people of cedar rapids iowa have a popeyes placed here we got like 5 hardess 5 Mc D&apos;s 4 kfc&apos;s 4 wendy&apos;s and no popeyes this is the place to be i have not had popeyes since i moved out of chicago so can the people of cr iowa get one please my email is erandy25@yahoo.com hope to hear from you soon 



 David T. 11/2/10 
 I Was Inside A Popeye&apos;s Chicken On Today On The Southside Of Chicago. At The 35TH Street Store And Many People Inside The Store Wasn&apos;t Satisfy Because The Store Worker Has A Nasty Attitude. And They Never Have ANY Hot Sauce Or Any Honey At All When Peoples Ask For Some.The Worker Have Poor Customer Service Skills At This Store. 



 Ernie Tumbleson 10/25/10 
 I`m a very concerned Grandfather of 1 of your employees.My granddaughter works a Popeyes in Fairfield ,Oh. and a few weeks ago I was told that 1 of the managers their had made some sexual comments to her.Her mother had called the H R dept.and was told that they would take care of it.Well the way it was taken care of was that that told my granddaughter that they wouldn`t work the same shifts.To me that is totally unacceptable,no time off for him or even fired O` by the way she is only 16 and her first job.Well I will pass her experience on to other people in the area.She has put her 2 weeks notice in and as of now no longer works for Popeyes.This could of gone alot further but she was to embarrassed to go on.
A very concerned Grandfather
Ernie Tumbleson

 



 scared in Delaware 10/17/10 
 You have people who deal drugs working and serving food at the location in Delaware. Why would that be??? Serving food to everyone ..children,adults and elderly? Drug dealers....Are you kidding me? what kind of place do you run? Don&apos;t you backround checks?
 



 a worried person 10/15/10 
 was wondering if you would tell me why the mexican counter lady at the store on fed. and elcuid aves here in san diego calif. has a son and daughter under 5 years old that hang out in the lobby while she works...fighting with each other and their mom rather loudly...also running though the store..and in thee back.....also you REALLY need to test the people there for drugs has i have on a few times that i been there smelled the oder of weed on a few of your workers.......is this normal for your stores to be run this way............ 



 KATHA 10/14/10 
 I JUST LEFT THE SOOOOOOOO CALLED FAMOUS CHICKEN SHACK............. SHAME, SHAME, SHAME ON THEM. i&apos;M PRESSING A LEGALLY LAW SUIT AND I&apos;LL START MY OWN RESTURANT. KNOW-ONE! NOT ONE GOT SEVERAL ORDERS RIGHT. FLYS EVERY-WHERE. DISCUSTING.. IF I GET HARD UP I&apos;LL GO TO KFC OR ANYTHING CLASSY. WHAT A DUMP. WHAT A SHAME, I REAALLY LOVED THE FLAVOR, BUT THE FLYS AND THE GIRLS IN-FRONT, MUST OF BEEN 6 OF THEM MESSED UP 3 ORDERS PRIOR TO ME, ..................HELLOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOO! THAT SHOULD HAVE BEEN A SIGN..... A LIGHT BULD MOMENR, GOOOOOOOOO-BYE POPEYES! see! Yah! 



 Diane 10/11/10 
 I have just finished reading the previous 13 reviews and 10 of them were not pleasant. I find the employees to be rude,not paying attention to orders, and when confronted will deny everything! What a shame. The food products are good but the employees are uneducated, uninformed and obviously not well trained. When I voiced my dilemma to the manager I was told she just arrived. Aren&apos;t managers paid to deal with situations as they happen regardless of when they started their shift? It just is not worth the aggrivation to check the order everytime and more often than not it isn&apos;t correct. When you confront someone at the restaurant, they are rude or indifferent and never apologize. They don&apos;t care and I can only asdume the corporate office condones their behavior. There are too many people who are unemployed who would love to have their job. Why does corporate put up with this? Your business is suffering and you have no one to blame but yourselves. 



 Jim 10/11/10 
 Your customer service in the Cincinnati Oh store at Madison Rd and Williams Ave in Oakley is the PITTS. The so called Mangers know and do nothing and the counter people could care less to get the orders right. They don&apos;t listen. NO MORE FOR ME. GET OUT OF TOWN. Board of Health needs to get in on this dump also. Hair in the food-no gloves and probly more that I could not see. 



 sharon 10/3/10 
 I recently was in the Atlanta airport and received the best service for a fast food restaurant ever. one young man named Dwayne was one of the hardest working and pleasant young person I have seen in a long time. 



 CHERYL 9/30/10 
 The Popeyes in Euless TX 306 N. Main is the sorriest restaurant I have ever encountered. I have given them chance after chance to improve and they just get worst. In the past they have been plagued with flies and still continute to sit unfinished orders out until the chicken is cooked. I went there today I and like most customers I dont scrutinize my change so when I returned my order which was unsatisfactory I saw that and I was shortchanged again. Goodbye Popeyes.... 



 Georgia Frasier 4/28/10 
 The food is good. However, the Ruston, Louisiana, Popeyes needs attention. It is chronically understaffed and it right across the street from a university. It takes on average 10-15 minutes to get them to take your order then another 5-10 to get it. This is in the drive-in. Fast food is NOT their working plan. I have driven off numerous times because of the wait. I have arrived at 4:30 pm, 6:00 pm and after 9:00 pm...same thing, so it isn&apos;t the &quot;time of day&quot;. And the general premises are shabby.

I would hope that someone in management wants to know and take corrective actions. 



 Jesse Torreyson 5/16/10 
 I am very concerned with the direction Popeyes is going in. They were are first choice when it comes to fried Chicken, how ever I&amp;others that I have talked to feel that they have priced themselfs out of the market. My wife went to go get some chicken for our family. A typical order . She orders a 12ps chicken , only chicken&amp;the guy said it would be $26.00 ... With out hesitation she said Thanks but no thanks. She went to Roy Rogers&amp;bought the same thing for $ 14.99 The service was 10x better&amp;obviously the price was a lot better. I hope popeys doesn&apos;t just throw this email away but uses it to improve their sales&amp;customer Service. Please feel free to email me if you would like to keep a customer. Jtorreyson@comcast.net This location is Frederick Maryland. Rt 40 location.

Reguards
Jesse Torreyson
 

 

 MTGreen 6/2/10 
 Sorry I had to post this complaint, because no one has answered the phone as of yet. Over 10 minutes of music playing, and while I&apos;m writing this email, it&apos;s still playing. So I feel you really are not that interested in real customers concerns.

Problem: The Popeye&apos;s location in Indianapolis, IN -- 46th in the Devington Plaza needs to remove their dumpers away from were individuals have to order thier food in the drive through. It absolutely stinks, and its not good for business. So I know I won&apos;t be returning there. MTG 



 anonymous 9/16/10 
 I&apos;m sorry Popeye&apos;s, I love your chicken but there is never any ready. The price is right, one question...why couldn&apos;t you pay taxes to stay open...its very sad to see y&apos;all go again in Indianapolis! Get it together and come back.... 



 Vernan Walker 9/20/10 
 Store Number 5649 Address 1116 Travis St Houston Texas the manager and clerk totatlly disrepectful to customers. The manager was very unprofessional telling customers that if they can do a better job they need to come behind the counter. There was only six customers in the store at that time. They were unorganized
and very rude. 



 jmoon 6/10/10 
 I VISITED POPEYES AFTER WORK ONE DAY WHEN I WAS TOO TIRED TO COOK DINNER, I ORDERED A 2 PIECE DARK MEAL WIRH RED BEANS AND RICE. TO MY DISMAY WHEN I GOT HOME I HAS A 2 PIECE ALL WHITE MEAT DINNER WITH COLESLAW. I TRIED CALLING THEM BUT THEY DID NOT ANSWER. I CALLED HEADQUARTERS AND THEY APOLOGIED, TOOK MY NAME AND ADDRESS INFO. THAT WAS ABOUT A MONTH AGO, I HAVEN&apos;T HEARD FROM THEM YET. 



 Shawn Whitfield 6/11/10 
 I live in Columbia, Mo. there is not a POPEYES in my city. Unless I travel to St. Louis or Kansas City. I think it would be beneficial to everyone, if there was a POPEYES establishment opened here. Thank you. 



 Sami 7/28/10 
 Hey I like your food but I&apos;m concered about my grandpa,s health can you let the customer chosse grilled or fried chicken. 



 Monique 7/1/10 
 I went to a popeyes in Baytown, tx and was very disappointed , my biscuit had a bug in it. A big visible bug, I have pictures to ptoove it that&apos;s nasty!! 



 jason 7/23/10 
 i too live in columbia missouri and wish they would bring popeyes back to columbia. were a bigger city now and need something other than kfc and lees chicken, i know their are plenty of people who feel the same and would keep them in business 



 David 7/23/10 
 I went to the Hagerstown md store tonight and while I was in the drive thru ordering my food a lady employee approached my car and stood between my door and the speaker while I was ordering my food she was trying to talk while I was which made placing my order impossible and she could not speak english I believe she was german or russian I told her I did not understand her at this time she started lifting on my door handle trying to enter my car so I pulled ahead and explained to the teller at the window what happened and he laughed and said thats weired and that was all so I then called the store and asked for the manager and they said he stepped out for abit so I then called later and spoke with him when I explained what happened and told him how I felt violated and was upset about the whole ordeal he said well she cant speak english and she does not know any better.Why make excuses people this should not be excepted and I really should and might sue popeyes wht if she harmed my infant son that was in the back seat I feel that the lady the drive thru teller and the manager should be FIRED 

 Page 1  Page 2  Page 3  Page 4  Page 5  Page 6  





 Write A Review For Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Corporate Headquarters 
Note: This is not to be used to contact Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits Corporate Offices nor is this site affiliated with them in any way. The purpose of this site is supply you with their phone number and address as well as share your thoughts about Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits. Your review will be posted and available for anyone to read so please keep that in mind when posting personal information. 

 
 
 Your Name Your Rating (5 Stars) Best (4 Stars) Better (3 Stars) Good (2 Stars) Fair (1 Stars) Poor 
 
 
 Other Headquarters 
 Barnes&amp;Noble Corporate Office 
 Farm Fresh Corporate Office 
 Trader Joe&apos;s Company Corporate Office 
 Miami Subs Corporate Office 
 Midas, Inc Corporate Office 
 T-Mobile Corporate Office 
 Best Buy Corporate Office 
 Home Depot Corporate Office 
 Directv Corporate Office 
 Giant Eagle, Inc Corporate Office 
 Live Nation, Inc Corporate Office 
 AT&amp;T;Corporate Office 
 Prada Usa Corp Corporate Office 
 USAA Corporate Office 
 Bealls Corporate Office 
 Tyson Foods, Inc Corporate Office 
 Aaa Auto Club South, Inc Corporate Office 
 Mr. Tire Corporate Office 
 Morgan Stanley Corporate Office 
 Honda Motor Company Corporate Office 
 Wendy&apos;s/Arby&apos;s Group, Inc Corporate Office 
 Abbey Carpet Corporate Office 
 Merrill Lynch Corporate Office 
 Eastbay Corporate Office 
 Qvc, Inc Corporate Office 
 more 
 

 
 Copyright2009-2012 eCorporateOffices - Privacy Policy - Contact Us - Location - Radio - Textbook 
All reviews on this website are user-generated and we take no responsibility of any kind for the content which is posted. We do not know the accuracy of the reviews.
	</body>
</document>
