<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004111" url="http://holidays.easyjet.com/italy/sicily/taormina-holidays.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:21" support="1" score="0.0014572127719894243" bingtitle="Cheap Taormina Holidays 2012 | easyJet Holidays" webtitle="Cheap Taormina Holidays 2012 | easyJet Holidays">
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>During your holiday in Taormina you’ll struggle to find a fast-food restaurant, Sicilians are not fans of the stuff so instead they encourage everyone to try their ...</description>
	<body>
		easyJet.com UK English [change] English Deutsch Español Français Italiano Nederlands easyJet Holidays 
 Flights 
 
Flights
 Book a Flight Where easyJet flies Speedy Boarding easyJet Plus Manage Bookings Airport Lounges 
 Where to stay 
 
Where to stay
 Hotels Hostels 
 Getting around 
 
Getting around
 Car Rental Transfers Airport Parking Stansted Express Gatwick Express 
 Essentials 
 
Essentials
 Travel Insurance 
 What to do 
 
What to do
 Holidays Ski breaks 
 
 call now for great holiday deals 
0843 104 1000 low rate 
 Holidays &gt; Italy &gt; Sicily &gt; Holidays to Taormina &gt; Home Special Offers City Breaks Beach Ski Help and Info My Bookings 
Sign up to easyJet&apos;s FREE email newsletter
 
Holidays to Taormina
 Holiday prices per person for 7 nights from £179.44 Overview Prices&amp;Offers Hotels 
Taormina deals
 
Sicily

Mazzaro Sea Palace

Taormina, Sicily

B&amp;B, Aug, 7 nights, 5 star
 from only £1,400 pp 
Sicily

Atlantis Bay

Taormina, Sicily

B&amp;B, Aug, 7 nights, 5 star
 from only £1,472 pp 
Sicily

Villa Esperia

Taormina, Sicily

B&amp;B, Jan, 7 nights, 4 star
 from only £328 pp 
Sicily

continental

Taormina, Sicily

B&amp;B, Oct, 7 nights, 3 star
 from only £410 pp 
Taormina Travel Information
 Language Italian and Sicilian Currency Euro Local time GMT/BST +1 hour Local airport Catania Flight time 3 hours 10 minutes Transfer time 50 minutes 
Grand Hotel San Pietro
 Click pin on map for more info 
Hotel Excelsior - Taormina
 Click pin on map for more info 
Hotel Caparena
 Click pin on map for more info 
Hotel Hellenia
 Click pin on map for more info 
D&apos;Orange D&apos;Alcantara
 

This is a cosy hotel situated near Taormina, in a small village called Francavilla di Sicilia. The 3 star hotel D&apos;Orange D&apos;Alcantara is the perfect solution, for clients visiting not only Taormina but...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Ariston
 

This hotel is the annexe property of the Hotel Ariston, situated 50 metres away. All services such as reception, check in and check out, restaurant are available at the Hotel Ariston. 0410 GA

 Click pin on map for more info 
Grande Albergo Capotaormina
 

The hotel offers a total of 190 rooms over 6 floors. Facilities at this air-conditioned establishment include a lobby, 24-hour reception and check-out service, hotel safe, lift access, hairdressing sa...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Park Hotel Silemi
 

This beach hotel is ideal for a seaside holiday in Letojanni. Comprising a total of 94 rooms spread across 6 floors, it is fully air-conditioned and includes a lobby, a hotel safe and lift access. The...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Antares
 

The 7-storey hotel comprises a total of 102 rooms and facilities include an inviting foyer with a 24-hour reception desk, a currency exchange desk, lifts, in addition to a café, a selection of shops, ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Vello D Oro
 

Nice reception waiting area, lounge room with bar and Sat. TV.

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Esperia
 

This is a lovely hotel located near the beach and with easy access to Taormina city center up on the hill. DC 07/08

 Click pin on map for more info 
Sole Castello
 

Renovated in 2001, this 3-floor hotel comprises a total of 54 rooms. Facilities include a 24-hour reception desk, safes, a lift, a bar, a TV room, a restaurant, an outdoor terrace, conference faciliti...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Linda
 

This hotel comprises a total of 40 rooms and features a foyer in the main building with a 24-hour reception desk, a lift, a bar and a breakfast room. Those arriving by car may make use of the local pu...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Crystal Sea
 

Opened in 2001, this hotel comprises a 5-storey main building with a total of 39 rooms. Guests may make use of the foyer with 24-hour reception desk, a hotel safe, a currency exchange counter and a li...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Natalina
 

The hotel comprises a total of 21 rooms set over four floors. Facilities on offer include a welcoming foyer with 24-hour reception, a currency exchange counter, and lifts. There is a bar and a restaur...

 Click pin on map for more info 
NH Grand Hotel Timeo
 

The building housing this historic hotel dates back to 1873 and represents one of the most interesting places in the region. It offers 83 rooms in total. It is air-conditioned and has a lobby with 24-...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Atlantis Bay
 

Opened in 2002, this 4-floor top hotel comprises a total of 86 rooms and features an elegant foyer with a 24-hour reception desk, safes, a currency exchange bureau and a lift in addition to a bar, a T...

 Click pin on map for more info 
La Plage Resort
 

Renovated in 2001, this hotel comprises a total of 61 rooms set over a single floor. Guests are welcomed in the foyer with 24-hour reception desk, a safe and a currency exchange counter. The air-condi...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Sant Alphio Garden
 

The main restaurant serves a buffet breakfast and evening meal with local Sicilian dishes and International cuisine. There are also 2 bars serving beverages with 24hr service. Relax around the outdoor...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Diodoro
 

Villa Diodoro Hotel

Enjoy a value holiday in Sicily by booking your stay at the comfortable Villa Diodoro Hotel.

The Villa Diodoro Hotel is a few steps from the town centre of Taormina, and offers a u

 Click pin on map for more info 
Corallo
 

This hotel comprises 5 floors with a total of 36 rooms and features a foyer with a 24-hour reception desk, a lift, a bar, a TV room and a restaurant. Those arriving by car may make use of the hotel ca...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Ipanema
 

This is a good property ideally located just meters away from the seaside. the hotel also offers a swimming-pool on the rooftop. DC 06/07

 Click pin on map for more info 
Grand Hotel Miramare
 

Freshwater swimming pool is immersed in the greenery of the garden in perfect harmony with its surroundings and is reached by a scenic characteristic pathway of 186 steps overlooking the splendid pano...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Bay Palace
 

The Bay Palace is a 4 star complex situated in Taormina Mare, Sicily. It consists of elegant rooms designed to offer guests comfort and services. The pool, the restaurant, the bar and the other hotel ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Marabel
 

Excellent value for money! Clean, practical, and comfortable guestrooms with private facilities at exceptionally competitive prices, this is what the 3 star hotel Marabel has to offer. Situated in St ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Albatros
 

This hotel affords 77 rooms spread over 4 floors. Guests are welcomed in the inviting foyer with 24-hour reception desk, a safe, a currency exchange desk and 2 lifts. There is a bar to make use of as ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Isabella
 

The hotel is ideally located on the main street of Taormina, with all its main attactions just a short walk away and among all the most popular shops. 02/09 IS

 Click pin on map for more info 
Olimpo
 

The 5-storey hotel comprises a total of 310 rooms and features an inviting foyer with a 24-hour reception desk, a currency exchange facility and lifts in addition to a café, a bar, a games room, a TV ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Bianca Resort
 

The hotel offers to all guests a shuttle service to the Ipanema Lido which is a complex situated by the sea with Swimming pool , private beach , Bar and football pitch . The access is free of charge f...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Mediterranee Hotel
 

There are 50 rooms in total across two buildings. Facilities include a lobby, a 24-hour reception service, a currency exchange, a cloakroom and lift access. There is also a bar, a TV room, a restauran...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Capo dei Greci
 

This is a very good property in a secluded and unique location in the Taormina area . DC 07/08

 Click pin on map for more info 
Nike Hotel
 

This charming beach hotel offers accommodation and facilities in Mediterranean style, and there are marvellous views of the hillside town of Taormina with its famous Greek-Roman amphitheatre and Mt. E...

 Click pin on map for more info 
NH Villa Sant&apos; Andrea
 

The Hotel offers a private sandy beach and free Wi-Fi. The wellness centre offers relaxing treatments and massage, and a well-equipped gym.The hotel&apos;s restaurant Oliviero serves typical Sicilian cuisi...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Hotel Baia Taormina Hotel&amp;Spa
 

This fully air-conditioned beach hotel offers much more than a relaxed and hospitable atmosphere. It provides its guests with an entrance hall with a 24-hour reception desk, a hotel safe, a currency e...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Bay Palace Hotel
 

Bay Palace Hotel

Enjoy a richly romantic holiday in Sicily by booking your stay at the luxurious Bay Palace Hotel.

The Bay Palace Hotel is located in the popular tourist resort of Mazzaro Beach, Taorm

 Click pin on map for more info 
San Domenico Palace
 

The touches of class&amp;elegance throughout the hotel could be listed at great lenght, but suffice to say this is problably the best hotel in Sicily. DC 08/08

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Paradiso
 

This is a recommended property ideally located just a short walk away from the historical centre and the Greek theatre. Amongst its services the hotel also offers from mid june to the end of october a...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Sporting Baia Hotel
 

The hotel offers restaurant, bar, 24h front desk, terrace, room service and bicycle rental.

 Click pin on map for more info 
Elios
 

Renovated in 2008, this family-friendly hotel is equipped with all the modern conveniences, including lift access, hot and cold running water and air conditioning. The establishment comprises a total ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Hilton Portorosa
 

Explore Italy&apos;s Patti Gulf from the hotel with incomparable views of the Portorosa Marina and Eolie Islands. Hold an inspiring conference in our naturally lit Congress Center and flexible meeting room...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Holiday Club Naxos
 

This holiday village consists of 252 apartments, situated within a broad and well-kept park. Besides the beauty of the location, guests staying here can make use of the lobby, 24-hour reception servic...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Riis
 

This historic Baroque hotel comprises a total of 44 guest rooms. It is air-conditioned and features a pleasant bar area (with happy hour), a tennis court, the Riis Health Club and a delightful swimmin...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Giardino Dei Greci
 

This new elegant and comfortable hotel comprises 68 rooms in total and welcomes guests into a lobby with a 24-hour reception and check-out service, safe and lift access. Fully air-conditioned, the hot...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Panoramic
 

This air-conditioned beach hotel was renovated in 2006 and has a total of 34 rooms. Guests are welcomed into a reception hall with a 24-hour check-in service. Facilities include a hotel safe, lift acc...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villaggio Alkantara
 

This apartment hotel comprises a total of 75 accommodation units. Facilities on offer to guests include a lobby area with a 24-hour reception and check-out service, a cloakroom and a newspaper stand. ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Bel Soggiorno
 

This historical 32-room hotel, in a building dating from 1908, is surrounded by a large garden filled with lemon, orange and mandarin trees and the stone terraces overflow with aloes and typical Sicil...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Il Piccolo Giardino
 

The Hotel Il piccolo Giardino has a convenient location in the downtown area of Taormina, Sicily, close to the bustling Corso Umberto. Set amid chic boutiques and interesting workshops where local cra...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Sylesia
 

Fully air-conditioned, this newly-built, 16-room hotel is situated in the middle of the wonderful Letojanni bay. Its lobby features a 24-hour reception and check-out service as well as a hotel safe fo...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Chiara
 

This city hotel comprises a total of 10 rooms over 3 floors and features a sun terrace. Facilities on offer to guests at this air-conditioned establishment include a lobby area with a 24-hour receptio...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Nefele
 

Renovated in 2006, this beach hotel offers a warm, welcoming and comfortable ambiance with a perfect merging of the antique and the modern. It comprises a total of 17 rooms including 1 studio and 1 ju...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Hilton Giardini Naxos
 

Set in a timeless oasis, this charming beach hotel is an elegant stage by the sea, an extraordinary amphitheatre showing guests the ancient and eternal Sicilian landscapes. Suggestive lights emphasise...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Sabbie D&apos;Oro
 

This hotel is a charming property that offers friendly service and lovely sea views. The hotel interiors are decorated in blue and white, reflecting the Mediterranean setting. In addition to the 39 gu...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Atahotel Capotaormina
 

This delightful villa has gorgeous views over the clear, indigo Ionian Sea to the Isola Bella, one of the most exclusive islands in the area. It offers 5 double bedrooms and the furnishings are extrem...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Bristol Park (Superior)
 

Location

The Bristol Park is located in one of the most exciting part of Taormina, close to all the major attractions and the famous Greek Theatre.

 Click pin on map for more info 
Continental
 

This is a recommended hotel ideally located in the city centre. DC 07/08

 Click pin on map for more info 
Bristol Park
 

This is an attractive property in a prime location in Taormina . It boasts a large outdoor swimming pool and a unique panoramic location! DC 02/09

 Click pin on map for more info 
Kennedy
 

Location

This hotel is located in Sant&apos;Alessio, 10 km north of Taormina on the picturesque Ionian Coast, and at the centre of the historic Valle d&apos;Agro&apos;. The warm, family-run hotel boasts commandin

 Click pin on map for more info 
Monte Tauro
 

The hotel, which maintains the atmosphere and the architecture of the original building, offers 100 rooms decorated with quality materials and fine elgance. All rooms are provided with modern commodit...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Andromaco Palace
 

The hospitality and impeccable service make a holiday at this hotel a pleasant and relaxing experience. The hotel is run by a family, and visitors are treated like personal guests. The family will als...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Baia Delle Sirene
 

Baia delle Sirene offers 22 luminous charming rooms with all the amenities and facilities associated to a hotel of its category.

 Click pin on map for more info 
Lido Mediterrane
 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Kristina
 

Villa Kristina was created in the early 60s through the inspiration of the owner, it stands in the hilly district of Taormina, just 3 minutes from Corso Umberto, the famous pedestrian precinct of the...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Ariston and Palazzo S.Caterina
 

Hotel Ariston and Palazzo Santa Caterina is located at the bottom of the ancient Greek Theatre of Taormina, amidst a century-old park with stunning views over the Mediterranean sea. Over the last year...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Naxos Beach Resort
 

The Beach Resort has 189 rooms and 453 cottages, which are harmoniously placed in lush vegetation. The establishment has 4 swimming pools, tennis courts, bars, restaurants and a private parking lot. T...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Athena
 

The hotel offers guests comfort and a range of facilities. Comprising a total of 31 guest rooms, the hotel features a lobby with 24-hour reception and check-out service, a hotel safe, lift access, a T...

 Click pin on map for more info 
La Riva
 

The hotel is a charming family-run establishment in an ideal setting for those who enjoy combining a relaxing sun and sand holiday with a bit of history and culture. It has 40 comfortable, traditional...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Villa Belvedere
 

This hotel is housed in a 5-storey villa built in 1902 with a large Mediterranean garden on various levels.

 Click pin on map for more info 
La Terra Dei Sogni
 

The hotel boasts views of the Gulf of Taormina and the Etna as well as being located near lemon and orange fields. Guests enjoy a traditional Sicilian cuisine using quality products. The hotel is full...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Corallo
 

In a peaceful environment, the Corallo Hotel has 36 rooms, a swimming pool and a restaurant, with panoramic views of the sea.

 Click pin on map for more info 
Solemar
 

This comfortable complex with sea views features 28 rooms with ensuite bathroom equipped with air conditioning, heating, satellite TV, telephone, safe and hairdryer. Facilities include a bar, restaura...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Etna Golf Resort
 

This charming golf hotel and spa complex is ideal for business travellers and holidaymakers alike and comprises a total of 98 rooms. It features an 18-hole golf course, surrounded by nature and its lo...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Lido Mediterranee
 

The property features 144 beds in 72 rooms. The restaurant is situated on the terrace, overlooking the beach. It serves Italian, Sicilian and international cuisine. Guests may also enjoy a drink in th...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Caesar Palace
 

The hotel offers attentive, efficient service. The complex has its own restaurant with buffet service, a grill and pizzeria by the swimming pool (open in summertime) and an à la carte gourmet restaura...

 Click pin on map for more info 
B&amp;B;I Mastrazzi Holiday In Sicily Taormina-Etna
 

The building itself was once a residence for local fishermen but has been delightfully renovated to provide 3 comfortable rooms. After a comfortable night&apos;s sleep in one of the guest rooms, the owners...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Innpiero Hotel
 

The Hotel Innpiero is located at the entrance of the main street in the town centre of Taormina, and offers a delightful base from which to explore all this area has to offer. Just a few metres from t...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Corallo Hotel
 

Superbly located in Taormina mare, facing the sea, the 4 star hotel Corallo is the perfect solution for spending quality time, in search of sea, art and culture. All rooms are elegantly decorated with...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Baia Di Naxos
 

The aparthotel is in ground floor of a building. It offers self-catering accommodation with air conditioning. The suites and studios have private entrances and en-suite facilities. Each has a kitchene...

 Click pin on map for more info 
Calipso
 

The hotel offers personalized service, relaxed atmosphere, rich and typical Sicilian breakfast, always with fresh food and a swimming pool with jacuzzi. Parking, Wi-fi and an Internet point available ...

 Click pin on map for more info 
The Ashbee
 

The house was built in the 1908&apos;s by Architect Charles Robert Ashbee, English designer and entrepreneur, prime mover of the Arts&amp;Craft movement. The new charming house offers some of the finest acco...

 Click pin on map for more info 
La Plage
 

General

La Plage Resort is located in Taormina, a small coastal town on the east coast of the island of Sicily, Italy, in the Province of Messina, about midway between Messina and Catania. The resor

 Click pin on map for more info 
Hotel Residence Circe
 

Location

Located in the heart of Taormina, in the pedestrian area, the Residence Circe is not far from the Greek-Romano.La Circe&apos;s central location, surrounded by some of the most famous shops and r

 Click pin on map for more info 
Nh Capo Dei Greci
 

General

The NH Capo dei Greci is a premiere resort and spa overlooking the majestic Taormina Bay. Each turn reveals dazzling waters and blue skies as far as the eye can see. All of our 200 guest roo

 Click pin on map for more info 
La Terra Dei Sogni Hotel&amp;Farm House
 Click pin on map for more info 
Hotel Isola Bella
 Click pin on map for more info 
Continental
 Click pin on map for more info 
Thysandros
 Click pin on map for more info 
Holidays to Taormina

Taormina is the kind of place that can take your breath away when you first see it. The snow capped Mount Etna acts as a dramatic backdrop to a town that has two stunning bays that joins it with the crystal clear Mediterranean Sea. Reachable within approximately three hours travelling from the UK, Sicily is home to the amazing Taormina where you can enjoy a peaceful Mediterranean holiday with your loved ones.

Things To Do in Taormina

The mix of Greek and Roman monuments in Taormina offer a fantastic collection of things to see. The ancient theatre is a bit of a puzzle to locals as no one is quite sure whether it was built by Greeks or Romans, meanwhile the medieval mansion of Palazzo Ciampoli has all sorts of influences that can be spotted amongst its architecture. Activities aren’t hard to come by on holiday in Taormina either, the Piccioli Golf Club is renowned and only half an hour away and the beaches offer water sports from snorkeling to sailing.



The beaches you’ll find on a Taormina holiday can be separated into two sets. Pebble beaches can be reached by cable car with coves and pools just waiting to be explored. Further south you’ll find long stretches of sand and calmer seas, ideal for sunbathing and swimming. These beaches are obviously much busier in the summer but if you can grab yourself a spot, it’s well worth it.



Those feeling particularly brave and adventurous during their holiday in Taormina can book a day trip to hike up the slopes of Mount Etna and see the viscous volcano up close. If you’d rather keep your feet on the ground then pay a visit to nearby Messina with its amazing reconstructed Norman cathedral and interesting streets to explore.



During your holiday in Taormina you’ll struggle to find a fast-food restaurant, Sicilians are not fans of the stuff so instead they encourage everyone to try their delicious, local food. Serving both Italian and Mediterranean food, even the fussiest eaters will find something they love in the authentic pizzerias and sea food restaurants.



The locals spend their evenings in Taormina with a very Mediterranean laid back attitude. So just grab a book and a glass of fantastic wine and just sit back, relax and soak up the atmosphere, let the drink keep flowing and the piano keep playing.

Enjoy holidays in Taormina easyJet Holidays

A chilled out, Mediterranean holiday in Taormina is fantastic value and simple to organise with easyJet Holidays. Simply choose a deal that can be tailored to suit you and book the flight and hotel together to save even more money.
 
Please wait whilst we retrieve the latest information on your destination
 Tweet 
Search for a Taormina holiday
 Click here for more search options From Please select All London All Scotland Belfast Intl Bristol Edinburgh Glasgow Intl Liverpool John Lennon London Gatwick London Luton London Stansted Manchester ------------------------------------------------------ All North All South West Aberdeen Belfast City Birmingham Intl Bournemouth Intl Inverness Isle of Man Jersey Leeds Bradford London Southend Newcastle To Please select Algarve Benidorm Corfu Costa Blanca Costa Brava Costa Del Sol Crete Cyprus Egypt Fuerteventura Ibiza Lanzarote Madeira Majorca Malta Sharm El Sheikh Tenerife Turkey Bodrum Area Turkey Dalaman Area Amsterdam Barcelona Berlin Budapest Copenhagen Krakow Lisbon London Central Madrid Marrakech Milan Monaco Munich Nice Paris Prague Rome Venice Austrian Alps French Alps Italian Alps Lake Como Lake Garda Lake Maggiore Slovenian Alps Slovenian Lakes Swiss Alps Andorra Ski Austrian Alps Bulgaria Ski French Alps Italian Alps Italian Dolomites Swiss Alps Andorra la Vella Andorra Ski Canilo Encamp Escaldes Engordany Austrian Alps Carinthia Innsbruck Salzburg Vienna Antwerp Bruges Brussels Ghent Bulgaria Bulgaria Ski Corsica North Corsica South Dalmatian Coast Split Zagreb Cyprus Prague Copenhagen Egypt Tallinn French Alps French Riviera Languedoc Roussillon Northern France Paris Rhone Alpes South West and Pyrenees Bavaria Berlin Bremen Cologne Dortmund Dusseldorf Hamburg Munich North Rhine Westerphalia Schleswig Holstein Gibraltar Athens Corfu Crete Halkidiki Kefalonia Kos Mykonos Rhodes Santorini Thessaloniki Zante Budapest Reykjavik Jerusalem Tel Aviv Abruzzo Campania Emilia Romagna Florence Friuli Venesia Giulia Italian Alps Italian Dolomites Lake Como Lake Garda Lake Maggiore Lazio Liguria Lombardy Marche Milan Neapolitan Riviera Pisa Puglia Rome Sardinia Sicily Trentino Alto Adige Turin Tuscany Umbria Venetian Riviera Veneto Venice Verona Jordan Luxembourg Madeira Malta Monaco Morocco Amsterdam Maastricht Rotterdam The Hague Utrecht Krakow Algarve Lisbon Lisbon Coast Porto Slovakia Ljubljana Slovenian Alps Asturias Barcelona Bilbao Cantabria Costa Blanca Costa Brava Costa Calida Costa De Almeria Costa De La Luz Costa Del Sol Costa Dorada Costa Tropical Formentera Fuerteventura Gran Canaria Granada Ibiza Lanzarote Madrid Majorca Menorca Navaria San Sebastian Seville Tenerife Toledo Valencia Basel Bern Geneva Montreux Swiss Alps Zurich Turkey Antalya Area Turkey Bodrum Area Turkey Dalaman Area Turkey Istanbul Area Bedfordshire Berkshire Buckinghamshire Cambridgeshire Channel Islands Cheshire City of Bristol Derbyshire Dorset East Sussex Essex Gloucestershire Greater Manchester Hampshire Isle of Man Kent Lancashire Leicestershire London Central London Outer Merseyside Northamptonshire Northern Ireland Nottinghamshire Oxfordshire Scotland Shropshire Somerset Suffolk Tyne and Wear UK Airports Wales Warwickshire West Midlands Wiltshire Worcestershire Yorkshire To Resort Please select Agrigento Catania Cefalu Giardini Naxos Letojanni Marina Di Butera Marsala Mazara del Vallo Messina Noto Palermo Portorosa Ragusa Siracusa Taormina or select destination from a list Check-In date Jul &apos;12 Aug &apos;12 Sep &apos;12 Oct &apos;12 Nov &apos;12 Dec &apos;12 Jan &apos;13 Feb &apos;13 Mar &apos;13 1 (Sun) 2 (Mon) 3 (Tue) 4 (Wed) 5 (Thu) 6 (Fri) 7 (Sat) 8 (Sun) 9 (Mon) 10 (Tue) 11 (Wed) 12 (Thu) 13 (Fri) 14 (Sat) 15 (Sun) 16 (Mon) 17 (Tue) 18 (Wed) 19 (Thu) 20 (Fri) 21 (Sat) 22 (Sun) 23 (Mon) 24 (Tue) 25 (Wed) 26 (Thu) 27 (Fri) 28 (Sat) 29 (Sun) 30 (Mon) 31 (Tue) Show Calendar Duration 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 Rating Any Rating 2 Star + 3 Star + 4 Star + 5 Star Board All All Inclusive Bed&amp;Breakfast Full Board Half Board Room Only Self Catering Rooms 1 2 3 
   Adults Kids (2-18) Infants (0-1) Guests 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Kids Ages 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 Room 2 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Kids Ages 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 Room 3 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0 1 2 3 4 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Kids Ages 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 
 for special assistance call 0843 104 1000 
Travel Guides
 Italy Sicily Agrigento Catania Cefalu Giardini Naxos Letojanni Marina Di Butera Marsala Mazara del Vallo Messina Noto Palermo Portorosa Ragusa Siracusa 
Hotels in Taormina
 2 Star Hotels Taormina 3 Star Hotels Taormina 4 Star Hotels Taormina 5 Star Hotels Taormina Taormina Hotels 
City Breaks
 Barcelona City Breaks Rome City Breaks Paris Breaks Amsterdam Breaks Prague City Breaks Milan City Breaks Berlin City Breaks Madrid Breaks 
Holidays
 Spain Holidays Egypt Holidays Greece Holidays Turkey Holidays Portugal Holidays Holiday Blog All Inclusive Holidays Ski Holidays 
easyJet Holidays
 Sitemap Terms of use Contact us Help About Us Privacy Affiliates Booking Conditions 
About easyJet
 Company Information Investors Media Sustainability Follow easyJet on: Facebook Follow easyJet Holidays on: Twitter
	</body>
</document>
