<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004038" url="http://www.bizrate.com/living-room-furniture/counter-height-swivel-chair/" time="2012-07-12-20:15" support="3" score="0.0047206249745774895" bingtitle="Counter height swivel chair in Living Room Furniture - Compare ..." webtitle="Counter height swivel chair in Living Room Furniture - Compare Prices, Read Reviews and Buy at Bizrate.">
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>Katelyn Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Wholesale ... tough enough to withstand rough use in a fast-food restaurant ... Swivel Chairs at JCPenney - Shop Selection of Swivel ...</description>
	<body>
		follow us:

 
 
 
 Suggestions 

 
 shop by categories     
 Appliances Automotive Babies&amp;Kids Books&amp;Magazines Clothing&amp;Accessories 
 
 Computers&amp;Software DVDs&amp;Videos Digital Cameras Electronics Furniture 
 
 Gifts, Flowers&amp;Food Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Jewelry&amp;Watches Laptop Computers 
 
 Music Musical Instruments Office Supplies Pet Supplies Sports Equipment 
 
 Toys&amp;Games Video Games Women&apos;s Shoes see all categories 
 
 Set Price Alert We&apos;ll send you an email when we find a lower price on: Today&apos;s Best Price:  Notify me when the price drops to: $   
Your email is safe - Privacy 
 Yes, I&apos;d like to be notified of other relevant products and savings. Home ›  Home&amp;Garden 
›  Furniture ›  Living Room Furniture › counter height swivel chair 
 
You&apos;re in Living Room Furniture
 
See Matches in:

 NCAA Shop Office Chairs Dining Room Furniture Patio Furniture 
 
Narrow Search Results
 
Price Range
 
 Under
$240 

 $240
-
$460 

 $460
-
$700 

 $700
-
$1,000 

 Over
$1,000 
 
 $ to $ Update&gt;&gt; 
 
By Seller

 Amazon Marketplace Buy.com DTYdirect.com DynamicHomeDecor.com eBay HomeandLiving.com OutdoorLivingShowroom 
 
By Product Type

 Arm Chairs&amp;Recliners 
 
By Table Shape

 Square 
 
By Keyword

 
 
 Sort: Best Match Price Low-High Price High-Low Product Rating Show: Free Shipping Sales Tax&amp;Shipping: 
 
 
 Bayshore Collection Swivel Counter Height Chair By Homelegance Furniture 

 Transitional aesthetic meets modern lines in the casually elegant Bayshore Collection. The 47œinch fixed oak veneer square tabletop features quartered book-match walnut inlay veneers and a heavily burnished finish. Supporting the unique t... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 modern counter height chairs 36 x 54 counter height table 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $154.35 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Bayshore Collection Swivel Counter Height Chair By Homelegance Furniture 

 Transitional aesthetic meets modern lines in the casually elegant Bayshore Collection. The 47 inch fixed oak veneer square tabletop features quartered book-match walnut inlay veneers and a heavily burnished finish. Supporting the unique tab... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Buy.com 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Buy.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Buy.com 
 (1,000,000+) 
 $154.35 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Black Drafting Counter Height Stool Chair | Art Bank Swivel Adjustable Tall 

 Retail Value = $159.99 Black Drafting Height Chair The Lafayette D rafting Height Chair offers both a spacious seat and back with a pneumatic height control mechanism in order to easily adjust to accommodate the needs of each and every user... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From eBay 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From eBay With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 eBay 
 (500+) 
 $78.48 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Director&apos;s Chair : Black Natural Frame Counter - Height Director&apos;s Chair 
 Free Shipping 
 Find furniture standalone seating at Target.com! Black natural frame counter-height director&apos;s chair 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 ero s chair delaney chair black faux leather 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $68.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Katelyn Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Wholesale Interiors 

 Katelyn Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Wholesale Interiors For a casual yet stylish breakfast nook or informal dining room, the Katelyn Pub Stool is a worthy contender. Design highlights include a windowpane backrest, beige fabric seat, a... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From www.hightechseating.com 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail By Wholesale Interiors From www.hightechseating.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 www.hightechseating.com 
 
 $215.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Chapman Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Coaster Fine Furniture 

 Chapman Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Coaster Fine Furniture This counter height stool with an updated craftsman style and a comfortable cushioned seat is ideal for seating at the coordinating table or a counter in your home. The rustic ... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From MadisonSeating 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail By Coaster From MadisonSeating With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 coaster chair covers 
 
 
 
 $209.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Largo Turks Isle 5 Piece Counter Height Dining Set 

 Hand crafted rattan used in the construction of Turks Isle is as durable as it is attractive. The woven accents on the chair crests and table base give each piece unique detailing and character. Brown and black highlights in the finish are ... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Furniture Crate 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Furniture Crate With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Furniture Crate 
 
 $2,069.00 $1,099.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Katelyn Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Wholesale Interiors 

 Katelyn Counter Height Chair Set of 2 by Wholesale Interiors For a casual yet stylish breakfast nook or informal dining room, the Katelyn Pub Stool is a worthy contender. Design highlights include a windowpane backrest, beige fabric seat, a... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From MadisonSeating 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail By Wholesale Interiors From MadisonSeating With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $199.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Reagan 5-Pc Counter Height Dining Set by Coaster 

 Take your dining to new heights with this counter height dining table group. Casual pub style gets a slight makeover in this table and chair set, from sleek black upholstery featured on the seats to a dark brown oak finish that wraps each p... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From MadisonSeating 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From MadisonSeating With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $414.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Set Of 2 JERSEY SEATING Black ABS Bar Stools Counter Swivel Chair Modern Style 

 Classy comfortable design. Durable an Solid ABS Other colors available Heavy duty hydraulic strut for adjustable height Base, Pole, and Foot rest are chrome polished. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 leather swivel chair streeter swivel chair 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $69.00 
 

 
 Set Of 2 JERSEY SEATING Red Leather Bar Stool Counter Swivel Chair 

 Classy comfortable design. Durable synthetic leather. Hi-back for added comfort and support. Heavy duty hydraulic strut. Height is adjustable. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 bar stool slipcovers 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $89.00 
 

 
 Liberty Crystal Lakes 24 Inch Swivel Counter Chair Set of 2 

 Nylon Chair GlidesGenerously Padded Upholstered SeatsSwivel Seat 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Furniture Crate 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Furniture Crate With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Furniture Crate 
 
 $719.00 $482.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 2 Madrid Counter Height Stools ( Chairs ) Dining (24&quot;Seat Height ) 

 Great addition to your dining room, around the island in your kitchen, or even your game room. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $150.88 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Coaster Reagan 5 Piece Counter Height Dining Set in Brown Oak Finish 

 Coaster - Dining Sets - 150086 - Take your dining to new heights with this counter height dining table group. Casual pub style gets a slight makeover in this table and chair set, from sleek black upholstery featured on the seats to a dark b... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Cymax 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Cymax With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 home theater seating set in burnished oak finish 
 
 Cymax 
 
 $712.86 $482.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Steve Silver Mango Counter Chair in Light Oak 

 Steve Silver Company - Dining Chairs - GO900CCK - A modern classic, the Mango Counter Height Chair (Light Oak) yields functional design and solid wood construction. Defined as casually elegant, the light oak finish and durable chocolate vin... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Cymax 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Cymax With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 chair in half recliner power oversized recliner chair in 
 
 Cymax 
 
 $175.00 $122.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Jofran Counter Height Fabric Bench in Saddle Brown Oak Finish 

 Jofran - Dining Chairs - 477BS49KD - Solid Asian Harwood construction Finished in Saddle Brown Oak Overall dimensions: 43&quot;&quot;W x 21&quot;&quot;D x 41&quot;&quot;H 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Cymax 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Cymax With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Cymax 
 
 $369.62 $275.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Liberty Low Country 5 Piece Counter Height Dining Set in Sand 

 Includes One 18&apos;&apos; Butterfly LeafTurned LegsNylon Chair GlidesSaddle Shaped Seating 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Furniture Crate 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Furniture Crate With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Furniture Crate 
 
 $1,249.00 $836.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Liberty Low Country 5 Piece Counter Height Dining Set in Black 

 Includes One 18&apos;&apos; Butterfly LeafTurned LegsNylon Chair GlidesSaddle Shaped Seating 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Furniture Crate 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Furniture Crate With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Furniture Crate 
 
 $1,249.00 $836.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Counter Height Metal Swivel Stool: White Bonded 

 Create a contemporary atmosphere with this chic and sleek counter stool from Diamond Sofa Crafted for aesthetic pleasure this stool also provides comfortable swivel seating for a great addition to your kitchen island or rec room it is sure ... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 ottoman metal swivel base 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $238.76 

FREE shipping
 

 
 24&quot;H Swivel Counter Height Stool Vintage Oak Finish 

 Dimension: 24&quot;Seat Height Finish: Vintage Oak Material: Wood, Leatherette 24&quot;H Swivel Counter Height Stool Vintage Oak Finish Item features black leatherette cushion seat. Assembly required. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail By Acme Furniture From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $50.64 
 

 
 Santiago Swivel Counter Stool 

 Hillsdale Furniture evokes the beauty of the islands with this Santiago counter stool. Featuring a rattan back, this counter-height stool adds a touch of the tropics to your decor. Complement your dining counter with this Hillsdale Furnitur... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Kohl&apos;s 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Kohl&apos;s With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $369.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 5pc Dark Artificial Marble Top Counter Height Dinette Dinning Set (Table&amp;4 Chairs ) 

 s 5-piece package includes the Table and 4 Chairs, The table features a contemporary marble-look veneer table top, 40&quot;L X 40&quot;W x 36&quot;H, Black Blended-Leather Chair w/ button, 19&quot;W X 22.25&quot;D X 41&quot;H, seat hight 24&quot;Black blended Leather, durab... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 marble top table antique marble top end tables 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $299.99 
 

 
 Home Elegance 710-24W Daisy Counter Height Chair in White Leatherette- Pack of 2 

 Daisy Dining Collection by Homelegance combines superb visual appearance and fine quality that you need in your dining area. The round counter height dining table features and elegant tulip base and beveled glass top to provide an open airy... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $258.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 5pc White Artificial Marble Top Counter Height Dinette Dinning Set (Table&amp;4 Chairs ) 

 5-piece package includes the Table and 4 Chairs; The table features a white contemporary marble-look veneer table top, 42&quot;L X 42&quot;W x 36&quot;H; Stool features black blended Leather, durable, easy clean, sophisticated look and feel, excellent sun... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $339.99 
 

 
 Lemans Swivel Counter Stool 

 This Lemans swivel counter stool looks good from any angle. Its classic frame and padded seat create a chair that&apos;s both stylish and comfortable. Shop Hillsdale Furniture at Kohls to complete your room. In brown. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Kohl&apos;s 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Kohl&apos;s With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $369.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Telescope 24 Inch World Famous Heavyweave Mesh Counter Height Director Chair 

  The deluxe Telescope 24 in. World Famous Heavyweave Mesh Director Chair is a pleasing alternative to the protected outdoor sling chair. The heavyweave mesh cover resists fading when placed in a protected outdoor setting and lasts much lon... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Hayneedle 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Hayneedle With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Hayneedle 
 
 $179.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 5 Pc Counter Height Table and 4 Stools Set 

 Counter height dinette set in espresso finish; Solid wood table and chair, chairs feature vinyl padded seats; Table 39&quot;x39&quot;x36&quot;H Stools 18.5&quot;x20&quot;x39&quot;H some assembly required 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $299.99 
 

 
 Poundex Sophia Swivel Barstool with 24-Inch Height or 29-Inch Height Adjustable Height , Set of 2 

 The &apos;&apos;Nora&apos;&apos; barstool collection features a selection of two contemporary styled chairs with round upholstered seat cushions in a light color framed in a dark metal finish with bold lines covering the chair supports. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 adjustable height lcd tv stand coffee table adjustable height 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $53.50 
 

 
 Pamplona Swivel Counter Stool 

 This Pamplona swivel counter stool is truly timeless. Its simple frame and padded seat create a chair that&apos;s both classy and comfy. Shop Hillsdale Furniture at Kohls for a look you&apos;ll love. In dark brown. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Kohl&apos;s 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Kohl&apos;s With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $379.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Espresso Finish Wood 24&quot;H Swivel Bar Stool Counter Chair 

 Espresso Finish Wood 24&quot;H Swivel Bar Stool Counter Chair This is a brand new espresso finish wood swivel bar stools. This item will make a great addition to any kitchen, bar, or dining room setting. The seat swivels as an added functionalit... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Living Room Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $51.50 
 
 show 30 60 90 120 items 
 1 2 3 4 5 next 
 
Stores Selling counter height swivel chair
  (Sponsored Links) 
 Tall Counter Stool - Save up to 80% + Free Shipping Great Selection&amp;All Made in USA! www.mybarstooldirect.com/TallStools 

 Counter Height Chairs Shop Counter Height Chairs . Free Shipping on Orders Over $50. www.jcpenney.com/ CounterHeightChairs Living Room Furniture - Bedroom Furniture - Kitchen&amp;Dining Furniture - Kids&amp;Teen Furniture 

 Crate&amp;Barrel Furniture - Up to 50% off Summer Sale. Quantities are Limited. Shop Now! www.crateandbarrel.com/ Bar Stools - Bar Carts - Bar Cabinets - Wine Cabinets 

 #1 Bar Chairs Swivel Compare The Best Bar Chairs Swivel . Research Solutions 4 Your Business! restaurantfurnishings.business.com/ 

 Bar Chairs Need Advice On Bar Chairs ? Let Our Home Pros Help, Ask Now! www.housecentral.com/ 

 Counter Height - Swivel Chairs Info. Access 10 Search Engines At Once. www.info.com/ CounterHeightSwivelChairs 

 Counter height chair - Save Up to 70% Plus Free Shipping Great Selection of Brands&amp;Styles. www.barstoolsupercenter.com/ 
 
More information about
 counter height swivel chair
 Best prices on Counter height swivel chair in Living Room Furniture online. Visit Bizrate to find the best deals on Living Room Furniture from . See which Home&amp;Garden stores have the Living Room Furniture that you want. Read reviews on Home&amp;Garden merchants and buy with confidence. Your Price Alert has been set! Set a price alert to be notified when the price drops. 
 Product Details for HP Pavillion DV6-6C10US 15 Inch 640GB Hard Drive Laptop PC - Steel Gray... 
 
$500.00

Today&apos;s Best Price
 
$499.00

Price I want to beat
 
Notifications will be sent to: CharlesJohnson@jfamstudios.com 

 Manage My Price Alerts 
 
$
 
Notify me when the price drops to or below
 
Your email is safe - Privacy Policy 
 

 Send me other relevant products and savings. 
 
 
 
 Show Recently Viewed Products 

 Hide 
 
Recently Viewed Products
 
 Share Page: 
 
 Hide 
 See the 2011 Circle of Excellence Winners! 

 Follow us: 
 
 Bizrate Sitemap Index Bizrate Store Ratings See All Categories 
©Shopzilla 2012
 
 
save money win money 

Sign up for our emails to save cash.

PLUS a chance to win our Daily Cash Giveaway! 
 
We won&apos;t share your email with anyone. Official Rules 
 

 
Muze for Music: Copyright 1984-2010 Muze Inc. For personal non-commercial use only. All rights reserved.
 
Stores are responsible for providing Bizrate with correct and current prices. Sales taxes and shipping costs are estimates; please check store for exact amounts. Product specifications are obtained from merchants or third parties. Although we make every effort to present accurate information, Bizrate is not responsible for inaccuracies. We encourage you to notify us of any discrepancies by clicking here .

Store ratings and product reviews are submitted by online shoppers; they do not reflect our opinions and we have no responsibility for their content.
 
 Email Signup   Get the hottest deals, products and exclusive offers.
 
Your email is safe - Privacy | Contest Rules 
 
 Congrats!   You&apos;re Bizrate&apos;s newest email subscriber.

 Please check your inbox to complete your signup (and enter sweepstakes).
 X
	</body>
</document>
