<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004464" url="http://www.lvlg.com/lasvegas/attracts/parks.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:53" support="4" score="0.016307349047972174" bingtitle="Nevada State and National Parks in the Las Vegas Surrounding Areas" webtitle="Nevada State and National Parks in the Las Vegas Surrounding Areas">
			<query id="000712" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>It&apos;s also fun to open the car windows and turn off the air conditioning as you turn off route 95 to ... BEFORE you head into the park &quot;loop&quot;, as once you get into the park ...</description>
	<body>
		Visit The Las Vegas Leisure Guide Home Page For More Las Vegas Information 
Parks&amp;Recreation Areas

Trips of a Day or Less
 Visit BEYOND THE NEON For Overnight Trips 
 Visit The VEGAS DAY TRIP ADVISOR For Do-It-Yourself Advice&amp;Suggestions 
 
 Ash Meadows National Wildlife Refuge 
 Beaver Dam State Park 
 Big Bend Of The Colorado Rec. Area 
 Bryce Canyon National Park 
 Cathedral Gorge State Park 
 Davis Dam 
 Death Valley National Monument 
 Echo Canyon State Park 
 Floyd Lamb State Park 
 Grand Canyon National Park 
 Hoover Dam 
 Kershaw-Ryan State Park 
 Kyle Ranch 
 Lake Havasu / London Bridge 
 
 
                                 Advertise In This
Box 
 
 
 Lake Mead National Recreation Area 
 Mt Charleston / Toiyabe Ntnl Forest 
 Old Las Vegas Mormon Fort Historic Park 
 Pahranagat National Wildlife Refuge 
 Parker Dam 
 Red Rock Canyon 
 Snow Canyon State Park 
 Southern NV Zoological-Botanical Park 
 Spring Mountain Ranch State Park 
 Spring Valley State Park 
 Valley of Fire State Park 
 Zion Canyon Giant Screen Theatre 
 Zion National Park 
 MORE DISTANT TRIPS 
 Custom Search 
 
 Related Topics:  Tours - Maps - Recreation - Vehicle Rental - Shows - Events 
 Trip Length Codes: (Starting From Las Vegas) 
 = 1/2 Day  = 1 Day  = Overnight  = 2+ Days 

 Trip time estimates given assume travel from and return to Las Vegas with
ample time to explore and learn about the beauty of Nevada and the surrounding areas. 
 
 Ash Meadows National Wildlife Refuge - A natural oasis in the
Desert. Located about 90 miles northwest of Las Vegas in Amargosa Valley,
it consists of over 22,000 acres of spring-fed wetlands and alkaline desert
uplands. Here can be found more than 20 plants and animals found nowhere else
in the world, including a few on the endangered list. Here can be seen
environmental extremes from Sand dunes, to ash tree groves, to wetlands all
in one desert environment. Open sunrise-sunset. Refuge Manager: (775) 372-5435

 Beaver Dam State Park - One of the most rustic parks in
Nevada, Beaver Dam State Park has deep canyon, forests of juniper and pinion pine, a beautiful flowing
stream and a reservoir. This is a perfect spot for photography or nature study. Or you can try fishing,
camping, picnicking and hiking. Boats are not recommended on the reservoir. Campgrounds,
group use areas, picnic areas, interpretive trails are available. Weather permitting, the park is
open all year. It is not recommended to travel during the winter months due to the 5000 foot
elevation off a gravel road. Located 34 miles east of Caliente, 6 miles north on US Hwy 93, then
28 miles east on a graded road. For more information contact: Beaver Dam State Park, Panaca
Region Headquarters, P.O.Box 176, Panaca, NV, 89042, (702) 728-4467

 Big Bend Of The Colorado State Recreation Area - This park starts below
Laughlin on the shores of the Colorado River. The views of the river and mountains is dramatic.
Currently, visitors enjoy picnicking, boating, fishing and swimming. Campgrounds and hiking
trails are under construction. Summer temperatures in this park can easily reach 120 degrees. 
Located 5 miles south of Laughlin on the Needles Hwy. For more information contact: Big Bend
Of The Colorado Recreation Area, P.O. Box 32850, Laughlin, NV, 89028-2850, (702)
298-1859.

 Bryce Canyon National Park - This spectacular park is one of the most scenic in America. Giant bright red hoo-doos rise from
the canyon floor and seem to touch the clouds. Explore the many cavernous trails leading
throughout the park. Or take a Park Ranger&apos;s hike and learn about the wildlife. Named after
rancher Ebenezer Bryce who said &quot;It&apos;s a hell of a place to lose a cow!&quot; you&apos;ll see why in this
wonderland of eroded rock formations ablaze in brilliant colors. Located 4 hours northeast from
Las Vegas in the heart of Utah&apos;s &quot;Color Country&quot;.

 Cathedral Gorge State Park - Cathedral spires of soft bentonite clay formed by
years of erosion give this gorge its name. Unique patterns and cave-like formations abound in
this long narrow valley. Trails take you on an exploration of the dramatic way nature&apos;s forces
have carved this gorge. Miller Point is a scenic overlook just north of the park&apos;s entrance. 
Shades campgrounds and picnic areas provide relief from the summer sun. Popular activities
in the park include hiking, nature study, photography and ranger programs. Located 2 miles
north of Panaca on US Hwy 93. For more information contact: Cathedral Gorge State Park, P.O.
Box 176, Panaca, NV, 89042, (702) 728-4460.

 Davis Dam 
 
 - About 90 miles further downstream from Hoover
Dam, just before you get to Laughlin, Nevada is Davis Dam. Completed in
1953 to control the frequent flooding on the Colorado river the dam made
possible the development and commercialization of Laughlin, NV and
Bullhead City, AZ. Self-guided tours have been discontinued at the present
time. For more information contact: Laughlin Visitors Bureau, PO Box
502, Laughlin, NV 89029, (800) 452-8445.


 Death Valley National Monument - Death Valley includes the lowest dry point below sea level in the Western
Hemisphere (280 feet), a museum, Scotty&apos;s Castle at the northern tip, and even
a couple of inns in case you decide to stay a while. Located about 140 miles
northwest of Las Vegas. Death Valley Visitors Center&amp;Museum: (619) 786-2331
 The following are links to tours in Death Valley 
 
 - 
Voted the all time best Photographic /
Sightseeing Tour tours in Las Vegas by Insider Viewpoint Magazine - (702) 889-8687 
 Free Kodak Gold 24 exp film with online booking
 
 
For more see our Tours Category .


 Echo Canyon State Park - This park offers beautiful scenery and a 65 acre
reservoir. Exploration of the native plants and unique rock formations is a popular activity. 
Wildlife is abundant for nature study. Camping, boating, fishing, hiking and picnicking are
available. The park is open all year but visitors can expect snow during the winter months due
to its 5200 foot elevation. Located 12 miles east of Pioche from Star Routes 322 and 323. For
more information contact: Echo Canyon State Park, Star Route, Box 295, Pioche, NV, (702)
962-5103.

 Floyd Lamb State Park -
This park was formerly known as Tule Springs. Its
history includes an early winter stopping point for Native Americans, and later a working ranch. 
In the 1950&apos;s it was popular as a guest ranch where, patrons could wait out the 6 week Nevada
residency requirement to get a quick divorce. Groves of shade trees surround 4 small fishing
lakes. A nice respite from the summer sun. Picnic areas have tables and grills. Group areas and
walking/bike paths are available. Located 10 miles north of Las Vegas from US Hwy 95 to
Durango to Tule Springs Road. Admission: approx $6 per person, fishing license required to fish.
For more information contact: Floyd Lamb State Park, 9200
Tule Springs Road, Las Vegas, NV, 89131, (702) 486-5413.

 Grand Canyon National Park - More than a mile deep, 217 miles long, and 4-18 miles wide, the Grand
Canyon is among the most popular camping and hiking destinations and
all around must-sees in the Southern Nevada area. Far at the very bottom
flows the Colorado River offering whitewater as well as calm rafting.
Check our Outdoors Recreation and Extreme Tours sections
for a selection of tour operators offering whitewater and camping adventures
at the Canyon.
Most visitors prefer to simply visit the upper rim and gaze at
the many natural formations and wide colorful vistas. Expect crowds in the
more popular public areas most seasons except mid-winter. It&apos;s somewhat of a
drive from Las Vegas being nearly 300 miles away by land to the nearest rim.
You can drive to the public sites yourself, but there are numerous, excellent,
affordable, bus, offroad vehicle, helicopter and airplane tours departing
Las Vegas every day, to make the visit more informative and overall far more
enjoyable, many of which even go to otherwise inaccessable areas by special arrangement.
Check below and in our tours section
for a large selection of tour operators offering literally hundreds of Grand Canyon
tour options for every imaginable taste, time, mode or budget constraint. Expect an
early morning until late evening or overnight trip if going by land. Sunrise and
sunset are quite spectacular at the Canyon. Many half and full day air tours,
both flying over only, as well as landing in or on the edge of the canyon, are
also available. Visit our Grand Canyon Detail Section. Grand Canyon Information Center: (520) 638-7888.
 The following are links to guided tours to the Grand Canyon 
 
 - The Ultimate Grand Canyon Adventure!
 - 1-800-653-1881 or (702) 597-5525 
 
 - 
Voted the all time best Photographic / Sightseeing Tour tours in Las Vegas by Insider Viewpoint Magazine - (702) 889-8687 
 Free Kodak Gold 24 exp film with online booking
 
 - Plane, bus, helo, train, hiking, rafting and off road tours of the Grand Canyon.
- Order on-line. 702-655-6060 or 888-512-0075
 Free airport transfers with online purchase of select tours!
 
 
 Save up to $50 per person on tours when you book online.
- 702-233-1627 or 1-888-609-5665
 
 
 

For more see also our Tours Category .
For some links to even more in-depth information about the grand canyon, try
one of these:
 Grand Canyon Explorer - hiking, lots of pictures, sponsored by the Grand Canyon Pioneers Society 
 Maps and History of the Grand Canyon 
 Official National Park Service Site - printable guide, hiking, online trip planner 

 Hoover Dam -
 Only 30 miles south of Las Vegas is one of mans greatest architectural
achievements and one of the most popular landmarks visited by Las Vegas visitors.
Still in operation since the 30&apos;s supplying electrical power to Nevada,
Arizona and California, Hoover Dam is truly a wonder to see. Visitors can
actually go into the depths of the dam and tour the inner workings. Or you
can peer over the edge of the nearly 800 foot drop while standing in two
time zones at once!
A nearby museum shows movies and artifacts involving it&apos;s creation.
The beautiful new Hoover Dam Visitors Center, at the edge of the dam, opened in
September 95 and ironically enough cost much more to build than the dam
itself did 60 years ago. Currently, you can watch engineering marvels in
progress, as efforts to reduce traffic over the dam itself are realized by
constructing an enormous bypass highway across the gorge about a half mile
from the dam.
Open 9:00am-4:15pm daily. Adm: $5 Adults, $2.50 Seniors&amp;Children 10-16, 
Children under 10 free; Includes tour of dam and movie. (702) 293-8367.
 The following are links to guided tours to Hoover Dam 
 
 
- The only riverboat cruise on Lake Mead
- (702) 293-6180
 
 - For Hoover Dam by helicopter.
 - 1-800-653-1881 or (702) 597-5525 
 
 - Voted the all time best Photographic /
Sightseeing Tour tours in Las Vegas by Insider Viewpoint Magazine - (702) 889-8687 
 Free Kodak Gold 24 exp film with online booking
 
 - Bus tours to Hoover Dam and optional Lake Mead cruise. Hotel to hotel service.
Order on-line. 702-655-6060 or 888-512-0075
 Free airport transfers with online purchase of select tours!
 
 
 Save up to $50 per person on tours when you book online.
- 702-233-1627 or 1-888-609-5665

 
 
 
For more see our Tours Category .
For more detailed visitor information about Hoover Dam and tours inside, including
a virtual interior tour with pictures, visit The Official Hoover Dam Home Page .

 Kershaw-Ryan State Park -
 A spring-fed pond in this park offered early settlers a
place to grow grapes, trees and even lawns. This is in sharp contrast to the rocky canyon walls
which tower over the little valley. Hiking trails, picnic areas and campgrounds offer a variety of
activities in this park. This park is at the north end of Rainbow Canyon. Located 3 miles south
of Caliente off US Hwy 93 to Star Route 317. For more information contact: Kershaw-Ryan
State Park, Panaca Region Headquarters, P.O. Box 176, Panaca, NV, 89042, (702)
728-4467.

 Kyle Ranch -
 Once part of a large ranch, what remains of it here
is acknowledged as the oldest standing building in Las Vegas. It is located,
just off Losee Road on the northeast corner of Carey Ave and Commerce Street
in North Las Vegas. The unassuming stone and wood ranch house and nearby white
shed date back to the mid 1850&apos;s when the entire valley was little more than a
railroad stop and ranching predominated rather than gambling. If you visit
the site, please respect all nearby areas marked &quot;private property&quot; and
&quot;no trespassing&quot;. No admission charge.

 Lake Havasu / London Bridge - Brought over stone by stone and reconstructed
in 1971, Lake Havasu&apos;s London Bridge forms the central focus of a modern 
&quot;Old English Village&quot; on the shore of the lake. Dozens of gift shops, antique shops
and cafes line the shore of this man-made lake north of Parker Dam. Boating,
fishing and many other water sports are available. This is also the well known
site of numerous televised water sports tournaments. Additional Info:
Call the Lake Havasu Tourist Bureau: 1-800-242-8278.

 Lake Mead National Recreation Area - Covering 300 square miles (and at least
one drowned city) Lake Mead is the largest man made lake in the United States. With nearly 600
miles of shoreline it&apos;s easy to find plenty of room to pursue your interest, whether it be boating,
fishing, swimming or ski-doo-ing. Only 35 miles southeast of Las Vegas. Nevada fishing
licenses are available at all local marinas, boating and bait shops. House and ski boat rentals are
plentiful (see
	</body>
</document>
