<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004321" url="http://mfpsolutions.blogspot.com/2011_02_01_archive.html" time="2012-07-12-20:34" support="8" score="0.00477519757696023" bingtitle="print4pay Hotel&apos;s &quot;MFP Solutions Blog&quot;: February 2011" webtitle="print4pay Hotel&apos;s &quot;MFP Solutions Blog&quot;: February 2011">
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000291" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000759" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000197" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001325" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>... created on a color copier in order to get a burger from Jack in the Box fast food restaurant. ...  Waste toner receptacle with yield of ... But how do you tell if you work for ...</description>
	<body>
		print4pay Hotel&apos;s &quot;MFP Solutions Blog&quot; 
 
 With over 3,500 worldwide followers that support copiers, multifunctional devices and printers, the information that comes across our message boards is enormous. The latest selling techniques, strategies, future products from the manufacturers and rumors are daily posts on the message boards. www.p4photel.org 
 
Pages
 
 Home About the P4P Hotel Experience Success! Premium Membership Benefits Industry Links Industry Forums Basic Membership Benefits Compare HP, Lexmark, and Ricoh Printers Advertise With Us! 
 
 Sunday, February 27, 2011 
 
 MFP Weekend Industry Notes for 2/27/2011 
 Special thanx to Print4Pay Hotel members and moles from across the globe for posting these updates on the P4P Hotel forums !

- Canon announced that it has finalized sale of its interest in a semiconductor plant in Singapore to Micron Technology of Boise, Idaho.
- Canon, Samsung and Hewlett Packard were all sued by Lodsys LLC in regards to alleged patent infringement over technology that exchanges info with customers via printers.

- Canon announced it will donate“one million dollars of in-kind printing services”from its LA branch to Operation HOPE. Curriculum will be printed by Canon and distributed by HOPE Corps to educate youth at no cost in area school districts, according to Canon’s VP of Zone Operations Eddie Saji.

- Marvell Technology (which makes print controller technology for companies like Xerox, etc.) was sued by Link A Media Devices Corp. over alleged patent infringement regarding hard drive technology.

- Zoran of California, which makes controllers for MFPs (i.e. Xerox, Canon, Ricoh, Sharp, etc.) as well as DVD players, Blu-Ray players, cable TV boxes and video games, announced it will be launching a product called“DirectOffice Mobile Print”.

o This new option for its print controllers will allow end users to print to their MFPs from smartphones and tablets via WiFi wireless technologies.

o Made in partnership with another print controller technology company, Software Imaging Inc. of England.

- Okidata is launching the pro905DP, which is a color desktop LED-based toner printer that is specially made for envelope printing. MSRP of $18,995 and includes an EFI Fiery.

- Hewlett Packard announced it has acquired Vertica Systems Inc. of Billerica, Massachusetts, which makes software that“helps business spot trends hidden in large amounts of data”. Purchase price not announced.

- Hewlett Packard announced that LG Electronics will relabel some of its printers in Asia. LG already relabels product from Lexmark.

- HP’s new CEO, Leo Apotheker, purchased a 6 bedroom home in Atherton, CA for $7 million.

- HP announced it won a 7 year, $281 million managed IT services contract from Oklahoma Healthcare Authority.

- Hewlett Packard announced HP Digital Health Solutions:

o Portfolio of products, solutions and partnerships

o holistically addresses the technology needs of care delivery

o expanded solution framework and formal reference architectures

o real-time information environment

o enable healthcare organizations to link to monitor health and deliver care to patients

o On display in the HP Health Solutions Center showroom in Plano, TX

- IKON, a division of Ricoh, announced it has filed suit against two former FM employees for supposedly violating a non-compete clause. The suit was filed against John Kolacinski and Robert Hornbeck, who now work for Myriad Litigation Solutions of California.

- Electronics For Imaging, maker of the Fiery print server, announced:

o It will buy back $30 million of its stock shares

o Has acquired Streamline Development, maker of PrintStream management information systems (MIS) software for printshop owners

- Kodak announced it sold a Prosper 5000XL production color inkjet system to Servinform, a printshop in Spain.

- Survey on proposed new leasing rules, by Deloitte:

o Only 7% of companies polled are ready for new rules, which would force companies to put leases on their books

o 80% say it will add burden to their financial reporting

o 40% said it will make it more difficult to obtain financing

o 40% believe it will force them into shorter term leases

o 35% don’t believe that their company’s lease data is accurate

o 25% believe it will require them to upgrade their existing IT systems

- Sharp announced it filed a lawsuit against a former Sharp branch copier sales rep in Phoenix, AZ. The lawsuit is aimed at Brenda Luettenegger, for allegedly violating a non-compete clause.

- According to one industry publication, the new Sharp copiers with the“Apple iPhone-like”touchscreen color LCDs, have been locking up in product demonstrations.

- The largest Sharp dealer in Canada, is Pitney Bowes, with a number of locations in the country. (while Pitney Bowes spun off it copier business in the U.S. as Imagistics, which is now part of Canon, it did not do so in Canada)

- Square 9 Softworks of New Haven, CT, maker of the SmartSearch document management software (DMS), announced that it now has panel integration option for both Xerox copiers (with EIP) and Sharp copiers (with OSA). It is also working on integration with Kodak desktop scanners

- OpenText of Waterloo, Ontario, Canada, (maker of RightFax, FaxPress, and document management software) announced it has completed its acquisition of Metastorm of Baltimore, Maryland, which makes business process management software, for $182 million.

- DocuLex, maker of document management software, announced that it has new feature allowing end users to pull email out of Microsoft Exchange 2010.

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/27/2011 08:14:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Canon , EFI , HP , Ikon , Kodak , Okidata , Pitney Bowes , Sharp Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Saturday, February 26, 2011 
 
 Can Color Copiers&amp;MFP Print Money? Well yes, however..... 
 I got nothing against a guy or gal trying to make a buck! But FOR THE LOVE OF GOD don&apos;t copy or print money on color copiers!!! The dumb asses below were all arrested for using fake bills!  

 To anyone that&apos;s thinking about, don&apos;t do it! There&apos;s a code that is printed on every sheet of paper that&apos;s not visible to you or me, however it is visible to the Feds, and they can track the serial number of the device and where it was sold!! 

Ronald Lindsey Bafile of Atlanta, Georgia, was arrested by police after trying to sell fake $20 and $50 bills he made on a color copier to undercover police. Apparently he was selling the fake money to pay for his addiction to marijuana and methamphetamine.


Anthony Paris, Kristy Guilds, Jeremy Rowe and Mitch McQuaid were all arrested in Oswego, New York, after trying to use fake $20 bills at a local McDonalds, that they made using a color copier.

Police arrested John Kenneth Martin of Diboll, Texas after they caught him trying to use fake $10 dollar bills he created on a color copier in order to get a burger from Jack in the Box fast food restaurant.


- Mark Allen Dearborn of Gilbert, Iowa was arrested by local police after he was caught with fake $20 bills that he made on a color copier, trying to make a purchase at a local Walmart.


- Lorree Ann Capps of Anderson, South Carolina was sentenced to 30 months in prison for making fake $20 bills using a color copier.


- Janelle Newsome and Richard Gladfelter were arrested for allegedly creating fake $10 and $20 bills using a color copier in South Charleston, WV.


-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/26/2011 11:26:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Color Copiers , copier crimes , MFP Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 TASKalfa 255C and TASKalfa 205C &quot;Spec Review&quot; 
 Kyocera (aka Kyota Ceramic Company) launched two new A3 color laser MFPs, called the TASKalfa 255C and TASKalfa 205C featuring:


o Are part of“SMARTtech”series or“Simple Management and Replacement Technology”

Claims that a PM can be performed in under 10 minutes due to cartridge based, tool-free design

PM cycle is 300,000

o advertised as offering benefits of A3 paper size, at the price of competitive A4 units

o Base MSRPs of $8259 and $7149

o Top speeds of 25ppm and 20ppm respectively

o Max duty cycles of 40K/month

o Very small 4.3”color LCD touchscreen

o Amorphous silicon (ASi ceramic) drum with expected life of 200,000 pages

o Black toner yield of 12,000 pages based on 5% coverage per page

Color toners yield 6,000 page each

Waste toner receptacle with yield of 7,500 pages (unit apparently does NOT recycle toner)

o 45 second warmup time, 13.6 second first copy out time

o 600x600dpi actual print resolution

o Auto duplex standard

o Maximum paper supply of 1,600 sheets

Comes standard with 550 sheet drawer and 50 sheet bypass

Drawers hold up to 64gsm

Max paper size of 11”x17”

Bypass can hold up to 140lb. index

o 50 sheet document feeder standard (top scan speed of 20opm)

o Shipped with no Styrofoam packing in the box

o Shipped on pallet entirely made of cardboard instead of wood

o Optional 400dpi fax board

o Optional 50 sheet stapling finisher

o Built-in print controller

Made by Peerless (now a division of Kyocera)

800MHz IBM PowerPC processor

USB port on control panel

10/100/1000BaseT ports

PCL, XPS and PostScript print drivers

1GB RAM standard (can upgrade to 2GB)

No hard drive available

IPv6 support

Integration with MS Windows Active Directory standard

Optional HID card reader

Scan to email with LDAP/SMB/SMTP/FTP/TWAIN

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/26/2011 10:59:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Kyocera , MFP , Spec Review Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Friday, February 25, 2011 
 
 Samsung MultiXpress CLX-9359DN and 9250ND &quot;Spec Review&quot; 
 Samsung of Korea announced it is finally shipping its A3 color laser MFPs into the U.S. Details:


o models to ship are the MultiXpress CLX-9350ND and 9250ND

o Base MSRPs of $14,498 and $10,802 respectively

o top speeds of 35ppm and 25ppm respectively

o 8.9”color touchscreen LCD

End users can customize the interface

o 10.5 second first color copy out time

o Black toner yield of 25,000 pages based on 5%

Color toners yield 15,000 pages

Imaging units yield 75,000 pages

Waste toner receptacle yield of 75,000 pages

o Advertised as offering up to 2400dpi (with interpolation, and offers up to 4 bits per pixel)

o 4 tandem OPC drum design

o Optional 600dpi fax board

o Reversing document feeder holds up to 100 originals (does NOT scan both sides of original at same time)

o Paper drawers have LEDs that light up to indicate when they are running low on paper

Standard bypass holds up to 12”x18”paper, up to 100 sheets

comes standard with two 520 sheet drawers

optional 2,000 sheet letter size stand

maximum paper capacity of 3,140 sheets

o Optional external stapling, bookletmaking finisher

o built-in print controller:

actual maker unknown

1GB RAM (can upgrade to 2GB)

250GB hard drive (only 88GB for document storage)

PCL, PostScript and XPS print drivers standard

10/100/1000BaseT and USB ports standard

Scanning includes TWAIN/email/USB/FTP/SMB/HDD/WebDAV/PC

eXtensible Open Architecture (XOA) allows for optional embedded software

o Also shipping the MultiXpress SCX-8040ND and 8030ND b/w A3 MFPs, have same features as the color models except:

Top speeds of 40ppm and 30ppm respectively

Base MSRPs of $11,374 and $9916 respectively

Single OPC drum

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/25/2011 04:43:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: MFP , MFP Industry Notes , Samsung , Spec Review Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Thursday, February 24, 2011 
 
 Ricoh MP C2051 and MP C2551 &quot;Spec Review&quot; 
 - Details on the new Ricoh A3 color laser MFPs, the Aficio MP C2051 and 2551 series:


o top speeds of 20ppm and 25ppm respectively

o Base MSRPs of $6,450 for C2051 and $8750 for C2551

o uses 4 tandem OPC drums w/PxP polymerized toner

o Induction heating belt fusing system

o 8.5”color touchscreen LCD control panel w/customizable icons

o 30 second warmup time, 10 seconds to recover from sleep mode with 9.2 second first color copy out time

o 600x600dpi as copier, 1200x1200dpi as printer, 4 bit
o Document feeder holds up to 50 originals with top color scan speed of 44opm

o Auto duplex standard, but can not handle card stock

o Comes standard with two 250 sheet paper drawers and 100 sheet stack bypass

With options, can expand paper supply to 4,400 sheets maximum

•$580 to add 550 sheet paper drawer

•$1780 to add two 550 sheet drawers

•$1990 for 2,000 sheet letter drawer

•Bypass can hold up to 100 sheets, up to 12”x18”for tabloid full bleed output

•Bypass holds up to 256gsm for simplex output only

•Option can convert paper drawer to envelope feeder for $280

o Support App2Me for panel integration with third party software

o Includes 1 user license of Personal Paperless Document Management (PPDM) for simple OCR loaded on one PC

o Finishing options include

250 sheet internal shift tray (no stapling) for $338

•Optional 2/3 hole punch for $765

o Optional $1375 analog fax board

200dpi standard, can upgrade to 400dpi maximum with $195 RAM board

Optional Internet Fax

o Built-in“GW”print controller

Actual maker unknown (most likely Oak Technology)

600MHz Intel Celeron processor

1.5GB RAM standard (can not upgrade)

160GB hard drive standard

•Requires $605 File Format Converter Kit to use boxes

•Comes standard with hard drive data overwrite, but ISO 15408 Common Criteria certified data overwrite is a $390 option

PCL&amp;XPS print drivers standard

•PostScript print driver for $611

10/100BaseT port standard

•1000BaseT port is $460

•WiFi for $565

•Optional USB port is for scan to and print from thumb drive

o Also accepts SD digital camera memory cards for $356

o Accept connection from digital camera for $267

Optional IPv6 support

Scan features standard include Twain/email/LDAP/SMB/FTP/URL

•Optional OCR called“ESA Transformer”

•Optional GlobalScan NX for routing

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/24/2011 07:56:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: MFP , ricoh , Spec Review Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 This Week in Xerox &quot;TWIX Notes&quot; 
 - Xerox announced it sold:


o Xerox 700 Digital Color Press to Fuller Davies, a printshop in Ipswich, England

o Two Xerox iGen4 EXP production color systems to EarthDigital of New Jersey.

- Xerox announced it terminated an undisclosed amount of employees from its research and development office in Webster, NY, in a cost cutting move.

- Xerox is showing its new production color wax printer, temporarily named“Xerox Production Inkjet System”. Details:

o uses the hot melted wax technology it acquired when it bought the Phaser printer division several years ago from Tektronix of Oregon

o this technology is also used in the Xerox ColorQube color wax copiers

o top speed of 2,200 letter size images per minute (500 feet per minute of paper on rolls)

o claims that company has several beta models in the field for testing in customer environments

o able to print on lightweight stock with no apparent ink soak through issues

o self adjusts in case wax nozzles are not firing properly

o print controller offers variable data option

o highest de-inkability rating from INGEDE, meaning it is easier to recycle pages printed on this device compared with water-based inkjet models

o supposedly based on 2,000 patents

o has intelligent scan bar that checks billions of hot wax droplets per second for registration

o pricing unknown at this time

- Xerox’s ACS office in Columbus, Ohio is in trouble after accidentally printing the social security numbers of 8,400 state child care providers on the outside of envelopes for a mailing, as part of its contract with the state.

- Xerox gave out a“Top Performer”award to XMC, a sales agent in Memphis, TN.

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/24/2011 07:42:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: MFP Industry Notes , Xerox Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Monday, February 21, 2011 
 
 Smart MFP&apos;s &quot;To the Cloud&quot; 
 It&apos;s not often that I get excited about a third party solution provider for copier and MFP&apos;s. Print Audit remains one of my favs, however another company has garnered my attention. 
 I found UDOCX (short for Unified Document Exchange) on a thread that they posted on the Print4Pay Hotel forums . In fact we were discussing cloud based MFP solutions and UDOCX was one of two companies mentioned as Software As a Service (SAAS) 
 You all know what I do, off to the web to check out their web site. So, what I found out is that this seems to be be AWESOME. Probably what I like most is that NO software is required to &quot;Print from&quot;, &quot;Scan2&quot;, &quot;Print Email&quot;, &quot;Scan2fax&quot; and more! 
 I borrowed this from the brochure: 
 UDOCX is a cloud-based document processing service that extends your browser-embedded MFP with mail, print, store and fax features without the need to install or maintain any additional software or hardware and while protecting a company’s compliancy and security policies. 
 Just lately and I&apos;m talking the last 6-12 months, I&apos;ve heard more IT people say that they don&apos;t want additional software on their servers nor do they want to store/maintain an additional server. UDOCX requires no server is sold as a monthly subscription service, buy it for one MFP of a fleet of MFP&apos;s. You may ask, what&apos;s the cost, well,.....I know the cost however I&apos;ll leave that to the folks at UDOCX and I believe the cost is extremely reasonable for the features and service that&apos;s provided.

I was able to connect with UDOCX the other morning, we had a webex for 6AM my time from the folks in the Netherlands. So I&apos;ve had the opportunity to view how the software works with the MFP browser and they were able to show me &quot;ease of use&quot; with the solution.

So, if you get the chance go to the UDOCX web site, download the brochure, view the site, set up a trial and above all tell em that you heard about them from the Print4Pay Hotel .

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/21/2011 09:08:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Digital printing , MFP , MFP Cloud , Print Audit , Print4Pay Hotel , scan2email , Scanning , Solution Selling Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Print4Pay Hotel to Launch New Copier&amp;MFP Web Portal 
 When you only have to rely on yourself, sometimes things can take awhile. 

I&apos;ve just about finished a major upgrade to the P4P Hotel web portal. The new portal will be the &quot;go to&quot; place for industry news, videos, blogs, guest bloggers and industry related threads and discussions. We&apos;ve consolidated all of the manufacturers web forums into one neat package. Every manufacturer is now represented on one simple forum.

BTW, make sure you check out our articles that can be purchased and downloaded and you may also want to get some P4P Hotel gear and have it around the office to remind everyone that the Prin4Pay Hotel is be the best source on the web for real &quot;feet on the street&quot; information!

So, keep checking in every day to http://www.p4photel.org/ and we&apos;ll have a new experience for you!

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/21/2011 05:58:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Guest Blogger , MFP , P4PHotel , P4PHotel News Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Wednesday, February 16, 2011 
 
 Samsung Looks to Penetrate US A3 Copier&amp;MFP Market 
 The rumors started about a year ago that Samsung would enter the A3 Copier&amp;MFP market. Just to clarify A3 devices allows users to scan, copy, fax and print documents up to 11x17 (tabloid).

 Today marked the official launch of 4 A3 devices in the US: 
 •CLX-9250ND–MSRP; $10,802 (25 PPM color) •CLX-9350ND–MSRP; $14,498 (35 PPM color) •SCX-8030ND–MSRP; $9,916 (30 PPM monochrome) •SCX-8040ND–MSRP; $11,374 (40 PPM monochrome) 
 I&apos;m kinda wishy washy with them entering the A3 market, I&apos;m not sure if it&apos;s the right move for them. For about a year I had heard rumors on the street that Samsung would counter with higher speed A4 devices like a 60, 70 and 90ppm devices. I strongly believe if Samsung had come to market with these A4 devices at these speeds they would have turned the MFP/Copier world on their heels. It&apos;s not a secret that 95% of the pages printed in the US are letter and legal. 
Just the other day I was at an account that&apos;s in the financial business, I was there to inspect 5 devices that were all 60 pages per minute to 90 pages per minute. I printed a report from each to device to get current meter reads, how often duplex was used, stapling, etc. I made it a point to check the 11x17 output for these devices, and each system was a big fat ZERO for 11x17&apos;s that were printed or copied. 

I&apos;m thinking Samsung should have stayed with a strength and developed the higher speed A4&apos;s to take market share away from Ricoh, Canon, Xerox and KonicaMinolta. The foray into the A3 market place may be a big mistake.

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/16/2011 11:02:00 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: A3 , A4 , Canon , ricoh , Samsung , Sharp , Xerox Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Monday, February 14, 2011 
 
 Office Copiers take to the Cloud! 
 Finally, after almost 8 years, scanning documents and printing documents to and from the Cloud is gaining acceptance. Back in 2003 Ricoh introduced a &quot;Cloud&quot; Document Management System for the web, it combined Document Management software and off-site storage for those documents. Users could share, revise and collaborate on documents that they uploaded from either the PC or the Copier/MFP. Ricoh as far as I know had built the first Cloud MFP connector for Document Mall.

Eight years later, the &quot;Cloud&quot; is now embraced rather then rejected for fear of a company losing their content to hackers, or competitors. The next version of &quot;Smart MFP&apos;s&quot; will allow users to connect to a Manufacturers Cloud or a third party Cloud service. 

Recently there have been many discussions on the Print4Pay Hotel forums  on &quot;Cloud Services&quot; and how it will affect the way we do business. 

Below are clips of the discussions:

 I am learning about scanning to the cloud from any MFP via email by opening a free account at...... 
by SSG

 A real interesting concept from Lexmark by SSG

 Most of my customers do not trust the cloud, those who do already have..... by AP

 You can even scan directly and securely to the cloud from your Ricoh MFP(to Microsoft Online, Office 365 BPOS, SharePoint). Just take a look at ..... by Constanzek

 Look forward, reason back. How many of us have big generators in the parking lot because we like to be in control of our own electrical uptime? Very few. Walk into any business and ask to meet.... by CashGAP


Other topics posted include &quot;Can you trust the Cloud?&quot;, &quot;The Snow Cloud&quot;, and &quot;The Great Cloud Fight&quot;.  

Whether we like it or not, the Cloud is here to stay and presents and excellent revenue stream for Manufacturers such as Xerox, Ricoh, Canon and KonicaMinolta. I would bet dollars to doughnuts that all of the copier manufacturers will offer this service as an additional option in the future. I also wouldn&apos;t doubt that some of these smaller Cloud companies get purchased in the near future. 

Keep in mind that the Cloud does not have to be for document storage and collaboration, the Cloud can print, the Cloud can fax and the Cloud can also host programs than can be used on line.

Some may ask, what&apos;s the downfall? Anyone care to comment on the downfall of the Cloud, fell free to post here. Here&apos;s a good article from the people at MS, Know Your Cloud. 

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/14/2011 08:43:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Document Mall , MFP , MFP Cloud , ricoh Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Sunday, February 13, 2011 
 
 This Week in Xerox &quot;TWIX Notes&quot; 
 Xerox acquired a provider of electronic health records (EHR) solutions to the healthcare vertical:


o Acquired WaterWare Internet Services Inc.

o Based in San Jose, CA

o Specializes in storing EHR data online called Aquifer EHR Edition

o Offers a system that pharmacists can use to manage patients’prescriptions called Nile Pharmacy

o Will work alongside Xerox DocuShare software
- Xerox announced that it was issued a total of 1,031 patents in 2010, up 46%. The patents are not only from office equipment division, but also from ACS and XMPie divisions.
- Xerox CEO, Ursula Burns, announced she has sold her condominium in New York for $2.5 million. She now lists an address in New Canaan, CT, which is much closer to Xerox’s headquarters in Norwalk, CT.
- Xerox announced it sold a DocuColor 7002 system to LT Print Group of Wirral, England.

- Xerox announced it will use Microsoft’s new Azure cloud computing platform to launch Xerox Cloud Print, a chargeable service that will allow end users to route a printing job to any available public printing, directly from their mobile devices.
- Xerox and data security. Brendan O’Connor of Black Hat USA, published instructions on how to hack into a Xerox WorkCentre MFP, through its Linux based operating system. Details on what he was able to do after hacking in:

o Steal passwords

o Collect all print jobs remotely

o Reset or change meters to affect copy charges from Xerox

o Change default print template, or print random pages

o Firewall network ports

o Schedule random reboots

o Randomly email print and scan jobs to other people

o Make long distance connections with fax modem

o Shut down device

- Xerox announced that it was recognized for the fifth consecutive year by J.D. Power and Associates for providing“An Outstanding Customer Service Experience”. Based on results of a survey of more than 1,000 Xerox customers.

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/13/2011 06:46:00 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: docuware , Fuji Xerox , Xerox Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 New Sharp &quot;Aires&quot; MFP&apos;s Equal Apple iPad Control Panels 
 Sharp will launch a new series of color laser A3 MFPs (code-named“Aries”) that will have control panels similar to an Apple iPad. Tentative specs:

o 10.1”color touchscreen LCD display

Touch screen responds to same types of gestures used with iPad or iPhone, such as flick, tap, slide and drag

Besides the touchscreen, there are apparently no hard buttons

Display can be configured with icons just like a desktop computer

Sharp sales reps may have a demo LCD to show customers on sales calls preconfigured with icons that relate to their business

o Models are MX-2610N, MX-3110N and MX-3610N

o Range in speed from 26ppm to 36ppm

o Uses new toner technology

o 1200x1200dpi print, 600x600dpi copy

Advertised as offering 9600dpi with interpolation

Max of 4 bits per pixel

o New product will be shown to dealers at the Sharp dealer meeting held at Wynn resort in Las Vegas during week of 3/14/2011

o 4 tandem OPC drum design

o 20 second warmup time from sleep mode

o 6.8 second first copy out time

o Optional 400dpi fax board (options allow for up to 3 fax lines)

Internet fax is option

o Comes standard with document feeder

Holds up to 100 originals

Top scan speed of 50opm b/w and 36opm color

Does NOT scan both sides of original at same time

o Comes standard with 550 sheet paper drawer and 100 sheet stack bypass

Can add up to three more 550 sheet paper drawers

Optional 4,000 sheet large capacity deck

o Finishing options include:

MX-FN10 booklet making finisher (15 sheet booklet max)

MX-FN17 50 sheet stapling finisher

MX-PNX5A punch kit

o Built-in print controller

Actual maker unknown (most likely Zoran)

1GB RAM

160GB hard drive

PCL print driver standard

•Optional PostScript driver (requires 1GB RAM upgrade)

•Optional XPS driver (requires 1GB RAM upgrade)

•Optional barcode support

IPv6 support

Optional web browse kit

Optional data security kit

Optional proximity card reader

10/100/1000BaseT and USB ports standard

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/13/2011 06:41:00 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: MFP , MFP Industry Notes , Ricoh. Sharp , Spec Review Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Monday, February 7, 2011 
 
 New Global Copier&amp;MFP Survey &quot;Suvey Said&quot; 
 I started a survey on the Print4Pay Hotel &quot;End User Forums&quot; just about two years ago. In that survey we asked &quot;What Copier/MFP Brand would you pay more for?&quot;  With over 750 page views I&apos;m gonna declare a winner. Mind you there&apos;s no science to this poll, users who view the poll can vote for their choice. Drum roll please!

Ricoh 17%


Xerox 21%

Canon 29%

KonicaMinolta 21%

Kyocera 6%

Sharp 5%

Toshiba 2%

Panasonic 0%

Oce 1%

So, there it is Canon sits at Numero Uno, Xerox and KonicaMinolta tied for second, Ricoh a close third and the rest of the pack, the rest....right, who cares.
-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/07/2011 10:30:00 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Canon , Konica Minolta , Kyocera , MFP Polls , OCE , Panasonic , ricoh , Ricoh. Sharp , Toshiba , Xerox Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Saturday, February 5, 2011 
 
 15 New Copier&amp;MFP RFQ&apos;s&amp;RFP&apos;s 
 Really, we&apos;ve uploaded 15 Copier&amp;MFP RFP&apos;s&amp;RFQ&apos;s in the last week on the Print4Pay Hotel forums. In addition we&apos;ve also posted an additional 5 leads for copiers&amp;MFP&apos;s for the commercial sector. 

The Print4Pay Hotel forums is a sited dedicated to Copier&amp;MFP professionals. The heart and soul of the site is our forums. Our forums give our industry a secure forum to discuss sales, marketing, solutions and talk about the industry as a whole.To date we have over 1,930 global members, our site generates over 100,000 page views. Our members are dealer owners, dealer principals, sales professionals, sales managers, and manufacturers representatives.

 Here&apos;s some of our recent threads for RFP&apos;s&amp;RFQ&apos;s: 

Copier RFP in DC


Xerox Color 550 Copier/Printer Lease in NC

NBS Print&amp;Copier Support Services

OMG! 100 MPF plus unit RFP with 11mil annually!!!!

Solicitation for Wide Format Digital Copier, Plotter and Scanner 

XEROX COPIER MAINTENANCE

36 Copiers in Ohio

COPIER MAINTENANCE SERVICE AND SUPPLIES AGREEMENT

Copier Bid in Washington, DC

45 ppm color in North Carolina

52 Copiers in GA 

COPIER MAINTENANCE&amp;SUPPLIES FOR THREE (3) YEARS

100+ units for RFP in MidAtlantic

Printer Repair Services in NJ RFP

Kansas 35ppm device

Membership for the forums is FREE, access to the secure &quot;leads&quot; forums can be purchased monthly and a yearly Premium Membership is less than $7 per month, but wait you get more with a Premium Membership you&apos;ll also gain access to all off the manufacturers forums and our secure &quot;P4P Document Library&quot;! The P4P Document Library features documents that I&apos;ve used in my copier sales career to increase sales and marketing. 

 Here&apos;s a sampling of the documents I&apos;ve posted: 

Advantage of Color


14 Benefits of Leasing MFP

P4P Hotel&apos;s Document Imaging Glossary

Envelope Press from Ricoh

Copier Security Booklet

Global and N America Print Production work flow forecast

 HP Cost Per Page Chart 
 
 Simple Excel Proposal Spreadsheet 
 
 A3 vs A4 Competitive Workbook 
 
Just a short sampling of the documents, click here for a FREE membership!
 
-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/05/2011 12:14:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: A3 , A4 , copier sales people , Equipment Leasing , HP , MFP , News Color , Print4Pay Hotel , RFPs , RFQs Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Has your organization developed a mobile device strategy yet? 
 Copier/MFP Dealer Principals, here&apos;s a information blog from Rick Backus our Guest Blogger for February!  


 Unless you have been living in a cave for the past 12 months you should be keenly aware of the myriad of new portable devices that are redefining the way many of us communicate and work. While smartphones have been, to varying degrees, part of the enterprise for a number of years the real game-changer today is the larger, more functional tablet-based devices. So where do these new devices fit into your enterprise?

Apple, Android and Blackberry all have or will soon have a presence in this arena. Most of us are already familiar with Apple’s iPad which has been around for almost a year now and accounted for over 15 million new units in 2010. Entries using the Android, Blackberry and Windows operating systems are just beginning to come to market this year.

Most users who are not bound to their desk all day typically use email, Internet and productivity applications. These users are not your standard“Power Users”who need tremendously powerful systems to crunch data, churn through graphic and media files or develop applications. They use productivity suites to create documents and simple spreadsheets along with an email/calendar/contact client and web browser. The new generation of tablet-based devices is tailor made for this type of user.

A tablet device with both Wi-Fi and mobile (cellular) connectivity, properly integrated into the enterprise, will give users access to all the resources they need to be productive no matter where they are. Having the tools you need at your fingertips is crucial in this highly competitive, 24 hour world. Imagine your sales force not only getting paperwork signed by the client but having it immediately delivered back to the office for processing.

 Reduced cost of ownership for hardware refresh is another motivation for migrating users to tablet devices. Initial acquisition and application costs can be substantially less than their notebook counter parts. Tablet devices include email clients but for those who want more functionality there are applications available that deliver extended graphics and features for very reasonable cost. Application suites for word processing, spreadsheet and presentation work are in the sub $100.00 range rather than the hundreds of dollar we have become accustomed to in the PC world. Of course for that price you get a bare bones application but that is right in line with these user’s requirements. There are literally tens of thousands of free and low cost applications out there for almost any task imaginable. 
Once you make the decision to bring tablets into your enterprise the next step is to configure your infrastructure to allow the necessary access. Email, applications, security and network resources all must be configured to allow and accommodate the new level of connectivity. Not all resources can accommodate these devices. Be certain to carefully weigh the need for access versus the expense of any reconfiguration.

As a tool to improve your competitive advantage, the benefits of this new technology will far outweigh the effort necessary to employ it. If you would like to learn more or need assistance implementing these devices contact me at rick@cybercon1.com .

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/05/2011 12:54:00 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Wednesday, February 2, 2011 
 
 This Week in Ricoh &quot;TWIR Notes&quot; 
 Ricoh dealer, DocuSource, of Cerritos, California, announced that it has achieved Gold Solution Provider status from Hyland, for its success selling the OnBase document management software package.“We have consistently made investments in the growth of this business–in sales, marketing and most notably, technical resources. We are thrilled to see our efforts pay off”said DocuSource VP, David Kaye.

- Ricoh announced launch of version 2.0 of its Personal Paperless Document Manager software (PPDMv2):

o Manages paper documents, PDFs and MS Office files

o Assemble document by dragging and dropping pages from other documents (XPS, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, WordPerfect, JPG, BMP, TIFF) to create new PDF

o Change, edit or markup PDFs

o Creates searchable PDFs with OCR engine

o Send or retrieve from MS SharePoint

o Convert files to Amazon Kindle

o Convert capture of text by digital camera into text file

o Auto highlight, redact, underline or cross-out by alphanumeric pattern search

Ricoh announced it will begin providing low-interest loans to employees in Japan to encourage them to make their houses more environmentally friendly (adding solar panels, etc.). The loans will be for 10 years in length at 4% interest.

In an interview in Computer Resellers News magazine, Ricoh U.S. president and CEO, Jeffrey Hickling, stated;“While a much larger share of our revenue comes from direct, we increased our investment in dealer support 50% in 2010”.“In what we’d call the midmarket and the commercial accounts, a direct coverage model alone can be prohibitively expensive”

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/02/2011 07:26:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: PPDM , ricoh Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 Tuesday, February 1, 2011 
 
 This Week in HP &quot;TWIHP Notes&quot; 
 Hewlett Packard confirmed that it has a world-wide backorder problem on toner cartridges for LaserJet P1102W and LaserJet M1212 models. It is working on“restoring”inventory as soon as possible.


Hewlett Packard hopes to expand an operations center in Des Moines, Iowa using state tax dollars of up to $1.6 million. The company would supposedly use the handout to add 308,000 square feet to an existing facility.

Hewlett Packard’s Alon Bar-Shany announced the availability of software development kits (SDKs) to allow third party applications to drive HP Indigo production color presses.

Hewlett Packard announced that by 2012, it will incorporate the webOS it acquired when it purchased Palm Computing in 2010, into future MFPs and printers for integrated applications.

-=Good Selling= Article written by Art Post at 2/01/2011 08:19:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: HP , Laser Printers , MFP Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 
 This Week in Xerox &quot;TWIX Notes&quot; 
 Special thanx to the Print4Pay Hotel member that posted this in our P4P Hotel forums. The Print4Pay Hotel has a worldwide membership of over 1,800 members. Here is the registration link P4PHotel forums. 

Xerox reported its last quarter’s financials:


o earnings per share of 12 cents

o total revenue up 42% (includes ACS)

o cash flow of $1.3 billion

o operating margin of 10.4%

o 11% increase in revenue from Business Process Outsourcing

o 5% increase in IT outsourcing revenue

o 13% increase in service signings

o 4% increase in equipment sales

Color equipment sales revenue up 6%

25% increase in A4 b/w units

27% increase in A4 color units

4% increase in color printer units

2% decrease in midrange b/w units

22% increase in midrange color units

11% decrease in b/w production print units

19% increase in color production print units

Gross margin decreased 1% to 34.1%

o Total liabilities of $18 billion

o Bad debt expense decreased by $45 million

o Digital pages under contract declined 2%

Color pages under contract increased 11%

o $264 million in employee severance costs from 6,000 employee layoff

o $19 million loss associated with sale of operations in Venezuela

Xerox’s chief financial officer (CFO), Lawrence Zimmerman, announced he is leaving the company. Replacement will be Lucan Maestri, formerly of Nokia Siemens.

Xerox announced that Better Buys for Business gave a“Innovative Product of the Year”award for the Xerox WorkCentre 7545/7556 color laser MFPs (which are made by Fuji)

Xerox announced it sold an iGen4 220 production color system to SCICOM Data Services of Minnetonka, Minnesota. The 220 is two iGen4 110 systems connected together to produce full-color two-sided documents at 110ppm.

-=Good Selling=- Article written by Art Post at 2/01/2011 08:03:00 PM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Fuji Xerox Links to this post 
 Reactions:   
 Newer Posts Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 

 

 

 

 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
Get Print Management Solutions
 
Your Leasing Partner
 
P4P Poll of the Month!
 
 Print4Pay Hotel Poll If your MFP could connect to the Cloud would you be more or less inclined to enable a Cloud Based Document Management Service? 

 -- Please choose one -- Yes No We&apos;d be interested, however we need more info View Results 
 
Popular Posts for last 7 days
 
 Should She Resign or Just Quit Selling Copiers &quot;Ask Art&quot; A few days ago I had an email from a P4P&apos;er ( Print4Pay Hotel member) in respect to her quitting the industry or just resigning and movin... Can Your Dealership Profit through the Click Charge ECM? Darn tootin! I wrote about the Intellenetics Enterprise Content Management solution a few weeks ago during Photizo&apos;s Global Transform sho... The End of Solution Sales? Are they Fracking Crazy? The other night I came across an article/blog titled &quot;The End of Solution Sales&quot;, as usual I gave it a read and was not in agreement w... Ricoh MP C2051 and MP C2551 &quot;Spec Review&quot; - Details on the new Ricoh A3 color laser MFPs, the Aficio MP C2051 and 2551 series: o top speeds of 20ppm and 25ppm respectively o Bas... Copier&amp;MFP Industry in Turmoil... the Final Five! A few years ago I posted a blog that outlined the &quot;MPF Wars the Final Five&quot; copier/mfp providers. Since that post on September 28th ... Ricoh MPC4502 Series MFP Review It&apos;s been a long time since Ricoh launched a new generation of A3 Color Multifunction Devices (MFP&apos;s), I thinking 4 years or so. A short ... Top 19 Old Copier Manufacturers that FADED Away! Did you sell these, did you ever see one, or maybe you weren&apos;t even a twinkle in your Mom&apos;s eye when these copier manufacturer were the K... Meet Sharp’s New President Doug Albregts Meet Sharp’s New President Doug Albregts By Scott Cullen (Editor’s note: The following interview appears in this week’s edition of... Can Multifunctional Copiers or Printers be Infected with Malware? Multifunctional Copiers or Printers be Infected with a Malware? My first thought was….. this is AWESOME! Finally all of those tree ... Top 7 Solutions @ Transform 2012 Conference &quot;Intellinetics @ #1&quot; Cost Per Page Billing for Document Management Services Photiizo’s Global Transform has concluded for 2012. I&apos;ll be attending the conf... 
 
What&apos;s New at the P4P Hotel Forums?
 Loading... 
Popular Posts
 
 Copier Sales Forums For those of you who don&apos;t know, the p4 photel www.p4photel.com operates 5 unique message boards that cater to Copier Sales People and C... I Want My....I Want My..... SMART MFP MTV, the Eighties, what a special place in time for some of us! So, where am I going with this?? Not really sure yet, however I wanted to ... HP LaserJet Pro CM1415 Color &quot;What&apos;s the Total Cost of Operation&quot; 31 years of selling laser printers to commercial accounts, well...I&apos;ve pretty much seen and heard it all. Over those years I&apos;ve had many cli... Print4Pay Hotel&apos;s Copier Forums &quot;Weekend Updates&quot; Finally we&apos;ve had some decent weather here in the Northeast! My apologies for not posting much the last week, it was the end of the month, ... Top Ten Copier&amp;MFP Industry Predictions for 2012 Whoa! What a year for the industry with the earthquake/tsunami in Japan, the floods in Thailand, the continued devaluation of the dollar v... Ricoh MP C2051 and MP C2551 &quot;Spec Review&quot; - Details on the new Ricoh A3 color laser MFPs, the Aficio MP C2051 and 2551 series: o top speeds of 20ppm and 25ppm respectively o Bas... Copier Questions Forum Launched! The p4photel has just released a beta version for Copier Questions Message Board Forum. The Copier Questions Forum is designed to give en... &quot;MFP Weekend Industry Updates&quot; P4P Hotel forums This week equals over 500 Multifunctional Copiers are up for Grabs in the Print4Pay Hotel forums ! I&apos;m finally starting to feel that a rea... The Death of The Direct Copier Channel? OH, how those of us in the Dealer Channel long for the days when the copier manufacturers sold only through dealers. For those not in the ... Panasonic Copier Division Dumps all but a Handful of Dealers One of my predictions for 2009 was that Panasonic would drop it&apos;s copier line. Well, on Feb 12, a letter was sent all to all but a handful ... 
 
Need a Quote for a Multifunctional Copier?
 Need a proposal or quote for a new Multifunctional Copier? Click this link and have P4P Specialists prepare a free proposal for you Get Multifunctional Copier Quote 
 
Subscribe To mfp solutions!
 Posts Atom Posts All Comments Atom All Comments 
Welcome to the MFP Solutions Blog
 We are connected! With over 2,300 worldwide members, the information that comes across the message boards is enormous. The latest selling techniques, strategies, future products from the manufacturers and rumors are daily posts on the message boards. Plain and simple we&apos;re connected with right people!

 P4PHotel was envisioned as a means to satisfy our“Need for Knowledge”for the Copier Industry. We have developed this site for the Digital Imaging Specialist to share information and to find answers quickly! P4PHotel is a place to store our knowledge, share and make searchable our knowledge, while sharing inspirations, ideas and our passion for our industry.

The P4P currently has over 2,200 members from 135 countries and has grown to include message boards for Ricoh Family Group , Canon , Konica Minolta , Kyocera , Sharp , OCE , Panasonic , Muratec , Toshiba , HP , Oki , Lexmark , InfoPrint and Xerox . Whether you are in Sales, Service or Customer Support with either a Dealer or a Manufacturer there is a place for you to call home at the P4PHotel !

 
About Me
 Art Post Highlands, New Jersey, United States At 23 years old I entered the industry through a NJ State sponsored training program for copier technicians. I was paid $3.50 an hour to learn how to fix copy machines, 90 days later I landed my first technicians job. After six months I was offered a position in sales, I opted to go the route of sales due to the fact I was real good at taking things apart and not so good at putting them back together.

The rest is history, 31 years later I am still a down the street rep and I&apos;ve had articles published by BERTL, Office World News, OPA and Image Source Magazine.Been named 1 of the Top 40 &quot;Most Infuential&quot; in the Copier Industry. I&apos;ve excelled in the copier industry due to three factors. Desire, Dedication and Determination to be the best at what I do.

I also own and operate the Print4ayPHotel, which is the largest Global Networking Group for Office Equipment Professionals.

I have a lovely wife and one son (in college) and one very large dog (Darby). View my complete profile 
Lijit Search
 Lijit Search 
Followers
 
Email Subscriptions powered by FeedBlitz
 
Your email address:
 
 
Powered by FeedBlitz 
 
The P4P Hotel Solution Links
 
 Find a Qualified P4P Multifunctional Copier Reseller Print4Pay Suites Blog Print4Pay Cafe Blog Print4Pay Hotel Boards Print4Pay Hotel KonicaMinolta Print4Pay Hotel Canon Print4Pay Hotel Kyocera Print4Pay Hotel (Main) Print4Pay Hotel Sharp Print4Pay Hotels &quot;MFP Reviews&quot; Print4Pay Hotel &quot;User Polls&quot; Print4Pay Hotel &quot;World of Wide Format&quot; Print4Pay Hotel &quot;How To?&quot; Print4Pay Hotel &quot;Pricing on the Street&quot; Print4Pay Hotel &quot;Rumor Mill&quot; Print4Pay Hotel &quot;What is?&quot; Print4Pay Hotel Xerox Industry Events Industry People in the News Industry Rumors Managed Print Services Manufacturers Press Releases Solution Software Press Releases Videos 
 
A3 Take Down Counter!!!
 
 P4P Hotel Poll Click Here for every A3 You Took down with an A4 

 -- Please choose one -- I took down another A3 Today! View Results 
 
MFP News Feed
 Loading... 
My Blog List
 
 The Death of The Copier Current Status: Managed Print Services - *Five *years in the making.

Four MPS Conferences under the belt. Hundreds of shows, Webinars, meetings, 
seminars, interviews, presentations, symposiums, ... 1 day ago MFPs, MFDs, PRINTERs&amp;COPIERs Oce:CBS::Ikon:RBS Simple Math - In case your math skills are a little rusty the equation reads Oce is to 
CBS as Ikon is to RBS. True or not True. Here is my argument for True: The 
carnage... 6 days ago Gap Intelligence TV Shopping–Simplified - Here at gap intelligence we’re always trying something new and different, 
whether it’s organizing a conference or flying kites in the park. Our 
latest ven... 1 week ago ChangeForge | Ken Stewart | Where business and technology collide Do You Have the Heart For It? - Do You Have the Heart For It?

If you were an artist, which would you choose: To create your own unique 
and inspired works of art (even if it meant scratc... 1 month ago This Ain&apos;t Your Fathers Office Tidbits - - *Toshiba released results of survey on office stress:* o 40% cite 
malfunctioning technology as their number one office complaint (such as 
laptop that fr... 1 month ago Multifunctional Copier Solutions in New Jersey Managed Document Solution &quot;Access it Anywhere&quot; - Looking for an off site repository for documents that you can access 
anywhere and find in seconds? Are IT costs killing the bottom line?

Look no futher th... 4 months ago Philip&apos;s NY Minute Disruptive Technology for Businesses - If there&apos;s one thing the digital revolution has taught us, it&apos;s that we 
shouldn&apos;t get too attached to anything. Technology has a way of seizing 
long-held i... 6 months ago Digital Printing and The Pirates that Sell it! Digital Press Certifications; Konica Minolta, Xerox, Canon - Interesting Developments... - Now here we are a month and a half later and we find that the Konica 
Minolta is not the only Digital Press that is certified by *IDEAlliance. *Even 
thought... 9 months ago Tough Love for Xerox Crowd Sourced Print Centric Innovation - A couple of days ago an interesting thing happened on social media. It 
started on Twitter then moved to G+.

On twitter there is a group of us, @GraingerEd ... 10 months ago Print4Pay Cafe The Week in Imaging - - Recent survey data from Computer World magazine about company’s usage of 
MFPs:


o most companies fail to utilize the advanced functionality of the hardwa... 1 year ago P4P Suites - 1 year ago Managed Print Services&amp;the Power of the Independent Selecting the Right Managed Print Services Solution - Part Sixteen - This series discusses some of the key factors in selecting the right MPS 
solution for your organization. As an independent, time is precious. Having 
fewer ... 1 year ago 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2012 (101) 
 ►  July (4) 
 Covering the Copier&amp;MFP Industry One Click at a ... Can Your Dealership Profit through the Click Charg... Should She Resign or Just Quit Selling Copiers&quot;As... The End of Solution Sales? Are they Fracking Craz... 
 

 ►  June (12) 
 Can Multifunctional Copiers or Printers be Infecte... Top 5 Reasons Why I Collect Copier&amp;MFP Proposals... Top 7 Solutions @ Transform 2012 DOCassess @ #5 Meet Sharp’s New President Doug Albregts What is an MFP Copier Solution Worth? Can Ricoh be Everything to Everyone? Is my Copier covered under the maintenance plan? Top 7 Solutions @ Transform 2012 Print Audit Premi... Ricoh MP 301SPF Review Ricoh Convergence 2012 Update! Top 7 Solutions @ Transform 2012 ESP @ #3 Top 5 WTF Issues with Copier&amp;MFP Salespeople 
 

 ►  May (12) 
 New Jersey Gives Copiers a Bad Name Top 7 Solutions @ Transform 2012 PretonSaver @ #2 Top 7 Solutions @ Transform 2012 Conference&quot;Intel... Transform 2012 Conference&quot;Hotter Than Ever&quot; 10 Phone Cold Calling Tips for Copiers&amp;MFP&apos;s Selling MFP&apos;s&quot;Making All the Calls&quot; Ricoh&quot;Where&apos;s the ICE&quot;? 10 Tips for Recession Proofing Your Business Good Copier Gone Bad! WTF, Memjet Partners with Fuji/Xerox, Canon/Oce&amp;... Xerox ColorQube&quot;Rebuttal&quot; MFP Wars&amp;The Plain Paper Copier Industry 
 

 ►  April (14) 
 Top 19 Old Copier Manufacturers that FADED Away! Nobody Ever Got Fired for Buying a Xerox Copier&amp;MFP Industry in Turmoil... the Final Five... Why Sell Copier and Managed Print Solutions by the... Daily Document Management Industry Notes from Arou... Ricoh MPC4502 Series MFP Review Copier&amp;MPS Industry Fighting Over the&quot;Last Shee... KYOTIER Hybrid Color 3-tier Cost Per Page Pricing ... Daily Managed Print Service Industry Notes from Ar... Daily Managed Print Service Industry Notes from Ar... Daily Document Management Industry Notes from Arou... Ricoh’s PCS Director Embedded Now Compatible with ... Introduction to Document Management with the Cloud... 2 Cents for Color MFP Cost Per Page/Coverage Meter... 
 

 ►  March (24) 
 Daily Document Management Industry Notes from Arou... Daily Managed Print Service Industry Notes from Ar... Daily Managed Print Service Industry Notes from Ar... Daily Document Management Industry Notes from Arou... The Birth of Managed Print Services&quot;According to ... Why RFP for Copiers don’t work anymore. Who’s buyi... Servicing Copiers&amp;MFP&apos;s&quot;Retain Customers with E... Daily Document Management Industry Notes from Arou... 
 

 ►  February (21) 

 ►  January (14) 
 

 ▼  2011 (209) 
 ►  December (13) 

 ►  November (25) 

 ►  October (28) 

 ►  September (32) 

 ►  August (22) 

 ►  July (5) 

 ►  June (7) 

 ►  May (11) 

 ►  April (15) 

 ►  March (18) 

 ▼  February (18) 
 MFP Weekend Industry Notes for 2/27/2011 Can Color Copiers&amp;MFP Print Money? Well yes, h... TASKalfa 255C and TASKalfa 205C&quot;Spec Review&quot; Samsung MultiXpress CLX-9359DN and 9250ND&quot;Spec Re... Ricoh MP C2051 and MP C2551&quot;Spec Review&quot; This Week in Xerox&quot;TWIX Notes&quot; Smart MFP&apos;s&quot;To the Cloud&quot; Print4Pay Hotel to Launch New Copier&amp;MFP Web Por... Samsung Looks to Penetrate US A3 Copier&amp;MFP Mark... Office Copiers take to the Cloud! This Week in Xerox&quot;TWIX Notes&quot; New Sharp&quot;Aires&quot;MFP&apos;s Equal Apple iPad Control P... New Global Copier&amp;MFP Survey&quot;Suvey Said&quot; 15 New Copier&amp;MFP RFQ&apos;s&amp;RFP&apos;s Has your organization developed a mobile device st... This Week in Ricoh&quot;TWIR Notes&quot; This Week in HP&quot;TWIHP Notes&quot; This Week in Xerox&quot;TWIX Notes&quot; 
 

 ►  January (15) 
 

 ►  2010 (180) 
 ►  December (10) 

 ►  November (17) 

 ►  October (14) 

 ►  September (13) 

 ►  August (11) 

 ►  July (13) 

 ►  June (10) 

 ►  May (10) 

 ►  April (17) 

 ►  March (19) 

 ►  February (22) 

 ►  January (24) 
 

 ►  2009 (335) 
 ►  December (22) 

 ►  November (26) 

 ►  October (31) 

 ►  September (28) 

 ►  August (33) 

 ►  July (30) 

 ►  June (23) 

 ►  May (23) 

 ►  April (33) 

 ►  March (21) 

 ►  February (31) 

 ►  January (34) 
 

 ►  2008 (177) 
 ►  December (38) 

 ►  November (30) 

 ►  October (27) 

 ►  September (31) 

 ►  August (9) 

 ►  July (3) 

 ►  June (1) 

 ►  May (6) 

 ►  April (9) 

 ►  March (7) 

 ►  February (7) 

 ►  January (9) 
 

 ►  2007 (70) 
 ►  December (10) 

 ►  November (9) 

 ►  October (9) 

 ►  September (5) 

 ►  August (1) 

 ►  July (3) 

 ►  June (6) 

 ►  May (6) 

 ►  April (9) 

 ►  March (4) 

 ►  February (4) 

 ►  January (4) 
 
 
Recent Posts
 
Multifunctional Copier Network Posts
 Newest message board threads: 

 Title Author Date 
 
My Outside of Work Favorite Links
 
 Gap Intelligence 
 
Disclaimer
 Print4Pay Hotel.com is intended to provide you accurate and authoritative information with regard to the subject matter covered. It is offered with the understanding that neither the publisher nor the author is engaged in rendering legal, accounting, investment or other professional advice or services. Information obtained from this website, including e-mail responses from Print4Pay Hotel.com should be considered as general educational information.
 
Labels
 11x17 (4) 120 ways to save (11) 2011 (1) 3-5 (1) 365 (1) 3M (1) 800 Ways to Save and Serve (9) 800 wyas to save and serve (1) A Week in the Life of Copier Sales (143) A21A (2) A3 (16) A4 (34) ABBYY (3) ACS (1) Adobe (6) AEC (4) AIIM/On Demand Show (10) AIO (3) America (1) Americans (1) AnyDoc (1) apeco (2) Apple (7) art post (1) Ask Art (4) Assessments (1) auxilio (3) auxillo (1) b2c (1) barcode (1) Baseball (2) Belmar New Jersey (2) BERTL (4) Best Buy Card (1) Bids (2) bizhub (1) bizhub c35 (1) bli (2) Books (1) Boomers (1) BPA (1) Brother (12) Browny (2) BTA (1) Business (1) C (1) cananda (1) Canon (219) Canon DR2050C (1) Certification Tests. Xerox (1) Christmas (3) Cirrato (1) Cisco (1) Citi Capital (1) Clicks (4) Close Sales (81) Closing (7) cloud (12) clx-9350dn (1) CM8000 (1) CM8050 (2) CM8060 (2) Cold Calling (11) Color Copiers (36) Color Printing (8) Color Scanners (12) ColorQube (20) ComColor (13) Compensation Plan (2) CompTIA (2) Contex (4) convergence (2) cool stuff (3) Cop (1) Copier Commericals (3) copier crimes (4) Copier Hard Drives (3) Copier Humor (43) copier lease (7) Copier Questions Forum (4) Copier Quotes (10) copier sales people (167) Copier Technicians (8) copier tips (11) Copiers (8) copystar (1) cost per page (24) Could (1) counterfieters (1) CPC (3) cpp (2) CRM (2) Cybercon (5) Danka (6) Dealer Tips (12) Dealerships (34) Death of the Copier (3) Dell (9) digidoc flow (1) digital duplicator (3) digital presses (3) Digital printing (5) Direct Branches (7) directmail (1) DLL (1) DMS (1) Docaury (1) Docuary (2) Docuary Web (2) Document Mall (4) Document Management (31) documents (6) Docushare (3) Docusultant (2) docuware (3) drupa (2) Duplicators (9) Duplo (3) e-paper (4) earthquake (3) ECi (1) ECM (4) ecopy (15) EFI (25) EIS Quatra (3) EIS Supra (3) electric (1) envelope printers (2) Epson (14) Equipment Leasing (26) Equitrac (9) erasable toner (1) Eric the Office Worker (1) eskofot (1) europe (1) ewriter (1) EzeScan (1) fake (1) Fax (4) Fax Server ROI Calculator (3) Fiery (5) finishers (1) Flatpack Cabinets (1) fleet (1) fm audit (1) Formax (2) Frontier Line (2) Fuji (11) Fuji Xerox (28) Fujitsu (3) funny (2) g (1) Gap Intelligence (1) Gartner (8) GBC (1) gelsprinter (2) Gestetner (3) global (7) Government (1) GreatAmerica (1) Green (10) Guest Blogger (11) Happy Friday (1) Hardware (2) HCL (2) Health (1) Healthcare (1) heidlberg (2) Hitachi (2) honor (1) How Stuff Works (2) HP (119) HP Edgeline (6) HP. Pricing on the Street (1) humor (1) hybrid dealer (1) IA (1) IBM (2) iDatix (1) iGen (2) Ikom (2) Ikon (55) imageclass (1) Imagepress (2) ImagePrograph (1) imageRUNNER (2) imagerunner advance (7) imagerunner C2550 (1) imagerunner C3080i (1) imagerunner C3480i (1) imagerunnerC1030 (1) ImageWare (2) Inc. (1) Independent (1) Infoprint (3) inkjet (2) Innovative Performance Group (1) intellinetics (1) internet (1) irene (1) IRS tax Codes (3) IT (3) ITEX (10) Jersey (1) Jersey Shore (1) jetmobile (4) jim parker (2) John Reiling (1) KIP (12) KIP3100 (1) Kodak (51) Kofax (4) Konica Minolta (58) KonicaMinolta (44) kWh (1) Kyocera (78) Lake Como (1) LAN Fax (6) Lanier (9) Laser Printers (32) LCA (3) leads (21) Lease (11) Lemark (2) Lexmark (58) life (1) Look Back (1) Lucas Distribution LLC (1) Lyra (3) m-files (1) Maintenance (1) Making Sense of the Madness (1) managed documensts (5) managed documents (3) managed print services (45) managed service (4) Manufacturers (2) MDS (4) MEAP (1) Memjet (9) Merry Christmas (1) MFD (2) mfiles (1) MFP (168) MFP Cloud (25) MFP Industry Notes (86) MFP News (70) MFP Polls (24) MFP Reviews (16) MFP Sales Data Spreadsheet (5) MFP Solutions (20) MFP&apos;s (27) MFPs (12) MicroSoft (5) MIF (2) MIF Review (1) Minolta (4) mita (3) monthly duty cycle (1) MPC2000 (2) MPC2500 (2) MPC3000 (2) MPC3500 (2) MPC4500 (2) MPS (61) MPS Mentor (5) MPSA (3) msp (1) MSPMentor (1) Multifunction printer (9) Multifunctional Copier System (29) Muratec (18) Mutoh (1) MWAi (2) NEC (2) New Jersey (1) News Color (5) Nexpress (2) Notable Solutions (1) NSI (6) nuance (5) nuvera (1) OCE (73) OCR (2) ODBC (1) Office Workers (1) Oki 9650n (2) Okidata (40) olivetti (1) omtool (1) OPS (1) Over the top (1) P4P Contest (2) P4P Document Library (1) p4pcafe (1) P4PHotel (62) P4PHotel News (16) P4PU (3) pagetrac (1) Panasonic (25) Paper (3) Paperless Office (2) Paradigm Imaging (17) Peter Drucker (1) phaser (1) photizo (6) Photocopier (2) Pitney Bowes (12) plotters (2) Polek (7) Poll (18) PPBG (1) PPDM (4) Pre-Owned Copy Machines (2) Premium Membership (1) Presstek (1) Pricing (9) Print (7) Print Audit (36) Print Audit Secure (4) print drivers (4) Print Management Solutions (26) Print Production (2) Print Shop in A Box (3) Print4Pay Hotel (24) Print4Pay Industry Notes (6) Printers (13) printfleet (1) Production Print (3) Proposals (5) Prospecting (7) PSIGEN (1) Publishing and Printing (2) Purchase (1) pxp toner (3) Quiz (1) quota (2) quotes (3) quotes. RFP (5) Ram Logic (2) RBS (4) Really Cool Software (2) Recycle (3) Rex Rotary (1) RFPs (30) RFQs (22) ricoh (285) Ricoh 240w (1) Ricoh C550ex (1) Ricoh C811dn (1) Ricoh Family Group (12) ricoh smart accounting (1) Ricoh SP W2470 (1) Ricoh. Sharp (27) Riso (18) Rock Paper (1) ROI (2) Royal (2) Rumors (5) S (2) SaaS (1) Sales Tips (85) Samsung (43) Samsung 6345N (6) Samsung 6555N (2) SAS (1) Savin (9) scan (3) scan2cloud (9) scan2email (5) scan2fax (4) scan2file (1) Scanning (17) ScanSnapS500 (1) Sea Girt New Jersey (1) Seine (1) Sell The Solution (55) selling copiers (18) SeriPrinter (1) service engineers (1) sfscan (1) Sharepoint (3) Sharp (68) Sharp. Ikon (1) smart mfp&apos;s (5) SMB (1) software (1) Solution Selling (59) Spec Review (9) Stethos (6) Street Pricing (13) Sucess Story (4) tablets (1) Tameran (1) TASKalpha (2) TCO (12) TDV (1) technology (1) toner (4) Top Ten (2) Toshiba (92) Tosihba (1) Total Cost of Operation (13) trees (1) TWIC (15) TWIR (10) TWIT (2) Twitter (2) TWIX (14) udocx (13) Used Copy Machines (2) Vircosoft (1) Ways to Save (4) Webinar (4) Wells Fargo (1) What is? (1) Wide Format (29) wideformat (3) windows 8 (2) WorkCENTRE (2) WWII (10) Xante (3) Xeikon (2) Xerography (3) Xerox (229) xerox 7346. lanier 550 (1) XMPie (1) Xsolutions (1) 
Are you on Dope?
 
Wild Horses
 
Pressure
 
Russians are Coming
 
New York
 
I Suck as a Sales Person
 
Steve Martin John Candy = Funny Sales
 
Back in Babies Arm!
 
Cheech&amp;Chong
 
Share It
 
 
 
 
 2011-2012. Picture Window template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
