<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004447" url="http://articles.chicagotribune.com/1996-03-07/news/9603070151_1_police-veteran-sexual-harassment-criminal-charges" time="2012-07-12-20:52" support="1" score="0.0018887826152656283" bingtitle="Suspended Orland Park Officer Fired For Sexual Harassment ..." webtitle="Suspended Orland Park Officer Fired For Sexual Harassment - Chicago Tribune">
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="106"/>
	<description>... public bloodletting, the Orland Park Board ... act on him at the side of his squad car on ... worked alone, once climbed behind the counter of a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		news 
 Front Page News Sports Business Entertainment Opinion Lifestyle 
 
 All Sections 
 Front Page News Sports Business Entertainment Opinion Lifestyle 
 
 Home &gt; Featured Articles &gt; Sexual Harassment 
Suspended Orland Park Officer Fired For Sexual Harassment
 
State Is Considering Criminal Charges
 March 07, 1996 | By Pamela Cytrynbaum, Tribune Staff Writer. Free-lance writer Diana Delogu contributed to this article. 
In the end, what spoke the loudest against Police Officer Robert Corrello Jr. were the graphic 59-page complaint and the voices of one woman after another testifying to instances of sexual assault, harassment, stalking and groping.

Putting an end to three months of that kind of painful public bloodletting, the Orland Park Board of Fire and Police Commissioners Wednesday night fired Corrello, a 13-year police veteran who the board ruled last month had used his badge to terrorize the women of this southwest suburb.
 
&quot;We all know it was wrong,&quot; Orland Park Police Chief Tim McCarthy said. &quot;As a public agency, we have a greater need to clean up our house, to do it publicly, and to do it quickly. We had a problem, we handled it. Now, we have to be vigilant.&quot;

The Cook County State&apos;s Attorney&apos;s Office is looking into possible criminal charges against Corrello, McCarthy said. A spokesman for the state&apos;s attorney&apos;s office said he could not comment on what cases are being investigated.

Neither Corrello, 40, nor his attorney were present for the announcement of the ruling by the three-member board.

After the ruling Wednesday night, McCarthy said, &quot;We readily admit that we had a police officer who engaged in conduct that was offensive, outrageous and in violation of numerous rules and regulations of this department. I hope the public is confident, however, that the Orland Park Police Department took appropriate measures from the beginning of this matter.&quot;

Corrello, who has been suspended without pay since Dec. 6, has maintained his innocence regarding the most serious charges, but he did admit to visiting a woman at her home and acknowledged kissing a female department store security guard.

He described his social encounters with the women as part of a &quot;community policing&quot; strategy of getting out to talk to the people. Corrello&apos;s attorney, Fred Kimmel, described his client as a &quot;normal red-blooded American man.&quot;

Board attorney Ronald Broida, speaking on behalf of commissioners, said Wednesday night, &quot;None of the charges of which Officer Corrello has been found guilty pertain to private, purely off-duty social circumstances. While Officer Corrello denied most of the alleged offending conduct, no contrary evidence was brought forth by Officer Corrello nor was there any explanation given . . . as to why these witnesses, many of whom did not know one another, would not truthfully and accurately testify in this proceeding.

&quot;In pleadings filed in this matter and in the arguments of counsel for Officer Corrello, an attempt has been made to trivialize the conduct of which Officer Corrello has been found guilty. This board does not agree with that characterization. Rather, it specifically finds that these acts of misconduct are repugnant to the proper high standards which all police officers should maintain when dealing with members of the public.&quot;

Corrello&apos;s wife, Laurie, who sat through hours of graphic and sometimes emotional testimony and who was present at Wednesday night&apos;s ruling, did not comment after the announcement. She said early in the hearing process that she believed the women&apos;s charges. She said she met Corrello years ago during a bogus traffic stop.

McCarthy first received complaints about Corrello in December 1994. A yearlong investigation followed, culminating in the 59-page complaint.
 
The hearings began in early December. The public revelations of Corrello&apos;s behavior have been &quot;very stressful&quot; for the department and the community, McCarthy said. But he said he would do it all again.

&quot;We&apos;re not going to shy away from these cases,&quot; he said. &quot;As uncomfortable as it is, it&apos;s worth it.&quot;

The commissioners found Corrello guilty Feb. 19 of sexually harassing eight women while on duty in incidents dating five years. The decision Wednesday night to fire Corrello capped months of public hearings in which women described Corrello&apos;s seemingly relentless and abusive behavior against women who repeatedly rejected his advances.

One woman testified that Corrello stopped her car and coerced her to perform a sexual act on him at the side of his squad car on a dark road.

The women testified that Corrello repeatedly described his explicit, violent sexual fantasies about them, often made lewd remarks loudly at the women&apos;s workplaces, and made several bogus traffic stops to socialize.

In other testimony, the women said: Corrello, who worked alone, once climbed behind the counter of a fast-food restaurant and slammed his body against a female worker while fondling her; he pushed a security guard against a wall and kissed her; he grabbed at a beauty parlor worker&apos;s breast.

Corrello, a Tinley Park resident, was found guilty of nine counts of misconduct, including those related to intimidation, abuse of power, immoral conduct, battery and conduct unbecoming an officer. The incidents violated a dozen department rules.

He was found innocent of charges that he failed to back another police officer during a police call, and misconduct charges involving four other women were dismissed.

Kimmel said he probably will appeal the discharge even though Corrello claims he can no longer return to work as a police officer because of a shoulder injury.

Attorney Richard Wimmer, who represents McCarthy, said Corrello was suspended 11 times and received a dozen reprimands during his 13 years with the department.
 Featured Articles Mormons quit church in mass resignation ceremony Decoding the diabetic diet Silva defeats Sonnen by TKO MORE: Website gives Illinois customers power to compare electricity rates How to handle a tick bite Brad Pitt&apos;s mother slams gay marriage, Obama How to cut your own hair Chicago&apos;s 2012 summer festival schedule Consumer report raises concerns about reverse mortgages Related Links Related Articles 
 Panel Formed To Investigate Sexual Harassment In Army 
 November 23, 1996 Sexual Harassment: A New Battleground For U.s. Campuses 
 July 31, 1989 Calumet City mayor chooses new team 
 September 12, 2003 Liability Argued In Child-on-child Abuse 
 January 11, 1999 
 Find More Stories About 
 Sexual Harassment 
 Terms of Service Privacy Policy Index by Date Index by Keyword www.chicagotribune.com Connect 
 Like us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter
	</body>
</document>
