<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004149" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2010/12/miss_yip_opens_downtown_outpos.php" time="2012-07-12-20:23" support="2" score="0.004353593488455957" bingtitle="Miss Yip Opens Downtown Outpost at 900 Biscayne - Miami ..." webtitle="Miss Yip Opens Downtown Outpost at 900 Biscayne - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Bourdain: Short Order &quot;Offended&quot; Me and My &quot;Sense of Pride&quot; Wynwood Street ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New Wakin-N-Bacon Brunch</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Restaurant Opening 
Miss Yip Opens Downtown Outpost at 900 Biscayne
 By Jose D. Duran Thu., Dec. 9 2010 at 12:53 PM Categories: Restaurant Opening 
 Pin It 
 
 Miss Yip&apos;s downtown digs. 
​ Good ol&apos; Miss Yip . When you wanted somewhat-affordable Chinese food right off Lincoln Road, it was always there. And now, when you want somewhat-affordable Chinese food in downtown Miami, it will be there, too.

We say somewhat because we&apos;ve always found the place to be a dollar or two overpriced, considering it&apos;s just Chinese food. Otherwise, service and food are usually good. We visited the new location at 900 Biscayne Monday night, and it wasn&apos;t busy, but there were clear signs of life.
 
An elderly Asian lady was making the dim sum in plain view of most of the dining room behind a glass wall, which is a nice touch. But the food is basically the same you&apos;d get at the South Beach locale. This is unfortunate because Miss Yip has stiff competition from eateries that are better priced. ( Wok Town , anyone?)

But price aside, places with Asian influences like Sakaya Kitchen and Gigi , both in the nearby Midtown area, have really raised the bar on what affordable food can be. Otherwise, Miss Yip is relying on a clientele that is looking for good-but-not-great everyday Chinese food. Will it succeed? Guess we&apos;ll have to wait and see.

 Miss Yip Chinese Café
900 Biscayne Blvd., Miami
305-358-0088 
Location Info
 
Venue



Map
 
 Miss Yip 

900 Biscayne Blvd., Miami, FL

Category: Restaurant 
 
 0 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Miss Yip Chinese Cafe Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
We found the food atr Miss Yip&apos;s to be very good, with the Green Tea Tirasimu outstandingly unique. Even more than the food, we found the whole experience at Miss Yip&apos;s to be exceptional. We arrived from out of town before noon for a late afternoon event at the Aush Centre for Perfoming Arts, excpecting to find an area of museums and restaurants. After walking the area in sweltering heat, we found Miss Yip&apos;s; we were welcomed like family, allowed to draw out our meal for over an hour with only firendly refills. When we asked if we could sit on their porch after we finished, they not only said for us to stay as long as we wished, but sent out large glasses of ice water as we cooled our heels on their spacious, comfortable, attractive patio.
 
I have never had a delivery order&lt;$25, and I&apos;ve only ordered one appetizer and one entree. I have never had a delivery in which they didn&apos;t have to call me to find the address. I live within a 1/2 mile on a busy and well known street. I have never had an order that was correct. Every time, half my order is ok, and I have to wait for the other portion to be delivered. The food is cold half the time. The staff is beyond rude. If you want to pay a lot of money for mediocre lukewarm food and get a LARGE dose of bad attitude, then you would love Miss Yip. If you expect to be treated with respect from an appreciative restaurant that likes their customers, seek your meal elsewhere. Worst experience from a delivery service ever, in any
 
you obviously work here
 
Incredibly disappointing, I haven&apos;t been to the original restaurant but the new one at 900 Biscayne is hopeless. Service was incredibly slow, waitress had no idea what she was doing and the food was not especially good and quite overpriced to me. We complained and got a grovelling apology and a discount.

My advice - go elsewhere.
 
miss yip is good, i love the food and prices are reasonable ,but the best is the happy hours
 
I agree with V Cortes, but then again, anyone who actually pays attention to Newtimes reviews needs some serious counseling.
 
I totally disagree with this editor. The 3 restaurants he mentioned to belittle Miss Yip are fast food and take-out places. They are all very different eating experiences bearing only one similarity, the cuisine is Asian. For instance, Wok Town has an oversized menu posted on the wall besides the counter where you place your order, pay and get a numbered card on a metal holder. You sit on a nice pressed wood picnic tables. It is nice,but only for a quick lunch on the go. On the other hand, Miss Yip is an actual sit-down restaurant following the traditional service etiquettes starting with the simplicity of offering of an actual menu. From then on, there is a good selection of Chinese food and Dim Sum. The place is pleasantly decorated in an authentic oriental style. I can only say that my dining experiences there have been very good. This is without consideration for the fact that the restaurant is still in the pre-opening stage and is learning to perfect its performance based on our customer satisfactions.
 
Sorry, Miss Yip is not good food. Somewhat reasonable and good Chinese food don&apos;t co-exist in SoBe. Mr. Chow&apos;s isn&apos;t bad, but so over priced.
 

TotalComments: 8
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Cafe Ponce
 View Ad | View Site 
Trio on the Bay
 View Ad | View Site 
Flip Burger Bar
 View Ad | View Site 
Momo Cha Tea House
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
