<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004713" url="http://www.toysrus.ca/product/index.jsp?productId=3822328&amp;prodFindSrc=endCap" time="2012-07-12-21:13" support="1" score="0.0016409882551061353" bingtitle="Toys &quot;R&quot; Us Canada - The Official Toys &quot;R&quot; Us Site - Toys, Games ..." webtitle="Toys &quot;R&quot; Us Canada - The Official Toys &quot;R&quot; Us Site - Toys, Games,&amp;More">
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>... Infant Soft &amp; Plush Interactive Toys Stroller &amp; Car Seat ... LEGO Friends - City Park Café (3061) ... Your Order. Track my Order; Returns; Cancellations</description>
	<body>
		Thank you for visiting Toys R Us. If you need assistance with shopping on our site, please call us at 800-869-7787 and a customer care representative will be happy to assist you. Please inform the Customer Service representative that you require assistance. 
 
 
 
 
 ?? tnf label.trusHeader.Language ?? Email signup My account Help Find more great products at Toys&quot;R&quot;Us 
 
 Baby Registry Wish Lists Gift Finder ?? tnf label.trusHeader.rFlyer ?? Gift Cards Store Locator 
 
 
 Deals Arts&amp;Crafts Baby Toys Infant Development Toys Infant Soft&amp;Plush Interactive Toys Stroller&amp;Car Seat Toys More &gt;&gt; Bikes, Trikes&amp;Scooters Trikes Bikes More &gt;&gt; Books - Book Sale on Now! Boys&apos; Toys Action Figures - Buy 3 Get Free Shipping*! Vehicles&amp;Radio Control &quot;R&quot; Boys Brands TV&amp;Movie Characters Comic Book Superheroes More &gt;&gt; Building Sets&amp;Blocks Blocks Building Sets More &gt;&gt; Electronics Digital Cameras&amp;Accessories More &gt;&gt; Games&amp;Puzzles-Buy 3 Get Free Shipping! Puzzles More &gt;&gt; Gaming&amp;Electronics Girls&apos; Toys Dolls&amp;Playsets Kitchens&amp;Household Playsets &quot;R&quot; Girl Brands More &gt;&gt; Save up to $600 on ALL Swing Sets Imaginarium Kitchens&amp;Household Playsets LeapFrog Learning Toys Imaginarium Playmobil Infant Development Toys 30% Off All Bruin Infant Toys Preschool Electronics More &gt;&gt; Movies-Buy 2 or More Get Free Shipping! Musical Instruments Outdoor Play Sand&amp;WaterTables Climbers&amp;Slides Wagons Inflatable Bouncers&amp;Trampolines Ride-Ons More &gt;&gt; Party Supplies Playmobil Plush Stuffed Animals&amp;Toys Infant Soft&amp;Plush More &gt;&gt; Preschool Toys Preschool Electronics More &gt;&gt; Science&amp;Discovery Storage&amp;Organization Trading Cards Vehicles&amp;Radio Control Remote Control Vehicles Race Tracks&amp;Playsets More &gt;&gt; Video Games Xbox 360 Nintendo Wii PlayStation 3 PlayStation 2 More &gt;&gt; Children&apos;s Bedroom Collections Collections Twin Beds Bedding&amp;Blankets Room in a Box Storage&amp;Organization Tables&amp;Chairs More &gt;&gt; &quot;R&quot; Top Rated &quot;R&quot; Exclusives &quot;R&quot; Brands Imaginarium &quot;R&quot; Learning Toys &quot;R&quot; Girl Brands &quot;R&quot; Boys Brands More &gt;&gt;  
 
 
 Birth - 12 months 12 - 24 Months 2 Years 3&amp;4 Years 5 - 7 Years 8 - 11 Years 12 - 14 Years Big Kids 
 
 The Avengers Lalaloopsy Disney DORA Fisher-Price Toys LeapFrog Barbie Crayola Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles Transformers Imaginarium LEGO-Buy 3 Get Free Shipping! Bratz Little Tikes Mega Bloks NERF Playmobil 25% Off All Playskool Toys See All &gt;&gt; 
 
 Deals Gifts for your Graduate Pre Order Now! &quot;R&quot; Brands &quot;R&quot; Exclusives NHL Shop Pokémon Shop Last Chance, Limited Quantities! Accessorize Your Toys! Contest Great Gift Ideas under $30 Birthday Gift Ideas Bratz True Hope See All &gt;&gt; 
 
 Imaginarium Train Sets Building Sets&amp;Blocks Electronic Learning Aids Playmobil Thomas&amp;Friends Arts&amp;Crafts Books - Book Sale on Now! 20% Off All Edu-Science Science&amp;Discovery Animal Planet Infant Development Toys Musical Instruments Games&amp;Puzzles-Buy 3 Get Free Shipping! Melissa&amp;Doug 30% Off All Bruin Infant Toys Breyer Horses The Smurfs 30% Off All Bruin Preschool Toys Preschool Electronics Preschool Building Sets 
 0 
 All Products Toys&amp;Games Video Games Baby Products Welcome! Login or create an account. Learn why 
 
 
&quot;Like Us&quot; for previews,
deals, sweeps and more
 
 
Shop this week&apos;s
deals
 
LEGO
Monster Fighters
 
Megabrands
World of Warcraft
 
Disney
Birthday Theme
 
Bratz True Hope
Learn more
 
 
 
 
 Save 20% 
 on These LEGO Batman Building Sets Save 25% 
 Playskool Toys Save up to $600 
 Swing Sets Save up to $30 
 Smart Trikes Save up to 40% 
 Climbers, Trampolines, Playhouses and More Save 30% 
 FurReal Plush Toys Buy 1 Get 1 1/2 Off! 
 Marvel and Star Wars Figures, Vehicles and Role-play Save 25% 
 Toys only Available at TRU! Save up to 50% 
 select Water Tables and Toys Save up to 30% 
 Bikes 
 Building Sets&amp;Blocks! Arts&amp;Crafts! Educational Electronics Science&amp;Discovery Games&amp;Puzzles Electronic Gaming Bouncers&amp;Trampolines Bikes, Trikes, Ride-ons&amp;more Sports&amp;Games 
 
 
 Top Rated 
 Outdoor Play View All &quot;R&quot; Brands View All Building Sets View All 
 
 Nerf - Super Soaker Tornado Strike 5.0 Reg Price: $27.99 Website Price:  $20.97 120mm Dart Scooter 5.0 Reg Price: $59.99 Website Price:  $29.97 Thomas and Friends Playville with 25 Balls 5.0 Reg Price: $79.99 Website Price:  $39.97 Springfree 8ft Round Trampoline with Safety Enclosure 5.0 Reg Price: $999.99 Website Price:  $799.97 Springfree 8 x 13ft Large Oval Trampoline with Safety Enclosure 5.0 Website Price:  $1,199.99 NERF VORTEX LUMITRON Blaster 5.0 Website Price:  $39.99 
 
 120mm Dart Scooter 5.0 Reg Price: $59.99 Website Price:  $29.97 Bruin - Stacking Cups 5.0 Reg Price: $9.99 Website Price:  $6.97 Imaginarium - Classic Train Table with Roundhouse - Espresso 5.0 Website Price:  $199.99 Dream Dazzlers - Sports Car with Jessica Doll 5.0 Website Price:  $19.99 Just Like Home - Design Your Own Cake 5.0 Reg Price: $16.99 Website Price:  $14.97 Stats - 6 in 1 Combination Tunnel and Tent Set 5.0 Website Price:  $89.99 
 
 K&apos;Nex - Mario Kart - Mario&amp;Diddy Kong&apos;s Fire Challenge Building Set 5.0 Website Price:  $69.99 K&apos;Nex - Mario Kart - Mario Circuit Ultimate Building Set 5.0 Website Price:  $129.99 LEGO Monster Fighters - The Werewolf (9463) 5.0 Website Price:  $26.99 LEGO Lord of the Rings - The Battle of Helm&apos;s Deep (9474) 5.0 Website Price:  $179.99 Mega Bloks - Halo Wars - Covenant Shade Turret (96949) 5.0 Website Price:  $12.99 LEGO Ninjago - Epic Dragon Battle (9450) 5.0 Website Price:  $149.99
	</body>
</document>
