<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004857" url="http://www.caradvice.com.au/71306/car-buying-advice-getting-the-best-deal/" time="2012-07-12-21:22" support="3" score="0.0029409452748360505" bingtitle="Car Buying Advice – Getting the best deal | Car Advice" webtitle="Car Buying Advice - Getting the best dealCarAdvice">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001178" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>First, make sure the car you want is in stock now – once the ... eg a $12,990.00 drive away price has no were near 5% ... No purchase, no payment and the broke makes nothing.</description>
	<body>
		CarAdvice.com.au
 
Car Advice
 Home Car Reviews 
 Car Comparisons Reader Reviews 
 Car News 
 Last 30 Days 
 Showrooms 
 Galleries 
 Videos Best Price Classifieds Login Email: Password: Forgot your password? Login using: New to Car Advice? Register here Close 
 Home »  Car Buying Advice–Getting the best deal 
 
Car Buying Advice–Getting the best deal
 
 Article Gallery 
 By John Cadogan | June 23rd, 2010 Tweet Print page 88 
At the time of writing, it’s one week until the ref blows the whistle on the 2009/2010 financial year. This is a crucial time for the car industry – and also a great time to need a new car. It’s the perfect time to secure a real bargain if you’re in the market for a new car. (It’s not a necessarily good time to buy a car for it’s own sake, but it’s a great time to buy one if you need one.)

 

 Three good reasons there: 

First, if you’re a business, you can usually claim a 30 per cent tax deduction for the depreciation of the car – in this financial year, even if you own it only for a few days. If you wait until July 1 (or after) to buy, you have to wait until June 30, 2011, for that 30 per cent deduction.

 

Second, car dealers are under pressure to make their sales targets. Many people don’t realize that most car dealers are independently owned businesses, which receive hefty and generally undisclosed incentives from the parent car companies if they meet or exceed their targets. So if you can find a car dealer who is just shy of his target, a hard bargain can often be driven towards the end of the month. What they potentially lose on your sale is often more than adequately recouped in target-meeting incentives.

Lastly, June is traditionally a high sales month, driven by businesses taking advantage of the depreciation allowance mentioned above. However, in this financial year many of those sales happened back in December, thanks to the Federal Government’s stimulus package, which gave businesses an extra 50 per cent deduction provided they bought capital equipment by 31 December 2009. So a lot of businesses brought their car purchases forward six months – and if they did that, well, they’re not in the market now. What was great news in December has become June’s problem.

 

All this means it’s a great time to buy, for the next week, provided you’ve got the cash. But how do you drive a really sharp bargain? First, make sure the car you want is in stock now – once the dealer has it on the floor or in his holding yard, it’s his problem – he’s already bought it from the car company, and he’s paying the interest on it. There’s no real point in trying to bargain hard on a car that there’s a four-week wait on. If a car is in stock, you might have to put up with buying a colour or trim level that’s not your first choice. You also must have the cash or the finance ready to go. You can use the dealer’s finance if the rate is right, but be aware that the dealership earns a commission from the finance, so you can use your acceptance of their finance as a bargaining incentive for an even sharper price. Leave your trade-in at home, seeing as high trade-in offers are used sometimes to confuse the deal’s fundamentals, and ask the drive-away price on the car. Subtract 10-15 per cent from that and see how you go – you might have to try more than one dealership to get your sharp price across the line, but if you shave 10 per cent off a $30k car, well, that’s not a bad afternoon’s work.

Lastly, and most importantly, target the right cars. According to Vfacts official industry sales figures, the market in general is up about 20 per cent for the five months to May 2010. Wouldn’t it be good if you could short-list the good cars in the market that bucked that trend and, for various reasons, were (say) 20 per cent down in sales? This would be a fair bit of work, and you’d need access to information not generally made readily accessible to the public. Don’t stress about these last two points – because I just finished that research. Keep reading.

 

These cars are the ones you can bet are generally in over-supply at the moment and shifting slowly. Dealers will generally be having a hard time moving them, and they’ll be overjoyed, in general, if you front up and make the right inquisitive noises – and the price is probably a lot more flexible than it would be on the market’s hot sellers right now.

The protocols here are that if the market’s up 20 per cent overall, these cars had to be down 20 per cent, compared with the 12 months to May 2009. They also had to be good cars – nothing I couldn’t put my hand on my heart and recommend to a friend is in that list. So that meant, arbitrarily, no Italian cars, and only one French car (‘good’ for me means more than just enjoying the driving; it’s also about being confident you could own them after the warranty runs out…but this is a personal prejudice – plenty of other cars in the market meet my ’20 per cent off the pace’ criteria; I just wouldn’t recommend them to a mate. It also meant not buying into a depreciation disaster.)

 Here are the cars: 

In the light segment, the best target is the Honda City. It’s 34 per cent off the pace to May this year, with only 860-odd sales as opposed to 1290-odd for the same five-month period in 2009. The Mitsubishi Colt is a solid proposition for a red-hot bargain – its sales are 41 per cent down. And the Peugeot 207 finds itself in a trend-bucking hole – with sales nosediving 27 per cent compared with last year.

 

The standout under-achiever in small cars is the Focus – 25 per cent fewer sales this year to May 2010 with 3900-odd sales as opposed to 2009’s 5200. Don’t kid there’s not the odd over-stocked Ford dealer out there begging for your attention right about now.

 

Nothing in the medium segment really stands out, but the Honda Accord Euro is selling 15 per cent less than 2009, so far this year, and Honda’s sales are generally below what the company would prefer – so while the Euro doesn’t quite meet the ‘20 per cent down’ criteria, it’s the best target in the medium segment, as well as a damn good driver’s car.

 

Large car? Think Honda Accord – the bigger of the two Accords, built in Thailand. It’s down 35 per cent this year so far, with only 1800-odd sales to May versus 2800 for the same period last year. A ripe target, with the V6 even featuring cylinder deactivation to boost economy on highway runs. If you’re more a ‘pimp my ride’ purchaser the Chrysler 300C has fallen into a 40 per cent sales slump this year, and even the Statesman is 21 per cent down – both admirable hard-bargaining propositions.

 

Premium large car? Think Mercedes-Benz CLS. The four-door coupe is on a massive 59 per cent slide so far this year with only 31 sales to May, against 76 last year to May. Potential for a big-buck bargain there.

 

People-mover? ‘Yawn’ is the sentiment most commonly expressed over this segment, but if you’ve got more than three kids they’re actually a lot more practical than SUVs – and the Mitsubishi Grandis is a massive 46 per cent down on sales. Up in the premium end of this field, the Chrysler Voyager is also 29 per cent down.

 

If you want a sports car, the venerated RX8 is a staggering 47 per cent down this year, and the polish seems to have come off Volkswagen’s uber-clever EOS coupe, which is 36 per cent down. Remember, the market overall is up 20 per cent.

 

Among compact and large SUVs there’s really nothing that shouts ‘bargain’. Those segments are selling like the house is on fire. But in medium SUVs, the Nissan Pathfinder is crying out for help – its sales are 69 per cent on the nose for the periods in question.

 

Luxury SUVs offer up a couple of high-priced surprises: the X6 (kooky design mistake perhaps?), which is 33 per cent behind last year’s eight-ball, and the mighty Porsche Cayenne, off the pace 29 per cent.

 

Need a 2WD ute, mate? Holden’s Colorado is on the nose, sales-wise, at least – down 36 per cent. The Mazda BT-50 stinks as well, though not to the same degree. It’s down 21 per cent.

 

Lastly, if you’ve got $200,000 or more burning a hole in your rather large pockets (and who doesn’t?) there are three hot targets. The sensational Audi R8 has sold just seven units this year – against 22 for the first five months of 2009. That’s a staggering 68 per cent sales slide. (This could be a market saturation or availability thing.) And two very desirable – and very different – Mercedes-Benzes appeared to have stalled. The big, fat … and yet incomprehensibly sleek … CL (think: S Class coupe) is 47 per cent behind in sales volume so far this year (eight sales in 2010 Vs 15 in the first five months of 2009). And the amazingly elegant SL is 48 per cent on the nose, with 16 sales in 2010 against 31 for the five months to May 2009.

 

Happy hunting. And if there are any rich widows out there who need assistance securing the best possible deal on a CL 65 AMG, and then running it in, drop me a line.
 
  
 Car Advice Editor&apos;s Column 
 Tweet Print page 
 Roman 
Nice little article. However, has anyone else noticed that when you point out these sorts of facts to some salespeople, they (unsurprisingly) deny it?
 
 http://www.facebook.com/sammo.8191 Sam Moss 
Is there such thing as a good car salesman? At least from my experience there isn’t..
 
 Andrew M 
Yes,
A good car salesman is someone who sells you a car for the most dollars they can get out of you.

Just because they arent on your side doesnt mean they arent good at what they do.
 
 http://carAdvice The Salesman 
Sam Moss……….
Your comment should be immediately erased.
All you are proving is how completely un educated and cave man like your brain is. I am a Car Salesman. I have the highest customer satisfaction rating in my field. Most of my business is from repeat and referral customers.
I am also a father and husband. A job I am also very good at.
 
 John Cadogan 
I reckon there are more good car salesmen than unethical crooks. Car salesmen get a bad rap—but you’re not alone. Try being a journalist…
 Andrew M 
ease up TS,

Sam clearly said he has never met what he terms a good one.
He never said you werent a good one.

I reckon you should have your comment removed for giving yourself one of the biggest pats on the back Ive seen in a while
 http://www.facebook.com/sammo.8191 Sam Moss 
Thanks for that rather self-indulgent comment Mr Salesman, I would expect nothing more coming from somebody like yourself. You seem to take anything that anybody says on here personally and get all defensive, let’s hope that you don’t do the same in your workplace!

If you read my original post, I said that IN MY EXPERIENCE there isn’t such thing as a good car salesman. As I have a reasonably thorough knowledge of cars, I have advised not only my parents but other family members as to their next vehicle purchase. As a consequence of this, I have dealt with a number of car salespeople over the past few years. I have found that, apart from maybe one or two exceptions, the vast majority of new vehicle salespeople that I have interacted with have been disappointingly unprofessional, self-indulgent and not knowledgeable at all on some of the vehicles that they were trying to sell, constantly referring to brochures for information.

Of course, as I reside in Perth, these comments of mine are made within the context of the Western Australian market, and the case may be, simply put, that WA is lacking talent in the new car sales field. Would you have any comments or knowledge to add regarding this Salesman? In fact, the man who sold my parents their new car,(who was a true professional, and actually did his job properly), recently left WA to seek employment with Peugeot in Melbourne–so this perhaps proves my theory.

For the record, I am 19 and studying at university. To say that my brain is‘uneducated’and‘caveman-like’(note the correct punctuation), I think would be somewhat inaccurate…
 Tyson 
Samo in your 19 years on this earth how many new cars have you purchased to form your opinion so concisley?
 
 
 http://carAdvice The Salesman 
Where in this article is their any reference to Salespeople?
 stinka 
thats because you are probably one of those d$%Kheads that come in all guns blazing expecting our best price and you havent even as much as gone on a drive yet , if you took the time out to try and be nice to the so called sales man you know you might actually get along with them and therefore score yourself a cracker of a deal. maybe try that next time youre looking for a car be a friend to them and they will try and help you.
 
 DB 
Could not have said it better
 
 
 Yawn@sickofsalesman 
maybe because most people read an article like this and they instantly become an expert
 
 JimboJones 
Ladies and Gentlemen, bow down: the 19YO university student has spoken! Discussion–over!

LOL!
 
 
 Peter 
Great helpful article! You’ve got a picture of the Mercedes CLC when you mentioned the CLS, how are the sales for the CLC going anyway?
 http://www.facebook.com/sammo.8191 Sam Moss 
What a great article, a great insight into the current market!

I’m currently saving up for a car (hopefully a new one, maybe a 207 fingers crossed!!), however it’s a pity that I’m not quite at the level of cash that I’d like to be at this stage. Hopefully in a years time the situation in the new car market will be similar and there will be some more bargains to be found!

Also, I’m not surprised about the Honda City’s declining sales, it’s so over-priced and you may as well step up to the Civic, unless of course you like the look. Hondas in general are lacking in that‘value’side of the equation that people expect from Japanese and Asian cars, and that makes their range far less desirable in my opinion.
 
 Simon 
True! Also Honda almost has no“performance”offerings unlike the Acura branding in the USA. Acura also recently came second (only to porsche) in a J D Power reliability survey. Why is Australia a motoring backwater?
 
 Tinman 
Steering wheel is on the wrong side in Australia and our marketplace is too small=backwater.
 
 
 MattP 
In my opinion, the impending release of the SLS explains the reduction in SL and CL sales.

If I was interested in a CL or SL Benz I would certainly not buy one if, for a lot of extra $$, I could buy an SLS which gets released in Australia next month.
 
 Joe 
Have you seen how much the SLS is compared to the CL and SL?

Those buying SL’s and CL’s aren’t even considering the SLS.
 
 MattP 
@Joe, are you absolutely positive that every single potential purchaser of an SL or CL is not considering an SLS instead?

I personally know some who are in that league and the SLS is a serious consideration for them.
 
 
 Andrew M 
Question,
Is the 30%/50% tax break still going??

I thought the tax breaks ended dec last year….
 
 John Cadogan 
The 50 per cent tax break is gone. It was a sales incentive part of the economic stimulus package following the financial crisis. The 30 per cent depreciation allowance has been with us for years, and it remains today.
 
 AAA 
Are they going to suddenly drop $2000-$3000 because of the EOFY? No.
 
 Andrew M 
The end of any month is key to getting the extra couple of K knocked off, not just EOFY.

You wont get any better deal on June 30 than you would on 31st May
 
 stinka 
thats true
 
 
 Ryan 
Sorry to be a party pooper. But with your depreciation comment, it sort of implies you will be able to claim full 30% depreciation on the car for the whole year of you buy it in the last week. That’s not the case. You will only be able to claim X% depreciation proportioned for the amount of days you have owned it during the 2010 financial year. So if you buy a car on the 23rd od june, you will only claim 7/365 of the depreciation on the car, as you’ve only owned it for 7 days.
 
 John Cadogan 
Ryan, That’s outdated rubbish. I’d suggest you should get your facts straight of speak to an accountant. (I did in the research for this story.) Small businesses are allowed to claim the full whack of 30 per cent without the pro-rata conversion you claim. That was part of the post-gst tax reform. Big businesses have to pro-rata the depreciation. Small businesses don’t.
 
 Dan 
John, while I don’t disagree with you, the comment you made about the depreciation in the article was too general. Agreed, small business can choose to use subdivision 328-D of the 1997 tax act and claim straight 30% deprecion without taking into account the length of ownership during the year. But they have to make that choice. Otherwise normal depreciation rules apply. You mentioned that‘business’can claim depreciation on that basis, which can be a bit misleading. Perhaps add‘small’in front of the‘business’and mention something that the availability of it may depend on individual circumstances also.
 
 Andrew M 
I agree, the depreciation statement was too general.

Thats why I thought it may have been implying the 50/30% tax break may have been confused with the issue
 
 John Cadogan 
OK. Fair enough. Agreed: Subject to individual circumstances, many small businesses can take advantage of a 30 per cent deduction in this financial year.
 
 
 
 http://www.ahg.com.au Tyson 
you should be carefull that sounds alot like finacial advice? Are you liscened under FRSA to give such advise?
 
 http://carAdvice The Salesman 
How do you know what a good deal is?
In my experience this article is completely wrong. Dealers do have targets to meet, that’s true. But what makes you think they wait until the end of the month to achieve them? How many business besides the car sales industry are under pressure to achieve target volume sales?
If I go to an electric retailer at the end of the month will I get a better deal or just the left over’s that no one else wanted at a discounted price?
I love the list……want a bargain, buy into a market that is failing!!!!. Are you kidding me!!!. If a car is down 35% from target now what is the market going to be like when you need to sell it or trade it in?
Take my advice.
This is how to get a bargain.
Build a relationship with the salesperson and the dealer. Believe me if you are ready to buy a car the salesperson and the dealer will do everything they can to sell you a car before you leave.
If the dealer lets you leave you can be assured you now know the best possible price. No dealer will let you leave with a “Loaded Gun” to go shopping with.
 
 Andrew M 
Sort of true T/S, but electrical retailers dont get monthly sales bonuses. Electrical retailers also have to pay for their stock before they sell it (techniclly speaking, I know credit terms may apply)
 matt 
Thankyou, i too am a saleman and am sick of the rudest of rude demanding best price or i lose their buisiness without evan saying hello or responding to my goodmorning how are you. I agree with you TS build the relationship be polite and make friends, then buy a car.
 
 matt 
edit, make sure it is the car you want to buy and want to buy there and then, high pressure yes but you will get what you want rather than fish for best prices on car you dont yet want to own when you are not actually there to buy.
 
 Forza M 
I also work in the industry, young Sam makes some valid points about my peirs being pretty ordinary human beings. Having said that the salesman is right to tear up at that comment. I am a Sales Manager at a dealership, we are in the top 5 nationally, because we treat people with respect and offer good deals. What sh-ts me more than anything is to see rude people walk in to our showroom and when prompted with a hello we get nothing back.

At this point I make a point of burning those people on the spot. If you cant say hello then you are not welcome in my house simple as that, my staff and I are human beings afte all!

Two other things, yes they are cheap shots.
1. A person that is saving up for a 207 deserves to be treated badly by carsales people

2. Andy M as per usual you are talking about a subject you dont know. I know that many car companies have offered excellent deals for June which were not availalbe in May
 
 Yonny 
I have bought quite a few new cars in my time, so have dealt with a lot of salesmen and a lot of sales managers.

But I dealt with the worst sales manager of all time late last year, at a big car dealership in the ACT. I was looking to buy a new car and wanted a trade-in price on my existing car. I was taken in to see the sales manager and the fat sack of sh!t wouldn’t even get out of his chair to waddle out to the forecourt–he said I had to agree to buy a car before he’d give a trade-in price. I could not believe it–the last time that happened to me was 30 years ago, and I didn’t think it still happened. And this wasn’t some dinky little car place either–it was one of Canberra’s biggest dealers selling a popular Japanese brand. I can’t believe that the dealer principal approved of those sorts of tactics–but perhaps he does……..

I bought my car, but not from that dealer.
 
 
 
 
 SellingCars! 
“Subtract 10-15 per cent from that and see how you go”
^^^Where did you get this number from? Seems like you just picked a random %

@The Salesman.
Your last paragraph seems to be the best advice here&gt;

seems most poeple think“shopping around”is the best thing todo. But no dealer is going to pull his pants down then let you leave. Remember they have seen it all befor
 
 John Cadogan 
No, mate. I didn’t just pick a random percentage. I did this wearing a hidden camera on A Current Affair—six times. There were, oh, only about two million witnesses. It works. You seem to be full of it in this case.
 
 Radbloke 
A Current Affair–That shining beacon of respectable investigative journalism and hard hitting reports.
 
 John Cadogan 
…which is exactly why I moved to Today Tonight. Actually, in motoring, both shows do a fair bit of good, solid journalism in the public interest. You have to watch closely for it, however, in between the‘which oven-baked fries are healthiest’,‘latest underwear technology development’and‘rip-off merchant’stories. And they’re consistently watched by 10 per cent of the population, so you can scoff if you want, but if you want to cut through to mainstream Australians you have to be on them. (The world’s not perfect.) In the past 5-10 years we’ve done things like call for ESC to be made standard on new cars, explained why premium tyres are worth the extra investment, showed why advanced driving courses are worthwhile, etc. (And, yes, done some‘fluff’stories as well.)
 
 Joe 
Today Tonight.. even more respectable than A Current Affair!

(I don’t think you can see my eyes rolling over the internet).
 Forza M 
Joe Joe Joe,

Very well said my friend, i just realised who this John Cadogen guy is. The bloke the car industry laughs at every time he gets on the TV. Keep it going Johnny you are great value!!!
 
 
 
 
 John Cadogan 
That’s outdated rubbish. I’d suggest you should get your facts straight of speak to an accountant. (I did in the research for this story.) Small businesses are allowed to claim the full whack of 30 per cent without the pro-rata conversion you claim. That was part of the post-gst tax reform. Big businesses have to pro-rata the depreciation.
 http://carAdvice The Salesman 
10% or 15% Sure….but from what price? The dealer is in part obliged to advertise drive away pricing set out by the manufacturer. For example.

$14,990.00 RRP
$ 450.00 Stamp Duty
$ 331.00 Rego
$ 347.00 C.T.P
$ 2195.00 Dealer Delivery
$18,313.00 Sub Total
$ 5,323.00 Over Allowance
$12,990.00 Drive Away

That’s more like 30% off the recommended retail drive away price.

I am sure you will find in the most part the drive away deal offered is based on volume of sales more than % of profit.
 
 John Cadogan 
I said:“ask the drive-away price on the car. Subtract 10-15 per cent from that”. I think that’s pretty clear. But, for the slow learners: The drive away price minus 10-15 per cent. D’oh!
 
 http://carAdvice The Salesman 
I doubt that. eg a $12,990.00 drive away price has no were near 5% margin.
Alot of puffery in that statement.
Dealers just dont have that much margin.
 
 JEKYL&amp;HYDE 
AGREE SALESMAN,

This bloke john c has only spent time to one side of the fence.maybe he could spend some time with you,then he will realise that there is sometimes alot more money in a t.v.(in real dollar terms,not percentage)than a $14k (or $38k for that matter)drive away car…
 
 John Cadogan 
Yes, I agree–not. That explains all the homeless car dealers in the country, then. Every time I’m at a dealer event there are more S Classes in valet parking and more Rolexes in the room than most people have ever seen. And fair enough–car dealers should make a profit…but equally consumers should get a fair deal. Sick of hearing how tough it is for most dealers; that’s rubbish.
 stinka 
mate your a tosser , i work in the car sales industry and i can tell you now when the cars are on sale at drive away prices , we are lucky to have $500 profit in each car at best. The dealers make their money in the back end from servicing and parts. Put the cars at full retail and yeah there might just be 10% to play with but 10 to 15 at heavily discounted drive away campaigns i think youve been smoking ice or something. Your so called research adds up to jack s$&amp;t to me.
 http://www.ahg.com.au Tyson 
Sarcasm in your own article Mr Cadogan? Poor form! Can you not accept that your article has been porley researched and written?
 
 
 
 
 Juzzy 
Great article John–I just bought a new car and I definately got a better deal because of the time of (fin)year.
 
 John Cadogan 
Thanks for the feedback. Good on you for getting a good deal.
 
 Fenno 
Also, Dont be afraid to Haggle on old Stock (ie 09 plates)
Another good time To squeeze those last few bucks out of a Sales Manager is Saturday afternoon. Might sound silly but 10 years in a dealership and I’ve seen the silliest deals done then.
 
 John Cadogan 
Great advice there, Fenno—I never thought of those two points. Thanks for the tip.
 Dan 
Buying a new car that is already one year old, you’d expect to get a better deal on it, given it is already one year old…
 mr fandangle 
why dont you tell the world so you cant make any money
 
 http://www.zupps.com.au Sales Specialist 
The fact you have been on a ACA John does not mean it is fact. Apart from the fact ACA sensationalise everything, did you acually purchase at least 1 car at 10-15% off? And I guess if you did Iit would be something with massive factory bonuses because its an 09 model that can’t sell in any market. Chrysler for instance may advertise $10grand off a 300c doesn’t mean that all cars will have that same margin. FACT is most cars have 6-8% margin, they also have whats called“holdback”, which is at best several hundred dollars for selling your own stock. Yes dealers get bonuses for numbers being met(targets) but you have to achieve a high NPS/CSI(customer satisfaction) and given the fact everyone“bags”car salespeople, we often never achieve this. So as The Carsalesman says, build a relationship with your local dealer, have some respect for sales people(they are people too), and be HONEST. Tell them what you would like to spend. If you keep everything a secret, how car they help you get a deal. And John, considering you work off the back of the motor industry, you should support it better. Without it you dont have a job pal!
 
 stinka 
here here very well put mate i couldnt agree with you more
 
 Claffz 
Be careful assuming there is 10-15% left in the drive-away prices of all cars, i work for a dealer selling a brand where the margins on drive-away prices are tiny.

What probably should have been said is at least 10-15% off the RRP plus on roads.

Drive away prices can be discounted already.

I think it’s a bit dangerous for us with this kind of information coming from such a respectable source (ie. i dont doubt i’ll have somebody making reference to this article come through this week)
 
 John Cadogan 
Guys, for the record, I didn’t mean a drive-away sale price, which is obviously discounted already. I meant the drive away price that is RRP plus on-roads. Apologies if there’s a misunderstanding there.
 
 stinka 
if you did your study as you say to get the so called facts you have you would be quite aware that every single brand on the market at this time of year has drive away campaigns running.
 http://CarAdvice The Salesman 
Here is the thing John. You did say that. Can you say busted????

June 24, 2010 at 3:29 pm

I said: “ask the drive-away price on the car. Subtract 10-15 per cent from that”. I think that’s pretty clear. But, for the slow learners: The drive away price minus 10-15 per cent. D’oh!
 
 AlsoSellingCars 
The dealer i work for has 500 in a 11990–12990 drive away car. same applies when u spec the car up to a 15990 car. But people still seem to think we will have thousands to play with.
 
 Rick 
For the sales consultants on the post, would you say the end of month deals/saturday arvo deals apply for a used car?

I am looking to buy a luxury used car (1 or 2yr old)–should I buy now or does it matter if I decide to buy at a month’s end? Cheers!
 
 matt 
To a point yes, if they haven’t sold a thing for the day then yes Saturday arvo is a good idea, but not too late, we do have a life and want to go home at some point aswell, so if they close at 5 try to avoid heading inat 4:45.
 
 http://CarAdvice The Salesman 
I wouldn’t say it matters. The cart still owes you the same amount of money @ 5.00pm that it did @ 8.00am.
If it is an old stock car then the dealer would re visit the price and adjust to suit the market.
You have to know the real bargains don’t stay in stock long.
 
 
 Mazda salesperson 
Try getting 10-15% on a few Mazdas .. .. it’s not gonna happen. Some of their models only have 0.05% margin in it!
 
 Zombieland 
Not true. Wife recently bought a Mazda3 Maxx Sport hatch. We already had a relationship with the dealer, and received over $3k off the sticker price. This equated to slightly over 10% and done with vitrually no haggling. The relationship is key if they know you’re definitely going to buy.
 stinka 
to the mazda salesperson , what a crock of s$&amp;t my mate runs a mazda yard and i can tell you most of the cars start with a very nice drink in them , its just they are very firm with their pricing and use the good old resale line and we are not a discount brand line to keep money in their pockets , the only one that doesnt have much margin is the 2
 
 http://CarAdvice The Salesman 
Spot on. Honda is the same…….
 
 
 http://www.ahg.com.au Tyson 
John Cadogan,

You where responsible for that horrific bit of Journalism with Today Tonight?

With your so called results, shaking a salespersons hand on a price and walking out? How do you know it’s a deal? It never went to management, you approached the whole thing with a level of such childishness that I had to laugh.

Service is paramount; if you walk in a demand the best price then you are not going to get it. Earn it through negotiation.

10% off the RRP Drive away is achievable.

Your targeted cars are a little skew if in the point of view for being down in sales, take for example the pathfinder, where there is a massive wait due to the factory not being able to supply. Cars that have been undersold are generally put on a drive away campaign as a result of slowing sales, take for example your Focus; try and get one, there are next to none available at the moment.

The motor industry will generally react to this faster than your article written at the end of a financial year.

If you want a good deal, pick a car that is in stock or easily obtained, I agree on this point.

Negotiate for 10-15% off the recommended retail. If you can achieve this, and they let you walk, then the margin isn’t there for the level of discount, we are in the business of selling cars, not wasting time. So if they let you walk it’s generally a good price (although un achievable).

Be courteous, be friendly, the experience can be a good one if the customer allows it to be. Pen to paper and negotiation. That is the key to buying a car.
 The dealer 
Mr Cadogan You are no doubt an Industry expert Hey who can argue with Today tonight and ACA you would also be aware that the industry benchmark for a dealership is a return on investment of approx 2.5 %, you can get a better return by putting money in a fixed term deposit. But you wouldn’t have a business and you wouldn’t employ up to a couple hundred people. I agree with everyone here that has said build a relationship with your salesman, if he is rude or dosen’t provide the service go to another dealer. Negotiate a deal that you think is good and are happy with, not what some“expert”tells you is a good deal
 
 JEKYL&amp;HYDE 
more truth…

john,get the chip off your shoulder.there are far bigger rolex wearing,merc driving“vultures”out there than“old money”car dealership owners.DO what i said before,spend a week with“the salesman”.write an article about it,prove your worth as a jurno,or continue around the track with“the blinkers on”.
 
 http://www.zupps.com.au Sales Specialist 
John, seems like you opened a can of worms here!! Many industry people can\’t all be \”LYING\”. All dealers/manufacturers must advertise all new cars inclusive of on-road costs, that means all new cars are DRIVE-AWAY!!! The main thing said here that is common between industry people is that there is no one size fits all discount.There are many variables, what segment its in,brand and availability, but in short people, if a dealer has the car you want in stock, then a deal can be negotiated, at what price, that depends on the model, but if you are hearing a few dealers at the same figure, go back to your local dealer and ask him to \”sweeten\”(i.e. mats)the deal to keep you in his PMA(area). Its no point negotiating on a car that unavailable or forward order. If you upfront, and genuinely ready to buy, any dealer will gladly put his best deal forward. How about a story from our end John, \”How the Salesman gets screwed\”……
 Forza M 
Dear car advice, it is very very disappointing to see this person writing for you, you website is read by not only car lovers but industry people, who at this point would be shaking their heads like I am.
 Flying High 
It is interesting that the car sales people here advise to‘build a relationship’with a dealer.

Whilst being polite in any purchase should be a given (sadly in many cases, customers leave their manners in the gutter from whence they were learned) it can be difficult for the average punter to build a relationship with a dealer, whom they might see once every 5, 7 or even 10 years. And whilst some may trust their local dealer for servicing in which a relationship might be built, the more savvy car purchasers would not touch some of the service departments with a barge pole. Further to that, the‘service’component of the dealership and the‘sales people’often might not even work in the same suburb, much less know who is getting serviced by whom.

Some comments expressed here might suggest that car sales people are either very honest straight shooters who only want the best for you and would never screw you over, to bottom dwelling scum suckers who would throw in their first and last born if it meant closing a deal. I know from personal experience the reality is somewhere in between, with degrees of car sales people leaning one way or another. Some know everything about a car, some couldn’t tell you if it was a sedan or a dishwasher. Some talk to a woman if she is to be the primary driver, others will only talk to a male, even if he was her 10 y.o. son

I would suggest that whilst you may find an odd bargain yourself, the better option in many cases is to simply employ the services of a car broker–who can and does build a relationship with the car dealers. You save yourself the hassle, and depending on the broker, a car will be given to you with a full tank, a simple but so oft neglected gesture.

Good luck with your future sales or purchases, which ever side of the fence you sit on.
 
 Flying High 
Salesman, in most cases, the purchaser does not actually have to pay the car broker directly. The price you pay is inclusive of any fees and if the total is more expensive than you could do yourself, you would not use them. They will offer you a price and it is then up to you to decide to purchase. No purchase, no payment and the broke makes nothing. Surely in your line of work, you would have to provide prices to brokers who are acting on behalf of their clients? If brokers could not beat the best price you get, they might not be in business for too long.
 mrfandangle 
let me guess your a car broker ,a typical car broker does f$%K all but puts his hand out to make an even better commission than what us sales reps get , car brokers in my experience are a bunch of parrasites who charge about $400 to do what the client can do on their own. on another note the car industry has brought this on themselves for running campaigns month after month so now the public expect deals non stop
 
 Flying High 
No, please, let me guess, you are a great wally.

in fact I am not a car broker, not even close. But thanks for your refreshing remarks on the people who are. Personally, I have made use of them in the past and would certainly consider using them again. Once again, no purchase, no cost. And if they cannot beat your best negotiated price they wont stay in the broking market for long.

You are however, right about the car industry bringing this on itself. Simply put, the average punter has little faith they will be offered a good deal, and often find the overall experience less than pleasant.
 
 
 http://CarAdvice The Salesman 
Why pay a car broker for a job you can do yourself?
 
 Flying High 
wrong reply button! as per above 
 buyer 
You know, I’ve often asked the same question about the‘dealer delivery’charge.
 
 http://www.ahg.com.au Tyson 
In some Cases“buyer”, The Only Profit in a car is the dealer delivery!
 
 
 http://www.esteemtrucks.com/ Jack 
I am just entering into the automotive world and i found that their is too much to explore…..i like your article….i hope to see some good post like this coming out often…..its helpful……
 matt 
John, if what you were saying is fair for both parties, then you really need to have a look over the other side of the fence. If i as a prestige salesman have someone come in and in a rude manner ask for my best price, i am not interested in wasting my time on them as some other desperate volume focused yard will undercut us anyway. i am constantly breaking sales records by avoiding the zombie wankers like you create (these people once had manners) and concentrating on someone who acknowledges firstly that i am a human being and secondly that if they talk about their needs i will meet them and if they get a good deal, it wont be 10-15%, that is fair for them not me, that would be an $80 deal for months work in some cases. How much do you get paid for showing your mug on Today Affair? Lets all write articles about exposing“journalists”for speaking shit 24/7,then the industry that has supported you John will bite back and will that then be a fair deal for you pal???? Dick.
 AlsoSellingCars 
Hey John ever thought of doing a TT or ACA story on aftermarket?

Seems you can save the most money buying a new car by avoiding the aftermarket girl.
 matt 
well, i think its a good article, and both sides off this argument need to understand…yes there are dipsh!t salesmen who dont deserve to be given even a“hello”and to the writer its wrong to generalise the industry workers like that i guess. each to their own, whoever you buy a car off, make sure they deserve your business,and return to them if you have a pleasent experience. These are expensive purchases though, and you cannot expect people to NOT haggel
 
 
CAR SEARCH

Search for car reviews, specifications and photo galleries by make and model.
 Make ALFA ROMEO ASTON MARTIN AUDI BENTLEY BMW BUGATTI CHRYSLER CITROEN DODGE FERRARI FIAT FORD GREAT WALL MOTORS HOLDEN HONDA HSV HUMMER HYUNDAI ISUZU JAGUAR JEEP KIA LAMBORGHINI LAND ROVER LEXUS LOTUS MAHINDRA MASERATI MAZDA MERCEDES-BENZ MINI MITSUBISHI NISSAN PAGANI PEUGEOT PORSCHE PROTON RANGE ROVER RENAULT ROLLS-ROYCE SAAB SKODA SMART SSANGYONG SUBARU SUZUKI TATA TOYOTA VOLKSWAGEN VOLVO Model &gt;&gt;Advanced options 
Advanced Options
 Price Range: Body Type: 
 4x4 Convertible Coupe Hatch People Mover SUV Sedan Sports Truck/Bus UTE VAN Wagon 
 
 Most Commented Recent Comments 
 
Showrooms
 
 
 Show All» 
 Car News News Archive Videos Classifieds 
 
 Car Reviews Reader Reviews Car Comparisons 
 
 About Us Contact Us Advertise with us Found an error? Star Ratings 
 
 Follow us on: Facebook Twitter YouTube 
 Find your next car on CarBuddy.com.au Copyright 2006-2012 |
CarAdvice.com.au Pty Ltd |
ABN: 84 116 608 158 | Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
