<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004398" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/38/1414029/restaurant/Southwest/New-England-Seafood-Charlotte" time="2012-07-12-20:38" support="4" score="0.005666791338515654" bingtitle="New England Seafood - Southwest - Charlotte | Urbanspoon" webtitle="New England Seafood - Southwest - Charlotte | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>The place doesn&apos;t look like much on the outside ... New England Seafoad is not a fast food restaurant - it is a ... we saw a sign for New England Seafood near exit ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Charlotte » Charlotte » Southwest » New England Seafood 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Atlanta Charleston Knoxville Los Angeles New York Research Triangle Richmond More... 
 
New England Seafood
 
(704) 527-2188
 Southwest 7825 Nations Ford Rd 
 Charlotte , NC 28217 
 newenglandseafoodcharlotte... 
 See all 18 reviews Cuisine Seafood , American , Southern/Soul Feature Kid Friendly Menu $$ $10-15 per entree Croaker, Perch, Whiting, Salt And Pepper Catfish, Alaskan White Fish... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch             Dinner             Late 
   47 people have voted 91 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Rusty&apos;s Deli&amp;Grille 96% $ South Charlotte - Sandwiches/Subs 8512 Park Rd 
 
 Terrace Cafe 85% $$$ Southpark - Breakfast/Brunch, American, Southern/Soul 4625 Piedmont Row Dr, Ste 105 
 
Critic reviews

 July 29, 2008 Charlotte Observer Would you choose classic fish and chips or Southern-style salt-and-pepper catfish when you want seafood?Would you... More from Charlotte Observer 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 1, 2012 Likes it Fish Sandwich... by D Cooper ( 33 reviews ) Fish Sandwich w/mac n cheese and coleslaw -
I stopped in this afternoon to try the big boy fish sandwich. The owner greeted me with a handshake,this is how all business owners should treat customers...I hope nothing but the best for this restaurant.!! I asked for salt/pepper batter on my flounder along with a side of cole slaw and mac n cheese. Everything was great and I will return when in the area. +1 more review from D Cooper April 23, 2012 Big ol&apos; Shrimps Shrimp dinner - From the road this place does not look like much,but once you enter it is clean and the team working there are great. Interesting trivia facts on the walls, I learned a few things I did not know. Croaker,catfish,cod,clams,big ol shrimp and more... After a quick chat with the guy behind the counter,I decided on the&quot;big ol&apos; shrimp&quot;he said he had. 10 of the biggest shrimp I have had in a long time,fried in a homemade salt/pepper batter that was perfect. Homemade coleslaw and... more» From the road this place does not look like much,but once you enter it is clean and the team working there are great. Interesting trivia facts on the walls, I learned a few things I did not know. Croaker,catfish,cod,clams,big ol shrimp and more... After a quick chat with the guy behind the counter,I decided on the&quot;big ol&apos; shrimp&quot;he said he had. 10 of the biggest shrimp I have had in a long time,fried in a homemade salt/pepper batter that was perfect. Homemade coleslaw and baked beans along with 3 homemade hushpuppies,not the frozen kind. The guy behind the counter then came over and sat down at my table and we chatted for a bit and he also happened to be the owner. I was impressed with the food and even more so with the friendliness of the owner and the lady (wife??) team. If you like fried seafood,give this place a try. March 29, 2012 yummm by Laura Heckman ( 1 review ) tried out this place for lunch today...who would have guessed it was so close to my work and yet i&apos;d never heard of it. VERY good fish basket! Not much for grease but the breading was so good and everything looked better on the table than it did in the photos. WILL be back! March 5, 2012 Likes it Great Seafood / Nice Owner by Mark M. ( 1 review ) I ate at New England Seafood for the first time today. Found it by accident while Googling for Fresh seafood in Charlotte. After reading the reviews I gave it a shot and I&apos;m glad I did. The congenial owner, Mitch, steered me into what to order and I had a fried seafood platter that came with flounder, shrimp, scallops, and oysters. Also fries, slaw, and hushpuppies. Wow was it good! I had the fish prepared with one filet battered in a salt and pepper mixture and the other with a light, New England, fish and chip batter. Everything else was the salt and pepper mix. My personal preference is the salt and pepper, but the were both very good. My plate was piled high with food. I couldn&apos;t finish it! Everything is fresh and cooked to order. Watch out because when it comes to the table it is piping hot. The restaurant is in an old Hardee&apos;s location, but don&apos;t let that fool you. This is the real deal. My only regret is that they ran out of their New England chowder, but that&apos;s for next time! January 6, 2012 Likes it Excellent Seafood and Atmosphere! by Kathy ( 1 review ) My husband and I happened upon New England seafood last night and were pleasantly surprised. What an amazing find! The food and menu was excellent!! In addition, the volume of food for the price was a great value. Neither I nor my husband could finish the food we ordered and had to request a doggy bag for each of us! One of the things we liked the most was the friendliness of the owners. They made us and other customers feel like we were the most important customers they had! My husband and I will definitely return to this restaurant!! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 29, 2010 Likes it Surprising Fare by Plaineater ( 82 reviews ) What a pleasant surprise--an old Hardee&apos;s made into a burger-style seafood place, with real seafood and a variety. The staff was more than accommodating--even going next door to get soft drinks when their machine was empty. Mitch showed us the shrimp and scallops before we ordered and allowed us to mix our order with shrimp and scallops on one dinner plate. The serving is not elegant--plastic cutlery on a paper plate, but Mitch said that they&quot;decided to spend on the food not the serving pieces.&quot;We had an ample order of shrimp and scallops with good fries and slaw for about $12. Everything was very good. I complimented him on the quality of the catchup, but everything was really very good. Order at the counter, eat in a hamburg-like seating area, but enjoy very good seafood from a wide range of sources (from looking at the menu): shellfish and ocean fish. Sandwiches, too. Very good value for a quick lunch or dinner. We&apos;ll eat here again when in the area. May 15, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Daniel Goldman ( 13 reviews ) At first glance you might want to think that New England Seafood is a Captian D&apos;s kind of place. Don&apos;t be fooled. Although a few of the menu items are similar, you will find that New England Seafood is several steps above in quality and service. Everything is fresh and made to order. That is awesome considering that the food is flavorful and well thought out. I tried their signature&quot;big boy&quot;fish sandwich, and so did my wife. I got it in the country style which is a seasoned salt and pepper batter, and my wife tried the classic batter which was milder and more&quot;buttery&quot;. Both were perfect, and were not At all greacy. Perfect really. If you don&apos;t like fish, they have chicken dishes and kosher hotdogs. The seafood dishes have a great variety like : Catfish, croaker, flounder, perch, whiting, salmon, soft shell crab, shrimp, oysters, and clams. Some ecletic desserts include fried twinkees (! I&apos;m not brave enough!) fried Oreo sundae, and other more traditional... more» At first glance you might want to think that New England Seafood is a Captian D&apos;s kind of place. Don&apos;t be fooled. Although a few of the menu items are similar, you will find that New England Seafood is several steps above in quality and service. Everything is fresh and made to order. That is awesome considering that the food is flavorful and well thought out. I tried their signature&quot;big boy&quot;fish sandwich, and so did my wife. I got it in the country style which is a seasoned salt and pepper batter, and my wife tried the classic batter which was milder and more&quot;buttery&quot;. Both were perfect, and were not At all greacy. Perfect really. If you don&apos;t like fish, they have chicken dishes and kosher hotdogs. The seafood dishes have a great variety like : Catfish, croaker, flounder, perch, whiting, salmon, soft shell crab, shrimp, oysters, and clams. Some ecletic desserts include fried twinkees (! I&apos;m not brave enough!) fried Oreo sundae, and other more traditional desserts. Here&apos;s the rub tho: all of these delicious items are served fast food style but made to order. I guess this means that you get all the quality of a sit-down seafood resturaunt in half the time and for half the price. This place is nowhere near my home, but you can be assured I&apos;m making the drive again! February 8, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Sam ( 1 review ) This place is a great find! The food was fantastic and the owner extremely helpful and personable. The place doesn&apos;t look like much on the outside but dont let that stop you from checking it out. You&apos;ll be glad you did October 6, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Scott ( 7 reviews ) I used to go to Showmars when I needed a fish sandwich fix. No more! This is the place to be. Now, if only I could find a good lobster roll;) August 31, 2011 Likes it Wowsah!! by Sheryl ( 5 reviews ) What a hidden treasure this place is!! Fish is AMAZING. Everything cooked to order - can&apos;t wait to try more of the menu. Definitely going back - and SOON! April 1, 2011 Likes it William Gerald SC by William ( 1 review ) Had a chance to eat the food! It is over the top. The taste is beyound words and the service is family style and just great. I would say please go and enjoy the experience. You will be back. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful March 30, 2011 Worth the visit by Kelly ( 1 review ) From Connecticut and visited the Charlotte area. Was blown away by the fish&amp;chips and chowder at this place. You should check it out! March 29, 2011 Likes it Sh! dont tell everyone. by crazzy for fish ( 1 review ) Search is over, found the best fish&amp;chips, clam chowder, shrimp, and scallops in north carolina. place doesnt look like it is very busy for lunch. Im able to get in and out without getting back to work late. sh! best kept secret in charlotte. March 28, 2011 Likes it Good Food Fast by lynngprice ( 1 review ) New England Seafoad is not a fast food restaurant - it is a Great Restaurant that serves food fast. Best Seafood restaurant in Charlotte March 26, 2011 Really likes it Outstanding in every way!!! by Steve Roberts ( 1 review ) I&apos;m am a professional traveler, From Georgia and have been from coast to coast too many times to count. I grew up in a house that for lack of a better way of saying it are&quot;SEAFOOD SNOBS&quot;. as such I learned at a very young age you can not always judge the quality of the food being served by the out side of a building. To this day I can clearly remember waiting two or three hours to be seated at the ANCHOR INN in Daytona, mine and my fathers all time favorite. It has been closed now for many years and I have been looking for a Seafood resturant to tantalize my taste buds the way they were back then. After my second trip to New England Seafood off Nations Ford in Charlotte I feel I have found it. The seafood is well above the level that I have found in many higher end resturants, the mastery of the spices the mixture in the batters the seasoning in the homemade New England Clam Chowder, well you will not find better this side of Boston, Although it does not look... more» I&apos;m am a professional traveler, From Georgia and have been from coast to coast too many times to count. I grew up in a house that for lack of a better way of saying it are&quot;SEAFOOD SNOBS&quot;. as such I learned at a very young age you can not always judge the quality of the food being served by the out side of a building. To this day I can clearly remember waiting two or three hours to be seated at the ANCHOR INN in Daytona, mine and my fathers all time favorite. It has been closed now for many years and I have been looking for a Seafood resturant to tantalize my taste buds the way they were back then. After my second trip to New England Seafood off Nations Ford in Charlotte I feel I have found it. The seafood is well above the level that I have found in many higher end resturants, the mastery of the spices the mixture in the batters the seasoning in the homemade New England Clam Chowder, well you will not find better this side of Boston, Although it does not look like much from the outside the differece is found on your table. If you are a fan of fried seafood this is a must visit. Vistors to Charlotte do not let the outward prevent you from trying what I confidently say will be one of the more enjoyable eating experiences that your taste buds have had in some time. May 21, 2009 by Peter - Elizabeth Clark ( 1 review ) My husband&amp;I are from Canada, along with a relative from England, recently visited&quot;New England Seafood&quot;, in South Charlotte (Nations Ford Road) and would like you to know that we were very impressed with the service/friendliness we received from Mitch - he was very helpful indeed. We would also like to say that we really enjoyed the meal he recommended (the family special), it was excellent. We will certainly go back to the restaurant if we are ever in the area again. Well Done, and Many Thanks, Peter&amp;Elizabeth Clark, Ontario, Canada. April 10, 2009 What a Great Surprise by Renee Masters ( 1 review ) We arrived at Charlotte Airport from New Jersey at 8:30 PM on Wednesday, April 1 2009, and the agent at the rental car desk advised us to catch a bite to eat before reaching South Carolina because there were so few eateries once crossing the state line. As we drove down highway 77, we saw a sign for New England Seafood near exit 4 and it appeared to be less than half a mile from the highway. We took the exit, turned left, and we immediately saw the sign. With it being nearly 9 PM, there was only one other couple in the restaurant so we were a bit concerned that the food might not be good. But, we elected to give the establishment a chance. We went to the counter and spoke to Mitch, who we didn&apos;t realize was the owner. There was a large selection of fish and methods of preparation, so we weren&apos;t sure what to select. Mitch saw us struggling, and asked if he could help us make our selections. He asked us what we liked, what type of preparations we enjoy, and he picked up on... more» We arrived at Charlotte Airport from New Jersey at 8:30 PM on Wednesday, April 1 2009, and the agent at the rental car desk advised us to catch a bite to eat before reaching South Carolina because there were so few eateries once crossing the state line. As we drove down highway 77, we saw a sign for New England Seafood near exit 4 and it appeared to be less than half a mile from the highway. We took the exit, turned left, and we immediately saw the sign. With it being nearly 9 PM, there was only one other couple in the restaurant so we were a bit concerned that the food might not be good. But, we elected to give the establishment a chance. We went to the counter and spoke to Mitch, who we didn&apos;t realize was the owner. There was a large selection of fish and methods of preparation, so we weren&apos;t sure what to select. Mitch saw us struggling, and asked if he could help us make our selections. He asked us what we liked, what type of preparations we enjoy, and he picked up on our&quot;New Yawk&quot;accents. Being from Boston, Mitch had a really good idea of what we&apos;d enjoy and made some excellent suggestions. He also suggested trying some authentic southern style preparation so we could compare the cuisine.. We had a seat and Mitch brought the food over in about 10 minutes. Suffice to say, his suggestions were terrific. Mitch was indeed correct when he guessed that we would prefer battered fish (the typical preparation in the Northeast that has a very light butter taste) to the southern style (which is made with a cornmeal batter and southern seasonings - much stronger flavor). The fish was so good, but don&apos;t forget the steak fries, hushpuppies and cole slaw which all were really excellent. Mitch was able to spend some time with us talking about how we started up the restaurant with his wife Kelley after relocating from the Boston area, and the challenges that face a small business. Between the excellent food and two good people who are trying to make a go with a small business, we can&apos;t urge everyone enough to stop in and patronize this establishment. It&apos;s convenient, the prices are very reasonable, the food is terrific, and you can choose from a broad selection. If you like seafood and find yourself on North/South Carolina border, New England Seafood is the place for you. Renee and Scott 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by D Cooper New England... by D Cooper Shrimp dinner 
 All 5 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Amon&apos;s Cafe Southwest - Coffee, Diner Sonic Drive-in 88% $ Southwest - Fast Food 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Ramada Limited South Charlotte -
7900 Nations Ford Rd 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 new england seafood charlotte nc new england seafood charlotte restaurants best fish and chips charlotte nc clam chowder in charlotte nc 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
