<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004938" url="http://findarticles.com/p/articles/mi_m0OQC/is_1_3/ai_100439343/" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="2" score="0.0117100116809468" bingtitle="Made to order: from humble beginnings in Brazil, fast-food chain ..." webtitle="Made to order: from humble beginnings in Brazil, fast-food chain Bobs is giving global giants such as McDonalds a run for their money in Latin Americas largest consumer market | Latin CEO: Executive Strategies for the Americas | Find Articles">
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>Made to order: from humble beginnings in Brazil, fast-food chain Bob&apos;s is giving global giants such as ... though Vader says the company is trying to boost the number of ...</description>
	<body>
		FIND ARTICLES IN THE INTERACTIVE BUSINESS NETWORK RESOURCE LIBRARY Business Library http://findarticles.com/ 
 Business Money Life&amp;Health 
 Search 
Departments

 Business Reference Technology News 
 
Popular Publications

 Economic Review Entrepreneur Business Wire Chief Executive, The Market Wire 
 
Departments

 Economy Careers Saving Spending Investing Retirement 
 
Popular Publications

 Better Nutrition Natural Health New American, The Encyclopedia of ... Real Estate Weekly 
 
Departments

 Arts Home&amp;Garden Autos Sports Health 
 
Popular Publications

 New York Times Upfront Health Management Technology Automotive Manufacturing&amp;... Sierra Automotive Industries 
 FindArticles / Business / Latin CEO: Executive Strategies for the Americas / Jan, 2002 
Made to order: from humble beginnings in Brazil, fast-food chain Bob&apos;s is giving global giants such as McDonald&apos;s a run for their money in Latin America&apos;s largest consumer market

by Larry Luxner
 Tweet 
 1 2 3 Next 
 More Articles of Interest 
 America&apos;s most wanted j-o-b-s - 10 hottest employment opportunities Effective organizational communication: a competitive advantage 7 tips for effective listening: productive listening does not occur naturally. It requires hard work and practice - Back To Basics - effective listening is a crucial skill for internal auditors Culture, leadership, and power: the keys to organizational change - includes bibliography The dropout dilemma: One in four college freshmen drop out. What is going on here? What does it take to stay in? 
 
IF FAST-FOOD JUGGERNAUT McDonald&apos;s has any competition at all in Brazil, it isn&apos;t coming from global rivals Burger King, Wendy&apos;s or Pizza Hut. Instead the main culprit is restaurant chain Bob&apos;s.

The home-grown hamburger chain has for decades been a fixture on street corners throughout Rio de Janeiro and Sao Paulo, but after years of decline Bob&apos;s is making a comeback.

Spearheading the revival is Peter van Voorst Vader, president and CEO of Brazil Fast Food Corp., which has owned the chain for the past five years. &quot;Basically. we&apos;ve concentrated on our strong points, with all our marketing based on better taste and variety&quot; rather than speed of service, he says. &quot;We&apos;re slower than McDonald&apos;s because we cook to order.&quot;

Launched in 1952 by Wimbledon tennis champion Robert &quot;Bob&quot; Falkenburg, Bob&apos;s opened its first hot dog, hamburger and milkshake joint on Rua Domingos Ferreira, in the then up-and-coming Rio de Janeiro neighborhood of Copacabana. By the late 1950s, the trendy restaurant had become a favorite hangout of wellknown American diplomat Harry Stone, jazz musician Booker Pittman and various Hollywood celebrities.

&quot;At that time, the main thing for the upper classes was to go to the Roxy Cinema, then to Bob&apos;s for dinner,&quot; says Vader, whose Rio office is lined with black-and-white photographs of that bygone era.

Bob&apos;s prospered in subsequent years, adding six more outlets, before Falkenburg returned to the United States in 1974 and sold the company to Libby do Brasil, which was later acquired by Swiss-owned Nestle. By 1978 the chain had expanded to Sao Paulo.
 
In 1987 Nestle decided to get out of the restaurant business, and sold Bob&apos;s to Vendex, a Dutch multinational that formerly owned retail outlets such as Dillard&apos;s and Sears in Brazil, as well as bookseller Barnes&amp;Noble in the United States. By then, the corporate ownership shuffle had begun to take a toll on Bob&apos;s.

&quot;All those comings and goings prevented Bob&apos;s from having a consistent policy,&quot; says Vader. &quot;When we got the company, its image was totally discredited. It was getting old, stuffy dirty, and badly run. Teenagers were boycotting Bob&apos;s--especially the girls. We cleaned it up and made it fashionable by painting the stores and introducing gimmicky ads. We&apos;ve basically had to gain the market back.&quot;

Short Order

Vader, 47, spent seven years as marketing director of petroleum company Shell do Brasil. During that time, he personally bought a Bob&apos;s franchise near Copacabana Beach. By 1996, after leaving Shell, Vader and his business partner, Omar Carneiro da Cunha--the former president of Shell&apos;s Brazilian operations--decided to buy the entire chain from Vendex with US$21 million raised on the Nasdaq stock exchange (symbol: BOBS).

&quot;At that time, it looked like a good price. Now it looks like we paid way too much,&quot; says Vader. &quot;The company today is probably worth about US$25 million--maybe US$35 million.... But if you had to build it from scratch, it would cost over US$100 million.&quot;

At last count, Bob&apos;s had 267 points of sale in Brazil--198 of them franchised and 69 owned by Brazil Fast Food Corp--making it the No. 2 fast-food chain in the nation. Slightly more than half of its outlets are located in the metropolitan Rio de Janeiro area, though Vader says the company is trying to boost the number of Bob&apos;s restaurants in Sao Paulo and several key Brazilian states such as Pernambuco, Santa Catarina, Para, Mato Grosso and Bahia.

&quot;A franchisee pays us an initial fee of US$30,000,&quot; says Vader, who gets 45 to 60 inquiries a month from potential investors. &quot;We approve the location and the building, and we supply the training. He pays us 4 percent royalties in the first two years and 5 percent after that. He also contributes 4 percent to the marketing fund.&quot;

Vader personally owns 4 percent of Brazil Fast Food Corp. and his partner Carneiro da Cunha owns another 4 percent. The remaining shares are publicly traded, with the largest chunks owned by AIG Latin American Equity Partners and a group of investors called Big Burger; each owns 12.5 percent. In addition to Brazil Fast Food Corp.&apos;s listing on the Nasdaq (it was the first Brazilian firm to list its shares on that exchange), in August 2000 it became the first fast-food company listed on Brazil&apos;s Bovespa stock exchange.

Kicking off an expansion program that same month, Bob&apos;s announced an agreement with Brazil&apos;s No. 1 gas station chain, Petrobras Distribuidora, to open Bob&apos;s stores at 30 Petrobras&apos; gas stations in Brazil. Five have opened so far, in the Rio de Janeiro area; meanwhile Vader is also negotiating with his old employer, Shell.

Distant No. 2

When it comes to burgers, Bob&apos;s can claim the No. 2 title in Brazil, but with only 12 percent of that market segment the company is far behind McDonald&apos;s and its 80-plus percent share of the burger business. As far as the fast-food market in general goes, Pizza Hut and Domino&apos;s are making inroads, as is Habib&apos;s, a chain that serves Middle Eastern fast food--though these chains are not considered direct rivals.

&quot;The competition for Bob&apos;s is McDonald&apos;s, because both have similar menus,&quot; says Habib&apos;s founder Alberto Saraiva, who now has 190 full-sized, sit-down restaurants in Brazil and seven in Mexico.

Saraiva disputes Vader&apos;s claim that the average Bob&apos;s outlet generates monthly revenues of 100,000 reais, saying the true number is closer to 70,000 reais. &quot;I know of some Bob&apos;s restaurants that sell as little as 30,000 or 40,000 reais a month,&quot; he says. &quot;It&apos;s more difficult for them to recoup their investments because they sell so little.&quot;

Whatever the true figure, Marcel Fleischmann, president of McDonald&apos;s Brasil--which has more than 1,000 points of sale throughout the nation--doesn&apos;t appear to be too worried about the competition. &quot;Bob&apos;s was a nice concept back in the late &apos;50s and early &apos;60s. After that, they didn&apos;t invest enough,&quot; he says. &quot;They are always looking for investors.&quot;

Vader concedes that things have been tough for Bob&apos;s lately Net operating revenues in 2001 were approximately 180 million reais--up 20 percent from the previous year--but the company continues to operate at a loss.

&quot;We thought we&apos;d break even this year, but the whole world went against us, says Vader, citing Brazil&apos;s energy crisis, continuing difficulties in Argentina and the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks as the chief culprits. While the price for Brazil Fast Food Corp. on the Nasdaq-US$1.35 in mid January--is above the year&apos;s low of US60 cents in October, is still below the year&apos;s high in January 2001, when it briefly spiked to US$3.

Impact at Home

Nevertheless, Bob&apos;s employs close to 6,000 people and gives local food producers lots of business. It buys hamburger patties and chicken from Sadia, ice cream from Caramba, and ice cream toppings from Smucker&apos;s. Polenghi supplies cheese, and Coca-Cola provides soft drinks. Since 1998, Bob&apos;s has conducted joint marketing campaigns with Shell, department store retailer Lojas Americanas and supermarket chain Sendas, offering special premiums to repeat customers through their &quot;Smart Card&quot; program.

More recently Vader launched a promotion that enables Rio de Janeiro customers to place delivery orders via the Internet. Vader says that going online has been a boon, creating administrative efficiencies by connecting stores with the company&apos;s central computers. &quot;In addition,&quot; says Vader, &quot;because participating stores are now able to process debit cards and credit checks online, the program reduces our exposure to bad checks.&quot;

In late November, Bob&apos;s officially went international, opening its first restaurant in Lisbon. Vader&apos;s partner there, Carlos Baisch, is the former director of franchising for Bob&apos;s. Vader says the company expects to launch 30 outlets in Portugal this year.

&quot;It&apos;s the same language, so you don&apos;t have to redo the menus [and] you can also use the same commercials,&quot; says the restaurateur, adding that he&apos;s talking to possible franchise partners in Argentina, Uruguay Paraguay and the US, &quot;where the big Brazilian communities are.&quot; But Vader says his focus remains the domestic market, particularly metropolitan Sao Paulo, which is home to more than 20 million people and hundreds of McDonald&apos;s restaurants, but only 30 Bob&apos;s outlets.
 Tweet 
 1 2 3 Next 
 Search 
 All ResourceLibrary 
 
Business

 Business Reference Technology News 
 
Money

 Economy Careers Saving Spending Investing Retirement 
 
Life&amp;Health

 Arts Home&amp;Garden Autos Sports Health 
 
 Most Recent Business Articles 
 
 Neonatal diabetes mellitus/ Yenidoganda diyabetes mellitus Demographic and clinical features of child abuse and neglect cases: one-year experience of The Hospital-Based Child Protection Team of Ege University, Turkey/Cocuk istismari ve ihmali olgularimizin demografik ve klinik ozellikleri: Ege Universitesi Cocuk Aseptic meningitis due to zona zoster infection/ Zona zoster enfeksiyonu sirasinda gelisen aseptik menenjit Acute cyanide poisoning after eating apricot pits: a case report/ Kayisi cekirdegi yeme sonrasi akut siyanur zehirlenme olgusu Determining causes and frequency of misdosing of antipyretics in patients presenting with fever to pediatric emergency/Ates yakinmasi ile cocuk acile basvuran hastalarda uygunsuz dozda ates dusurucu kullanma sikliginin ve nedenlerinin belirlenmesi 
 
 Most Recent Business Publications 
 
 Brandweek Latin Trade Business Asia Store Equipment&amp;Design Cheers 
 
 Most Popular Business Articles 
 
 America&apos;s most wanted j-o-b-s - 10 hottest employment opportunities Effective organizational communication: a competitive advantage 7 tips for effective listening: productive listening does not occur naturally. It requires hard work and practice - Back To Basics - effective listening is a crucial skill for internal auditors Culture, leadership, and power: the keys to organizational change - includes bibliography The dropout dilemma: One in four college freshmen drop out. What is going on here? What does it take to stay in? 
 
 Most Popular Business Publications 
 
 Market Wire Chief Executive, The Entrepreneur Brandweek Business Wire 
 
Content provided in partnership with 
 
 Business Reference Technology Newspaper 

 Economy Careers Saving Spending 

 Investing Retirement Arts Home&amp;Garden 

 Auto Sports Health All RSS Feeds 
 Search ©2011 CBS Interactive. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use | Advertise | Jobs
	</body>
</document>
