<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004866" url="http://www.bizjournals.com/twincities/news/2011/08/12/fast-food-twin-cities-doesnt-have.html" time="2012-07-12-21:23" support="2" score="0.001326406129269674" bingtitle="Slideshow: Top fast-food restaurants absent from Minnesota ..." webtitle="Slideshow: Top fast-food restaurants absent from Minnesota - Minneapolis / St. Paul Business Journal">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>Receive DailyUpdate E-mail; Receive Morning Roundup E-mail; MSPBJ Honors ... in the last couple of years. &gt;Click here to take our poll on which fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		A message from The Business Journals:

We have detected you are using Internet Explorer 6, an outdated browser that we no longer fully support and Microsoft suggests upgrading for a more secure, faster, and functional web browsing experience. Use these links to download a new browser or upgrade your existing browser: Internet Explorer 9 | Firefox | Safari | Google Chrome 

If you received this message in error or choose not to upgrade at this time, please feel free to continue to the page you have requested.
 
This was printed from Minneapolis / St. Paul Business Journal
 
 The Business Journals Digital Network: The Business Journals Local Business Directory Book of Lists Upstart Business Journal 
 
 Subscribe - Get 4 FREE issues 
 Bizjournal logo 
 Login Register 
 Search 
 Choose a city 
 Albany Albuquerque Atlanta Austin Baltimore Birmingham Boston Buffalo Charlotte Cincinnati Columbus 

 Dallas Dayton Denver Greensboro/Winston-Salem/High Point Honolulu Houston Jacksonville Kansas City Los Angeles Louisville Memphis 

 Milwaukee Minneapolis/St. Paul Nashville Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh/Durham Sacramento San Antonio 

 San Francisco San Jose Seattle South Florida St. Louis Tampa Bay Washington, D.C. Wichita 
 Home 
 Receive DailyUpdate E-mail Receive Morning Roundup E-mail MSPBJ Honors&amp;Nominations Editorial Calendar Submit People Announcements 
 News 
 Blogs Premium Companies Industries Photo Galleries Press Releases My News 
 People 
 People Executive Profiles Names in the News Beginners to Big Shots 
 Events 
 Business Events Nominations 
 Exclusives 
 Beginners to Big Shots MPI: Meetings Mean Business National Blogs Social Madness 
 How-To 
 Marketing Funding Human Resources Technology Growth Strategies How-To Videos 
 Buy 
 Subscriptions Book of Lists MyBookofLists Sales Leads Reprints Whitepapers 
 Find 
 City Guide Commercial Real Estate Search Businesses for Sale 
 Jobs 
 Find a Job Post a Job Employers Jobs FAQ 
 Contact Us 
 About Us Help 
 
 
 twitter 

 Email Print Reprints Comments 
 
Send this story to a friend




 Email address of friend (insert comma between multiple addresses): Your email address: Copy Me Add a brief note: Send Email Processing... 
 Slideshow: Top fast-food restaurants absent from Minnesota
 
Minneapolis / St. Paul Business Journal by John Vomhof Jr.
 Date: Friday, August 12, 2011, 6:55am CDT - Last Modified: Friday, August 12, 2011, 7:03am CDT 
Related:
 Retailing&amp;Restaurants View photo gallery (15 photos) 
No. 50, Krystal, $377 million in 2010 U.S. sales, 364 locations.
 
Of the nation&apos;s Top 50 fast-food restaurants, 15 of them have no locations in the Twin Cities.

The slideshow to the right shows the 15 that are missing. The ranking comes from QSR magazine&apos;s list of the largest fast-food joints in America. Also included are two statistics: 2010 U.S. sales for each company, and total number of U.S. locations.

The Twin Cities have 17 of the 20 biggest fast-food restaurants. Can you name the three that are missing? A clue: They are ranked Nos. 7, 11 and 15 in the country.

&gt; Click here to see which of the three will be moving into the Twin Cities soon.

&gt; Click here to see which restaurants moved into the Twin Cities in the last couple of years.

&gt; Click here to take our poll on which fast-food restaurant you would most like to see enter the Twin Cities market.
 

 
See all your followed company news on your personalized dashboard .

To access the full benefits of bizWatch and receive a weekly email with aggregated news on all the companies you are following, please provide your email address below.
 Sign Up Now 
You must have a bizjournals account to follow a company.
Please Log In or Register .
 twitter 
Comments
 
If you are commenting using a Facebook account, your profile information may be displayed with your comment depending on your privacy settings. By leaving the &apos;Post to Facebook&apos; box selected, your comment will be published to your Facebook profile in addition to the space below.
 
Inside Minneapolis / St. Paul Business Journal
 
Most Popular
 
 Most popular Slideshows Facebook Twitter Emailed Mobile 
 
 List Leaders: Largest MN employers based outside of MN Best Buy cutting 2,400 jobs, including 650 at Geek Squad $12 million hotel planned for shores of Lake Minnetonka List: European firms that have cut Minnesota jobs MyBurger takes on food trucks in marketing campaign (photos) Destination Golf Course Rankings: Brainerd area Buffalo Wild Wings unveils redesigned restaurants, logo Supervalu puts itself up for sale Food Trucks: How they&apos;re affecting other downtown businesses Best Buy sues over leaked Samsung Galaxy SIII ad 
 
 List Leaders: Largest MN employers based outside of MN $12 million hotel planned for shores of Lake Minnetonka List: European firms that have cut Minnesota jobs MyBurger takes on food trucks in marketing campaign (photos) Destination Golf Course Rankings: Brainerd area 
 See more slideshows» 
 
 Supervalu puts itself up for sale 
 
 Mitch Reierson commented on Best Buy cutting 2,400 jobs, including 650 at Geek Squad on Saturday, July 7th
 
 Bonnie Harris commented on Best Buy remakes its stores; can it remake its staff? on Friday, July 6th
 
 David Gene Black commented on Food trucks: Their effect on other eateries + Photos, a poll and a map on Monday, July 9th
 
 ALEC Welcoming Committee commented on Best Buy leaves ALEC, policy group that backs voter ID laws on Wednesday, July 11th
 
 
Like the Minneapolis / St. Paul Business Journal
 
mspbjnews

 @mspbjnews 

 MiG fighter plane overshoots runway, stops just short of busy road. http://t.co/UzWnsrQa Supervalu&apos;s stock is down 44% today. Now $3/share. @ mspbjnews What went wrong at Supervalu? http://t.co/iy0MSrY2 @ samablack Confirmed: Target opening first 24 Canadian stores in Ontario in March. http://t.co/Ddj9vcFB 
 
 $12 million hotel planned for shores of Lake Minnetonka Supervalu puts itself up for sale Best Buy cutting 2,400 jobs, including 650 at Geek Squad Archway Marketing sold to New York investment firm for $300M Buffalo Wild Wings unveils redesigned restaurants, logo What went wrong at Supervalu (plenty) and who could buy it? Regis hires Royal Caribbean executive Hanrahan as new CEO 
 Sign up for email newsletters See more emailed stories» 
 Download the free iPhone app Download the free Android app 
 View mobile site Learn more about our mobile apps» 
People
 See More People Search and Contact all People 
Mpls./St. Paul Jobs
 
 Senior Business Lender (Agricultural) Central Minnesota Credit Union | New York Mills, MN Senior Business Lender (Commercial) Central Minnesota Credit Union | Moorhead, MN Careers at Verizon Wireless Verizon Wireless | Local Opportunities Marketing Director Dell, Inc. | Eden Prairie, MN Account Manager Aerotek | Anoka, MN 
 Post a Job | View More Jobs Listings 
Twin Cities Real Estate
 Featured Property Rate: $11-$11 Building Size: 33,800 SF Use Type: Lease View This Listing See More Real Estate 
How-To: Marketing
 
 Really want profitable revenue growth? Shed the old paradigm Here are some key salesperson attributes you won’t find anywhere else No (business)man is an island: We all need partners 
 View More How-To: Marketing Online 
 News People Events Exclusives How-To Buy Find Jobs Contact Us My Account 
 Services 
 Book Of Lists Commercial Property Local Business Directory Jobs myBookofLists Search Subscribe to Paper 
 Subscriptions 
 Subscribe to Paper Trial Subscription Renew subscription Single copies Digital edition Premium content Subscriber FAQs Help Book Of Lists Change Mailing Address 
 Tools 
 Newsletters Syndication/RSS Twitter Mobile Submit People Mobile App LinkedIn Today 
 About 
 Advertise Contact Us About the paper About the business journals 
 Affiliates 
 Upstart Business Journal Sports Business Journal SportsBusiness Daily Sporting News Mass High Tech TechFlash Sustainable Business Oregon Hemmings Motor News 
 
©2012 American City Business Journals. All rights reserved. Use of this Site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement (updated 3/14/12) and Privacy Policy (updated 3/14/12).

 Your California Privacy Rights .

The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of American City Business Journals.

 Ad Choices .
	</body>
</document>
