<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004156" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/1223428" time="2012-07-12-20:24" support="26" score="0.08119655618217414" bingtitle="Once while going through a drive thru fast food restaurant, I told ..." webtitle="Once while going through a drive thru fast food restaurant, I told the cashier I would like to pay for the person behind me. The look on her face said it all. Has anyone here done random acts of kindness? | Answerbag">
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000599" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001052" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001353" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001492" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>... through a drive thru fast food restaurant, I told the cashier I ... What is the average number of employees working at any given time in an average fast food restaurant with ...</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Life And Society / Etiquette / More Etiquette 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
Once while going through a drive thru fast food restaurant, I
told the cashier I would like to pay for the person behind me.
The look on her face said it all. Has anyone here done random
acts of kindness?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 7 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by Runs_With_Scissors on January 20th, 2009
 
 In a toll booth, I&apos;ve paid for the guy behind me. Never thought of doing so in a drive-thru at a fast food place. Today was the day to do it, though. LOL - I went to Starbucks and ran a few errands after the inagruation. I don&apos;t think I&apos;ve seen so many ppl in such a great mood. It was like someone released happy gas all over the country. 
 
Comments

 
Hi friend! Yes the energy was contagious today. I too was caught up in it and was happy to be part of history. +5

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Special K on January 20th, 2009
 
 yeah some old guy was walking in the cold and i drive him to the gas station. a bunch of other shit too i did, but i cant remember. u see? 
 
Comments

 
You get +5 because you have compassion. :) keep passing it on!

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
thanks carlos- ur ok!

 Report 
 
by Special K on January 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by pink crayola on January 20th, 2009
 
 I used to work in drive-thru and this happened often. We&apos;d get one car pay for the car behind him, and then they would pay for the car behind them... it went on as long as 11 cars one time. 
 
Comments

 
lol, I would hate paying for an order of everything on the menu when I only order a soda.

 Report 
 
by KiloWattKid on January 20th, 2009
 
nobody ever paid for me in my life- i&apos;m missing out. this world is filled with a bunch of cheap bastards:)

 Report 
 
by Special K on January 20th, 2009
 
hahahahahhahaha I hear ya

 Report 
 
by KiloWattKid on January 20th, 2009
 
11 cars!! wow...didn&apos;t you wonder what the heck was in the water?
great story..... made me smile... you get+5

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 4 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Leeses Pieces is COATed in chocolate on January 20th, 2009
 
 all the time.

and i don&apos;t do it for the bragging rights or so people can do something in return. i help people when i see the chance, especially if they are struggling.

there was this lady in the Home Depot parking lot who could not figure out how to get this new plastic storage bin in her 2-door sports car. i was able to get it in :)

or, letting people go ahead of me in line if they only have a few items or are obviously in a rush.

do those count? 
 
Comments

 
absolutely!! people like you make the world a happier place. +5

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
thank you. although i realize that mentioning it here kinda made it bragging, but it wasn&apos;t meant like that. i wish more people would consider doing these small acts more often. what goes around, comes around.

 Report 
 
by Leeses Pieces is COATed in chocolate on January 20th, 2009
 
yes it does. I didnt mean for the question to sound like I was bragging. I hope no one took it like that :) I just like to hear when good things happen to people. Once this man lost his wallet and was tearing his car apart with a panicked look on his face. I asked what was wrong and he told me. I said I hope you find it, lunch is on me. He was shocked. LOL.... he didnt want me to pay for it. But in the end he was grateful.

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
oh it didn&apos;t sound that way, i just thought that my answer did. i love hearing about these kinds of acts too. i don&apos;t think about it, so i have probably done it a lot, but it surprises me when i hear about other people doing because it IS so rare.

 Report 
 
by Leeses Pieces is COATed in chocolate on January 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 4 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by dea_ex_machina on January 20th, 2009
 
 can i just ask - how could you pay for the person behind you when they had not placed their order yet? How did you know how much to pay? 
 
Comments

 
By the time you get to the checkout window, the people behind have placed their order at the intercom.

 Report 
 
by pink crayola on January 20th, 2009
 
they placed their order then drove up behind me. The cashier took my money then figured theres as they were just behind me.

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
ahhh !! I see.. I am unfamiliar with the way these things work!

 Report 
 
by dea_ex_machina on January 20th, 2009
 
:) have a good day...

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 4 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Special K on January 20th, 2009
 
 I paid for some fat kid at white castle when he didnt have enough money- i gave him like 50 cents- if not he would have been like one burger short. 
 
Comments

 
I used to have white castle burgers. They are sure tiny but good. +5

 Report 
 
by ICU says April is Autism Awareness Mo. on January 20th, 2009
 
well this fat kid liked them carlos:)

 Report 
 
by Special K on January 20th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Baccduckus is a Carbonproduct on January 20th, 2009
 
 Only when I have my gun on me. That&apos;s just when people will think I&apos;m a push over and try to take my fairy wings or princess&apos;tiara. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 What does see you next Tuesday mean? 
by Answerbag Staff on June 8th, 2010
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Why is helping others important? 
by Answerbag Staff on March 11th, 2010
 
 | 4 people like this
 
 How do I hold a conversation with a man? 
by Answerbag Staff on May 19th, 2010
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Do you introduce yourself as &quot;Mr/Mrs/Ms/ Miss .....&quot; or on your full name or only first name? 
by Marky Mark on June 3rd, 2012
 
 | 5 people like this
 
 Give an example of a funny or dumb bit of political correctness, please? 
by Marky Mark on June 3rd, 2012
 
 | 11 people like this
 More More Etiquette See only professionally researched More Etiquette questions 
 
You&apos;re reading Once while going through a drive thru fast food restaurant, I told the cashier I would like to pay for the person behind me. The look on her face said it all. Has anyone here done random acts of kindness?
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 Does anyone remember that early-90&apos;s fast-food commercial with Seth Green working at the drive-thru where he keeps yelling&quot;Cha-Ching!&quot;? What restaurant was that ad for? 
 
 We are trying to get a parking variance and need information we have been unable to find - we hope someone here can help us. What is the average number of employees working at any given time in an average fast food restaurant with drive-thru (like a Jack 
 
 I work at a fast food restaurant as a cashier and when a customer ordered something and paid money and then he just stand there and I stand behind the cash register, I feel embarrassed cause he just stand there looking at me and what should I do? 
 
 My husband was ranting at the stupidity of a guy working the drive through window at a Wendy&apos;s. What are the requirements for working the cashier at a fast food restaurant? 
 
 I was standing in line, one day, to pay for some&quot;to go&quot;food i ordered at Cracker Barrel restaurant. as i approached the cashier, someone ran their arm underneath mine and said&quot;breakfast is on me&quot;. saw no one. was this an angel? 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 What was the first fast-food restaurant to offer patrons 20 free minutes of Internet time? 
 
 Do you need a high school diploma to work at a fast food restaurant? 
 
 What would a queen leaf cutter ant use as a food source for a new colony? 
 
 What is the approximate price to pay per week for a restaurant food delivery? 
 
 How do I buy restaurant gift cards online? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 Fast food while going to tour Going through a drive thru Paying for the guy behind you at the fast food drive thru Fat lady going thru a drive thru Going through the drive thru 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet How do you #save #money? http://t.co/dvcMGuY2 http://t.co/9WfZNlkl 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
