<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004489" url="http://www.yumsugar.com/Long-Waits-Restaurants-How-Long-You-Stand-Line-8254852" time="2012-07-12-20:55" support="2" score="0.0025799869975113065" bingtitle="Long Waits at Restaurants: How Long Will You Stand in Line?" webtitle="Long Waits at Restaurants: How Long Will You Stand in Line?">
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="87"/>
	<description>One San Francisco seafood restaurant that doesn&apos;t take reservations plies patient ... Materious Puzzle Tray Eco Chic Collaboration Newton Vineyard; DC Design House Pictures</description>
	<body>
		Don&apos;t Miss Our First Ever POPSUGAR Must Have Bag! Only 792 left . Join now to receive July&apos;s Summer must-have bag! 
 Front Page Entertainment 
 Celebrity Entertainment Sex&amp;Culture Katie Holmes Takes Her Mom and Suri Cruise For a Zoo Day 
 Style 
 Fashion Beauty CelebStyle Fashionologie ShopStyle STYL.MX 4 Easy Steps to This Gorgeous Cascading Braid 
 Living 
 Health Home Mom&amp;Kids Food Tech Money Pets Circle of Moms Taste the States: 50 Iconic American Foods From A to Z 
 PopSugar TV 
 Celebrity 01:48 Video: Would Channing Star in Fifty Shades? Yes! Latest on PopSugarTV PopSugar Rush I&apos;m a Huge Fan Specials The Buzz Celebrity Interviews Fashion 01:27 Nicole Richie Talks Summer Essentials — and Latest on FabSugarTV Fashion Week FabSugar Lookbook Currently Trending Fab How To Fab Flash Beauty 02:04 Karlie Kloss Reveals Her Supermodel Inspiration Latest on BellaSugarTV Bella Beauty Book Bella Secret Weapon Bella How To Bella Beauty Review Bella Beauty Beat Food 00:52 Make Tuna Tartare at Home With This Recipe From a Latest on YumSugarTV Get the Dish Yum How To Fitness 02:22 Jackie Warner&apos;s Prescription For a Killer Beach Latest on FitSugarTV Get the Bod Class FitSugar Fit How To Healthy Recipes Branded Content Meet Our Editors and Tell Us How You Stand Out! Latest Branded Content Starbucks Levi&apos;s New Balance Frye 
 Must Have 
 
 Shop 
 
 Sign In 
 To die for. 
 Recipes 
 Original Recipes Fast and Easy Breakfast Appetizers Soup Salads Sandwiches Dinner Vegetarian Baking Dessert Reader Recipes 
 Cooking Basics 
 Yum How-to Cooking Tips 
 Party Planning 
 Cocktails Wine Beer Edible Gifts Menus Party Planning 
 Food News 
 Celebrity Chefs Taste Test Savory Sights 
 Food Video 
 Latest Popular Get the Dish Yum How To 
 Summer 
 Taste the States: 50 Iconic American Foods From A to Z Fast and Easy Summer Dinners A Burger by Any Other Name: Touring McDonald&apos;s International Menu Options Summer Calls For No-Bake Desserts 10 Shore Food Specialties to Enjoy Now 
 More 
 Community Kitchen Goddess Super Special Occasion Savory Sights Celebrity Chefs Cocktails Edible Gifts Fast and Easy Grilling Halloween Holiday St Patrick&apos;s Day Sugar Community Vegetarian 
 
 
Long Waits at Restaurants: How Long Will You Stand in Line?

How Long Will You Wait in Line For a Table?
 
 Updated Aug 22 2011 - 12:03pm · Posted Apr 28 2010 - 8:00am by YumSugar · 24 comments 
 Eating out · Poll · restaurants · Lines · Long Lines · Long Waits · Waiting For Food 
 Some restaurants&apos; lines are legendary: diners show up expecting to wait at least an hour — even multiple hours — to snag a table. One San Francisco seafood restaurant that doesn&apos;t take reservations plies patient diners with free wine. I&apos;ve even been known to kill time over Bloody Marys while waiting more than an hour for brunch. But usually I draw the line at an hour and a half wait. What&apos;s the longest you&apos;ll wait in line for a table?

 Source: Flickr User Jarnocan 
 Link Love 
 RIP Marion Cunningham, food legend of Fannie Farmer fame — Grub Street SF Girl Scout cookies are the latest food to get the deep-fry treatment — Delish Don&apos;t make bad hummus; follow these tips — Food52 Only McDonald&apos;s can serve french fries at the Olympics — Eater Details on season three of The Great Food Truck Race — Zagat 15 no-cook meals to beat the heat — Kitchen Daily Is the food in your fridge still good after a power outage? — MyRecipes 
 Join The Conversation: Sign Up / Log In powered by Please sign in to comment. Featured Partners 
 

 PHOTO: Jason Segel Holds Hands with Matilda Ledger » Kate Cleans (and Guts) Fish with Scouts » Tom Cruise Gets Set Visit from Son Connor Cruise » Kristin Chenoweth Released from Hospital After On-Set Accident » 
 More News at PEOPLE.com 
 

 Liquor.com: How to Cocktail Video: The Green Beast » 15 Ways Rice Krispie Treats Just Got Better » 20 Things To Do With Summer Peaches » Obscure Summer Produce You Should Be Eating » 
 
 

 Seoul Sausage: Non-Food Truck Food Truck of the Week » Flora in Arlington Unveils Its New Dining Room » Six Picks for University City Dining Days, June 12-26 » Order an Ice Cream Truck: There&apos;s an App for That » 
 More News at Zagat You might also like Wedding Roundup: DIY Decor, Bachelorette Party Ideas, and More Inspiration For Your Big Day Wedding Desserts to Try in Lieu of a Wedding Cake 10 Things to Make With Fresh Basil A Burger by Any Other Name: Touring McDonald&apos;s International Menu Options 10 Car-Friendly Foods to Pack on a Road Trip Sponsored Links ShopStyle Headlines Top Brands 
 Jimmy Choo Kenneth Cole Reaction TOMS Shoes Dermalogica  Clarks
	</body>
</document>
