<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004764" url="http://www.vegsouthflorida.com/palmbeach.html" time="2012-07-12-21:16" support="15" score="0.04332625428578142" bingtitle="Palm Beach County vegetarian and vegan-friendly restaurants" webtitle="Palm Beach County vegetarian and vegan-friendly restaurants">
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000530" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>The highlight of this &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant is the salad bar, where you choose ... A few outdoor tables, but primarily take-out. Located at North Dixie ...</description>
	<body>
		Helping 
 animals one bite at a time! Please support the Palm Beach County restaurants 
 listed below, and tell them you saw them on VegSouthFlorida.com. Of course, 
 we can&apos;t list every restaurant with a salad on the menu. To be listed, a restaurant 
 must offer 3 or 4 vegan dishes, or be exceptional with fewer. Please let us 
 know if there are restaurants that should (or should not) be listed 
 here, or if you have updates. We&apos;re relying on you to keep this web site current. 
 Contact us at info@vegsouthflorida.com . 
 Restaurants are listed by region: North, Central , West , South . Veg-friendly restaurant chains . = recommended = 
 100% vegetarian 
 
 
 
Northern 
 Palm Beach County

 Valerie&apos;s Market 
6350 W Indiantown Road, Suite 9
Jupiter 33458
(561) 401-9662
( web site | map )

Vegetarian deli and health food store. Prepared foods to go. Daily specials, such as vegan lasagna, Shepherd&apos;s pie, stuffed mushrooms, chickpea salad sandwiches and chili. Smoothies and juice. Located in Chasewood Plaza. Closed Sunday.

 ——————— 

 The Yard House 
11701 Lake Victoria Gardens Ave.
Palm Beach Gardens 33410
(561) 691-6901
( web site | map )

The Yard House is a popular place to go for drinks (they promise the&quot;world&apos;s largest selection of draft beer&quot;), but you might think that there is nothing on the menu for vegans to eat. Think again! The menu features over one dozen of their popular entrees made with gardein brand fake meats, including veggie boneless wings, veggie beef sliders, veggie chicken&amp;avocado sandwich, veggie chicken rice bowl, and more! The veggie wings and sliders are available during happy hour. The busy restaurant has indoor and outdoor seating. Open for lunch and dinner. Located at Downtown At The Gardens.

 ——————— 

 Christopher&apos;s Kitchen 
4783 PGA Boulevard
Palm Beach Gardens 33418
(561) 318-6191
( web site | map )

Christopher&apos;s Kitchen is the Restaurant of the Month. See home page for review.

 ——————— 

 Field 
 of Greens 
4665 PGA Boulevard
Palm Beach Gardens 33418
(561) 625-0036
( web site | map )

The highlight 
 of this&quot;fast food&quot;restaurant is the salad bar, where you choose 
 greens, veggies, toppings and dressing, and the staff toss it for you. Great 
 selection of vegan garnishes, including black beans, pistachios and sun-dried 
 tomatoes. Also popular are homemade vegan soups (Portabella Mushroom, Lentil, 
 Split Pea, Asparagus and Roasted Butternut Squash), vegan chili and vegetarian, 
 grilled panini sandwiches.

 ——————— 

 Central 
 Palm Beach County 

 Indus Herbal Indian Cuisine 
1649 Forum Place
West Palm Beach 33401
(561) 249-0123
( web site | map )

Indus Herbal Indian Cuisine opened in the Summer of 2010 and quickly found a following. Large selection of vegetable dishes. Vegan items are marked on the menu. Lunch buffet.

 ——————— 

 The India Palace 
4778 Okeechobee Boulevard
West Palm Beach 33417
(561) 478-5606
( web site | map )

Indian cuisine is usually a safe bet for vegetarians, and India Palace doesn&apos;t disappoint. The menu features a wide variety of meatless dishes, including popular favorites such as Aloo Gobi (cauliflower and potatoes) and Channa Masala (chick peas cooked with onion and tomatoes), as well as less common dishes. Closed Monday.

 ——————— 

 Saffron 
731 Village Boulevard
West Palm Beach 33409
(561) 616-8585
( web site | map )

Richly-decorated 
 Indian restaurant, with a good selection of vegetable dishes and breads. Full 
 bar and attentive staff make this a good choice for a family gathering or 
 an intimate dinner for two.

 ——————— 

 Leila 
120 South Dixie Highway
West Palm Beach 33401
(561) 659-7373
( web site | map )

Upscale 
 Middle Eastern restaurant. Menu features several vegetarian entrees and salads. 
 Located on the corner of Datura Street and Dixie Highway.

 ——————— 

 Salloum Foods 
327 5th Street
West Palm Beach 33401
(561) 659-7322
( web site | map )

There 
 are many excellent Middle Eastern restaurants in south Florida, but if you&apos;re 
 looking for authenticity you can&apos;t beat Salloum Foods. This deli, market and 
 pita bakery serves falafel sandwiches, lentil&amp;potato soup, excellent 
 salads (we recommend the Fattoush or butter bean salads), veggie cabbage rolls 
 and spinach pies. Pastries available for dessert include cashew/almond&quot;Birds 
 nests&quot;(sweetened with sugar syrup, not honey). When you&apos;re there, grab 
 a tub of hummus, olives or a bag of pitas to take home. A few outdoor tables, 
 but primarily take-out. Located at North Dixie Avenue and 5th Street.

 ——————— 

 Field 
 of Greens 
460 S. Rosemary Avenue, Suite 180
(City Place)
West Palm Beach 33401
(561) 820-2465
( web site | map )

See 
 above review.

 ——————— 

 Joy noodles&amp;rice 
2200 S. Dixie Highway
West Palm Beach 33401
(561) 655-5212
( web site | map )

 Joy noodles&amp;rice is a brand-new restaurant, from the owners of the excellent Wattana Thai down the road. Joy is not an exclusively vegetarian restaurant, but there is a good selection of vegan dishes on the menu. We recommend the Chiangmai Noodle Soup (potato noodles, fried tofu, bok choy and bean sprouts in a spicy/sweet curry coconut broth). We were also impressed with the Mixed Vegetables with Mushroom Sauce because of the fresh, varied vegetables such as asparagus, yellow squash and edamame (not your standard stir-fry selections). The Cucumber Kim Chi Salad makes a great starter. Open for lunch and dinner. Located half mile north of Belvedere Road. 

 ——————— 

 Howley&apos;s 
4700 S. Dixie Highway
West Palm Beach 33405
(561) 833-5691
( web site | map )

Howley&apos;s, established 1950, is a West Palm Beach institution. Friendly staff and a funky, fun atmosphere. Howley&apos;s serves predominantly meat dishes (unfortunately), but there are a few good choices for vegetarians. We recommend the Grilled Veggie (vegan) Burger, with avocado and sweet potato fries, or fresh fruit. Or try the portabella mushroom sandwich. Open for breakfast, lunch and dinner (open until 4am on weekends).

 ——————— 

 Wattana Thai 
7201 S. Dixie Highway
West Palm Beach 33405
(561) 588-9383
( web site | map )

Family-run restaurant with over a dozen vegetable 
 dishes on the menu. Start with the deep fried tofu appetizer, then try a delicious 
 stir-fry of tofu and vegetables with your choice of sauces like green curry, 
 savory basil or the spicy volcano sauce. Or try their Pad Thai, soup or a 
 clear rice noodle dish. Wattana also has a smaller menu of Japanese favorites.

 ——————— 

 darbster 
8020 South Dixie Highway
West Palm Beach 33405
(561) 586-2622
( web site | map )

 darbster is West Palm Beach&apos;s first vegan restaurant. It was worth the wait! The new restaurant features outdoor seating in a relaxed setting. We recommend the Palm Cakes entree (the fried hearts of palm have a delicious creamy texture), the&quot;darbster&apos;s chik&apos;n&quot;entree, the Mac&amp;Cheez (elbow pasta with a subtle cheesy flavor, topped with toasted bread crumbs), and the Sliders appetizer (faux-steak bites on a crunchy sesame bun with tangy sauce). The menu also includes raw dishes and vegan desserts. Closed Monday and Tuesday. 

 ——————— 

 Mother Earth Coffee&amp;Gifts 
410 Second Avenue North
Lake Worth 33460
(561) 460-8647
( web site | map )

Organic/fair trade coffee and teas. Try a spicy yam veggie burger (made with yam, spinach, kidney beans), or stop by on Thursdays when the lunch/dinner special is a hearty vegan meal. Mother Earth hosts weekly music/storytelling events. Cash only. Closed Sunday-Monday.

 ——————— 

 Snappers 
398 N. Congress Avenue
Boynton Beach 33426
(561) 375-8600
( web site | map )

Snappers and its sister restaurant, Wave 2700, are seafood restaurants but with a good selection of vegetarian and vegan dishes. Menu items include Risotto Italiano (vegan), a Steamer Basket (filled with steamed tempeh and vegetables), vegan nut loaf with sage gravy, and several pasta dishes made with fresh vegetables. Located in Oakwood Square.

 ——————— 

 DIG 
5199 West Atlantic Avenue
Delray Beach 33484
(561) 638-0500
( web site | map )

DIG is a new restaurant (opened in June 2011) with a healthy,&quot;green&quot;menu that has many options for vegetarians and vegans. From the huge salad bar and soup of the day, to vegan lasagna, veggie burgers and sushi. Try the hummus, which is prepared tableside. DIG offers organic juices and smoothies, and a full selection of cocktails, wine and beer. Located just west of Military Trail.

 ——————— 

 Bamboo Fire 
149 NE 4th Avenue
Delray Beach 33483
(561) 749-0973 or (954) 907-4174
( web site | map )

Caribbean cuisine in a comfortable environment. Menu features several vegetarian entrees—including spicy jerk tofu, coconut tofu, curry vegetables and grilled tofu strips—starters (such as cumin-seasoned garbanzo beans) and sides (sweet plaintains, rice&amp;peas, braised cabbage, okra fried rice). Open for dinner. Hours vary in the off-season, so call ahead.

 ——————— 

 Mellow 
 Mushroom 
25 SE Sixth Avenue
Delray Beach 33483
(561) 330-3040
( web site | map )

The only South Florida location for this popular pizza chain. Where else can you get tempeh and five different flavors of tofu on your pizza? And vegan cheese (Daiya)! Also excellent hoagies and calzones. Choose from among 100 beers. Weekly specials. Fun atmosphere. Open late (&apos;till midnight on Friday and Saturday).

 ——————— 

 The Green Gourmet 
16950 Jog Road
Delray Beach 33446
(561) 455-2466
( web site | map )

The menu at The Green Gourmet changes frequently, but dishes always start with fresh, organic ingredients, often from local farms. Popular vegan dishes include vegetable lasagna and cabbage/shitake mushroom dumplings. Vegan sides include cauliflower mash, cream-less mashed potatoes. Also soups, salads and sandwiches. Located in The Shoppes at Addison Place.

 ——————— 

 Western 
 Palm Beach County 

 Hippocrates 
 Health Institute 
 1443 Palmdale Court
West Palm Beach 33411
(561) 471-8876
( web site | map )

Raw, organic, 
 vegan buffet featuring different dishes each day; delicious, raw versions 
 of caesar&apos;s salad, tacos, pizza, Pad Thai, nut loaf, etc. Also, salads, home-grown 
 sprouts and wheatgrass and a variety of juices. All-you-can-eat buffet is 
 open to the public every day of the week except Wednesday. Lunch is served from 12:30-2pm and dinner 
 from 5:30-7pm. $20 per person.

 ——————— 

 Taste of India 
7750 Okeechobee Blvd. Suite 11
West Palm Beach 33411
(561) 721-8600
( web site | map )

Menu features nine strictly vegan dishes and over a dozen vegetarian dishes (may include yogurt or cream), along with delicious appetizers, breads and soups. Try a traditional favorite like Aloo Gobhi or Channa Masala, or one of several less common dishes, like Vegetable Chettinadu (vegetables in spicy black pepper and roasted coconut sauce). Located just west of the Land Rover dealership.

 ——————— 

 Talay Thai 
7100 Fairway Drive
Palm Beach Gardens 33418
(561) 691-5662
( web site | map )

Recommended Thai restaurant with many vegan/vegetarian options. Appetizers include vegan spring rolls, summer rolls and dumplings. Any of the curries, noodles and stir fry dishes can be prepared vegan (no eggs or fish sauce), and with tofu. Knowledgeable servers and a great atmosphere. Located in the LA Fitness shopping center.

 ——————— 

 Field 
 of Greens 
10140 Forest Hill Boulevard
Wellington 33414
(561) 795-4345
( web site | map )

See review 
 above. Located in The Pointe at Wellington Green.

 ——————— 

 Japan Express 
13873 Wellington Trace
Wellington 33414
(561) 792-8889‎
( web site ) | map )

The menu at Japan Express has an unexpectedly large selection of vegan options, and the dishes are not what you would expect. Vegetable fish fingers, cold green tea noodles and spinach roll with yuzu citrus are just a few of the unusual starters. Main dishes feature soy protein, seitan or tofu as&quot;meat.&quot;Your choices include black pepper seitan with Chinese broccoli, vegetable spare ribs with garlic and pineapple, vegetable chicken lo mein, Malaysian curry stew, and many more. Good sized portions. Lunch specials. Make sure you ask for the vegan menu! Located in Wellington Market Place shopping center.

 ——————— 

 Southern 
 Palm Beach County 

 The Salad Spot 
690 Yamato Road
Boca Raton 33431
(561) 613-6680
( map )

Make your own salad with fresh ingredients. Huge assortment of salad fixings. Also, fresh fruit and soups. Open M-F. Located at southeast corner of Yamato and Congress, next to Subway.

 ——————— 

 Chow Thai 
23034 Sandalfoot Plaza Drive
Boca Raton 33428
(561) 487-8414
( map )

Recommended restaurant. Extensive menu features many vegan selections, including tofu steak, tempeh dishes. Friendly staff.

 ——————— 

 Juice&amp;Java 
21316 St. Andrew Boulevard
Boca Raton 33431
(561) 852-2230
( web site | map )

Large menu includes many options for vegetarians/vegans, such as tofu coconut curry rice, or cauliflower mash with veggie burger. Also, organic pasta dishes, wraps, vegan soups, stews and salads. Juices and smoothies, and desserts as well! Juice and Java is open for breakfast, lunch and dinner (closed Sunday). Indoor and outdoor seating.

 ——————— 

 Mikey&apos;s Hotdogs 
620 Glades Road
Boca Raton 33486
(561) 368-6178
( web site | map )

Sometimes you just want a (veggie) hot dog, and Mikey&apos;s is one of the only places in South Florida where you can find one. Mikey&apos;s also offers vegetarian sliders, falafel sandwiches and veggie wraps. Sides include chips, fries, sweet potato fries and hummus. The fresh lemonade is recommended. For every 10 hot dogs you eat you get a free one! Located in the Oaks Plaza Shopping Center.

 ——————— 

 Maoz Vegetarian 
6000 Glades Road
Boca Raton 33431
(561) 393-6269
( web site ) | map )

 The first Florida location for this international vegetarian restaurant chain. When you spot the employees wearing&quot;Veg Out&quot;aprons, you know you&apos;re in the right place. Start with warm falafel balls served in pita bread or on a salad, add eggplant, hummus or babaganoush, then head to the toppings bar where you&apos;ll find a great variety of sauces and fresh vegetables (such as chickpeas, pickled baby eggplant, beets, and brocolli and cauliflower). Add Belgian fries or sweet potato fries and some freshly squeezed juice or mint-flavored iced tea to complete your meal. Don&apos;t forget to try the vegan rice pudding! Located in the Food Court of Boca Raton Town Center mall. 

 ——————— 

 5-Spice 
1200 Yamato Road, #A1
Boca Raton 33431
(561) 989-1688
( web site | map )

Recommended 
 Asian-theme restaurant. Add tofu to create-your-own noodle or rice bowls. 
 Starters include vegetarian curry samosas, summer rolls and tempura.

 ——————— 

 Wave 2700 
2700 N. Federal Highway
Boca Raton 33421
(561) 361-2700
( web site | map )

Wave 2700 and its sister restaurant, Snappers, are seafood restaurants but with a good selection of vegetarian and vegan dishes. Menu items include Risotto Italiano (vegan), a Steamer Basket (filled with steamed tempeh and vegetables), vegan nut loaf with sage gravy, and several pasta dishes made with fresh vegetables. Organic wines.

 ——————— 

 Pine 
 Garden 
1668 N. Federal Highway
Boca Raton 33432
(561) 395-7534
( web site | map )

Neighborhood 
 Chinese restaurant with a twist. Make sure you ask for the seperate vegetarian 
 menu. 100+ meatless entrees, including noodles, vegi&quot;meats&quot;(pork, 
 shrimp, duck), tofu, fried rice and vegetable dishes. The mock meats can taste 
 alike. We recommend sharing one of the&quot;meat&quot;dishes—such 
 as the popular Crispy Orange Beef—and a vegetable dish (try the Eggplant 
 in Spicy Garlic Sauce). The soups are also excellent. Before you leave, ask 
 them to get rid of the grubby fish tank at the entrance (it&apos;s almost enough 
 to ruin an appetite!).

 ——————— 

 Baja 
 Cafe 
201 NW 1st Avenue
Boca Raton 33432
(561) 394-5449
( web site | map )

Cal-Mex 
 cuisine. Excellent (lard-free) veggie burritos and fajitas, homemade salsa 
 and chips.

 ——————— 

 4th Generation Organic Market 
75 SE 3rd Street
Boca Raton 33432
(561) 338-9920
( web site | map )

 4th Generation Organic Market is a great place for lunch or to grab something to take home for dinner. The deli counter features freshly-made sandwiches, raw vegan options (the raw mock tuna wrap is delicious), and prepared hot foods, such as vegan lasagna, tempeh chili and mac&amp;cheese. The raw/vegan side dishes are also excellent (we recommend the cashew cheese). Don&apos;t skip dessert! Vegan options include macaroons, coconut cake, chocolate pecan clusters and homemade ice cream! 4th Generation also has a nice variety of organic produce and packaged goods, and hosts cooking demonstrations, wine tastings and other in-store special events. 

 ——————— 

 Veg-friendly 
 restaurant chains 
 Below 
 is a short list of popular chain restaurants in Palm Beach County where you 
 can find good, vegan food. (You can also eat vegan at Subway, Taco Bell and many others; click 
 here for a more complete list.) 

 California Pizza Kitchen ( web site )
Pizza, pasta and salads. Many options for vegetarians. Vegan options include the Vegetarian with Japanese Eggplant pizza (thin crust, no cheese), the Tomato Basil Spaghettini, and the Dakota Smashed Pea and Barley Soup. Locations in Boca Raton, Palm Beach Gardens, Wellington and West Palm Beach.

 Cheeburger 
 Cheeburger ( web site )
Create your own burger. Start with a veggie burger patty (may not be vegan), then choose from 
 a wide selection of toppings. Grilled portobello mushroom sandwich also available. 
 West Palm Beach location.

 Chili&apos;s ( web site )
Chili&apos;s is happy to substitute black beans (vegan) for meat in wraps and fajitas, and you can add sliced avocado, mushrooms or extra lettuce to the dish. Unfortunately, the veggie burger at Chili&apos;s is not vegan. 9 locations in Palm Beach County.

 Chipotle ( web site )
Excellent vegetarian burritos and fajitas. The black beans are vegetarian 
 (pinto beans are not). Vegan guacamole. Locations in West Palm Beach, Wellington, 
 Boynton Beach, Delray Beach and Boca Raton.

 Houston&apos;s ( web 
 site )
Great veggie burger. The&quot;Seasonal Vegetable Platter&quot;entree is 
 also recommended. Boca Raton Location.

 Moe’s 
 Southwest Grill ( web 
 site )
Skip the meat! Choose tofu on your made-to-order burrito, taco, quesadilla, 
 fajita or nachos. Moe&apos;s black beans and pinto beans are vegetarian. Rice is made with vegetable stock. Very large 
 portions. Moe&apos;s guacamole is vegan. Locations in Boca Raton, Palm Beach Gardens, 
 Boynton Beach and West Palm Beach.

 Nature&apos;s 
 Way Café ( web 
 site )
Large menu includes avocado sandwich, veggie burger, large salads, soups, 
 shakes and smoothies. 11 locations in Palm Beach County.

 Offerdahl&apos;s 
 Cafe Grill ( web 
 site )
Substitute tofu for any protein, hummus instead of cream cheese. Menu also 
 includes a&quot;Very Vegan&quot;hummus sandwich, black bean burger and excellent meatless 
 chili. Soy milk available for coffee. Boca Raton location.

 Panera 
 Bread ( web site )
A great lunch at Panera is their black bean or garden vegetable soup (both vegan) in a sourdough bread bowl. Also a good place for bagels and salads. 
 Eleven locations in Palm Beach County.

 Pei 
 Wei Asian Diner ( web 
 site )
&quot;Flavors from Thailand, Vietnam, Japan, Korea and China.&quot;Order 
 vegetables&amp;tofu in any of their signature dishes, noodle&amp;rice 
 bowls. Locations in Wellington, Boynton Beach and Boca Raton.

 P.F. 
 Chang&apos;s China Bistro ( web 
 site )
Several vegan dishes. We recommend the vegetarian Ma Po Tofu entree (tofu 
 in a spicy sauce with steamed broccoli) and the vegetarian lettuce wraps appetizer.
Locations in Palm Beach Gardens and Boca Raton.

 Pollo 
 Tropical ( web 
 site )
Very tasty black beans and white rice. Side dishes incude boiled yuca, fried 
 yuca, sweet plantains, and balsamic tomatoes. Order separately, or try the&quot;Vegetarian TropiChop&quot;(black beans&amp;rice with salad). The 
 corn has dairy in it. We recommend the drive-thru; the chicken carcasses on 
 the grill can ruin your appetite. 10 locations in Palm Beach County.

 Seasons 52 ( website )
Recommended for its vegan options, including the Winter Market Vegetable Plate (roasted vegetables, grilled tofu and cracked wheat tabbouleh). Also, vegan soups, salads and appetizers, and delicious flatbreads that can be made vegan. Tofu may be substituted for meat in other dishes (ask your server). Locations in Boca Raton and Palm Beach Gardens.

 Sweet 
 Tomatoes ( web 
 site )
Vegan salads and soups. Several vegetarian pasta dishes. Buffet-style. Locations 
 in West Palm Beach and Boca Raton.

 Tijuana Flats ( web site )
Quality, fast Mexican food. They can pretty much make anything—burritos, enchiladas, tacos, chimichangas—vegan. (Black beans are vegan; refried beans have cheese.) Very reasonably priced. Palm Beach Gardens location.

 TooJay&apos;s ( web site )
We recommend the simple but delicious Mediterranean Health Trio (tabouleh, hummus and fresh fruit salad, served with pita bread), but TooJay&apos;s menu also includes sandwiches (Vegetable Reuben Ciabatta, Portobello Mushroom Stack), roasted vegetable wrap and other options for vegans and vegetarians. 9 locations in Palm Beach County.

 Whole 
 Foods Market ( web 
 site )
Salad bar, soups, and a hot bar where you can usually find several vegetarian 
 dishes. If you&apos;re lucky, you may find vegan cookies or cakes in the bakery 
 department. Locations in Wellington, Palm Beach Gardens and Boca Raton .
	</body>
</document>
