<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004779" url="http://www.mcall.com/topic/" time="2012-07-12-21:17" support="135" score="0.20248502754403688" bingtitle="Topic Galleries -- mcall.com" webtitle="Topic Galleries -- mcall.com">
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000591" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001458" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000092" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000980" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000328" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001031" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000682" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000339" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000804" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000088" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001402" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000780" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001240" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000332" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000082" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000072" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000581" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000525" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000518" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001429" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000792" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001150" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001331" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000203" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000338" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000672" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000698" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000326" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001472" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001341" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001206" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001440" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000809" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>Order Back Issue; Purchase Photos; Purchase Reprints; Archives; Contact Us; Feedback; SUBMIT AN EVENT; Resources. Apartments; Public Notices; RSS Feeds; History; PA Treasury</description>
	<body>
		ALWAYS FREE: PLACE AN AD JOBS CARS APARTMENTS HOMES STORE HOME DELIVERY 
   
 

89°F
 Thursday, July 12 , 2012 3:03 PM EDT 
 HOME 
 MC VIP DEALS CLASSIFIEDS TICKETS Pictures Videos POLLS THE MIX Home&amp;Garden Bride&amp;Groom LV TRAFFIC WEATHER 
 NEWS 
 LOCAL NEWS ELECTION 2012 BREAKING NEWS COLUMNISTS PENNSYLVANIA IN THE &apos;BURBS NATIONAL OPINION LV TRAFFIC SUBMIT A TIP 
 COMMUNITIES 
 EASTON AREA EAST PENN NORTHAMPTON PARKLAND WHITEHALL 2012 GRADUATIONS SUBMIT A TIP 
 POLICE 
 Local police news POLICE AND FIRE COVERAGE MAP SCAMS WATCHDOG LV TRAFFIC ROAD WARRIOR 
 SPORTS 
 VARSITY IRONPIGS PHILLIES OLYMPICS EAGLES PENN STATE FLYERS SIXERS OUTDOORS NASCAR GOLF CALENDAR COLUMNISTS FANSHOP 
 BUSINESS 
 LOCAL ON THE CHEAP RETAIL WATCH Watchdog EMPLOYMENT TOOLKIT BLOGS Lehigh Valley Top Stocks 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 MUSIC MOVIES TV CELEBRITY RESTAURANTS NIGHTLIFE ARTS/CULTURE DAY TRIPS KIDS GAMES COMICS EVENTS COMMUNITY CALENDAR 
 LIFE 
 HEALTH FOOD FAMILY KIDS BOOKS GARDENING PETS ARTS TRAVEL VACATION STARTER SHOPPING SCOUT HOROSCOPES THE MIX EVENTS 
 OPINION 
 WHITE CARPENTER LETTERS SUBMIT LETTERS YOUR VIEW EXPLAIN IT TO ME iTHINK WHO DREW IT BEST? BLOGOSPHERE ASK THE EDITORS 
 BLOGS 
 CAPITOL IDEAS LV MUSIC TV WATCHERS LV HEALTH GROLLER PHILLIES FILES HOG BLOG VALLEY 610 BILL WHITE LV PARENTING MORE BLOGS 
 OBITS 
 TODAY&apos;S OBITUARIES OBITUARY SEARCH In Memoriam Form 
 VIDEO 
 VIRAL VIDEO LOCAL NEWS VIDEO ENTERTAINMENT VIDEO SPORTS VIDEO HSS/VARSITY VIDEO OUTDOORS VIDEO ON THE CHEAP VIDEO 
 ALWAYS FREE: PLACE AN AD JOBS CARS APARTMENTS HOMES 
 HOMES RENTAL HOMES NEW CONSTRUCTION OPEN HOUSES AUCTIONS APARTMENT RENTALS COMMERCIAL PROPERTIES 
 STORE HOME DELIVERY 
 
 FEATURED: LIVE: Arena Demo Webcams NEW: Northampton Area News COVERAGE 2012 Olympics REASSESSMENT: Lehigh Co. Tax Bills 
 
 
 
 
 Advanced Search 
Advanced Search
 X 
 include all of these words: include any of these words: include this exact phrase: exclude: Select a date range this week past 30 days past 3 months past year Create a custom date range From: To: 
 
Topic Galleries ( Beta ) 
 
Topic galleries provide easy access to stories and photos about people, places, organizations, events and subjects of interest to you. 
 They bring together rich multimedia content from across our network of newspaper and TV Web sites.
 You&apos;ll find thousands of topics, from hot issues to celebrities and from local festivals to global phenomena.
 Top Topics Northrop Grumman Shipbuilding Baltimore Orioles Bear Creek Mountain Resort&amp;Conference Center Republican Party Promenade Shops Dunkin&apos; Donuts Jesse Jackson Ric Bradshaw Mark R. Warner Volkswagen Nissan Subaru Layoffs and Downsizing Hersheypark Nancy Pelosi Hampton Bay Days Celticfest Chicago Bears Penn&apos;s Peak Floods Motorvehicle Accidents Yale University Paula Abdul Google Inc. Maxwell Street   Northrop Grumman Shipbuilding Baltimore Orioles Bear Creek Mountain Resort&amp;Conference Center Republican Party Promenade Shops Dunkin&apos; Donuts Jesse Jackson Ric Bradshaw Mark R. Warner Volkswagen Nissan Subaru Layoffs and Downsizing Hersheypark Nancy Pelosi Hampton Bay Days Celticfest Chicago Bears Penn&apos;s Peak Floods Motorvehicle Accidents Yale University Paula Abdul Google Inc. Maxwell Street 
 1 / 25 
 see ranking of popular topics» Search or Browse for a Topic collapse results Browse Topics 
 Animals
 Celebrated Animals Celebrities Fictional Animals Species 
 Entertainment
 Celebrities Concerts Educational Movies Plays and Musicals TV Programs 
 Events
 Accidents and Disasters Arts and Culture Business and Economic Charitable and Community Concerts Crime Victims and Criminals Criminal and Legal Education Entertainment Events Festivals Government and Politics Governmental Historic Military Events and Wars Scientific and Technological Significant Sports Weather and Natural Disasters 
 Facets
 Formats Genres 
 Health
 Behavioral Conditions Dentistry Diets Diseases and Illnesses Drugs and Medicines Epidemics and Plagues Exercises Health Programs Healthcare Professionals Hospitals and Clinics Human Anatomy Indications and Symptoms Injuries and Wounds Medical Specializations Physical Conditions Procedures and Surgeries Supplements and Vitamins Therapies and Treatments 
 Organizations
 Clubs and Interest Groups Corporations Cultural Education Educational Governmental Hospitals and Clinics Nonprofits Sports Teams 
 People
 Athletes Business Leaders Celebrities Crime Victims and Criminals Fictional Characters Healthcare Professionals Historical Figures Politicians Religious Leaders Sports 
 Physical Activities
 Celebrities Exercises Politicians 
 Places
 Cultural and Civic Entertainment and Dining Geo Locations Landmarks Places of Worship Recreational Shopping 
 Products
 Appliances and Housewares Bedding and Linens Beverages and Foods Books Car Makes and Models Cards, Gift Wrapping, and Stationary Clothing, Accessories and Shoes Consumer Electronics Drugs and Medicines Flowers and Plants Furniture Games and Toys Health and Personal Care Luggage Musical Instruments Office Products Periodicals Recreation and Sports Sound Recordings Tickets 
 Subjects 
 
 All Events Organizations People Places Subjects 
 view: All | Accidents and Disasters | Arts and Culture | Business and Economic | Charitable and Community | Concerts | Crime Victims and Criminals | Criminal and Legal | Education | Entertainment Events | Festivals | Government and Politics | Governmental | Historic | Military Events and Wars | Scientific and Technological | Significant | Sports | Weather and Natural Disasters view: All | Clubs and Interest Groups | Corporations | Cultural | Education | Educational | Governmental | Hospitals and Clinics | Nonprofits | Sports Teams view: All | Athletes | Business Leaders | Celebrities | Crime Victims and Criminals | Fictional Characters | Healthcare Professionals | Historical Figures | Politicians | Religious Leaders | Sports view: All | Cultural and Civic | Entertainment and Dining | Geo Locations | Landmarks | Places of Worship | Recreational | Shopping view: All | Geo Locations 0 - 9 A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X - Z Loading... 
   ! !!! (music group)   $ $700 Billion Bank Bailout (2008)   1 1-800 Contacts Inc. 1-800-Flowers 10 km and 15 km Combined Skiing 10 Most Fascinating People (tv program), The 10 Things I Hate About You (movie) 
 
 10,000 B.C. (movie) 10,000 Maniacs (music group) 100 M Backstroke 100 M Breaststroke 100 M Butterfly 100 M Freestyle Swimming 100 M Hurdles 100 M Sprint 100 Monkeys (music group) 100 Yard Dash 110 M Hurdles 12 (movie, 2007) 12 Angry Men (movie) 12 Hours of Sebring 12 Rounds (movie) 
 
 127 Hours (movie) 12th Planet (music group) 13 (movie) 13: The Fear is Real (tv program) 1500 M Race 1600 Penn (tv program) 17 Again (movie) 1958 NFL Championship Game 1st Fighter Wing (military unit) 1st Mariner Arena 1st Source Corp.   2 2 Broke Girls (tv program) 2 Mile Run 
 
 Advertisement 
 
 Special Sections 
 Outlook 2012 Breast Cancer Community Guide 2011 Career Training Education Guide Readers Choice NIE - Newspapers In Education Public Notices War Stories: In Their Own Words 
 

 Special Sections 
 H&amp;G;Directory Travel Agent Guide Bride&amp;Groom Outlook 2011 Inside Lehigh And Berks Counties Valley Health Your New Lifestyles 55+ Summer Fun Spots 
 

 Advertising 
 Contact Advertising Department Jobs Cars Real Estate Apartments FSBO Homes For Sale Place an Ad Interactive Media Kit 
 

 Milestones 
 Births Obituaries Engagements 
 

 Services 
 No Paper? Digital Subscriptions Home Delivery
Subscriptions Vacation Options Order Back Issue Purchase Photos Purchase Reprints Archives Contact Us Feedback SUBMIT AN EVENT Be a workout winner 
 

 Resources 
 Apartments Public Notices RSS Feeds PA Treasury PA Lottery NJ Lottery Grocery Coupons Online Coupons Internships Submit: Me and My Grandma (or Grandpa) Submit: My Fuzzy Friend 
 
 
 
 Privacy Policy Terms of Service About Our Ads 

 Baltimore Sun Chicago Tribune Daily Press Hartford Courant Los Angeles Times Orlando Sentinel Sun Sentinel The Morning Call 
 
 The Morning Call, 101 North Sixth Street, Allentown, PA 18101 
 
 A Tribune Newspaper website
	</body>
</document>
