<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004077" url="http://www.interior-decorating-ideas-for-you.com/restaurant.html" time="2012-07-12-20:18" support="20" score="0.03731037195854934" bingtitle="Restaurant - Decorating Ideas Family Owned Business" webtitle="Restaurant - Decorating Ideas Family Owned Business">
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001018" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000293" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000877" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000307" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000313" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000306" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>I personally love going into an inviting place to eat. To me, besides the food, the decor makes or breaks a business. When you enter your establishment, look through ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant - Decorating Ideas
A Family Owned Business
 Your restaurant is family owned. You have worked and will continue to work so hard at 
the number one priority, pleasing your customers and bringing them back.

One of the most 
important aspects of running a business besides customer satisfaction, is the look and 
feel of the total environment.


 
 I personally love going into an inviting place to eat. 
To me, besides the food, the decor makes or breaks a business.

When you enter your establishment, look through the eyes of each of each customer.

Is the outside reflect the area you live, or do you want to create your 
own unique flavor through your foundation theme?

Does the entrance, booths or tables 
create an invitation for relaxation and enjoyment?

 What about your theme? A theme stems from your own thoughts and personality. 
The name of your restaurant will be an important aspect of the overall theme. Get 
creative or just keep the name simple.

Make it stand out in your customers mind. Of course 
the food and atmosphere is your main criteria to bring your customers back again. Overall color scheme. Know what colors compliment each other.

 







I like the first photo with the cows. If you have a steak place or an establishment in a country setting, 
great idea. You can also think about if you are in the city, unique idea to draw your customers inside.

The second picture is popular in many businesses. The board outside with the menu. Great idea to share your curb 
side appeal with your fabulous menu.

Are you looking for some original photos to add some excitement to your establishment? TK Creations has many different items that you can used 
to decorate with your own personality. Great year around ideas to spruce up your business and entice your customers with style!

If you are just starting 
out and doing it yourself, think of the overall feel of your business. Are you creating 
a formal, informal, fun, bizarre, or just simple, ma and pa type of place? If you are contracting 
out some of the decorating, be involved as remember, this is your family owned business.

 







These next two photos shares two different look and feel. The first picture gives you the total look of the outside establishment. 
Blue is the color theme and this is where you bring the blue tones right inside.

I like the idea of inside providing the atmosphere 
with blue in your accessories and accents and neutral or white walls. Think about your style and maybe Blue Willow dishes would work 
well with the color scheme. A French country theme comes to mind.

The second picture can easily be seen as a nautical theme. I love the wood look and also the helm or steering wheel. This sets the tone inside. The walls are sponged in blue to create the 
atmosphere of the sea or ocean. Great idea for coastals establishments.

 







The first picture&apos;s interior sets the atmosphere for a dining experience. The orange and green represent warm colors, and a flare of 
modern to oriental booths create a look and feel for a variety of different menus. The accent of the wood beams gives this eating place 
a unique feel.

The second photo has a totally different interior. I like the blending in of the brick beams with the gold-yellow and brick tone 
striped carpet. Another color is introduced with the soft blue tone chair cushions. A great accessory is putting decorating lighting 
on the brick posts to highlight this feature. A great look and feel for a variety of themes and menus.

 Think of all aspects of the room or rooms, and the total layout of the business.

Ceilings, walls, 
floors, tables, chairs, or lounge area. If you have a small area, create the area to give it a more 
open appearance. Warm colors from the color wheel and also soft tones.





 If you have a restaurant and want an old time look, accents and accessories are wonderful. Play off your theme with the right styles of pictures, collectables, 
furniture, window treatments, etc...

If you are doing a family base 
create that nostalgia feel throughout the place with frames that match, lighting, tables, and chairs. 
Decorating any type of interior space in your family restaurant should be one that reflects you, your customers, and your 
location. This is one of the items I personally look at when I go to any type of family owned business.

 Having owned my own 
off line business and now an on line business, I take high pride in how the overall feel of the business, as well as satisfying 
my customers and visitors.

Decorating your restaurant doesn&apos;t have to exceed your budget. Plan your overall decorating scheme, and 
if you are redoing your interior or exterior, keep in mind some of the ideas above.

 









Identify your theme whether it be a certain era, 
animal, natural wonder, country, etc... and go with those base colors.

If you have a beach or maybe a tropical establishment, think of the water, sand, and other natural colors. 
If you live in a tourist area or a large city your competition is going to be greater. This is where 
you can bring your own unique style of decorating in.

 Make the locals as well as the traveler feel welcome. 
Stand out from the other family restaurants by putting your own flare of decor.

You may have a successful business due
to your wonderful food, but if it lacks the right colors and decor to fit the name or menu, the balance and your look and feel will be off.

Small town family owned restaurants usually don&apos;t have as much competition, maybe a few chain establishments. 
This is where you can shine and bring in the local heritage, outdoor environment, and your special look and feel. Country 
decor usually has a simplistic style.

Don&apos;t be afraid to put some stripes with plaids as long as your color tones and the 
sizes of the stipes and plaids don&apos;t clash. Red and white checker tablecloths are also very popular for a country look.

Maybe 
you have a fruit or vegetable base theme, take off from that and make your colors, accents, and accessories match the fruit or 
vegetables. The page on the decorating with peppers gives you some ideas of accessories that would match into a pepper theme.



 Formal places are relaxing with more classical or jazz style. The &quot;happening&quot; place to go will do well with 
an upbeat, but not overbearing music.

Let your customers enjoy the his or her experience with you. Give them 
the interior atmosphere along with your food that will make them walk out with a smile. You will also know 
there is a pretty good chance he or she will return.

Think about putting some Whimsical Decor for you own establishment. Put accessories into your own business to give your customer that personal touch.

If you have any questions on decorating your family owned 
restaurant, feel free to contact me and I would be happy to give you some ideas and suggestions. Feel free to 
pop over into the 
I hope this page has given you a few ideas 
on how to take your family owned restaurant and decorate for your customers, through your own personality.

One place that 
Tom and I visited was San Diego&apos;s Old Town. Cafe Coyote restaurant
was a hit in our eyes. The music set the tone as we walk up to be seated. Once inside the decor stood out and we both had 
a feeling if the food was good, this was going to be a memorable experience. The food was really good!

 Your family owned restaurant is your true pride and joy. The menu, food, atmosphere, and decor play the lead 
roles in your business being a success.

A couple of final thoughts for you. Attire for your staff should also reflect 
the colors you decorate both on your outside and inside. Music also plays a big factor on the atmosphere of your 
customers dining experience. Nature eating establishments are great with soft water running, CD&apos;s with soothing 
music.


 


Below is a great place for you and others to write about your own restaurants or visitors can write about their own favorite restaurant. 
Great publicity and also a chance to show off your own style.


 Do You Own - Manage A City Or Family Restaurant? 

 
Ah, the fast pace of city living, or the quiet atmosphere of a small town. Do you own or manage a a restaurant? What is it about your restaurant that makes your customers satisfied? Share with us the details. What is your decor and theme? This is a great way also to get free publicity right here on the Internet. If you are a customer, feel free also to share your favorite restaurant with all of us. Eating out is a great way to unwind and relax, have a productive business meeting, an enjoy business peers, family, and friends. 
 
Name And Location Of Restaurant

 


 Bring On Your Restaurant To All Of Us [ ? ] 
 
 Close Help 

 Go ahead and share -

 
 
 
 


 Upload 1-4 Pictures or Graphics (optional) [ ? ] 
 
 Close Help 

 Do you have a picture to add? Great! Click the button and find it on your computer. Then select it.
 
 
 
 

Add a Picture/Graphic Caption (optional)   

 Click here to upload more images (optional) 
 


 

Add a Picture/Graphic Caption (optional)   



 

Add a Picture/Graphic Caption (optional)   



 

Add a Picture/Graphic Caption (optional)   
 


Author Information (optional)

To receive credit as the author, enter your information below.

 
Your Name
 
 (first or full name) 
 
Your Location
 
 (ex. City, State, Country) 
 



Submit Your Contribution

 Check box to agree to these submission guidelines .

 
 (You can preview and edit on the next page) 
 
 Read About Other Restaurants 

 
What do you think about these restaurants?

 
 Juke Joint Restaurant&amp;Blues Exhibit, Vicksburg, MS   
Best Southern Fried Chicken, Wings&amp;Burgers. In the heart of downtown Vicksburg, MS. The setting is filled with Blues&amp;Jazz inspired art.

 Lucky T&apos;z Mossville, IL   
Homemade menu! The building was built in 1845 and has an amazing history! Only open over a week now but looking forward to learning to make it a great ...

 Corner Bistro in Towne Lake (Woodstock, GA)   
We are getting ready to redecorate on a budget of course.. :) We have a patio with wrought iron and red and black umbrellas. Getting ready to do some ...

 The Dizzy Diner in Terry, Montana   
The Diner features inside seating as well as a drive thru. They feature a full menu with breakfast served all day. They are open year round with hours ...
 

 Return To Themes 

 Return To Interior Home 

 
 
 Bring Beauty Of The Tropics Inside 
 
 


 
 The New Restaurant Entrepreneur:
An Inside Look
at Restaurant
Deal-Making
and Other Tales
from the
Culinary Trenches 

 Decorate
With Your
Own Personality 
 


 
 Kimberly
Your Everyday
Interior Designer 

 
 My Story
Love Of Colors
And Designing 
 
 

 
 
 Checkerboard Decorating 
 
 


 Amazon.com Widgets 

 
 Restaurant Decorating Ideas 
 
 

 Inside Scoop 
 Interior Home 

 Interior Blog 

 My Story 
 Our Stores 
 Christmas Year
Around Shop 


 Inside Out
Decorating Store 

 TK Creations 

 Decorate Foundation 
 Color Wheel 

 Room Decorating 

 Walls&amp;Ceiling 

 Kids Corner 
 Fun Decorating 
 Party Decorating 

 Themes 

 Accents 

 Accessories 

 Holiday - Seasonal 
 Share With Others 
 Cool Room Ideas - Kids 

 Arranging Fresh Flowers 

 Decorating Tips 

 Christmas Decorating 
 Chat And Find 
 Special Links 

 Site Navigator 
 Be Our Sponsor 
 Sponsor And Advertise 
 Outside Decorating 
 Outside In
Garden Store 

 Landscape Solutions 

 [ ? ] Subscribe To This Site 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 

 Privacy Policy | Indoor Contact 
 
 
 www.interior-decorating-ideas-for-you.com | All Rights Reserved 
 Copyright 2012
 Return to top
	</body>
</document>
