<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004640" url="http://www.lessbrittmorelife.com/" time="2012-07-12-21:08" support="3" score="0.0034278568130670785" bingtitle="LessBritt &amp; MoreLife LessBritt &amp; MoreLife |" webtitle="LessBrittMoreLife LessBrittMoreLife |">
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>Favorite fast food restaurant? Chick-fil-A or Popeyes ... Which store would you choose to max out your credit card? ... The top contains a tray into which hot coals are ...</description>
	<body>
		LessBritt &amp; MoreLife 
 
 Home About Me Blogroll Bucket List Contact Me Disclosure Progress Quotes 
 
 1 year 
 2 3 days by Brittany in Austin , blogging , journey , life , love Tweet 
 Today, July 10th, marks a rather big anniversary for me. It may not seem like a big deal to some of you, but it is to me It’s been a year that I’ve lived in Austin! I can’t believe it’s been a year already. Some days it feels like i just moved here, and others it feels like I’ve been living in Austin for 5 years.   This was a big change for me.  I followed my heart and my dreams, packed up my things, and moved to a new state and a new city. While i did have family and a few friends in Austin before i moved, I’ve grown more than I ever thought I would. I’ve grown and learned a lot this year. Always listen to yourself and your heart, NO MATTER WHAT! Can’t wait to see what the next year has in store! 

 

 The last year in photographs: 
 
Car packed up, let&apos;s get the move on!
 
curls, smiles, wine, and friends 
 
colors are fun.
 
Coldplay at ACL! amazing.
 
Sister and I at ACL!
 
love having a friend from Lafayette living in Austin 
 
Lafayette bound for Erika&apos;s wedding! 
 
The bride and I! 
 
Claddagh ring and engagement ring love! 
 
The bride and I... picking up her dress 
 
THE DRESS 
 
Bathroom pictures are the best
 
Heather and I watching the NFC Championship Game
 
laughing hysterically, always
 
my birthday. stubb&apos;s. cold weather. middle sister.
 
birthdays rock!
 
 
 
everyone needs to wear red lipstick at least once 
 
smile. always.
 
 
 
Brittany Mullins&amp;Isaac came to Austin! Love them 
 
park date with kelly and bella!
 
went home for Festival Internationale! Love this place 
 
friends and festival&lt;3
 
Holden boys!
 
aviators, sunshine, Saints, and smiles 
 
Lake Travis- Memorial Day
 
always the happy one.
 
smiles and sunburns
 
love this one, Ash! 
 
whoaaaa. my hair really is getting long!
 
Love Miss Amelia! 
 
the high school girls and one of our favorite guys 
 
BFF kissy faces are the bestttt
 
2 of the best friends a girl could ask for!&lt;3&lt;3&lt;3
 
2 of my favorite friends in Austin 
 
A haircut, aviators, and red lipstick ?! Yes please! 
 
almost back to Austin 
 
 


 I finally learned how to use my toilet plunger and use it effectively, ha. I learned that it’s okay to be single and happy Still working on the being single and happy with it par I’ve learned it can be fun to hangout by yourself, reading, or just doing nothing at all I’ve learned that being an adult sucks sometimes, and that’s all there is to it I’ve learned that making new friends as an adult, is A LOT harder, than making new friends as a child / teenager Friends are made more easily when you find people that you have things in common with, obvs. Even though your best friends live 6 hours away from you, there’ll always be there no matter what, and you’ll miss them A LOT when you see them, and then have to go back to your new home. I’ve learned that even though i’m super outgoing, happy, energetic, extroverted, and silly; it’s okay to be quiet and reserved sometimes too. I’ve learned that i don’t always have to say or do something when there’s that awkward silence. It’s okay to just be quiet.&lt;—- WHOA! That’s a big one. I’ve learned that not everyone is raised on hugging all the time. Attempting to hug people that aren’t super hug-gy is SUPER awkward. Not everyone likes to take pictures and be in pictures as much as i do. 

 
 Festival Internationale de Louisiane! 
 0 21 days by Brittany in cajun , festivals , friends , life , Louisiana , love Tweet 
 Festival Internationale is one of my favorite festivals in the world, and one of my favorite things about Louisiana! This festival is all about sharing franco-phone, french speaking culture, music, cajun food, cajun hospitality, having a wonderful time enjoying great people, music, food, culture,&amp;dancing!

 

“Festival International de Louisiane is a community-based, non-profit arts organization formed in 1986 to produce an annual visual and performing arts festival celebrating the French cultural heritage of southern Louisiana–primarily a combination of French, African, Caribbean and Hispanic influences. The largest outdoor, FREE Francophone event in the U.S., the Festival places special emphasis on highlighting the connections between Acadiana and the Francophone world. Each year performing, visual and culinary artists from Europe, Africa, Canada, the Caribbean and the Americas are invited to share their talents with Louisiana artists, residents and visitors.

 Since its creation, Festival International de Louisiane has become famous as a premier presenter of some of the most unique world musicians and performances in the United States. Popular Louisiana artists such as Aaron Neville, Dr. John, Irma Thomas, Allan Toussaint, Zachary Richard, Sonny Landreth, Beausoleil, Buckwheat Zydeco, Boozoo Chavis, Amedee“Bois Sec”Ardoin, D.L. Menard, Terrance Simien, C.J. Chenier, Geno Delafose, Marc Broussard, Marcia Ball, Clarence“Gatemouth”Brown, Canray Fontenot and Buddy Guy have all performed on our stages.” source 

 

 It’s so many kinds of amazing! It’s pretty much life changing I got to see some of my favorite people, have an amazing day, enjoy the sunshine, dancing, good beer, food, and lots of laughter! 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 


 

 

 
 
 Wordless Wednesday 
 3 57 days by Brittany in Wordless Wednesday Tweet 
Game DAAAAAAY!
 
I make funny faces on a regular day 
 
Happy Hour at Chuy&apos;s = THEEEEE best!
 
FREE SEAN PAYTON!
 
Purple and gold wearing Saturday&apos;s are the best! 
 
werdddddd.
 
Love my Mama!!! 
 
Smiling is the best.
 
Wide-brimmed hats are my fave! =)
 
ahhhhh yes. Be still my heart!
 
Friends are the best! They make life sweeter and more bearable!&lt;3
 
 Days 1 and 2 in Lafayette 
 3 65 days by Brittany in friends , Louisiana , love , Photography Tweet 
 

Oh man. I love Louisiana and Lafayette for that matter. ALWAYS will! I learned a few valuable lessons while in Lafayette:

 

 Lafayette will ALWAYS be my home NO MATTER WHAT !  Lafayette and Louisiana in general, will always have a HUGE piece of my heart. I have a new“home”now. Whoaaaa that’s a big realization! I need to work on maintaining my old friendships, and work on my new friendships in Austin as well! Apparently people in Austin may not like hearing about everything Louisiana / cajun / home ALLLLL the time?!?! Who’da thunk it? haha. I have used my Louisiana roots as part of my identity for SO long. It will always be a part of who I AM.  It isn’t everything of who I am. That’s for sure! I’m excited about the new friends I’ve made over the past few months. God has brought them into my life at the EXACT moment I needed though! WOW! Amazing how those things work, ehhhh??? I’ve missed cajun dancing and dancing in general in my life. A LOT!!!!  That needs to change MUCH sooner than later! 
 Days 1 and 2 as captured by photograph — 
smiles
 
A beautiful day for a road trip!
 
well hello there, Boudin Capital of the World!!!!! 
 
A beautiful sight! 
 
The caaaautest man was sitting outside enjoying his meats! 
 
My hair really is getting long!
 
best friends = happiness
 
LOVE her!&lt;3
 
happiness. joy. peace.
 
no words needed.
 
I love the open road.
 
 
 
Callin&apos;Baton Rougeeeeee! 
 
 
 
Tiger Stadium, baaaabbby!
 
Ben&amp;Dad
 
what you lookin&apos;at?
 
 
 
yeah girlllll.
 
 
 
cheeeeeeeeeese 
 
Love.
 
beautiful ladies!&lt;3
 
Lurrrrrrve Miss A!
 
Shan&amp;I .... more BFF love 
 
smiles and awe.
 
 Wordless Wednesday 
 2 71 days by Brittany in Wordless Wednesday Tweet 
Just a few snippits from my weekend in Lafayette! LOTS more to come posts 
 YES YES YES!!!!! 
 
 I-10 east bound! Mike&amp;Benedict! 
 This kid has my heart!!!!!!&lt;3 
 The amazing and wonderful Denton’s! 
 Shan and Miss Amelia!&lt;3 
 Joni’s smiling with teeth!!!! MISSION ACCOMPLISHED!!!! :) 
 laughter = the best picture! 

 
 
 
 A BIG Purchase!! :D 
 11 73 days by Brittany in Photography , Texas Hill Country Tweet 
For about 4 years, i’ve been wanting a DSLR! I’ve been wanting to do something with my love of photography! I finally started doing more research and decided on what i wanted!

 

I knew i wanted to stick with Canon, and go with the Rebel series! Thanks to my savings and my glorious federal tax return i could finally get that BEAAAAUTIFUL DSLR! I went with a Canon Rebel T2i! LOVE LOVE LOVE!!!!!!!
 
YAY! 
 
 

 

This is Claiborne Hester Flynn Staires! And I LOVE HIM!!! ALOT! 

 

I couldn’t be more excited! I really have been taking pictures of EVERYTHING and EVERYONE! It’s awesome. ha.

I went with the body kit lens 18-mm. It’s pretty good for close up things and people. But as far for the zoom factor, not so much. I’ll be doing research and looking into getting a zoom lens. Any input on a zoom lens would be great!

 

Here are just a few pictures that i took in Texas Hill Country!&lt;3&lt;3&lt;3
 
One of my favoriteeeeees!
 
 
 
Wildflower Celebration!
 
:)
 
something about fences....
 
Fences&amp;Flowers ... 2 of my fave things! 
 
Texas Hill Country 
 
A smiling photographer is a happy photographer!
 
 Thoughtless Thursdays! 
 10 91 days by Brittany in Austin , friends , life , love , Wordless Wednesday Tweet 
 Thoughtless Thursdays are one of my favorite kinds of posts! What a better way to get back into the swing of blogging?! And my life is pretty amazing! Gosh i love it A Lot. 

 
 
Partaaaaaay time! 
 
Boudin Balls at Cypress Grill are always a great choice! 
 
I&apos;m officially a resident of Texas, ya&apos;ll.
 
So i bought the beer for a girls weekend... but let&apos;s just say it didn&apos;t get dranken / drunken 
 
Jana and I laughing hysterically about tequila and boob was encroaching her elbow space... pahahahah. Love that woman!
 
PS–Give Jana some blog love, ya’ll!
 
Miss Amelia Denton has arrived!!!! She was born on March 7th! What a great week to be born on Love her so much already!
 
Shan, Ben, and Amelia&lt;3
 
Sister and I! Givers was such a great start to my birthday night!&lt;3 you!
 
Frost Bank Tower in the rain = a beaut!
 
Birthday lovin at the SXSW Samsung party! I called it the SXSW hipster party pahahaha.
 
Ghostland Observatory recording live for ACL Live! We heard about the free concert via facebook! Gotta love social media Finally got my Team Gleason shirt NO WHITE FLAGS! Let&apos;s find a cause and cure for ALS!
 
Amber and I met some random guy from New Orleans! Gotta love cajuns and Louisianaians! 
 
Amber and I kissy faces + cajuns = pure louisiana love!
 
St. Patty&apos;s day excitement + Lafayette friends living in Austin + good beer + Lucy&apos;s = so much unbelieveable amazingness!
 
 
 
Bronze Radio Return at SXSW! Amaaaazing! Do yourself a favor and check them out 
 
 
 
Tyrone Wells at SXSW!
 
Miss Amelia Evangeline Denton at 11 days old!
 
early morning.
 
 

 
 
getting ready for Mik&apos;s birthday party! I love wearing red lipstick 
 
My first flip cup game! So fun We won 3 out of the 4 games. And i learned that the more you drink, the harder it is to flip the cup! pahahaha 
 
My new friend L-awesome, and I! Having boys take pictures after a few drinks = kinda fail.
 
Saturday drives with the windows down, music up, and singing at the top of my lungs are my faveee! 
 
One of my favoriteeeee people, G!&lt;3
 
smile. You&apos;re always winning!
 
V, G, and I after dinner!
 
Once a who dat, always a who dat! No. Matter. What. So much love!&lt;3
 
Driving through car washes are still one of my favorite things to do! 
 
work faces of Brittany! I sure am something special 
 
One of my most favorite cajuns, EVER! Can&apos;t wait to see you in 2-ish weeks, J!
 
A new beer that i love, St. Arnold&apos;s Spring Bock! St. Arnold&apos;s is a craft beer located in TEXAS! woot 
 
Brooklyn Lager FTW, at pint night!
 
Curls + smiles + free payton tshirt = a winning combo!
 
 

 

 
 
 I’m baaaaaaack :) 
 1 135 days by Brittany in Austin , Birthday , blends , Louisiana , love , Mardi Gras , nursing Tweet 
Hi friends!

It’s quite a while since i’ve really blogged! But the down time and break has been very much needed! Work has been crazy, but good, and busy. 2 of the girls on my medical team have been having issues, so they’ve been out a lot, and i’ve been working more over the past few weeks! Phewwww. Glad things are calming down-ish.

 

Austin’s doing great. Late winter/early spring/spring is my favorite time of the year, while besides football season Flowers and trees blooming, grass growing, sun shining, cool air, good times. AHHHH my fave.

 

This year was the first time in my life i had work on Lundi Gras / Mardi Gras / Ash Wednesday! Gosh that was no fun AT ALL! It was also the first year i missed partaking in Mardi Gras! NEVER AGAIN! No matter where I’ll be living. I want to go home for Mardi Gras! Do one day of cajun/country Mardi Gras, some Mardi Gras in Lafayette, and New Orleans Mardi Gras! So much fun! There is so much more to Mardi Gras than boobs and beads, people! There’s dancing, cooking, eating, drinking, being with friends and family, parades, fun signs, balls, getting dolled and dressed up, the beauty of celebrating life!

 

I view life as one should celebrate Mardi Gras! Living life the best that you can, with all you have! No regrets. No looking back. Sure life may not be great all the time, but that’s okay. Just do the best you can, with what you have.

 

Being single sucks sometimes, but other times it’s great! Like if i was married or with kids, i wouldn’t just be able to go for a drive on a Sunday afternoon driving through Texas Hill Country But like 2 wise friends have reminded me this week, there is a guy out there for me! And he’s been waiting for me for almost his entire life, like i have been waiting for him for almost 26 years! whoa. Crazy awesomeness, but beautiful!

 

This weekend Austin won’t know what hit‘em! Some amazing bloggers that i know and love are coming to town! We’re gonna have such a good time! If you’re in Austin, let me know! I’d love for you to come meet us and have some good times too! Laissez Les Bon Temps Rouler! I can’t wait to meet Holly , Jana , Megan , Emily , Savannah , and Rochelle ! Jenn –we’re definitely going to miss you this weekend!

Two or three weeks ago Holly, Jana, and I started having iphone group text messages! Oh my gosh! So much fun! I love those ladies! They’re so many kinds of amazing and i can’t wait to meet them in THREEEEE days &lt;3

 

Yes i realized i haven’t talked about food, eating, and exercising! Well those have kind of been at a halt over the past few weeks! I’ll be working on small changes now, making changes stick, and not giving up when i want to, or when i get overwhelmed! Makes life-long changes is something easy that comes with time, and it’s something i know that i can do!

 

Oh yeahhhh—in 10 days i’ll be 26! Yes i said TWENTY-SIX! WHoaaaaaaa. That’s a BIG DEAL , ya’ll! In case you didn’t know it, I lurrrrrre birthdays! LOTS!

 

&lt;3

 
 
:)
 Next» 
 
Welcome!
 
My name is Brittany and I am a 26 year-old Nurse.

&quot;How do you go from where you are to where you want to be? I think you have to have an enthusiasm for life. You have to have a dream, a goal, and you have to be willing to work for it.&quot;
-- Jimmy Valvano

Follow along as i talk about losing weight, finding myself, life, living life in Austin, working as a nurse, being a crazy fanatical LSU and New Orleans Saints FAN, adventuring in and around Austin, making new friends, meeting new people, being an awesome 20-something and so much more!
 Search Website 
 My latest tweets 
 
 Yep. This is happening today. http://t.co/De9AhyIV about 5 hours ago from Instagram Reply Retweet Favorite Yep. – Zydeco Gris Gris by Pine Leaf Boys, from #SoundHound http://t.co/Z09TTWy3 about 5 hours ago from SoundHound ∞ Reply Retweet Favorite @barif0815 yesss!!!! It&apos;s so good ;) made with real sugar cane!!! about 5 hours ago from Twitter for iPhone in reply to barif0815 Reply Retweet Favorite Yes please!!!!!! :) #lsu #geauxtigers #lovepurplelivegold #purpleandgoldforeverrrr &lt;3 http://t.co/TBFVzngp about 5 hours ago from Instagram Reply Retweet Favorite @barif0815 jealous!!! Take my with you! I&apos;ll bring the beer :) about 5 hours ago from Twitter for iPhone in reply to barif0815 Reply Retweet Favorite 
 @CajunBrittinAtx 
Recent Posts
 
 1 year Festival Internationale de Louisiane! Wordless Wednesday Days 1 and 2 in Lafayette Wordless Wednesday 
 
Categories
 
 5k (1) America (1) apartments (1) Austin (42) Birthday (4) blends (13) blogging (6) cajun (6) cancer (1) changes (5) dating (1) emotional eating (3) exercising (3) family (6) festivals (1) finding myself (5) Fitbloggin (11) Five for Friday (2) food success (2) football (5) Friend Making Monday (1) friends (12) goals (6) Guest Blog Posts (3) half-marathon (9) Happy Hour (1) journey (14) life (50) live music (1) LIVESTRONG (1) Louisiana (5) love (17) LSU Tigers (4) Mardi Gras (3) mean people (2) New Orleans (5) New Orleans Saints (5) nursing (12) packing (1) Photography (2) tears (1) Texas Hill Country (1) true love. (5) Uncategorized (137) weddings (2) weight loss (11) weight watchers (9) WILW (1) Wordless Wednesday (7) 
 
stylish-blogger
 
Stylish Blogger Award
 
 LessBritt&amp;MoreLife ©2012 |

 Powered by WordPress and Mystique theme by digitalnature 
39 queries in 1.62 seconds
 (40.04M) Go to Top Facebook Twitter FourSquare RSS Yelp StumbleUpon Email Pinterest grab this
	</body>
</document>
