<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004196" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Subway-Greenbriar.html" time="2012-07-12-20:26" support="1" score="0.0007942209452203929" bingtitle="Subway Greenbriar, 13059A Lee Jackson Memorial Hwy, Fairfax, VA ..." webtitle="Subway Greenbriar, 13059A Lee Jackson Memorial Hwy, Fairfax, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>5-205.15B - The sink basin at the front counter is slow ... I will check temps before leaving to see if this ... This is a routine inspection at this fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Subway Greenbriar, 13059A Lee Jackson Memorial Hwy, Fairfax, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: Subway Greenbriar 
Address: 13059A Lee Jackson Memorial Hwy, Fairfax, Virginia 
Phone: (703) 378-3370 
Total inspections: 23 
Last inspection: May 29, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 2-401.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Open drinking containers stored in a manner that may contaminate food, food contact surfaces or utensils. Observed two uncovered drinks in kitchen. May 29, 2009 Critical Procedures 1 0 Details / Comments 
 3-305.11(A)(3) - Food stored on the floor and/or food stored less than 6 inches off the floor. Onions stored in rack on floor. 4-501.11(B) - Refrigerator shelf coating are peeling and beginning to rust. 43.1-3-5(a)-(c) - Critical The establishment has been closed and the permit to operate suspended due to the following imminent health hazard: Insufficient hot water at three vat and hand sinks. 5-103.11(A) - Critical There is insufficient hot water. The highest temperature observed at three vat sink and hand sinks was 90 F. 120 F is needed for manual washing and 100 F is needed for hand washing. 6-305.11(B) - Lockers or other suitable facilities are not provided for employees clothing and other possessions. Purse stored on shelf with food. 
 December 12, 2008 Routine 2 3 Details / Comments 
 2-301.12(A)-(B) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed food employee using improper handwashing procedures. No warm water and less than 20 seconds. 3-305.11(A)(3) - Food stored on the floor in the walk-in refrigerator. 4-501.11(A) - The following equipment was observed damaged and no longer smooth and easily cleaned or sanitized: shelves in a reach-in refrigerator are rusty. 6-303.11(B) - Observed that inadequate lighting was provided in the reach-in freezer. Bulb is out. 6-501.11 - Observed that the floor and walls in the kitchen are not maintained in good repair. 
 June 25, 2008 Routine 1 4 Details / Comments 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat The following food items were observed cold holding at improper temperatures using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: chicken and steak in containers on the prep line are 56F. January 07, 2008 Critical Procedures 1 0 Details / Comments 
 3-305.11(A)(3) - Corrected During Inspection Food stored on the floor,box of lettuce, of the walk-in refrigerator. 3-501.16(A)(2)(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following food item was observed cold holding at improper temperature using a calibrated food temperature measuring device: meatballs on the steam table are 118F. 4-204.112(B) - Corrected During Inspection There was no temperature measuring device located in one reach-in refrigerator. 4-302.14 - There is no bleach test kit located in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions. 4-501.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection The following equipment was observed damaged and no longer smooth and easily cleaned or sanitized: plastic containers. 4-702.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The food-contact surfaces of the equipment were not observed sanitized due to a low concentration of bleach sanitizer. Less than 50ppm. 4-703.11(C) - Corrected During Inspection Critical When tested, a low concentration of bleach chemical sanitizer was found in the sanitize basin. Less than 50ppm. 4-903.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Clean utensils were found stored in a dirty container. 43.1-3-3(a) - Critical There is no Certified Food Manager present at the beginning of the inspection.Mr. Sethi took the exam in Arlington, per Subway, and is waiting for the test results.Call me with the card number and expiration date. 6-202.11(A) - Corrected During Inspection Light bulb in the walk-in refrigerator is not covered by a protective shielding. 6-303.11(B) - Corrected During Inspection Observed that inadequate lighting was provided in the reach-in freezer. light bulb out. 6-303.11(C) - Corrected During Inspection Observed that inadequate lighting was provided in the food preparation areas. Across from the 3-vat sink. 6-501.16 - Corrected During Inspection Observed that the mop is improperly stored between use. 7-102.11 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Working container of poisonous and toxic material, windex, is not properly labeled with a common name. 
 July 05, 2007 Routine 5 9 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. January 12, 2007 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 4-202.16 - Soda crates found used for the following:1. to store onions near the back chips rack. 4-501.11(A) - The following equipment was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged:1. peeling shelving in the 2-door reach-in refrigerator2. cracked door of the microwave 4-501.11(B) - The door gaskets of the front 2-door reach-in refrigerator and the Superior 2-door reach-in refrigerator are torn. 43.1-3-3(a) - Corrected During Inspection Critical There was no Certified Food Manager present at the beginning of the inspection. 6-202.15(A)(1)-(3) - Openings to the exterior of the building are present along the back door. Observed light entering the bottom of the back door, suggesting easy entrance by pests. 6-303.11(B) - Observed that inadequate lighting was provided in the Norlake 2-door upright freezer. Observed no light provided in the unit equipped with a light fixture. 6-501.11 - Observed that the wall by the back handsink is not maintained in good repair. Observed the coving peeling from the wall exposing cracked foundation. 6-501.111(C) - Critical Adequate methods are not being used to control pests. Observed one live baby cockroach exit the wall in poor repair and one live adolescent cockroach beneath the preparation table near the wall in poor repair. 6-501.16 - Repeat Observed the mop in the mop bucket not hung to air dry. 
 January 03, 2007 Routine 2 7 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. January 03, 2007 Routine 0 0 - No violation noted during this evaluation. January 03, 2007 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 4-302.14 - There is no test kit located in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions. 4-501.11A - Repeat The quaternary ammonium dispenser at the three-compartment sink was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged. 4-703.11C - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat When tested, no sanitizer or a low concentration of chemical sanitizer was found in the sanitize basin. 6-202.11A - Repeat The light bulb in the walk-in refrigerator was not covered by a protective shielding. 
 August 28, 2006 Critical Procedures 1 3 Details / Comments 
 3-304.14B2 - Repeat Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. Observed wet cloths stored on the counters instead of in a bucket filled with sanitizer solution. 4-101.111 - The nonfood contact surface of the cheese shelf in the walk-in refrigerator is lined with cardboard and therefore is not corrosion resistant, nonabsorbent, and/or smooth. 4-501.11A - The following equipment was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged:1. cracked door on the bottom microwave, preventing effective cleaning2. rusted shelving in the front 2-door reach-in refrigerator. 4-501.11B - Repeat The door gasket of the left door of the Superior 2-door reach-in refrigerator is torn. 4-702.11 - Critical The food-contact surfaces of the following equipment were not observed sanitized: 1. Equipment in the sanitize basin of the three-compartment sink with no sanitizer solution. 4-703.11C - Corrected During Inspection Critical When tested, no sanitizer or a low concentration of chemical sanitizer was found in the sanitize basin. Observed the quaternary ammonium dispenser not properly dispensing the correct concentration. 5-501.113B - Observed the dumpster uncovered. 6-202.11A - The light bulb in the walk-in refrigerator is not covered by a protective shielding. 6-303.11B - Inadequate lighting was noted in the Norlake 2-door upright freezer. Observed a burnt out light bulb in the unit. 6-501.16 - Repeat Observed a mop in the mop bucket not hung up to air dry. 7-202.12C - Corrected During Inspection Critical Pesticides are being applied without a Certified Operator. Observed a can of Raid in the establishment used to spray for ants and roaches. 
 July 17, 2006 Routine 3 8 Details / Comments 
 3-304.14B2 - Repeat Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. Observed wet cloths stored on the counters instead of in a bucket filled with sanitizer solution. 4-101.111 - The nonfood contact surface of the cheese shelf in the walk-in refrigerator is lined with cardboard and therefore is not corrosion resistant, nonabsorbent, and/or smooth. 4-501.11A - The following equipment was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged:1. cracked door on the bottom microwave, preventing effective cleaning2. rusted shelving in the front 2-door reach-in refrigerator. 4-501.11B - Repeat The door gasket of the left door of the Superior 2-door reach-in refrigerator is torn. 4-702.11 - Critical The food-contact surfaces of the following equipment were not observed sanitized: 1. Equipment in the sanitize basin of the three-compartment sink with no sanitizer solution. 4-703.11C - Corrected During Inspection Critical When tested, no sanitizer or a low concentration of chemical sanitizer was found in the sanitize basin. Observed the quaternary ammonium dispenser not properly dispensing the correct concentration. 5-501.113B - Observed the dumpster uncovered. 6-202.11A - The light bulb in the walk-in refrigerator is not covered by a protective shielding. 6-303.11B - Inadequate lighting was noted in the Norlake 2-door upright freezer. Observed a burnt out light bulb in the unit. 6-501.16 - Repeat Observed a mop in the mop bucket not hung up to air dry. 7-202.12C - Corrected During Inspection Critical Pesticides are being applied without a Certified Operator. Observed a can of Raid in the establishment used to spray for ants and roaches. 
 July 17, 2006 Routine 3 8 Details / Comments 
 4-202.16 - the wooden painted board with nails used as a storage rack (next to three vat sink) is not easily cleanable. 4-204.112B - There was no temperature measuring device located in the front undercounter refrigerator across from sandwich prep unit.. 4-501.11B - Repeat The thermometer in the three door refrigerator (across from three vat sink) is broken Some of the refrigterator shelves are rusty 4-502.11A - metal mixing bowl is dented on part of the rim 5-205.11B - The handwash station at the front area is being used for purposes other than washing hands. There were pickle slices and other food debris in the sink 6-201.11 - ceilings in the bathrooms are acoutical tile 6-301.14 - Corrected During Inspection A sign or poster that notifies food employees to wash their hands is not provided at all lavatories used by food employees. 6-501.110B - Corrected During Inspection Repeat Employee clothing and other possessions have been found stored in areas that may contaminate food, food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items. 
 March 23, 2006 Routine 0 8 Details / Comments 
 4-202.16 - the wooden painted board with nails used as a storage rack (next to three vat sink) is not easily cleanable. 4-204.112B - There was no temperature measuring device located in the front undercounter refrigerator across from sandwich prep unit.. 4-501.11B - Repeat The thermometer in the three door refrigerator (across from three vat sink) is broken Some of the refrigterator shelves are rusty 4-502.11A - metal mixing bowl is dented on part of the rim 5-205.11B - The handwash station at the front area is being used for purposes other than washing hands. There were pickle slices and other food debris in the sink 6-201.11 - ceilings in the bathrooms are acoutical tile 6-301.14 - Corrected During Inspection A sign or poster that notifies food employees to wash their hands is not provided at all lavatories used by food employees. 6-501.110B - Corrected During Inspection Repeat Employee clothing and other possessions have been found stored in areas that may contaminate food, food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items. 
 March 23, 2006 Routine 0 8 Details / Comments 
 3-304.14B2 - Corrected During Inspection Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. 3-305.11A3 - Food stored on the floor and/or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor.(boxes of Fanta syrup) 4-501.11B - Repeat The shelves in the two door undercounter refrigerator (under microwave and oven) are starting to rust; one of the silicone bread baking holders is frayed 4-901.11A - metal and plastic pans at drainboard found stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 6-501.11 - door knob is missing from mens&apos; room door (repairs in progress) 6-501.110B - Employee clothing and other possessions have been found stored in areas that may contaminate food, (food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items.(pocketbook on shelves with bagged pickles) 6-501.16 - Corrected During Inspection Repeat Mops and brooms not hung up to air dry. 
 October 18, 2005 Routine 0 7 Details / Comments 
 3-302.12 - noted one unlabeled bottle of water (?) 3-501.16A - Corrected During Inspection Critical the cream soup and meatballs holding hot on line are below required holding temp 3-501.16C - Corrected During Inspection Critical pans of meats, cheese and salads on line are above required cold holdng temperature 3-501.17A - Corrected During Inspection Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE)meatballs in a bag in the walkin is not properly dated for disposition. 4-501.11A - Corrected During Inspection temperatures -hot and cold-in the main unit on line were not at required leve; apparently the unit is not working 4-501.11B - some of the shelves in the reachin refrigerator on line are starting to rust 6-501.110B - Repeat found employee apron and hat on dry storage shelving 6-501.114A - there are items in the rear of the store which do not seem to be needed in regular operation 6-501.16 - Mops and brooms not hung up to air dry. 
 April 19, 2005 Routine 3 6 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. November 23, 2004 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 43.1-3-3A - Critical there was no manager on site when I arrived; she arrived after I had completed my inspection 6-501.12A - light shields above three vat sink are soiled 5-202.11A - Critical a system for adding soap and sanitizer to the three vat sink has been attached to the plumbing system but it is now not possible to provide hot and cold water separately as required to adjust the temperature of the water for the three vat sink 3-305.11A3 - bottles of vinegar are stored on the floor 6-501.110B - Employee clothing and other possessions have been found stored in areas that may contaminate food, food-contact surfaces of equipment, single-service items, or single-use items. 4-302.14 - There is no test kit located in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions. 
 November 09, 2004 Routine 2 4 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. April 02, 2004 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 5-501.17 - Repeat There is no covered refuse container for the disposal of feminine napkins in the ladies room stall. 6-202.15 - there is a small gap at the bottom of the rear door 43.1-1-5F - a small homestyle refrigerator is used to hold bottled water 
 April 02, 2004 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. September 12, 2003 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 43.1-3-3A - Critical Repeat There was no CFM when I arrived at the establishment. 5-205.15B - The sink basin at the front counter is slow to drain. 5-205.11B - The handwash station at the back is being used for purposes other than washing hands. 2-401.11B - Critical A food handler was observed drinking from an uncovered beverage container while in the kitchen. 4-302.14 - Repeat There is no test kit located in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions.Quat test strip. 6-501.113B - Observed cleaning tools improperly stored inbetween the wall and the handsink. 3-305.11A3 - Repeat Food stored on the floor and/or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor(.walk-in) 3-501.16B - Critical Seafood salad cold holding at improper temperatures. 
 September 09, 2003 Routine 3 5 Details / Comments 
 43.1-3-3A - Critical THERE IS NO ONE PRESENT WITH A NORTHERN VIRGINIA CERTIFIED FOOD MANAGERS CERTIFICATE. 5-501.17 - THERE IS NO LID ON THE TRASH CAN IN THE LADIES RESTROOM. 6-301.12A - THERE ARE NO PAPER TOWELS AT ONE HAND SINK. 4-204.112B - THERE IS NO THERMOMETER IN ONE REACH-IN FREEZER. 6-101.11A - THE WALL BY THE PREP TABLE IS NOT FINISHED. 7-207.11B - Critical BOTTLES OF ASPIRIN AND PEPTO-BISMOL ARE ON SHELVES IN THE KITCHEN. 7-102.11 - Critical Repeat THE WINDEX AND ALL-PURPOSE CLEANER ARE IN UNLABELED BOTTLES. 7-208.11B - A BOX OF BAND AIDS IS ON A SHELF IN THE PREP AREA. 6-202.11A - Repeat THERE IS NO SHIELD OVER THE LIGHT BULB IN THE WALK-IN REFRIGERATOR. 
 March 13, 2003 Routine 3 6 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
