<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004203" url="http://articles.cnn.com/keyword/food-industry" time="2012-07-12-20:26" support="3" score="0.009579884313804793" bingtitle="Articles about Food Industry - CNN" webtitle="Articles about Food Industry - CNN">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>A city lawmaker has proposed a bill that would ban fast-food restaurant gimmicks that ... of the meat industry on the information about nutrition we receive ...</description>
	<body>
		IN THE NEWS 
Food Industry
 Find More Stories About » 
 Tobacco Companies Private Sector Immune System Food Safety Web Services |   More 
 Featured Articles US 
 Center to assess threats, prevent food tampering 
 February 15, 2002 The FBI and a leading private food trade organization agreed Friday to form a center to assess threats and protect the nation&apos;s food supply from tampering, officials said. The Food Industry Security and Analysis Center, or ISAC, will coordinate information sharing between the federal government and the food industry on threats to food as well as the food industry&apos;s physical assets and its computer infrastructure. The center aims to merge information from the intelligence community, law enforcement, the Department of Defense and the private sector, said Ronald Dick, director of the FBI&apos;s National Infrastructure Protection Center. POLITICS 
 Why Clinton waded into the Frankenfood fray 
 May 3, 2000 Why this rash of new regulations Ask the manufacturers of the products in question. The genetically modified food industry recognizes that they need to have consumer confidence in order to push ahead, says TIME Washington correspondent Dick Thompson. In addition, the stakes are high Biotech crops already account for about one half of the nations soybeans and cotton, one third of all corn, and smaller amounts of canola, potatoes and squash. And in the wake of recent consumerdriven decisions by McDonalds and FritoLay to stop accepting genetically modified potatoes, theres little doubt the American antiGM movement is gathering momentum. HEALTH 
 CNN Food Central Functional foods may mean a healthier food industry 
 June 8, 1999 From Financial News Correspondent Susan Lisovicz ;CNN It used to be the way to good nutrition was following the food pyramid, but today food companies say the key to optimal health is hightech valueadded groceries called nutraceuticals. ; Following in the wake of less junky junk food and lite foods are the nutraceuticals, foods marketed as medicine. This new food category claims to provide health benefits and can include everything from dietary supplements to engineered foods and specifically prepared meals. HEALTH 
 Health chief wants healthier menus 
 February 2, 2004 Health and Human Services Secretary Tommy Thompson said Tuesday he wants restaurants to do &quot;what&apos;s right&quot; in the fight against obesity by changing their menus to promote healthier lifestyles. &quot;We spend $117 billion a year on obesity-related diseases and 300,000 Americans die,&quot; Thompson said in a CNN interview. &quot;We&apos;re asking the fast food industry and all of the restaurants to start looking at their menus and see if they can diversify and put healthier foods on there and help to promote them. WORLD 
 Cuba sentences ex-Fidel Castro confidant to 20 years 
 By Shasta Darlington, CNN | May 5, 2011 A Cuban court has sentenced a Chilean businessman who was once a close friend of Fidel Castro to 20 years in prison, state media said Thursday. Max Marambio, whose Rio Zaza company made juices and long-life milk sold across the island, was convicted in absentia of bribery and fraud. Cuba has asked for the extradition of Marambio, who is currently in Chile. As part of the same trial, former Food Industry Minister Alejandro Francisco Roca Iglesias was convicted of bribery and actions that damaged the economy. HEALTH 
 Author documents &apos;dark side&apos; of U.S. fast food 
 January 16, 2001 In the introduction for Eric Schlosser&apos;s historical and critical analysis of the fast-food industry, the author writes that processed food &quot;has helped to transform not only the American diet, but also our landscape, economy, workforce and popular culture. &quot; Those are strong words for a 100-plus-billion-dollar industry that has kept pace with modern society. Schlosser insists the convenience of fast food is not all it&apos;s cracked up to be. &quot;The fast-food industry is spending billions of dollars a year marketing their food, and they&apos;re marketing very high-fat, unhealthy food to children,&quot; the author told CNN. But fast food has its fans, including some experts who say it can be a part of a healthy diet. HEALTH 
 Food safety program to get a 43 million boost 
 January 24, 1997 From Correspondent Eugenia Halsey ;WASHINGTON CNN Four children died and hundreds more got sick from eating undercooked hamburgers infected with a dangerous form of e. coli bacteria four years ago. Beginning Saturday, the government is going to do something about it. ;In his Saturday address, President Bill Clinton is expected to announce plans to spend 43 million to ensure that food inspectors learn hightech procedures that will enable them... WORLD 
 Firm sees ozone as food disinfectant 
 January 15, 2002 For most of the past century, weapons of war have been used to clean our food. After World War I, scientists found a new use for stockpiled chemicals like chlorine -- both as a water purifier and as a powerful agent to kill bacteria on food. Before then, ozone -- a naturally occurring chemical compound -- had been used to clean water. Now a small biotech company in the south of England is pitching the idea of once again using ozone in the food industry. Nick Adams, CEO of Bioquell, says it&apos;s what the public wants. HEALTH 
 CNN Food Central U.S. officials predict no Y2K food shortages 
 November 18, 1999 WASHINGTON CNN Government and food industry officials on Thursdaypredicted the nations food supply would not be hampered by Y2K computerproblems.; Agriculture Secretary Dan Glickman and John Koskinen, chair of thePresident Council on Y2K Conversion, flanked by representatives from the foodindustry, said that grocery stores, convenience stores and major chainrestaurants have completed their Y2K preparations and anticipate no problemsfor consumers.; The bottom line is this Food companies are ready and consumers will beable to buy fruit and grocery products over the New Years holiday and beyond,said John Block, former secretary of agriculture and current chief of the FoodDistributors International. LIVING 
 CNN Student News: Daily Discussion 
 October 6, 2009 October 7, 2009 Media Literacy Question of the Day In what ways might news media portray both sides of a controversial story? How does a story like the one on the list of risky foods underscore the importance of balanced reporting? Afghanistan Talks What do you think might be the options that President Barack Obama is considering as he reviews the U.S. strategy in Afghanistan? What criteria do you think that President Obama will use in deciding whether or not to send additional U.S. forces to Afghanistan? 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 &gt; 
 Articles By Date US 
 Rules &apos;holdup&apos; puzzles food industry and food-safety advocates 
 By Lizzie O&apos;Leary and Aaron Cooper, CNN | May 3, 2012 Most of the provisions in a landmark food safety law which passed 16 months ago still haven&apos;t gone into effect and are stuck in a rule-making process at the White House, four months overdue. That leaves 80% of the U.S. food supply operating largely under safety laws dating from the Great Depression, and safety advocates and the food industry alike are puzzled. &quot;It&apos;s still unclear what&apos;s holding them up,&quot; said Chris Waldrop, who directs food policy for the Consumer Federation of America. Advertisement OPINION 
 Why the French still crave America&apos;s love 
 By Philippe Coste, Special to CNN | April 18, 2012 If the Americans followed the French presidential elections as avidly as the French stare at the poll ratings of Mitt Romney and Barack Obama, they would know that &quot;Sarko l&apos;Américain,&quot; Sarkozy the American, may soon have to say &quot;good bye&quot; to the Elysée Palace. The omens are bad and the possible demise of the most pro-American president in our history raises questions about our long and complex transatlantic relations. How will French election be decided? Not that there is so much to worry about. TECH 
 Scientists hatch plan to recycle eggshells into plastic 
 April 3, 2012 &quot;Go to work on an egg&quot; was the slogan of a successful British television advert and &quot;green chemists&quot; from the UK are doing just that with plans to create plastics made from eggshells. Scientists from the University of Leicester in England are experimenting with a process that extracts the proteins found in eggshells, called glycosaminoglycans, which are commonly used in the pharmaceutical industry to help people with cartilage and connective tissue problems. The aim of the current project is to adapt the proteins to create a starch-based plastic that could then &quot;bulk up&quot; existing plastics and be molded into anything from shop fitting to supermarket meal trays. OPINION 
 The question on everyone&apos;s mind 
 By LZ Granderson, CNN Contributor | October 25, 2011 There isn&apos;t a question that&apos;s more quintessentially American than &quot;What do you do for a living?&quot; It is just safe enough to start a conversation with a stranger, it is universal enough so anyone can answer, and it strikes right to the core of what our culture values most -- money. Sure, on the surface that question doesn&apos;t sound as if it&apos;s been ripped from the Gordon Gekko &quot;greed is good&quot; manifesto -- but the reality is it blows past the pleasantries and heads right into the grit of someone&apos;s finances, revealing their place in the pecking order of society and thus a glimpse into just how happy they may or may not be. Since the end of the 20th century, &quot;What do you do for a living?&quot; WORLD 
 Cuba sentences ex-Fidel Castro confidant to 20 years 
 By Shasta Darlington, CNN | May 5, 2011 A Cuban court has sentenced a Chilean businessman who was once a close friend of Fidel Castro to 20 years in prison, state media said Thursday. Max Marambio, whose Rio Zaza company made juices and long-life milk sold across the island, was convicted in absentia of bribery and fraud. Cuba has asked for the extradition of Marambio, who is currently in Chile. As part of the same trial, former Food Industry Minister Alejandro Francisco Roca Iglesias was convicted of bribery and actions that damaged the economy. US 
 New York City lawmaker proposes fast-food toy ban 
 By Jordana Ossad, CNN | April 6, 2011 A city lawmaker has proposed a bill that would ban fast-food restaurant gimmicks that include children&apos;s toys, like the McDonald&apos;s Happy Meal, unless the meal meets certain nutritional standards. New York Councilman Leroy Comrie said Wednesday that the measure would limit the restaurants&apos; ability to &quot;target and lure in the most vulnerable members of our society,&quot; arguing that it is intended to battle childhood obesity. The bill follows a similar measure in San Francisco that will take effect December 1 and was considered the first of its kind for a major American City. OPINION 
 The high price we pay for cheap food 
 By Arthur Potts Dawson, Special to CNN | December 19, 2010 Not long ago, I was very kindly invited to Buckingham Palace, as a member of Britain&apos;s food industry. Hundreds of very smart foodies turned up, having showered, shaved and left behind their stoves, whisks and knives. It is a funny thing seeing many of your contemporaries in suits and dresses when you&apos;re used to seeing them in their whites and aprons. I spent most of the evening introducing myself or just observing the many groups of people that mingle at occasions like these. One group caught my eye for most of the evening. US 
 Illegal immigrant women face risks, study says 
 By the CNN Wire Staff | November 16, 2010 Unauthorized immigrant women do the jobs that put food on the plates of Americans, but face harassment and other challenges daily in the workplace, a study by the Southern Poverty Law Center found. The report, titled &quot;Injustice On Our Plates,&quot; is based on interviews with 150 immigrant women from Mexico, Guatemala and other Latin American countries. &quot;Despite their contributions to our economy, these immigrants live at the margins of U.S. society -- subsisting on poverty wages, enduring humiliation and exploitation in the workplace, and living in constant fear that their families will be shattered if they are detected,&quot; according to the report. US 
 Mayor vetoes San Francisco ban on Happy Meals with toys 
 By Michael Martinez, CNN | November 12, 2010 San Francisco, California, Mayor Gavin Newsom vetoed Friday the city&apos;s ban on most McDonald&apos;s Happy Meals with toys. In making the veto, the mayor released a new report on how a public-private partnership is combating childhood obesity and how San Francisco&apos;s more than 55,000 public school students are now eating fresher and healthier foods. &quot;Parents, not politicians, should decide what their children eat, especially when it comes to spending their own money,&quot; said Newsom. 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 &gt; 
 ©2012 Cable News Network. Turner Broadcasting System, Inc. All Rights Reserved Privacy Guidelines Terms of Service Index by Date Index by Keyword Articles.CNN.com Advertising Practices
	</body>
</document>
