<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004578" url="http://giftah.com/store/wendys-72" time="2012-07-12-21:03" support="1" score="0.0012098072604216311" bingtitle="Wendy&apos;s Discount Gift Cards - Giftah.com - Discounted Gift Cards ..." webtitle="Wendy&apos;s Discount Gift Cards - Giftah.com">
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>The fast food restaurant chain founded in 1969 by Dave Thomas has grown to become ... Sell your Wendy&apos;s gift card to Giftah, we will pay 76% of your card&apos;s balance.</description>
	<body>
		Enter your email for a chance to win a shiny new iPad®2 Giftah Logo 
 Home Buy Sell Wishlist How It Works More 
   Blog About FAQ Contact Press   
 
 
 View Cart | Sign Up / Login Home &gt; Wendys 

   
Wendy&apos;s Discount Gift Cards
 

 

Wendy’s Old Fashioned Hamburgers is more commonly known as just Wendy’s. The fast food restaurant chain founded in 1969 by Dave Thomas has grown to become the worlds third largest fast food chains with over 6,650 locations. Wendy’s has built a large following with its high quality fast food offering of chicken, hamburgers, French fries, and their famous Frosty. It’s now possible to save money at Wendy’s with a discount Wendy’s gift card. If you like square burger patties you will love saving money at Wendy’s with a discount gift card.
 Read more... 

 

How to check your Wendy&apos;s gift card balance?

 Check by phone, call: 866-936-1936 Check Online: click here 

 Guaranteed Transactions Free Shipping 
Sell your Wendy&apos;s Gift Card :

Do you have an unwanted gift card? Sell your Wendy&apos;s gift card to Giftah, we will pay 76% of your
 card&apos;s balance.

Wendy&apos;s
 
 
 You will receive : Up to 76% 
Featured

store
 
Category

Browse by Category

 Arts&amp;Crafts Gift Cards Automotive&amp;Gas Gift Cards Children&amp;Toys Gift Cards Clothing Gift Cards Convenience&amp;Drug Stores Departments Stores Gift Cards Electronics Gift Cards Entertainment Gift Cards Food Gift Cards Gifts&amp;Flowers Gift Cards Health Beauty and Spa Gift Cards Home Gift Cards Jewelry Gift Cards Luxory Goods Gift Cards Maternity Gift Cards Movies Games and Books Office Supplies Gift Cards Pets Gift Cards Restaurants&amp;Dinning Gift Cards Services Gift Cards Sports Gift Cards Travel Gift Cards 

 See more 
Gift Card Value

Browse by Gift Card Value

 Below $20 (4) $20 - $40 (17) $40 - $60 (12) $60 - $100 (4) $100 - $150 (64) Above $150 (38) 
 
Recipient

Browse by Recipient

 Boyfriend Brother Cousin Father Girlfriend Grandma Grandpa Husband Mother Sister Wife 

 See more Sorry, we do not have any gift cards for this store. We would be more than happy to let you know when we get new cards for this store though. Try out the wishlist! 
 Stay at home mom lives off discounted gift cards for a full month Check Taco Bell Gift Card Balance Free Dollar General Gift Cards Check Tim Hortons Gift Card Balance Amazon Appstore Gift Cards 
 
 

Follow us

find out about exclusive gift card deals.
 


 About Blog Press FAQ Media Kit Policies Terms&amp;Conditions 

©2012 Giftah. All right reserved
Designated trademarks and brands are the property of their respective owners
	</body>
</document>
