<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004751" url="http://www.wikihow.com/Eat-More-Fruits-and-Vegetables" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="6" score="0.01791010526314614" bingtitle="How to Eat More Fruits and Vegetables: 15 steps - wikiHow" webtitle="How to Eat More Fruits and Vegetables: 15 steps - wikiHow">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>... own smoothies at home saves money and trash ... together, prepare a vegetable tray to eat before the meal. ... Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant: Eat Less Sugar</description>
	<body>
		the how to manual that you can edit 
 Sign Up or Log In or Log In via 
 Follow us on Pinterest 
 Home Articles Community My Profile Edit 
 Home » Categories » Health » Diet&amp;Lifestyle » Nutrition and Lifestyle Eating 
 
 How to Eat More Fruits and Vegetables 

Edited by Jhrunnergirl and 15 others 
 Pin It Article Edit Discuss History Organic produce 





Have you ever wanted to incorporate more fruits and vegetables into your diet? Ever felt like it would be too difficult? Believe it or not, it is actually quite easy.

 
 
 Edit Steps 
 
 1 Keep plenty of fresh fruits and vegetables on hand . Remember, most eating decisions happen at the store. Think ahead to eating more fruits and veggies and less junk food, and purchase your foods accordingly. 2 Buy fresh, organic , local produce when possible; it often tastes better . If it is also fresher or cultivated with more care (and fewer synthetic fertilizers), there&apos;s a good chance it will even be more nutritious.
 Choose fruits and vegetables with minimal processing. Choose fresh, in-season peaches, for example, rather than canned peaches that have added sugar and have been stored. Know the seasons for your favorite fruits and vegetables and buy in season. Tomatoes ripen in the later part of the warmer season, so a tomato purchased in January (at least in the northern hemisphere) may have been shipped in from elsewhere, grown in a greenhouse, or stored. 
 3 Aim for variety . Don&apos;t only eat one kind of thing. Fruits and vegetables means both, and includes far more than apples.
 Colors of fruits and vegetables often signal different nutritional qualities. Purchase and eat a wide spectrum. 
 4 Explore new and different varieties of foods you already know . Have you ever tried purple peppers or yellow watermelon? Try out the variety at your local farmer&apos;s market, or grow them yourself from seeds or seedlings. 5 Eat a salad with lunch or dinner . Remember that all salads aren&apos;t iceberg lettuce.
 Try lots of different kinds of lettuce, plus other greens, such as spinach, arugula (rocket), kale, chard, beet greens, and so on. Add plenty of goodies. Raisins, nuts, olives, and different kinds of cheeses don&apos;t only add flavor depth to a salad but also round it out nutritionally. Remember, though, that these items are garnishes. Greens are very good for you, but it is possible to make a salad without greens , too, if you&apos;d prefer a change of pace. 
 6 Keep a fruit bowl on your counter or on your desk at work. Keep a fruit bowl on your counter or on your desk at work . It reminds you to grab a piece of fruit whenever you wander in hungry, and it adds an attractive splash of color.
 Some fruits will last longer when stored in the refrigerator. Keep one or two in the bowl to remind you that the rest are there. Choose a heavy glass or glazed ceramic bowl for a fruit bowl, if you find one. A sturdy one will last a long time, and it will wash clean if ever the fruit in it goes past ripeness. 
 7 Learn how to stir fry and how to make soup . Both sorts of dishes are easy to do, infinitely flexible, and very easy to load up with vegetables of all sorts.
 Make your own soups and stews. It&apos;s not that hard, and homemade soup is fresher, better tasting, and more nutritious than overcooked, high-sodium canned soups. 
 8 Incorporate fruits and vegetables into your favorite recipes . For instance, add diced apples and chopped celery to chicken salad . 9 Substitute fruits and vegetables for junk food . Do you often eat a mid-morning or mid-afternoon snack? Eat fruits and veggies instead of potato chips. 10 Make smoothies . They&apos;re a fun and easy way to get your fruits. You can freeze your own fresh fruit or buy frozen fruit blends.
 Use plain yogurt, milk, or unsweetened fruit juice in smoothies. Commercially sweetened yogurts and fruit cocktail drinks often have a lot of added sugar. Sweeten your smoothies with sweet fruits, such as bananas and mangoes, and add sugar sparingly or not at all. Making your own smoothies at home saves money and trash compared to purchasing them at smoothie shops, and it means you get to control exactly what goes in. Store a smoothie in a thermos or in the fridge if you&apos;d like to make it now to drink later. It might melt a little, but that won&apos;t affect the flavor. 
 11 Use dips to make fruits and vegetables more flavorful . Dip carrots in ranch dressing or apples in peanut butter.
 Many dips are high in fat, and most purchased dips and salad dressings have plenty of artificial ingredients. Read the labels carefully or make your own. Watch your portion size. 
 12 Take a fruit or vegetable when you leave your house . Avoid using vending machines or going for fast foods or restaurant foods too often. If you work or study pack a lunch with plenty of good foods. You&apos;ll eat better and save money, too. 13 Develop the habit of eating certain fruits and vegetables at certain times of day . For instance, an orange for a mid-morning snack and an apple for an afternoon snack. 14 When hosting or attending a social get-together, prepare a vegetable tray to eat before the meal . Offer to bring a veggie tray to pot luck gatherings. If there are vegetables left over at the end, use them in a pot of soup. 15 Eat fruit for dessert . There is far less sugar in fruit than in baked desserts or candy, and fruit sugars come with fiber and other nutrients. 




 
 
 Edit Video 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 



 
 
 Edit Tips 
 
 The more fruits and vegetables you eat, the easier it becomes. By eliminating high-fat and high-sugar foods from your diet, it will be easier to acquire a taste for fruits and vegetables . Eat organic fruits and vegetables as much as possible to avoid pesticides, herbicides, and genetically modified food. The USDA recommends eating 5-9 servings of fruits and vegetables per day. Fruits and vegetables should come with little or no packaging. After you&apos;re done using peels and trimmings for soup, compost the rest and there will be no waste . Make the transition slowly so that your digestion and metabolism have time to adjust. Try eating one or two more servings of fruits and veggies today than you did yesterday, and work up to two or three tomorrow. 




 
 
 Edit Warnings 
 
 Always eat a variety of fruits and vegetables for the maximum health benefits. If you only eat one type of fruit or vegetable, your body will not get all the vitamins, minerals, enzymes, and phytonutrients it needs. 




 
 
 Edit Related wikiHows 
 
 How to Eat Healthy How to Eat More Fruit How to Stay Healthy During the Winter How to Eat More Fruits and Vegetables How to Make a Rich and Creamy Fruit Smoothie How to Develop a Taste for Fruits and Vegetables How to Prepare Fruits and Vegetables for Smoothies 




 
 
 Edit Sources and Citations 
 
 http://www.mypyramid.gov http://www.eatingforvitality.com 
 
Articles for You to Write
 Here is a list of suggested articles that have not yet been written. You can help by researching and writing one of these articles. To get started writing one of these articles, click on the red link of a title below.


 How to Eat Dessert on a Diet How to Eat Healthy Winter Desserts 
 
Article Info
 
Last edited:
 April 26, 2012 by Ttrimm 

Categories:
 Nutrition and Lifestyle Eating 

Recent edits by: Jjrb230 , DifuWu , Mind Funeral ( see all )
 
Article Tools
 Share this Article: Tweet 
 
 Discuss Print Email Edit Send fan mail to authors 
 + Embed this: Republish this entire article on your blog or website. 


 Thanks to all authors for creating a page that has been read 12,074 times. 
 
Was this article accurate?

 Yes No 
 

 Write An Article Random Article Follow wikiHow on facebook 
Related Articles

 Avoid High Fructose Corn Syrup Pair Food and Wine Avoid Feeling Drowsy After Lunch Protect Your Mind With Brain Foods 
 
 Featured Articles 

 Curb Your Addiction to News Make a Baby Sling Teach Kids to Garden Recognize a Potentially Abusive Relationship 
 
Meet a Community Member
 
Meet Twoscompany , a community member from California who&apos;s been writing articles, patrolling recent changes, and helping new wikiHow members for over a year. Her favorite thing about wikiHow? &quot;The awesome community!&quot; Her proudest achievement thus far is having become a New Article Booster , which requires the skills to make great edits like this .
 
 Join The Community 
 
 - collapse Things to Do 

 Write an Article Edit this Article Request a New Article Answer a Request Login for more! 

 + expand Places to Visit 

 Recent Changes Forums Community Portal 
 
Follow Us On...

 
 
 
the how to manual that you can edit

 Home About wikiHow Terms of Use RSS Site map 
 

Explore Categories
 
 Arts and Entertainment Cars and Other Vehicles Computers and Electronics Education and Communications Family Life Finance and Business Food and Entertaining Health Hobbies and Crafts Holidays and Traditions Home and Garden Other Personal Care and Style Pets and Animals Philosophy and Religion Relationships Sports and Fitness Travel wikiHow Work World Youth 
 All text shared under a Creative Commons License . Powered by Mediawiki. 
 x 
Thank Our Volunteer Authors.

Give this article a +1.
	</body>
</document>
