<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004784" url="http://wikitravel.org/en/Cairo/Downtown" time="2012-07-12-21:17" support="10" score="0.02420462538143069" bingtitle="Downtown travel guide - Wikitravel - Free Worldwide Travel Guides ..." webtitle="Downtown travel guide - Wikitravel">
			<query id="001457" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000797" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001394" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000297" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant, done Egyptian style. Usually very busy ... Nice place to sit and have a drink, but poor service. ... This is a budget style hotel on the lower end of ...</description>
	<body>
		Help Wikitravel grow by contributing to an article. Learn how . 
Cairo/Downtown
 From Wikitravel Africa : North Africa : Egypt : Lower Egypt : Cairo : Downtown Jump to: navigation , search 
 
 
Contents
 
 [+] Understand 
 History Orientation 
 [+] Get in 
 By metro By bus By taxi 
 See Do Buy [+] Eat 
 Budget Mid-range Splurge 
 [+] Drink 
 Coffee houses Bars 
 [+] Sleep 
 Budget Mid-range Splurge 
 Contact 

 
 Midan Talaat Harb 
 Downtown Cairo is the commercial heart of the modern city of Cairo , centered on Midan Talaat Harb and located to the east and north-east of Midan Tahrir (Tahrir Square). Formerly known as Midan Ismaili until it was renamed on the 2nd of September 1954 by president Nasser as Midan Tahrir &quot;Liberation Square&quot;. Midan Tahrir was the location of Africa&apos;s first Hilton hotel, which is now under renovation under the name of Nile Ritz Carlton. The other imposing building on Midan Tahrir opposite the Egyptian museum, is the bay-fronted government Moga&apos;maa building opened in 1952 which houses the bureaucratic offices, and where visitors can renew or extened their Egyptian visas. Although lacking in obvious tourist &quot;attractions&quot;, Downtown is nonetheless the convenient location of many smaller hotels, retail outlets, travel agencies and restaurants that would be of interest to the traveller. The district&apos;s central location makes it, together with Midan Tahrir, a natural &quot;jumping off point&quot; for exploration of the city. The east end of Downtown is marked by Midan Ataba , the starting point of Islamic Cairo .

 [ edit ] Understand 

 [ edit ] History 

Downtown Cairo&apos;s wide boulevards and streets were laid out in the late 19th century on the orders of Ismail the Magnificent, the Paris of Baron Hausmann being the obvious model for a ruler wishing to Europeanise his capital and his country. The architecture of many buildings is clearly redolent of Paris in the 1870s, if now somewhat run down from neglect and dusty from the Cairene climate.

 [ edit ] Orientation 

Downtown Cairo&apos;s main thoroughfare&apos;s are Sharia(St) Talaat Harb and Sharia(St) Qasr El-Nil, intersecting at the central junction of Midan Talaat Harb. 
Previously known as Soliman Pasha St, before being renamed on the 12th Feb 1964 to Talaat Harb St.The statue of the French General Jean Anthelme Seve also known as Soliman Pasha Al Faransawi, stood where the statue of Talaat Harb, founder of the Banque Misr now stands.Cairienes know this street by both names.

Be warned, all hotels/hostels as well as individuals who work the street in downtown will try to sell you vastly overpriced tours around Egypt. They can be very forceful at times as the competition for tourists is strong and they want to take money from you before the next one gets to you. Do not let yourself be bullied into taking one of these until you have spoken to fellow travelers who can give you a more neutral opinion. In fact there are very few places in Egypt where it would be necessary to organize tours from the capital, and fewer where it would be financially advantageous.

If you are a confident traveler and used to navigating your way around cities, then Cairo should be no different for you. Downtown has many small tourist oriented tour kiosks. The problem that visitors face is these tours often are inflated in price and always include at least 2 stops to &apos;uncles&apos; perfume, papyrus, or handicraft shops. This takes away many hours from the tour itself and time at monuments in the hope that at least a few from the coach will buy something.

The better option would be negotiate a taxi for the day. Stop a few taxis and ask what the price would be for a whole day of sightseeing at the places you want to visit. If the price is mutual, a taxi driver will be happy to escort you around town and wait hours in the shade outside for you if he is sure of a good fare at the end of the day instead of driving around Cairo looking for fares.

 [ edit ] Get in 
 Map of downtown Cairo 
The Main traffic hub of Cairo Downtown is at Abdel Mo&apos;nem Riyad Station.

 [ edit ] By metro 

The Sadat metro station is located at Midan Tahrir, right beside the Egyptian Museum. From Midan Tahrir, Downtown Cairo is readily accessible, with only a 10 minute easy walk to the centre of the district, via Talaat Harb Street. You can take the metro from the Sadat station to the rail station (Mubarak station) or to Coptic Cairo (Mar Girgis station).

 [ edit ] By bus 

 By Local Coach 

The Abdel Mo&apos;nem Riyad Coach Station a five minute walk from Tahrir Sq and behind the Egyptian Museum lies four coach stations. One is the micro-bus station, and alongside is the local bus station serving the areas of Giza , Ma&apos;adi , Helwan , Sheikh Zayid City . The third serving the East of Cairo ie Heliopolis, Medinet Nasr, Cairo Airport , and El Rehab .

 By Intercity Coach 

The fourth station on Abdel Mo&apos;nem Riyad Station, is across the road from the other three stations and this is where you can board the Intercity Coaches. The offices and bookings of Superjet, East Delta, West Delta, and El Gouna are here with destinations including Hurghada, Sharm el Sheikh, Ras Sidr, El Gouna, Alexandria, Delta Cities, Marsa Matrouh, Port Said, Ismailia, Suez, El Tur, El Arish, Nuweiba, Dahab, Rafah , etc.

 [ edit ] By taxi 

Taxis to/from Zamalek, to Downtown should cost around 5 LE and to Citadel, Coptic Cairo or Islamic Cairo should cost around LE 10. Do not let the taxi driver choose you. You choose him and always look confident and that you use them regularly. Flag one down, hop in and always sit in the back of the cab. Try not to get into any discussion with the driver. Simply state your destination and look out the window. Ignore any chat if you can. Egyptians do not chat with drivers on the whole. Avoid eye contact especially in the mirror.
Do not confirm the fare before getting in. No resident of Cairo does this, you should always pay afterwards, (after) you have stepped out of the cab, with no discussion of the price (unless the taxi driver thinks you&apos;ve given him an unfair price). If you are obviously a tourist with your Lonely Planet Guide, North Face backpack, and are wearing shorts then you can sometimes expect an argument even if you have offered the correct price. Either pay him more to keep the peace (odds are he needs the money more than you) or just walk away.
To avoid any confrontation regarding price, choose a cab from the new yellow, or white with black ones with meters.Then add a few LE tip if you so choose.
A great look into the life of the average Cairo Taxi driver can be found in the excellent book &apos;Taxi&apos; by Khalid El Khamissi. [1] After reading that you may become more sympathetic to their daily struggle for business.

 [ edit ][ add listing ] See 

 Abdeen Palace Museum , ( Accessible from Midan Tahrir via Mohammad Mahmoud Street or Al-Tahrir Street, or via Naguib metro station ). Collections are showcased on the lower floors in the Silver Museum, the Arms Museum, the Royal Family Museum, and the Presidential Gifts Museum, and the Historical Documents Museum was added in 2006. The palace, designed in the 1800s by a French architect, is worth seeing including the fountain courtyard.   edit 

 Karim Francis Gallery , 1 Sharia El-Sherifein , ☎ +202 2391 63 57 , [2] .  edit 

 Museum of Islamic Art , Bab El Khalk Square, Port Said St ( near Abdeen Palace ). Established in 1880 under authority of Khedive Tawfiq, the museum showcases pieces from mosques, homes, and palaces in Islamic Cairo. The museum has been closed for renovations since summer 2006, and is scheduled to reopen in 2009 (at the earliest).   edit 

 The Postal Museum , Al-Ataba Square ( Ataba metro station exit Ataba Sq ), ☎ +202 2391-0011 . This museum holds a plethora of historical exhibits relating to all things postal, from the history of the post system dating back to the time of the Pyramids to extensive stamp collections.   edit Egyptian Museum , Midan Tahrir ( On the Midan Tahrir Sq opposite Tahrir Metro ), ☎ 25782448 , [3] . A must for any visitor to Cairo. The Gold Room where King Tutankhamuns treasure is displayed is a &apos;must see&apos;, as is the Mummy Room. Warning, only the Gold Room and the Mummy Room are air conditioned, and you must pay an additional fee to see the Mummy Room. A brand new Egyptian Museum to replace this one is currently under construction close to the pyramids at Giza. 30LE student, 60LE adult .  edit Yacoubian Building , 34 Talaat Harb St Downtown . For readers of Alaa al Aswani&apos;s best selling book The Yacoubian Building. You can see the Yacoubian Building on Talaat Harb St where it still stands and where the story was based, although in the book it is referred to by it&apos;s old name of Soliman Pasha St.   edit Prince Said Halim&apos;s Palace , Champollion Street ( Off Midan Falaki ). Now almost derelict and often misleadingly called the Champollion Palace, this once beautiful building is worth a look for it&apos;s beautiful architecture, baroque and classical archways. Built in 1896 by designer Antonio Lasciac from imported Italian marbles and stone. This once beautiful Palace and gardens is a reminder of the &apos;Glory days of Cairo&apos; before the nationalization of President Nasser and it&apos;s eventual transformation into Al Nassareya Boys School which quickly destroyed the beautiful building which today is a temporary Art Gallery.   edit 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Do 

 Cinema Metro , 35 Talaat Harb . Once one of Cairo&apos;s most opulent movie palaces, the Metro has fallen on sadly disheveled, dusty, almost squalid times. 10-20 LE .  edit 

 Cairo Puppet Theatre , Azbakia Park ( Near the Ataba metro station. ), ☎ (02) 2268-5241 ( info@cairopuppettheatre.org ), [4] . A fantastic way to spend an afternoon with the kids. the Cairo Puppet Theatre puts on a variety of shows including myths, fairy tales and fun children&apos;s stories.   edit 

 Ramses Hilton Cinema , 1115 Corniche El Nil ( Ramses Hilton Mall ). Theater at the Ramses Hilton shows modern, mainstream movies. Best to get there by taxi.   edit Visit Midan Falaki - Falaki Square , ( From Midan Tahrir take Tahrir St heading to Abdeen Palace and Falaki is approx a 5 minute walk. ). Midan Falaki is a public square surrounded by coffee merchants and coffee shops. During the day you can sit and enjoy one of the many blends and play a game of backgammon with the more intellectual Egyptians who frequent the cafes during the day. However a more raucous clientele tend to congregate later in the evening. A nice place to people watch, and buy some unusual blends of coffee. Ta&apos;kiba Coffee shop is a short walk away by the wrongly named Champollion Palace,on Champollion Street,and round the corner from the Townhouse Gallery and Theater. The gallery has a clean toilet for public use.   edit 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Buy 
 Midan Talaat Harb 
The Downtown district of Cairo features a number of Egyptian department stores . These were once fantastic emporiums, full of the world&apos;s best products - until July 1961 when every one of Egypt&apos;s great department stores were nationalized. Those days are long gone, but quality shopping has moved to upmarket malls in Heliopolis, Nasr City, Maadi and other upscale neighborhoods. Today, Downtown is the place to go for cheap fakes and local produce of variable quality and the full range of Arabic pop music (and films).

The Midan Ataba area is home to large bookseller markets, where you can find inexpensive books, as well as electronics and clothing markets. Near the main post office, there are vendors selling stationary and cards. Talaat Harb Street is the place to find shoes, with one shoe store after another.

 Madbouli , 6 Midan Talaat Harb ( near Sadat Metro station ), ☎ +202 2575-6421 . Mostly Arabic bookstore with a range of political literature and other books.   edit Omar Effendi , 25 Adly St , ☎ +202 2392-5011 , [5] . A large iconic Egyptian, 150 year old department store. Sadly filled with Chinese and poorly made Egyptian clothing even now since it&apos;s privatization and takeover by the Gulf Kuwaiti Sultan Centre Company.   edit Sednaoui Department Store , On Khazindar Square ( near Al-Ataba Square-near Ataba Metro station ). This once family owned department store was nationalized in 1961 and now has the neglected feeling of an East German department store before the wall came tumbling down. It has 3 floors and has a grand sweeping staircase, and a glass roofed atrium worth seeing for that alone, if you like old architectural building designs. Sells very cheap fabrics on the 2nd floor where you can buy shirt, blouse , and curtain material and have made up by one of Cairo&apos;s many tailors.   edit El Shawarby St , ( near Sadat Metro station ). The best street to bargain hunt for music, DVDs and clothes, don&apos;t be afraid to haggle, watch how the locals do it for tips.   edit Shorouk Bookshop , 1 Talaat Harb Square ( near Sadat Metro station ), ☎ +202 2391-2480 . Located on Midan Talaat Harb, Shorouk has two floors with a good selection of both Arabic and English language books.   edit Talaat Harb Mall , ( close to Yacoubian Building ). Most famous for it&apos;s downstairs fast food restaurants. Many cheap clothes stores are also in the vicinity of the mall which is placed just above Midan Talaat Harb.   edit Attaba Bookstalls , Attaba Downtown ( Take metro to Attaba station and take Attaba Sq exit. ). Everyday incl Fridays . Over 100 new and second hand book stalls all displayed in little Arabesque kiosks. Every type of book and magazine available in many languages.Usually hassle free and sellers are content to let you browse in peace. Always barter, and the price will come down the more you buy.Very old books and classics up to newly released novels and magazines. A great place to find treasures and find a few books for your trip. Visit Mahmoud at kiosks 83 and 84 for a great selection of used English books and a fair price. Many books are under 10LE each.   edit AUC Bookstore ( Hill House Campus AUC Tahrir ), Kasr el Aini St ( few mins walk from Tahrir Sq ), ☎ 7975900 , [6] . 9-6 Sa-Th . Great bookstore just minutes away from Cairo Museum in the AUC Hill House campus. Excellent selection of new books and all the usual Egyptian authors works can be found there amongst the latest releases.   edit Al Bostan Mall , Al Bostan St ( From Tahrir Sq, take Talaat Harb St 200 mtrs and turn right into Bostan St. The mall is the large pink building facing you. ). Early till late everyday, after 1PM Fridays. . Large old Mall mainly selling computers, second-hand PC&apos;s and laptops, and computer accessories with some clothing and footwear stores and a few airline offices. Toilets on each of the 4 floors.   edit 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Eat 

Downtown is not the main haunt for the greatest of culinary treats, although quality eating does exist. It&apos;s however heaven for Egyptian snacks, sweets and fast food. All restaurants under &quot;splurge&quot; serve alcohol unless otherwise noted.
 Quick Sandwich Restaurant 
 [ edit ] Budget 

 Hardees , ( Sadat Metro station ). It is on Midan Tahrir Sq itself. delivery 19066. Free Wifi.   edit 

 McDonalds , ( Sadat Metro station ). It is on Midan Tahrir Sq itself. Delivery 19991. Free Wifi   edit 

 K.F.C , ( Sadat Metro station ). It is on Midan Tahrir Sq itself. Delivery 19019. Free Wifi   edit 

 Quick Sandwich , 2 El Fawala Street ( Downtown, Opera Square ). A pioneer in the Egyptian based chains offers some of the best Shawerma rolls and Shish-Kebab sandwiches, excellent value meals and great taste- delivery is an option by calling 16013. relatively cheap.   edit Kushari al-Tahrir , Abdel Khaleq Tharwat St .  edit GAD , 13, 26th of July St. , ☎ +202-2576-35-83/33-53 . Fast Food Restaurant, done Egyptian style. Usually very busy packed with locals, but very good food at a very non-tourist price. Good fuul and falafel for about 1.5 LE a sandwich. Large restaurant located on 26th July St, just off Talaat Harb St, in downtown Cairo. A large schawerma &apos;Doner kebab sandwich&apos; costs 8 LE.   edit Al Tazaj Fakieh , 30 Talaat Harb St , ☎ 19018 . Kebab with a chicken twist, this Cairo chain serves up chicken in all it&apos;s oriental varieties.   edit 

 [ edit ] Mid-range 
 Groppi&apos;s cafe in Talaat Harb 
 Alfi Bey , 3 Al-Alfi Street . Egyptian cuisine is served in this small restaurant, including kofta, kabobs, stuffed pigeon, lamb, and chicken.   edit 

 The Greek Club , Talaat Harb Square ( enter off Mahmoud Bassiouni ), ☎ +20 2 575 0822 . 5 LE entrance fee, open from 19:00. Mostly frequented by liberal and leftist Egyptians rather than Greeks, this is one of the best restaurants in Downtown Cairo. The Greek food offered is limited and the menu often erratic, but the dishes they do have in supply are very good and cheap. Alcohol (including imported spirits) is served and it&apos;s possible to just have a drink. Some of the best Kofte in Cairo. Closes down completely during Ramadan.   edit Felfela , 15 Sharia Hoda Sharaawi , ☎ +20 2 392 2833 . open daily 7.30AM-12.30AM . no credit cards A Cairo institution, this restaurant represents the original flagship of the now burgeoning Felfela chain of restaurants throughout Cairo. Long wooden tables and eclectic, somewhat kitschy décor: aquariums, clocks, half-lit grottos complete with mini-waterfalls. Somehow it all works. Specializes in classic Egyptian cuisine. The vegetarian dishes are better than the meat. Try the lemonade - perfect refreshment on a hot day! Also serves beer.   edit Groppi&apos;s , Midan Talaat Harb . Situated on the square itself is the once opulent Groppi&apos;s, formerly the most famous café, tearoom and patisserie in Egypt. Between the 1920s and early 1950s, Groppi&apos;s was the place to be seen by Cairene society. Its former glories stripped away to dusty memories, Groppi&apos;s is nonetheless still just open for business. Be sure to check out the ornate mosaics around the doorway - a relic of former times.   edit La Chesa , 21 Adly St. , ☎ 02-393 9360/5768 . Serving fondues, and other traditional Swiss dishes, pizza, salads and patisseries, this is one of the better continental restaurants in Downtown Cairo.   edit 

 After Eight ( Middle Eastern brassiere ), 6 Kasr El-Nil St . Open 20:00 - till late. Brassiere cum night club serving cocktails and Middle Eastern Cuisine. Excellent service with life band and DJ.   edit 

 [ edit ] Splurge 

 Cafe Riche , 17 Talaat Harb St ( near Sadat metro station ), ☎ 02-392-9793 . Another place of forlorn glory. Very popular with tourists, but the reasons for fame are questionable, it&apos;s rather expensive for what you get and service is slow, even for Cairo.   edit Peking , 14 Saray el Azbakia St. ( off Emad El Din St. ), [7] . Branch of the Cairo Peking restaurant chain. All their branches offer relatively predictable, but very good Chinese food.   edit 

 Da Mario Italian restaurant ( Nile Hilton Hotel ), ( Sadat metro station on Midan Tahrir ). Authentic Italian cuisine and good service.   edit 

 Maharajah restaurant ( Ramsis Hilton ), 1115 Corniche El-Nil St , ☎ 2577-7444 . Open every day 13:00 to 00:00. Exotic Indian dining experience.   edit 

 Windows on the World restaurant ( Ramsis Hilton Hotel ), 1115 Corniche El Nil St. . Open everyday 17:00 to 02:00. International cuisine with cocktails and evening entertainment served in the 36th floor restaurant with stunning panoramic views over the Nile and to the pyramids beyond   edit 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Drink 

 [ edit ] Coffee houses 

Downtown is a primary walk for coffee houses and almost every side-street has one. However, some areas and street have clusters of small places which makes for a very lively atmosphere.

 Bursa . This cluster of coffee shops in carless streets are accessed from Qasr-El-Einy/Sherif. It is a very popular place among young democracy activists and members of oppositional movements and lively until late night.   edit 

 Tawfiqiyya Souq , ( North of 26th July in Downtown ). This is another street with lots of coffee shops and lots of atmosphere.   edit 

 [ edit ] Bars 

 Houria , Bab-Al-Louq . This place doubles as coffee shop and bar, making it quite unique in Cairo. Some of the cheapest beer you can get in Cairo and given that this is also one of the least sleazy of the cheap downtown bars, there&apos;s no reason not to rave about the place. Reopened in May 2010 and as busy as always. 9 EP for a bottle of Stella; amazingly good service, but the waiters are equally insistent on a spot of baksheesh.   edit 

 Odeon , 6 Abdel Hamid Said St ( Odeon Palace Hotel, off Tala&apos;at Harb St ), ☎ 02/767-971 . 24 hours . This roof-top open-air hotel bar is also a restaurant, but most visitors prefer just to drink or have shisha. Beer (Stella or Saqqara) is 10 EP. Very popular among backpackers and foreign students. Open during Ramadan. Nice place to sit and have a drink, but poor service.   edit 

 Sherlock Holmes pub ( Ramsis Hilton Hotel ), 1115 Corniche El Nil ( Behind and five minutes walk from Egyptian museum ). Atmospheric British style pub with warm cosy atmosphere. Local and imported alcohol , moderate prices.   edit 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Sleep 

Downtown Cairo is full of cheap but often dirty hostels and hotels.




 Tulip Hotel , 3 Talaat Harb sq,Downtown Cairo ( 2,min walking from saddat subway station ), ☎ 0020223939433 , [8] . checkin: 12:00 N ; checkout: 11:00AM . Egypt is an exciting, and cultural place to visit.Hotel Tulip is strategically located right in the heart of historical Cairo most exclusive district and is only minutes away from the renowned shopping and entertainment haven of DOWNTOWN. We have recently renovated our hotel,the hotel interior has very high ceilings, large rooms, beautiful iron balconies, and comfortable beds. Our rates is affordable so you can enjoy the Middle East even if you are traveling on a budget. We keep our hotel clean and comfortable so our guests can relax after enjoying their time in Egypt. TULIP --- H o t e l --- n e a r --- b y 2 minutes walking distance from el Tahrir square where the Egyptian museum is located. 2 minutes walking distance from Sadat subway Station and bus station. 10 minutes walking distance from the NILE RIVER. 20 minutes from the zoo. 7 minutes from Egyptian main railway station. 25 minutes from the pyramids. 30 minutes from the airport. free WiFi,Free Breakfast ,clean and cozy Hotel 90 LE .  edit 

 Cairo Downtown Hotel , 2 Amir Kadadar Street, Bab El Looq Tahrir Square ( Tahrir sq ), ☎ 0020227928932 , [9] . checkin: 12:00PM ; checkout: 11:AM . We have old colonial building from the earlier British era the interior has very high ceilings, large rooms, beautiful polished wood floors, iron balconies, and comfortable beds. Our rates is affordable so you can enjoy the Middle East even if you are traveling on a budget. We keep our hotel clean and comfortable so our guests can relax after enjoying their time in Egypt. 155 LE .  edit 

 [ edit ] Budget 

 Arabesque Hotel , 11 Ramses St. , ☎ 002 02 2579 9681 ( arabesquehotel@yahoo.com ), [10] . Located right next to the Egyptian Museum and Nile it&apos;s a great place to start exploring the city. The rooms are comfortable and the staff are friendly though somewhat unprofessional. The common room offers fantastic floor to ceiling windows for wonderful views of the city. Rooms start from 115 EGP. Note that after the 2011 revolution, rooms can be bargained down to less than half that by a skilled bargainer.   edit 

 Arabian Nights Hostel , 10 Al Aded St. , ☎ 002 02 2924 0924 ( arabiannightshotel@yahoo.com ), [11] . A very fun hotel located next to Khan el Khalily and near the Citadel. Staff are very friendly and helpful. There is a great view from the roof, with an Arabian style tent set up. They are now having a free Sufi dancing show on their roof every Sunday. Comfortable clean rooms, good help with trip ideas and Cairo tips. Free wifi, air conditioning, breakfast and as many hot drinks as you want. Rooms start from 80 Egyptian pounds.   edit 

 Australian Hostel , 23 Abd El khaleq Sarwat Downtown Cairo - Egypt , ☎ +202 23958892 , [12] . Nice clean rooms, Friendly staff and AlTahrir Kosheri is just around the corner. Centrally located but hard to find. Just past the KFC and Radioshack, on the third Floor. 6 people dorms for 50 EGP a night.   edit 

Berlin Hotel, 2 El Shawarby St - 4th Floor (Opposite to the Central Bank of Egypt in central area of down town Cairo), ☎ +20223957502, . checkin: 07:00 A.M; checkout: 12:00 P.M. berlinhotelcairo@hotmail.com. This is a budget style hotel on the lower end of the scale. Lift broken, no bathroom in room. central Cairo,WiFi is available free of charge

 Brothers Hostel/Hotel , 34 Talaat Harb St, 4th Floor , ☎ 002 02 2579 6946 ( hostelbrothers@yahoo.com ), [13] . Extremely friendly atmosphere, very comfortable beds, clean, the staff is always willing to help, including booking affordable trips, bus tickets and explaining/giving recommendations about their city. This hotel-hostel is in the famous Yacoubian Building. Dorms from 50 EGP, central location, 24 hour reception and security, free wifi and internet access, air conditioning, airport transfers and breakfast included.   edit 

 Cairo Moon Hotel , 28 Adly Street ( Downtown ), ☎ 002023905119 ( cairomoonhotel@yahoo.com ). A beautifully designed hotel with lots of open space and a gorgeous terrace where you can have breakfast overlooking Cairo. The rooms are large with high ceilings and lots of light. They offer free breakfast, wireless internet and hot drinks throughout the day. Dorms are 60 EGP and rooms start from 100 EGP.   edit 

 Canadian Hostel , [14] .  edit 

 Cecilia Hostel . Generally pretty grungy. Things are not particularly clean, but the staff is generally nice. Free wifi, but slow.   edit 

 Dahab Hostel ( Dahab Hotel ), 26 Mahmoud Bassioui , ☎ +202 579-9104 , [15] . This low-key, basic hostel is popular with the &quot;no frills&quot; travelers who want a basic room redolent of a Dahab beach experience in the big city and not much else. The Dahab is basically a collection of rooms on a rooftop in the Downtown area. WiFi is Free! Beds starting at €3 .  edit 

 Dina&apos;s Hostel , 42 Abd El Khalek Sarwat, 5th floor ( Downtown ), ☎ +202 2396-3902 , [16] . Old world charm, tall ceilings, beautiful architectural details, extremely clean rooms (bed and bath) and helpful staff. Some rooms have AC and private bathrooms others have fans and share bath. Just let them know which you prefer and they are happy to accommodate you. Very approachable and open for cultural exchange and discussion about Egypt. Beds starting at 25EGP .  edit 

 Each Way Hotel , 44 Talaat Harb St. , ☎ 00202 0122844677 , [17] . This is a new place in Cairo designed for all budget travelers. Established on July 2008, Each Way Hostel is in a pleasant, quiet area Talaat Harb Street(Downtown), only a short walk from Talaat Harb Square. It is a clean, economical place and close to Egyptian museum and several other main sights with several transport options available. $16-22 .  edit 

 Egyptian Night Hotel , 13 Merit Basha St. , ☎ 02 2576 0604 ( egyptiannighthotel@yahoo.com ), [18] . This is a cozy new hostel located directly across from the Egyptian Museum, with views of the Nile. The inside is colorful, with very friendly staff. Many of the rooms come with balconies. Free WiFi. They offer a good continental breakfast with drip coffee. Dorm rooms 70 EGP. Private rooms starting from 25 USD.   edit 

 Jasmine Hostel , 26 Sherief St. , ☎ 002 011 1411 454 ( jasminehostel@yahoo.com ). Very clean hostel in downtown. Rooms are nice and big. Friendly staff and free WiFi. Private rooms start from 70 EGP.   edit 

 Juliana Hotel , 8 Ibrahim Naguib, Garden City ( close to Downtown, in the tree-lined area of the Canadian, British and US embassies ), ☎ +2 012 424 9896 ( julianahotel@hotmail.com ), [19] . checkin: 1PM ; checkout: noon . WiFi, Internet and printer for free, breakfast included, questionably clean and somewhat cramped rooms a few with Balcony, some with A/C, TV and original parquet wood floors, towels daily. The Egyptian staff may not understand English. Private rooms from 55 L.E .  edit 

 King Tut Hostel , 37 Talaat Harb St., 8th floor , ☎ +20-2-3917897 , [20] . Single/double LE45/70 with shared bathroom, LE75/100 en suite .  edit 

 Let Me Inn , 19 Adly St, 5th Floor . Very friendly homely and comfortable hostel with fantastic staff, internet and laundry etc. Rooms are good too. A great place to meet other travelers and to get away from the hustle bustle. A backpacker favorite.Dorms $5-10   edit 

 Lialy Hostel , 8 Talaat Harb Sq , ☎ 00202 5753404 ( lialy_hostel@yahoo.com ), [21] . One of the best hostels in Cairo, clean rooms with breakfast, cheap, friendly staff and a great location. Like the Luna though, do not buy a tour from here, they are incredibly overpriced.   edit 

 Luna Hotel , 27 Talaat Harb St. , ☎ +202 2396-1020 , [22] . checkin: 12PM ; checkout: 11:59AM . One of the best hostels in Cairo, Hostel/Hotel Luna offers both quiet and noisy rooms (depending on the orientation towards Sharia Talaat Harb, incredibly noisy street below), for prices that soared lately, but the cleanliness of rooms is beyond comparison.   edit 

 New Minerva Hostel .  edit 

 New Palace Hotel , 17, Soliman El Halaby st, From Emad El Din st , ☎ 002 02 25751283 - 002 02 25751322 , [23] . Friendly staff, breakfast included, internet and printer access, free WiFi, rooms with bathroom and AC. 24h/day rooftop restaurant with a peaceful atmosphere, billard table and satellite TV. Dorms from $6.50, private rooms from $9 .  edit 

 Nubian Hostel , 4 Elwy St. , ( nubianhostel@hotmail.com ), [24] . Comfortable and clean hostel in downtown. It&apos;s on a side street so it&apos;s relatively quiet. The staff are friendly and relaxed. It has free WiFi. Private rooms start from 70 EGP.   edit 

 Rotana Palace hotel , 37 Talaat Harb St. . Very clean rooms and bathrooms, Satellite TV, free WiFi, modern rooms, breakfast included single ensuite 120LE   edit 

 Sara Inn Hostel , [25] .  edit 

 Sultan Hotel , Tawfiqqya Souq ( near Nasser metro station, north of Sharia 26th of July ). Dorms from 20LE, homely family atmosphere, satellite TV, kitchen. Popular with Japanese. In the same building are also the Safary Hotel and the Venice Hosokawaya Hotel.   edit 

 Traveler&apos;s House Hotel , 43 Sherief Street ( Downtown ), ☎ 002023964362 ( travelershousehotel@yahoo.com ). A new hotel in Cairo. Situated in downtown near the Orabi Metro station. Nice clean rooms with high ceilings and large windows. A large common room with a balcony is perfect for hanging out at the end of the day. Free breakfast, wireless internet and hot drinks throughout the day. A dorm room is 45 EGP and rooms start at 75 EGP.   edit 

 Venice Hosokawaya , 4 Souk El-Tawfikia Street, 4th floor , ☎ +20 2 27735307 , [26] . checkin: 13:00 ; checkout: 12:00 . Venice Hosokawaya Hotel was established in January 2008, after a complete renovation and staff replacement of the old Venice Hotel. Popular with Japanese and the owner is Japanese national , staff can speak English , Japanese , Arabic . clean and comfortable . Free breakfast , Free wireless internet , Free kitchen.Dorm room is 35LE , Private room from 95LE   edit 

 Wake UP! Cairo Hostel , [27] .  edit 

 [ edit ] Mid-range 

 * Grand Hotel , 26 July St , ☎ 025757700 ( grandhotel@link.net ). US$40 .  edit 

 Rooms in Cairo , 19A Adly Street , ☎ 0020107571855 ( roomsincairo@gmail.com ). This is an Irish couple subletting apartments to holidaymakers and short-term visitors. Very comfortable accommodations, air-con in bedrooms and breakfast is included. Excellent location and the added benefit of having fully equipped modern kitchen. Excellent for families. From35Euro per night .  edit 

 [ edit ] Splurge 

 Talisman Hotel de Charme , 39 Taalat Harb St., 5th floor ( tucked away in a small alley ), ☎ + 20 0 - 2393 94 31 ( info@talisman-hotel.com ), [28] . Located on the 5th floor of an older building, the outside of the hotel may not be impressive, but this 25-room hotel provides clean, nicely decorated rooms, private marble bathrooms, air conditioning, free internet, and breakfast. The staff is friendly and helpful, providing high-end service. US$61 .  edit Nile Hilton Hotel ( Midan Tahrir Sq ), 1113 Corniche El Nil, Cairo 12344, Egypt ( Sadat Metro station on Tahrir Sq ), ☎ 2578-0444 . adjacent to Egyptian museum, casino , spa , sauna, health club, business center, internet access, various restaurants and cafe bars.   edit * Note: The Nile Hilton is at the time of writing (January 2011) closed for renovations and will reopen as a Ritz Carlton hotel in 2012. 

 Ramsis Hilton Hotel , 1115 Corniche El Nil ( Behind and 5 minutes walk from Egyptian museum ), ☎ 2574-4400 . Business center, fitness center, outdoor pool, various restaurants and bars.   edit 

 [ edit ] Contact 

There are a handful of internet cafes around Midan Talaat Harb.

 This is a usable article. It has information for getting in as well as some complete entries for restaurants and hotels. An adventurous person could use this article, but please plunge forward and help it grow ! 



 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://wikitravel.org/en/Cairo/Downtown &quot; Category : Usable articles 
Personal tools

 Log in / create account 
 
Namespaces

 Page Discussion 
 
 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main Page Project Home Travellers&apos; Pub Recent changes Random page Help Uploads&amp;bug reports Wikitravel Extra 
 
feeds
 
 Travel news and trivia 
 
Destination Docents
 
 About Docents 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Special pages Printable version Permanent link 
 
In other languages
 
 de : Kairo/Stadtzentrum 
 
 This page was last modified on 2 July 2012, at 22:44. Text is available under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 , images are available under various licenses , see each image for details. 

 Privacy policy About Wikitravel Terms of use
	</body>
</document>
