<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004568" url="http://www.ciao.co.uk/sr/q-china+china+belfast" time="2012-07-12-21:03" support="2" score="0.0037616624400423917" bingtitle="China China Belfast - Prices, Offers &amp; Tests of China China Belfast" webtitle="China China Belfast - Prices, Offers&amp;Tests of China China Belfast">
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 29 Shaftesbury Square, ... ... One About the Irishman...?&quot;, &quot;Tea in a China Cup ... coincidence (or the fact I obviously like my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Join Ciao | Login | Help | Mobile 
 
 Browse by category 
 Appliances 

 Books 

 Cameras 

 Cars 

 Computers 

 Electronics 

 DVDs 

 Music 

 Phones 

 Travel 

 More 
 
Ciao - for people with opinions

 
 Latest reviews Write a review 
 
 Latest questions Latest videos 
 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS Shopping Offers Reviews ALL RESULTS &gt; Shopping &gt; Results for &quot;China China Belfast&quot; 
Shopping»
 
 
 Results on ciao.co.uk Results in online shops Special Offers 
 

 1 - 6 of 6 results for &quot;China China Belfast&quot; sort by: Popularity | Price | Rating | Date 
 
 
 China China , Belfast 
 
Chinese Restaurant - Address: 1 University Stree, Belfast BT7 1FY ... more 
 Chinese Restaurant - Address: 1 University Stree, Belfast BT7 1FY (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Belfast &gt; Belfast Restaurants 
 
 China Nights, Belfast 
 
Chinese Restaurant - Address: 3 Ardoyne Road, Belfast BT14 7HX (On ... more 
 Chinese Restaurant - Address: 3 Ardoyne Road, Belfast BT14 7HX (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Belfast &gt; Belfast Restaurants 
 
 China Express, Belfast 
 
Chinese Restaurant - Address: 1 Knock Road, Belfast BT5 6QD (On Ciao ... more 
 Chinese Restaurant - Address: 1 Knock Road, Belfast BT5 6QD (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Belfast &gt; Belfast Restaurants 
 
 Little China , Belfast 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 29 Shaftesbury Square, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 29 Shaftesbury Square, Belfast BT2 7DB (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Belfast &gt; Belfast Restaurants 
 
 China Buffet King, Belfast 
 
Chinese Restaurant - Address: Level 2 Victoria Square, Belfast BT1 ... more 
 Chinese Restaurant - Address: Level 2 Victoria Square, Belfast BT1 4QG (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Belfast &gt; Belfast Restaurants 
 
 China Garden Take Away, Belfast 
 
Chinese Restaurant - Address: 393 Donegall Road, Belfast BT12 6FR ... more 
 Chinese Restaurant - Address: 393 Donegall Road, Belfast BT12 6FR (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Belfast &gt; Belfast Restaurants 
 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members
 
 1 




 
Offers»

 1 - 7 of 7 results for&quot;China China Belfast&quot; sorted by: Popularity | Price 

 
 McCaw Allan Titanic&quot;Made in Belfast &quot; China Mug 
McCaw Allan Titanic&quot;Made in Belfast &quot; China Mug
 
 
Built at the Harland and Wolff shipyard in Belfast , Northern Ireland, the RMS Titanic became famous as the largest ocean liner built in her day. She...... more 
 Built at the Harland and Wolff shipyard in Belfast , Northern Ireland, the RMS Titanic became famous as the largest ocean liner built in her day. She also became famous for sinking in 1912 with a huge loss of life. During her maiden voyage to New York City, she struck and Iceberg on Sunday 14 April 1912, sinking two hours and forty minutes later.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £4.13 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 6.99 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace kitchen 
 From Belfast to Peking, 1866-69: A Young Irishman in China - F.K. Porter 
From Belfast to Peking, 1866-69: A Young Irishman in China - F.K. Porter
 

Pages: 160, Hardcover, Irish Academic Press Ltd


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 24 hours... £ 27.50 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon books 
 From Belfast to Peking, 1866-69: A Young Irishman in China - F.K. Porter 
From Belfast to Peking, 1866-69: A Young Irishman in China - F.K. Porter
 

Pages: 160, Hardcover, Irish Academic Press Ltd


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £2.80 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 15.00 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace books 
 Plays:&quot;Did You Hear the One About the Irishman...?&quot;,&quot;Tea in a China Cup&quot;,&quot;Joyriders&quot;,&quot;Belle of Belfast 
Plays:&quot;Did You Hear the One About the Irishman...?&quot;,&quot;Tea in a China Cup&quot;,&quot;Joyriders&quot;,&quot;Belle of Belfast City&quot;,&quot;Clowns&quot;Vol 1 (Methuen Contemporary Dramatists) - Christina Reid
 

Pages: 368, Paperback, Methuen Drama


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 24 hours... £ 14.24 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon books 
 Plays:&quot;Did You Hear the One About the Irishman...?&quot;,&quot;Tea in a China Cup&quot;,&quot;Joyriders&quot;,&quot;Belle of Belfast 
Plays:&quot;Did You Hear the One About the Irishman...?&quot;,&quot;Tea in a China Cup&quot;,&quot;Joyriders&quot;,&quot;Belle of Belfast City&quot;,&quot;Clowns&quot;Vol 1 (Methuen Contemporary Dramatists) - Christina Reid
 

Pages: 368, Paperback, Methuen Drama


 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £2.80 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 8.54 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace books 
 aber RMS Titanic Coal Sculpture MADE IN UK 
aber RMS Titanic Coal Sculpture MADE IN UK
 
 
RMS Titanic used 825 tons of British coal every day, so it is rather appropriate that this beautiful model of the Titanic is made with deep mined British coal...... more 
 RMS Titanic used 825 tons of British coal every day, so it is rather appropriate that this beautiful model of the Titanic is made with deep mined British coal Approximate size Height 40mm x Length 220mm x Width each one handmade by skilled craftsmen from the coal industry with British coal. Due to the nature of coal, no two pieces will be the same, making each one a unique gift The history of carving sculptures from coal can be traced back 6,000-7,000 years. The jet black decorative artefacts that were discovered at the cultural stratum at the Xinle ruins in Shenyang, in Northern China&apos;s Liaoning Province, include some of the earliest coal carvings. RMS Titanic was the largest passenger steamship in the world when she set off on her maiden voyage from Southampton, England to New York City on 10 April 1912. Four days into the crossing, at 23:40 on 14 April 1912, she struck an iceberg and sank at 2:20 the following morning, resulting in the deaths of 1,517 people in one of the deadliest peacetime maritime disasters in history. An Olympic-class passenger liner, RMS Titanic was owned by the White Star Line and constructed at the Harland and Wolff shipyard in Belfast , Ireland. She set sail for New York City with 2,227 people on board. The high casualty rate when the ship sank was due in part to the fact that, although complying with the regulations of the time, the ship carried lifeboats for only 1,178 people. A disproportionate number of men died due to the women and children first protocol that was followed. Titanic was designed by some of the most experienced engineers, and used some of the most advanced technologies available at the time. It was a great shock to many that, despite the extensive safety features, Titanic sank. The frenzy on the part of the media about Titanic&apos;s famous victims, the legends about the sinking, the resulting changes to maritime law, and the discovery of the wreck have contributed to the interest in Titanic.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £4.08 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 2-3 business days... £ 14.99 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace kitchen 
 aber larger model RMS Titanic Coal Sculpture made in uk 
aber larger model RMS Titanic Coal Sculpture made in uk
 
 
RMS Titanic used 825 tons of British coal every day, so it is rather appropriate that this beautiful model of the Titanic is made with deep mined British coal...... more 
 RMS Titanic used 825 tons of British coal every day, so it is rather appropriate that this beautiful model of the Titanic is made with deep mined British coal Approximate size Height 80mm x Length 460mm x 90mm Width each one handmade by skilled craftsmen from the coal industry with British coal. Due to the nature of coal, no two pieces will be the same, making each one a unique gift The history of carving sculptures from coal can be traced back 6,000-7,000 years. The jet black decorative artefacts that were discovered at the cultural stratum at the Xinle ruins in Shenyang, in Northern China&apos;s Liaoning Province, include some of the earliest coal carvings RMS Titanic was the largest passenger steamship in the world when she set off on her maiden voyage from Southampton, England to New York City on 10 April 1912. Four days into the crossing, at 23:40 on 14 April 1912, she struck an iceberg and sank at 2:20 the following morning, resulting in the deaths of 1,517 people in one of the deadliest peacetime maritime disasters in history. An Olympic-class passenger liner, RMS Titanic was owned by the White Star Line and constructed at the Harland and Wolff shipyard in Belfast , Ireland. She set sail for New York City with 2,227 people on board. The high casualty rate when the ship sank was due in part to the fact that, although complying with the regulations of the time, the ship carried lifeboats for only 1,178 people. A disproportionate number of men died due to the women and children first protocol that was followed. Titanic was designed by some of the most experienced engineers, and used some of the most advanced technologies available at the time. It was a great shock to many that, despite the extensive safety features, Titanic sank. The frenzy on the part of the media about Titanic&apos;s famous victims, the legends about the sinking, the resulting changes to maritime law, and the discovery of the wreck have contributed to the interest in Titanic.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £2.99 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 34.99 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace kitchen 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members


 
Related tags for China China Belfast»
 from china china made china china china kitchen china china china edinburgh china travel china wear china hotels china china denby 
Reviews»

 
 Just Like The Real China! 

 Advantages: Fantastic Food, Clean, Fresh, Beautiful, Good Quality and Decent Price
 Disadvantages: None at all for me


...There is one spot in the Galleria shopping centre in Hatfield that has for years, always been a restaurant. I?m not sure if it is just coincidence (or the fact I obviously like my food to much) that whatever opens up in the space is wonderful in my opinion, but always closes down after about 18 months. The latest restaurant to open its doors in this great little spot is ?The Real China?

The Real China

?The Real China? is a chain of restaurants which has many locations across the UK. I hadn?t actually come across any previously or heard of the restaurants but I am very happy I have now.

As a company, according to the website, all of the locations are buffets as is the one in Hatfield, which also have sushi bars. I am not sure how many branches they have in the UK but if any of you know of one nearby and are fans of Chinese...

 chugglebunny 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average very helpful 
Review of The Real China , Hatfield 
 
 A Taste of China on the Fylde Coast 

 Advantages: Great food, lovely restaurant, pleasant staff
 Disadvantages: A little on the expensive side


...China Red, as the name would suggest, is a Chinese restaurant in Poulton-Le-Fylde (near Blackpool). It&apos;s not actually that near to where I live, but I recently won vouchers after an incentive at work and with the global economic climate as it is, I thought that only a fool would pass on a freebie meal (and I&apos;m no fool, let me tell you). So it was I found myself perusing the restaurant&apos;s website (www.chinared-restaurant.co.uk) for directions and perhaps a sneak preview of the food on offer. I&apos;m a massive fan of Chinese food so my mouth was watering pretty much as soon as the page loaded and so I went ahead and made a reservation. 

Making A Reservation 

Although the restaurant seats up to 170 people, the website does recommend that you make a reservation to avoid disappointment and, I have to say, I would agree. We went...

 dkm1981 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of China Red, Poulton 
 
 China - Unforgettable 

 Advantages: Great Sights, Changing Culture.
 Disadvantages: Difficult Language


...Introduction
=
Two years ago my wife and I decided that we were going to go all out and have a big holiday before we started a family. After setting ourselves a budget in the region of 4000 (including spending money) we finally decided to take a 12 day all inclusive tour of China&apos;s highlights and a three day extension in Shanghai. Going with Kuoni we would have transport, a guide and meals included as well as a cruise down the Yangtze river. I hope in this review to give you an impression and some handy hints shold you choose to visit yourselves.


The Country

China is the worlds most populated (1.3 billion) and third largest country (after Russia and Canada). It encompases a huge variety of climates from deserts to rainforests. Temperatures also vary greatly depending on where you are in the country...

 hero164 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average very helpful 
Review of China in general 
 
 
 About Us - 
 Jobs
 - 
 Advertise with Us
 - 
 Press
 - 
 Become a Partner
 - Ciao Quality Seal Ciao Deutschland - Ciao France - Ciao Italia - Ciao España - Ciao Nederland - Ciao Sverige Site Index - Ciao Charts - Most searched products - Data Protection 
 ©2012 Shopping Guide GmbH
	</body>
</document>
