<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004615" url="http://message.snopes.com/showthread.php?t=9617" time="2012-07-12-21:06" support="1" score="0.00048120516977830276" bingtitle="Weight gain through external food absorption - snopes.com" webtitle="Weight gain through external food absorption - snopes.com">
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>fast food restaurant because even if she didn&apos;t eat the food ... Then you could just pick &apos;em and eat &apos;em ripe, right ... test to see if cranking the music up loud in your car ...</description>
	<body>
		snopes.com &gt; Urban Legends &gt; Food Weight gain through external food absorption 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register FAQ Calendar Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 

   Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
  # 1   01 June 2007, 05:51 AM 
 snopes   Join Date: 18 February 2000 Location: California Posts: 99,978 
 Weight gain through external food absorption Comment: This sounds a bit far fetched to me, but I&apos;d like to know for
sure. A client told me she didn&apos;t want her granddaughter working in a
fast food restaurant because even if she didn&apos;t eat the food she could
become overweight. The client truly believes that the body can absorb the
oil while working over a fryer or grill. It sounds like a myth to me. 
 
 snopes View Public Profile Visit snopes&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by snopes 
 
  # 2   01 June 2007, 06:06 AM 
 llewtrah   Join Date: 13 December 2001 Location: Chelmsford, UK Posts: 16,006 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by snopes Comment: This sounds a bit far fetched to me, but I&apos;d like to know for
sure. A client told me she didn&apos;t want her granddaughter working in a
fast food restaurant because even if she didn&apos;t eat the food she could
become overweight. The client truly believes that the body can absorb the
oil while working over a fryer or grill. It sounds like a myth to me. 
 I first heard this when a school friend&apos;s brother worked at a fast food place and he put on loads of weight and got spotty (and smelled bad after his shift). Possibly he was snacking, though he claimed not. 
 
 llewtrah View Public Profile Visit llewtrah&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by llewtrah 
 
  # 3   01 June 2007, 07:41 AM 
 Floater   Join Date: 24 February 2000 Location: Stockholm, Sweden Posts: 6,220 
 Of course this is true. How else would small children get any nourishment? 
 
 Floater View Public Profile Visit Floater&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by Floater 
 
  # 4   01 June 2007, 08:16 AM 
 llewtrah   Join Date: 13 December 2001 Location: Chelmsford, UK Posts: 16,006 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Floater Of course this is true. How else would small children get any nourishment? 
 Small children can also secrete food from their skin. Place small well-washed child on white blanket. Turn back for 30 seconds (any longer might result in a charge of child neglect). Turn back. The place looks like a Jackson Pollack painting, but there is no evidence of vomit or poop. Only explanation is child has ability to exude multicolour paint from pores of skin. Later in life, these pores reverse their action and let in fat.

Don&apos;t worry - I&apos;ll do it 
 
 llewtrah View Public Profile Visit llewtrah&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by llewtrah 
 
  # 5   01 June 2007, 04:56 PM 
 Troberg     Join Date: 04 November 2005 Location: Borlnge, Sweden Posts: 11,143 
 This reminds me of another question. According to Brainiac Science Abuse, we get 90% of our energy from the oxygen we breathe. Wouldn&apos;t that mean that exercising to lose weight is wrong, as it cause us to breathe much more, thus increasing our oxygen intake? 
 
 Troberg View Public Profile Find all posts by Troberg 
 
  # 6   01 June 2007, 05:01 PM 
 Enchanting_eyes   Join Date: 17 September 2003 Location: Norfolk, VA Posts: 5,360 
 This was not true of me when I work in fast food. Ill break it down for ya, what im bored today.

Age: 16-17 where: Dairy Queen in Z-hill FL. Weight: About 90 pounds soaking wet and holding a weight bar. I worked there for about a year, ate alot of blizzards, we would create our own tell the managers a customer changed his mind then ate it. We also snacked on chili cheese fries, and chicken strips. We had cool managers/owners I miss that place.

Age: 18 Where: Burger King, Nowhereville GA. Weight about 90ish, probably less since I weighed less when I got pregnant. I was one of the cooks, and we would sneak fresh chicken strips all the time, they were so good right out of hot grease. We also never paid for our lunches, we were sneaky like that or we thought that. Once again didn&apos;t gain or loose weight. 
 
 Enchanting_eyes View Public Profile Find all posts by Enchanting_eyes 
 
  # 7   01 June 2007, 05:06 PM 
 Eddylizard   Join Date: 15 June 2006 Location: Tonbridge, Kent, UK Posts: 17,870 
 Braniac Science Abuse isn&apos;t exactly a paragon of scientific truths. They have concluded correctly though, that the only thing a caravan is good for is to be blown up using exotic explosives.

Wouldn&apos;t the oxygen have to combine with something like food to generate energy? People who don&apos;t eat tend to become listless and eventually die, despite breathing.

It&apos;s a brilliant idea though. A hamburger patch - a bit like a nicotine patch. No time for breakfast? Just tape one on your arm before you go to work. I&apos;d buy one. 
 
 Eddylizard View Public Profile Find all posts by Eddylizard 
 
  # 8   01 June 2007, 05:56 PM 
 chillas   Join Date: 09 September 2002 Location: Columbus, OH Posts: 10,126 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Eddylizard It&apos;s a brilliant idea though. A hamburger patch - a bit like a nicotine patch. No time for breakfast? Just tape one on your arm before you go to work. I&apos;d buy one. 
 Man, I was hoping a hamburger patch was a small area in a field where wild hamburgers grew. Then you could just pick &apos;em and eat &apos;em ripe, right off the vine. 
 
 chillas View Public Profile Find all posts by chillas 
 
  # 9   01 June 2007, 06:22 PM 
 putitinwriting   Join Date: 29 December 2006 Location: Tallahassee, FL Posts: 2,177 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by llewtrah I first heard this when a school friend&apos;s brother worked at a fast food place and he put on loads of weight and got spotty (and smelled bad after his shift). Possibly he was snacking, though he claimed not. 
 Even if he was telling the truth about not snacking, he probably started drinking a lot of soda. Fast food workers generally get it for free, and it&apos;s hot and thirsty work. 
 
 putitinwriting View Public Profile Find all posts by putitinwriting 
 
  # 10   02 June 2007, 08:21 AM 
 Troberg     Join Date: 04 November 2005 Location: Borlnge, Sweden Posts: 11,143 
 Quote: 
 Braniac Science Abuse isn&apos;t exactly a paragon of scientific truths. 
 Yeah, I know. They made a test to see if cranking the music up loud in your car made it harder to correctly judge your speed, and found that it actually became harder, thus missing the obvious conclusion: if the music is higher, judging your speed becomes irrelevant. If you have a sufficiently loud sound system, you can drive as fast as you like.

Still, having scantily clad beautiful women setting off huge explosions can&apos;t be all bad! 
 
 Troberg View Public Profile Find all posts by Troberg 
 
  # 11   03 June 2007, 02:08 AM 
 FloridaGirl   Posts: n/a 
 My mom worked at McD&apos;s for 7 years. She weighed less when she left than when she started (so she said, and pictures of her seem to confirm this). She says it&apos;s because she lost her taste for fast food. 
 
  # 12   03 June 2007, 03:51 AM 
 Little Galaxy   Join Date: 21 November 2003 Location: Melbourne, Australia Posts: 882 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Eddylizard It&apos;s a brilliant idea though. A hamburger patch - a bit like a nicotine patch. No time for breakfast? Just tape one on your arm before you go to work. I&apos;d buy one. 
 Something like this, perhaps? 
 
 Little Galaxy View Public Profile Find all posts by Little Galaxy 
 
  # 13   03 June 2007, 06:26 AM 
 1958Fury   Join Date: 05 October 2005 Location: Nashville, TN Posts: 3,885 
 Call me the anti-Jared. I gained a lot of weight from working at Subway. Not exactly through osmosis though. I absorbed a lot of meatball subs through my mouth. 
 
 1958Fury View Public Profile Visit 1958Fury&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by 1958Fury 
 
  # 14   03 June 2007, 01:03 PM 
 Toys For Big Boys   Join Date: 31 December 2005 Location: London, England Posts: 1,980 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Eddylizard 
Wouldn&apos;t the oxygen have to combine with something like food to generate energy? People who don&apos;t eat tend to become listless and eventually die, despite breathing.
 
 The oxygen is required for cellular respiration to take place. 
 
 Toys For Big Boys View Public Profile Find all posts by Toys For Big Boys 
 
 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is On Forum Rules 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Urban Legends   Automobiles   Business   College   Computers   Crime   Critter Country   Disney   Entertainment   Fauxtography   Food   Glurge Gallery   History   Horrors   Humor   Inboxer Rebellion   Language   Legal Affairs   Medical   Military   NFBSK   Old Wives&apos; Tales   Politics   Questionable Quotes   Religion   Science   Spook Central   Sports   Trivia   Urban Legends Non-UL Chat   Amusement Bark   The Bad Gastronomer   Business Bytes   Crash and Burn   The Doctor Is In   Fun House   NFBSK Gone Wild!   Police Blotter   Techno-Babble   We&apos;ve Got Mail   Weird News   Wild Kingdom SLC Central   SLC   Moot Court   Soapbox Derby   Social Studies   Rantidote   Hurricane Katrina   War, What Is It Good For? Diversions   Sightings   Book Corner   Urban Legends Contest About This Site   Announcements   Copyright Trap   Snopes Spotting   Technical Questions 
 


 All times are GMT. The time now is 07:06 PM . 
 
 -- Default Style ---- Olympics -- Medical snopes.com - Archive - Top 

 Powered by vBulletin®Version 3.8.7
Copyright©2000 - 2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
