<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004430" url="http://www.omnivorebooks.com/events.html" time="2012-07-12-20:50" support="2" score="0.006565655616545029" bingtitle="Omnivore Books on Food · Events" webtitle="Omnivore Books on Food · Events">
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>just call the shop at 415-282-4712, we’ll be happy to take care of it for you. ... Baking &amp; Desserts is a gorgeously-packaged book from the successful, healthy fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		Events at Omnivore Books on Food

 
 If you would like a signed copy of a book from one of our events, but are unable to attend,
just call the shop at 415-282-4712, we’ll be happy to take care of it for you. 

           
Wed. July 11•Marcus Samuelsson•Yes, Chef: A Memoir. Dinner with the author at Camino Restaurant in Oakland•6:00 p.m.•$85 including wine, cocktails are extra. SOLD OUT! 

 

Contact the restaurant for reservations: 510-547-5035. Join us for a 3-course dinner with chef Marcus Samuelsson, to celebrate his memoir. Yes, Chef chronicles Marcus Samuelsson’s remarkable journey fromhis adoptive home in Scandinavia to some of the most demanding and cutthroat restaurants in Switzerland and France, from his grueling stints on cruise ships to his arrival in New York City, where his outsize talent and ambition finally come together at Aquavit, earning him a coveted New York Times three-star rating at the age of twenty-four. But Samuelsson’s career of “chasing flavors,” as he calls it, had only just begun.



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Thurs. July 12•Richard Foss•Rum: A Global History•6-7 p.m•FREE.

 

This book chronicles the five-hundred-year evolution of rum from a raw spirit concocted for slaves to a beverage savored by connoisseurs. Charting the drink’s history, Foss shows how rum left its mark on religious rituals—it remains a sacramental offering among voodoo worshippers—and became part of popular songs and other cultural landmarks. He also includes recipes for sweet and savory rum dishes and obscure drinks, as well as illustrations of rum memorabilia from its earliest days to the tiki craze of the 1950s. Fast-paced and well written, Rum will delight any fan of mojitos and mai tais.



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Mon. July 16•David Chang, Peter Meehan&amp;Chris Ying•Lucky Peach #4 signing•7:30-8:30 p.m.•FREE

 

What else needs to be said? Meet the creators of this year&apos;s most popular food magazine and get them to sign your copy of the new issue of Lucky Peach!



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Wed. July 18•Dina Yuen•Indonesian Cooking: Satays, Sambals and More•6-7 p.m.•FREE

 

 Indonesian Cooking is Chef Dina Yuen&apos;s culinary exploration of the world&apos;s largest and most diverse archipelago—the fabled Spice Islands of Indonesia. This is a vibrant, multi-layered nation with a fabulous and largely unexplored cuisine—and her easy-to-follow recipes now make them accessible to everyone.



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Sat. July 21•Adam Perry Lang•Charred and Scruffed•3-4 p.m.•FREE

 

With Charred&amp;Scruffed, bestselling cookbook author and acclaimed chef Adam Perry Lang employs his extensive culinary background to refine and concentrate the flavors and textures of barbecue and reimagine its possibilities. Adam&apos;s new techniques, from roughing up meat and vegetables (&quot;scruffing&quot;) to cooking directly on hot coals (&quot;clinching&quot;) to constantly turning and moving the meat while cooking (&quot;hot potato&quot;), produce crust formation and layers of flavor.



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Sun. July 22•Adrienne Kane•United States of Pie: Regional Favorites from East to West and North to South•3-4 p.m.•FREE

 

An utterly charming collection of regional heirloom American pies, from long-lost recipes to classic favorites, sweetly illustrated and chock-full of time-tested baking tips and secrets for perfect pies. &quot;A charming recipe collection...Kane&apos;s book includes the most thorough instructions we&apos;ve seen yet on mastering pie dough; so whether you&apos;re new to the form, or a been-there, done-that pie aficionado, you&apos;ll find so much to love in these pages!&quot; -Matt Lee and Ted Lee, authors of The Lee Bros. Simple Fresh Southern 



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Wed. July 25•April Bloomfield•A Girl and Her Pig: Recipes and Stories•Dinner with the author at Camino Restaurant in Oakland•6:00 p.m.•$100 including wine (not including tip&amp;tax); April will be cooking, too! Contact the restaurant for reservations: 510-547-5035.

 

Join us for a 3-course dinner with chef April Bloomfield, chef of New York&apos;s Spotted Pig and The Breslin. In A Girl and Her Pig, April Bloomfield takes home cooks on an intimate tour of the food that has made her a star. Thoughtful, voice-driven recipes go behind the scenes of Bloomfield&apos;s lauded restaurants and into her own home kitchen, where her attention to detail and reverence for honest ingredients result in unforgettable dishes that reflect her love for the tactile pleasures of cooking and eating.



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Sat. July 28•Jenny Rosenstrach•Dinner: A Love Story•3-4 p.m.•FREE

 

“I can’t decide which I like more—reading this book or cooking from it. Jenny is that rare writer who can literally make you laugh and cry—and most importantly, she inspires you to stop just talking about dinner and start making it.” - Adam Rapoport, Editor in Chief, Bon Appétit.



Add this event to your calendar .
 
Tues. July 31•Margo True•Sunset Edible Garden Cookbook•6-7 p.m.•FREE

 

Here to help gardeners enjoy a healthier lifestyle is Sunset Edible Garden Cookbook with detailed gardening advice and over 150 recipes using luscious homegrown fruits and vegetables. This cookbook combines Sunset&apos;s fast recipes with practical gardening tips that will garner beautiful, delicious produce year after year from coast-to-coast.



Add this event to your calendar .
 

 back to top Omnivore Books on Food · 3885a Cesar Chavez Street · San Francisco, CA 94131 · 415.282.4712 · Hours: Mon-Sat 11am-6pm, Sun 12-5
	</body>
</document>
