<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004771" url="http://www.jamieoliver.com/forum/viewtopic.php?id=60789" time="2012-07-12-21:16" support="1" score="0.0011247916912532157" bingtitle="Jamie Oliver - Forums / School fundraiser... at McDonalds?! - beta" webtitle="Jamie Oliver - Forums / School fundraiser... at McDonalds?! - beta">
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... families to &quot;share a dinner together&quot; at the fast food restaurant ... would get a &quot;coupon&quot;, when they check out the cashier ... Which is why I came up with the Nickel-a-Meal ...</description>
	<body>
		JamieOliver.com
 country uk 
 UK Australia USA Deutschland Nederland 
 sign in newsletter 
 jamie recipes foundation books&amp;tv restaurants party plan shop share more 
 global-menu-8 
 news stories photos bio food philosophy facebook twitter rss 
 
 jamie recipes bbq chicken vegetarian pasta beef fish video recipes member recipes 
 
 jamie oliver foundation fifteen school projects ministry of food food revolution kitchen garden project 
 
 books&amp;tv jamie&apos;s summer food rave up jamie&apos;s great britain 30-minute meals christmas with bells on 
 
 jamie&apos;s italian fifteen barbecoa recipease cooking school fabulous feasts catering union jacks 
 
 jamie at home 
 
 jme shop jme food fifteen shop mobile apps jamie oliver products wood fired ovens 
 
 gardening blogs member recipes supperclub forums 
 
 jamie magazine home cooking skills home cooking skills australia videos competitions wine 
 
 gardening blogs member recipes supperclub forums 
 share 
 gardening blogs member recipes supperclub forums 
 
Blogs and forums

 Forums 
 Recent posts Unanswered posts Search 
 Blogs Foodwise 

 Register Login 
welcome Guest 
 Jump to forum --- Introductions Food and Wine FAQs Gardening / Growing Foundation Leftovers 
forum: Foundation
 
 

 Not a member? Advertisement Subscribe to forums RSS 

 
Pages: 1 | Home  »  Foundation  » School fundraiser... at McDonalds?! 
 Share 
 #1  Wed 14 Apr 10 6:02am 
 
 nicole_planb 
 Member Member since Wed 14 Apr 10 
School fundraiser... at McDonalds?!
 
I just found out this afternoon that my daughter&apos;s middle school PTO (Parent Teacher Organization) is having a fundraiser&quot;family night out&quot;at McDonald&apos;s. The event encourages all families to&quot;share a dinner together&quot;at the fast food restaurant on a given evening and 20% of all proceeds will benefit PTO activities. I am shocked that they picked McDonald&apos;s to host such an event. We live in a rural area of Massachusetts known for its bounty of locally grown produce/meats/cheeses and we have tons of healthy, locally-owned restaurants that are community minded. As a professional in nonprofit fundraising, I understand the appeal of&quot;easy money&quot;but I will NOT be participating in this effort. My 13-year old daughter is a bit of a food activist so I am hoping we can spend time together writing a letter to the Principal and PTO... and enclose an substitute donation that is restricted to an activity or purchase (i.e. books or dvds) related to healthy eating. It is bad enough that they have to eat junk at school... but to classify a night at McDonalds as a&quot;warm and fuzzy&quot;positive family night out is pushing it.  I wonder how other families may feel.
 
Offline
   
 #2  Wed 14 Apr 10 1:14pm 
 
 cohphanta 
 Occupation Book Seller From Jacksonville, FL Member since Sun 04 Apr 10 
Re: School fundraiser... at McDonalds?!
 
Raise a fuss. Get in touch with the head of the PTO and ask. Maybe see if you can get support to have an&quot;alternative&quot;night out for those who don&apos;t want to do that. I&apos;m a trouble maker. ...if you have a local bookseller that likes to work with the community, contact them. See if they would be willing to go to that McDs that night, with books on healthy eating and cookbooks and donate a percentage of the sales to the program. You may have to ask the McDs and the head of the PTO,but it&apos;s worth a shot. If not, see if you can get teh bookstore to &apos;host&quot;a&quot;get healthy school&quot;week. I say week because then the parents can go in and shop when it&apos;s convienent. Every child/parent would get a&quot;coupon&quot;, when they check out the cashier would write the amount of purchase on the coupon. After the week is over, the manager/owner would talley them up and figure out the percent they agreed to and give to the PTO. I ran a bookstore for 7 years and this does work. It&apos;s worth a try.
 
Offline
   
 #3  Wed 14 Apr 10 6:13pm 
 
 NickelMan 
 Member Occupation Writer, consultant, pain in the butt. From Benicia, California, USA Member since Mon 22 Mar 10 
Re: School fundraiser... at McDonalds?!
 
Don&apos;t hear about this too often, which is a surprise. Everyone likes McWhatever fast food outlets, so it makes sad sense that someone would do this. Personally I think we need to force the fast food industry to be part of the solution. Which is why I came up with the Nickel-a-Meal(.info) campaign idea. Imagine how much money and attention we could raise if these outlets promoted the idea that a voluntary, extra nickel would be added to the cost of each value meal? Those many, many dollars could then be transferred electronically to food empowerment projects in the area. The fast food restaurants would be forced to hear over and over again about how the money collected at their place is feeding a local revolution for change ... and consumers would have a visible way to fight back ... not to mention a ton of money to do it with. Most social change efforts fail because of a lack of resources. We can do that by being creative. I encourage you to use the opportunity you are faced with to pressure the local McDonald&apos;s to be part of the solution and to educate your neighbors. Good luck. Google Nickels Against Obesity to see more. Thanks.
 
Offline
   
 #4  Wed 14 Apr 10 10:02pm 
 
 dtoneatti 
 Member Occupation retired public relations From Ottawa, Canada Member since Wed 14 Apr 10 
Re: School fundraiser... at McDonalds?!
 
I am totally shocked that responsible parents would even suggest having such an event at a McD!! Has anyone ever seen the movie&quot;Supersize Me&quot;? McD and others are the biggest culprits of the problems we now face in North America. Get the PTO to host a fundraiser elsewhere or better still, get a copy of the movie before the fundraiser and organize an&quot;evening at the movies&quot;for the PTO to make them realize that the fast food industry is killing their kids!! The only reason I would go into a fast food place is to use their bathroom! 
 
Offline
   
 #5  Thu 15 Apr 10 1:14am 
 
 bettyblack 
 Member Member since Thu 15 Apr 10 
Re: School fundraiser... at McDonalds?!
 
Raise funds and awareness for your organization. Host a movie night! Organize a public screening of Dirt! The Movie to learn more about school gardens and the food you eat. Find out more at www.dirtthemovie.org and contact them for more information.
 
Offline
   
Pages: 1 | Home  »  Foundation  » School fundraiser... at McDonalds?! 
 Share 
Powered by PunBB 
 
shortcuts

 Jamie 
• News 
• Diary 
• Biography 

 Recipes 
• Recipes 
• Member recipes 

 
 Shop 
• Jme Shop 
• Mobile apps 
• Jamie Oliver Products 
• Wood Fired Ovens 

 Books&amp;TV 
• Jamie&apos;s Great Britain 
• Jamie&apos;s 30 Minute Meals 
• Jamie Does 
• Jamie&apos;s American roadtrip 
• Jamie at Home 
• Cook with Jamie 
• Jamie&apos;s Italy 

 
 Restaurants 
• Barbecoa 
• Recipease 
• Jamie&apos;s Italian 
• Fifteen 
• Fabulous Feasts 

 Campaigns 
• Jamie&apos;s Food Revolution 
• Ministry of Food 
• School Dinners 

 
 Share 
• Forums 
• Blogs 
• RSS 

 Party plan 
• Jamie at Home 

 
 More 
• Home Cooking Skills 
• Magazine 
• FreshOne Productions 
• Tonic Productions 
• Gardening 
• Wine 
• Videos 
 Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy Customer Services Sitemap Affiliates Advertise Help Careers with Jamie
	</body>
</document>
