<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004127" url="http://fpn.advisen.com/articles/article81199618-1742855730.html" time="2012-07-12-20:22" support="1" score="0.0010492138120412802" bingtitle="Advisen FPN" webtitle="Advisen FPN">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>... go to the Losses &amp; Exposures dropdown and select MSCAd ... tort,insurance,losses,risk)),&lt;near/7&gt;(&lt;any&gt;(&lt;near/5 ... any&gt;(customers,personal,medical,&lt;phrase&gt;(credit,card ...</description>
	<body>
		Wednesday, August 06 2008 
 
 You are in: Front Page News Headlines  -&gt; Advisen Did You Know: Advisen for Cyber Liability 
 
 Did You Know Advisen Did You Know: Advisen for Cyber Liability Publication Date: 08/05/2008 Source: Advisen John Passaro CNA comment 
 Advisen for Cyber
Liability 

When was the last time
you spoke to your clients about cyber exposures? On the heels of our
data security briefing, we want to make you aware of Advisens
cyber functionalities. We have a POLICY FORM library online which
contains cyber liability forms to compare, 385 cyber-related LOSS
EVENTS to show exposure examples, WHO WRITES WHAT Coverage Where for
cyber markets as well as BENCHMARKING and a NEWS SEARCH that puts all
cyber exposure stories and examples in one place. Amid a soft market,
this rapidly evolving insurance solution represents a new revenue
source for brokers and underwriters that is being bought by an
expanding array of companies.




Headlines are filled
with news about businesses that have experienced security breaches to
their data or their clients&apos; data, says CNA Vice President of
Technology John Wurzler. As a business owner, you need to protect
your increased reliance on technology by investigating products that
cover online and offline services, computer attacks and viruses,
employee acts, hacking, identity theft and theft of proprietary or
confidential information as well as infringing or disparaging
content. Think of it this way -- any business or organization that
uses a computer needs an insurance partner that stays current with
emerging trends, understands the latest technology exposures and
creates cyber coverage options to best meet clients&apos; technology usage
needs.




Dick Clarke, a Senior
Vice President in the Executive Protection Group, at broker J. Smith
Lanier&amp;Co. added,&quot;Like the introduction of Employment
Practices Liability insurance about twenty years ago, there is a long
learning curve for cyber exposures and corresponding insurance
products, which has just recently reached its zenith. Before
insurance brokers can effectively sell cyber insurance products, they
must understand the basic exposures which are generally more involved
than just a transactional website, and then be able to recommend a
good insurance solution.&quot;




 CYBER LIABILITY ON
ADVISEN 




 Read our Cyber
Liability Briefing 

Digitized information
has transformed the way business is conducted, but it also has
created dangerous new liability exposures. One recent data breach is
expected to result in more than $200 million in lawsuit settlements
and loss mitigation expenses. Data security has been the domain of
the Information Technology department, but as insurance products
become more sophisticated, corporate risk managers will be
increasingly called upon to help manage this enormous exposure. Read
our brief: Data Security: A Growing Liability Risk was
published on July 28, 2008. This five-pager provides a basic primer
to understanding cyber liability exposure. To access, click on the
Topical Analysis dropdown menu and select Liability. Non-subscribers
may purchase a copy for $50 via corner@advisen.com or 610.388.9132.




 Cyber Loss Events 

When youre reviewing
cyber exposures, you need to consider how bad can this be? You
also want to review the details of known cases and their settlements.
Our MSCAd Large Loss database of over 9,500 cases&amp;actions
contains 385 entries related to cyber risks. Settlements range from
$34,590 to $1.2 billion. The three largest industry segments that
have experienced loss events related to cyber are higher education,
banks and healthcare companies. To access Advisens Large Loss
database, go to the Losses&amp;Exposures dropdown and select MSCAd,
our acronym for our Master Significant Case and Action database.
Click on the Case tab and choose Cyber Risk and then Show List.




 Cyber News Search 

Given the array of
cyber issues and risks involved, weve created a search mechanism
to generate a list of relevant news stories. Consider this also to
be a list of war stories.




Find news articles from
a large number of wires and periodicals in one place. Copy&amp;paste the following Boolean logic string into the keyword box on your
Advisen News Search (under the News tab on the top Advisen tool bar).
Click on the&quot;Search&quot;button to execute the search:




&lt;and&gt;(&lt;any&gt;(cyberliability,cybertort,cyberinsurance,&lt;phrase&gt;(&lt;any&gt;(internet,cyber),&lt;any&gt;(liability,tort,insurance,losses,risk)),&lt;near/7&gt;(&lt;any&gt;(&lt;near/5&gt;(&lt;any&gt;(computer,internet,technology),security),data),breach),&lt;and&gt;(data,&lt;any&gt;(lost,stolen,&lt;word&gt;hacker,&lt;word&gt;hacked,&lt;word&gt;cracked,breach),&lt;any&gt;(customers,personal,medical,&lt;phrase&gt;(credit,card),liability,lawsuit)),&lt;and&gt;(internet,liability))&lt;in&gt;v_resourcesummary,&lt;not&gt;&lt;any&gt;(inewsnetwork,&lt;phrase&gt;(ap,online)))




Save the cyber news
search once so that you can access it easily again. Click on the&quot;Save Search&quot;button. Then, give the search command a name
and click on the&quot;Save and Return to Results&quot;button. Now
your cyber news search is stored under the My Advisen tab under My
Searches. Using similar Boolean logic, customize your Advisen member
id to always find news on any of your favorite companies or
industries, subjects&amp;topics.




Not interested in doing
this yourself? Call your Advisen rep and well create the search
for you.




 Policy Forms 

How can you quickly
analyze and compare the cyber liability coverages available to
protect your client? The Advisen policy form library contains over
2,100 forms broken apart by clause. There are 687 Errors&amp;Omissions forms which include at least 40 with cyber in their
form name. Compare any two or more forms side-by-side to assess
coverage terms and provision wordings. Also, consult our collection
of GL, Fiduciary and D&amp;O forms since some of these forms contain
cyber protections, too. To access, click on the Policy&amp;Law
Comparisons dropdown menu and select Errors&amp;Omissions.




 Who Writes What
Cyber Coverage Where? 

Advisen displays all
the insurers and wholesalers we know who have written a program in
the last 18 months. Sorting this data by LOB/coverage, for example,
means we show 48 markets that wrote E-business liability in the last
18 months. Now sort the list by rating, etc. To access, click on the
Prospecting&amp;Peers dropdown menu and select Who Writes What
Where. Our universe of Markets for all lines is currently 1,142.




 Cyber Benchmarking 

How much does cyber
cover cost? What limits are available? What is the rate per mil
that public, private and not-for-profit organizations pay? Advisens
program online data encompasses several aspects of this topic. 
Review premium, limit and retention data for Computer Crime Bond
under Fidelity/Surety/Crime; e-Business Liability under Liability;
and Electronic Data Processors E&amp;O under Professional Liability. 
To access, click on the Benchmarking dropdown menu and select
Advanced.




 New Product
Announcements 

How do you know when a
new cyber product is coming out?&quot;New cyber insurance products
are being developed and/or updated on a fairly constant basis,
says Dick Clarke. These products all have similarities, but no two
are alike, so having a source for detailed product comparison becomes
critically important to the insurance broker.&quot;Read Advisens
New Products Announcement (NPA) column in Front Page News or under
the News dropdown menu. NPA contains short descriptions of your new
commercial insurance products or services, such as Navigators Pros
new Tech InNAVation Information Technology Professional Liability
policy for information technology services, software, Internet
consulting, technology development and web design firms.







NEED ASSISTANCE?

If we can help you
prepare for a prospect or client presentation, please contact us at support@advisen.com .




Contact us and we will
walk you through the quick steps above. Call your Advisen rep at
212.897.4800 or support@advisen.com 




Reach John Wurzler at
CNA at 616.285.2679 or john.wurzler@cna.com 




Reach Dick Clarke at J.
Smith Lanier at 770.814.4585 or dclarke@jsmithlanier.com
	</body>
</document>
