<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004507" url="http://www.watchfreemovies.ch/watch-movies/1997/watch-good-burger-14295/" time="2012-07-12-20:55" support="1" score="0.001648917692621389" bingtitle="Watch Good Burger online free 1997 - download Good Burger ..." webtitle="Watch Good Burger online free 1997 - download Good Burger -  LetMeWatchThis">
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>... forced to get a summer job at a fast food restaurant called Good Burger after causing a car ... new friend Ed the not-so bright cashier ... South Park</description>
	<body>
		Advanced Search 
 Movies TV Shows Music Forum 
 
 Let Me Watch Good Burger (1997) Online 
 
 
Dexter Reed, a high-schooler is forced to get a summer job at a fast food restaurant called Good Burger after causing a car wreck by his school teacher Mr. Wheat. So Dexter must pay off his teacher&apos;s car by working very hard at Good Burger. Meanwhile things turned worse when Mondo Burger, a mammoth fast-food chain opens across the street, it looks like Good Burger is soon going to be history for good! Now it is up to Dexter and his new friend Ed the not-so bright cashier to save the day, as they develop a delicious special secret sauce that Ed created brings hundreds of new customers to their door and makes their new competition desperate to steal the recipe and all of their customers.
 
 Currently 3.55/5 
 (20 votes) Released: July 25, 1997 Runtime: 103 mins Genres: Family Comedy Director: Brian Robbins Actors: Linda Cardellini Carmen Electra Sinbad Abe Vigoda Brad Wilson Andres Aybar Floyd Levine Paul Parducci Kelly Devine Kim Delgado John R. Corella George Clinton David Shackelford Wendy Worthington Eve Sigall 
 
 Favorites To Watch Watched 
 
 
 
 Good Burger (1997) LetMeWatchThis Links 
 
 Good Burger | HQ Version 668 views 
 Watch Good Burger - HQ Version rating: 4/5 
 (21 votes) 

 Version 2 sockshare.com 1521 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 2 rating: 3.33/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (12 votes) 

 Version 3 sockshare.com 1188 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 3 rating: 2.92/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (13 votes) 

 Version 4 putlocker.com 3087 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 4 rating: 3.15/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (13 votes) 

 Version 5 megavideo.com 548 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 5 rating: 3/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (10 votes) 

 Version 6 megavideo.com 366 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 6 rating: 3/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (10 votes) 

 Version 7 megavideo.com 180 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 7 rating: 2.82/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (11 votes) 

 Version 8 stagevu.com 305 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 8 rating: 3/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (11 votes) 

 Version 9 [ Part 2 ]
 
 [ Part 3 ] youtube.com 332 views 
 Watch Good Burger - Version 9 rating: 3.08/5 1 2 3 4 5 
 (12 votes) 
 This movie is available for download - Click for free download 
 = Low Quality = Medium Quality = High Quality How do I watch these? 
 
 Watch LetMeWatchThis Featured Movies 
 
 Good Burger (1997) Keywords 
 African American Automobile Based On Sketch Comedy Based On TV Series Basketball Black American Car Accident Competition Cult Favorite Driving Without A License Fast Food Restaurant Food In Title Friend Friendship Hamburger Mental Institution Miniature Golf Reckless Driving Sabotage Slow Witted Spy Student Summer Job Teacher Teacher Student Relationship Teenage Boy Title Spoken By Character 
 Post a review/comment for Good Burger (1997) 
 Please login to add a review / make a comment 
 
 Attention! 

Click here for direct download Good Burger.avi 
 
 
Join the site, it&apos;s free!
 Username: 
 Password: 

 Remember Me 
 Forgot Login | Sign Up 
I can&apos;t watch movies! Help!
 Follow @real_letmewatch 
Watch / Download Movies
 
Latest Comments
 Battleship 
 jellybaby32 : AWESOME FILM!! it was slightly spoilt by the tinny overloud music so parts of...
 The Champagne Gang 
 Jessica132b90 : boring don&apos;t watch this unless you want to fall asleep
 Hideaways 
 deenosaur016 : I love this movie! One of my favourites right now! :)
 G.I. Joe 2: Retaliation 
 DaVeO52 : People didn&apos;t complain. Executives saw that Channing is a hot commodity now...
 Ice Age: Continental Drift 
 timtebow36 : great movie guys i loved it
 Savages 
 sarahrose19892 : Hopefully we gget to see this soon eh. :D
 Ted 
 XetoN : nice movie but the quality suuucks.... High quality will bet Veeeery Coool
 Gone with the Wind 
 Lovely71 : This is one of my favorite movies of all time :o)
 Another Cinderella Story 
 holliegibson : this movie is exalent
 Another Cinderella Story 
 holliegibson : this site is very good!xx
 
Watch Featured TV-Shows
 
White Collar 
Pretty Little.. 
Bones 
Eureka 
Burn Notice 
Weeds 
True Blood 
The Vampire D.. 
Rizzoli&amp;Isles LetMeWatchThis Online - LetMeWatchThis - Watch free movies online ! Let me watch this Movies Search Feed - Let Me Watch This Requests - Contacts - FAQ - Legal | Full Downloads LetMeWatchThis is #1 place to watch movies online without paying ridiculous theater prices. Below, is a list of free full movies.
	</body>
</document>
