<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004057" url="http://whatithoughtofit.com/category/eating_out/restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-20:17" support="6" score="0.009877645644501304" bingtitle="What I Thought of It » Restaurants" webtitle="What I Thought of ItRestaurants">
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="134"/>
	<description>She will call up to confirm a free table and then ... Banzai is best described as a Japanese fast-food restaurant. ... Then my food arrived. The rice was warm and well ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Rating System 
 Search: 
 What I Thought of It 
 Thought-full reviews of things and places 
Thought-full reviews of things and places

You&apos;ve come to the right place if you&apos;re looking for a second (or first) opinion about something. Just do a search or browse our categories. Find out what we thought of it, then tell us what you thought of it!
 
Category:

 Accommodations 
 Campgrounds Hotels / Motels 
 Eating Out 
 Bars / Pubs Coffee / Tea / Drinks Fast Food Restaurants Sweet Treats Wings 
 Food Products Products 
 Household shoes 
 Recreation 
 Attractions Movies / TV Outdoors Theater Walks / Hikes 
 Retail 
 Bookstores Department Stores Drugstores Online Shopping Secondhand Services Specialty Stores Sports / Outdoors 
 Uncategorized 
 
Archives:

 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 
 
Blogroll:

 Development Blog Documentation Plugins Suggest Ideas Support Forum Themes WordPress Planet 
 
Meta:

 RSS Comments RSS Valid XHTML XFN 
 
Extra:

 
 

 
 Sky 360 Restaurant&amp;Lounge 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Sky 360 Restaurant&amp;Lounge 
101 9 Ave SW
Calgary AB  T2P 1J9
Phone: 403 532 7966
 www.sky360.ca 

 In Calgary and looking for a restaurant with a view? This is the spot! The Sky 360 Restaurant is situated in the Calgary Tower, just one level below the observation deck. What’s more, the restaurant revolves, so imagine being 525 feet above street level and getting a complete 360-degree bird’s-eye view of Calgary while you eat. The view is incomparable! Sky 360 makes a complete revolution in 45 minutes at lunch time and in 1 hour at dinner time, so you get a full visual tour of the city in the course of your meal.

So here’s the short recommendation: YES, it is good, and YES, by all means go to Sky 360. Read on if you’d like to find out why.

You might expect a restaurant at the top of the Calgary Tower to feature an expensive menu. That isn’t exactly true. In fact, Sky 360’s prices are very competitive with the nicer, non-tower dining establishments in town. They are just a smidge above the prices at your average chain restaurant, while obviously having superior ambiance. Adult admission to the top of Calgary Tower is $12.95, but this is waived for a Sky 360 customer who orders an entree. So, you’ve now saved $12.95 and your lunch menu burger is only $16.

When you first enter the Calgary Tower, go to the desk and ask for the hostess of the Sky 360 Restaurant. She will call up to confirm a free table and then direct you to the elevator. In exchange for getting to go up the tower for free, you must order a lunch or dinner entree, so plan to have more than a coffee.

When you reach the restaurant, another hostess will escort you to your table. Sky 360 has arranged all the tables to face the 360-degree windows. There is a mix of booths, tables for two, and seating for large groups. As soon as you sit down you’ll feel the restaurant turning. The vertical walls and windows stay in place while the floor moves. Prepare to lose some orientation if you leave your table to visit the washrooms (in the non-revolving center of the tower). When you try to go back, your table won’t be where you thought it was.

The Sky 360 menu has enough to have something for everyone. The food list is short, so a frequent diner could get bored. I don’t know if and how often the menu changes.

For lunch, I quickly settled on the Beef Burger. My friend chose the Seafood Bouillabaisse on the advice of our server Geraldo, who did an exquisite job of attending to us.

The food was not long in arriving. In any case, it doesn’t feel like waiting when you can admire Calgary from the restaurant’s vantage point.

 My burger looked sumptuous: a beef patty with a slice of bacon and aged cheddar on an onion bun. It tasted even better than it looked - it was bursting with juice and flavor. The sauce dripped down my hands every time I took a bite. Besides that teeny flaw, I could have one of these burgers everyday. The fries were the right degree of crispy. The portion size of this meal even exceeded my appetite. The burger was easily more substantial than the typical chain-restaurant burger, leaving little doubt as to which one is the better value for money.

The Seafood Bouillabaisse was beautifully presented. It was teeming with tasty morsels, including tender salmon, large juicy scallops, shrimp, and mussels. The broth was rich in flavor and texture. The dish came with basil pesto crostini (resting on top, in the photo), a zesty and crunchy accompaniment. Geraldo had made the perfect recommendation. He would get my vote for best server in Calgary.

After your meal, go up one level to the observation deck. Here you can spend more time taking in the tower view.

 Last thoughts: Having lived more than three years in Calgary, I’m kicking myself for not discovering Sky 360 until now. The food is exceptional, the service superb, and the view second to none. I would love to go for dinner and gaze down on Calgary all lit up at night. I also want to go back for lunch on a clear day to enjoy an aerial view of the mountains. You can be sure I’ll be looking for excuses to visit Sky 360 Restaurant&amp;Lounge again and again.

 Food +++++ 
 Service +++++
 Ambiance +++++
 Washrooms +++ 
 
Tags: burger , Calgary , Calgary Tower , seafood 
 
 
 Bumper’s: The Beef House, Banff 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Bumper’s Beef House 
603 Banff Ave
Banff AB
Phone: 403 762 2622
 www.bumpersinn.com/beefhouse.htm 

 After a day of basking in the fresh air of the Rocky Mountains, the body yearns to wind down with hearty food. We were drawn to try Bumper’s, which claims that“if you haven’t been to Bumper’s, you haven’t been to Banff”.

Bumper’s is not one of the many restaurants in Banff’s downtown core. It’s a bit more hidden but still easy to find. If you follow Banff Avenue heading out of town, you’ll find Bumper’s on the left, just before you hit the woods. It’s basically the last building in town.

Bumper’s Beef House has an airy, rustic atmosphere. The inside is furnished in wood, with a huge wooden man in the middle of the restaurant. As you can deduce from the name, Bumper’s serves everything you’d expect from a steakhouse, plus more. Most items on the Bumper’s menu include helping yourself to the all-you-can-eat salad bar. If you don’t want anything else, it’s even worth going just for the salad bar. The salad bar is one of the biggest and best I’ve ever seen. It’s a generous spread of vegetables, fruits, cheeses, legumes, dressings, soups, and fresh-baked dinner rolls.

For dinner we ordered Pile-O-Bones and Bumper’s Super Burger, and both included the salad bar. It was fairly early (they open at 5 pm) and before the dinner rush, so our food arrived much faster than in the average steakhouse.

The Pile-O-Bones, which are prime rib bones, were massive. The waitress had warned that they would be“chewy”. They did prove to be a workout for the jaw, but my friend gnawed happily on these flavorful beef ribs.

I had the Bumper’s Super Burger, touted on the menu as“one of the burger wonders of the world”. It was far from being so! The bread looked black. I normally like bread well toasted, but in this case the bun was simply burnt. The waitress apologized and explained that the toaster was broken. That’s fine, but how did burnt bread escape the cook’s eyes? I was given a new bun, this one barely toasted, but anything was better than blackened. I could tell after digging in that the bread wasn’t fresh to begin with. I also got cheese on my burger after declining cheese when I placed my order. Overall the burger tasted okay but no more.

 Last thoughts: Bumper’s is a nice restaurant in Banff, farther away from the busier tourist hangouts yet still close enough to be a convenient option. Would I go back? Possibly, but if so I’m staying away from their“wonder”burger.

 Food ++ 
 Service +++
 Ambiance ++++
 Washrooms ++++ 
 
Tags: Banff , burgers , ribs 
 
 
 Huckleberry’s Family Restaurant 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Huckleberry’s Family Restaurant 
205 Laurier St
Invermere BC
Phone: 250 342 3800
 www.huckleberrysrestaurant.com 

 While on a little road trip we had to stop in Invermere for lunch. After driving around to scope out the food territory, we were drawn to try Huckleberry’s Family Restaurant.

To find this family restaurant in Invermere, just take the main road into town and look on your left. Huckleberry’s Restaurant looks like a big log cabin inside and out. On entering you’re greeted by a large ice cream counter. On a warm day, people can pop in to buy a cold treat and enjoy it outside on the picnic tables (also crafted from logs). On this day we opted for a sit-down meal inside. The dining room is split in two, on either side of the ice cream counter. Both sides are sparsely decorated, and the tables and chairs could have been chosen with more thought to complement the cozy log-cabin setting.

Huckleberry’s has an extensive menu bursting with choices. The menu itself is very busy and colorful, thus somewhat hard to read. I went for the Schnitzel Burger while my companion picked the Seafood Omelette with Huckleberry Pancakes.

Our food arrived shortly. The Schnitzel Burger looked good: a nicely breaded piece of meat on a fresh bun. It was the first time I’d had schnitzel in a burger. The schnitzel was cooked right and a perfect fit with the bun. The fries were crispy and tasted great.

The Seafood Omelette looked quite plain at first but proved to be full of tasty stuffing. It paired well with the Huckleberry Pancakes (it normally comes with plain pancakes). The pancakes were dotted with pieces of huckleberry and heavenly with the house-made huckleberry syrup.

Our server was very friendly and entertained all my questions about huckleberries. He even gave us ideas for things to see while in Invermere. A server who is fully engaged with his customers is a rare treat these days.

 Last thoughts : Huckleberry’s Family Restaurant is a must-go and must-return. The food is super, the decor unique, and the service exemplary. If you’re going anywhere near Invermere, eat at Huckleberry’s and you will leave happy.

 Food ++++ 
 Service +++++
 Ambiance ++++
 Washrooms ++++ 
 
Tags: Huckleberry&apos;s , Invermere 
 
 
 Banzai Sushi&amp;Teriyaki House 
 Eating Out , Fast Food , Restaurants No Comments 
 Banzai Sushi&amp;Teriyaki House 
526A 4 Ave SW
Calgary AB  T2P 0J6
Phone: 403 262 9060

 We had just seen a Sunday matinee movie and were famished. On our way home we walked by Banzai Restaurant on 4th Avenue in downtown Calgary.

We decided to stop for a bite to eat.

On entering Banzai Sushi&amp;Teriyaki House you find a fresh environment with great ambiance and decor. On this Sunday afternoon it was not particularly busy, but I think weekdays at lunch time would be a much different story.

Banzai is best described as a Japanese fast-food restaurant. We each ordered a Bento Box (described as a“lunch box”but apparently available all day). The counter lady bade us to take a table then later brought our order.

Each Bento Box ($8.25) came with miso soup, two spring rolls, rice, salad, and two“entrees”. Mine were beef and chicken. Both types of meat were cooked to perfection and topped with teriyaki sauce; the chicken was accompanied by shredded cabbage. The folks at Banzai know their marinades, because the beef and chicken had great flavor. The spring rolls were small and skimpy on filling, but they were crispy and tastily greasy.

My friend’s entrees were California rolls (3 pieces) and tempura (2 shrimp, 1 yam, 1 cucumber, 2 mushrooms). The tempura was good and crisp, and the rolls were adequate.

 Last thoughts: Going to Banzai Sushi&amp;Teriyaki House is a quick way to quench your craving for Japanese. For a fast-food establishment, it really delivered on taste, service, and atmosphere. I wouldn’t mind going back.

 Food ++++ 
 Service ++++
 Ambiance +++++
 Washrooms ++++ 
 
Tags: downtown , Japanese , Sushi 
 
 
 A Touch of Ginger Delight 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 A Touch of Ginger Delight 
318 10 St NW
Calgary AB  T2N 1V8
Phone: 403 270 3816

 Let me start by saying that I don’t single out bad places. Good and bad experiences are equally deserving of blog space on What I Thought of It .

Being in the vicinity, we popped into A Touch of Ginger Delight in Kensington for dinner. On this Saturday night, all but one table in the medium-sized restaurant was empty. In hindsight, this should have been a warning.

We were quickly seated by a friendly server. I ordered a Coke without ice, which she repeated to herself, yet minutes later there arrived a Coke with ice. Of course, this mistake has occurred in other restaurants, but at A Touch of Ginger Delight, it was just the beginning.

I ordered item C63 from the menu, a rice dish with shredded pork and BBQ pork. My friend had questions about some menu items, but the waitress was not knowledgeable and needed to ask the kitchen twice.

While waiting for the food to arrive I went to the washroom. It looked clean, but the stench made it difficult to finish my business. I couldn’t tell where the smell came from.

Then my food arrived. The rice was warm and well prepared. There was a salad of shredded lettuce and carrots on the side. The lettuce was browning on the edges, clearly past freshness. The shredded pork on top of the rice was cold. I don’t mean lukewarm - I mean almost freezing cold. Luckily it eventually absorbed some warmth from the rice. The BBQ pork was the thinnest piece of pork I’ve ever seen. If the shredded pork and BBQ pork were supposed to be different, then something was off, because they tasted exactly the same. To make it worse, neither one came close to tasting like pork. I felt like I was eating synthetic or expired food.

In the course of my meal, a couple of people finished and left. Their tables were cleared but not cleaned, then new customers were seated at the same tables. Perhaps more diligent cleaning would be advisable amid worries of the H1N1 virus spreading around Calgary.

 Last thoughts: I am surprised that A Touch of Ginger Delight is still in business. I hope it is not always like what I experienced. This was my worst meal in living memory. I could not bear to finish my food and ended up eating something at home. I’m never going back to A Touch of Ginger Delight, and be careful if you’re planning to pay a visit.

 Food - 
 Service +++ 
 Ambiance ++
 Washrooms - 
 
Tags: Thai , Vietnamese 
 
 
 Swiss Chalet Rotisserie&amp;Grill 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Swiss Chalet Rotisserie&amp;Grill 
5010 4 St NE
Calgary AB  T2K 5X8
Phone: 403 275 1642

 After repeatedly hearing radio advertisements for the new Summer Sensations meal, we made plans to dine out at Swiss Chalet. At dinner time on a Sunday night, the Swiss Chalet at McKnight Boulevard&amp;4th Street NE was packed with customers, yet we were still seated immediately.

The atmosphere at this Swiss Chalet restaurant is on the old-fashioned side, which could be intentional given that the customers tend to be from an older generation.

Service was efficient right from the start, and our food arrived after a short wait. The Summer Sensations meal ($11.99) includes a quarter chicken, salad (spinach or tomato-cucumber), a choice of side, and a sundae or pie for dessert.

 Uniquely among restaurants, Swiss Chalet Rotisserie&amp;Grill offers a choice of white or dark meat when you order chicken. We chose dark and were happy we did. The chicken was perfectly cooked, slightly juicy, and very flavorful. The salads looked and tasted fresh (we thought spinach was a better choice than tomato-cucumber). The side of fries was a bit overcooked but still tasted good. The side of vegetables was somewhat bland (needing table pepper) but at least not drenched in butter. All in all, each Summer Sensations meal was more than enough to fill one stomach.

Dessert was still to come. I chose the sundae (vanilla ice cream, chocolate fudge, whipped cream, cinnamon sugar, cherry on top). It was good, but the fudge was poorly mixed in, either sitting on top or stuck on the bottom. My friend chose the pecan pie, warmed up. The pie filling - buttery, sweet, nutty - really hit the spot.

 Last thoughts: We had a great dinner experience at the Swiss Chalet Rotisserie&amp;Grill. The staff were extremely courteous, the food was good, and the meal was excellent value. Judging from the full house that night, many others agree. I will definitely keep this restaurant in mind the next time I feel like chicken.

 Food ++++ 
 Service ++++
 Ambiance ++++
 Washrooms +++ 
 
Tags: chicken , rotisserie , Swiss Chalet 
 
 
 Red Sea Fish&amp;Chips 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Red Sea Fish&amp;Chips 
4105 4 St NW
Calgary AB  T2K 1A3
Phone: 403 289 9904

 I was craving fish and chips, so I decided to try a new place - Red Sea Fish&amp;Chips - for dinner. This place is next to Stavros in the strip mall on the corner of 40th Avenue and 4th Street NW.

The first thing you’ll notice when you walk into Red Sea is that everything is blue. The place is casually decorated in the style of a fast-food restaurant. Everything is sea-themed, down to the signs on the men’s and women’s washrooms.

The restaurant has a row of tables along one wall and a bar against the other wall. Not much was happening when I got there on a Tuesday night. Only one table was taken up, so I had my pick of where to sit.

I had a look through the menu, then the server approached to take my order. Red Sea seems to be a nice little family business. My server was carrying her 14-month-old, fast asleep, on her back. I ordered the Seafood Platter, which comes with bacon-wrapped scallops, battered prawns, 2 pieces of cod, and fries - all for $15.95.

The food took some time to arrive but looked pretty good when it came. The scallops wrapped with bacon were a great flavor combination. The battered prawns were not too greasy and decently meaty. The cod was heavily breaded, making a hard, crispy shell around the fish. The fish inside was flaky and great with the tartar sauce.

The fries/chips were cooked to a nice crisp taste. I’m a big fan and consumer of fries, and you could wake me up in the middle of the night for these Red Sea fries.

 Last thoughts: Red Sea Fish&amp;Chips is a great little gem. As a family business, it delivers much more than chain restaurants, where these days no one seems to care. The food is good and worth the visit. If you like your fries crispy, you’ll have to check out Red Sea’s take on the chips. Go on any day except Sunday (when they’re closed).

 Food ++++ 
 Service ++++
 Ambiance +++
 Washrooms ++++ 
 
Tags: fish&amp;chips 
 
 
 Dairy Lane Cafe 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Dairy Lane Cafe 
319 19 St NW
Calgary AB  T2N 2J2
Phone: 403 283 2497
 www.dairylanecafe.ca 

 A bright, sunny Saturday in Calgary and a long walk around town brought us to Dairy Lane Cafe. After our long walk we were ready for food, but the nice weather had given others the same idea, so we had to wait. We were told 30 minutes, and exactly 30 minutes elapsed before we got a table.

Dairy Lane Cafe is on the tiny side. It only has about ten two-person tables inside and five two-person tables outside. Expect a wait whether it’s breakfast, lunch, or brunch.

The ambiance is that of an old-fashioned diner in a new setting. Although Dairy Lane Cafe opened in 1950, you wouldn’t guess that from its appearance. Everything is fresh, clean, and well-maintained.

The friendly staff keep an eye on how your meal is going. They could have come sooner to take our order, but I prefer that over feeling hurried to order when I’m still perusing the menu.

The menu is small, and that would limit how many times I’ll go back to the Dairy Lane Cafe. Have a look at the menu on their website (prices are not accurate anymore) to see what they have to offer. 

I went with my usual restaurant choice: a burger. The Dairy Lane Burger comes with cheese, bacon, and mushrooms. Dairy Lane Cafe chooses locally grown and organic ingredients wherever possible, and I think that makes everything taste better. The burger was very good, and the crispy bacon on top made it a feast to eat. It was definitely one of the better burgers I have eaten. The accompanying fries were nicely browned, crispy, and also great-tasting.

My friend chose the Vegan Tofu Scramble, and this dish looked amazing. It was prettily garnished with fresh avocado and a side of red tomato slices. The curry flavour and tofu-potato medley made it a unique, signature-worthy dish.

 

It is always nice to see a local business do so well in competition with the big chains. Restaurant chains are plentiful and familiar, but sometimes one wants something more. Dairy Lane Cafe offers that something more. They even do their bit for the planet by using 100% carbon-free energy in their quest to deliver good-quality food for a reasonable price. Their prices are just slightly but noticeably higher than comparable establishments in Calgary.

 Last thoughts: Dairy Lane Cafe certainly made me happy. My walk back home was a bit more difficult after they stuffed me with great food. I think I would go back, but I wish there were more things on the menu to try. If you’ve never been there, you have to go at least once. There’s always a line-up for weekend brunch.

 Food +++++ 
 Service ++++
 Ambiance ++++
 Washrooms ++++ 
 
Tags: brunch , diner 
 
 
 The Old Spaghetti Factory, Banff 
 Eating Out , Restaurants 1 Comment 
 The Old Spaghetti Factory 
2nd Floor Cascade Plaza
317 Banff Ave
Banff AB  T1L 1J7
Phone: 403 760 2779

 Going to Banff always brings up the question of where to go for food. This time I decided to go for dinner at The Old Spaghetti Factory.

The Old Spaghetti Factory is on the second floor of the Cascade Plaza mall. A lot of thought and care went into the interior decor, which I really enjoyed looking at while dining there.

When I got there around 6 pm on Sunday, it was busy but I had no problem getting a table.

The nice thing about The Old Spaghetti Factory is that they offer a complete meal for a not-bad price. For about $15, you get soup or salad, an entree, a side dish, ice cream, and coffee or tea.

My drink arrived with complimentary bread and garlic butter, and who can resist warm buttered bread?

I ordered the New York Steak, not with a side of spaghetti but with a side of fries. The starter salad came less than a minute after I ordered. The salad was not too bad but obviously not freshly prepared. Some of the lettuce leaves were frozen, which is common in restaurants that prepare salads beforehand and keep them chilled.

The main-course New York Steak looked pretty good, but I ordered medium-well and got medium-rare. I left it at that and tried to enjoy it anyway. The cut of meat was not the best. It had some fat, which I didn’t mind, but the rest was almost impossible to chew. Actually the whole steak was extremely tough. Thankfully, the fries were the thick-cut and tastily seasoned.

For dessert I chose the Spumone Ice Cream with Peppermint Tea. Again this only took a minute to arrive. The tea was very good, but the ice cream I could have done without. At first I thought it had some pistachio bits (spumone is supposed to have pistachios), but they turned out to be ice crystals.

I needed a washroom break, so I went through the door marked“Restrooms”and found myself standing in the mall. The Old Spaghetti Factory does not have its own washrooms, so you’ll have to use the ones in Cascade Plaza.

 Last thoughts: The Old Spaghetti Factory provided great service but ho-hum food. Maybe one shouldn’t expect much for $15, but the meal was nonetheless below par. With my pick of restaurants in Banff, you won’t find me back in this one. Elsewhere for the same price, I can get tastier food and go without the“free”starter and dessert. Look at your other options in Banff before you walk into The Old Spaghetti Factory.

 Food +++ 
 Service ++++
 Ambiance +++++
 Washrooms +++ 
 
Tags: The Old Spaghetti Factory 
 
 
 Joey’s Only Seafood, Motel Village 
 Eating Out , Restaurants No Comments 
 Joey’s Only Seafood, Motel Village 
2120 Crowchild Trail NW
Calgary AB  2TM 3Y7
Phone: 403 284 4968

 Joey’s Only Seafood Restaurant in Motel Village is nicely situated next to the pedestrian overpass from McMahon Stadium and just meters away from the Banff Trail CTrain Station.

The interior has a pleasant ambiance. It is a small space that manages to contain a good number of tables, and there’s a large aquarium in the center for your viewing pleasure.

Service at this Joey’s is always a bit rushed and not too friendly, but the staff do what they’re supposed to do, which is enough for me.

I have no complaints about the food. Joey’s Seafood has some of the best fish&amp;chips - crispy, not too greasy, just enough batter. Go for the two-piece meal, because I can’t imagine anyone being able to finish three pieces of fish. Joey’s also has the best tartar sauce, which is supplied in a big squirt bottle at each table. 

On Tuesdays Joey’s has all-you-can-eat fish&amp;chips for $9.99, so if you’re famished you can fill up on tasty fish and fries for a bargain.

Sometimes Joey’s offers a fish-&amp;-chips platter with one piece each of pollock, haddock, and halibut, so that you can decide which one you like best. In my experience, all three are delicious.

If you’d like a departure from regular potato fries, you can subsitute sweet potato fries. Joey’s does them very well - hot and crisp - and serves them with a lime mayonnaise dip. Joey’s sweet potato fries are so good, I could live on them.

 Last thoughts: Joey’s is one of my favorite restaurants, and I’ve yet to have a bad experience in the times I’ve frequented Joey’s. It’s a cozy, affordable place for fish&amp;chips and other seafood.

 Food +++++ 
 Service +++
 Ambiance ++++
 Washrooms ++++ 
 
Tags: fish&amp;chips , Joey&apos;s Only Seafood , sweet potato fries 
 

 «Previous Entries    
 
Recent Posts

 11-20-2009 Fun with Dick and Jane 11-16-2009 Sky 360 Restaurant&amp;Lounge 11-13-2009 As Good As It Gets 11-09-2009 Bumper’s: The Beef House, Banff 11-06-2009 Elf 
 
Recent Comments

 Shane Well, I disagree with this review completely. I go to this r... GuyfromBrooks Just on a note, there aren&apos;t any Self Check Outs at the Broo... ken Possibly just your experience here. I found the staff friend... rhiannon okrainec 2011 well lets start off by saying ew....... i wouldnt go ba... Chevygirl I worked at the Smittys in Strathmore for awhile after the n... 
 ©2012 What I Thought of It. All Rights Reserved. Entries RSS Comments RSS Login
	</body>
</document>
