<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004089" url="https://www.numbersusa.com/content/nusablog/nelsong/august-21-2008/foreign-workers-take-jobs-away-skilled-a.html" time="2012-07-12-20:18" support="2" score="0.0008229112826782584" bingtitle="Foreign workers take jobs away from skilled Americans | NumbersUSA ..." webtitle="Foreign workers take jobs away from skilled Americans | NumbersUSA - For Lower Immigration Levels">
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>But American colleges and universities graduate four to six times the number ... and benefits comparable to what a high school graduate earns managing a fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		No to Immigrant Bashing Press Room Donate Accuracy Guarantee 
 
 About Us 
 &quot;No&quot;to Immigrant Bashing Privacy Policy Supporters What NumbersUSA Is All About Contact Us Ethics for Action Press Our History NumbersUSA In the News 
 Hot Topics 
 5 Great Solutions Chain Migration Mandatory E-Verify State and Local Policies The Visa Lottery Birthright Citizenship Foreign Worker Timeout The CLEAR Act Secure the Border The SAVE Act More Topics Recent News Recent Blogs 
 Take Action 
 ActionBuffet Mandatory E-Verify End Birthright Citizenship End Chain Migration Donate 
 Elections 
 2012 Presidential Hopefuls Congressional State&amp;Local Browse All Candidates 
 Congress 
 Report Cards Immigration Bills Contact Info for all Congress Your Members of Congress 
 Enforcement 
 H.R. 2885 vs. Exisiting State Laws Attrition Through Enforcement Workplace Verification (E-Verify) Border Control State / Local Policies 
 Issues 
 Amnesty America&apos;s Jobless Birthright Citizenship Black Americans Chain Migration Environment Farmland High-tech workers Illegal Immigration National Sovereignty Refugees Taxpayer Burden U.S. Population Unions Urban Sprawl Visa Lottery 
 Resources 
 Video Clips Publications Public Opinion Polls Change the Numbers Quality-of-Life Maps Rumor Mill Press Releases Statistics Immigration Numbers&amp;Projections Feeds 
 
 No Match, please try again. Email: Password: Login or Register Forgot Login Need Help? Action Board My Three Congress My Account Logout Need Help? 
Your browser does not support javascript, otherwise a personal login and logout would be displayed.
 
 Home &gt; Hot Topics &gt; Foreign Worker Timeout &gt; Foreign workers take jobs away from skilled Americans 
 
 Hot Topics 

 5 Great Solutions Chain Migration Mandatory E-Verify State and Local Policies The Visa Lottery Birthright Citizenship Foreign Worker Timeout 
 July 9, 2012 EDT - posted on NumbersUSA 
Report Says U.S. has Too Many Scientists but Not Enough Jobs 

 June 6, 2012 EDT - posted on NumbersUSA 
House Introduces Companion Bill of Senate&apos;s Startup Act 2.0 

 May 18, 2012 EDT - posted on NumbersUSA 
New Virginia Law to Publish Unemployment Rates of Recent College Grads 

 May 7, 2012 EDT - posted on NumbersUSA 
State Department to Strengthen Oversight Over Work-Visa Program 

 May 4, 2012 EDT - posted on NumbersUSA 
American Teens Finding it Harder to Get a Job 
 The CLEAR Act Secure the Border The SAVE Act More Topics Recent News Recent Blogs 
 
Foreign workers take jobs away from skilled Americans

 
 
 By Gene69 of TX, Updated Thursday, August 21, 2008, 9:31 PM EDT - posted on NumbersUSA 
 
Wealthy advocates of H-1B visas have industriously worked to keep this employer-designed program hidden from middle-class Americans, who are outraged when they learn how it harms them.

In 2002, Nobel economics laureate Milton Friedman correctly identified the 1990 H-1B visa program as a &quot;government subsidy&quot; because it allows employers access to imported, highly skilled labor at below-market wages.

False allegations of worker shortages have been a popular approach. But American colleges and universities graduate four to six times the number of students needed to fill openings in technology fields that are generated by retirements and business expansion.

Consequently, since 1960, there have been more than 30 million graduates with bachelor&apos;s degrees who are qualified to work as scientists, engineers, computer programmers and mathematicians (the STEM fields) pursuing approximately 8 million &quot;high tech&quot; positions requiring this level of training. The importation of foreign technical professionals further swells the job-seeker ranks.

Between 1975 and 2005, more than 25 million admissions were approved in just five highly skilled visa programs.

Former Microsoft lobbyist Jack Abramoff helped direct $100 million in political expenditures between 1995 and 2000, enabling Microsoft and other employers to procure employer-friendly changes to H-1B visa legislation in 1996, 1998 and 2000. As a result of this work force glut, real wages in STEM fields have remained flat since at least 2000.

Contrary to Stuart Anderson’s claim, this program prevents innovation since American citizens are typically discarded by employers by age 35 — before their inventions can be turned into practical revenue generators.

It facilitates hiring discrimination against Americans. In the April 15, 2007, edition of the New York Times, Indian Commerce Minister Kamal Nath called H-1B the &quot;outsourcing visa.&quot;

This program also undermines national security, as 200,000 U.S. science and engineering jobs have already been lost to communist China.

In the late 1980s, bureaucrats at the National Science Foundation found that they could increase the supply of technical professionals by importing them — offering foreign nationals the prospect of remaining in the United States.

This increase in supply depresses wages — an important policy objective.

One measure showing that this government intervention was successful (at least from the employers&apos; perspective) is that a typical postdoctoral research or teaching position in a STEM field (requiring 12 years of education after high school) offers pay and benefits comparable to what a high school graduate earns managing a fast-food restaurant.

University of California at Davis computer science professor Norm Matloff recommends sharply diminishing the size of the H-1B program to about 15,000 admissions annually so that it is only used to import &quot;the best and brightest&quot; — rather than the &quot;fresh [inexpensive] young blood&quot; of average talent currently imported from the developing world.

In a 1993 article in the American Scholar, CalTech Vice Provost David Goodstein pointed out that the American taxpayer is forced to support extremely expensive research universities whose main purpose is to train students from abroad who will stay here and take jobs that could have gone to Americans, or go home and take our knowledge and technology with them.

We are ignoring our own students and using our money to train our economic competitors.



 Gene Nelson is an information technology professional at NumbersUSA
 





This article appeared in the August 21, 2008 edition of The Examiner and is the property of the Washington Newspaper publishing company, Copyright 2008.




 
NumbersUSA&apos;s blogs are copyrighted and may be republished or reposted only if they are copied in their entirety, including this paragraph, and provide proper credit to NumbersUSA . NumbersUSA bears no responsibility for where our blogs may be republished or reposted.
 Views and opinions expressed in blogs on this website are those of the author. They do not necessarily reflect official policies of NumbersUSA. Subscribe to our Blog Feed Related Searches: 
 High-Tech Worker Visas 
 
 nelsong&apos;s blog Email this page Printer-friendly version Digg Newsvine Facebook MySpace Twitter 
 
 
Comments

Although comments are moderated, they do not necessarily reflect the views of NumbersUSA or its staff.
 
 Hello , you have characters remaining. Comment
Guidelines Privacy
Guidelines Loading Comments… Show Previous Comments 
Related

Video Clips

 Roy on CNN to Discuss Irish Work Visa bill 

News

 House Introduces Companion Bill of Senate&apos;s Startup Act 2.0 

 Senator Grassley Looks Into Boeing&apos;s use of Visas for Russian Engineers 

Blog Entries

 Webcast Shines Light on Wave of Bills That Will Hurt American Workers, Wages and College Graduates 

 Now We Know -- White House Clarifies War On Jobless Higher-Skilled Americans 

Legislative Analysis

 Reform of the H-1B Work Visa: Major Points 

In the News

 H-1B demand spike may signal improving outlook for skilled pros 

 Thousands Of H-1B Visas Still Up For Grabs 

 Opposing view: Invest in American workers 
 
©2012 NumbersUSA, 1601 N Kent St, Suite 1100, Arlington, VA 22209, All Rights Reserved
 About Us  •  Contact Us  •  Sitemap  •  Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
