<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004260" url="http://lovecrossesborders.org/" time="2012-07-12-20:30" support="2" score="0.0016537611222546306" bingtitle="Love Crosses Borders" webtitle="Love Crosses Borders">
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>... was much of a gardener and I used to throw a fit as ... had to confuse I was inspired by an American fast food restaurant. ... put all the dishes away, bagged all the trash from ...</description>
	<body>
		Love Crosses Borders 

The Tale of the Corporate City Girl Following her Cowboy
 
 Home Our Story Characters in My Life Contact 
 Jun 22 
 Desert Life, Family Visit&amp; Puppies! 
 Posted on June 22, 2012 by lovecrossesborders Desert Life, Family Visit&amp; Puppies! 
As usual I have postponed an update for a while and have a lot to catch up on. Trying to keep things brief, I returned back to Chihuahua around the 1 st of June after visiting Colorado for two weeks. My first trip home since moving to Mexico was amazing. I was able to see a lot of friends and family. There were a few faces I didn’t get to see but all in all, I left Colorado feeling loved and fulfilled with the time I got to spend with everyone! As funny as it sounds I was missing Cowboy, our life and the ranch so I actually came home a few days earlier. Plus, my dog at the ranch had seven little pups and I wanted to get back to them. Not to mention Cowboy had been missing my cooking, and made me well aware I am not “allowed” to leave him again for a long period of time, he gets too hungry. Needless to say, he has been well feed since I have retuned.
 
Mi Amor—At the Engagement Party
 
 

Whenever anything crazy happen to us Cowboy always says, “Are you going to blog about this,” in a mocking tone. My response is usually, “Maybe,” or “Yes.” Therefore, I have to share this little story. I flew into El Paso and Cowboy drove up to pick me up and we were going to drive back down to Chihuahua, it is a little cheaper than flying direct. Anyway, I did a little shopping at my favorite store in El Paso, Target, and bought a few new pillows for the living room at the ranch. They are super adorable I must add. As we were driving to Chihuahua you have to pass a checkpoint. Unfortunately, my pillows in their plastic bags must have given it away that we had gone shopping. The border agent asked us how much money we had spent and if we had our receipts. We already knew the drill so luckily we had all of our receipts. However, the bad news is they had changed the amount you are able to come across the border with, without having to declare anything. In December it was $300 now all of a sudden it was only $75. We had also done some other shopping at Home Depot and were over the $75 limit. The border guy was a total jerk and was not going to give us a break. We didn’t have any extra cash to pay the declaration fee because we were not anticipating it and there is no ATM in the area so we literally had to turn around and drive to Juarez to find an ATM at a gas station. Then turn back around, declare my pillows and other items and pay $45 in tax. The pettiness of $45 for tax on our purchased goods in the States added an additional hour to our returning trip home to Chihuahua. 

 

There should be a sign hanging on the entrance gate that says, “Welcome to the Desert.” When I left to go home to Colorado the weather was still decent. After I returned the average temperature during the day is now between 95-102 degrees. So it is HOT. Plus we don’t have air conditioning so I am adjusting to all of that. However, Pancho, Cowboys father just constructed a new terrace in the front of the house that looks great and provides some extra shade during the day. The roof structure is made out of okotio cactus and looks so darn cute.

 
 
Precious Pup
 
Once we made it to the ranch, as I previously stated, seven precious puppies greeted me. India, the mama pup, wouldn’t let most people go near her and she would bark if you were walking by the tree where she had her pups. However, she let me go strait to them and even pet them and look at them. Throughout the whole process whenever I see her feeding them I always make sure the runt is eating and has a good spot. If he doesn’t I go and move the little guy so that he gets big and fat. The pups are already four weeks old and have begun barking, pooping, walking, crying, and all the other annoying things young babies do. They also opened their eyes last week and are looking more like their mom and dad everyday. I am of course, head over heels, in love with the seven silly creatures and give them so many kisses. I play with them everyday and I am quite convinced the workers think I am crazy. Cowboy often reminds me, “We don’t think you are crazy, we know you are.” His comment is actually meant in a sweet manner. Since the women culturally speaking don’t frequent the ranch the workers are still shocked I live here much less enjoy it and work hard outside. We are planning to keep two males, so I have been scooping out which two I want to keep. A few of the workers families in the city want one so I think we should be able to find nice homes for all of them, when the time comes in a few weeks. Cowboy and his parents keep joking that I am going to be a crazy puppy lady and not want to get rid of any of them and want to keep them all. But I know we can’t feed all of them and I have already come to terms knowing we will have to give them away in a few weeks! (I think I’ve come to terms with it all anyway). 

 

In other animal news, the baby chicks are huge and look like normal adult chickens now. We still don’t know if they are chicks or roosters but with a little more time we should be able to tell. Unfortunately, two of the baby chicks escaped and didn’t make it while I was gone but we still have four that did make it and seem to be getting along with all the other ladies nicely. I am thrilled to announce calving season has begun. From now until August we should see around 80 new calves. Cowboy told me just yesterday he saw the first two babies of the season. I nearly threw the book I was reading across the room because I was so excited. I find baby calves to be so precious. I hope to have pictures in the near future of course. I’m not so happy to report we have a pretty large pack of coyotes right now so we are hoping they don’t eat a lot of the calves this year. We try to go out looking for them with a rifle but of course when you have the gun you never see them and when you don’t have the gun you do seem them. Hopefully we can get the coyote population down and keep all of our cows safe. 

 

Given the news that calving season has begun and the sad state of the ranch. For those that don’t know the Chihuahua area has been in a sever drought for two years now receiving little to no rain. We keep praying and hoping for rain to help the grass and vegetation on the ranch. In fact, I was teasing Cowboy that he might have to go to church with me again. I made him go with me in April, I think, and the Father prayed for rain and the following week it rained lightly three days in a row. It was not enough rain to help drastically but any moisture will help. So for all of my friends and family that read this, I kindly ask you to pray for rain too!! Cowboy also jokes that he is bad luck for the ranch. He took over as manager two years ago and since he arrived it has not rained; he thinks he brought the drought. I keep reminding him he does not have that kind of power and his arrival and presence on the ranch has no correlation with Gods decision to bring a drought to the area. The rainy season is supposed to start in July and if we don’t start getting rain things are going to get grim.

 
 
Bird Friend
 
In animal news continued…. I had wanted a birdbath for a while and we recently bought one. Since purchasing it, I have been seeing so many new birds around. Plus we just filled the feeders. The other day I saw some sort of desert cardinal. It was red and gray and had a bright orange beak. At first I thought it was some kind of parrot, but quickly realized it had to be something else since parrots are tropical birds. According to a bird book we have it is a Pyrrhuloxia, a really stunning creature. The Peccary pigs have started coming by the house area everyday for a visit for the past week now. I think they are coming close to the house to get food and there is also a water hole near by. The mesquite trees have started flowering and throw a sweet bean pod. The pods are all over the ground near the house so I think the pigs are coming to have a little sweet treat. The dogs are not happy about this, even Max the lazy family lab lets out a loud bark when he sees them. So far the pigs have not caused harm to the dogs, us, the garden, or other animals near the house so we basically leave the pigs alone and they mind their own business. I should also mention the horses go crazy for the mesquite pods, especially Camilla, Cowboys gorgeous mare. I usually pick up a handful of them and bring some to her almost everyday. Plus she loves the attention and someone to scratch behind her ears.

 

Now that summer is here we have lowered the cows from La Sierra, our largest pasture up in the mountains, and will begin to implement our holistic management style. The guys will start rotating the cattle once a week to a different pasture. The idea behind the management style and holistic approach is bettering your land, resources and animals with what you have. Therefore, we put a high density of cattle on a smaller parcel of land for only a brief period of time, one-week tops. This helps to not over graze the pasture, it let’s the pastures rest and recover and also helps with vegetation and grass growth.  I won’t bore you all with the logistics but it is a very fascinating processes, one that I enjoy seeing the results of. Given this, my poor Cowboy will be in the saddle a lot. I feel for him because it is scorching hot and he has a bad back that he refuses to go get looked at. So once again I keep hoping to see thunderheads rolling over the mountains in the direction of the ranch to also help keep the heat down!
 
Taking Inventory of His Herd
 
 

For a few words on the fabulous garden, we have been able to harvest a lot of veggies and I am LOVING all the opportunities to cook with homegrown stuff. We are eating spinach, basil, radishes, bell peppers, tons of jalapenos and other kinds of hot peppers, beets, and we just started to harvest some tomatoes and yellow squash. I had planted some carrots but our soil was to heavy and clay like so they didn’t grow much. Since then, we have improved our soil by adding some sand and mulch so I’m hoping my second batch of carrots grow better. I kid you not I think the vegetables taste so much better, different, and more crisp than store bought goods. While I was home in Colorado I bought a lot more seeds so I was eager to come home and get more things planted. Including several other kinds of squash, like spaghetti and acorn squash. Other new seeds include: kale, red cabbage, several new herbs, chamomile flowers so I can hopefully make some homemade tea, new types of tomatoes and even some eggplant. I also bought different types of cucumbers in hopes to pickle them in the fall.

 
 
Watermelon
 
Speaking of pickling…. I have a newfound interest as I previously blogged about. I am going to start canning our harvest. We have tons of hot peppers that are ready to harvest so next week I am going to give canning my first attempt! (Wish me luck). I have also looked up some jalapeno jelly recipes. I love jalapeno jelly with cheese and crackers plus they make a nice gift. So I have my grocery list made up for items I will need to can peppers and also make jam. Looking ahead to the fall I hope to can/pickle zucchini, green beans, carrots, onions, and also make other types of jam. We just planted strawberries, raspberries and purchased some grape plants. So hopefully in the future I can preserve some sweet stuff too! Another gardening project that is up in coming is roasting sunflower seeds. I have ten large heads that have smarted to go to seed so I am in the R&amp;D, (research and development), stages of this idea.

 

I continue catering to the garden every morning, before the heat of the day approaches, and I am really getting into it. I have been doing a lot of research on companion planting and which plants, herbs, and flowers complement or help each other grow. On the flip side, I have been learning which plants to avoid putting next to each other. I even made a spreadsheet for easy reference! This style of gardening is said to help with bugs and other pests. I just replanted two new areas in the garden using companion planting tips so we will see how it goes. I am eager to plant more plots in the garden this way.

 

We finally made a compost pile and we are trying to breed worms in it. Sounds crazy I know! Cowboy’s brother has a wonderful operation at the orchard and he has a bunch of worms he uses to improve his soil for his berries. Cowboy liked his idea so much he took some of the worms and is going to try and implement the same thing. Basically we have to get them to multiple and grow a lot of worms, once we have some we will then put them in our garden beds to help improve the soil structure. I am happy about this because I have been wanting a compost pile for a while so I can throw away even less stuff. Between the chickens and the dogs we never have any table scrapes however, neither of them enjoy the rind of fruits and vegetables. Plus you can put used tea bag and eggshells in the compost pile among other things. Not to mention scraps, leaves and trimmings from the garden can also go in there.

 
 
Some of the Gals at the Engagement Party
 
To wrap this LONG post up, for some exciting news, my mother was just here for her first Chihuahua visit! It meant the world to me for her to come and see my life, where I now live, and most importantly meet Cowboys family. I think she really enjoyed it and can now go and report to the “others,” meaning all my other family that are still weary of me living in Mexico I am fine and live in a beautiful place surrounded by wonderful faces. My mother timed her trip, or should I say I timed it for her, so that she could come with me to some family functions. It was an honor and privilege to celebrate the future marriage of Cowboys brother and soon to be sister in law. While my mom was here there was a beautiful bridal shower for Marisa and also an engagement party for the couple to be. For the icing on top of the cake Marisa’s mother and aunt were also able to attend from Sydney and it was such a joy to finally meet them. The saying, “the apple doesn’t fall far from the tree,” is so perfect to describe Marisa and the gals in her family. They are all so sweet, kind, outgoing and identical in many mannerisms. I think it was nice for my mother to have someone to share the experience of having her daughter move to Mexico with. We were all able to giggle and reminisce about us girls following our hearts to Mexico to be with our loves.
 
Mothers and Daughters
 
 

Cowboys aunts from Mexico City, whom I have not met, were also able to come. I was thrilled to finally meet them and get a chance to know more of his mother’s side of the family. Both events were a perfect opportunity to meet Cowboys father and mothers family including many aunts, uncles and cousins. Not to mention my mother was able to meet a lot of the family friends as well. I am happy to report everyone seemed to love her and befriended her right away! Several people joked that when you have handsome boys you get gorgeous girls, so I guess that means Marisa and I have both found ourselves charming men and in return they didn’t do too bad and now have us in their life. It was truly a special time spent with very special people.
 
Marisa and I
 
 

My mother was also able to come to the ranch and see my ranch life! She really enjoyed it and I think she could have stayed another few days. I told her next time she comes we can stay at the ranch the whole time. She was loving the cows, puppies, peccary pig sightings and even helped me in the garden a lot. She loves to garden and is very jealous and envious of my edible paradise. I cooked for her while she was with us. I tried to keep it traditional and made tortas one night and a batch of homemade beans, a steak and tortillas the next night. For breakfast we had eggs, chorizo, tortillas and papaya. She was also able to watch the guys shear the sheep! I kept reminding her it is never a dull moment on the ranch.
 
Mom in Chihuahua
 
 

As for a tip on relationships—Compassion is a great tool. Cowboy has been upset with the dry condition of the ranch and the lack of rain. Therefore, the inadequate amount of grass to keep all the cows feed. I don’t know the answers to tell him nor do I know if everything will be ok. Plus all of those things are totally out of our control. However, I am able to listen to his frustrations and remind him he is doing an amazing job managing the ranch, cattle, land and scarce recourses we do have. After all, I am the one who sees his blood, sweat and tears, literally, at the end of the day. Acknowledging the positive things and hard work of your partner is key, I think!

 

To all my friends, family and loved ones….I hope this update finds you all in great spirits, happiness and contentment. Sending love always xoxo
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment May 21 
 Ranch Life, Orchard Visit&amp;Home Sweet Home 
 Posted on May 21, 2012 by lovecrossesborders Ranch Life, Orchard Visit&amp;Home Sweet Home 
Missing Him Already
 
This update comes to you from Denver, Colorado! I was able to come home for a little visit, which is my first trip since moving four months ago. First of all, I have no idea where the last four months have gone. It feels like I was just packing my apartment and driving south to Mexico last week. Leaving Cowboy, the ranch and Chihuahua was bitter sweet. I have really come to think of the ranch as “home” and I always hate saying goodbye to Cowboy. Especially since the first portion of our relationship was long distance, and goodbyes were sad because we never knew when we would get to see each other again. Luckily, I know I get to go back home to him in a few weeks and I am ecstatic about being home!! The excitement I had when I was picked up by my mother and sister at the airport was indescribable. It feels really good to be home and able to catch up with family and friends. I came home to surprise a special young lady whom I used to nanny for years ago. She graduated from high school this past weekend and I came to surprise her at her graduation party. The surprise has come and gone and my arrival can be made public now. I think she was quite shocked and her and her family were appreciative of the gesture. I was also able to attend another good family friend’s high school graduation party which was special.

Now let’s back up and fill you in on ranch life from the last few weeks. As always, there has not been a dull moment. Two weeks ago it rain three days in a row. We did not receive a torrential down pour by any means but the moisture should hold us over and help the grass continue to grow until the rainy season starts in another month or two. We received sever new Beefmaster bulls that are gorgeous animals. I guess I should call them handsome animals and not gorgeous since they are males. Either way, we are excited to have them and put them to work in the fall. Also, our garden is amazing. We have been able to eat a fresh salad using lettuce, spinach, basil, and arugula from our own garden! We have some baby tomatoes starting and sever peppers growing! 
 
La India
 
A quick animal update….La India, my dog, should be giving birth in the next few weeks, which I might miss and am devastated about. Our Foreman was telling Cowboy the other day, that when we are not at the ranch on weekends she sits at the gate staring at it crying, apparently waiting for us to return. Hearing this broke my heart because I am going to be gone for a few weeks. Cowboy kept telling me, “I guess you can’t go because you can’t leave you “daughter” alone especially when she gives birth.” I gave him strict instructions to be extra kind to her while I am gone. The chicks are getting so big and all six are still alive and doing great. They are totally self-sufficient and know how to do everything.  I have seen numerous snakes now. I think the rain made them come out of hibernation, with a little moisture there seems to be more food and lizards for them. Luckily I’ve only seen two rattlesnakes, one of which was dead, a worker killed it. I recently learned rattlesnakes are a big cash business in the city. When the workers see one they either kill it or try to capture it because they are worth twice as much alive….GROSS!  I have also seen two gardener snakes and one bull snake.
 
The Handsome Rooster
 
Now for some sad news, our beautiful rooster died a week ago. It is quite ironic how it happened and the guys are convinced I brought bad energy to the situation, which killed the rooster. We had two roosters and I had been noticing the handsome one was not looking good and he was missing a lot of feathers. The other rooster is a fighting rooster and is very territorial and mean to the other rooster and some of the hens. So I made the decision the fighting rooster had to go, his time on the ranch was up. I asked one of our workers to kill it on a Friday afternoon. As it turns out it is one of the other workers roosters so we couldn’t kill it. Nolo, our worker, acknowledge the situation and lack of space for him and said he would take the rooster to his son next week. When we returned to the ranch on Monday we learned the handsome good rooster had died over the weekend. I was sad but the rooster was pretty old anyway. So everyone was joking that I brought bad karma to the roosters by mentioning the fighting rooster had to leave. However, we do think the fighting rooster is the one that killed him. So we will be looking for a new good looking rooster and still getting rid of the fighting rooster.

I recently gave Manuel, our worker that likes to learn English, my Spanish/English dictionary. He is always asking how to say words so I figured I can always buy another one. He was so excited about receiving the small gift. The first English word he flipped to was the word, zilch. He was asking me how to say the word and what it meant. I told him not to worry about that word, we don’t use it often. He then left, went and got his glasses and sat outside the rest of the evening reading and learning new words. At one point the rest of the workers arrived and asked him, “what are you doing.” He responded with, “I’m learning English.” They all started giggling at him.
 
A Beautiful Mural in the City
 
Cowboy is always inventing, building and constructing new things. We are somewhat forced to do this because we can’t run down the street to a store when we need something. We recently made a large net to clean the algae from the water tank by the house. This project turned out great and we have been able to keep the “pond” a lot cleaner. Speaking of projects, we are still curing the hide of the cow that died a few weeks ago. The hide smells terrible so we don’t know if we spoiled it or if it is just a part of the process. We have a couple more steps to follow and if the smell does not improve I am making the executive decision to through it away! Now for a little about my project, I completed my “refurnishing” task. I recently sanded, striped, and repainted a hutch we keep dishes in. The furniture looks amazing and brand new. However, it was quite the undertaking.
 
Checking out the Berry Field
 
Marisa and I
 
I was finally able to visit the orchard, which is where Cowboy’s brother Fran and his fiancée Marisa live. Marisa and I arranged a little family trip with the four of us to the orchard for a weekend, which was a blast. The orchard is more in the Sierra Madre Mountains, totally different landscape than the ranch. I actually felt like I was home in Colorado with pine trees. The scenery was beautiful. It was so nice to finally get to see all of their projects and business investments. They also have cattle and pigs. The pigs were so adorable and new to me. Fran and Marisa are growing some berries and oats so it was fun to see that. Fran is also renting a spectacular new ranch for some of his Angus and we were able to go and see it. The orchard is located near a town so we were able to enjoy a few nice meals and walk around. I fell in love with the adorable town settled right at the base of the mountains. It had so much character and Spanish charm.
 
Spanish Charm
 
That basically brings you up to speed on some of the past events. Now I am Stateside again and really happy to be here. I know the time is going to fly by so I am going to try and make the most of it. I have already gotten to spend time with one of my best friends and her baby boy. She had her baby the week before I left, and I have had to watch baby Shane grow up through pictures so it’s so nice to see him and hold him in person. It is also nice to sit on the couch and chat with my mama. After all, she is the best mom in the world and I have missed her dearly. I’m also happy to be home for some quality sister time! I’ll be taking a trip to one of my favorite towns in Colorado, Aspen, to visit with another best friend. I will also be taking a trip to Colorado Springs to visit some grandparents. There are also several dinners arranged with friends and family. I have a feeling I am going to go home exhausted. I have a little shopping to do while I am home so I should keep plenty busy.
 
Baby Shane and I
 
 

As for a tip on relationships, distances makes the heart grow fonder is the best I can come up with. I joked with Cowboy before I left that this trip will be good for our relationship. I told him he will have the opportunity to see how much he really appreciates, loves and enjoys my presence at the ranch. He will not have three good meals cooked for him everyday, a clean house, someone to talk to, someone to water the plants, someone to check on the chickens, some one to gather eggs, someone to gather his dirty laundry, some to drink tea with him at night and someone to do the dishes. He will have to fend for himself for the next two weeks!

Blessed to be home and grateful to be living the life God has planned for me. Felling very happy XOXO

 
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment May 2 
 A Must Share… 
 Posted on May 2, 2012 by lovecrossesborders A Must Share… 
Oh what a day!! I would consider it a “must share.” For all my animal loving friends I would like to apologize now for this little post and also suggested maybe you don’t read this. I will try to omit the gross details. However, if you really want to know what a day on the ranch is like keep reading….

 

We often joke that there is no reason to make “solid” plans on the ranch because like the weather in Colorado, they could change in 5 minutes. That very point was proven this morning. Cowboy and I had just finished breakfast around 7:30 am and he went to look for some insecticide for the garden. As a side note, I had a mild tantrum yesterday as a result of finding several “cabbage loopers,” which are caterpillars hatched from moth larva. They are chewing noticeably large holes in all the leaves of my beautiful cabbage and lettuce heads. They are very destructive and we need to find a solution to kill them pronto. Anyway, Cowboy came back inside and reported there was a casualty. A year old calf in the corrals had died over night. It ate too much alfalfa too fast for supper the night before and it’s stomach blotted and all the gasses basically killed the little guy.

 

Cowboy apparently decided he wanted to get some use out of the thing and told the workers to butcher it. Now I knew they had done this before, but I was not prepared for the process or the amount of time and precision it took. So, the guys picked up the cow and brought it away from the house and hung the carcass by its back legs from the bucket of the tractor in mid air. Essentially mimicking a processing line. I’ve toured through a beef processing plant before so I was not mortified at the scene and actually wanted to see how the heck they were going to pull this off with their little knives. I’m sure they thought I was crazy and wondered why I would want to watch such a sight or be around an unpleasant smell. So I told them about the company I worked for in the States, which was a large manufacturer for protein. Cowboy also told them I had toured a plant before, so I think they then understand why it didn’t bother me. I have the mentality that it is just the circle of life. One of the guys even asked if they would hire him in the States at one of the plants to cut the meat. As usually I just giggled and told him possibly.

 

The workers stripped the hide of very diligently, using their knives to cut and separate the hide from the muscle/meat. Once the hide was off, they cut open the stomach, cleaned out all the guts, and bagged up all the good pieces of meat and handed it to me. Such a lovely little surprise! So, I have a sink full of extremely fresh meat. The best part of the day was power washing the hide.

 

Also an unexpected treat was Cowboys decion to keep the hide and use it as a rug. I absolutely adore cowhide rugs in homes, but I didn’t have this idea in mind. I guess it will always be a good conversation started. Maybe the story will go something like this, “My boyfriend saved this calf a few days after it was born because his mother abandoned him. He lived in the corral for most of his life with two other orphan calves. One day he ate too much, blotted, and died. Now we use him as a rug.” It’s a nice color but I was not anticipating keeping the large, heavy fur hide.

 

The tractor is still being used to hang the carcass in mid air while the meat cures. Aren’t you all glad I don’t have pictures of this event! Oh did I mention the head is also hanging from the bucket of the tractor. Needless to say there is never a dull moment around here and we try to utilize all aspects of the ranch. This unplanned project took two hours which was most of the morning. I guess you could say the day got off to an unusual and delayed start. The good news is we will be having BBQ tonight! In fact the workers are going to build a pit and roast it somehow. I am at least excited to see how they cook it. If it’s not good I will just throw a lot of BBQ sauce on it. I am also looking forward to grilling some rib eyes that are sitting in my sink!

 

 

 

 
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment Apr 30 
 The History of Cowboys 
 Posted on April 30, 2012 by lovecrossesborders The History of Cowboys 
 I’ve posted this fun fact before on a different page of my blog. However, I thought I would share again because it is very interesting. A few months ago I was talking to my “Cowboy.” He asked me if I knew the history of cowboys. I said, “No.” I have always thought of cowboys as men that wear tight Wranglers, ride horses, compete in rodeos, and wear sexy chaps, spurs and a hat. He proceeded to tell me the basics and I was very fascinated. By the end of our conversation I said, “So it’s in your blood to be a good Vaquero (cowboy).”

Here is what I have learned….

Contradictory to most American beliefs, the cowboy is actually a Spanish tradition and icon. Vaquero’s came from Spain and settled what is now Mexico and Texas in the 16 th century. A vaquero is one who herds cattle typically on horse back. Vaquero’s came to the Americas with very old and rich techniques thought to have been influenced by the Moors and Arabs.  The mid 1800’s marked a significant period in history. As English settlers expanded west; culture, traditions, and language began merging. Overtime the Spanish Vaquero’s essentially trained the American settlers how to properly heard, manage, roundup, and care for cattle. Today many of the same traditions and practices are used.  Therefore, it is totally my opinion that some of the best ranchers and cowboys come from or live in Mexico!
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment Apr 29 
 Baby Chicks, Branding, and Rattlesnakes… 
 Posted on April 29, 2012 by lovecrossesborders Baby Chicks, Branding, and Rattlesnakes… 
Common Sight After a Hard Day of Work
 
Where oh where to begin? A lot has happened in the last three weeks, which is all the more reason I need to write more frequently. I will try to summarize without writing a novel. When we arrived back to the ranch, after our weeklong road trip, we were amazed to learn it had rained! There were actually puddles and parts of the dirt roads that were not passable on the ranch. In fact, one day I had to go pick Cowboy up across the ranch at the corrals. He called me on the radio before I left to get him in the Jeep and said, “I forgot to mention, you have to come a different way to get me. The other road is underwater. Just follow the tire tracks and you will get here.” I was a little skeptical but the funny thing is, his advice actually lead me straight to him. Plus, I got to explore a whole new road on the ranch. On a positive note, the ranch is the greenest I have ever seen it. It looks like a completely different place. When I came for my first visit in October 2011 the ranch was experiencing a fierce drought. Than when I moved here in January it was winter and there was no foliage on the trees. Spring is still in the air and the cactus, grass, trees, flowers, bushes, and mesquites are all looking ravishing. It’s amazing how fast the dry grass recovers with just a little rain. We keep hoping and praying for more storms.
 
Harvesting From the Garden!
 
A few words on the garden…We have been able to start harvesting lettuce, radishes, cilantro, and basil. Let me just tell you, there is nothing better than a homegrown salad! I transplanted around 90 new plants to the outdoor beds. Most of which were chili plants, lettuce and tomatoes. I also planted some watermelon, cantaloupe, squash, cucumbers, zucchini and green beans. I’m still trying to understand the dirt and a good watering schedule, especially living in a desert. I seem to give them too much water or not enough. Plus we have to fertilize more often since our soil is very sandy and not rich in organic matter. We have also constructed some nice shade structures so our poor little plants don’t fry and they seem to be working perfectly.
 
Beautiful Sight in La Sierra with Blossoming Okotio Cactus
 
I am happy to report my Spanish is improving mucho and I have been talking with one of the workers wives a lot. She is only there on the weekends but we have been able to converse quite a bit. Her name is Maria and she is very sweet and loves to chat. I wish I could understand everything she says and respond a little better, but if I keep working at it and speaking with her I will be carrying on conversations in no time. In fact, I attended Maria’s cooking class this past weekend. She makes the best flour tortillas and puts mine to shame. Hers are large, round and fluffy. Mine are oblong shaped, not as fluffy which makes burrito making a bit of a challenge. I am apparently using too much lard and baking powder. I also need to knead the dough with my hands longer and concentrate more on the consistency of the mixture, which means adding hot water a little at a time not all at once. All in all, my cooking class was fabulous. Watching Maria roll out the tortillas was amazing. As I told her, “es un arte,” which means it is an art. She rolls little bits at a time and rotates the tortilla 90 degrees after rolling the dough from the center out. She does not roll the whole entire tortilla every time. It is a little hard to explain but a technique that seems to work and has worked for many years. I also told her, “Yo necesito practicar,” which translates to “I need to practice.” She laughed and said she has had a lot of practice.
 
We have Palm Trees!
 
Cowboy has been very impressed with my Spanish skills. He couldn’t believe I carried on a conversation with Maria and actually comprehended most of it. Sometimes she gets to speaking so fast and I have no idea what she is saying so I just nod and respond with, “Si,” which means yes. I have an English/Spanish dictionary and it has become my best friend. I have also been making time to read Spanish, which will hopefully help me put sentences together better. Cowboy says I need to speak to him in Spanish now, it is apparently the only way I will get better.

Now lets get down to life on the ranch, my favorite topic. We have spent most of the last three weeks at the ranch, except for two days. We usually head to the city for clean clothes and groceries. As always we have been very busy. As I previously discussed gardening still has me on my toes. We had around 60 old cows we have been selling in groups of 20 to a local butcher and the last of the old ladies left the ranch. Rounding up and loading the trucks is always a sight to see. Luckily, the ranch hands and Cowboy have it down to a science and it only takes them a few minutes.
 
Branding
 
We branded the male steers a few weeks ago, which was exciting to observe but probably not too nice for the cows. There were 78 of them so it took most of the day in the hot weather. Oh, have I mentioned the summer weather is here to stay for the next few months. It has been in the 90’s for the last week or so. We are building a new water deposit on the far end of the ranch in hopes to separate a large pasture and make it into three smaller pastures. This is a large undertaking and will take several weeks to finish in order for the cows to start drinking from it. Building fences and separating the pasture, called Barbona, will also take a significant amount of time and might not get done for a while.
 
Mama and her Chicks
 
A few words about the animals….for starters, I saw my first rattlesnake, or cascabel in Spanish. It was a smaller snake, possibly a baby, sleeping under a log. One of the workers found it while he was cleaning the yard. I obviously had to snap a few shot of the little snake. I have been warned the snakes start to come out after the first rain and with the heat. Needless to say I have been paying much more attention as I walk around the ranch. La India my precious dog daughter is pregnant. The family yellow Labrador came for a visit and is now going to be a father. Her belly is getting bigger by the day and I love to pet it. Six baby chicks hatched, which has been so fun to observe. They are the cutest little things ever. We are possibly expecting more. One of the mama hens is still sitting on a nest. Luckily we don’t have to assist in raising the baby pollitos except give them fresh food, water and a clean cage. The mama hen does all the mothering and teaches them good manners hopefully. It is amazing to watch them, within the first day of hatching they already knew how to eat, peek food, and drink water. They seem to be smart little fur balls.

 

We have a nice old hutch in the kitchen that I have been wanted to refurnish. It is probably 75+ years old and has been painted several times and the paint is chipping and looks a little beat up. So, I decided to buy some sandpaper, a nice tan color of paint and get to work. My ambitious idea has turned out to be A LOT more work than I thought. I finished the bottom half in two days, with the assistance of Cowboy, and I need to purchase some paint stripper to finish the other half, which is much larger. However, I will say it looks amazing so far and the color is perfect. As Cowboy pointed out, it is a similar color to dust so mabe the dust will blend in better.
 
My Pregnant Puppy
 
A final story to report on the ranch front is a comical one. Since we don’t have electricity and everything runs off our generator we are very dependent upon it. The other night the fan belt broke. So we were without power for a day. I had to make dinner with a headlamp. After dinner we sat around a bunch of candles and an oil lamp and talked for a while. Cowboy reminded me, “This is how it was before you came.” The ranch has only been operating with power for 9 months! Crazy to think it used to be so dark at night. I have to admit I don’t know how long I would last if we didn’t have power. All systems are back up and running and we even purchased an extra fan belt in case it happens in the future.

Cowboy, his father, and myself went for a little visit to a friends ranch north of Chihuahua. We are looking to purchase some Beefmaster bulls. Our hopes for the ranch is to improve the genetics of our heard and over time have only one bread. Beefmasters are very hardy cattle and do well in our climate. This will take several years and it starts with having all of the same bulls. Since Cowboys father inherited the ranch only 8 years ago from his father there is still a lot of work to do, which is another reason we recently sold some of the old cows. It was a lot of fun visiting another ranch in the area so that I had something to compare ours to. Plus his bulls were in great shape and will be a great addition at our ranch. Once we receive them we will get rid of our remaining black bulls that are not Beefmasters. After this step all of our bulls will be the same bread.
 
A Handsome Bull on Our Ranch
 
In other great news Marisa has returned home from Australia. For those that don’t know Marisa is Cowboy’s soon to be sister in law and has become a wonderful companion of mine. She was home visiting family, friends, and finalizing some wedding plans. I think we spent three hours catching up! I’m ecstatic to report my mother is coming for her first visit in June! I warned her that it is going to be extremely hot but she is still coming, and I think she is very excited. We are going to have a full house of woman in June. Marisa’s mother and aunt will also be here the same time my mother will be. We are hosting a bridal shower for Marisa and a good family friend is having a dinner for the engaged couple. My mother will be able to attend both events with me, which I am very excited about. I joked with Marisa that the poor men in the family are going to want to run away after all the mom’s have left.
 
A Picture for My Mama, She Loves Birds! Sparrows Making the Ranch Home for Spring
 
Looking Nice in the City
 
Finally, a quick note on relationships since my post would not be complete without one. Never settle for second best. My mother used to always tell me there are a lot of fish in the sea. I am so blessed to say I found a great “catch.” The other day, Cowboy was telling me how we are a perfect fit because I push him to do things he would not normally do. It was refreshing to hear him say that and it was also news to me. In return he pushes me to do things that are outside of my comfort zone. The other day he was trying to teach me how to ride a motorcycle. I was actually really nervous and have never drove a motorcycle in my life. Unfortunately I will need a little more practice because I drove the thing strait into a mesquite tree. I thought he would be mad at me and instead he just laughed and made sure I was ok. I have learned finding companionship and friendship in a relationship is a very key component. Often times at night Cowboy will look at me and say, “Where have you been all day, it seems like I never see you.” I just laugh at him and say, “I was next to you, here at the ranch all day. Where have you been?”

As always I hope this update finds all my friends and loved one in great health and happiness. Did I mention I will be home soon for a visit!! XOXO
 
God is Good
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment Apr 10 
 Road Trippin’ 
 Posted on April 10, 2012 by lovecrossesborders Road Trippin’ 
I hope this update finds everyone in good spirits. Since the last update I have spent one week at the ranch and one week on a road trip in the United States site seeing and visiting some family. Ranch life is still wonderful and keeps me very busy. Getting away from the ranch for a week was a nice break. Plus I was able to go and visit my grandparents in New Mexico. They are not in the best health so it was nice to see them before it is potentially too late. Poor Cowboy got sucked into the family thing for three days of our trip but all in all he enjoyed his time chatting with my grandpa who has endless stories.
 
A Lucky Horseshoe...a Common Sight at the Ranch
 
A little about the ranch….I finally attempted to use the oven and made some chocolate chip cookies and banana bread or, pan de plátano. I cannot take credit for the cookies being homemade. However, the banana bread was and as usual I didn’t follow a recipe and added some cranberries, which was a nice touch. Cooking in the oven is interesting because it seems to be about 25 degrees hotter than the temperature you select. So you definitely want to check on your treats more frequently so they don’t get burned.

Aside from baking, which I enjoy as long as it is somewhat healthy, I have been tending to the chickens. We currently have three hens that are brooding or setting on eggs. The three ladies have decided they want to be mothers I guess and are sitting on 10+ eggs each. In the springtime this is very common for their motherly instincts to kick in and brood. Our egg production has rapidly decreased and we are only able to collect two or three eggs a day right now. If you try to take the eggs from the hens they get very angry and peck at you plus they ruffle their feathers and it looks like they have a Mohawk. So we have decided to leave them alone and let nature run its course. The whole chicken thing is very comical and a learning experience. The other hens see that the three hens are sitting in the boxes and that it is a safe place to lay their eggs. So, all the other hens seem to take turns going into the boxes where the three setting hens are and lay their eggs there so that the setting hens will protect them. At one point we had three chickens in one box at a time: the setting hen, and two other hens laying eggs. It takes 21 days for an egg to hatch so we might be chick parents in two weeks.
 
Outdoor Garden Beds
 
The garden is coming along wonderfully. As my mother recently pointed out, no one thought I was much of a gardener and I used to throw a fit as a kid when she would make me help her plant flowers in the summertime, and now I am a regular farmer Joe! I have always enjoyed and supported the idea of living off your land. Plus I think the holistic healthy approach to life gives me motivation and enjoyment in the garden. We have transplanted all of our carrots, beets, and radishes. We should be able to start harvesting several vegetables soon. I recently planted more vegetables so that we can have food year round.

Pancho, Cowboys father, recently told me a very funny story. Our foreman, Chalo told Pancho he is going to the United States. Pancho responded with, “Ok just let me know when your going and I’ll prepare your paperwork. Why do you want to go there anyway?” Chalo said, “I’m going to get me an American woman.” I have apparently set the bar very high and the guys at the ranch see how hard I work. There are VERY few Mexican women that will even set foot on a ranch much less work and live on one. This is definitely a cultural difference. Mexican woman enjoy the city. For those that know me, you know I do not sit still for long. I guess all the workers see me working around the house, in the garden, tending to the chickens, watering all the plants and trees, talking with the horses, cooking three meals a day, trying to keep the house somewhat clean, driving alone on the ranch to the corrals, going to the corrals with the guys and helping with anything I can, constructing projects with Cowboy, which often includes hammering or using the drill and many other things.
 
My Grandparents
 
Cowboy and I left last week, April 3 rd , for a little road tip north to New Mexico. His father gave us a week off and we decided to go and visit my Grandparents that live in Truth or Consequences New Mexico. I thought we were going to have to take his father with us for a minute because he was so excited helping us get all the fishing gear ready. We loaded up the car with fishing poles, tackle, a tent, sleeping bags, climbing gear, a gas stove for cooking, and boots for hiking. It took us all day to drive to New Mexico because the line to cross at the border took us two hours. Cowboy warned me that it was going to take a while because all the people from the Chihuahua area drive to the United States for Easter break. I of course didn’t believe him and thought we would breeze through the border with no problem but he was right, yet again.
 
Cowboys Walleye
 
While in Truth or Consequences we were able to do a little fishing in the Rio Grand River and also at two large lakes in the area. Cowboy caught one nice Walleye but I got skunked there. We must not have had the right bait or something because they were not biting worth a darn all three days we were there. The place we stayed, which was darling, had natural mineral soaking baths so we got to relax a little too. T or C is known for its natural mineral hot springs. We had some nice meals with my grandparents and an earful from my grandfather. He is always full of stories. He was sharing with us a little about the Wagner family history. I don’t know a lot of it so it was a very fascinating conversation. As it turns out my family was quite prominent back in the day. On my grandfathers fathers side we have ties dating back to the Mayflower and apparently a family member was a signor of the Mayflower compact. We learned all sorts of other stuff too.

We left T or C and headed to a little town called Ruidoso, which is in the mountains. The little town in the pine tress made me feel like I was home in Colorado. I really enjoyed it and wished we had spent one more day there. We went fishing at this beautiful lake, ironically called Bonito Lake, and once again got skunked. Actually we did caught one thing,  a crawfish. The trick was to fish with live bait. There were two families next to us using worms catching countless trout and we didn’t get one fish using spinners and other lures. However, we still had a blast and that’s what matters.
 
Bonito Lake
 
On Saturday, April 7 th , we had a cave tour in Carlsbad. So we drove four hours from Ruidoso to Carlsbad. Neither one of us had ever been to Carlsbad Caverns and were happily surprised by the monument. The cave tour was the highlight of our trip and a must see if you have never been. We signed up for a very strenuous four-hour tour with two guides and six other people. At points in the tour we were crawling on our belly through a tunnel that was two feet tall by three feet wide. It was a lot of fun and we were able to see part of the cave that very few people have even seen.
 
Camping in our Hotel....Yummy Cuisine (NOT)
 
We stayed in the Carlsbad area on Saturday night. We were without restaurants, cell service, or good food for two days. We were however, able to buy some chicken noodle soup, raviolis, chips, ramen of course, and fruit and camped out for the next two days. We went fishing one more day at a lake near Carlsbad. I finally caught a fish! It was not exactly the kind of fish you brag about but it put up one heck of a fight. I caught a carp, which is a gross bottom feeder!
 
What a Beautiful Carp!
 
We camped one night in Guadalupe National Park, which is in Texas. I was shocked by the beautiful landscape. I didn’t know Texas had mountains and amazing ones at that. After that we drove to Fort Davis Texas. I really enjoyed the drive and we passed by some amazing ranches. Cowboy the whole time kept saying, “I want that ranch.” Several ranches we passed had large mountains with rock formations. He loves to rock climb so his dream is to own land where he could enjoy his hobbies: rock climbing and ranching.
 
Guadalupe National Park, TX--The View From Our Campsite
 
El Capitan Rock, Guadalupe National Park TX
 
Fort Davis is a cute little town. We stayed at this summer camp place called Prude Ranch. They also have cabins available to the public. When Cowboy was a kid he went to Prude ranch in the summer and won several belt buckles as a result of his excellent horse riding skills. Cowboy was also a camp counselor there one summer. Pancho, his father, has told me several stories about Prude Ranch. One summer Pancho went to pick up Cowboy but he didn’t want to go home so Pancho left him there all summer with only one pair of clothes. I had a wonderful time visiting it and seeing it for myself. Now I know where all the stories took place. It was a very cute camp and reminded me of several camps and ranches in Colorado. 

We finally returned back to Chihuahua exactly one week later. We had a great time but we are both eager and excited to get back to the ranch. We have a lot of projects to tend to and we keep praying for rain. La Nina is supposed to be leaving sometime in May and we are hoping the El Nino weather pattern returns soon.

 A tip on relationships: This was our first road trip together and our first trip without a lot of structure or plans. I am a more organized person and sometimes it is difficult for me to just fly by the seat of my pants. Cowboy has caught on to this and is learning I can turn into a control freak when there are no set plans. However, I continue to ask him for help in the relationship and to push me outside of my comfort zone and to do things that are foreign to me. So with his help and acknowledging my defects I can hopefully become a more calm and relaxed traveler and partner! I must say, all in all, it was actually a wonderful trip and we had a great time.

God Bless xoxo
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment Mar 23 
 Spring Is In the Air 
 Posted on March 23, 2012 by lovecrossesborders Spring Is In the Air 
Spring is in the air at the ranch. Trees are beginning to blossom, the mesquites are turning green, and flowers are budding on the cactus. Between writers block, trying to find time and endless projects I have not posted anything for two weeks. Anyway, we had a wonderful family fiesta at the ranch two weeks ago, Saturday March 9th. There were around 35 people, both family and good friends in attendance. Pancho, Cowboys father, prepared brisket in a clay oven the night before the party. Preparing the brisket was quite a sight and so much fun. The party was also a blast and it was nice to see Cowboys family again. His Uncles, Aunts, and Cousins, (Tios, Tias, y Primos), came and I got to meet one of his female cousins I had not met yet. Her name is Susana and she just returned back to Chihuahua from Guadalajara. Both her and her boyfriend were able to make it and they are so wonderful. I look forward to spending more time with them and getting to know them better. She grew up on her families ranch, a different ranch than the one I live on, so she knows all about this life and can probably give my some helpful tips! In fact, the first thing she said to me was, “I can teach you how to cook using that oven.” She as talking about the wood burning oven that is like a million years old but a very beautiful piece of furniture. 

 
 
Putting the Brisket in the Oven...Sealing the Door Shut (Pancho&amp;a Worker)
 
Family gatherings here are much different, well they seem different, than any of my family festivities. The parties usually start in the mid afternoon and sometimes last into the wee hours of the night. Also, the size of my family compared to Cowboys family is very different. My immediate family is very small. However, thanks to my step dads wonderful family, I inherited several more Aunts, Uncles, Cousins and of course a fabulous Grandmother. My grandfather passed away last year. I miss him, his laugh, and charismatic personality dearly. He used to always say he got the biggest smile on his face just thinking about me. I know he is smiling down on all of us.
 
The Family Enjoying the Feast
 
 

Anyway, Cowboy jokes that he doesn’t even know some of his cousin’s names because he has some many. The things I enjoyed most about the party and family in general was the hugs as people arrived, the excitement, conversations, food, dessert, laughter, playing games and the visible love and joy of each other’s company. I am starting to pick up the meaning of conversations and can understand maybe 40%, mas o menos which means more or less, so I am able to participate a little more. Thankfully they all speak English but I don’t except them to speak English to me forever, I need to learn the language where I am living. I am in the listening phase so I enjoyed sitting with the Aunts and Cowboys mother and giggling with them at the content of their conversations.

 

I have officially been living here for two months. I really don’t know where the days, weeks, and now months disappear to. I thought I would have more time to stay in touch with friends and family and that is not happening. Which is good in a sense because I am staying VERY busy and I have not been bored once since arriving here. I was a little worried how I would fit in and if there would ever be days that I would be bored or sitting on the couch twiddling my fingers and so far that has not happened.

 

I have been missing my friends and family. I was able to Skpye with my princess mom, sister and step-dad last weekend, which was a nice treat. I had not talked with them in several weeks, except for a few e-mails. I can feel a little trip home coming on possibly in May. One of my best friends had a beautiful baby boy a week before I left and I am looking forward to seeing how big and handsome he has gotten. I was also able to Skype with my dad on his birthday this week, which was awesome!! While skyping with him I was able to see my step-mother and my little brother and sister that are 9, almost 10, year old twins. They always put a smile on my face and I miss them a lot. I told my brother and sister they should ask mom and dad for a passport so they can come down for “summer camp” on the ranch. My little brother said, “Yeah, I’ve been wanting one of those.” The demeanor in which he said it was hilarious, as if people just hand them out on the street corner.
 
A Sight to See at our&quot;Summer Camp&quot;
 
 
 
The Green House
 
Ranch life has been amazing, as usual. My garden is really taking off and looking great. We just finished filling our two large outdoor beds with dirt and compost. I have begun transplanting the lettuce, cabbage and spinach, (in Spanish lechuga, repollo, espinaca) from the greenhouse. Next week I will transplant the carrots, beets, and radishes (zanahorias, betebelles, y rabanos). I also have several flowers and herbs that are coming along nicely. Who knew I was going to be a good gardener? I have two theories about this actually…My grandfather on my mom’s side was an amazing gardener. He used to grow the best Olathe sweet corn I have ever had. He is probably my “gardening” angel now, as he has also past away. My dad’s father can also grow a mean garden and award winner tomatoes. He has given me a lot of tips on how to grow the perfect tomato.

 

We should be able to harvest some items in the next month or so. All of our tomatoes and chilies have to stay in the greenhouse for a while. They are very sensitive to the weather and we have to be sure we are not expecting a late season frost. We have three types of tomatoes and six kinds of chilies. We also purchased two pecan trees from a man selling them on the side of the road in a near by town. They are baby trees so we won’t have any pecans for at least four or five years but it is a nice investment.
 
Lizzy the Lizard Helping me in the Greenhouse
 
 

Another project that just started is cleaning out the sheep cage. It has turned into a disgusting project. Cowboy does not recall if it has even been cleaned. We have enough compost/fertilizer to last for the rest of our life. We are using the tractor to dig all the ground up then we will put the fence back up and move them into their new home! I suppose I am happy to report I am not helping with this project. The poor workers have to deal with the stench.

 

Cowboy has been very busy building some metal feeders for the cattle. We are having to purchase some bales of feed for the yearling cows at the corrals. We are still weaning the calves so they are in the corrals while the mothers are up in La Sierra, a pasture. Cowboy loves to construct and engineer projects. He came up with the feeder design all by himself. I joke with him that his mother must have dropped him on his head in a really good way when he was a baby because he is beyond intelligent. Not only is he intelligent he is a handy man and gets the job done. Those are the best kind to have around, according to my God Mother Zizzy! Cowboy’s father was so impressed by the design that he wants Cowboy to build two more feeders. If the conditions don’t improve and God continues to think we don’t need rain we will have to bring the feeders to the pasture where the cows are.
 
The Face of an Engineer
 
 

I have not been assisting with this project either as the construction of it far exceeds my skills. There has been bending of metal poles and welding involved. One of our workers, Manuel, used to weld as a profession so he is in heaven and has been loving this project.
 
Manuel Welding Away
 
 

It is also the windy season here and there has been mucho viento (a lot of wind)!! I understand Colorado has also been experiencing a lot of wind. There have been three or four days where I have not left the house, except to collect the eggs, because it has been so windy and miserable. The difference here, opposed to other places, is all the dirt and dust. Since it is so dry here when it is windy it basically turns into a dust storm. If you go outside for a second you will come in with a mouth full of dirt and sand. In fact, when the guys have to work outside in the wind they sometimes wear goggles so they can see. Aside from the wind the weather has been amazing. The evenings are always a bit cold, since we live in a desert. During the day the temperature has been in the 80’s and hit 90 last week. Can’t complain about that. I’m sure I will be complaining come summer when it is over 100, so I am trying to enjoy the weather now.

 

I have seen all sorts of wildlife around lately. I have officially seen my first scorpion, and have seen three since then. I basically wear my camera as a necklace so I was able to get a shot of one of the scorpions! As a funny side note, I was giving the chickens fresh water and turned a rock over and underneath was a little scorpion. The chickens, my favorite one actually whom I’ve named Princess Peach, swarmed like mad and ate it like candy. I was of course screaming at her, “No no drop it.” Come to find out, chickens are a natural predator and eat scorpions. I had to google this to make sure my chicken wasn’t going to die and that’s what I found out. 

 
 
Family of Pigs
 
Cowboy and I were working on the garden bed and were happily surprised by a family of 10 pigs that came prancing by. They were about 50 yards away and didn’t pay much attention to us, luckily. They are Peccary wild pigs and are extremely aggressive, especially the mother pigs if they have any babies. You have to be very mindful when you see them. I was able to grab the camera in time to capture some shots. La India, my loca dog daughter, chased one of them off which was quite a sight but I was scared and didn’t want it to charge her, so once again I was yelling at the animals.
 
Getting Some Air
 
 

As always, I have been cooking up a storm. The other day I was making some tortillas, which turned out to be a bad idea because I was starving and ate half the batch. You don’t exactly want to eat too many because the two main ingredients are flour and lard. But the hot fluffy things are so delicious. Cowboy entered the kitchen and was apparently very hungry too and wanted to help. The kitchen turned into a big mess and there was flour everywhere. But I loved and appreciated his help. My step-mom has a saying, “A messy cook is a good cook.” Cowboy’s tortillas were more like pitas. They needed to be rolled a little more, but the taste was still the same.

 

We have been able to go to the city the last two weekends, which has been a nice change of scenery. The main reason I enjoy going to the city is to catch up and visit with Marisa, I need to get my girl time in every once and a while! Marisa is such a wonderful gal with such a huge heart. I just love chatting with her, hearing her stories, and getting to know her more. She is from Australia so I have been able to learn a little about Australia and the culture there. It is very similar to the States from what I have gathered so far. I will have my own little Aussie experience in September, as we will be going to Sydney for her and Cowboy’s brothers wedding.

 

Cowboy’s parents traded with us and stayed at the ranch both weekends when we went to the city. We went to see the movie Safe House with Ryan Renoylds. They have a VIP movie theater here and it is quite the experience. It is 100 pesos, which is equivalent to $7.90 US dollars. You sit in leather recliners and you have a waitress! You can order dinner, popcorn, a latte, crapes, and even sushi! I had a cappuccino and popcorn, great combo I know.

 

As always I have been taking a lot of pictures. The sights are so beautiful around here and there is a lot to photograph. Cowboy’s grandfather, who is also an artist, really enjoys my pictures. Every time we see him he always asks me if I have new photos. Between the sunsets, animals, people, and landscape there is never a dull moment. I hope this update finds all my loved ones in good health and happiness, may God continue to bless you all! XOXO
 
Sunset
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Email LinkedIn StumbleUpon 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under My Posts | Leave a comment 
Post navigation
 ← Older posts Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Desert Life, Family Visit&amp; Puppies! Ranch Life, Orchard Visit&amp;Home Sweet Home A Must Share… The History of Cowboys Baby Chicks, Branding, and Rattlesnakes… 
 
 Giddy Up and Follow Me 
 
Enter your email address to follow this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 10 other followers

 

 
 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 October 2011 
 
Everyday is a Monday
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Jun       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 Love Crosses Borders Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Matala . Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Matala by Nicolo Volpato . Follow 
 Follow“Love Crosses Borders” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
