<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004300" url="http://www.unf.edu/~dtanner/dtch/chapters/dtch/dt_ch9.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:33" support="1" score="0.000406403574113344" bingtitle="Chapter 9 Limited Resource Decisions - University of North Florida" webtitle="Chapter 9 Limited Resource Decisions">
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Which Products to Produce. In order to maximize ... of complementary products be available. For example, at a fast food restaurant, if a company had limited drink cups, it ...</description>
	<body>
		Chapter 9 



 Resource Allocation Decisions 
 
 

 So far we have made an assumption that managers were able to acquire as much materials and hire as many qualified employees as needed to produce products for sales. In other words, there have been no restrictions on quantity for a company to buy. We know that in reality, this is not always the case. Acquiring sufficient resources is necessary for profitable operations, but when they are not available, managers are forced to make decisions of which product will be manufactured in order to best use the limited resource. 

 

 

 Limited Resources 

 M anagers often focus on one key factor: Which product will generate more &apos;profit&apos;? When a manager is faced with limited resources, i.e., a production constraint , only a limited number of inventory units can be produced. To determine which products should be produced, the key is to determine the contribution margin per unit of the constrained resource. 

 

 

 Examples of Constraints 

 Manufacturing companies often have shortages of particular resources that must be used in production. Three common limited resources are: 
 
 Limited skilled labor - There may be only a few qualified employees that are trained to perform a task in the production cycle. This limited resource is labor hours. 

 

 Limited production materials - Suppliers may back order materials, so a manufacturing company&apos;s production facility cannot produce all the products needed without materials. This limited resource is materials measured in terms of pounds, ounces, yards, or other measurement. 

 

 Limited facilities - A factory may have assembly space for only a limited number of work areas, or forklifts to move finished products. and other bottlenecks that stop production. This limited resource is measured in different quantities. 
 
 

 Which Products to Produce 

 In order to maximize profits, a company must produce the products with the highest contribution margin per unit of constrained resource. 

 

 Assume Product A has a contribution margin of $50 and Product B a contribution margin of $20. The company has only 500 hours of skilled labor available each week. Product A takes 2.5 hours and Product B takes 48 minutes to produce. First convert minutes to hours: 48 / 60 minutes = 0.80 hours. Their respective contribution margins per hour are: 

 

                                                   Product A:    $50     = $20.00 

                                                                     2.5 hours 

 

                                                   Product B:    $20       = $25.00 

                                                                       0.80 hours 

 

 If customers will buy either product without regard the preference, Product B should be produced because it generates $25, a higher contribution margin for each hour of labor. The company should produce only product B if it desires to maximize profits. Eliminating a product is not always advantageous due to demands by customers. 

 

 Sometimes customers demand a minimum number of complementary products be available. For example, at a fast food restaurant, if a company had limited drink cups, it would not be wise to produce only milk shakes and eliminate soft drinks just because the milkshakes would contribute more to profit out of each cup. Many customers prefer soft drinks and would opt to buy nothing and seek another fast food place In this case. 

 

 

 Example Constrained Resource Problem 

 BucketCo makes 2 models of resin buckets—beach buckets and garden buckets. Due to a shutdown of a resin supplier, BucketCo is only able to obtain 3,960 pounds of resin during each of the next few months. As a result of the supply decline, the price per pound of resin has risen to a total of $1.60 per pound. In order to stay competitive, BucketCo needs to produce at least 900 of each bucket model to remain competitive. It can sell all the buckets it produces. Information for the budget of next month follows: 

 
 
 
   
 
 Beach Buckets 
 
 Garden Buckets 
 
 Units 
 
 2,000 
 
 3,000 
       
 Sales 
 
 $120,000 
 
 $50,000 
 
 Variable costs 
 
 48,000 
 
 27,500 
 
 Fixed costs 
 
 20,000 
 
 10,500 
 
 Net income 
 
 $52,000 
 
 $12,000 
       
 Contribution margin per unit 
 
 $36.00 
 
 $7.50 
 
 Profit per unit 
 
 $26.00 
 
 $4.00 
 
 Resin needed per bucket 
 
 1.2 pounds 
 
 0.24 pounds 
 
 
   

 Given the limited resource, how many buckets of each model should BucketCo produce to maximize profits?  
 
 Step 1: Determine the contribution margin per pound of resin: 
 
 Beach: $36.00 / 1.2 pounds = $30.00 per pound 

 Garden: $7.50 / 0.24 pounds = $31.25 per pound 

 

 This information tells us that for every pound used to produce a Beach bucket, the company generates $30.00, and for every pound used to produce a Garden bucket, the company generates $31.25 of profit. 
 
 Step 2: Select the product producing the smallest contribution to profit as the product for which minimum production will be met. 
 
 Because Beach generates less contribution margin per pound than Garden, minimum units (900) of Beach will be produced. 
 
 Step 3: Determine the amount of limited resource to be used by the minimum production product. 
 
 Pounds to be used for production of 900 Beach buckets: 900 x 1.2 pounds = 1,080 pounds  
 
 Step 4: Determine the amount of limited resource available for the most productive product. 
 
 Pounds available for Garden buckets: 3,960 - 1,080 = 2,880 pounds 

 

 Because 900 Beach buckets must be produced at the minimum, they will consume 1,080 pounds as determined in step 3. The remaining 2,880 pounds will be used for the most profitable product. 
 
 Step 5: Determine how many units of the most productive product can be produced with the remaining resource. 
 
 Units of Garden buckets to be produced: 2,880 / 0.24 pounds each = 12,000 Garden buckets 
 
 Solution: Production of 900 Beach buckets and 12,000 Garden buckets will maximize profits given the limited number of pounds of resin available and the minimum production of 900 buckets of both models. 

 
 
 While this problem illustrated limited materials, companies often experience trouble finding qualified employees which equates to limited hours of qualified labor, and limitations on the number of hours a machine can run or space for production, 

 
 
 This page was last edited onSaturday January 12, 2008 11:59 AM 
Website designed and maintained by dtanner@unf.edu 
Copyright 1999-2008. University of North Florida. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
