<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004355" url="http://www.yellowpages.com/springfield-mo/mip/chick-fil-a-8224841" time="2012-07-12-20:36" support="2" score="0.0023155678267102915" bingtitle="Chick-Fil-A Springfield, MO, 65804 - YP.com" webtitle="Chick-Fil-A Springfield, MO, 65804 - YP.com">
			<query id="001320" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000510" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>Love this place. Provided by Judy&apos;s Book This is ... and it is no wonder because it is a fabulous fast food restaurant ... are available. served by the slice, as a tray or as ...</description>
	<body>
		Join
 
 Thanks! Click the link in the email sent to activate your account.
 
Check your email at Email Inbox to activate your account. No email? Check your spam/junk folder or Resend It» Resend It» 
 X 
 White Pages Mobile Apps Advertise with Us 
 
 Sign In Join Sign in with Facebook 

 Welcome, User 
 » My Profile » My Locations » My Reviews » My Photos » My Searches and Listings » My Deals 
 Sign Out 
   YP.com What are you looking for? near Where? Home&gt; Springfield Yellow Pages &gt; Fast Food Restaurants in Springfield, MO &gt;Chick-Fil-A 
 Chick-Fil-A 
 37.162821 -93.261961 5.0 stars 
 6 Ratings 4 Reviews 
 » 
 Do you love this place? 

Help others by recommending it!
 X Not Now 
 Thanks! 
 Now see what others are saying» 

 
 X 
 » Close 
 Quickly rate your faves! 

Just point at the stars and click. Simple.
 
stars

 1 stars 2 stars 3 stars 4 stars 5 stars 
 
Your Rating
 
 (417) 883-2275 

 2825 S Glenstone Ave, Springfield , MO 65804 

Near Southeast Springfield

 View Menu Visit Website 
 
 Save Email Send to phone Facebook Twitter 
 
Videos&amp;Photos

 Add a Photo 
 


 Be the first to add a photo» 
 
Business Details

 Edit info for this business 
 Hours: Open 7 Days Categories: Chicken Restaurants, Fast Food Restaurants Neighborhoods: Southeast Springfield 
General Info

Started in 1946 with a simple idea of making chicken sandwiches, Chick-Fil-A has grown into one of the largest, privately owned restaurant chains in the United States. It has expertise in preparing chicken recipes and uses peanut oil in its cooking processes. The chain s restaurants serve chicken wraps, sandwiches, burritos and nuggets, as well as a variety of salads, hand-spun milkshakes and waffle fries. Recognized as the pioneer in quick-service mall food, Chick-Fil-A operates more than 1,400 restaurants in over 35 U.S. states. With annual sales of nearly $2 billion, the chain employs approximately 50,000 associates. Chick-Fil-A participates in various community-based projects, such as health awareness and scholarship programs. Its Kid&apos;s Meal program is designed to help parents with physical and character development of their children. Additionally, the chain s restaurants conduct the Chick-Fil-A Leadership Scholarship Program, which focuses on creating higher education opportunities for employees.

 ...read more 
 
Reviews&amp;Recommendations

 Write a Review 
 5.0 stars 
6 Ratings
 
stars
 
Your Rating
 
0 recommendations
 
 
 


 

 See all recommendations» 
 
 
 5 stars 

 Cartertj79 10/15/2011

The best chicken in town

Provided by YPmobile 

You need to open more stores over on the west side of spfld, you have the best chicken in the world and I want a store that is closer, PLEASE!

 Respond Flag abuse 
 
 5 stars 

 allyallyt 11/06/2010

yum yum

this is good eating! clean restaurant. wish it was larger, its always busy here

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 5 stars 

 Debbie L. 10/03/2006

Wonderful Chicken

Provided by Judy&apos;s Book 

You gotta love Chic Fil A. I appreciate the fact that they not only have the fattening, tasty chicken, but they also have the less fattening, but still tasty chicken. They&apos;ve got terrific waffle fries, for the fry lovers out there. They also have veggie and fruit salads for those who are trying to be health conscious. I also like all of the different sauces. The best thing is that for kids, most of the time they get a book with the kids meal. That is awesome. I would much rather my children come home looking at a book (they&apos;re preschoolers and can&apos;t read yet:) than playing with some little, cheap plastic toy that will be lost within just a few days.

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 5 stars 

 Carl R. 04/13/2006

Love this place

Provided by Judy&apos;s Book 

This is located inside the Battlefield Mall in the food court. It has been around a long time, and it is no wonder because it is a fabulous fast food restaurant that always has quality food that is so great tasting you will never tire of it. They have a lot of different chicken items on the menu, so you will have plenty of ways to eat your chicken. Great side items and some of the best waffle fries ever! Great sweet tea as well. Always crowded because it is so good.

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 
 YP Mobile Page for Chick-Fil-A, Springfield, MO
 » Map&amp;Directions Paid Advertisement 
About

 About YP.com Contact Us Advertise with Us Careers Legal | Terms of Service and Use Privacy Policy Small Business Advertising Advertising Choices 
 
Site Directory

 Home Find a Business Maps&amp;Directions Find a Person White Pages Mobile Apps Reverse Phone Lookup Site Map Mobile YP 
 
City Guides More Cities » 

 Atlanta Austin Baltimore Boston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver 

 Detroit Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Memphis 

 Miami Milwaukee New York Oklahoma City Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Saint Louis 
 
AT&amp;T Family

 AT&amp;T AT&amp;T Wireless AnyWho Ingenio Yellow Pages Keen 
 
 Find Us on Facebook 

©2012 YP Intellectual Property LLC. All rights reserved.
YP, the YP logo and all other YP marks contained herein are trademarks of YP Intellectual Property LLC and/or YP affiliated companies.
AT&amp;T, the AT&amp;T Logo and all AT&amp;T related marks are trademarks of AT&amp;T Inc. or AT&amp;T affiliated companies.
All other marks contained herein are the property of their respective owners.
 Submit
	</body>
</document>
