<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004754" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/302/1280166/restaurant/Boston-Market-Tallahassee" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="1" score="0.0019118470973193019" bingtitle="Boston Market - Tallahassee | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Boston Market - Tallahassee | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>... they bring it to you, you eat it, they clean it up. Great idea for a &quot;fast&quot; food restaurant. ... quick knife-and-fork meal. ... something missing from my order.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Tallahassee » Tallahassee » Boston Market 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Atlanta Birmingham Jacksonville Los Angeles New York Orlando Tampa Bay More... 
 
Boston Market (Closed)

Sorry, this restaurant is permanently closed. Actually open? Click here. 

 View all 3 Boston Market locations 
 
(850) 878-7660
 Tallahassee 1415 Governors Sq Blvd 
 Tallahassee , FL 32301 
 bostonmarket.com 
 Cuisine American Menu Mediterranean Salad, Southwest Santa Fe Salad, Caesar Salad, Market Soup... View menu | Add menu photo   20 people have voted 50 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 El Tapatio Mexican... 78% Tallahassee - Mexican 1002 N Monroe St 
 
 Longhorn Steakhouse 75% $$ Tallahassee - American, Steakhouse 2400 N Monroe St 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Diner reviews are sorted by relevance

 December 4, 2010 Service and food have stepped up by Amie ( 16 reviews ) I stopped going to Boston Market years ago when it was Rotisserie Grill (or whatever). The food and service sucked and it was expensive. I&apos;ve rediscovered it. The service is excellent and the staff is friendly. There are also new more affordable menu choices. The Gov. Sq. Blvd. one has become my go to spot when I want a quick knife-and-fork meal. August 22, 2011 Better now then before by Michael ( 9 reviews ) Before they put the table side service in place the service/food was ok I still think they have the best mac and cheese of any restaurant hands down, the noodles aren&apos;t ever soggy when I go there. If it&apos;s just been made then it&apos;s even better. I like the new style of service, they bring it to you, you eat it, they clean it up. Great idea for a&quot;fast&quot;food restaurant. February 19, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Tracy ( 10 reviews ) Crap service. I stopped eating at Boston Market because no matter which location I vist, the service is horrible and there is always something missing from my order. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos
 Be the first to contribute a photo for this restaurant. View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Little Italy 84% $$ Tallahassee - Italian, Pizza Burger King $ Tallahassee - Burgers, Fast Food Krispy Kreme 55% Tallahassee - Coffee, Desserts/Ice Cream, Donuts Crispers 77% Tallahassee New Leaf Market and Deli 89% $ Tallahassee - Vegetarian, Buffet, Breakfast/Brunch 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 boston market closed tallahassee boston market in tallahassee 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
