<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004748" url="http://www.livinglakecountry.com/mukwonagochief/policeandcourts/118004589.html" time="2012-07-12-21:15" support="1" score="0.0009095748500487087" bingtitle="Sex offender accused of lewd behavior in Vernon - Mukwonago Chief" webtitle="Sex offender accused of lewd behavior in Vernon  - Mukwonago Chief">
			<query id="000145" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>... himself while driving past a drive-through window at a Town of Vernon fast food restaurant ... and then asked for napkins, and when the female clerk handed him the napkins ...</description>
	<body>
		ALERT! We&apos;ve revised our Privacy Policy and TOU. Click here for information. 
 Welcome to livinglakecountry.com   Login Edit profile Register Logout Blogs 
 Home Lake Country Reporter Oconomowoc Focus Sussex Sun Kettle Moraine Index Mukwonago Chief Jefferson Advertiser Classifieds    
84°
 
Cloudy | 6MPH
 EXTENDED FORECAST 
NEWSROOM * CIRCULATION * ADVERTISING
 CONTACT US SUBSCRIBER SERVICES 
 »Subscribe »Manage Subscription 
Thursday
 
July 2012
 
12
 Home » Mukwonago Chief » Police and Courts Police and Courts 
Sex offender accused of lewd behavior in Vernon

Man allegedly exposed himself in drive-through

By Jim Stevens 
 
 Posted: March 15, 2011 

 Waukesha— A Waukesha man, who is a registered sex offender, has been charged with exposing himself while driving past a drive-through window at a Town of Vernon fast food restaurant last year.

Kevin J. Biersteker, 21, formerly of the Town of Mukwonago, was charged March 14 in Waukesha County Circuit Court with a misdemeanor count of lewd and lascivious behavior.

According to the criminal complaint, Biersteker was at the McDonald&apos;s restaurant at National Avenue and Highway 164 on May 12, 2010, and ordered a glass of water. Biersteker drove around and then asked for napkins, and when the female clerk handed him the napkins, she saw he was masturbating. The clerk asked Biersteker&quot;what&apos;s wrong with you?&quot;the complaint said.

Biersteker was later reported offering to buy alcohol for some 16-year-old girls in Vernon, and he drove by them slowly, the report said.

Biersteker was convicted in June 2008 of a felony count of causing a child to view sexual activity. A charge of second-degree sexual assault was dismissed as part of a plea agreement with prosecutors. He was sentenced to 15 months in prison and three years of extended supervision.

Biersteker was also convicted at the same time of lewd and lascivious behavior and was fined.

A warrant has been issued for his arrest.
 
 1 Comments 
 Post a Comment Sort by: Oldest | Newest | Most Thumbs Up 
 
 heathercore - Mar 17, 2011 3:54 PM 
 »Report abuse 0 0 Click thumb to rate 0 0 Please login to rate There is an&quot;I&apos;m lovin&apos; it&quot;joke in there somewhere. 
 Sort by: Oldest | Newest | Most Thumbs Up Post a comment 
We encourage your comments but will strive to remove discussion that contains personal attacks, racial slurs, profanity or other inappropriate material as outlined in our guidelines . We post-moderate comments on most content, but may choose to pre-moderate some comments so please be patient if you don&apos;t see yours appear right way. We also ask for your help by reporting comments you think are inappropriate.
 
Please login or register to post a comment.
 
 Logged in as: Characters remaining: 2000 Comment:
 required discussion guidelines | terms of use | privacy policy Post Your Comment 
 
 
E-mail Newsletter

Top stories from the Lake Country area. Tuesday afternoons and Thursday mornings.
 
 
Enter your e-mail address above and click &quot;Sign Up Now!&quot; to begin receiving your e-mail newsletter Get the Newsletter! 
 Login or Register to manage all your newsletter preferences. Manage all your newsletter preferences. Tools 
 print e-mail save 
 TEXT SIZE 
 reddit Delicious facebook 
 
 Newsvine Digg it Technorati Mixx 
 
advertisement
 
 
 Offer available to Waukesha County&apos;s Lake Country residents only 
 
  
 

 
 Spring 2012 Coupon Book 
  
 Construction Updates 
 

 Get the latest on I-94, I-43 and Hwy 18 construction 
 Newsletter/Facebook/Twitter 
     

 Sign up for the Living Lake Country newsletter here 

 Find us on Facebook 

 Follow us on Twitter 
 Community Blogs 
Lake Country residents share their views on news, happenings and current events.
 
 The Engineering Perspective 
 By Bernie Ziebart 
 The real war on women (68) 
 
 It&apos;s Hemmer Time 
 By Amy L. Geiger-Hemmer 
 Is the Racine recall election mess a &quot;trial run&quot; for November? (68) 
 
 Fighting Liberal Lies! 
 By Jim Hayett 
 More disappointment with jobs and the economy. (25) 
 
 Lake Country Rotary Happenings 
 By Sarah Schroeder 
 Winner of our Harley 2012 FXDC! Thank you all who participated in our Beer Celebration and the Raffle! 
 
 Eagle&apos;s Eye 
 By Al Neuhauser 
 Postmortem (15) 
 
LivingLakeCountry.com features more than a dozen community bloggers - a group of volunteer conversation leaders who are up on the latest topics and never short on an opinion. Just a few are pictured here. Check out the rest and see what they have to say!

 View All Blogs 

 Discussion Guidelines 

Do you want to become a Community Blogger? LivingLakeCountry.com welcomes your thoughts and opinions. Contact us for more information:
 I want to blog 
 
advertisement
 Editors&apos; Choice Awards 
 
 Posted Friday, July 6 
 
 Photo of the Week by Scott Ash:  

   

 WATCH OUT -   Catholic Memorial sophomore Jake Showmin gets hit with a pitch during the game against Kettle Moraine at Five Diamonds on Friday, June 29.

 

 News or Feature Story of the Week by Donna Frake:  Apartment fire claims life of woman 

 

 Sports Story of the Week by Joe Trovato:  Trovato: Finally, a milestone 

 

 Page or layout design of the week by Matt Colby: Fun for the Fourth 

 
 

 
 Your Photos Elation Dance Center
 - Delafield
 , WI 
 
MORE: See full gallery
 

 SUBMIT: Post Your Photos now

 
 Your Stories 
 
 

 Do you have news or an event that you would like to share with the community? Whether it&apos;s a community organization, a business, a local school, or a notable neighbor, we&apos;d love to hear about it!! 
 
 
 American Cancer Society 1st Annual Bowling For More Birthdays AngelsGrace Bike Show to be held in Oconomowoc A Big Piece of the Puzzle: Paying for Assisted Living Jannsen + Company Accountant, Pewaukee Resident Earns CPA Licensure ActionCOACH of Elm Grove Hires Three New Team Members Youth Bow Give Away! Local American Family Insurance Agent Jeff Tjugum earns Distinguished Insurance Agency distinction from J.D. Power and Associates Summerstage Presents - Arsenic&amp;Old Lace! 
 

 MORE: See the rest of Your Stories 

 SUBMIT: Post Your Story now

 
 Other ways to find us 
   Click here for a location near you 

 

 

 Learn more about Lake Country Publications 
 

 Information on Mukwonago Publications 

 

 

 Find more on MetroParent West at milwaukeemoms.com 
 
 Legal Notices 
 View legal notices here .
 Home | Lake Country Reporter | Oconomowoc Focus | Sussex Sun | Kettle Moraine Index | Mukwonago Chief | Classifieds 

©2012 LivingLakeCountry.com. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy/Your Californial Privacy Rights | Terms of Use | Advertise with Us 
Produced by Journal Interactive , a division of Journal Communications, Inc. Back to top
	</body>
</document>
