<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004552" url="http://www.empowerfitnesstraining.com/articles/VisaliaPersonalTrainerArticle1.htm" time="2012-07-12-20:57" support="1" score="0.00033688299571924815" bingtitle="Burn Your Fat Pants - empowerfitnesstraining.com - Empower Fitness ..." webtitle="Burn Your Fat Pants">
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Don’t just fly by the seat of your pants and go through whatever fast food restaurant is closest. 3. Spread your meals out: Try to eat 3 meals and 2 snacks ...</description>
	<body>
		Burn Your Fat Pants 

   

 7
sure fire ways to lose weight, drop inches, and burn your fat pants
forever. Most of us have been there,
broken down and bought a pair of pants that were bigger because we got tired of
squeezing into our smaller ones. Im
going to give you 7 fitness tips that will have you in your skinny jeans before
you know it. Never wear fat pants again! 

   

 1. Set realistic goals: Take it slow. Dont go all out only to burn
yourself out after a couple of weeks or months. Start off by making small changes to your lifestyle, and eventually you
will move on to bigger changes. Write
down specific short- term goals and aim for them. 

   

 2. Meals: Preplan all of your meals. When
you are prepared, you make healthier food choices. Dont just fly by the seat
of your pants and go through whatever fast food restaurant is closest. 

   

 3. Spread your meals out: Try to eat 3 meals and 2 snacks
everyday. This keeps your blood sugar
levels even, and helps to avoid overeating. There are 3500 calories in one pound of fat. If you can burn 500 more
calories than you consume everyday of the week, you will lose a pound a week. 

   

 4. Drink lots of water: Drink at least four 16oz. glasses of ice
water a day, and you will burn an extra 100 calories a day. Water is a natural fat burner and has several
other health benefits like healthier skin, improved energy, and it helps to
remove toxins from the body. 

   

 5. Exercise: Get in 30 minutes a day of some
sort of continuous physical activity, such as walking, running, house cleaning,
mowing the lawn, lifting weights, etc. Walking 4 days a week, and weightlifting 3 days a week works best. Resistance training helps your body to burn
calories easier. The more muscle your body has, the better you will burn
calories. 

   

   

 6. Fitness Plan: Make your fitness plan easy, and
non-intimidating. I see a lot of people
that go over board with their fitness plans and burn out. Make your fitness plan flexible, so that it
fits into your schedule and busy life. Any exercise is good exercise as long as you are not sitting down
watching television and eating. 

   

 7. 3 Hour rule: If you are going to be very active after a meal, then feel free to eat
more calories. But, if you are going to be sedentary, consume fewer calories. Always think about what you will be doing up
to three hours after you eat. 

   

 Follow these 7 sure- fire
ways to burn your fat pants forever. Remember, set realistic goals and see them through. Your body, mind, and soul will thank you for
it. 

   
 
   
 
   

 I hope the article was helpful;
I am now accepting new clients. Call Today! (559)636-3488 . To Set up a complimentary training session,
and receive a 7 day meal plan, and Body composition test, a value of
$99.00. Dont miss out I would hate to
have to turn you away. 

   

   

 Written by Andy Salazar
C.P.T. 

 Owner: Empower Fitness
Training 

 218 N. Conyer St. B 

 Visalia, CA 93291 

 (559)636-3488 

 www.empowerfitnesstraining.com
	</body>
</document>
