<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004298" url="http://www.knoxkoupons.com/restaurants2.html" time="2012-07-12-20:33" support="1" score="0.010153338714052246" bingtitle="Knoxville Restaurants | Dining Clubs | Fast Food restaurants ..." webtitle="Knoxville Restaurants | Dining Clubs | Fast Food restaurants | Coupons and special e-mail offers">
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>... and many others offering discounts, free food and ... Bennigans - Receive a $5 gift card when you purchase a $25 ... Locations, Phone Numbers, and Online Pizza Ordering ...</description>
	<body>
		Knoxville Tennessee Restaurants 

 Special Dining Offers and Restaurant Coupons
for Knoxville TN and Restaurants Nationwide 
 
Both local, national and chain restaurants located in Knoxville and across the U.S. have lowered prices and developed more promotions to get you to try their restaurants. Here&apos;s a handy list of coupons, V.I.P. clubs, birthday clubs and monthly promotional newsletters featuring special offers you can take advantage of. Most coupons are subject to change, and you will be taken directly to the restaurant websites where you can print out the coupons or sign up for their current e-mail offers.
 
 Save On Dining Out - Here&apos;s a list of restaurants offering coupons
special e-mail clubs and other discounts to save you some money! 


 
 Baskin Robbins - Printable coupon for $3 off any cake or pie with a purchase of $15 or more.
 (Get Coupon) Bennigans - Receive a $5 gift card when you purchase a $25 in gift cards. Expires: Unknown
 (Get Coupon) Boston Market - Printable monthly coupons and online orders.
 (Get Coupon) Cold Stone Creamery - Monthly special promotions (often includes buy-one-get-one-free offers).
 (Get Coupon) Dairy Queen - Join the Blizzard Fan Club and receive two Blizzard Treats for the price of one. Expires: Unknown
 (See Details) Hardee&apos;s - Printable promotios and special offers
 (Get Coupon) Kentucky Fried Chicken - Printable monthly coupons.
 (Get Coupon) Little Caesars - Printable monthly coupon.
 (Get Coupon) Mimi&apos;s Cafe - Receive a FREE BREAKFAST by joining the E-Club and also other special offers.
 (Get Coupon) Quiznos Sub - Sign up for the newsletter and receive monthly printable coupons.
 (See Details) Red Lobster - Join the Red Lobster Club and receive coupons. Expires: Ongoing
 (See Details) Romano&apos;s Macaroni Grill - Join the&quot;Mac Pack&quot;and get a free appetizer and more. Expires: Unknown
 (See Details) Ruby Tuesday - Join the&quot;So Connected&quot;club and receive a special offer gift on your birthday.
 (See Details) Sonny&apos;s Pit Bar-B-Que - Join the R-U-Smokin Club and get a e-mail $5.00 off Coupon
 (Get Coupon) Schlotzsky&apos;s Deli - Print four coupons for sandwiches and pizza. Expires unknown
 (Get Coupon) T.G.I.Fridays - Friday&apos;s Gold Points - Join for free and earn point for discounts on meals and menu items.
 (See Details) Texas Roadhouse Grill - Join the VIP club for special restaurant coupons and offers
 (See Details) 
 
 * Some Offers May Expire Without Notice 

=========================================================================

 GET LOCAL RESTAURANT COUPONS 
 Click Here for a whole page of Knoxville Restaurant Deals?
 We&apos;ve conveniently located lots of discounts for area restaurants. Some of them at 50% off or more! 

=========================================================================

 Knoxville Restaurant Guide 

 Use our guide to fine dining in Knoxville. Get local restaurant information and savings discounts!
 



=========================================================================
 
 Printable Pizza coupons and promotional discounts from your
favorite pizza restaurants. 

 
National Pizza Companies - Coupons, Specials, Locations, Phone Numbers, and Online Pizza Ordering Resources.

 Chuck E. Cheese 
Over 500 locations in the U.S. and Canada.

 Cozzoli&apos;s Pizza 
Providing over 480 CiCi&apos;s all-you-can-eat pizza buffet restaurants in 26 states across the U.S.

 Domino&apos;s Pizza 
International chain. Find coupons, company information and locations.

 Donato&apos;s 
Order online, find locations, read their FAQ information on their web site

 Godfather&apos;s Pizza 
US chain. Print coupons, find locations, read about their community involvement, and get franchise information.

 Little Caesar&apos;s 
Provides delivery locations throughout the United States.

 Papa John&apos;s Pizza 
Menu and ingredients information, store locator and online ordering, restaurant directory, and franchise details.
 
 Snappy Tomato Pizza 
US pizza chain. Print coupons, review the menu, find locations and franchise information.
 
 Knoxville Night Life, Entertainment, Live Music Night Clubs 

 
 Color ~ Knoxville Restaurant Guide ~ 
 North Knoxville Restaurants | South Knoxville Restaurants |
 East Knoxville Restaurants | West Knoxville Restaurants | 
Downtown Knoxville Restaurants | Farragut Knoxville Restaurants |
 Turkey Creek Knoxville Restaurants 
 

============================================================================


 Home | Tell A Friend | Post Office | Newsletter! 

 

 For Everything You Need to Know About Knoxville Tennessee!
Go To Our On-Line Information Directory 
 
 

 Interested in placing your coupon in Big KnoxKoups?
 E-Mail us at jerry2@smokysavers.com or Phone Printech Promotions at 865-670-0224 

 ©1998-2009, Printech Graphic Communications, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
