<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004703" url="http://www.city-data.com/forum/georgia/44235-north-georgia-florida-migration.html" time="2012-07-12-21:12" support="1" score="0.0007148033766371672" bingtitle="North Georgia and Florida Migration (Atlanta, Toccoa: appointed ..." webtitle="North Georgia and Florida Migration (Atlanta, Toccoa: appointed, transplants, crime) -   City-Data Forum">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>... only about 15 minutes from Blue Ridge in Polk County ... down and respect the locals and dont try to change ... excited because there was going to be a new fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		City-Data Forum &gt; U.S. Forums &gt; Georgia North Georgia and Florida Migration (Atlanta, Toccoa: appointed, transplants, crime) 
 
 User Name Remember Me Password 
 
 
 Register Search Today&apos;s Posts Mark Forums Read 
 
 Welcome to City-Data.com forum! Make sure to register - it&apos;s free and very quick! You have to register before you can post and participate in our discussions with 1 million other registered members. User profiles and some forums can only be seen by registered members. After you create your free account you will be able to customize many options, you will have the full access to over 15,000 posts/day about local topics and you will see fewer ads. 
 
 Jump to a detailed profile or search
site with 
 Search Forums   ( Advanced ) 
 Business Search - 14 Million verified businesses 
 Search for:  near:  
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 7 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 &gt; 
 
 
 
   02-09-2007, 12:54 PM 
 Prichard Senior Member   1,419 posts, read 5,007,970 times Reputation: 685 
 North Georgia and Florida Migration I&apos;d like to hear all comments, opinions, constructive advice and personal accounts that North Georgian Natives have about people from Florida buying land, cabins, houses, or even Mansions up in the Mountains.

And, I&apos;d like to hear accounts of Florida (or other) transplants who have migrated or are considering migrating to the North Georgia mountain regions.

Here are a few things that we aught to consider.

What do North Georgians think about Floridians buying vacation homes up there? What about Floridians who move there permenantly? Can Floridians find jobs in Blue Ridge, Morganton, Clayton, Toccoa, Hiawassee?

What do any Floridian Transplants think of living up in these parts?

Where do N. Georgians flee to when they don&apos;t like where they&apos;re living anymore?

How many N. Georgians end up moving to larger cities like Atlanta when they become adults?

Do any Floridian transplants get active in local politics in North Georgia? What&apos;s your thoughts on things up there?

Feel free to go where you want with this discussion - I&apos;m just looking for honest feelings and honest opinions, don&apos;t hold back! 
 
 
 
 
   02-12-2007, 12:03 PM 
 hacholly Member   21 posts, read 35,348 times Reputation: 15 
 Wow did all the floridians move back or are they afraid to type the truth? 
 
   02-13-2007, 07:48 AM 
 ellie secret agent   Location: a primitive state 4,298 posts, read 7,194,234 times Reputation: 2943
	</body>
</document>
