<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004702" url="http://www.buycheapr.com/us/result.jsp?ga=us12&amp;q=spongebob+legos+set" time="2012-07-12-21:12" support="1" score="0.0008934427780110817" bingtitle="spongebob legos set - BuyCheapr.com" webtitle="spongebob legos set - BuyCheapr.com">
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>help Summer Lovin&apos; Tie-Dye 9 ounce paper cups 8-pack. ... Patties and let SpongeBob know there&apos;s an order up. ... just another day at Bikini Bottom&apos;s premier fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		SHOP RESEARCH HOME | LOGIN | ROWS 
 COMPUTER 
 Monitors Laptops Ultraportables Printers Tablet PCs Multimedia Software 
 ELECTRONICS 
 Flat Panel TVs Digital Cameras Camcorder MP3 Player GPS Devices Mobile Phones PDAs and Electronic Organizers DVD Recorder 
 SPORTS&amp;OUTDOOR 
 Bikes Treadmills Soccer Golf 
 CLOTHING 
 Women Men Shoes Luggage Sunglasses 
 KIDS 
 Toys Baby Care Car Seats Baby Carriers Cots, Cribs and Bassinets Buggies and Strollers 
 GARDEN 
 Garden Tools Pools Greenhouses 
 OFFICE 
 Fax Machines Photocopiers Office Supplies Shredders Voice Recorders and Transcribers 
 MORE... 
 
 
Results for&quot;spongebob legos set&quot;
 
Filter by:

 Free Shipping 
 
 KidKraft 2 in 1 Espresso Table with Lego Compatibl $ 103.99 - $ 103.99 COMPARE PRICES 2 Offers help by LEGO heart 
 
 Sun 370691 Lego LED Headlamp 2 White LEDs $ 12.34 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at CampingWorld.com help Toys from LEGO. heart LEGO 4 Piece Toy Organizer Tote $ 29.59 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at eBags help Toys from LEGO. heart Sun 370692 Lego Led Lantern Swinging Handle $ 22.39 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at CampingWorld.com help Toys from LEGO. heart Lego Star Wars 3 The Clone Wars $ 49.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Meijer.com help Video Games from LEGO. heart KidKraft 2 in 1 Espresso Table with Lego Compatibl $ 104.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at DollHousesGalore.com help Toys from LEGO. heart KidKraft 2 in 1 Espresso Table with Lego Compatibl $ 104.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at ChildrensTablesandChairs help Toys from LEGO. heart Personalized LEGO City Zipbin Toy Basket and Playm $ 24.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Personal Creations help Babies&amp;Kids from LEGO. heart LEGO Luggage LN0125 300 Fire Minifigure Vertical L $ 18.30 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Wayfair help Indoor Living from LEGO. heart RooMeez Lego Table Solid Color Door Maple and Whi $ 139.70 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Hayneedle.com help Babies&amp;Kids from LEGO. heart Personalized Lego Flashlight $ 24.99 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Personal Creations help Toys from LEGO. heart Boys Gray Lego Fire Truck Graphic Tee $ 10.00 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Children&apos;s Place help Babies&amp;Kids from LEGO. heart LEGO Luggage LN0125 500 Construction Minifigure Ve $ 18.30 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Wayfair help Indoor Living from LEGO. heart RooMeez Lego Table Maple Maple JC292 1 $ 139.70 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at Hayneedle.com help Babies&amp;Kids from LEGO. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Bikini Bottom Undersea $ 49.50 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help SpongeBob is throwing a huge party and everyone is invited! While Patrick is at the turntable spinning his favorite tunes, Squidward mans the juice bar and SpongeBob is getting silly by catapulting the party cake at Mrs Puff! Includes SpongeBob&apos;s... heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 49.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.06 GO TO SHOP at Target.com help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Lego spongebob bikini bottom undersea party 3818 heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the De $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the Deep The evil Plankton is trying to flee after stealing the secret Krabby Patty recipe from Mr. Krabs. Help Super SpongeBob and Patrick stop Plankton and retrieve the secret recipe with LEGO SpongeBob... heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the De $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.95 GO TO SHOP at Official LEGO®Shop help Catch Plankton and keep the secret recipe safe! heart LEGO Spongebob Heroic Heroes Of The Deep 3815 $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 5.18 GO TO SHOP at Target.com help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Encourage imagination and endless fun with this spongebob building set from lego. Featuring over 90 pieces, this set includes everything your child needs to embark on an exciting underwater adventure with... heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures Let children enjoy the world of imagination with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures. With Patrick, SpongeBob, Mr. Krabs and other vibrant characters, fans of the show can really get into... heart LEGO Sponge Bob Krusty Krab Adventures Set 3833 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 5.53 GO TO SHOP at Target.com help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Create your own exploits with spongebob and his friends using lego s krusty krab adventures set. Enjoy hours of fun while unleashing creativity with these brightly colored bricks. This collection allows kids... heart LEGO Harbour 4645 551 pcs 4645 $ 73.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO Harbour Kids can experience the thrill and excitement of working at the docks with LEGO Harbour. They can help workers unload cargo from the ships and load the heavy-duty trucks using cranes. The large cargo ship has compartments to store grain.... heart LEGO City Harbour 4645 $ 73.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target.com help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Lego city harbor is always bustling with activity. Use the crane to offload the grain from the cargo ship, place it onto the conveyor and load it onto the truck. There&apos;s no time to waste, as the next ship is... heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman 3817 Arrgh! Captain SpongeBob and his first mate Patrick have found an old treasure map and are searching for the treasure. Barnacles! The Flying Dutchman is here on his ghostly ship. Help keep him at bay... heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman 381 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.95 GO TO SHOP at Official LEGO®Shop help Help SpongeBob and Patrick to sink The Flying Dutchman! heart LEGO Spongebob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 5.56 GO TO SHOP at Target.com help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Lego spongebob the flying dutchman 3817 heart LEGO Spongebob Glove World 3816 $ 19.49 S&amp;H: $ 5.34 GO TO SHOP at Target.com help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Spongebob and his friends cheer and giggle as they enter glove world amusement park, their favorite place to play. As they wait for the amazing ride to start, they realize that eating a giant ice cream before... heart Licenced Character Toddler Boy s SpongeBob Pajama $ 8.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.95 GO TO SHOP at Kmart help Fly off to bedtime with the dynamic duo at your side. These Lego Batman shortie pajamas feature Batman and Robin on in full color on the short-sleeve top and sleep shorts. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World 3816 169 pc $ 19.77 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World SpongeBob and his friends Patrick and Sandy are in their favorite park to have loads of fun. Kids can join them in the excitement with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World. Place SpongeBob and his friends on the... heart LEGO City Harbor 4645 Scholastic $ 89.99 S&amp;H: $ 9.99 GO TO SHOP at The Scholastic Store help LEGO City Harbor 4645 - Toys&amp;Games-Toys-Building Toys-Construction Set Toys heart LEGO City Harbor amp LEGO City Marina $ 99.00 S&amp;H: $ 1.94 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO City Harbor: 551 pieces Includes 4 minifigures: fisherman, worker, crane driver and chief officer Vehicles include large cargo ship, crane and heavy-duty truck Features conveyor and light tower Accessories include fishing rod, fuel tank, trash bin, pier elements, trolley, a rat and grain Store grain inside the ship&apos;s compartments Move the crane to drop grain onto the conveyor belt Turn the conveyor belt to transport the grain onto the truck for transport Measures over 15&quot;(38cm) wide, 9&quot;(22cm) long and 8&quot;(20cm) tall Large cargo ship measures over 16&quot;(40cm) long, 3&quot;(7cm) wide and 5&quot;(12cm) tall Truck measures over 5&quot;(12cm) long and 3&quot;(7cm) tall Available in stores for layaway LEGO City Marina: 294 pieces Includes 5 minifigures: wind surfer, lifeguard, sailor, diver and girl Features watch tower, surf shop and paradise cafe Vehicles include dinghy and quad bike Accessories include surfboard, windsurfer, harpoon, scuba gear, 4 pairs of flippers, 3 life jackets and more Measures over 14&quot;(35cm) wide and 7&quot;(17cm) tall Quad bike measures over 2&quot;(5cm) long Dinghy measures over 3&quot;(7cm) wide and 6&quot;(15cm) long heart LEGO City Harbor $ 74.61 S&amp;H: $ 0.97 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO City Harbor: 551 pieces Includes 4 minifigures: fisherman, worker, crane driver and chief officer Vehicles include large cargo ship, crane and heavy-duty truck Features conveyor and light tower Accessories include fishing rod, fuel tank, trash bin, pier elements, trolley, a rat and grain Store grain inside the ship&apos;s compartments Move the crane to drop grain onto the conveyor belt Turn the conveyor belt to transport the grain onto the truck for transport Measures over 15&quot;(38cm) wide, 9&quot;(22cm) long and 8&quot;(20cm) tall Large cargo ship measures over 16&quot;(40cm) long, 3&quot;(7cm) wide and 5&quot;(12cm) tall Truck measures over 5&quot;(12cm) long and 3&quot;(7cm) tall Available in stores for layaway heart LEGO Harbor 4645 $ 73.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help LEGO City harbour is always bustling with activity! Use the crane to offload the grain from the cargo ship, place it onto the conveyor and load it onto the truck. There&apos;s no time to waste, as the next ship is already arriving! heart LEGO City Harbor amp LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Gl $ 89.00 S&amp;H: $ 1.94 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO City Harbor: 551 pieces Includes 4 minifigures: fisherman, worker, crane driver and chief officer Vehicles include large cargo ship, crane and heavy-duty truck Features conveyor and light tower Accessories include fishing rod, fuel tank, trash bin, pier elements, trolley, a rat and grain Store grain inside the ship&apos;s compartments Move the crane to drop grain onto the conveyor belt Turn the conveyor belt to transport the grain onto the truck for transport Measures over 15&quot;(38cm) wide, 9&quot;(22cm) long and 8&quot;(20cm) tall Large cargo ship measures over 16&quot;(40cm) long, 3&quot;(7cm) wide and 5&quot;(12cm) tall Truck measures over 5&quot;(12cm) long and 3&quot;(7cm) tall Available in stores for layaway LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World Set: 169 pieces LEGO SpongeBob Glove World comes with SpongeBob, the ice cream vendor, Sandy Arenita and Patrick heart LEGO Harbour 4645 551 pcs 4645 $ 73.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO Harbour Kids can experience the thrill and excitement of working at the docks with LEGO Harbour. They can help workers unload cargo from the ships and load the heavy-duty trucks using cranes. The large cargo ship has compartments to store grain. The movable cranes can lift the grain off the ship and onto the conveyor belt. Equipped with a wireless radio, the chief officer runs the dock and takes care of everything. Why You&apos;ll Love It: The fisherman mini figure, with a rod for catching fish on the pier, gives kids a realistic seaside experience. Age: 6 to 12 years Features Fisherman, worker, crane officer and chief officer mini figures A cargo ship and heavy duty truck A light tower Crane, conveyor belt and grain Includes fishing rod and pier elements heart LEGO City 4645 Harbor $ 89.99 S&amp;H: $ 14.45 GO TO SHOP at EntertainmentEarth.com help Accessories include fishing rod, fuel tank, trash bin, pier elements, trolley, a rat and grain Turn the conveyor belt to transport the grain onto the truck for transport! Includes 4 minifigures: fisherman, worker, crane driver and chief officer The LEGO City Harbor is bursting with activity! Its a busy day down at the LEGO City Harbor as ships dock and unload their goods! Use the crane to unload the grain from the cargo ship, then drop it onto the conveyor belt and move it into the awaiting truck. The chief officer keeps his dock running smoothly as trucks and ships come and go full of cargo, while a fisherman is busy catching his dinner on the pier! 551 pieces. Ages 6 to 12. heart LEGO City Harbour 4645 $ 73.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Lego city harbor is always bustling with activity. Use the crane to offload the grain from the cargo ship, place it onto the conveyor and load it onto the truck. There&apos;s no time to waste, as the next ship is already arriving. heart LEGO Harbor 4645 $ 65.99 S&amp;H: $ 10.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help LEGO City harbour is always bustling with activity! Use the crane to offload the grain from the cargo ship, place it onto the conveyor and load it onto the truck. There&apos;s no time to waste, as the next ship is already arriving! heart LEGO Spongebob Squarepants 3815 Heroic Heroes of t $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.95 GO TO SHOP at EntertainmentEarth.com help Includes 3 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick and Plankton Accessories include recipe and Planktons robot suit Spin the boatmobiles propellers! Catch Plankton and keep the secret recipe safe! Planktons finally gotten the Krabby Patty recipe. Super SpongeBob and Patrick are on it. Get them into the boatmobile and start the chase! Can our heroes catch Plankton and rescue the recipe? You decide! 95 pieces. Ages 5 to 12. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the De $ 14.97 S&amp;H: $ 0.97 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the Deep Set: Age Range: 5-12 years 95 pieces LEGO SpongeBob Heroic Heroes set comes with the evil plankton, and Heroic Heroes SpongeBob and Patrick heart LEGO Spongebob Heroic Heroes Of The Deep 3815 $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Encourage imagination and endless fun with this spongebob building set from lego. Featuring over 90 pieces, this set includes everything your child needs to embark on an exciting underwater adventure with spongebob and patrick. Hours of entertainment await your child with this building set. heart LEGO SpongeBob Heroic Heroes of the Deep 3815 $ 14.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.84 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Evil Plankton has stolen the secret Krabby Patty recipe from Mr. Krabs and super friends SpongeBob and Patrick are giving chase in their Boatmobile. Can our heroes catch him and keep the secret formula safe? heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the De $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Diapers.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the Deep The evil Plankton is trying to flee after stealing the secret Krabby Patty recipe from Mr. Krabs. Help Super SpongeBob and Patrick stop Plankton and retrieve the secret recipe with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the Deep. Chase him on the speedy boatmobile before he escapes. Why You&apos;ll Love It: Use the bubble shooter to shoot evil Plankton and retrieve the secret recipe. Age: 5 to 12 years Features Super SpongeBob and Patrick mini figures Plankton mini figure with robot suit Secret recipe Boatmobile with bubble shooter Spinning propellers attached to the boatmobile heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the De $ 14.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the Deep The evil Plankton is trying to flee after stealing the secret Krabby Patty recipe from Mr. Krabs. Help Super SpongeBob and Patrick stop Plankton and retrieve the secret recipe with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Heroic Heroes of the Deep. Chase him on the speedy boatmobile before he escapes. Why You&apos;ll Love It: Use the bubble shooter to shoot evil Plankton and retrieve the secret recipe. Age: 5 to 12 years Features Super SpongeBob and Patrick mini figures Plankton mini figure with robot suit Secret recipe Boatmobile with bubble shooter Spinning propellers attached to the boatmobile heart LEGO SpongeBob Heroic Heroes of the Deep 3815 $ 14.89 S&amp;H: $ 4.84 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Evil Plankton has stolen the secret Krabby Patty recipe from Mr. Krabs and super friends SpongeBob and Patrick are giving chase in their Boatmobile. Can our heroes catch him and keep the secret formula safe? heart Lego Spongebob Heroic Heroes Of The Deep 3815 $ 21.75 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help LEGO SpongeBob? Heroic Heroes of the Deep 3815 Features SpongeBob Squarepants appeals to kids of all ages Catch Plankton and keep the secret recipe safe Features SpongeBob, Patrick and Plankton minifigures Boatmobile included 95 Details Dimensions: 2 x 10.5 x 5.5 inches Manufacturer recommended age: 5 - 12 years Manufacturer: LEGO High Positive Comments from our buyers! We&apos;ll do our best to give you the best offer!*** Buy with confidence. Products are new and in its original packing.Shipping on heart LEGO Spongebob Squarepants 3817 Flying Dutchman $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.95 GO TO SHOP at EntertainmentEarth.com help Avast, Spongebob! Help SpongeBob and Patrick sink The Flying Dutchman! Set features Pirate SpongeBob, Pirate Patrick, and The Flying Dutchman minifigures. Includes a pirate ship, small island, treasure map, cutlasses, and more! Help SpongeBob and Patrick sink The Flying Dutchman! Captain SpongeBob and his first mate Patrick have found an old treasure map and are searching for the treasure. Barnacles! The Flying Dutchman is here on his ghostly ship. Help keep him at bay using the bubble blaster or hell make everyone walk the plank! This exciting set includes 3 LEGO minifigures - Pirate SpongeBob, Pirate Patrick, and The Flying Dutchman - plus a pirate ship and small island. The pirate ship features a plank, sail, and crows nest, while the island sports a boardwalk, treasure chest, and cannon. Accessories include a treasure map, 2 cutlasses, a shovel, and a bag of souls! The pirate ship measures over 7-inches long x 7-inches tall. The island measures 5-inches wide x 3-inches tall. Arrgh! 241 pieces. Ages 6 to 12. heart LEGO SpongeBob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.95 GO TO SHOP at Kmart help Arrgh! Captain SpongeBob and his first mate Patrick have found an old treasure map and are searching for the treasure. Barnacles! The Flying Dutchman is here on his ghostly ship. Help keep him at bay using the bubble blaster before our friends are made to walk the plank! Includes 3 minifigures: Pirate SpongeBob, Pirate Patrick and The Flying Dutchman. heart LEGO SpongeBob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.84 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Arrgh! Captain SpongeBob and his first mate Patrick have found an old treasure map and are searching for the treasure. Barnacles! The Flying Dutchman is here on his ghostly ship. Help keep him at bay using the bubble blaster or he&apos;ll make everyone walk the plank! Includes 3 minifigures: Pirate SpongeBob, Pirate Patrick and The Flying Dutchman Features pirate ship and small island Pirate ship features plank, sail and crow&apos;s nest Island features boardwalk, treasure chest and cannon Accessories include treasure map, 2 cutlasses, shovel and a bag of souls Pirate ship measures over 7&quot;(17cm) long and 7&quot;(17cm) tall Island measures 3&quot;(7cm) tall and 5&quot;(12cm) wide Suitable Age 6 Years +. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman Bui $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 0.97 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman Building Set: Minifigures of SpongeBob, Patrick and the Flying Dutchman Features pirate ship and small island Pirate ship features plank, sail and crow&apos;s nest Island features boardwalk, treasure chest and cannon Accessories include treasure map, 2 cutlasses, shovel and a bag of souls Pirate ship measures: 7&quot;L x 7&quot;H Island measures: 5&quot;W x 3&quot;H heart LEGO Spongebob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Lego spongebob the flying dutchman 3817 heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants The Flying Dutchman 3817 Arrgh! Captain SpongeBob and his first mate Patrick have found an old treasure map and are searching for the treasure. Barnacles! The Flying Dutchman is here on his ghostly ship. Help keep him at bay using the bubble blaster before our friends are made to walk the plank! Includes 3 minifigures: Pirate SpongeBob, Pirate Patrick and The Flying Dutchman.Recommended Ages: 6 - 12 years heart Lego Spongebob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 29.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Powered by Frooition Pro -- All Categories -- LEGO SpongeBob The Flying Dutchman (3817) List: $100.00 Our Price: $90.00 You Save 10% Off List This item is eligible for free shipping with a $75 purchase of ToysRUs qualifying items. More shipping options available on our Shipping Tab . Click here to view full size. Full Size Image Click to close full size. Item Description LEGO SpongeBob The Flying Dutchman (3817) Help SpongeBob and Patrick give The Flying Dutchman that sinking feeling with the L heart Lego Spongebob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 29.99 S&amp;H: $ 5.03 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Powered by Frooition Pro Eligible items ship Free on orders over $100! Click here to view full size. Full Size Image Click to close full size. More Items! LEGO SpongeBob The Flying Dutchman (3817) Age Range: 7 - 12 years This item is eligible for free shipping with a $100 purchase of FAO qualifying items. You can read more about delivery times and shipping options below, on our Shipping Tab . Item Description Help SpongeBob and Patrick give The Flying Dutchman that sinking feeling with the LEGO heart LEGO SpongeBob The Flying Dutchman 3817 $ 24.49 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Arrgh! Captain SpongeBob and his first mate Patrick have found an old treasure map and are searching for the treasure. Barnacles! The Flying Dutchman is here on his ghostly ship. Help keep him at bay using the bubble blaster or he&apos;ll make everyone walk the plank! Includes 3 minifigures: Pirate SpongeBob, Pirate Patrick and The Flying Dutchman Features pirate ship and small island Pirate ship features plank, sail and crow&apos;s nest Island features boardwalk, treasure chest and cannon Accessories include treasure map, 2 cutlasses, shovel and a bag of souls Pirate ship measures over 7&quot;(17cm) long and 7&quot;(17cm) tall Island measures 3&quot;(7cm) tall and 5&quot;(12cm) wide Suitable Age 6 Years +. heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 49.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.95 GO TO SHOP at Kmart help SpongeBob is throwing a huge party and everyone is invited! While Patrick is at the turntable spinning his favourite tunes and Squidward mans the juice bar, SpongeBob is getting silly by catapulting the party cake at Mrs Puff! This fantastic set also includes SpongeBob&apos;s house and Squidward&apos;s house, and 4 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick, Squidward, and Mrs Puff. heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party $ 49.60 S&amp;H: $ 0.97 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party: SpongeBob&apos;s house Squidward&apos;s house SpongeBob mini-figure Patrick mini-figure Squidward mini-figure Mrs. Puff mini-figure heart LEGO Spongebob Squarepants 3818 Bikini Bottom Unde $ 49.99 S&amp;H: $ 9.45 GO TO SHOP at EntertainmentEarth.com help Big party in Bikini Bottom! Mrs. Puff, Gary, Spongebob, Patrick, and Squidward are all here and ready to have a great time. There&apos;s a DJ table, Spongebob&apos;s house, a playground, and even more fun which you can put together! 471 pieces. Ages 6 to 12. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Bikini Bottom Undersea $ 49.50 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help SpongeBob is throwing a huge party and everyone is invited! While Patrick is at the turntable spinning his favorite tunes, Squidward mans the juice bar and SpongeBob is getting silly by catapulting the party cake at Mrs Puff! Includes SpongeBob&apos;s house, Squidward&apos;s house and 4 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick, Squidward, and Mrs Puff.Recommended Ages: 7 - 14 years heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 49.60 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help SpongeBob is throwing a huge party and everyone is invited! While Patrick is at the turntable spinning his favorite tunes, Squidward mans the juice bar and SpongeBob is catapulting the party cake at Mrs. Puff! Includes SpongeBob&apos;s house, Squidward&apos;s house and 4 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick, Squidward, and Mrs. Puff. Features DJ table and speakers, merry-go-round, seesaw and juice bar with cabinet Also includes Gary SpongeBob&apos;s house features bed with ejecting function and Gary&apos;s bowl Squidward&apos;s house features music stand and art studio Spin the merry-go-round! Play on the moving seesaw! Catapult the cake! SpongeBob&apos;s house measures 6&quot;(15cm) wide and 8&quot;(20cm) tall Squidward&apos;s house measures 3&quot;(7cm) wide and 6&quot;(15cm) tall Suitable Age 6 Years +. heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 46.49 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Lego spongebob bikini bottom undersea party 3818 heart Lego Spongebob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 60.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Powered by Frooition Pro -- All Categories -- LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party (3818) List: $100.00 Our Price: $90.00 You Save 10% Off List This item is eligible for free shipping with a $75 purchase of ToysRUs qualifying items. More shipping options available on our Shipping Tab . Click here to view full size. Full Size Image Click to close full size. Item Description LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party (3818) Everyone&apos;s welcome at the LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea P heart Lego Spongebob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 60.99 S&amp;H: $ 5.75 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Everyone&apos;s welcome at the LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party (3818)! SpongeBob is throwing a huge party and everyone is invited! While Patrick is at the turntable spinning his favorite tunes and Squidward mans the juice bar, SpongeBob is getting silly by catapulting the party cake at Mrs. Puff! The LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party (3818) building playset features: 4 MiniFigures: SpongeBob, Patrick, Squidward and Mrs. Puff Gary also included DJ table and speakers, merry-go-round, seesaw, and juice bar with ice cabinet SpongeBob&apos;s house with ejecting bed function and Gary&apos;s bowl Squidward&apos;s house with music stand and art studio Merry-go-round spins! heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party 3818 $ 48.50 S&amp;H: $ 9.48 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help SpongeBob is throwing a huge party and everyone is invited! While Patrick is at the turntable spinning his favorite tunes, Squidward mans the juice bar and SpongeBob is catapulting the party cake at Mrs. Puff! Includes SpongeBob&apos;s house, Squidward&apos;s house and 4 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick, Squidward, and Mrs. Puff. Features DJ table and speakers, merry-go-round, seesaw and juice bar with cabinet Also includes Gary SpongeBob&apos;s house features bed with ejecting function and Gary&apos;s bowl Squidward&apos;s house features music stand and art studio Spin the merry-go-round! Play on the moving seesaw! Catapult the cake! SpongeBob&apos;s house measures 6&quot;(15cm) wide and 8&quot;(20cm) tall Squidward&apos;s house measures 3&quot;(7cm) wide and 6&quot;(15cm) tall Suitable Age 6 Years +. heart Lego 3830 Spongebob Squarepants Bikini Bottom Expr $ 245.00 S&amp;H: $ 15.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help All aboard for new adventures with SpongeBob SquarePants, Patrick, and the Bikini Bottom Express The bus keeps leaving without SpongeBob and Patrick! Can they get their tickets from the machine before it speeds away again? Includes SpongeBob, Patrick, and all-new bus driver minifigure Top lifts off bus for added play inside 210 pieces Simply Vintage Brings You The best value on all Vintage and Non Vintage Toys&amp;Collectibles and Lego Sets. All of our Lego&apos;s and toys are original and Most have a best offers available. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Bikini Bottom Express $ 124.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help All aboard for new adventures with SpongeBob SquarePants, Patrick, and the Bikini Bottom Express. The bus keeps leaving without SpongeBob and Patrick! Can they get their tickets from the machine before it speeds away again? Lift the roof off the bus to seat SpongeBob and Patrick inside. A propeller on the back of the bus really spins. Includes SpongeBob, Patrick and all-new bus driver minifigure, plus a ticket booth and bus stop. Bus measures 6&quot;long. 210 pieces. heart LEGO SpongeBob The Krusty Krab $ 159.95 S&amp;H: $ 5.49 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Join SpongeBob, Squidward, Mr. Krabs and Plankton in a Krabby Patty adventure at the Krusty Krab restaurant. Push down on the lever to flip the Krabby Patties and let SpongeBob know there&apos;s an order up. When it&apos;s time for closing, help SpongeBob clean up by tossing the trash in the dumpster. Then, place the money in the safe and be sure to hide the Krabby Patty secret formula so Plankton doesn&apos;t find it. It&apos;s just another day at Bikini Bottom&apos;s premier fast food restaurant. This set includes SpongeBob, Squidward, Mr. Krabs and Plankton mini-figures. Even includes Krabby Patties and more. SpongeBob comic strip is included on the box. It has 295 Pieces totally. heart SpongeBob Squarepants Exclusive Limited Edition Le $ 104.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Manufacturer: LEGO heart Lego SpongeBob SquarePants The Emergency Room 23 $ 137.00 S&amp;H: $ 6.49 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Rush SpongeBob to the emergency room with the doctor in the ambulance. Once there, you can examine him with all the latest medical equipment, Patrick is waiting too. heart LEGO SpongeBob Figure bandage on head $ 7.39 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help LEGO SpongeBob Figure (bandage on head) heart LEGO 3833 SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Advent $ 25.99 S&amp;H: $ 7.95 GO TO SHOP at EntertainmentEarth.com help Dive down to Bikini Bottom and experience the Patty Wagon! 209 pieces include the Krabby Patty vehicle, plus SpongeBob, Patrick, and Mr. Krabs Minifigures. Features Mr. Krabs&apos;safe, money, working doors, and more. It&apos;s loads of fun from the hit Nickelodeon show! Dive down to Bikini Bottom for a swell time, and drive the Patty Wagon to the all-new Krusty Krab! Patrick&apos;s got the Patty Wagon all revved up, and SpongeBob is checking out the new gadgets inside the Krusty Krab. Good ol&apos;Mr. Krabs is just hoping the boys don&apos;t cause any damage! The Krabby Patty vehicle and SpongeBob, Patrick, and Mr. Krabs Minifigures are included, plus the Krusty Krab restaurant features details like Mr. Krabs&apos;safe, money, working doors, and more. Loads of fun from the hit Nickelodeon show, the set includes 209 pieces and measures 6 1/2-inches long x 4-inches tall. heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 0.97 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO 3833 SpongeBob SquarePants: SpongeBob, Patrick and Mr. Krabs minifigures Krabby Patty vehicle also included Measures 6.5&quot;(16cm) long and 4&quot;(10cm) tall! heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.84 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Dive down to Bikini Bottom for a swell time! Patrick&apos;s got the Patty Wagon all revved up and SpongeBob&apos;s checking out the new gadgets inside the Krusty Krab. Good ol&apos;Mr. Krabs is just hoping the boys don&apos;t cause any damage! 6 - 12 Years heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures $ 24.97 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures Let children enjoy the world of imagination with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures. With Patrick, SpongeBob, Mr. Krabs and other vibrant characters, fans of the show can really get into the action. Like always, Mr. Krabs is hoping the boys don&apos;t cause any trouble. The Patty Wagon completes the scene. . Why You&apos;ll Love It: Vibrant characters made out of great textures stimulate children&apos;s senses. Age: 2 years and up Features Includes mini-figures of SpongeBob, Patrck and Mr. Krabs Includes Patty Wagon Krusty Krab restaurant Includes 209 pieces in all heart LEGO Sponge Bob Krusty Krab Adventures Set 3833 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Create your own exploits with spongebob and his friends using lego s krusty krab adventures set. Enjoy hours of fun while unleashing creativity with these brightly colored bricks. This collection allows kids to build bikini bottom s famous burger joint, as well as the patty wagon. heart Lego Spongebob Krusty Krab Adventures 3833 $ 31.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Powered by Frooition Pro -- All Categories -- LEGO SpongeBob Krusty Krab Adventures (3833) List: $100.00 Our Price: $90.00 You Save 10% Off List This item is eligible for free shipping with a $75 purchase of ToysRUs qualifying items. More shipping options available on our Shipping Tab . Click here to view full size. Full Size Image Click to close full size. Item Description LEGO SpongeBob Krusty Krab Adventures (3833) Dive down to Bikini Bottom for a swell time! Patrick&apos;s got the Patty Wagon al heart LEGO Spongebob Squarepants Minifigure Grinning wit $ 1.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Almost two inches tall Spongebob minifigure from larger set Now sold separately for your playing enjoyment, Manufacturer: LEGO heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Krusty Krab Adventures $ 21.99 S&amp;H: $ 8.49 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Dive down to Bikini Bottom for a swell time! Patrick&apos;s got the Patty Wagon all revved up and SpongeBob&apos;s checking out the new gadgets inside the Krusty Krab. Good ol&apos;Mr. Krabs is just hoping the boys don&apos;t cause any damage! 6 - 12 Years heart Lego Spongebob Krusty Krab Adventures 3833 $ 31.99 S&amp;H: $ 5.01 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Patrick&apos;s got the Patty Wagon all revved up and SpongeBob&apos;s checking out the new gadgets inside the Krusty Krab. Good ol&apos;Mr. Krabs is just hoping the boys don&apos;t cause any damage! To be able to understand why LEGO has been successful for so long, just look to the name. LEGO originally got its name from founder Ole Kirk Christiansen by combining the Danish words&quot;Leg Got&quot;that means&quot;play well&quot;and later realized that the word LEGO in Latin translates to&quot;I put together.&quot;The LEGO set became a standard of creative play for children around the world, unlocking the creativity to build vehicles, buildings, cities and more. Most historians point to the invention of the wheel as a major turning point in world history. The invention of the LEGO wheel had the same monumental effect in the history of LEGO, making it possible to create cars, trucks and eventually the LEGO train building set that is one of the most successful LEGO sets of all time. LEGO innovation continues to this day with product lines like DUPLO that heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World 3816 169 pc $ 19.77 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Diapers.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World SpongeBob and his friends Patrick and Sandy are in their favorite park to have loads of fun. Kids can join them in the excitement with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World. Place SpongeBob and his friends on the ferris wheel and spin it for a great undersea ride. Why You&apos;ll Love It: The ticket counter, with its revolving gates and ice cream shop, makes the set more realistic for Spongebob fans. Age: 5 to 12 years Features SpongeBob, Patrick, Sandy and Ice cream vendor mini figures Ticket counter with revolving gates Rotating ferris wheel Ice cream shop Easy to assemble Colorfully printed pieces heart LEGO Spongebob Squarepants 3816 Glove World $ 19.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.95 GO TO SHOP at EntertainmentEarth.com help Includes 4 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick, Sandy and Ice Cream Vendor Features Ferris wheel, ice cream shop, ticket stand and fish ice cream vendor Spin the Ferris wheel to go for a ride! Have a whale of a time at Glove World Amusement Park! Join SpongeBob and his friends for a day of non-stop action in Glove World Amusement Park, their favorite place to play! Buy a ticket and jump in line for the Ferris wheel! Just dont drop your giant ice cream cone! 169 pieces. Ages 5 to 12. heart LEGO SpongeBob Glove World 3816 $ 19.64 S&amp;H: $ 4.84 GO TO SHOP at Amazon help Have a whale of a time at Glove World Amusement Park! Join SpongeBobTM and his friends for a day of non-stop action in Glove World Amusement Park, their favorite place to play! Buy a ticket and jump in line for the Ferris wheel! Just don&apos;t drop your giant ice cream cone! heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World $ 19.97 S&amp;H: $ 0.97 GO TO SHOP at Walmart help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World Set: 169 pieces LEGO SpongeBob Glove World comes with SpongeBob, the ice cream vendor, Sandy Arenita and Patrick heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World 3816 169 pc $ 19.77 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at YoYo.com help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World SpongeBob and his friends Patrick and Sandy are in their favorite park to have loads of fun. Kids can join them in the excitement with LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World. Place SpongeBob and his friends on the ferris wheel and spin it for a great undersea ride. Why You&apos;ll Love It: The ticket counter, with its revolving gates and ice cream shop, makes the set more realistic for Spongebob fans. Age: 5 to 12 years Features SpongeBob, Patrick, Sandy and Ice cream vendor mini figures Ticket counter with revolving gates Rotating ferris wheel Ice cream shop Easy to assemble Colorfully printed pieces heart LEGO Spongebob Glove World 3816 $ 20.00 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at Target help Find building kits and sets at Target.com! Spongebob and his friends cheer and giggle as they enter glove world amusement park, their favorite place to play. As they wait for the amazing ride to start, they realize that eating a giant ice cream before getting on maybe wasn&apos;t the best idea after all. heart Lego Spongebob Glove World 3816 $ 28.32 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help LEGO SpongeBob Glove World 3816 Features Have a whale of a time at Glove World Amusement Park Includes 3 minifigures: SpongeBob, Patrick and Sandy Set includes ride, ice cream shop and ticket stand Fish Vendor also included 169 Total Pieces Details Dimensions: 2 x 10 x 7.5 inches Manufacturer recommended age: 5 - 12 years Manufacturer: LEGO One-day Shipping service is optional and includes 1-business day handling . If you buy the item today we will ship it tomorrow using One-day Shipping servic heart Lego Spongebob Squarepants Glove World 3816 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.00 GO TO SHOP at eBay help LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World (3816) SpongeBob and his friends cheer and giggle as they enter LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World (3816), their favorite place to play! LEGO originally got its name from founder Ole Kirk Christiansen who combed the Danish words&quot;Leg Got&quot;which means&quot;play well&quot;. Historians point to the invention of the wheel as a major turning point in world history. heart Lego Harry Potter 4736 Freeing Dobby 73 Pcs Ages 6 $ 11.99 S&amp;H: $ 3.24 GO TO SHOP at eBay help LEGO Harry Potter 4736 Freeing Dobby 73 pieces BRAND NEW ages 6-12 mini figures x3 Brand new in box heart Lego Spongebob Squarepants Glove World 3816 $ 24.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.78 GO TO SHOP at eBay help SpongeBob and his friends cheer and giggle as they enter LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World (3816), their favorite place to play! To be able to understand why LEGO has been successful for so long, just look to the name. LEGO originally got its name from founder Ole Kirk Christiansen who combed the Danish words&quot;Leg Got&quot;which means&quot;play well&quot;. He later realized that LEGO in Latin translates to&quot;I put together.&quot;The LEGO set became a standard of creative play for children worldwide, unlocking the creativity to build vehicles, buildings, cities and more. Historians point to the invention of the wheel as a major turning point in world history. heart LEGO SpongeBob Glove World 3816 $ 19.37 S&amp;H: $ 4.29 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Have a whale of a time at Glove World Amusement Park! Join SpongeBobTM and his friends for a day of non-stop action in Glove World Amusement Park, their favorite place to play! Buy a ticket and jump in line for the Ferris wheel! Just don&apos;t drop your giant ice cream cone! heart LEGO Spongebob LOOSE Mini Figure Spacewalk Spongeb $ 4.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help Exclusive to LEGO Set 3831 Rocket Ride heart Spongebob Lego Set 4982 Mrs Puff s Boating School $ 149.99 S&amp;H: $ 9.99 GO TO SHOP at eBay help Name: Mrs. Puffs Boating School Manufacturer: LEGO Series: Spongebob Squarepants Details (Description): Help SpongeBob learn to drive!SpongeBob needs to get his boating license, so it&apos;&apos;s off to Mrs. Puff&apos;&apos;s Boating School! But will the school still be standing when he&apos;&apos;s done? Pull back SpongeBob&apos;&apos;s boat and let go to send him zooming down the driving course and through the brick wall. * SpongeBob&apos;&apos;s boat has a pull-back motor! * Crash through the wall and get past the anchor in the driving cou heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World $ 26.68 S&amp;H: $ 7.74 GO TO SHOP at Amazon Marketplace help With the LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World Set, your child can have some fun at the Glove World Amusement Park with SpongeBob and all his friends. This SpongeBob LEGO set includes 169 pieces that will help develop your little one&apos;s creativity. It also comes with minifigures of SpongeBob, the ice cream vendor, Sandy Arenita, and Patrick to immerse your child in the world of SpongeBob. Help SpongeBob and his friends pass through the park&apos;s revolving gate entrance. Spin the Ferris wheel and le heart Brandon s Lego Spongebob Set 3825 3827 Most of Bik $ 70.00 S&amp;H: $ 8.99 GO TO SHOP at brandonmichaelford - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart Spongebob Squarepants Lego SETS 2 Bikini Bottom a $ 32.00 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at surfer720 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart LEGO SPONGE BOB LOT 3 SETS 3831 4981 3830 ROCKET R $ 60.00 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at jhbrewer66 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Party Buildi $ 64.50 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at 1751tony - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart Legos Sponge Bob Mrs Puff s Boating School set 49 $ 5.50 S&amp;H: $ 4.95 GO TO SHOP at dennis87bmw635 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart Lego Spongebob Squarepants THE FLYING DUTCHMAN Min $ 9.99 S&amp;H: $ 1.64 GO TO SHOP at rileystreasurechest - eBay help Other heart Lego SpongeBob Sets amp Minifigures including Sand $ 5.50 S&amp;H: $ 4.99 GO TO SHOP at lisamostuff - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart Legos Sponge Bob The Bikini Bottom Express set 38 $ 5.99 S&amp;H: $ 4.95 GO TO SHOP at dennis87bmw635 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart Lego Patrick from Spongebob Squarepants Minifigure $ 5.50 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at rc-cpr - eBay help Figures heart SPONGE BOB SQUAREPANTS LEGO SET 3815 HEROIC HEROES $ 9.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.00 GO TO SHOP at fisher-pricefun - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart GLOVE WORLD Spongebob Squarepants Lego Set 3816 16 $ 29.99 S&amp;H: $ 6.50 GO TO SHOP at biggieone1974 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart LEGO Spongebob Minifigure from 3815 Heroic Heroes $ 4.99 S&amp;H: $ 2.50 GO TO SHOP at tonycwix - eBay help TV, Movie&amp;Video Games heart SpongeBob Lego Set 4982 Mrs Puff s Boating School $ 70.00 S&amp;H: see site GO TO SHOP at ggamboa1 - eBay help SpongeBob Squarepants heart LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Glove World Set 3816 N $ 27.40 S&amp;H: $ 0.00 GO TO SHOP at w.shawn.d - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart Lego 3825 4982 3827 4981SpongeBob Square Pants 4 S $ 129.99 S&amp;H: $ 15.00 GO TO SHOP at laceysangel - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart NEW Lego Belville Set 3 JELLYFISH Trans Pink Blue $ 3.99 S&amp;H: $ 2.00 GO TO SHOP at apple_blossom_park - eBay help Parts&amp;Pieces heart 2 SpongeBob Lego Sets 3816 Glove World amp 3833 Kr $ 20.99 S&amp;H: $ 14.00 GO TO SHOP at re_re7112 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart SPONGEBOB SQUAREPANTS amp PATTY WAGON LEGO From 38 $ 8.99 S&amp;H: $ 3.99 GO TO SHOP at fordluver4x4 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart LEGO SPONGEBOB Squarepants ASTRONAUT MINIFIGURE WI $ 6.56 S&amp;H: $ 1.99 GO TO SHOP at goodplays - eBay help Figures heart NEW Lego 3825 Spongebob Squarepants Krusty Krab 13 $ 9.99 S&amp;H: $ 2.50 GO TO SHOP at divadeals2004 - eBay help Spongebob Squarepants heart 
 
 Bookmark Page facebook twitter 
 
Sort List By:
 Filter by Price Up to $6 $5 - $9 $8 - $37 $37 - $109 $108 - $166 $165 or more Filter by Merchant Amazon Marketplace (14) eBay (13) YoYo.com (12) Walmart (8) Amazon (6) EntertainmentEarth.com (6) 
My Favorites

Add your favorites by clicking
on the heart!


 
Offers for spongebob legos set

 LEGO City Harbor 4645 Scholastic 
 $ 89.99 LEGO SpongeBob SquarePants Bikini Bottom... 
 $ 49.50 LEGO City Harbor amp LEGO City Marina 
 $ 99.00 LEGO SpongeBob Bikini Bottom Undersea Pa... 
 $ 49.99 LEGO City Harbor 
 $ 74.61 
 
Write a review on spongebob legos set 

Your opinion is important to us!
Let us know what you think by
writing a review about this
product.
 WRITE A REVIEW 
 
©2009-2012 BuyCheapr.com 
 ABOUT US About BuyCheapr.com Terms of Use Privacy Policy Contact / Imprint Sitemap PRODUCTS 
 Computers Consumer Electronics Sports&amp;Outdoor Clothing 
 
 Kids Garden Office More... 
 REVIEWS Write a Review User Reviews Expert Reviews close 
 

How likely are you to recommend BuyCheapr.com?

Likelihood to recommend BuyCheapr.com
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Not likely at all Very Likely 
Did BuyCheapr.com meet your shopping needs?
 Yes       No 
Please tell us the reason for your score above.
	</body>
</document>
