<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004726" url="http://isitnormal.com/story/i-like-to-drink-pee-51723/" time="2012-07-12-21:14" support="1" score="0.0003821414716554365" bingtitle="I like to drink pee | Is It Normal? | http://isitnormal.com" webtitle="I like to drink pee | Is It Normal? | http://isitnormal.com">
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>i even drink my pee and,..... i ate my own shit,while watching 2 gals 1 cup video..... ... What&apos;s your favorite fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Home Submit Post Feedback Help IIN Gold 

 Sign In Sign Up 
 Please  Sign In  or  Sign Up Free We&apos;re here to help each other. Play Nice! safe(r) mode™is on Saving... 
Are You Normal?

 Ask your question today!
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Sex 
I like to drink pee Favorited ( undo ) Following ( undo ) 42% Normal 9  Comments 
 Anyone understand of what I&apos;m talking about? Anyone can tell why I like drink pee? Anyone has the same interest? 
 Is It Normal? Thanks for voting! Saving... Next &gt;&gt; 
 Does this post fit one of these flags? If so, click it! [ Off Topic ] [ Inappropriate ] [ Best Of ] [ Vulgar ] [ Funny ] [ Fake ] [ Weird ] [ Interesting ] [ Stupid ] [ Lame ] [ Messed Up ] Comments ( 9 ) danielle11078 2 years ago | pl That&apos;s kinda gross... Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 guitarplayer32 2 years ago | pl Mmmmmmm yummy Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 fun4us 1 year, 10 months ago | pl It is more normal or common than you think. Almost everyone has done it or at least tried it. Go to&quot;gaypornjuice.com&quot;and have a ball watching the videos. I drink a little most every day. Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 xxDreamWeaverxx 1 year, 3 months ago | pl That is disgusting. Pee is your body&apos;s unwanted liquids. Why make your body reprocess them? Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 jensapa 1 year, 3 months ago | pl Gross. I don&apos;t understand the fascination with people an stuff that comes out there body. Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 skullz95 1 year, 1 month ago | pl I do it its so hot Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 shitlover 7 months ago | pl i eat my cum daily on a ham and chicknuggets,choko kakes etc. it taste very lovely. try it.

i even drink my pee and,.......

i ate my own shit,while watching 2 gals 1 cup video.......

love yourself... Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 nakedtime10 4 months, 2 weeks ago | pl I enjoy peeing in my coffee while I&apos;m drinking it yummy. Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 jondoerandom 1 month, 1 week ago | pl I heard it has a lot of health benefits! besides if you start eating your feces as well you&apos;ll basically leave no waste! tree huggers should be all over you, man. Comment Hidden ( show ) Report We&apos;ll look into it, thanks! Reply 1 1 Add A Comment 
Sorry, you need to be signed in to comment.

 Click here to sign in or register. 
 
Sorry, you need to be signed in to comment.

 Click here to sign in or register. 
 Check out these other IIN posts or create your own :
 69% IIN that I need to have a light on to go on the Internet / watch tv ? 5 Comments Have u ever had a friend with benefits 15 Comments 45% Too obsessed with a person 8 Comments 27% Not blinking much or too much 4 Comments 70% IIN that I like math so much? 15 Comments 88% Bitter Breakfast 5 Comments 71% IIN to want to wait until marriage 13 Comments 88% When i break up with someone i start to fantasize about someone else?? 6 Comments 94% IIN for a guy to have a bath a night time. 9 Comments IIN THIS MAN 12 Comments 
 Advertisement Buy Ads Categories&amp;More 
 Browse by Category 
 Aging Art Expeditions Fears Food/Drink Habits Hobbies Misc Observations Pets School Sleep Sports Thoughts Work 

 Appearance Drugs Family Feelings Friends Health Hygiene Music Peeves Relationships Sex Spirituality Technology Urges/Desires 
 Upcoming Posts (Unmoderated) Newest Posts 
 Newest Stories 

 Newest Polls 
 Most Popular Posts Recently Commented On 
 More Stuff To Check Out 
 Posts Needing Love Best Of Vulgar Funny Weird Interesting 



 Funny photos by Photoshop Disasters 
 Do you believe that extraterrestrial aliens exist? 
 Yes, They Exist! 188 They may exist 125 No! they&apos;re fake! 27 Skip&amp;see results 
 44 Comments Send us Quick Feedback: Questions? Comments? Tell us!
	</body>
</document>
