<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004894" url="http://www.collegehumor.com/picture/5312592" time="2012-07-12-21:24" support="1" score="0.00016232499782455563" bingtitle="Taking out the garbage. One douche at a time. - CollegeHumor Picture" webtitle="Taking out the garbage. One douche at a time. - CollegeHumor Picture">
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>In High School I worked at a fast food restaurant with my best friend. To give you some info my best friend ... Currently Viewing Taking out the garbage. One douche at a time.</description>
	<body>
		Home Videos 
 All Recent Video Playlists Most Viewed Sketch Comedy TV/Movies Originals All Originals Sketch Celebrities Animation Jake and Amir Troopers Hardly Working Very Mary-Kate Dinosaur Office The Six 
 x Pictures 
 All Recent Picture Galleries Most Viewed TV/Movies Categories Animals Art Cars College Epic Facebook Food Foreign Gross Holidays Nerdy People Politics Pop Culture Pranks Relationships Religion Sexy Signs Sports The Internet Words WTF Girls Cute College Girl Hottest College Girl 
 x Articles 
 All Recent Most Viewed TV/Movies Columns CollegeHumor Interview The Graphic Truth Caption Contest TLDNR Exclusive Leaks 420 Special Axe Cop Almost Reading HumorUs 
 x uPick 
 uPick Categories Beach Rants News .GIFs WTF Fail Win Classroom Screencap Rough Love Text Mess Pet Stories Jokes Idiotech Work Sucks Roommate Confessions Polidicks Pranks I Fought the Law 
 x Politics 
 Electoral CollegeHumor Political Timeline Election Cheat Sheet 
 More 
 More CollegeHumor Recent Toplists Surveys Topics CH Live Tour Best of CH CH LiveCast Hotlinks TV/Movies Stalk Us Facebook Twitter Youtube CH Staff Blog Subscribe (RSS) Recent Videos CH Originals Recent Pictures Recent Articles 
 x 
 Submit↑ 
 Sign in | Sign up | 
   Signing in... 
Sign in to CollegeHumor
 

 Use Your CollegeHumor Account Forgot your password? Use Your Facebook Account 
You&apos;ll also be able to post your CollegeHumor activity to your Facebook feed.
 Not registered? Create an account Signing in via Facebook Connect... Submit a Picture 
Taking out the garbage. One douche at a time.
 
From Matt [It&apos;s Confucius us] on July 28, 2009 
 previous next View Original Size See More garbage truck Like this Picture Share this Picture Share on Tumblr 37 Share on Facebook Tweet Email to a friend Embed 
 CollegeHumor’s Favorite Funny Videos 
 Close 
 Send this page to a friend 
 

 
 Your Name 
 Your Email 
 Friends&apos; Emails (Separate multiple addresses with commas) 
 Send 
 uPick I Fought the Law Run-ins with the cops See All» Up +131 Down I gotta GO. 
So today I was on my way home from the market when I got a stomach ache. It was an explosive mess waiting to happen. The speed limit was 40 and I was doing about 55 when a cop pulled me over. He asked me if I knew how fast I was going and I told him about 15 over, and to please hurry and give me my ticket because I was about to crap myself. He started laughing at let me go without ... Read More» even a warning and told me to drive slower. I guess cops are human too. 
 
 jay | July 9, 2012 

 Be the first to comment! 
 Tweet Submit your own picture, video, or story to uPick See all of the uPick Categories» 
 Recommended Pictures Comments (122) 
 Party-Goer Shows His O-Face 
I like to imagine he’s singing.

From bassman109 
 95 likes | 7 comments | April 13, 2012 Guy Gives Roommate $20 via Drawing of Stripper 
That stripper is giving away her biggest tip of the night.

From neszero 
 4 likes | 1 comment | June 08, 2012 Expert Pole Dancer 
The expert here is the girl on the left.

From 4gifs 
 63 likes | 6 comments | June 07, 2012 Flashing Nemo 
And they thought touching the butt was cool.

From thefrogman 
 65 likes | 2 comments | May 23, 2012 Child&apos;s Skull Before Losing Baby Teeth 
Oh, children are sharks. This explains a lot.

From allenizabeth 
 2,628 likes | 19 comments | May 16, 2012 Butts Bouncing Forever 
Knee socks with high heels? That’s crazy! Right? RIGHT?! Guys? Is anyone listening to me?

From NewHaarlem 
 201 likes | 11 comments | June 11, 2012 Recent Pictures 11,198 / 42,104 
 picture Big yellow rats never looked so damn good! 273 likes | 227 comments | +500,000 views Currently Viewing Taking out the garbage. One douche at a time. 37 likes | 122 comments picture Blood for oil, ay? 2012 is closer than we think PEOPLE!!! 17 likes | 91 comments 
 ← Newer Older → Your Friends on Facebook like Hot links The web&apos;s weirdest 
 The golden age of porn lives on. A good rule of thumb: don&apos;t trust a naked guy unless it&apos;s after you&apos;ve already had sex with him. The theft of BBQ potato chips is the worst crime Canada has seen in 62 years. &quot;Ladies should be seen and not heard, but also not seen.&quot; The only political agenda movies should have is pro-explosion. If these propaganda posters were trying to convince us how weird they are, they&apos;re working. Are the words you are reading right now art? YOU DECIDE. Turns out Adele&apos;s been pregnant for the same length of time Rollin&apos; in the Deep was at number 1: nearly forever. Meet your area&apos;s hottest available douchebags! Another easy money-saving tip: time travel back to the days before inflation and triple your dollars&apos; value. R-Rated Hotlinks More Hotlinks 
   
Newsletter Weekly Roundup 
 
 The best CollegeHumor content delivered directly to your face! 

Enter your email to receive a weekly newsletter of the best videos, girls, and more.
 Subscribe 

 
RSS Subscribe 
 RSS 
 Recent Videos Recent Pictures Recent Articles CollegeHumor Originals 
 
Friends BFF 
 
 Failblog AdultSwim Uproxx HerCampus HollywoodTuna Popoholic BroBible GorillaMask I Am Bored Smosh Caveman Circus The Smoking Gun 
 
 The Stuff Funny Videos / Funny Pictures / Funny Articles / Newsletter / Our Book / Mobile / FAQ 
 
 Seriously About / Site Map / Site Index / Advertise / Jobs / Contact / Privacy Policy / Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 CH Network Jest / SportsPickle / Dorkly / Hardly Working / Bleep Bloop / Jake and Amir / CH Media 
 
©2012 Connected Ventures, LLC. All rights reserved. | Brought to you by CollegeHumor
	</body>
</document>
