<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004998" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/78794730/Hard-Rock-Miners-Handbook" time="2012-07-12-21:31" support="1" score="0.0013937516841030701" bingtitle="Hard Rock Miners Handbook" webtitle="Hard Rock Miners Handbook">
			<query id="000074" bing-rank="25"/>
	<description>Hard Rock Miners Handbook - Free ebook download as PDF File (.pdf), text file (.txt) or read book online for free. Written by McIntosh Engineering. The Hard Rock ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   M C INTOSH ENGINEERING Nor th Bay , Ontar io T empe, Ariz ona Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook   HARD ROCK MINER’S HANDBOOK  McIntosh Engineering M C INTOSH ENGINEERING Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook by Jack de la Vergne TITLE The Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook, Edition 3 Copyright © 2003 McIntosh Engineering Limited 710 McKeown Avenue • North Bay, Ontario • Canada Phone (705) 494-8255 • Fax (705) 474-2652 Copyright © 2003 McIntosh Engineering Inc 4440 South Rural Road • Tempe • Arizona • USA Phone (480) 831-0310 • Fax (480) 831-0317 AUTHOR J.N. de la Vergne SPONSOR Scott L. McIntosh EDITOR Susan L. Andersen PUBLISHER AND PRINTER* McIntosh Engineering *Also published in CD format and available for download from www.mcintoshengineering.com BOOKBINDER Beck Bindery Service Ltd. ISBN ISBN 0-9687006-1-6 EDITIONS Edition 1 – June 2000 – Hard Copy Edition 2 – July 2000 – CD and Web Edition 3 (CD/Web) – May 2003 – CD and Web Edition 3 (Hard Copy) – August 2003 – Hard Copy   FORWARD  McIntosh Engineering Forward Edition 3, May 2003 by Scott McIntosh Jack de la Vergne&apos;s Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook is a work of the heart. Originally published in June of 2000 as a compilation of Jack’s continuing 35++ year mining industry career, I personally knew the lifetime of effort that Jack put into the original. Although I helped Jack with sponsorship and encouragement, Jack did all of the real work and I never believed w e would consider publishing an update. But, having received significant encouragement from the many readers of the book, and many new Rules of Thumb, Jack made the decision that a complete update was warranted and I was on board. The original publication, Edition 1, was published as a hard copy; the CD and web version with minor changes were published as Edition 2. Two hundred hard copies were distributed to customers and close friends of McIntosh Engineering while thousands of electronic copies were freely distributed via CD and our website. Mining industry response to the book is incredible. Thanks in large part to the efforts by John Chadw ick of the Mining Journal, the Infomine website and many others, the Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook has been distributed to over 113 countries worldwide. Daily website hits and downloads continue as students and professors, miners, engineers and mining executives embrace the Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook as an invaluable source of practical mining information. Our plan for publishing Edition 3 co nsists of two versions – CD (May 2003) and hard copy (August 2 003). As we have done for the past three years, the handbook is available for free download from our website (www.mcintoshengineering.com) and the CD version is free on a request b asis. Although publishing the hard copy is a huge effort, we have had many requests for hard copies since the original publication and are planning to publish 1,000 hard copies to be available for a nominal charge to cover printing costs. Thank you to everyone who contributed to the success of the o riginal publication and this update. Thanks to Jack most of all, but thanks also to the many persons who submitted new rules of thumb and tricks of the trade as well as those who helped with the chapter updates and reviews. A worthy cause appreciated by many. Scott McIntosh, May 10, 2003 McIntosh Engineering Note I’ve included the Forward for Edition 1 (following) as it contains helpful and important information for the reader. The Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook was personally conceived and written by Mr. John (Jack) de la Vergne, whose continuing 35+ year mining industry career spans engineering, construction, and operation of mining projects worldwide. The Handbook was written to assist miners and engineers in the difficult world of hard rock mining and is Jack’s gift to the industry that continues to provide him with employment, challenges, and fascin ation. Although the accent of the Handbook is on metal mining as indicated by the title, it is our hope and intention that much of the information may also be valuable to our friends mining soft, and other not-so-soft industrial mineral and energy resources. The Handbook is a not-for-profit publication intended to be of service and value to the mining companies we serve and the entire mining community, including students, teachers, consultants, contractors, manufacturers, salespersons, media representatives, financial institutions, mining associations, and government officials. It is our intention to provide the Handbook free of charge to any person involved i n the mining industry. In addition to a limited number of hard copies, we are publishing a free CD version of the Handbook and the full text will be available for download from our website ( www.mcintoshengineering.com). The Handbook was written with the knowledge that to begin solving a problem, an immediate approximate answer is frequently both necessary and useful. Rules of Thumb and comparable data are often sufficient to provide immediate answers and to begin the problem solving process. As a result, excerpts of the Hard Rock Miner’s Handbook consi sting of an abridged version of the Rules of Thumb were previously published and delivered at mining con ventions in the USA and Canada. The strong response from mining people provided many new rules and encouraged us to pursue this endeavor as a separate project. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Hard Rock Miners Handbook
 Written by McIntosh Engineering. The Hard Rock Miners Handbook. Download or Print 459 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Books - Non-fiction Rating: Upload Date: 01/19/2012 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Free ebook download as PDF File (.pdf), text file (.txt) or read book online for free. Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
