<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004969" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080710020046AAKOuTE" time="2012-07-12-21:29" support="2" score="0.00656368220512673" bingtitle="What are some of the differences between fast food and home-cooked ..." webtitle="What are some of the differences between fast food and home-cooked meals? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000846" bing-rank="193"/>
	<description>Cars &amp; Transportation; Computers &amp; Internet; Consumer ... now is changing the choices in the happy meal. Subway ... Of course you can&apos;t eat there everyday and if you do ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 You K Member since: July 10, 2008 Total points: 100 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What are some of the differences between fast food and home-cooked meals?
 Im doing a research paper and I just wanted to have some points of view from other people. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Felix Member since: February 17, 2007 Total points: 237,040 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 fast food is more expensive and much worse for you.. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 29% 2 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (9)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by babymed1... Member since: June 03, 2008 Total points: 1,355 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I know that there are alot of contraindications for eating fast food based upon nutrional value, but I would like to put a spin on it for a minute.

One positive thing is that it provides working single mothers like myself a quicker way to feed the family. There are some good choices out there now for example McDonalds now is changing the choices in the happy meal. Subway provides low fat subs and even Taco Bell has a way of reducing the calories. Of course you can&apos;t eat there everyday and if you do it doesn&apos;t help if you don&apos;t make the healthier choice. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote by Chuck P Member since: March 05, 2007 Total points: 44,545 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Home cooked usually refers to made from scratch not processed food. Although some of the ingredients still come from cans it is usually more nutritious than fast food. Fast food often adds extra fat and salt for flavor along with preservatives. They are moving towards even more processed and fast frozen foods that deteriorate the nutrients even further. They deceive the public by claiming or naming the food as being healthy while knowing full well they are not even close. Buyer beware when eating at any of those so called fast food places, Mexican and Burger places are the worst for processing and adding fat. Small single operators are not to be confused with the large chains that actually have their own commissaries. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by ♥ilu♥ Member since: July 03, 2008 Total points: 160 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Here are the advantages of home-cooked meals:
http://www.articlestree.com/food-and-drinks/stop-the-eating-out-madness-the-benefits-of-preparing-home-cooked-meals-tx391598.html

Fast food,why it&apos;s unhealthy:
http://www.pamf.org/preteen/mybody/nutrition/fastfood.html
http://news.minnesota.publicradio.org/features/2004/12/30_scheckt_mcstudy/

Good luck on your research parer! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote by Softball Chick Member since: July 07, 2008 Total points: 893 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Fast food is cheap imitation meat and calories that are unwanted. Home cooked meals are healthier and taste better because you know what goes in it and if it&apos;s cooked right. Home-cooked is way better than fast food! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote by minnie mouse Member since: May 26, 2008 Total points: 1,855 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 well home made meals u know how its cooked in what its cooked and by whom it gets taste, fast food, u will simply never know if the oil was new, was the pot clean and how many employee put their fingers in there 2 taste b4 it reached u? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by ♥ Heaven ♥ Lee ♥ Member since: February 06, 2008 Total points: 20,630 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Home cooked meals can be much more nutritional. The ingredients used are more natural, as well. Not many fast food places will boil or steam food, like you can do at home. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 14% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Amanda M Member since: February 07, 2008 Total points: 1,554 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 They use way more grease in restaurants, and its probably cleaner at home because you can see the food being made 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Amanda N Member since: June 13, 2008 Total points: 632 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Grease,Carbs,Not real meat,More Money,and the extra belly... 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by 04758392... Member since: May 01, 2008 Total points: 6,283 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 nothing really, it&apos;s just home cooked may be more convenient to make or something like that. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 I just finished Training at Subway, it was 3 days long 4-10.... The last 2 days I was cleaning ? Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 What is the difference between fast food restaurants and… fast food vs home made food? homecooking vs. fast food? Fast food vs. homemade dinner?? Do you like home cooked food or fast food? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
