<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004696" url="http://www.luuux.com/food/habit-burger-grill-yummy-burgers" time="2012-07-12-21:12" support="11" score="0.037789552721803885" bingtitle="The Habit Burger Grill | Yummy Burgers! | LUUUX" webtitle="The Habit Burger Grill | Yummy Burgers! | LUUUX">
			<query id="001341" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000495" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000478" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000494" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000493" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000476" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000482" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000485" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000492" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000469" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>... wasn&apos;t near by so I yelped to see what burger place ... When you walk in, you form a line - order then you ... never tried that fast food restaurant, but the food looks so ...</description>
	<body>
		Login Join Now! Log In or Sign Up to LUUUX.
 Click here to learn more. Click Here To Learn More. 
 Luuux 
 
 All Fashion Technology Health&amp;Beauty Design Sport&amp;Fitness Entertainment Places Food Community Shop 
 Home ›› Food ›› The Habit Burger Grill | Yummy Burgers! 
 Food »The Habit Burger Grill | Yummy Burgers!
 
My boyfriend, our friend and I had lunch today and we didn&apos;t know where to eat.. I wanted Red Robins but it wasn&apos;t near by so I yelped to see what burger place was near by and had decent reviews and that would have to be The Habit Burger Grill . It was all of our first times trying this place out.

First Impressions:
● Easy decor [not too overwhelmed like Red Robins though I still love Red Robins]
● You pick your own spot to eat [tables or booths, there were a lot of booths, I love booth seating!]
● Nice and quiet, music playing but it&apos;s not overwhelming
● NO WI-FI here [not sure about other Habit Burger places but the one I went to didn&apos;t have Wi-Fi so it&apos;s not a good place to go eat to do homework or anything.
● Very affordable, everything is less than $7!

When you walk in, you form a line - order then you get a beeper like you do at Rubios and the lights go off then you go get your food tray. After you&apos;re done, you clean after your self and dump the tree in the trash.

WHAT WE ORDERED:

Habit Burgers:
● BBQ Bacon Charburger $3.85
[100% fresh lean beef with crisp lettuce, grilled onions, mayo, pickles on toasted bun, no tomatoes for ME]
+ Add cheese ($0.50 cents extra)

● Teriyaki Charburger $3.25
[100% fresh lean beef with crisp lettuce, tomato, grilled onions, mayo, pickles, with grilled pineapple on toasted bun for my Boyfriend]
+ Add Bacon ($0.75 cents extra)

● Swiss and Mushrooms Charburger $4.45

Side:
● Onion Rings $1.95

Drinks:
● Regular $1.65
● Water cups FREE

Grand total including tax for 3: $17.67
 Not bad for 3 burgers and onion rings compared to Red Robins! 

Overall: I really enjoyed the food especially mines, my burger was juicy and taste really good. My boyfriend said his was unique cause there was pineapple in his burger! Our friend enjoyed hers too but she doesn&apos;t like vegetables lol. I would definitely go here again when I&apos;m in the area and recommend this burger place. And like always, thanks to my boyfriend for paying for everything. =)

 Have you ever ate at The Habit Burger Grill? A lot of reviewers said this place compares to Five Guys&amp;In&amp;Out. I would have to say In&amp;Out is good in it&apos;s own way while Habit Burger is good in its own way because at In&amp;Out there isn&apos;t the same burger type [where as Habit Grill has bacon, avocado for extra] so it&apos;s hard to compare. As far as Five Guys, I never tried it out so I wouldn&apos;t know.

 Want to see if there is The Habit Burger Grill near you? http://www.habitburger.com/locations/ 

Photos via Mine | Don&apos;t Take
Burgers left to right: Swiss&amp;Mushroom, Teriyaki Burger&amp;Bacon Burger.
 By Michelle Mai Huynh♡  |  January 19, 2012 |  Follow Michelle Mai Huynh♡ Report 
 © Source link: http://www.habitburger.com/ If you feel this post is incorrect or infringing on the rights of another person or organization, please click the &quot;Report&quot; link 
 57   likes 0 Log in or Sign up Share Share on Tumblr Share it anywhere and earn Luuux$ 
GET A LUUUX SHARELINK
 Drop the link to your post on your Blog, YouTube, or Twitter Feed, Facebook wall or anywhere on the Internet and earn Luuux$ for clicks. You\&apos;ll even earn extra for anyone who signs up and becomes a member after clicking your ShareLink. Get embed code for the Luuux button Get text link Tags: Food  • Hamburger  • Burger  • Onion Rings  • The Habit Burger Grill  • Habit Burger 
More Food posts

 Ralphs Food Haul! Birthday Cake Date Night at Olive… Shannon&apos;s DOTN -… Lunch: Quesadilla and… Dinner of the Night! DESSERTOTD: Creme… Edible Arrangements Step aside Jamba Juice,… Vanilla Ice Milk Mi Quang-Vietnamese… SOTN - Cannoli time! DOTD: Lasagna + Chicken… APPETIZEROTN: Calamari! LOTD: Chasu Ramen! Buffalo Chicken Jazz… Homemade Turkey Ceasar… Egg and Bagel Bo Chien Bo, It&apos;s… Samanco! 
 
Shoplinks Will be opened in new window 

 Poketo Mug Coffeepot by Silvia Portella Poketo Mug Animals by Luke Ramsey Poketo Mug Alien by Leah Chun Poketo Mug Forest Monsters by Peskimo 
 
Comments (46)
 ♡A. Leungツ : 
Those burger looks so so gooood :)
 February 4, 2012 - 19:57 
 Abuse 
 Maria D : 
Wow those burgers are huge! I would love to go eat there~
 January 22, 2012 - 05:30 
 Abuse 
 Jason Bandasack : 
Wow, these burgers looks amazing.
 January 20, 2012 - 10:25 
 Abuse 
 May Tii Ly : 
holy cow, that&apos;s some good looking burgers...I&apos;d love some right now. lol.
 January 20, 2012 - 10:15 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Janz Gonz: yeah they also had other foods all at affordable deals too under $7
 January 20, 2012 - 06:48 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Jenna S. ♥: same here by revisiting this post =]
 January 20, 2012 - 06:39 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Choi ❤: aww sorry to hear =[
 January 20, 2012 - 06:38 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Carnegie Sophia: they were a good size =D
 January 20, 2012 - 06:25 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Amanda Panda: lol sorry =] it was mighty good! hopefully they have a san jose location they have tons in ca =]
 January 20, 2012 - 06:24 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Sam ...: IT WAS =] I actually want some right now by looking at the photos again lols
 January 20, 2012 - 06:20 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Conny Chan: I didn&apos;t try that but my friend said it was really good better than the Carls Jr.
 January 20, 2012 - 06:19 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Anna Vu: Super juicy&amp;cheap too =D
 January 20, 2012 - 06:17 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Paulo Leite: Yup I was shocked that thee food wasn&apos;t that expensive =)
 January 20, 2012 - 06:15 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Cecilia Chiu: I would even pay up to $7 for the burger, it was that good =]
 January 20, 2012 - 06:13 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
hello itsniina: Me too! I&apos;d take onion rings over french fries any day =)
 January 20, 2012 - 06:12 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Lilly M: I know right, fast food places sell onion rings for more!
 January 20, 2012 - 06:06 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
☆ Holly Ann ☆: Link above will tell you the locations theres a lot in CA =)
 January 20, 2012 - 06:03 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Mica G.: aww hopefully soon =D
 January 20, 2012 - 05:49 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Anastasia&lt;3: They are huge and for 100% beef&amp;affordable even better!
 January 20, 2012 - 05:47 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Monica Michele..: you tried it before? cool! =D i like the bacon more cause pineapple peels my tongue
 January 20, 2012 - 05:41 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
May Hoang: I know right so affordable!
 January 20, 2012 - 05:40 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Diana Khoubaeva: They were good with a crisp =)
 January 20, 2012 - 05:38 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
D. Star: They were yummy and super affordable too =)
 January 20, 2012 - 05:34 
 Abuse 
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ : 
Shannon ツ: Yup only $2, such a good deal huh! I love onion rings and I know at fast foods like Carls Jr it&apos;s much more than $2! =)
 January 20, 2012 - 05:32 
 Abuse 
 Janz Gonz : 
Wow everything looks great and the price is amazing!
 January 20, 2012 - 04:32 
 Abuse 
 Adele S : 
Now those are burgers! mmmm
 January 20, 2012 - 03:53 
 Abuse 
 maleeda lor : 
i love burgers....yummmmmmm
 January 20, 2012 - 03:20 
 Abuse 
 Jenna S. ♥ : 
Omg now i&apos;m craving a burger and onion rings so badly! Everything looks awesome!
 January 20, 2012 - 00:50 
 Abuse 
 Choi ❤ : 
Omg, looks like it&apos;s full of yummyness. I actually had a burger meal today at a cafe and it doesn&apos;t even look half as nice as what is pictured. Damnnn
 January 20, 2012 - 00:34 
 Abuse 
 Carnegie Sophia : 
those burgers look huge
 January 19, 2012 - 22:09 
 Abuse 
 Amanda Panda : 
omggg michelle your killing me with your food post!!! DAMN those burgers looks soo good and those onion friess .. i wish i can get some of those in san jose
 January 19, 2012 - 21:37 
 Abuse 
 Sam ... : 
the BBQ Bacon Charburger sounds really good
 January 19, 2012 - 21:16 
 Abuse 
 Conny Chan : 
swiss n mushroom and the onion rings look bomb
 January 19, 2012 - 20:53 
 Abuse 
 Anna Vu : 
Those burgers are so huge, they look delish!
 January 19, 2012 - 20:22 
 Abuse 
 Paulo Leite : 
never tried that fast food restaurant, but the food looks so delicious and it is not expensive
 January 19, 2012 - 20:21 
 Abuse 
 Cecilia Chiu : 
yumm everything looks delicious! i would love to give it a try since it&apos;s so inexpensive.
 January 19, 2012 - 09:57 
 Abuse 
 hello itsniina : 
Those onion rings look so delicious! I love onion rings!
 January 19, 2012 - 08:20 
 Abuse 
 Lilly M : 
I&apos;ve never eaten there, but that&apos;s cheap for onion rings mmm onion rings lol.
 January 19, 2012 - 08:16 
 Abuse 
 Bigfoot Holly Ann_♥ : 
my mouth is drooling! lol everything looks so good! i wonder if we have one around here! i&apos;ve been to the one near ventura!
 January 19, 2012 - 08:05 
 Abuse 
 Mica G. : 
oooh look so freakin good! All the locations near me aren&apos;t open yet though.
 January 19, 2012 - 07:32 
 Abuse 
 Anastasia&lt;3 : 
These burgers look amazing! They are huge!
 January 19, 2012 - 07:24 
 Abuse 
 Monica Michele.. : 
love the habit i have to try the Teriyaki Burger now
 January 19, 2012 - 07:15 
 Abuse 
 May Hoang : 
wow those looks so good! everything is so cheap too!
 January 19, 2012 - 06:00 
 Abuse 
 Diana Khoubaeva : 
those onion rings look spectacular LOL! the burgers look really yummy too.
 January 19, 2012 - 05:29 
 Abuse 
 Cheesin Peasin : 
omg those burgers look AMAZING.
 January 19, 2012 - 05:12 
 Abuse 
 Shannon ツ : 
Those onion rings were only $2? Sadly there isn&apos;t one even on the East coast, but if there was I&apos;d go there just for those onion rings lol
 January 19, 2012 - 05:06 
 Abuse 
 
Popular posts

 
 Homemade Taco Soup 

A few night back I made some really delicious taco soup. Hear me out before you t...
 
 turkey dinner in july? 

pshhh i think you can have thanksgiving dinner whenever you want!! november is waa...
 
 Dynamite and Spicy… 

Sushi is one of my favourite food. One order of sushi roll was not enough for me s...
 
 Riceless Sushi Roll 

I recently tried out this sushi roll because it was so unique and different from a...
 
 Cake Pops! 

Cake pops are a huge hype right now, great to make for birthday parties, baby show...
 
 Yumpuffs - Mini… 

I have been looking for something sweet that is fairly healthy and I found this Al...
 
 
Posted by
 Michelle Mai Huynh♡ Female from SD, United States Add as friend | Follow Top contributor of Design 
 
 
Popular posts

 
 LOTD: Multilayer… 

I&apos;ve eaten this sandwich before and I really loved it and decided to get it again ...
 
 Quaker Soft Baked… 

This month I received the Influenster Mom Voxbox I love these things whats not to ...
 
 fish&amp;amp; chips cafe 

Today I was with my sister and my mom and we were at old fishermans warf Monterey ...
 
 food truck - first time! 

i ordered some food from a food truck for the first time. food trucks have gained ...
 
 Mrs Mak&apos;s BDay Dinner… 

Amy Leung had did a post HERE recently on Dream Kitchen. And I saw that the locat...
 
 Mint Chocolate Chip… 

Yesterday I ran to Starbucks because I earned a $5 gift card to starbucks from Vig...
 
 ©2011 Luuux 
Footer
 
 About Press Advertising Jobs Help Privacy Copyright Policy Site Terms Shop Terms Delivery Info
	</body>
</document>
