<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004009" url="http://www.city-data.com/forum/urban-planning/82020-all-talk-about-mcmansions-8.html" time="2012-07-12-20:13" support="1" score="0.0016793760059341857" bingtitle="All this talk about McMansions - Urban, city, town planning, land ..." webtitle="All this talk about McMansions - Urban, city, town planning, land use, zoning, transportation and transit, environmental issues, urban design, community development, subdivisions, revitalization - Page 8 - City-Data Forum">
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>Location: The better side of the Mason-Dixon Line ... that no matter where a person goes, they will receive ... as the way in which &quot;the principles of the fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		City-Data Forum &gt; General Forums &gt; Urban Planning All this talk about McMansions 
 
 User Name Remember Me Password 
 
 
 Register Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Search Blogs Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 Welcome to City-Data.com forum! Make sure to register - it&apos;s free and very quick! You have to register before you can post and participate in our discussions with 1 million other registered members. User profiles and some forums can only be seen by registered members. After you create your free account you will be able to customize many options, you will have the full access to over 15,000 posts/day about local topics and you will see fewer ads. 
 
 Jump to a detailed profile or search
site with 
 Search Forums   ( Advanced ) 
 Business Search - 14 Million verified businesses 
 Search for:  near:  
 
 
 
 Page 8 of 8 &lt; 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 
 
 
 
   03-21-2008, 09:37 AM 
 Cruikshl Southerngirl   Location: right here 883 posts, read 1,648,477 times Reputation: 376 
 McMansion is a personal opinion. People in a 1500 sq ft house would think my 3850 sq ft is one. I think 6000 sq ft is pushing the McMansion name. Then again somebody in that 6000 sq ft house thinks it&apos;s just right. Different strokes for different folks. I, on the other hand, have a hard time with builders building ugly houses no matter what size. 
 
 
 
 
   03-21-2008, 10:16 AM 
 holloway1010 Senior Member   Location: Baton Rouge 373 posts, read 878,178 times Reputation: 152 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by lammius ^ why are all of the living spaces RIGHT AT ground level?? You have these tall walls, I suppose giving the appearance of high ceilings, yet the windows are resting right on the ground! They look so strange. I hope there&apos;s good storm drainage. And once those shrubs grow taller than 6 inches, so long view. 
 
Most of the cielings in these types of houses are pretty high, generally 10 to 14 feet at their highest, but they usually add a tray cieling or something else to add architectural intrest to the otherwise empty space near the cieling. I must admit the build quality of most of these homes is pretty good. Of course, there are always those people who try to slip into a&quot;nice&quot;neighborhood that they can&apos;t afford, and the houses they build end up a piece of crap. I think that that first and second house have a second story whose widows only open up to the backyard, which might explain why the walls are so high on the front. 
 
   04-08-2008, 08:17 PM 
 Legal Alien Member   51 posts, read 96,644 times Reputation: 53 
 Definition of a&quot;McMansion&quot;? I keep reading posts with references to mcmansions. Is there a certain cut-off (square footage/size of lot/cost) when a home moves into this category? Where did this term originiate? 
 
   04-08-2008, 10:43 PM 
 Tom Lennox 70 Senior Member   Location: The better side of the Mason-Dixon Line 2,948 posts, read 4,361,355 times Reputation: 1134 
 Yeah you can feel the isolation and lack of community in some of these pictures. On one hand I hope to be able to live in a large house with a big yard someday but I also look fondly at the lifestyle of small town middle America where everyone is down to Earth, honest, humble people in close-knit communities. 
 
   04-08-2008, 11:29 PM 
 tande1n5 Senior Member   Location: San Diego, CA 807 posts, read 1,969,945 times Reputation: 310 
 There is a LOT about the definition here that gives to personal opinion. Although I also think that McMansions are tasteless (The local flavor in California is to make it look like it came from Tuscany), you can see that some people on this board think that Big+Built after 1950=McMansion for sure.

The Captains of Industry built their Gilded Age masions for sheer display of wealth, so conspicuous consumption alone cannot be the qualifier.

The architecture of the day has always been derided by some at the time, from Beaux-Arts, to Victorian, to Modernist, so that&apos;s also completely subjective.

Many of the early tract homes from the 1950&apos;s that are VERY alike are now enjoyed as&quot;midcentury modern&quot;now that the trees are mature, so it&apos;s not this alone either.

People of means have always owned bigger homes than are absolutely needed, and oftentimes took the entire lot in a larger metro area, so simple wastefulness isn&apos;t the answer either.

Neither is it completely about the non-historically accurate allusion to period styles, or else the revival movements that spawned the beautiful mission-revivals of Southern California in the 1920&apos;s and 1930&apos;s should be looked at as terrible as well. They&apos;re very inaccurate in their execution, and can be quite grandiose.

It therefore must come down to a combination, with poor&quot;slap-em-up&quot;craftsmanship to boot... AND personal opinion.

It DOES have a lot to do with the larger numbers of these big homes these days. More can afford them now (and some can still move in even though they technically can&apos;t). With lenient credit, and let&apos;s not forget about the modern day of dual incomes (the houses of old were owned with only one breadwinner), these are possible for a larger percent of the population. 
 
   04-09-2008, 09:33 AM 
 jm31828 Senior Member   Location: Lynnwood, Washington 996 posts, read 709,914 times Reputation: 805 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by phoenixxphyre Rows of houses that are all the same...and no one seems to care....


it was true when the song came out, and it&apos;s true now. Well, of course, we care or we wouldn&apos;t be posting a thread about it, but the people who live there, totally not bothered by being cookie cutter even in their extremes. 
 Wow, I guess I am the minority on this board, but I happen to think- even though these things do often look the same in each neighborhood/community, they are beautiful nonetheless! The ONLY concern I&apos;d have about them would be the poor quality materials used in some of them (some, not all- some are built quite well, at least here in the Midwest). But as far as appearance, I have no gripes at all- I could only wish my neighborhood looked as beautiful as those. 
 
   04-09-2008, 10:50 AM 
 Ben Around Senior Member   5,251 posts, read 6,343,235 times Reputation: 2118
	</body>
</document>
