<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004659" url="http://itunes.apple.com/us/tv-season/the-league-season-3/id464472007" time="2012-07-12-21:09" support="1" score="0.0016845753124541058" bingtitle="iTunes - TV Shows - The League, Season 3" webtitle="iTunes - TV Shows - The League, Season 3">
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>Taco finds a market for Kevin and Jenny&apos;s wedding cocktail napkins. And Pete ... Taco competes in a jingle contest for a disgusting fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Apple Store Mac iPod iPhone iPad iTunes Support 
 
 

 What’s New What is iTunes What’s on iTunes iTunes Charts How To 
 Opening the iTunes Store. If iTunes doesn&apos;t open, click the iTunes application icon in your Dock or on your Windows desktop. Progress Indicator iTunes 
iTunes is the world&apos;s easiest way to organize and add to your digital media collection.

We are unable to find iTunes on your computer. To preview or buy TV shows, get iTunes now.
 
Already have iTunes? Click I Have iTunes to open it now.
 iTunes for Mac + PC 
The League, Season 3 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning 

Open iTunes to preview or buy TV shows.
 
Description

To be a fan of The League on FX, you don&apos;t need to know much about fantasy football, or sports at all. You just need to have friends that you hate. FX&apos;s ensemble comedy follows a group of old friends in a fantasy football league who care deeply about one another - so deeply that they use every opportunity to make each other&apos;s lives miserable.
 
   Name Description Time Price   1 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Lockout The terrible reign of Ruxin as League Champion continues while the guys devise a grand plan with 23:24 $2.99 View In iTunes 2 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Sukkah Everyone is disappointed with their draft, but no one trusts each other enough to trade. Jenny goes 21:24 $2.99 View In iTunes 3 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Au Pair Ruxin hires a hot Au Pair for Baby Geoffrey, and is afraid Taco will sleep with her. Andre explores 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 4 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video Ol’ Smoke Crotch Kevin struggles with getting older. Ruxin is so desperate to get rid of his au pair that he gets 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 5 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video Bobbum Man Jenny forgets a special anniversary with Kevin. Andre seeks line up Nirvana. Taco creates an off 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 6 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video Yobogoya! Taco competes in a jingle contest for a disgusting fast food restaurant. Pete holds a grudge against 22:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 7 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video Carmenjello Kevin and Jenny search for the perfect paint color to get back their privacy, Sofia accuses Ruxin of 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 8 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video Thanksgiving Thanksgiving is family time as Ruxin gets an unexpected visit from his father (guest star Jeff 22:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 9 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Out of Towner The guys are psyched for a visit from Chuck, one of the League&apos;s out-of-towners, but he shows up 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 10 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Light of Genesis Kevin thinks his Krav Maga instructor may actually be into him. Jenny entrusts Andre with a secret 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 11 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Guest Bong Pete&apos;s new girlfriend wants to help him with his line up; Kevin&apos;s past at the DA&apos;s office has him 21:18 $2.99 View In iTunes 12 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video St. Pete Kevin and Jenny make a bold bet on the play-offs; Taco enlists Ruxin to get more involved with Taco 21:36 $2.99 View In iTunes 13 HD TV-MA Closed Captioning Video The Funeral It&apos;s the season finale. The race is on for the Shiva and the Sacko. Taco teams up with Chicago 23:00 $2.99 View In iTunes 
 
 Total: 13 Episodes 

 
 
Viewers Also Bought
 
 It&apos;s Always Sunny In Philadelphia Season 7 View In iTunes 
 
 How I Met Your Mother Season 7 View In iTunes 
 
 30 Rock Season 6 View In iTunes 
 
 The Office Season 8 View In iTunes 
 
 Community Season 3 View In iTunes 
 
Customer Reviews
 
 Nick Kroll makes this show           
 by
 
 FXFaithful 
The other cast members are also amazingly hilarious but Ruxin really steals the show for me.
 
 Best Show on T.V. Period!!           
 by
 
 Kevin Blake 
I check out the first episode of the 1st season and just fell in love with the show. This show is insanely hilarious!! Its laughs, laughs on top of laughs. The characters work so well together on screen and Ruxin&apos;s swag is on mars!!
 
 SHOW IS THE SHIZNIT!!!           
 by
 
 ACS1977 
Been watching since the very first episode and this has to be my favorite show of all time!!! They never miss a beat and kick this season off right!! All the characters are at their best!!!
 View In iTunes $29.99 
 HD Version Genre: Comedy Released: Oct 06, 2011 © 2011 Bluebush Productions, LLC. All rights reserved. CC in English 
 
In SD

 
 The League Season 3 
 
 
Customer Ratings
           239 Ratings 
More Seasons

 
 The League, Season 2 View In iTunes 
 
 The League, Season 1 View In iTunes 
 
 
Become a fan of the iTunes and App Store pages on Facebook for exclusive offers, the inside scoop on new apps and more.
 
 Home iTunes 
 
iTunes

 Download iTunes 10 What is iTunes? What’s on iTunes iTunes Charts A-Z Features How Tos 
 
More iTunes

 Digital Music Basics iTunes Ping AirPlay iTunes Gifts iPod + iTunes Support Accessibility 
 
Partner Programs

 Partner as a Company Partner as a Content Provider Join the Affiliate Program Linking Tools iTunes LP and iTunes Extras App Store Volume Purchase 
 
iTunes Store

 Browse iTunes Store Browse App Store Buy Music Now Buy iTunes Gift Cards Redeem iTunes Gift Cards iTunes Corporate Sales Free Single of the Week Inside iTunes 
 
Shop the Apple Online Store (1-800-MY-APPLE), visit an Apple Retail Store , or find a reseller .

 Apple Info Site Map Hot News RSS Feeds Contact Us 
 
Copyright © 2011 Apple Inc. All rights reserved.

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
