<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004945" url="http://wikitravel.org/en/Peddler%27s_Village" time="2012-07-12-21:27" support="1" score="0.00018215347550320165" bingtitle="Peddler&apos;s Village travel guide - Wikitravel" webtitle="Peddler&apos;s Village travel guide - Wikitravel">
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="111"/>
	<description>It is a wonderful place to go if you want to spend a day or a weekend shopping, dining, and ... Coming from New York City--Take the New Jersey Turnpike to Newark Airport Exit ...</description>
	<body>
		Help Wikitravel grow by contributing to an article. Learn how . 
Peddler&apos;s Village
 From Wikitravel Mid-Atlantic : Pennsylvania : Philadelphia Region : Bucks County : Peddler&apos;s Village Jump to: navigation , search 
 
 
Contents
 
 Get in Get around [+] See 
 Annual Events 
 Do Buy Eat Drink Sleep Contact Get out 

 
 
 Peddler&apos;s Village is in Bucks County , Pennsylvania .

Peddler&apos;s Village, a small town located in Lahaska and near New Hope holds 75 years of history. It is a wonderful place to go if you want to spend a day or a weekend shopping, dining, and lodging.&apos;

 [ edit ] Get in 

The best way to get into Peddler&apos;s Village, if from Pennsylvania, is to drive. However, if you decide to fly, plan to arrive at the Philadelphia International Airport and take the train to Willow Grove.

 Coming from New York City-- Take the New Jersey Turnpike to Newark Airport Exit to Route 78 West to Route 287 South to Somerville. 
Get on Route 202 South, and Peddler&apos;s Village is located at the intersection of Route 202 and Street Road.

 Coming from Trenton, New Jersey Take 95 South to Pennsylvania. Get off at Exit 51--New Hope. 
Turn right onto Taylorsville Road. Follow Taylorsville Road to Route 32 North. 
Turn left onto Route 32 North and follow to New Hope. 
Make a left at the first traffic light onto Bridge Street (this is also Route 179 South). 
Continue straight on Route 179 South to Route 202 South. Turn left onto 202 South and follow to Street Road.

 Coming from Philadelphia Area Take Route 476 to the PA Turnpike toward New Jersey. 
Get off at Exit 343--Willow Grove. 
Stay to the right after the toll onto 611 North. 
Turn right at the light at Street Road.
Make left on Route 263 North.
Bear left to Route 263 North to Peddler&apos;s Village.

 [ edit ] Get around 

Once arriving in Peddler&apos;s Village, the best way to get around is on foot. If you are driving, there is a parking lot to park your car, free of charge. Everything is located in a close proximity and in walking distance.

 [ edit ][ add listing ] See 

 [ edit ] Annual Events 

From September 10, 2007 to Sunday, October 28, 2007, be sure to see the Annual Scarecrow Competition&amp;Display . Admission is free, and you will get the chance to see some of the best and creative scarecrow presentations.

Also see the Grand Illumination Celebration on November 16, 2007. This is Peddler&apos;s Village lighting ceremony, which marks the beginning of the holiday season. The lights will be turned on at 6:15PM, so don&apos;t miss it!

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Do 

Year-round, there is much more to do than see at Peddler&apos;s Village. There are many stores to shop in, restaurants to dine and drink in, and a lodge to relax and sleep in.

Also, if the boutiques aren&apos;t enough for you, don&apos;t miss out on the Penn&apos;s Purchase Outlet Mall located conveniently across the street from Peddler&apos;s Village!

 Penn&apos;s Purchase Outlet Stores , [1] .  edit 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Buy 

Peddler&apos;s Village offers over 70 shops. From art and culture to fashion to home decor, each shop meets the needs and wants of its guests.

 A Touch of Britain North Star Gallery Gail West Leather Jewelry Connection The Village Toy and Doll Shoppe Penn&apos;s Purchase Outlets , [2] . M-Sat 10-8, Sun 10-6 . Located across the street from Peddler&apos;s Village.   edit 




 [ edit ][ add listing ] Eat 

From casual to upscale, a guest visiting Peddler&apos;s Village has a broad choice of dining selections.

 Cock &apos;n Bull , 215-794-4000. The village staple for 45 Years, the Cock &apos;n Bull has been serving traditional American dishes like steaks, seafood, and even the classic Chicken Pot Pie. An all-you-can-eat buffet of beef and seafood is featured on Thursdays. A Sunday brunch buffet is offered every Sunday morning from 9:30AM-2PM, and Sunday dinner ends at 9PM. M-Sa 11AM-10PM. 

 Make sure you stop by Earl&apos;s Prime to enjoy sophisticated steak and seafood. With live jazz music on weekends, enjoy your experience of consuming some of the finest dishes. Lunch is not served on Sunday, but from Monday through Saturday lunch is served from 11am to 4pm. Dinner hours also vary. From Monday through Thursday, you can enjoy dinner between the hours of 3pm and 10pm. On Fridays and Saturdays, dinner runs from 4pm to 11pm. Sunday dinner hours are 1pm to 9pm. 

 Contact Earl&apos;s Prime at 215-794-4020. 

 Murder Mystery Dinner Theater ends December 31, 2007, so hurry up and make your reservations. It is located at the Peddler&apos;s Pub and the cost is $45 which includes the dinner, show, tax, and gratuity. Casually dressed, help solve a murder mystery case while indulging in a delicious dinner. (Fridays and Saturdays only.) 

 The contact telephone number for this event is 215-794-4000. 

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Drink 

To have some drinks or a casual lunch, stop by Hart&apos;s Tavern , which serves not only cocktails, but pizza, nachos, and burgers.

 The Peddler&apos;s Pub , where the Murder Mystery Dinner takes place, is also a good place to have a meal and cocktails. 

Most of Peddler&apos;s Village&apos;s dining facilities offer Children&apos;s Menus.

 [ edit ][ add listing ] Sleep 

 The Golden Plough Inn ,Route 202&amp;Street Road, Lahaska, 215-794-4004. Has 70 rooms, and helps a guest to satisfy his or her relaxation needs. Many of the rooms have fireplaces and spa-like bathtubs. Upon arrival to your room, you will be presented with champagne and a snack basket. The Peddler&apos;s Village might have only one place to rest your head, but it is cozy and also created to have an 18th century style. 

 [ edit ] Contact 

For further information on shopping, dining, lodging, events and directions, Peddler&apos;s Village&apos;s Hospitality Center will be more than happy to answer all of your questions. The helpful representatives will be available from 9am to 8pm and can be reached at 215-794-4051 .

 [ edit ] Get out 

Close in distance to Peddler&apos;s Village is Philadelphia , which is home to many historical and modern attractions, sporting events, restaurants and shops.




 This article is an outline and needs more content. It has a template , but there is not enough information present. Please plunge forward and help it grow ! 
 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://wikitravel.org/en/Peddler%27s_Village &quot; Category : Outline articles 
Personal tools

 Log in / create account 
 
Namespaces

 Page Discussion 
 
 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main Page Project Home Travellers&apos; Pub Recent changes Random page Help Uploads&amp;bug reports Wikitravel Extra 
 
feeds
 
 Travel news and trivia 
 
Destination Docents
 
 About Docents 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Special pages Printable version Permanent link 
 
In other languages
 

 
other sites
 
 Wikipedia 
 
 This page was last modified on 16 October 2008, at 04:23. Text is available under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 , images are available under various licenses , see each image for details. 

 Privacy policy About Wikitravel Terms of use
	</body>
</document>
