<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004157" url="http://blogs.ocweekly.com/stickaforkinit/2012/02/mcstinkynigger_landmark_steakh.php" time="2012-07-12-20:24" support="42" score="0.09977321458492532" bingtitle="Case of the &quot;McStinkyNigger&quot; Orange County Restaurant Receipt ..." webtitle="Case of the &quot;McStinkyNigger&quot; Orange County Restaurant Receipt Settles - Orange County Restaurants and Dining - Stick a Fork In It">
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001215" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000552" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001055" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000115" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>... steakhouse that repeatedly listed him on credit card receipts as ... In December, an Irvine fast-food restaurant gave two Asian Americans order receipts that referred to them ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Navel Gazing Moxley Confidential Ask a Mexican Archives Search OC Weekly Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Hey, You! Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Music Home Music Blog Ask Exene Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Food Blog Find a Restaurant Reviews Menus Deals Happy Hours Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Arts Features Theater Trendzilla OC Bookly Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Film Blog Film Festivals Film Poll 2011 Showtimes Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2011 2010 2009 2008 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Alternative Healing MMJ Home MMJ News Ask a Lawyer The Rolling Paper Coupons Dispensary Guide MMJ Newsletter 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 News 

 IRS Nabs Santa Ana Restaurant Owner 

By R. Scott Moxley
 
 Bargains 

 Free Slurpees on 7-11...at 7-11! 

By Edwin Goei
 
 Chain Reactions 

 Red Robin to Introduce Ghost Pepper Burger 

By Edwin Goei
 
 Food Festivals 

 Go To Tijuana This Weekend for TWO Craft Beer Fests! 

By Dave Lieberman
 
 Mexi Meals 

 How They Market Mexican Food in England! 

By Gustavo Arellano
 
 100 Favorite Dishes 2012 

 That&apos;s Some Good Pig Snout! 

By Shuji Sakai
 
 Hops to It! 

 New Bruery Tasting Room Now Open! 

By Anne Marie Panoringan
 
 Chain Reactions 

 Secrets of McDonald&apos;s Revealed! 

By Michelle Woo
 
 Five Great... 

 5 Great Things To Make With Spam 

By Michelle Woo
 
 Mexi Meals 

 [INFOGRAPHIC] 11 Facts About Tapatio 

By Gustavo Arellano
 
   Really?!?!? 
Case of the &quot;McStinkyNigger&quot; Orange County Restaurant Receipt Settles
 By R. Scott Moxley Mon., Feb. 13 2012 at 3:44 PM Categories: Indigestion , News , Really?!?!? 
 Pin It 
 
 Landmark Steakhouse McSettles after racist receipts 
​ A federal lawsuit filed by a successful African-American businessman against a Newport Beach steakhouse that repeatedly listed him on credit card receipts as &quot; McStinkyNigger ,&quot; &quot; McNigShit &quot; and &quot; McCottonwood &quot; has been mutually dismissed, according to records at Ronald Reagan Federal Courthouse in Orange County.

Court files show that lawyers representing plaintiff Mark McHenry and Landmark Steakhouse of Corona del Mar agreed to a stipulated settlement of the lawsuit on Feb. 2 -- a month before the case was scheduled to be heard by a jury.
 
No terms of the settlement were revealed. But you can guess any payment 
to McHenry is going to be financially substantial. It is against federal
 law for a public business to brazenly discriminate against a customer 
based on race. 
And there was this: The 10-month-old case ended after 
McHenry&apos;s lawyers at Reed Smith LLP in Los Angeles uncovered an additional 12 inflammatory examples of racists 
comments and after U.S. Magistrate Judge Victor B. Kenton rejected the restaurant&apos;s strenuous attempts to thwart the lawyers from inspecting 167,000 other customer receipts to check for a systematic, widespread use of racial epithets.

In a deposition, Mario Marovic , a partial owner of CDM Restaurant, Inc. which includes Landmark Steakhouse, said that he does not &quot;discriminate against any group of people on any basis whatsoever.&quot;

The court files reviewed by the Weekly show that Marovic was shocked by McHenry&apos;s allegations, conducted an 
investigation and ultimately blamed the racist incidents on a bartender, Michael Cederoth . Though Cederoth did not confess, Marovic 
believed he&apos;d given &quot;inconsistent&quot; answers during interviews and fired 
him a week after the lawsuit was filed, according to court records.

A
 customer during dozens and dozens of visits, 
McHenry had considered the restaurant enjoyable, took friends there and 
was a generous tipper. After one visit he returned home, saw an 
inflammatory receipt and discovered older receipts were similarly 
despicable . When confronted, restaurant employees including manager Dustin Caratello repeatedly apologized and attempted to downplay the 
bigotry, according to court records.

 
 What likely would have been Exhibit A in an upcoming federal trial. 
​ 
At the time of the McHenry incidents, the Orange County Young Republicans chose Landmark Steakhouse as their &quot;favorite spot&quot; for monthly drink mixers. We know this because both sides in the litigation tied the group to the dispute in their official filings, and the federal judge noted their presence as well, according to court records.

 Just weeks after McHenry filed his lawsuit, an elected member of the Orange County Republican Party emailed fellow Republicans a doctored photograph of Barack Obama that portrayed the president and his parents as chimpanzees .

Obama is scheduled to attend a Thursday Corona del Mar campaign event just blocks away from the Landmark Steakhouse.

 In December, an Irvine fast-food restaurant gave two Asian Americans order receipts that referred to them as &quot;Ching&quot; and &quot;Chong.&quot; 

 Follow Stick a Fork In It on Twitter  @ocweeklyfood  or on  Facebook ! And don&apos;t forget to download our free Best Of App here ! 

 --R. Scott Moxley / OC Weekly 

(email: rscottmoxley at ocweekly dot com)
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Barack Obama , bigotry , CDM Restaurants , Ching , Chong , Corona del Mar , Landmark Steakhouse , Mario Marovic , Mark McHenry , Michael Cederoth , Newport Beach , Orange County restaurants , Orange County Young Republicans , racial epithets , racist , Reed Smith LLP , Ronald Reagan Federal Courthouse Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Thank you for publishing this story.  This kind of action needs to be known about and talked about and for everyone to see and hear about it.  Absolutely, McHenry had to go back again and again.  The whole point is that, well I can only speak for myself, I don&apos;t want people to be excluded because of skin color.  Yes, even in a privately owned restaurant.
 
You know what is really sad? This guy gave was a regular customer and got this kind of treatment despite his generous tips ;(  Anyways, business is business. Don&apos;t ever make a paying customer feel unwelcome.
 
why he tip them still tho?
 
Im not racist, I just observe, that server should go to jail for hate crimes
 
He left a.good tip...... I&apos;d understand if he didn&apos;t tip, I&apos;d never do that, but where I&apos;m from 3 white tables outta a full resturant is the norm, and getting tipped 0-5% from African Americans is the norm even to African-American servers, I dunno if they don&apos;t know we only make $2 an hr.....I really don&apos;t.think they care, but its sad to have $500 in sales and leave w/ less than $20, usually $10-$15 after tipout......yeah we have to.give.our tips to ,.foodrunners, bartenders, busboys, and hostess
.......yeah so when we should leave w/ $150 we get 10%, now 10 to15% of African-Americans do tip! some nights I thank god for them when they make up for the other ppl who haven&apos;t , they aren&apos;t the only bad tippers, red necks don&apos;t tip if they do its coin change, canadians don&apos;t tip a dime, servers make $10 hr in Canada.........Jus my obervation after 10 yrs serving in south Carolina........sad
 
i dont understand why or how they were able to add that to the receipt. is that what they typed instead of table number or bar stool number? if thats the case then it&apos;s pretty unnecessary. if this guy was a regular they should have known his name of maybe his favorite food and could have jokingly labeled him&quot;ribs&quot;or&quot;hamburger&quot;or whatever. also have none of you people posting looked at the $10 tip he gave?
 
Why should he have to? Here&apos;s the thing: I&apos;d leave as soon as this treatment started but the offending party should not be in a position to treat people like that. I&apos;m sure that the owner wants the business so basically the employee is the only wildcard. They are the one who doesn&apos;t take their job seriously enough to do it right and with respect for the customers who keep them employed.
 
So much for California being progressive.
 
Are you illiterate?&quot;After one visit he returned home,saw an inflammatory receipt and discovered older receipts were similarly despicable.&quot;
 
Racism in Newport Beach?  No way.  Can&apos;t you fools stick to wearing Affliction and getting tattoos of barbed wire?  Dorks.
 
Unbelievable!
 
This just makes me sick. I can&apos;t believe that in this day and time some ignorant jerk thinks he can get away with this type of behavior! I have seen racism happen on both sides of the color lines -- but it&apos;s real origin is pure evil.
 
All due respect here - it was probably the&quot;rogue&quot;bartender at fault and not the restaurant in general.  Is this, or the Ching and Chong thing really all that racist?  I&apos;ll acknowledge that it was very stupid for the employees to type those&quot;slurs&quot;into their computer system.  Shit man, I joke around and say the word&quot;nigga,&quot;but I&apos;m not a racist, nor would I discriminate against someone of another race in hiring someone, or for any other reason.  Should we lighten up a little and stop being so overly PC?  It&apos;s not like they told they guy&quot;Get out, we don&apos;t serve black people in this establishment...&quot;Well, just my $0.02 - and don&apos;t call me a racist - my wife is Filipino for crying out loud!  And come on - we have to admit that most racist jokes are pretty funny... aren&apos;t they??
 
Amen Baby
Get your facts together. The bartender was WHITE. HELLO to you jerkoff
 
Eh, I hope he didn&apos;t get TOO mujch money.
He deserves legal fees plus $65 total.

African Americans tend to be VERY sensitive and whiney about these kind of things.
I was at Popeyes once and an African American employee called me a &apos;cracker&apos;.

Did I sue? No. Because I&apos;m better than that.

But I could have. Hopefully this restaurant didn&apos;t have to pay any more than legal fees + the cost of the meal...

Then again our courts, police, judges, and politicians are corrupt. So they probably had to pay a ridiculous amount.


Either way next time I hear the word &apos;cracker&apos; directed in my direction. You can expect a lawsuit :)
 
Pull your head outta your ass.
 
so your saying the n word has nothing to do with slavery?????....have you looked up the definition and the origin of the word
 
Seriously? in this day in time??? Some days I&apos;m embarrassed to be white.
 
just sue them then u will be nigga rich
 
Funny...We, ASIANS  are considered CHING AN CHONG  because of our chinita eyes.!!!  am not offended anyway...Ching and Chong are good MATHEMATICIANS unlike that stupid AMERICAN MONKEY who got us named to a such...&apos;funny names or words.&apos;
 
here is the sad truth of the matter - the &apos;man&apos; has always been able to get minorities to fight amongst yourselves.  this was seen as black overseers were often as cold and cruel as the slave owners.  as soon as you figure out that you are doing what &apos;the man&apos; wants you to and say okay i&apos;m done being a puppet, maybe there will be more minorities in positions of power willing to follow their own agendas and not the man&apos;s.  cheers dave
 
Didn&apos;t you read the article Mitch? He&apos;s suing their butts off, the offending server was fired (hope your little&quot;joke&quot;was worth it, jerk-face), and he still wants to eat there. If you walk away from this they&apos;ll do it to the next, and the next, and the next. They didn&apos;t burn his cheeseburger, you nim-rod, they called him a nigger. That you don&apos;t see the difference is just sad. Good thing they didn&apos;t serve you. It&apos;ll print out McMoron, too!
 
are you kidding me?!!!...these are NOT minor insults!!!
 
so as long as a nigger is calling a nigger a nigger that&apos;s acceptable?
 
I think the customer went back over and over in order to save these comments on his bill as evidence for a nice settlement.
 
I am wondering if A, he saw the comments and continued to go to the place in order to get a nice settlement. B, he did something to piss off a waitress or some other obnoxious behavour (which still doesn&apos;t justify the comments) There&apos;s more to this story than we&apos;re hearing. Who ever wrote this on his bill is a total moron anyway and taints all the other employees.
 
Tip is nice, but he must have seriously upset the bartender and probably other staff. Something&apos;s up with this story that the knucklehead race-baiting reporter won&apos;t mention.
 
You make some great points but I must mention the fact that you are wrong about no other country having niggers only blacks. The truth is there is no such thing as blacks, they are ALL niggers where ever they group. You just need to widen your news sources.
Both Canada, Paris and England are experiencing the same nigger problems we are if not worse because they are all much more liberal.
 
You know I&apos;m reading these comments and I&apos;m ashamed! WE ALL have prejudice of some sort. But to blatantly be disrespectful to someone is IGNORANT! We all say horrible nasty things about people behind their back. Dont lie.
For those that say the gentle man needs to get a thick skin-screw you! When youve been called  McStinkyNigger,&quot;&quot;McNigShit&quot;and&quot;McCottonwood, basically the N word. How often or on what day should this be ignored?! We turn our head ignore alot. Sometimes, I just dont feel like it. Now if he had of responded by confronting or fighting. Then it would have been &apos;oh, another dumb,ghetto ass black man. Stop the madness, we do right by the law were wrong. We do wrong its whats expected.
 
Not only is the bartender a racist, he does not know how to treat a customer who tips almost 20%...
 
Funny. As.  Hell.
 
How come the bartender didn&apos;t get punched right away? Smth is fishy!
 
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RVSOOBQB6I0
 
You mean like he did.He went and whined to the judge.
 
In your case it would read Mr. Asshole!
 
John in a case recently a black guy from New york City sell some weed to this white guy he knew for his own personal use.The white guy soon went away to college i dont remember where maybe upstate new york, or jersy or Boston he would come back some weekends to buy weed for his personal use but after a while he started selling some.He soon started asking the black guy for more weed cocaine and pills which the black guy did not have because he only sold a little weed. The black guy did not have any of this but being in New york City where such thing are not to hard to acquire he asked some question and procured some as a favor to this guy.The white guy now dealing large on campus got caught.He then set the black guy up and asked him to deliver a larger quantity of drugs than he ever ordered before and a variety of drugs.And had the guy deliver as a favor to him these drugs which he normally came to ny to get because they wanted the black guy to come to the area in which his arresting officers had jurisdiction.There the black guy was arrested and charged.The black guy ends up getting several years in prison and the white guy got probation.This story i read in the New York Times.Studies have shown that when black and whites go before judges for the same offenses blacks most times receive much harsher sentences and the whites receive counseling and probation etc especially in drug cases. These things are facts.
 
The negro received treatment comensurate with its skin color.
 
The gratuitous comment about Republicans emailing a picture of Obama made to look like a chimp brings to mind how Democrats did precisely the same thing with Bush Jr.
 
I regret that you cannot legislate racism out of existance. I also dont believe taking people to court every time a disparaging remark is made will improve racial tensions. If i make a remark against a black i am labled a racist, its labled a hate crime and i am subject to severe financial penalties. What happened to freedom of speach? I don&apos;t have to like what is said but everyone should have the right to make stupid comments without the courts getting involved.
 
Oh yea @rebeccarhenry I feel your pain .... All that racism&amp;bigotry I&apos;ve been subjected to as a white person ... Woe is me&lt;note the sarcasm&gt;
 
@Roman ... I&apos;m white. I live in LA. I&apos;ve lived in predominantly black or Latino neighborhoods for the past 15 years and countless times have been the only white person in an establishment. No one has ever&quot;glared&quot;or&quot;snarled&quot;at me, called me names or printed mcwhitey on any of my receipts. You must be living in a hypothetical world where whites were enslaved and then systematically discriminated against for generations. News flash dude: you are coming from a place of privilege, don&apos;t try to pretend that a racial slur projected at you or I is equally harmful in a world where there still so much racial inequality being perpetrated by morons like you.
 
Hahahahahahahahaha Mcstinkynigger! Thats as classy as it gets. If i was a nigger and a server gave me that receipt i would laugh and tip him extra for makin me laugh. People are way to sensitive these days
 
It is obvious that the intelligence level on this little blog is zero. However, I will leave you with this little bit of info:

Racism has been fueled in this country since the civil rights movement by the media. It will never end until we stop letting it run our social world. There will always be stupid people that cannot get over a persons skin color. However, why continue to divide people with stuff like&quot;50% of black people feel that OJ is not guilty while 75% of white people think he is guilty&quot;. Those numbers are false, but this is exactly how the media broke it down. Whycan&apos;t we say&quot;60% of Americans feel that OJ is guilty&quot;and leave race out of it. Remember the story about the black teens down south (I think Alabama) that died because they couldnt swim and all the adults couldnt swim to save them.The media took the story in the dirction of how many black people couldnt swim vesus white people. What the heck does that have to do with anything. Another example was a story about how disperity in dental coverage between blacks and whites is why blacks have trouble in school. They cannot concentrate because of dental pain. Really, you have to be racist or a complete moron to think that holds any kind or reality. WISE UP AMERICA, STOP RACISM BY FIGHTIN THE MEDIA BIAS&gt;TAKE THE FIGHT TO THE MEDIA. WE ARE ALL AMERICANS!!!
 
Now, I agree it&apos;s wrong, but why would he continue to go to a place that made him uncomfortable. And technically, if they served him with the same prices they served other people then they technically didn&apos;t discriminate.
 
IF SOMEONE DOES THE SAME TO MITCH MOM LIKE&quot;PINCHE PUTA BARATA PEDORRA&quot;I AM SURE HE WILL ACT VERY NORMAL AND WALK AWAY.............
 
he shouldn&apos;t have to walk out. And if a server insulted you in this manner they deserve more than for you to walk out, they deserve to be fired. Besides it&apos;s ILLEGAL
 
and he still tipped them! now thats class
 
Kind of strange all this stuff is happening in California - land of everyone loves everyone.
 
@ andy t: i really hope you&apos;re not serious. you&apos;re an idiot.
 
if it were an isolated incident i can see your point of view. but to find that this happened repeatedly and not just to you is a sign of widespread racsism, or at best ignorance. it is not ok to use that sort of language in a professional atmosphere, let alone anywhere, and he did the right thing by taking the steps he did.
 
evryones replys are so long i just want to say amen
 
Ignorance is bliss
 
Thanks!
 
Pandejo, skinhead, circlejerk, but dont soil our conversation... Lmao.  High brow stuff from a moderator.
 
There&apos;s nothing wrong with a word - nigger - so what? But for a customer to be called _anything_ he doesn&apos;t like, is inconsiderate.
 
Another non-reader of such a simple story of racism. The guy didn&apos;t see the racist comments until after he got home. I can assure you he didn&apos;t go back to eat once he read what was on the receipts....DUH
 
Well maybe he stinks, I don&apos;t know but now I know that you for sure stink!
 
Apparently there is still room for it one of GR82BYT&apos;S three businesses~
 
You sir are a Whitey, Cracker, Honky, Red Neck, WT loser, Hill-billy, Okie, Arkie, hobo! OK, so do we have a problem?
 
Correct, that&apos;s why McHenry sued the owner  :)
 
Um @Mike, didn&apos;t you read the article? It clearly says McHenry didn&apos;t see the nastiness on the receipt until after he got home.
 
I have a hard time taking a post seriously that begins,&quot;First of all, I sick of the black community trying to make all white people responsible for slavery.&quot;All I can say is that I sick of this idiotic argument too. What, you think this is an enlightened view? Think again. No one is trying hold living white people responsible for slavery, we&apos;re trying to hold you responsible for your actions now.
 
Maybe that&apos;s why try as I might, I just can&apos;t respect Harley8619
 
Hey GR82BPU-trid, What, were you Heinrich Himmler in a past life? Your spelling is passable for a 3rd grader, your argument is beyond stupid.
Good luck on hiring only white people in your three businesses, what did you say their names were? If you had even just one testicle you&apos;d put your $ where your pie-hole is and tell us all the names of these three thriving establishments  :)
I am thinking a business you&apos;d like would be&quot;Cletus&apos; the Slack-jawed Yokel Whitewashing LLC&quot;or&quot;Bubba&apos;s Monster Truck Accessories&quot;or&quot;Adolf&apos;s Geneology for White Folks.&quot;
 
I am disgusted with so many of these comments!!  it is 2012, anyone who has a problem with people of a different background(for that reason only) need to go back to the hole they crawled out of!!  get a life you hateful SOB&apos;s!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
 
Irish porch-monkeys can be extremely dangerous. always use caution when you see one creepin&apos; up. let&apos;s just hope he does somthing resposible with the windfall.like maybe a new caddie with pink fur on the dash and a big purple swan on the hood. but hey, good for you Sir. only in America can ya get that kinda green for a receipt malfunction. I would&apos;ve sued the shit outta them cracka-ass-crackas. but my case would&apos;ve been laughed out of court for being called Mr McHonkey.
 
I like ur comment Kayt,There are too many racist ppl in the world. Im from Canada, and we are not like the Americans; regarding the blacks and the mexicans. I have two sons who moved to the USA and they have changed so much in their attatudes towards racism, and not good ones either! I often have arguments with them over that specific subject!! They were not raised like that, and it upsets me to no end when they start that crap!! I cant believe the difference between Canada and USA regarding racism. What it comes down to is bad Kharma, what goes around, comes around ppl,I feel sorry for you!
 
Don&apos;t ever write a comment as dumb as this one please. you just wasted 2 seconds of my valuable time. wow, free speech?? wtf??
 
so happy he sued them! Yup, you hire a racist who gives racist service to your customers, you should pay. It&apos;s not having a&quot;thin skin.&quot;It&apos;s sticking it to those assholes who take our money while laughing behind our backs. And it&apos;s a form of justice. That bartender deserved to be fired from here to the moon!
 
lol GR82BSTUPID as smart as u think u are ur as dumb as that bartender. hang yourself
 
GR82BYT.....that&apos;s the real cakifornia issued lincense plate on my BLACK truck. I AM a white male racist.....It&apos;s my choice. I think I am better than any black, brown, yellow, or red person out there. NOT because I&apos;m WHITE, just becasue I&apos;m me :). I don&apos;t suffer from low self-esteem or guilt for the rich culture that I come from, nor do I think anyone else should. Unfortunatly the history of this country had a little problem called&quot;slavery&quot;. Wasn&apos;t my idea, wouldn&apos;t say that I&apos;d want to be one, or own one for that matter. But it happened in this country. America is the ONLY country to have niggers in it, other countries have black people. Not my fault, not my rules, just the way it is. As a white man in America I have/had some serious advantages over others. I didn&apos;t ask for them, but again, its the way it was. I&apos;m sure if I went to China I&apos;d have a hard time getting a job or a place to live as I&apos;d be the outsider there. Unfortunatly the term&quot;racist&quot;is easily apllied to white people, while many Asians, Latinos, etc. have just as strong feeling about other races. Heck Latinos from the north hate lations from the south....I don&apos;t get it, but that&apos;s their culture and there choice. To me it&apos;s all very simple, Dogs will always chase cats, just part of nature, one color of human will always have issues with a different color. maybe not always,  but many times. I don&apos;t think it make anyone&quot;ignorant&quot;, which is ALWAYS the buzz word when it comes to race, I think it just make people different. As long as we&apos;re not killing each other, who cares??? If I own a business (I actually own several) why shouldn&apos;t I be able to hire only white people? Every seen anyone other than a Chinese person working in a Chinese resturant? Didn&apos;t think so. Ever seen a a black Sushi chef? Doubt it.....I don&apos;t see that as a problem, just a fact. We don&apos;t all need to love each other, and that fact that we choose not to, doesn&apos;t make us ignorant, it makes us normal, which may turn out to be the biggest thing we all have in common.....
 
you are all stupid. if you got a reciept that said mccracker or mcwhitey or mrnazi you would have done the same thing. get paid.
 
I have read ignorant comments before but yours has to be an insult to intelligent life on earth. Go back to your trailer, you don&apos;t deserve to have access to a computer. Fuckin clown.
 
OUT OF ALL THE COMMENTS I READ I HAVE COME TO ONLY ONE CONCLUSION...ANDY T IS A RACIST INBRED.
 
Yoohoo.  I agree with your statement for the most part....that (some) blacks still blame today&apos;s white society for the injustices of our ancestors and claim that&apos;s the cause of todays circumstances of SOME of their black brothers and sisters. To blame the current white populace for what our ancestors did 150 years ago is not only un-realistic, it&apos;s unfair. &apos;WE&apos; had nothing to do with it! There are a myriad of &apos;today&apos;s blacks&apos; that made it &apos;big&apos; through their own efforts and determination...Oprah Winfrey, Colin Powell, Bill Cosby, Condoleezza Rice, Tyra Banks, Beyonce Knowles, Will Smith... to name but a very few. They didn&apos;t blame white society or our ancestor&apos;s practice of slavery, and sit on their hineys and cry &apos;foul&apos;. They went to school and studied and worked hard and made their own way up &apos;the ladder of success&apos;. And if you want to talk &apos;racism&apos; there are still a lot of &apos;anti-white&apos; predjudices coming from the black communitites.

BUT you could have made your point(s) without the implied &apos;dirty words&apos;.&quot;= )
 
I have been married to a Native American for almost 50yrs and we have also seen people who hated us as I am white, but on the other side my children learned the N word from Black Children they went to school and were neighbers with. Not in the home. I believe that there have been horriable things done to all races and religions since the begginng of time. But hating your neighber because he is differant is just plain stupid. Remember how the Irish were treated? My Stepmother was a Muslim and she was appaled at the way some Muslims acted 9,11 made her cry just like the rest of the world . So come on people we are all Gods children under  skin. Hating anyone because they are differant is just ignorant Maybe we have all seen or felt hate from our fellow man but treat everyone the way you want to be treated and people will treat you the same way.. I live in a Small town and see it everyday but I have traveled all over the world including Africa and have been treated super as thats how I treat people...
 
I cannot find the words to convey just how ignorant that establishment and its employees are. Whatever the settlement was, it could never be enough to regain the dignitythat Mr. McHenry suffered from those ignorant bigots.
 
More power to him he may win a large settlement and bankrupt that place they deserve it a bunch idiots. They probably expected this man just not show up anymore.but he was smart he continued to partronize their business and he also may own it.  Ha
 
Self worth,, bigots ususally try to deflect  by saying what if this happened in a   or what if,, the fact is  it happened in an affluent neighborhood, not some run down slum.  Face it black restaurants relish the thought of having a repeat and loyal customer,,  and yeah  google there have been numerous establishments of minority status sued successfully,, so find another excuse to hide behind racism
 
If he felt he could right this on reciepts ,,he was not the only person to see the receipts,, so therefore it maskes teh restaurant liable also
 
Son your confused ,,donit try to hide your bigotry with intelligience,, try reading what typing before you post it and if it doesnt right then rtype it and try again,, just what are you trying to say,, cause you sound confused and probasbly should take your own advise and STFU
 
As i stated earlier its not a problem until it  hits home with America,, minorities have never and will never be truly considered americans.. America has lived a lie from the beginining ,,,Christopher  Columbus discovered something that was already occupied,,... this country was built  on the backs of many different ethnic groups,, yet the majority of the groups dont enjoy the same freedom that the constitution says we have
 
At age 77 I am amazed by so many of the comments posted here. It is time people start realizing what has made America great and read the words  of our constitution. Prejudices may be natural but when the prejudices turn into actions that try to take away the dignity and respect each person has a right to then it is time for people to pay fines and even go to jail for their stupid behavior. If its any consolation realize that when true equality between people comes it may appear as if things are really getting bad because of all of the confrontations. Actually things are better than ever, it is just that those formerly prejudiced and discriminated against now have the courage to fight for and demand their rights to equality per Rudolf Dreikurs. He has said it happens between many groups as labor and management, teachers and students, rich and poor, etc. etc. I am guessing most of the comments made here are by males between age 9 and 29 and I now believe almost all of them are just crazier than hell and will do almost anything to get attention and approval from their pier groups.
 
fuck the niggers the jails are full of them .put them on a ship and send there ass back
 
wow intelligience speaks,, son of his big sister and uncle
 
In reply to Andy  what whites do is rob entire cooperzations after individuals have worked their entire life,, set up pozai schemes to defraud hard working individual.. and oh yea lets not forget whzt whites really do they dont rape and kill pone individual,, they comitt mass murders  serial killings,, because they didnt get enough attention or daddy like suzy more than me  dont sound stupid and you wont get stupid responces....  incarceration is a form of business in this country,, so tell me why this country has more individuals incarcerated than the rest of the civilized world
 
This is YOUR business?  You want YOUR employees to insult YOUR customers?  This is NO business after awhile.
 
you sede with individuals like mitch its not a problem until it hits in his back yard,, much like the crack epidemic,, not an issue until little susy and joyfull johnny got hooked and stoll all of moms money,,did the establishment see an issue with crack...
 
wow  a guy gets disrespected and called all sort of names yet he still patronises the restaurant.  yet supposedly educated people think the problem lies with him,, the guy who was chased down the street by blacks  hmm,,  and the black prison quote  get your fact straight before you sound even more stupid,,,  Have you forgotten that racism has now been replaced by classism,, you see there are more non minorities in line now for food stamps and welfare than any other race.  And politicians now seem to court the african american and the hispanic race every 4 years  hmm.. nothing new here either...  so the white hoods and suites were replaced by brooks brothers and the wall street,,, but wait  most of you are probably right at or below the poverty line too so you lash out at other people..   good for you go pat yourself on teh back and continue inbreeding
 
......Harley....  and &apos;speek&apos; is actually spelled &apos;speak&apos;. It&apos;s also how well you &apos;speak&apos; and spell the English language that earns you respect....AND credibility!  : = )
 
Totally agreed. And from the looks of the receipt, not only did he tip well but he spent a good amount of money there each visit. Some people just don&apos;t get it, man; you can&apos;t bring your personal views to a professional establishment, especially if it depends on your livelihood.
 
An actual slave&apos;s experience. There are many more like this recorded.

(1) Ottobah Cugoano, Narrative of the Enslavement of a Native of Africa (1787)I was early snatched away from my native country, with about eighteen or twenty more boys and girls, as we were playing in a field. We lived but a few days&apos; journey from the coast where we were kidnapped, and consigned to Grenada. Some of us attempted, in vain, to run away, but pistols and cutlasses were soon introduced, threatening, that if we offered to stir, we should all lie dead on the spot. 
We were soon led out of the way which we knew, and towards evening, as we came in sight of a town. I was soon conducted to a prison, for three days, where I heard the groans and cries of many, and saw some of my fellow-captives. But when a vessel arrived to conduct us away to the ship, it was a most horrible scene; there was nothing to be heard but the rattling of chains, smacking of whips, and the groans and cries of our fellow-men. Some would not stir from the ground, when they were lashed and beat in the most horrible manner.

Yes, some of them were indeed kidnapped, and some were sold. Either way, it was wrong and a painful and horrible experience for MANY!!!
 
America is not the land of the&quot;free&quot;nor the home of the&quot;brave&quot;.  If so why do so many hide behind racism and hate?  What if I may ask does anyone get out of either of the two?  Being a RACIST on shows how much you fear someone and how ignorant you are.  Why not take the time to get to know someone (the content of their character) and judge them by that?  Why not help if you have the means to or the knowledge?  If knowledge is power why do so many fear other&apos;s obtaining it ?  I think it is because you may figure out I&apos;m not the person I wanted you to believe I was and then I&apos;m exposed for who I really am.  Just treat everyone the way you want to be treated and the world we live in will be a much better place.
 
In reply to Notarace...
Did you even read the article??  He is a SUCCESSFUL businessman...he doesn&apos;t need a free ride because he SUCCESSFULLY earns his ride.&quot;Don&apos;t have to work (which I never did anyway)&quot;...again SUCCESSFUL BUSINESSMAN.  (And&quot;habit&quot;only has one&quot;b&quot;)
 
However, illegal immigration is, well, illegal. It&apos;s unfair to call citizens WHO PAY TAXES racist because we want EVERYONE to come into the country legal.  Most do not have a problem with hispanics here legally, just the illegal.
 
Many of the people commenting on this site seem to be just as intelligent as the people working at the Landmark Restaurant.  If they are foolish enough to put their bigotry in writing then they deserve to be taken to court.
 
Azielysrayl you are so stupid. black ppl never even knew about christianity until white ppl taught it to them as slaves. the bible came to us in hebrew and greek, definately nt african languages.christianity is white mans religion.stupid blks
 
Darrell..Very good point. However, the man should have complained at the very first incident and not let it go on.  I sure would have! The kind of behavior displayed by that server should not be allowed in any public place. Key word here is &apos;public&apos;...i.e., having nothing to do with race or ethnicity. However, I must agree with an earlier post where someone said that (some) blacks still depend on the injustices their ancestors endured to (try) to gain sympathy and/or &apos;unearned benefits&apos; from the &apos;white&apos; society as a whole. I am a white American, with some Cherokee blood. I married a Hispanic (natural born citizen of the US). I taught all five of my &apos;mixed heritage&apos; children to judge people, not by the color of their skin or the shape of their eyes, but by the CHARACTER they display. I think the world would be a better place if everyone would follow that advice.
 
Wait until you become a victim of blacks then see how you feel
 
Its not hate because of skin color its because of what the color denotes.
 

TotalComments: 100
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 The Bruery&apos;s New Tasting Room Grand Opening Umami Burger Anaheim Grand Opening Gringo Bandito Taco Eating Challenge @ Chronic Tacos More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 RESTAURANTS 
 
 
Bowlmor
 View Ad | View Site 
Irvine Barclay Theatre
 View Ad | View Site 
Bowlmor
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow ocweeklyfood on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; About Us | Work for OC Weekly | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 OC Weekly, LP. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
