<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0004557" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/healthy-fast-food-options-baby-toddler-445336.html" time="2012-07-12-20:58" support="1" score="0.0006685438377029963" bingtitle="Healthy Fast Food Options for Your Baby or Toddler: Part One ..." webtitle="Healthy Fast Food Options for Your Baby or Toddler:  Part One - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>... to feed your baby or young toddler at a fast food ... When you go out to eat a fast food restaurant with your baby or ... available at Wendy&apos;s is the mandarin orange cup.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
Healthy Fast Food Options for Your Baby or Toddler: Part One
 Emily Harmon , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Jul 19, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Toddlers For You Feeding Your Baby 
 Flag Close Post a comment When you go out to eat a fast food restaurant with your baby or toddler, there aren&apos;t a ton of good choices to feed him or her. If you&apos;re concerned about only feeding your child the &quot;good stuff&quot; there are some options out there that are both healthy and safe for your baby or toddler. Here are some suggestions.
 McDonalds. One of the best options for feeding your baby or toddler at McDonald&apos;s is the fruit and yogurt parfait. As long as your baby is old enough to enjoy yogurt and berries (generally around 10 months) this is a great option. The only drawback is that you have to do the feeding for younger babies since it is quite messy. McDonald&apos;s also has apple dippers which are fresh apple slices with caramel sauce. Just skip the caramel sauce for younger ones. Finally, the snack sized fruit and walnut salad is a good option. Just cut up the apples and grapes for your little one, and serve along with the yogurt. You can enjoy the glazed walnuts yourself.

 Wendy&apos;s. One of the best options available at Wendy&apos;s is the mandarin orange cup. There is little sugar in this healthy choice and the texture is great for toothless babies to &quot;chew.&quot; A baked potato is another option for your little one. You can choose whether or not you want to add a little sour cream for flavor. Skip the salt and butter. Yogurt with granola is a good choice though it will have to be spoon fed for younger ones and the granola may be a little hard to chew for those with no or few teeth. Another option is to get a side salad and let your baby eat the tomatoes and cucumbers off of it, cut into small pieces.

 Taco Bell. Pintos and cheese, minus the red sauce is an option for your baby at Taco Bell. The smooth texture is easy to eat, but be warned that there is a small amount of trans fat in these beans. Another good option is to order a fresco style chicken taco. You can pull apart the chicken pieces and tortilla and serve it along with some of the salsa (you may want to remove the onions). Again, though, there is a small amount of trans fat in the tortilla. Taco bell is one of the least toddler and baby friendly fast food restaurants when it comes to healthy options.

 Arby&apos;s. Arby&apos;s has a few good options just for kids that will also work well for your baby or toddler. The kids&apos; meal fruit cup has fresh grapes and apples that you can just chop into small pieces. They also offer a ham or turkey and cheese sandwich on whole wheat bread, minus the crust. For an older toddler this sandwich works well as is, or for a younger one you can disassemble it and pull into small pieces. Just ask for the sandwich without the mayonnaise and know that the lunchmeat does contain quite a bit of sodium. Also, keep in mind that the bread has honey in it, so skip it for babies under one year old.

While eating at a fast food restaurant can be challenging if you want to only feed your baby or toddler healthy foods, it can be done. Do your research ahead of time and you&apos;ll be armed and ready when you get up to the order counter.
 
Published by Emily Harmon - Featured Contributor in Lifestyle

I am a happily married mom of an elementary school aged boy and toddler girl. I work full time in the education/library field and part time as a crafter/artisan.  View profile 
 
 Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Many fast food restaurants are now offering healthy choices. This means Americans can get their instant satisfaction without receiving a side order of thunder thighs. But, how... Fast-Food Survey Results - Where&apos;s Your Beef? Zagat and the Today Show surveyed 5,535 people to find out who has the best fast-food. Dave would have been proud. Fast Food Calories: Where to Find Them This article helps you find fast food calorie information in your area and compare meals Kick the Fast Food Habit Addicted to fast food?&quot; Here are some ideas to help you beat your addiction. Fast Food Failures What if someone put together a list of all the really bad fast food restaurants? What if that someone was me? 

 Make Your Own Fast Food with No... Product Review: Ore Ida Fast Foo... How to Make a Practical Dog Food 
 
 Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Eat Fast Food and Still Be Healthy Breaking the Fast Food Habit Healthy Fast Food Choices Fast Food is Everywhere in CA What Kind of Fast Food Tonight? How to Stay Safe and Clean in Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 
 Resources 
 
 www.mcdonalds.com 
 
4 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Sherry W 7/20/2007 
Great ideas here! Very good idea for an article.
 Ava Snow 7/20/2007 
Great article !
 Mommy2Lots 7/20/2007 
Great tips. It&apos;s so hard to find healthy options these days. :-)
 Dahloan Hembree 7/20/2007 
We use to get the pintos and cheese at Taco Bell for ours when they were little
 
 Displaying Comments 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
