<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005601" url="http://www.foodservice.com.au/" time="2012-07-12-22:09" support="1" score="0.0021017993864203607" bingtitle="Food Service Guide- food service and hospitality industry guide" webtitle="Food Service Guide- food service and hospitality industry guide">
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>... market, which is growing as more people eat ... food, italian food, chineese food, fast food, fast food restaurant ... Italia were the winners of the 2006 World Cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Bidvest Australia offers the most comprehensive range of products and services to the Australian foodservice market, which is growing as more people eat outside the home due to shifting consumer demands. Bidvest&apos;s strategy remains to create value by focusing on supplying the right product to the customer, at the right price, on time. The management and staff are all passionate about service and entrenching Bidvest&apos;s position as the leading foodservice products distributor in Australia with service levels appropriate to the requirements of the customer. Bidvest is differentiated by the high calibre of its extremely focused and motivated staff. They provide a wealth of experience and their passion and commitment truly sets Bidvest apart from its competitors. The Australian company employs approximately 1500 people. The national facilities and distribution capabilities allow Bidvest Australia to provide a fully comprehensive range of products and services on a national level at economies of scale beyond its competitors. The Company operates its own fleet of modern refrigerated vehicles, with all product being delivered free into store for local customers.
 www.bidvest.com.au 
Consider the benefits for your restaurant, hospitality event, next new product development or simply your next home cooked meal, from working with thepioneer of the native Australian food industry with 23 years of experience in commercialising wild species from bush tucker to bushfoods then on to authentic Australian ingredients. We lead the market in our quality, range, volumes and innovation of ingredients and our professionalism of service. www.cherikoff.net

Goodman Fielder Food Services, a division of Goodman Fielder Limited, is a premier supplier of fats, oils, cereals and innovative ingredient solutions to the Australian food service industry. Our product range includes edible oils, catering and table margarine, bakery ingredients, snack foods, breakfast cereals, sauces, dressings, cake mixes, desserts and other meal components. Our brands, many of which are Australian icons, include ETA edible oils and spreads, Crisco premium healthy oils, White Wings cake mixes, Meadow Lea margarines, Pampas pastry, Pilot bakery ingredients, Culinary Centre Cuisine premium frozen cakes and Praise mayonnaises. We also distribute Equal sweetener and Uncle Toby’s cereals and nutritious snacks. 
 www.gffoodservice.com.au

Simplot Foodservice provides its customers with a range of high quality, cost and time saving product solutions from the Edgell, I&amp;J, Captain&apos;s Catch, CHIKO, John West and Leggo&apos;s brands. The Foodservice Team at Simplot are a hard working, dedicated and enthusiastic group of professionals that strive to please customers. We are one of the biggest foodservice suppliers in Australia, with key categories ranging from; frozen vegetables, canned vegetables, fish, finger foods, snacks, seafood, VA potato, chips, canned fruit, Leggo’s tomato sauces and paste, desserts and the Chiko range. www.simplotfoodservice.com.au

Now, over 50 years later, as well as a major supplier and importer of European food, Cantarella Bros. is the largest pure coffee company in Australia. 
 Today, under the leadership of Les Schirato, Managing Director, supported by an experienced and motivated management team and directed by an external board, the Cantarella Group has carved a unique place for itself in the Australian marketplace both as an importer and manufacturer. It is ranked within the top 500 privately owned Australian companies and is without question a major market leader. www.cantarellabros.com

One of the purest waters available, Santa Vittoria Italian mineral water is bottled at the source in the Dolimiti Mountains in Northern Italy. Santa Vittoria mineral water is extracted at a year round temperature of 8 degrees celcius and contains an extremely low sodium level of 0.6mg/L. The light carbonation along with its purity and low sodium level make Santa Vittoria the perfect accompaniment to fine dining as it does not alter the flavour of cuisine. www.santavittoria.com.au

If your company buys, sells, distributes or is involved in any of the following let us know and we can list you for free: food, food gift basket, food service, food services, mexican food, italian food, chineese food, fast food, fast food restaurant, mediterranean food 
 chinese food, indian food, whole food, french food, health food, thai food, cajun food, food dining, food delivery, food service management, food service equipment, food delivery service, food service distributor, food service jobs, food service company, food service supply
 
 The Italian restaurant guide - looking for an Italian restaurant, do you have a favourity Italian restaurant that you would like to recommend, then let us
know about it. visit www.ItalianRestaurants.com.au Gourmet Deli Food Service Italy Travel Guide Gourmet Food Deli - Gourmet deli, if you are looking for gourmet food, small goods, salami, olive oil, ethnic food, food baskets, gourmet wine and more, gourmet deli.
 www.gourmetdeli.com.au Food Service Guide - food service and hospitality industry guide for food distributors, hospitality industry, hotels, cafe, restaurants. Food equipments and supplies for the industry.
 www.foodservice.com.au The Italy Travel Guide: are you thinking of travelling to Italy, do you have a love for Italy, would you like to visit Italy, are you planning a holiday to Italy or do you just want to find something out. visit www.italy.com.au       La Bottega Healthful Italia Lifestyle Guide La Bottega is your very own Italian food finder. If you are having trouble finding a specific brand or Italian food then let us know, our food scout will source it for you, we will do our best to find it
 www.labottega.com.au Healthful the health and beauty guide, for health food, healthy living and healthful tips. If you want to be healthy then do something about it, eat healthy, think healthy be healthy
 www.healthful.com.au Italia Lifestyle Guide: Italia were the winners of the 2006 World Cup. The country that brings you Ferrari, Spaghetti, Fashion, Music, Entertainment and everything beautiful.
 w ww.italia.com.au
	</body>
</document>
