<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005886" url="http://condimentcollection.com/tips.asp" time="2012-07-12-22:33" support="1" score="0.0023710728618396228" bingtitle="Condiment Collection" webtitle="Condiment Collection">
			<query id="001006" bing-rank="47"/>
	<description>... ife Span Table » ... Ask your friends and family to help you search for condiments. ... your city and stop at every gas station, fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Main Links » H ome » M ember Login » P ictures » S earch » D onate / Contribute Reading Material » F AQ / Why Collect? » C ondiment BLOG » N ews » R ecipes » T ips for collecting INTERESTING! » V ote for your favorite » L ife Span Table » E bay Auctions » T op 10 » C ollector Map 
 

 
   Tips For Collecting 
 ( Yes, there is an art to collecting. ) 

 1
 Out of the States Hide Ask your friends or family traveling over seas in the military or on vacation to bring back condiments. Hopefully they will be able to sneak some on the plane. Dont forget, airlines have their own condiments too! 
 
 2
 Trade with other Collectors Hide Go online and search for other condiment collectors. There are some collectors rings and you may even find someone to trade with. Yes, there are people in the world that have wierd collections too. You will be surprised how many are out there. 
 
 3
 Send Letters Hide Send an email or a letter to as many condiment manufacturers that you can find. Make up a story and hope they send you a box full of condiments. Hasnt worked for me yet, but that wont stop me. 
 
 4
 Door to Door Hide You can make any story up for this one. Just go door to dor in your neighborhood and ask for condiments. You can use the following stories as an example: Collecting for a school project, feeding the needy, collecting for a friend, taste testing, ect. Better yet, ask for condiments rather than candy during Halloween. 
 
 5
 Find the OLD ones Hide Ask your grandparents or really old friends if they can raid their friends houses and their own. You may find a few condiments that are 20-30 years old. Some people are packrats...so you never know. 
 
 6
 Ask your Friends Family Hide Ask your friends and family to help you search for condiments. Always ask them to give you doubles, just in case you meet someone who wants to trade. They may think you are wierd and crazy, but who cares? This is for a good cause. 
 
 7
 Raid as many houses as you can Hide Go to all your relatives and friends houses and raid their drawers and fridges. You are bound to find a rare condiment package. 
 
 8
 Drive Around Town Hide Drive around your city and stop at every gas station, fast food restaurant, foreign specialty shops, hotels, restaurants, grocery stores, and ask for every packed condiment they have. Make up a story if you have to. 
 
 

 

 
 Copyright©2012 | Condiment Collection | Emperial Design, Inc. | All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
