<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005737" url="http://obscurestore.typepad.com/obscure_store_and_reading/2007/08/man-sues-mcdona.html" time="2012-07-12-22:22" support="14" score="0.0320720096141439" bingtitle="Obscure Store and Reading Room: Man sues McDonald&apos;s for $10 ..." webtitle="Obscure Store and Reading Room: Man sues McDonald&apos;s for $10 million over cheese on hamburger">
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000912" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>He should be forced to pay his hospital bill in ... got to looking over the display of burrito condiments ... People who place &quot;special orders&quot; at a fast food restaurant are ...</description>
	<body>
		Obscure Store and Reading Room 
 Home 
Friday, August 10, 2007
 
Man sues McDonald&apos;s for $10 million over cheese on hamburger
 
Jeromy Jackson says he bit into a hamburger and had a severe allergic reaction to the cheese melted on it. The young man, who insists he clearly ordered two Quarter Pounders without cheese, ended up being rushed to a hospital. (Charleston Daily Mail) 
 Aug 10, 2007 12:59:13 PM 
 Comment 74 Reblog It 0 
 
74 Comments
 
&quot;We&apos;re interested in seeing McDonald&apos;s take responsibility and change a systemic quality control problem that endangers the lives of up to 12 million Americans with allergies,&quot;said Timothy Houston, the Morgantown lawyer representing the plaintiffs.&quot;And while they&apos;re working on that they can give my lactose intolerant client $10M!&quot;

Look! Look at stuff before you put it in your mouth!
 
Posted by:
 Rusty | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:09 PM 
 
&quot;His mother Trela Jackson and friend Andrew Ellifritz are parties to the lawsuit because they say they risked their lives rushing Jeromy to United Hospital Center in Clarksburg.&quot;

Risked their lives? How? Did they have to run through a mine field? Were killer bees attacking? Were they being chased by a T-rex? Were there snipers dressed as Ronald McDonald on the top of the hospital roof waiting to pick them off as they drove up?

I swear to Bob, this is why halfway legitimate lawsuits end up being jokes.
 
Posted by:
 | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:11 PM 
 
Crap...sorry. That post above was mine.
 
Posted by:
 pnwgal | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:12 PM 
 
why just 10 million? Id go for 20 billion
 
Posted by:
 stomper | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:12 PM 
 
&quot;By my count, he took at least five independent steps to make sure that thing had no cheese on it,&quot;Houston said.&quot;And it did and almost cost him his life.&quot;

Hmm...and it only would have taken one step to look at the burger itself before eating it. It would seem to me that if one is deathly allergic to a common ingredient one would verify these things beforehand.
 
Posted by:
 | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:12 PM 
 
Whenever we&apos;ve gone fast food, we always end up with at least one thing&quot;special order.&quot;It takes just 10 seconds to lift the lid on the burger to make sure your instructions were followed. I realize the article said they were eating in a darkened room, but I never drive off before checking my order, ever.

Come to think of it, I&apos;ve never heard of anyone being&quot;near death&quot;because of a dairy allergy. Anyone?
 
Posted by: Soo | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:24 PM 
 
He missed the very important step of LOOKING AT THE BURGER before he bit into it. Gimme a break!
 
Posted by:
 cherie | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:29 PM 
 
And if he&apos;s that allergic in the first place, you think he wouldn&apos;t be able to have anything at all there...do you think that the workers there change gloves after they&apos;ve handled cheese from the previous burger? If he&apos;s so allergic that a single bite can endanger his life, then why wouldn&apos;t cross contact with dairy do the same thing?

Also, again if he&apos;s really life-threateningly allergic, shouldn&apos;t he have an epi-pen with him at all times? That surely would have saved the rest of the family enough time to avoid driving over medians and through shopping malls to get him to the hospital. The whole thing stinks to me, as much as it pains me to stick up for McArteryClog&apos;s.
 
Posted by:
 Tokio | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:30 PM 
 
I have trouble believing anyone is that allergic to cheese to being with but for argument&apos;s sake, ok... but as other posters have already pointed out, if you&apos;re that damn allergic to something, and then you order a meal that normally comes with that very thing that is so deadly to you... look at it for chrissake!

Also, special ordering is always kind of a mess anyway. You&apos;re guaranteeing your order or someone who is ordering with you is going to get their food screwed up in some way.
 
Posted by:
 elchampino | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:33 PM 
 
To answer a few questions: a good friend of mine is deathly allergic to dairy. We&apos;re not talking a severe case of mud butt or anything like that--we&apos;re talking his throat completely closes up and he can&apos;t breathe. Of course, my friend isn&apos;t a complete idiot, so he carries two epi-pens with him at all times, and he&apos;s showed his friends, family, and girlfriends how to use them in case the need ever arises.
 
Posted by:
 Vodka | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:36 PM 
 
Ahhhh...the American way! I&apos;m not alergic but I look at my food before I eat it. Duh!
 
Posted by:
 bob | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:40 PM 
 
It just seems borderline suicidal to put your life in the hands of the folks behind the McDonald&apos;s cash register.

Vodka - I had no idea anyone could have that kind of reaction to a dairy product. The one explanation I could come up with is the kid&apos;s family is too dirt poor to even have epi-pens on hand (how much do those things go for? I have no idea).

That still doesn&apos;t excuse the shear stupidity exhibited here, though.
 
Posted by:
 elchampino | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:43 PM 
 
I doubt the lawyer ever expects this to actually go to trial. What they are counting on is that McDonalds will settle for a percentage of what they&apos;re wanting.
 
Posted by:
 IronOre | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:55 PM 
 
When you hear about a case like this, just remember a few checks and balances: the court could totally dismiss the suit, or comparative fault could come into play. That&apos;s where the jury says the guy really was injured, but it was mostly his fault because he didn&apos;t check for cheese. If he&apos;s 90% at fault for his injuries, he will get either (depending on the state) nothing at all or only 10% of the damages.

And of course that doesn&apos;t mean 10% of what you ask for, it&apos;s 10% of what the jury thinks your actual damages were. So if this guy gets $50,000 for going to the hospital, pain and suffering, etc., and the jury says he is 90% at fault, he will recover either nothing or $5,000.
 
Posted by:
 Andrewdoane | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 01:59 PM 
 
Taint that funny.
 
Posted by:
 Taint | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 02:31 PM 
 
He should be forced to pay his hospital bill in cash. It is unfair to charge the other policyholders for his stupidity. Along the lines of life insurance policy not paying for a suicide.
 
Posted by:
 Get Real | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 02:35 PM 
 
I always order my burgers without cheese at McDonald&apos;s.
But I always check to see if they followed that order.
I look first!
I once had a double burger where the second pattie was just half a pattie.
My guess is that 1 out of 5 times they screw it up.
Earlier this week, McDonald&apos;s execs were quoted that there are too many order mixups there&amp;they need to cut that number down. Wendy&apos;s&amp;Burger King rarely have mixed up my order. McD does because they&apos;re still wedded to the make a lot with everything way despite the change a few years ago.
 
Posted by:
 Garry | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 02:52 PM 
 
People who are&quot;dirt poor&quot;can get certain&quot;life-saving&quot;prescriptions at low or no cost. I&apos;m thinking it&apos;s more that this guy either chose not to get an epi-pen, or was tooling around town with complete idiots.

I mean, think about it. Those two felt they had&apos;risked their lives&apos;driving this guy to the hospital. The WonderTwins they ain&apos;t.
 
Posted by: Soo | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:00 PM 
 
Rusty,

Lactose intolerance is completely different from a dairy allergy. Severe lactose intolerance leads to spending a lot of time in the bathroom. Severe dairy (or other food) allergy leads to anaphylaxis and possibly death if not treated immediately.

Especially if you are that allergic to something, check the food before you turn down the lights. Special orders get screwed up, and even regular orders can get screwed up.

Yeah, I&apos;d be worried enough about cross-contamination if I had a severe allergy like that, and probably wouldn&apos;t even eat at McD&apos;s. (I try to avoid McD&apos;s anyway.)
 
Posted by:
 B | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:00 PM 
 
Only the first paragraph is responding to Rusty ... the rest is just general comments about the article. I didn&apos;t make that clear.
 
Posted by:
 B | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:02 PM 
 
I went to a Moe&apos;s a few months back, and the woman in front of me was trying to get the preparer to understand that she was allergic to avocados while the preparer just stood there with that deer-in-the-headlights look. I couldn&apos;t take it anymore so I said kinda loudly that the lady can&apos;t have the&apos;guac&apos;, to please change your gloves and wash your hands before putting on new gloves, and that the lady was going to leave a nice tip in the jar. The preparer finally snapped out of it and did as requested.

But meanwhile, I got to looking over the display of burrito condiments, and the guac was spilled everywhere, along with the black beans and the rice. How could anyone with any kind of allergy eat there safely?

I have no allergies, but I was so grossed out puzzling it over, I hardly ate any of my order and I haven&apos;t been back.

You really can&apos;t expect excellence from a service industry known for employing people to work hard for minimum wage. It&apos;s kindof like Walmart--if they paid more, they&apos;d probably prefer to hire people with an obvious interest in your satisfaction.
 
Posted by: Soo | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:11 PM 
 
I have mixed feelings about this. On the one hand, it is a very stupid lawsuit, and I think the idiot with the food allergies should have looked at what he was stuffing into his empty head.

On the other hand, I once received a&quot;meatless&quot;Big Mac from McDonald&apos;s, and I&apos;m still a little ticked off about it.

Plus the damn fries were cold.

 
Posted by: Dan | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:13 PM 
 
I very seldom eat at McDonald&apos;s, for a number of reasons, but when I do, I always, always, ALWAYS look at what I am eating. For example, can&apos;t stand onions, and for some reason they can&apos;t seem to get that through their head. Can&apos;t count the number of times I have had to take back a steak biscuit because there are onions on it, often three or four times on the same biscuit. But the point is, I look, and I merely dislike onions. Come on, it&apos;s McDonald&apos;s. Not a place I would trust my life to.

And what, are they too good to call for paramedics like everyone else? McDonald&apos;s did not risk their lives in their mad dash to the hospital. That&apos;s just plain stupid.
 
Posted by:
 bitsy | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:13 PM 
 
this whole lawsuit lacks common sense..if you&apos;re allergic to their product,dont eat it,stupid.LOOK to make sure they got it right,because odds are, they DIDNT.this idiot is just looking for some easy money.
 
Posted by:
 nunya | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:25 PM 
 
Oopsie. He forgot to check between the bun. Hope he&apos;s more careful with his dates.
 
Posted by:
 oopsie | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 03:52 PM 
 
It&apos;s human error. These things happen. It&apos;s unfortunate that this fellow had such a severe reaction, but McDonald&apos;s did offer to pay his entire medical bill. What more can be reasonably expected? Ten million seems a little ridiculous. I mean c&apos;mon.
 
Posted by:
 Dave | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 05:00 PM 
 
This guy trusted his life to McDonald&apos;s? And didn&apos;t bother to check his burger? (snort)

I thought he was a weanie when I read that. Then when I saw that his pals want money for&quot;risking their lives&quot;I KNEW he was a major weanie.
 
Posted by:
 Swangirl | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 06:10 PM 
 
Last time I looked you either order a quarter pounder or a quarter pounder with cheese. By this dimbulb ordering a quarter pounder without cheese he confused the guy taking the order. He heard&quot;quarter pounder&quot;and&quot;cheese&quot;so thats what he gave him.
 
Posted by:
 csg | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 06:21 PM 
 
probably nobody wants gorgonzola anyway, lads.
i suspect.
forget any toppings,
and nugget dip.
divvy up more burgers.
 
Posted by:
 custis | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 06:47 PM 
 
I work at a McDonalds and mistakes happen alot. It&apos;s not like it&apos;s on purpose or anything, just that the goal of fast food is to get it out fast. Everything behind the counter in a Mcdonalds is timed, we can&apos;t double-check every order. Something like this happened at my McDs awhile ago. Some lady came back half an hour later from drinking a vanilla milkshake and was cursing and screaming at everyone because there was a bit of strawberry in the bottom (the machine does this sometimes) The girl behind the counter offered her a new one, but the lady said she was going to break out in hives and who the f*ck was gonna pay for the hospital trip and all that. She cursed at the 14 year old girl behind the counter and almost reduced her to tears. Of course McDonalds paid all the bills, but it makes you think... I mean, she drank the entire milkshake. The entire thing, even though she&apos;s allergic to strawberry, and the strawberry was at the bottom, so she tasted that first. I know that she couldn&apos;t see the strawberry, but still, she finished the shake?...

Sorry that was more of a rant then I wanted it to be :P

This one sounds like an uber-scam to me, though. I mean really, common sense much?
 
Posted by:
 Juju | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 06:48 PM 
 
Trela and Jaromy Jackson? I know I am not permitted to form a conclusion. But to Jim, and other moderators or site owners, how about 10 to 1 odds? You, or whomever, you know what I am talking about. You want to risk $10,000 to maybe get $100,000?

My e-mail is shown. But...since I know I am right, just send the ten grand to anyone but the NAACP.
 
Posted by:
 Bluntfacts | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 07:07 PM 
 
All 3 of them need a giant order of sterilization.
 
Posted by:
 Farmer Bob | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 09:00 PM 
 
I don&apos;t get these people who don&apos;t check their orders, esp with a special request. And then there are those who order thru the drive-thru, go home,&amp;find the completely wrong order. DJ on the radio was just talking about it--and yet HE STILL GOES BACK THERE&amp;NEVER CHECKS THE ORDER BEFORE PULLING AWAY. Moron. He said on the air that it had happened the night before, and that it has happened before. Have no idea if anyone called him on it, as I had to head out the door then.
I always check an order, just as I check my change.
 
Posted by:
 Dee | Friday, August 10, 2007 at 09:25 PM 
 
McD restaurants are like huge blenders that churn out finely mixed garbage. Everything gets mixed with tiny particles of everything else in it. Don&apos;t want catsup? I&apos;ve seen them scrape off a bun and serve it! If you are allergic to anything, do not ever even enter a McD.
But wherever you eat, look at your food before stuffing your mouth!
 
Posted by: Charles Brobst | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 04:40 AM 
 
I agree with everyone on check your order. My husband always has a special order at Mc. It is wrong 9 out of 10 times.He always looks at the burger before he walks away from the counter.All this because he hates mustard. Here is someone deathy allergic to cheese. He doesn&apos;t even look? That&apos;s just dumb ass dumb. Whatever happen to&quot;buyer beware&quot;? Maureen
 
Posted by:
 Maureen | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 06:00 AM 
 
&quot;Here is someone deathy allergic to cheese. He doesn&apos;t even look? That&apos;s just dumb ass dumb. Whatever happen to&quot;buyer beware&quot;? Maureen

Aint that the truth????
 
Posted by:
 Jim | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 06:08 AM 
 
Wellll....I guess I&apos;ll throw my two cents into the ring.

Now, I completely understand the point of view of looking at your food and checking it before you eat it, and espc if your as allergic as this guy is.

BUTTTTTT.

If any of you are like me and just don&apos;t like onions on your burgers, and everytime you order one they almost ALWAYS put the damn things on no matter how clear you make it to them NOT to do so...their incompentence tends to get old after awhile.

Then these stupid bastards have the nerve to give YOU a dirty look or a crappy attitude because you ask them to give you what you paid for.

My grandmother is deathly allergic to tomatoes (of all things) and she NEVER counts on the employee to get it right...and the last time she gave the employee the benefit of the doubt at a fast-food resturant downtown to make sure the order had no tomatoes was years ago....and she almost died for it....(McD&apos;s in downtown philly).

I&apos;ve come to find that I generally run into this problem when I go to any fast food place that isn&apos;t run and manned by white people....which doesn&apos;t surprise me in the least.

I go to the fast food places in the suburbs...never a problem, the food is always hot and fresh and the order is almost ALWAYS right.

You go to ANY of the fast food places within the city, and you can pretty much count on the order being wrong or the food just cold or just crappily put together....and don&apos;t even think about expecting whatever you told them NOT to put on the sandwich to not be there....they ALWAYS manage to screw it up somehow or another.

BTW...I&apos;m not trying to be racist, I&apos;m just sharing my personal experiences when it comes to the differences in ownership and quality of service when you go to a place that isn&apos;t manned by either people who can&apos;t speak english (proper or otherwise, and ebonics doenst count) or people who couldn&apos;t even make it thru middle school or basic math, let alone get a fast-food order right.

But, alas, that&apos;s why I&apos;ve coined the phrase:

&quot;And that&apos;s why they work at McD&apos;s....&quot;

Personally, I stopped going to any of the McD&apos;s in downtown Indy when one of my co-workers caught a black guy working behind the counter spitting into her food because she complained about her mcnuggets being cold....the scumbag spit on the fresh ones before he brought it to her, but she seen him do it.

Why she didn&apos;t sue, I&apos;ll never know...but I would&apos;ve owned that place had it been me.
 
Posted by:
 ThatGuy | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 07:26 AM 
 
I Don&apos;t eat a Macdonalds anymore because here in Chicago they let beggers and panhandlers wonder around their stores extorting money. Food alergies are a problem especially peanuts, peanut oil might end up anywhere and how can you tell?
This guy should have checked his burger for cheese before taking a bite, but we don&apos;t even know if the Macdonalds made a mistake. They went through the drive-thru and ate at home. How do we know he took the right bag when he got home? They proabably had 3 or 4 bags of food and the guy with the cheese alergy might made a mistake and got the wrong sandwich.
 
Posted by:
 Daniel | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 09:00 AM 
 
&quot;the scumbag spit on the fresh ones before he brought it to her,&gt;&gt;but she seen him do it.&lt;&lt;&quot;

Complaining about&quot;ebonics&quot;and using it in the same post a few paragraphs. Tsk. Tsk.
 
Posted by:
 andie | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 09:32 AM 
 
Yada, yada, yada. Same old obscure opinions. A poem, shall we?

Mr. Jackson stopped by Micky Ds
Ordered a burger without any cheese
When he got home, he took only one bite
And allergic reactions took to flight.

Whereupon he did convulse
And got to the ER with barely a pulse
Later on, did he hire a leach
With the sole ability of the law to preach

Now comes the giant, with no remorse
Not shrewd of mind, (but that, of course)
“I pay you half your doctor bills”
But Jackson had suffered not the least of ills

Clearly he’d said “No cheese on mine”
But for minimum wage, one hires no mind
Now, enter the leach with a mind that’s sharp
Who can sing to a jury with words like a harp

But, most importantly he is skilled
At the minutia that gets a giant killed
Objective law, nothing more or less
Oh, and getting the witness to confess

Objective law he will not eschew
And with it, like a sword, a giant he’ll skew
Poor dumb Cyclopes never sees it coming
An army of lawyers it’s senses numbing

Drunk with power he forges ahead
Having long since forgotten both fear or dread
“With my boot I will surely crush my foe
His lawyer I’ll squish with my little toe”

Poor dumb Cyclopes only sees one thing
Whatever is needed, the profit to bring
Unwieldy in fight, he will lose this battle
Not learning this lesson, returns to the cattle

Grinding them up swiftly, he churns out more burgers
Does a rhyme exist that that compliments “burgers”?
Never you mind, for the ending draws near
Only one thing left for the reader to fear

The draw of trial lawyers to make us all rich
For a piece of the prize, most all of us snitch
Or, tell a strange truth or falsely confess
(All of us wishing we had the blue dress)

And unhappy bloggers spend all of their time
Spouting limp arguments (without any rhyme)
And sit fat and happy in front of computers
In lieu of being disgruntled commuters

I’ve been useless enough, this I have learned
My mind is still sharp and my buttocks still firm
I go cut my grass or clean out my shed
Not wanting to be found… in front of my monitor… dead.

(Oh, I really didn’t care enough to properly punctuate… or write well.)
Objectivity of the law is the only important thing here. It appears, (from the surface) they have a strong, objective case. To quote someone wise, “You only get justice one third of the time. You either get a bad lawyer, a bad judge… or you get justice. (A smart lawyer and a good judge)
Only fools believe they deserve justice. Even then, they have forgotten the other half of the matter.

Humans…





 
Posted by:
 Mikey | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 12:32 PM 
 
People who place&quot;special orders&quot;at a fast food restaurant are pains in the ass who need to get the hell out of the way. I seldom go through drive-throughs anymore, because I just can&apos;t tolerate the idiots who peruse the menu like they&apos;re at Sardi&apos;s. Folks, here are your options at a burger joint: burger, bigger burger. Fries are optional.

Now order your motherf***in&apos;greasy shite and get the f*** out of my way.

(Oh, and if you think it&apos;s cute to have your 4-year-old place the order, please all of you die in a fiery crash. Thanks.)
 
Posted by:
 Me | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 02:05 PM 
 
Here&apos;s an interesting one. I am allergic to all&quot;aged&quot;things: red wine, cheeses.... incidentally, I&apos;m also allergic to mold and mildew, my throat closes up. But when I eat aged things, I immediately projectile vomit nonstop. It was unfortunate that I discovered this at a restaurant, but ANYHOO... I just never LIKED these cheeses before, but somehow avoided having it put on a food order until that time.

My point is, I&apos;m not going to stop going to restaurants. Even Italian, where parm is all the rage. I found that if the aged thing is cooked (like beef, or sauce that has some parm in it), I am not as severely allergic. I will get a migraine, and may vomit in a few hours. But I will not ingest, and immediately vomit, nonstop, unable to catch a good breath. As such, I ask before hand if the sauce has parm in it, etc.

I like (specifically) italian food. Just as this guy may like burgers without cheese. I don&apos;t think he should not eat there, but I DO agree, dude... LOOK AT YOUR FOOD. My bet is he was high. Getting fast food, and going into a dark basement? I do that when I&apos;m high. Adn that would explain why his friends&quot;risked their lives.&quot;haw haw. ahem.

oh, and ThatGuy? Incidentally, I&apos;ve had several mess-ups where blue cheese was left in a salad, or mozz wasn&apos;t substituted for parm... and believe it or not WHITE people made these mistakes! It&apos;s true! Not trying to be racist, just sharing my personal experience. In all seriousness, I think a more logical, likely explanation would be that the McD&apos;s you mentioned are in busy downtown areas. BUSY. Fast. rushed. Ya dig?
 
Posted by:
 ISBN | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 03:02 PM 
 
You guys are totally unaware of McDonald&apos;s&quot;Ace In The Hole&quot;defense here.
When it comes to crunch time, the McDonald&apos;s lawyer will make the unexpecte, yet truthful claim that,&quot;That crap ain&apos;t cheese!&quot;
 
Posted by:
 mick | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 03:18 PM 
 
B,

Thanks for the info without trashing me!

 
Posted by:
 Rusty | Saturday, August 11, 2007 at 08:06 PM 
 
Cheese! I was wondering what that yellow crap was on my McMysteryMeat.
 
Posted by:
 Sigh | Sunday, August 12, 2007 at 09:47 AM 
 
Wait a minute...this guy has a near fatal allergic reaction and only incurs an ER bill of $700.00? Having worked in emergency medicine for the last 12 years I can tell you that he did not get a whole lot done for that price. I&apos;d just like to know what kind of medical care he got. Doesn&apos;t sound like he was very sick to me. And too, in 12 years I&apos;ve never seen a&quot;cheese allergy&quot;but I&apos;ve seen a whole lot of drama queens. Someone please! Get the Dramatologist on call, STAT!
 
Posted by:
 Number2 | Sunday, August 12, 2007 at 01:10 PM 
 
My bullshit meter is ding-dinging at full alert. The&quot;darkened room&quot;story is just an answers (and a stupid one at that) for when the obvious question is asked: Why didn&apos;t you look before you bit?

This thing better be thrown out. I hope they&apos;re found to be frauds and have to pay McDonald&apos;s court costs. There should be years of medical records to explain his awful reaction to cheese.
 
Posted by:
 bloodyhell | Sunday, August 12, 2007 at 03:09 PM 
 
Someone pointed out my thought... $700 in the ER room is not going to cover anaphylaxis. I am a medical insurance adjuster. Those bills would be a minor ER charge, minor ER physician charge. No xrays, no EKGS, no monitoring... I&apos;d have to take the educated guess that he got at most a benedryl or steroid shot.

IMO, this suit is without merit and the gentleman has a responsibility to watch his own health. That includes checking his food.
 
Posted by:
 Brio | Monday, August 13, 2007 at 03:46 AM 
 
Wow, I am impressed McD&apos;s uses&quot;cheese&quot;real enough to cause such a reaction!
 
Posted by: swarthytroll | Monday, August 13, 2007 at 04:36 AM 
 
bloodyhell, that was basically what i was thinking. If you notice in the article&quot;he and his family&quot;say he nearly died. It never says anything about what a doctor has said (correct me if i missed it). So I&apos;m HIGHLY doubting he spent time in ICU, stopped breathing...and almost died. What I&apos;m going to guess is he wants some money, figured this would be a great way to get it. Told his family he&apos;d share with them. Got a burger, made himself sick, went to the hospital and then started the&quot;legal&quot;process. I hope it gets thrown out like the idiot that sued the cleaners over lost pants.

On another note. One very hungry night after work a number of years ago I stopped along the way at a Wendy&apos;s (the upper class of fast food lol). Wendy&apos;s was about 20 minutes from my home and like a moron, I didn&apos;t check my order. When I got home and took a bite of my chicken sandwich....there was a problem....NO CHICKEN!! How do you forget the MEAT in a sandwich?!?!
When I called the restaurant they offered me free food. Silly. I should&apos;ve demanded one of their workers drive me my meat...but I knew better.
 
Posted by:
 cherie | Monday, August 13, 2007 at 04:55 AM 
 » 
The comments to this entry are closed.
 
 NEXT POST Where are Green Bay&apos;s bomb-sniffing dogs when you need them? There could have been a terrorist incident at the Packers&apos; Lambeau Field and not a single bomb-sniffing dog was on duty. On a Gravy Train break or something? Police had to search a suspicious truck that was loaded with&quot;garage... PREVIOUS POST Boy, 15, arrested after videotaping man&apos;s&quot;Jackass&quot;stunt A 42-year-old man jumped off a 65-foot-high bridge to the astonishment of onlookers. He was pulled from the water and taken to a hospital, where he was treated for internal injuries, while a 15-year-old boy who recorded the jump was... 
 
 


 1 Following 36 Followers 
Search
 
Recent Comments
 
 rickets: im gonna miss you OSRR(JIM).
been reading almos... | more » On Dear readers: After 13 years, I&apos;m closing The Obscure Store twerp: Nope! Regina beat you to it! And now I beat R... | more » On Dear readers: After 13 years, I&apos;m closing The Obscure Store ReginaFilangee: And to quote Lee Greenwood,
 
...thank my lucky... | more » On Dear readers: After 13 years, I&apos;m closing The Obscure Store 
 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed Powered by TypePad
	</body>
</document>
