<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005033" url="http://www.flipdog.com/jobs/oregon-il/food-beverage/" time="2012-07-12-21:33" support="2" score="0.012789741501547335" bingtitle="Oregon Food Beverage Jobs (IL) &amp; Employment - FlipDog Job Search" webtitle="Oregon  Food Beverage Jobs (IL)Employment - FlipDog Job Search">
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001066" bing-rank="82"/>
	<description>... work areas; operating a variety of kitchen utensils ... in food handling and extensive beverage menus.... ... Job Purpose: Serves fast food restaurant customers by directing ...</description>
	<body>
		Oregon Food Beverage Jobs (IL)

Sort by: Date | Relevance 
 
 
 Sports Management Company - Food And Beverage Supervisor Jobs In Sports (Chicago, Illinois) 

Job Title: Sports Management Company - Food and Beverage Supervisor Location: Chicago, IL JobID: 453192335 Job#453192335 MAJOR RESPONSIBILITIES: • Supervises Food&amp;Beverage and Bar operations during events to ensure client satisfaction and quality control standards. • Maintains inventory controls at all times and quality of food being served is to company standards. • Inspects food service facili...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Thu 14th June
 
 Food And Beverage Director Brenden Gardens (Springfield/Champaign, Illinois) 

Food and Beverage Director Experience and or training in nutrition, food preparation, safe food handling, techniques and food service management required. Prefer 2 years food service supervisory experience in restaurant setting, focusing on food management, cost control and presentation. Computer skills-food ordering and budget controls a must. Over see staff of 17. Full benefits, 401k plan, Salar...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Sun 17th June
 
 Sales Manager - Beverage/Canning Executive Recruiting Associates (Chicago North, Illinois) 

Sales Manager – Beverage/Canning $70K + ($30K - $40K) Buffalo Grove, IL International client needs an experienced Sales Manager for Seaming&amp;Filling Division of a packaging conglomerate. · Must be familiar with canning operations, bottling companies, etc. · Need to also have technical knowledge of capital equipment to service and parts in beverage and canning companies. · Previous background with...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Yesterday
 
 Beverage Wholesaler Driver/Warehouse Specialty Imports (Bloomington/Peoria, Illinois) 

Beverage Wholesaler Warehouse Load trucks for delivery. Full-time with hourly wage. Valid driver&apos;s license required. Daytime shift. Must be flexible with hours and able to work independently. Email resume: specialtyimports @sbcglobal.net or fax 309-673-1127....
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Sat 23rd June
 
 Food Preparer HMSHost (Chicago, Illinois) 

Summary: The Food Preparer is responsible the preparing various food products; ensuring proper food handling procedures are followed; arranging necessary supplies and equipment between storage and work areas; operating a variety of kitchen utensils and/or equipment for food product cooking, serving and storing; receiving and inventorying food and beverage products; performing all other responsibil...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 27th June
 
 Fast Food Attendant HMSHost (Chicago, Illinois) 

Summary: The Fast Food Attendant is responsible for performing a variety of duties within a fast food / snack bar establishment which may include completing customer transactions, cleaning the food or stock areas, assisting in the kitchen area, and maintaining inventory; performs all other responsibilities as directed by the business or as assigned by management. This is a non-exempt position and ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 27th June
 
 Fast Food Restaurant Manager Jimano&apos;s Pizzeria (Chicago North, Illinois) 

Job Purpose: Serves fast food restaurant customers by directing food and beverage preparation; maintaining customer goodwill; collecting revenues; maintaining supplies, equipment, and sanitation; managing staff. Duties: * Accomplishes fast food restaurant human resource objectives by recruiting, selecting, orienting, training, assigning, scheduling, coaching, counseling, and disciplining employees...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 4th July
 
 Macy&apos;s Woodfield, Schaumburg, IL: Starbucks Barista, Part Time Macy&apos;s Stores (Chicago Northwest, Illinois) 

Overview: The Starbucks Barista sells and creates coffee beverages following Starbucks standards providing outstanding customer service through product knowledge. Key Responsibilities: - Follows Food Division Standards and Best Practices - Demonstrate current and working knowledge of drip coffee, cold beverage, espresso bar and pastry stations. - Follows Food Safety standards and maintains work ar...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 3 days ago
 
 Macy&apos;s Woodfield, Schaumburg, IL: Starbucks Barista, Part Time Macy&apos;s Stores (Chicago Northwest, Illinois) 

Overview: The Starbucks Barista sells and creates coffee beverages following Starbucks standards providing outstanding customer service through product knowledge. Key Responsibilities: - Follows Food Division Standards and Best Practices - Demonstrate current and working knowledge of drip coffee, cold beverage, espresso bar and pastry stations. - Follows Food Safety standards and maintains work ar...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Today
 
 Data Collector- Child And Adult Care Food Program Meal Claims Study- Chicago, IL Icf (Chicago, Illinois) 

Health, Education, and Social Programs Public Health Division Field-Based in Chicago, IL Area About ICF International ICF International (NASDAQ:ICFI) partners with government and commercial clients to deliver professional services and technology solutions in the energy, environment, and transportation; health, education, and social programs; and homeland security and defense markets. The firm comb...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 20th June
 
 Director, Analytics - Quaker Food&amp;Snacks PepsiCo (Chicago, Illinois) 

Major Responsibilities: Work with Senior Director of Consumer Insights&amp;CMO to create long-term vision for Quaker Analytics team. Lead the development, integration, and standardization of Syndicated research and tools across the Quaker Marketing organization. Provide energetic leadership to implement agenda throughout the Quaker organization. Represent Quaker on Pepsico Analytics Council and coor...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Today
 
 General/Assistant General Manager - Chicago, IL And Surrounding Areas California Pizza Kitchen (Chicago Northwest, Illinois) 

California Pizza Kitchen, multiple recipient of the &apos;People Report™ Best People Practices Award &apos;for lowest management and hourly turnover, one of Forbes&apos; Top 200 Small Businesses, and one of Business Week&apos;s Top 100 Growth Companies! WHAT IS CPK? California Pizza Kitchen (CPK) is a leading full-service casual dining chain in the premium pizza segment that opened its first restaurant in March of 19...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Fri 15th June
 
 Blending Manager Nestle Professional Vitality (Chicago, Illinois) 

Nestlé Professional Vitality has an immediate opening in the Chicago, IL area for a Blending Manager. The Blending Manager will be responsible for safety, productivity, and sanitation across a three shift blending and bulk receiving operation. They will manage one salaried and twenty-four hourly employees. This individual will need to be a strong people manager, be a hands-on type, and have great ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Thu 28th June
 
 Automation Engineer- Process Improvements Tetra Pak (Chicago North, Illinois) 

AUTOMATION ENGINEER-PROCESSING IMPROVEMENTS THE POSITION: This position is based in Vernon Hills, IL, this opportunity will report to the Product Manager of Processing Improvements. This role will impact our company and benefit our customers by actively being involved in design, development, testing, commissioning, and support of control system upgrades. KEY RESPONSIBILITES: Control system analysi...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Mon 2nd July
 
 Cook Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (Chicago, Illinois) 

Part-Time Cook Job Number: 51346 Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (BSL) a publicly traded company (NYSE: BKD) Horizon Bay, now part of Brookdale Senior Living, the nation&apos;s largest senior living provider, is seeking a Cook, for our community in Plainfield, IL!!! One Company - One Mission - One Voice. Good people make the difference and are the key to the company&apos;s success. Brookdale Senior Living oper...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Fri 1st June
 
 Server Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (Chicago, Illinois) 

Part-Time Server Job Number: 51350 Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (BSL) is a publicly traded company (NYSE: BKD) Want to become a member of our professional team and work for the largest senior living provider in the United States? Consider joining our team at The Park at Plainfield in IL!!! One Company - One Mission - One Voice. Good people make the difference and are the key to the company&apos;s succe...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Fri 1st June
 
 Cook Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (Chicago, Illinois) 

Cook Job Number: 51628 Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (BSL) a publicly traded company (NYSE: BKD) Horizon Bay, now part of Brookdale Senior Living, the nation&apos;s largest senior living provider, is seeking an experienced Cook for our community in Niles, IL! One Company - One Mission - One Voice. Good people make the difference and are the key to the company&apos;s success. Brookdale Senior Living operates ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 6th June
 
 Senior Financial Analyst - Accounting Supervisor Kraft Foods (Chicago, Illinois) 

This position offers the opportunity for cross-functional exposure to divisional and functional organizations through Accounting Services. This position serves as an excellent opportunity to strengthen communication and organization skills, and promote growth of leadership competencies. Under the general direction of the Accounting Services Manager, the Accounting Supervisor performs accounting du...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Tue 12th June
 
 Executive Chef Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (Chicago, Illinois) 

Executive Chef Job Number: 47186a Brookdale Senior Living Inc. (BSL) a publicly traded company (NYSE: BKD) Want to become a member of our professional team and work for the largest senior living provider in the United States? Consider joining our team at The Hallmark of Chicago in Chicago, Illinois. One Company - One Mission - One Voice. Good people make the difference and are the key to the compa...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 20th June
 
 Experienced Restaurant Manager O&apos;Charley&apos;s Restaurants (Springfield/Champaign, Illinois) 

O’Charley’s seeking Talented&amp;Experienced Restaurant Managers Are YOU one of the best Restaurant Managers in the Champaign, IL area? O’Charley’s is seeking experienced talented managers to join us for our local area Restaurants! You know O’Charley’s for Good Food, Good Times, now become part of a team that is “A Cut Above” the rest. “A Cut Above” at O’Charley’s is more than our friendly, upbeat a...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 27th June
 
 
 1 2 3 Next 20 Oregon Food Beverage Jobs (IL) 
 
Oregon IL Job Search Tip

Oregon boasts one of the largest salmon fishing industries in the world. Tourism is also a booming industry as more and more people discover the beautiful Oregon coastline and breathtaking mountains. Oregon&apos;s largest employers are the Doerenbecher Children&apos;s Hospital, Oregon State University, Oregon Health Sciences University, Intel Corporation and Hewlett Packard Corporation. Sources: Wikipedia, America&apos;s Career Info Net.

 Oregon at a Glance: 

 
Unemployment Rate: 5.5%
 
2005 Per Capita Income: $32,103
 
Largest Cities: Portland, Eugene, Salem, Gresham, Hillsboro
 
Minimum Hourly Wage: $7.50

Here are some jobs to look at:
 Radiation Therapist Jobs , Radiation Therapist Jobs by State 
 Technical Writer Jobs , Technical Writer Jobs by State 
 Tour Guide Jobs , Tour Guide Jobs by State 
 Delivery Driver Jobs , Delivery Driver Jobs by State 
 Strategic Account Manager Jobs , Strategic Account Manager Jobs by State 

Find more Oregon Jobs on Monster.com

Learn how to write a resume , find relevant examples of resumes , read through resume help , and then create your resume .

Search through Oregon jobs by city on Flipdog!
 
 
Related Cities
 
 Chicago Food Beverage Jobs 
 Bloomington/Peoria Food Beverage Jobs 
 Chicago North Food Beverage Jobs 
 Chicago Northwest Food Beverage Jobs 
 Chicago South Food Beverage Jobs 
 Quincy Food Beverage Jobs 
 Rockford Food Beverage Jobs 
 Southern Illinois Food Beverage Jobs 
 Springfield/Champaign Food Beverage Jobs 
 More Related Cities… 
 
Job Categories
 
 Accounting Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Construction Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Education Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Engineering Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Finance Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Government Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Healthcare Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Marketing Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Nursing Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Real Estate Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Retail Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Sales Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Security Jobs In Oregon IL 
 Teaching Jobs In Oregon IL 
 More Job Categories… 
 
Create a FREE Monster account!

 Build a searchable resume and let employers find you Sign up for a JobAgent and have jobs emailed to you Get expert career advice 
 
 Services from Monster.com 

Career Resources
 
 Career Advice Sample Resumes&amp;Cover Letters Salary Comparison Calculator Entry-level Jobs&amp;Internships Scholarship Search Online Degrees&amp;Continuing Education 
 
Monster for Employers
 
 
 Post Jobs 

Post jobs in minutes and get immediate results
 
 Search Resumes 

Search by Zip Code, Title, Industry and Keyword
 
 
Share this Page
 URL: 
Share this page with friends on:
 
 Del.icio.us Digg Facebook Netscape StumbleUpon Reddit 
 
 
 Job Search Home Jobs by Category Jobs by Title Jobs by Company Most Popular Job Searches Search Tips Job Posting 
 
Get these results in RSS   
 
 Job Seekers: Search Jobs Post Your Resume Create a Free Account Find Career Advice Sign-up for Job Alerts 

 Employers: Monster Hiring Solutions Post Jobs Search Resumes 

 The Monster Network: Scholarship Search Financial Aid Internships Online Degree Search More Monster Sites 
 
 About FlipDog Jobs by State New Jobs Privacy Terms of Service  Copyright©2012 FlipDog. All Rights Reserved. 
 Keywords Location 
Powered by  
 
 Advanced Search Recent Searches Search Tips 
 
 You are here: Home Illinois Jobs Oregon IL Jobs Oregon Food Beverage Jobs (IL)
	</body>
</document>
