<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005582" url="http://topkitch.en.alibaba.com/product/446342503-212377929/Italian_restaurant_Kitchen_Equipment.html" time="2012-07-12-22:07" support="2" score="0.0032230036853674667" bingtitle="Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment - Detailed info for Italian ..." webtitle="Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment - Detailed info for Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment,Kitchen equipment,Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment,It-KE on Alibaba.com">
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Payment Terms: T/T,MoneyGram: Supply Ability: 5 Set/Sets ... Counter Table With Sink . Work Table With Shelf ... Fast Food Restaurant [1] Italian Restaurant [5] Snack Machine [128]</description>
	<body>
		Alibaba.com Join Free  |  My Alibaba Post Buying Request 3 rd year View My Store on AliExpress.com 
 
 Guangzhou Topkitch Kitchen Equipment Co., Ltd. 
 
 
 Home Products Company Profile Contacts 
 Home Products Kitchen/Restarent Project Equipment Italian Restaurant Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment Dinnerware Set Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipmen... drink glass for italian restaurant Restaurant/Hotel Kitchen Equipment Hotel Project 
Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment Language Option 
 French German Italian Russian Spanish Portuguese Korean 日本語 
 
 Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment Report Suspicious Activity Suspicious activities include posting prohibited/restricted item, fraud, etc. Add to My Favorites 
Product Details:

 Place of Origin Guangdong, China (Mainland) Brand Name Topkitch Model Number It-KE Type Cooking Equipment Pizza oven, Pasta machine equipment Combi-steamer, Dishwasher equipment Salamander, Fryer,ice maker, Freezer equipment Dough spiral mixer, bone saw machine equipment 
 
Payment&amp;Shipping Terms:

 Price: FOB USD 10000~20000 / Set
 Get Latest Price Minimum Order Quantity: 1 Set/Sets Port: Guangzhou Packaging Details: Carton with wooden shelf or case Delivery Time: 25~35days Payment Terms: T/T,MoneyGram Supply Ability: 5 Set/Sets per Month 
 Ms. Renee Ng Place Order via   
Buyer Protection
 ensure your transaction safety By placing an order on Alibaba.com, you can:
 Ensure the safety of your transaction Receive assistance throughout the entire process 
 «Prev Product 1 2 3 4 5 Next Product» 
Detailed Product Description

 We provide one-stop service for you. Design, supplying the top quality equipments, also other relative untensils.

 
 Commercial Restaurant Kitchen Projects 

 

  

 

 We provide one-stop service for you, who is going to open restaurant for yourself  

 or for your clients. You might not know what kind of equipment do you need. You  

 might not know if Chinese kitchen equipments are good enough for your standard.  

 You might not know which one to chose. You don&apos;t even know where to start. Don&apos;t  

 worry. Topkitch will help you to solve all the issue and concern by our years experience  

 to assist our clients&apos; kitchen projects. No matter your restaurant is big, or small,  

 western one or eastern one, we will always be there if you would like to chose us as  

 your partner.  

   

 *What you need to do if you want to purchase the wholes set of kitchen equipments  

 from Topkitch which is in China, or your restaurants which are not in China?  

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

The pizza oven

 

 

The conveyor pizza oven

 

 

 

The dish washer

 

 

 

The pasta cooker

 

  

 

Salamander

 

 

 

Dough spiral mixer

 

 

Salad / Pizza work table

 

 

Gas range with oven

 

 

The Fryer

  

 

Counter Table With Sink

 

 

Work Table With Shelf

  
 
 Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment
 
Get Latest Price
 
To get an accurate quote from the supplier, enter your detailed requirements below:
 
 From: Enter email or Member ID 
 Email or Member ID is required. Password: Enter Alibaba.com Password 
 Password is required. Forgot your password? Enter the code shown: Load new image code is required 
 Example: Add order quantity, product type etc. Dear Ms. Renee Ng,
Please send me your best price for Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment Enter between 20 to 8,000 characters. OK Email to this supplier «Prev Product 1 2 3 4 5 Next Product» 
Other Products from this Supplier
 Italian restaurant Kitchen Equipment Hotel restaurant Kitchen Equipment Dish washing machine&amp;kitchen equipment Restaurant/Hotel Kitchen Equipment Commercial Kitchen Equipment Gas Soup Kettle Commercial Kitchen Equipment Electric Soup Kettle Commercial Kitchen Equipment Electric Soup Kettle Commercial Kitchen Equipment Gas Soup Kettle CE certificate Dish washer&amp;kitchen equipment CE certificate Conveyor Dishwasher&amp;kitchen equipment 
See more Kitchen equipment ,  Restaurant equipment ,  kitchen equipment for restaurant products from this supplier.

 
 Want to get more exact suppliers with detailed quotations? Post an RFQ now&gt;&gt; 
 Not sure about product quality? Find reliable inspectors to help ensure product quality! 
 Related Searches: product cart , processing machine , food processing machines , packaging machinery technology , meat grinding , smoked meat , wastewater treatment process , maki sushi , cookie dough balls , rabbit meat processing More.. 
 Verified Company
 Guangzhou Topkitch Kitchen Equipment Co., Ltd. [
 Guangdong,
 China (Mainland) ] 
 A&amp;V; Check 


 View Contact Details Add Company to Favorites 
 Product Showcase 
 
 Products [726] 

 Kitchen/Restarent Project Equipment [13] 
 Western/American Resetaurant [1] Fast Food Restaurant [1] Italian Restaurant [5] 
 Snack Machine [128] Western Kitchen Equipment [111] BBQ Grill [42] Bread Making Equipment [47] Ice Cream Equipment [75] Oven [74] Meat Processing Equipment [51] Middle East Grill [13] Fast Food Equipment [11] Ice Makers [31] Vegetable and Fruit Equipment [14] Commercial Refrigeration Equipment [116] 
 


 Email this page Bookmark this page Print this page 
 Company Information - Site Map - Partnerships 
 Buy - Sell - My Alibaba - Community - Trade Shows - Safety&amp;Security - Help - Contact Us 


Browse by: Manufacturers - Wholesalers - China Gold Suppliers - All Products - Countries - Importers - Buying Leads - China - India - UK - Australia 

 Alibaba Group : 
 Alibaba.com: Alibaba China - Alibaba International - AliExpress | Taobao Marketplace | Taobao Mall | eTao | Juhuasuan | Alibaba Cloud Computing | China Yahoo! | Alipay 

 Product Listing Policy - Intellectual Property Policy and Infringement Claims - Privacy Policy - Terms of Use 

 Copyright Notice ©1999-2012
 Alibaba.com Hong Kong Limited and licensors. All rights reserved.
 _&amp;page;_&amp;content;_&amp;is;_&amp;ok;_
	</body>
</document>
