<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005806" url="http://www.digitalsignagetoday.com/article/163050/Krystal-drive-in-menus-now-feature-digital-signage" time="2012-07-12-22:27" support="7" score="0.020480605932525497" bingtitle="Krystal drive-in menus now feature digital signage ..." webtitle="Krystal drive-in menus now feature digital signage | DigitalSignageToday.com">
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000348" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000850" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001479" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000598" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>... of choices available on the digital menu board. The customer&apos;s order ... dining experience to a modern fast-food restaurant ... Nationwide Installation and Support ...</description>
	<body>
		Get Free Membership | Sign In | Advertise 
 
 Home Features News Blogs Videos Photos Webinars White Papers Products&amp;Suppliers▼ 
 Companies by Name Companies by Category Products&amp;Services Submit RFI to Suppliers 
 Research Centers▼ 
 3D Digital Signage Advertising Audience Measurement Banks / Financial Cellular Signage Cloud-Based Digital Signage Content Content Management Corporate Communication Customer Experience Digital Billboards Digital Merchandising Display Technology Distributors / Resellers DOOH Advertising Education / Schools Entertainment Venues FAQ 
 
 Hardware Healthcare / Hospitals Hotels Installation / Integration Interactive / Touchscreen LED Signs Menu Boards Mobile Interactivity Networks Outdoor Signage Restaurants Retail Software Transportation / Travel Trends / Statistics Wayfinding 
 Events ▼ 
 Follow on Twitter Follow on LinkedIn Follow on Facebook Follow on RSS Newsletter Sign Up 
 Project Help 
 Research Centers 3D Digital Signage Advertising Audience Measurement Banks / Financial Cellular Signage Cloud-Based Digital Signage Content Content Management Corporate Communication Customer Experience Digital Billboards Digital Merchandising Display Technology Distributors / Resellers DOOH Advertising Education / Schools Entertainment Venues FAQ Hardware Healthcare / Hospitals Hotels Installation / Integration Interactive / Touchscreen LED Signs Menu Boards Mobile Interactivity Networks Outdoor Signage Restaurants Retail Software Transportation / Travel Trends / Statistics Wayfinding 
 
 Get help from all our vendors with one click. 
 
 
 
Krystal drive-in menus now feature digital signage
 Tags: Menu Boards , Restaurants , Scala, Inc. September 9, 2008 
 EXTON, Pa.— Scala , a provider of end-to-end solutions for the connected signage market, has announced Krystal Restaurants of Chattanooga, Tenn., is delivering a unique customer experience at it &apos;50s style drive-up restaurant.   Founded in 1932, The Krystal Company is the oldest quick service restaurant chain in the Southeast and the second oldest chain in the United States.   The Krystal Restaurant located in Chattanooga wanted to design its restaurant with a &apos;50s traditional theme of drive-in eating with cars selecting meal choices from a menu available at the car location. The meal would then be delivered to the car by &quot;car hops&quot; and customers would typically relax in their car and eat their meal or take it out.   While Krystal wanted to maintain this &quot;retro&quot; look but also wanted to enhance the customer dining experience and introduce efficiencies of modern fast food restaurants. Krystal contacted Hammond Communications Group, who designed a unique digital menu board experience for Krystal&apos;s customers.   The Hammond Group, a Scala Certified Partner, created a solution that utilized a three-zone layout to narrowcast rich media (video, graphics and audio), a live TV signal and text crawl to multiple displays.   Although the system included interior displays, it is the application for exterior signage that is truly unique. Each car stall is equipped with a traditional backlit menu board with 32-inch LCD displays. Hammond customized the solution so that screen content is triggered upon the car&apos;s arrival and departure and controlled by the customer who can elect to scroll through a menu, watch TV and more.   Sensors in the parking stall detect when a car approaches triggering the digital menu board to activate the screen. The customer selects a meal of choice from the myriad of choices available on the digital menu board. The customer&apos;s order is dynamically sent to the restaurant where the order is prepared in the kitchen and &quot;car hops&quot; deliver it directly to the customer&apos;s car.   If the customer chooses to eat in the car, the digital menu board provides an entertainment option consisting of a live TV feed for the local Chattanooga area. Audio is piped into the car through a specific station on the car&apos;s FM radio.   The installation of the digital menu boards with digital meal ordering and live television feed is integral to the overall image of the restaurant. The solution allows Krystal Restaurant to maintain its &quot;retro&quot; look and feel while upgrading the customer dining experience to a modern fast-food restaurant deliver process. 
Related Content

 
 Obamacare may ramp up digital menu board adoption 
 Food trucks hitting the road with digital menu… 
 Why deploy digital menu boards? Key benefits and… 
 Get help from all our vendors with one click. 
 
 Reader Comments 
Add a Comment

We welcome your thoughtful comments. All comments will display your real name.
 
Want to participate in the discussion?

 Register for Free 

Or log in for complete access.
 Email me when comments are added. 
 Clear Post 
 Be the first to post a comment for this story. 
Features

 &apos;Green&apos; wayfinding kiosks making splash at Ireland&apos;s National Aquatic Centre Social media &apos;changes everything&apos; for digital signage kiosks Skype Station digital signage kiosks taking off »View More Features 
 Sponsored by: 
News

 Chief turning digital displays interactive Keywest Tech updates MediaZone Pro digital signage software Webinar: Taking DOOH outdoors ... Literally »View More News 
 
Blogs

 Digital signage + social media = big opportunities The separation of tech and art Digital signage finds its voice »View More Blogs 
 
User Comments

 I was so facinated by many of new introduced technologies @infoComm12… I am a huge believer in social media for marketing, and I believe that… Part of me sees how a Skype Station could add value, but a larger part of… 
 Photo Gallery 
466

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show466_thumb6865.jpg

Skype Station taking off

Skype Station taking off

458

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show458_thumb6753.jpg

Olea kiosks now in Bon-Ton

Olea kiosks now in Bon-Ton

454

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show454_thumb6691.jpg

Portugal airports liven up with multitouch solutions

Portugal airports liven up with multitouch solutions

386

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show386_thumb6597.jpg

Digital signage on cabs and loos at Screenmedia Expo 2012

Digital signage on cabs and loos at Screenmedia Expo 2012

437

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show437_thumb6283.jpg

DSE 2012: The picture show, Part II

DSE 2012: The picture show, Part II

435

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show435_thumb6217.jpg

DSE 2012: The picture show, Part I

DSE 2012: The picture show, Part I

431

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show431_thumb6137.jpg

Digital signage news photo gallery for February

Digital signage news photo gallery for February

426

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show426_thumb6029.jpg

January digital signage news slide show

January digital signage news slide show

406

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show406_thumb5639.jpg

DSA Crown Awards

DSA Crown Awards

399

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/slideshows/show399_thumb5537.jpg

Keywest enters kiosk market

Keywest enters kiosk market
 
 
Skype Station taking off
 
Olea kiosks now in Bon-Ton
 
Portugal airports liven up with multitouch solutions
 
Digital signage on cabs and loos at Screenmedia Expo 2012
 
 »View More Photos Products&amp;Services 
LG M4210LCBA - 42&quot; class (42.0&quot; measured diagonally

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4314.png

4314/LG-M4210LCBA-42-class-42-0-measured-diagonally

Digital Signage Mounts

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/4035.png

4035/Digital-Signage-Mounts

AccuWeather

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/accu_title.jpg

3027/AccuWeather

Life-Size Infinite Touchscreen

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/5057.png

5057/Life-Size-Infinite-Touchscreen

VX2450wm-LED Monitor

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/image8_small.jpg

3997/VX2450wm-LED-Monitor

Black Box HDMI Matrix Switches

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/3192.png

3192/Black-Box-HDMI-Matrix-Switches

Commercial Grade quality for single or multi unit deployments

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/E_Family_150px.jpg

3956/Commercial-Grade-quality-for-single-or-multi-unit-deployments

Content Management Software - Remote Transfer

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/remote_transfer_100.gif

184/Content-Management-Software-Remote-Transfer

CD3225 Commercial Display

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/image7_small.jpg

3996/CD3225-Commercial-Display

U340 - DFI Technologies

http://global.networldalliance.com/new/images/products/U340.gif

3448/U340-DFI-Technologies
 
 
LG M4210LCBA - 42&quot; class (42.0&quot; measured diagonally
 
Digital Signage Mounts
 
AccuWeather
 
Life-Size Infinite Touchscreen
 
 »View More Products Most Popular 
 Read Emailed Discussed 
 
 Skype Station digital signage kiosks taking off Obamacare may ramp up digital menu board adoption 5 Things: Five tips to stay ahead of the digital signage evolution Social media &apos;changes everything&apos; for digital signage kiosks Skype Station digital signage kiosks taking off 
 
 No data available. 
 
 InfoComm12: 7 digital signage trends (Commentary) Skype Station digital signage kiosks taking off Retail tech heats up to beat holiday shopping lockdown New technology allows buttons to pop up from touchscreens Social media &apos;changes everything&apos; for digital signage kiosks 
 Sponsored by: White Papers 
 Newest Popular 
 
 New Embedded Solution Made Possible by using Intel Architecture in Transparent Displays Next-Generation Vending Machine Based on Intel® Architecture Features Large Transparent Display Screen and Intel® AIM Suite - Anonymous Viewer Analytics Point-of-Sale Meets Mobility and Functional Flexibility Standardization Simplifies the Delivery of Digital Signage Solutions Designing Intel® vPro™ technology Capable OPS Display Panels 
 
 Four Considerations for Digital Signage Implementation in Education Subway Uses Digital Signage to Increase Sales and Improve Customer Experience Webinar: How to Make your Digital Signage Pay for Itself Infographic: 12 Benefits of Digital Menu Boards The Airport Express in Hong Kong 
 Sponsored by: Video Gallery Find the Titanic! Static to dynamic: Cross-applicability of NFC RedDotNet launches NFC integrated kiosk Sponsored by: »View More Videos Request Information From Suppliers Save time looking for suppliers. Complete this form to submit a Request for Information to our entire network of partners. Tell us what you&apos;re looking for... 
 Inside Networld Media Group Network 

 Self-Service World 
 Energy-saving kiosks functioning swimmingly in Irish aquatic center Indian electric company deploying bill-pay kiosks Paymentus introduces mobile billing, payment solution 

 Popular on Networld Media Group 
 Digital Signage Software Comparison Guide Digital Signage Future Trends Report Retail Digital Signage ROI Digital Signage Reference Library for Retail Mobile Payments 
 Other Networld Media Group Sites 
 ATM Marketplace Church Central Digital Signage Today Fast Casual Fast Casual Executive Summit Kiosk Marketplace Pizza Marketplace QSR Web Retail Customer Experience Retail Customer Experience Executive Summit Self-Service World 
 Global Partners 
 Digital Screenmedia Association LG Electronics USA, Inc. NEC Display Solutions Nanonation Symon Hewlett-Packard Company 
 


 DigitalSignageToday.com Home | Showcases | Privacy Policy | Submit RFI | Editorial Policy | About Us | Contact Us 

 Bloggers | Advertise | Mobile Version | Site Map | RSS | News Panel 

 ©2012 Networld Media Group All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
