<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005264" url="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/martysjotd/messages/1332?xm=1&amp;m=e&amp;l=1" time="2012-07-12-21:47" support="6" score="0.00956980587076662" bingtitle="martysjotd : Messages : 1332-1361 of 1600" webtitle="martysjotd : Messages : 1332-1361 of 1600">
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>... were spotless, and the mess-hall tables and condiment ... I then went on to add fries to my order, and he ... pulled up to the drive-thru of a fast-food restaurant and ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Groups 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 martysjotd ·Marty&apos;s Clean Jokes of the Day 
 
 Home Messages Attachments 
 
 Members Only Files Photos Links Polls Calendar Promote 
 
 Info Settings 
 
Group Information

 Members: 4005 Category: Humor Founded: Mar 15, 2000 Language: English 
 Already a member? Sign in to Yahoo! 
Yahoo! Groups Tips

Did you know...
 Message search is now enhanced, find messages faster. Take it for a spin. 
 
Messages
   Messages Help 
 
 Message # Search: Advanced 

 Messages 1332 - 1361 of 1600  Oldest  |  &lt; Older  |  Newer &gt;  |  Newest 
 
 Messages: Show Message Summaries  ( Group by Topic ) Sort by Date   #1332 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Feb 2, 2006 3:39 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 8:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, February 01, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

The other day my sweet wife called son #4&apos;s new teacher at the
preschool for the blind, and asked how son #4 was doing. She said,&quot;Oh, he&apos;s doing great. I wish all of the other kids did everything I
asked them to.&quot;Cool...

Then today my sweet wife went out to son #4&apos;s bus (van) driver and
asked him how son #4 was doing on the bus ride to and from school.&quot;Oh, he&apos;s doing very well. He&apos;s having a positive influence on the
other kids.&quot;My wife thought, yeah, right. Then bus driver went on
to say,&quot;Every time one of the kids says something bad [`stupid
head&apos;] son #4 corrects them and says something like, `that&apos;s rude,
don&apos;t say that&apos; or when they say `shut up&apos; he says `that&apos;s not nice,
we don&apos;t say that at our house&apos;&quot;Hmm...

A good start, but hopefully not too self righteous.

Tomorrow it&apos;s son #4&apos;s Antarctica trip. They&apos;re `flying&apos; there and
spending a lot of time outside looking for penguins. Next week they
get to go swimming.

Hey, I want to go...

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

The&quot;big Texas burger&quot;story reminded me of an embarrassing moment
I had in my days as a flight attendant. I was counting empty seats
on an almost full airplane so we could board some standby
passengers. A very large lady was making her way down the aisle
to her seat as I called out to the ticket agent,&quot;She makes
two.&quot;After her dirty look, I was too embarrassed to explain
what I meant!
~Betty H.

[Oops!]

_________________________________________________________



A blonde, a brunette and a redhead apply for a position at a large
company. First the brunette goes in. The guy looks over her
application and asks her one question:&quot;How many D&apos;s are there in
&apos;Bonanza&apos;?&quot;The brunette replies,&quot;None.&quot;The guy says,&quot;OK, you may go into the next room for the next
stage of the interviewing process.&quot;The redhead goes in next. The
guy asks her the same question:&quot;How many D&apos;s are in &apos;Bonanza&apos;?&quot;She replies,&quot;None.&quot;The guy says,&quot;OK, you may go into the next room.&quot;The blonde goes
in and he asks the same question:&quot;How many D&apos;s are in &apos;Bonanza&apos;?&quot;After counting on her fingers for a few minutes the blonde
replies:&quot;77.&quot;The guy, in shock, asks her how she came up with 77. She says:&quot;Dun da da dun dun da dun dun da da&quot;(the Bonanza theme)...&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;An old man was critically ill. Feeling that death was near, he
called his lawyer.&quot;I want to become a lawyer. How much is it or
the express degree you told me about?&quot;&quot;It&apos;s $50,000,&quot;the lawyer said.&quot;But why? You&apos;ll be dead soon,
why do you want to become a lawyer?&quot;&quot;That&apos;s my business! Get me the course!&quot;Four days later, the old man got his law degree. His lawyer was at
his bedside, making sure his bill would be paid.

Suddenly the old man was racked with fits of coughing and it was
clear that this would be the end. Still curious, the lawyer leaned
over and said,&quot;Please, before it&apos;s too late, tell me why you
wanted to get a law degree so badly before you died?&quot;In a faint whisper, as he breathed his last, the old man said,&quot;One less lawyer......&quot;_________________________________________________________



The computer in my high school classroom recently started acting
up. After watching me struggle with it, one of my students came up
and took over.&quot;Your hard drive crashed,&quot;he said. I called the
computer services office and explained,&quot;My computer is down. The
hard drive crashed.&quot;&quot;We can&apos;t just send people down on your say-
so. How do you know that&apos;s the problem?&quot;&quot;A student told me,&quot;I
answered.&quot;We&apos;ll send someone over right away.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (2)   #1333 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Feb 3, 2006 5:05 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 10:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ******************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ******************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, February 02, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Tonight is the first day of real play practice. All the rest of
was just that silly singing stuff. Of course, I dont have a singing
part, so we practiced lines tonight. Heir Zeller has a pretty small
part, but I dont mind. My sweet wife doesnt have any speaking
parts either, but lots of singing. When son #2 and I walked out of
the door, he looked at my 4 single sheets of copied paper, looked at
his 1/2 inch think bound notebook that my sweet wife made for him,
and he laughed and laughed. I got more lines then you do! Humpf...
yeah, but I get to watch more of the play then you do, naaner
naaner. And, I dont have to memorize as many. See, I can look on
the bright side of things.

It appears that son #4s hair is coming back in places. Theres
still a huge chunk thats hasnt grown anything yet, but some of it
has a tiny little bit of peach fuzz. Yipee!

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy todays Jokes!
Marty



=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:&gt;&quot;Tomorrow it&apos;s son #4&apos;s Antarctica trip. They&apos;re `flying&apos; there&gt;and spending a lot of time outside looking for penguins. Next week&gt;they get to go swimming.&quot;Are you serious?
~Sandra H.

[Um, no. It was pretend day (Grin)]

_________________________________________________________



The story goes that four ministers had a series of theological
arguments, and three were always in accord against the fourth.

One day, the odd minister out, after the usual&quot;3 to 1 majority
rules&quot;statement that signified that he had lost again, decided to
appeal to a *higher* authority.&quot;Oh, Lord!&quot;he cried.&quot;I know in my heart that I am right and they
are wrong! Please give me a sign to prove it to them!&quot;It was a beautiful, sunny day. As soon as the minister finished his
prayer, a storm cloud moved across the sky above the four. It
rumbled once and dissolved.&quot;A sign from God! See, I&apos;m right, I knew it!&quot;But the other three
disagreed, pointing out that storm clouds form on hot days.

So the minister prayed again:&quot;Oh, God, I need a bigger sign to show that I am right and they are
wrong. So please, Lord, a bigger sign!&quot;This time four storm clouds appeared, rushed toward each other to
form one big cloud, and a bolt of lightning slammed into a tree on
a nearby hill.&quot;I told you I was right!&quot;cried the minister, but his friends
insisted that nothing had happened that could not be explained by
natural causes.

The minister was getting ready to ask for a *very big* sign, but
just as he said,&quot;Oh God...,&quot;the sky turned pitch black, the earth
shook, and a deep, booming voice intoned,&quot;HEEEEEEEE&apos;S RIIIIIIIGHT!&quot;The minister put his hands on his hips, turned to the other three,
and said,&quot;Well?!&quot;&quot;So,&quot;shrugged one of the other ministers,&quot;now it&apos;s 3 to 2.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A man sought medical aid because he had &apos;popped eyes&apos; and some
ringing in his ears. A doctor looked him over and suggested removal
of his tonsils. Well, the operation resulted in no improvement, so
the patient consulted another doctor, who suggested removal of his
teeth. The teeth were extracted, but still, the man&apos;s eyes were
popped and the ringing in his ears continued. A third doctor told
him bluntly,&quot;I&apos;d say you&apos;ve got only six months to live.&quot;In that
event, the doomed man decided he&apos;d treat himself right, while he
still could. He bought a flashy car, hired a chauffeur, and had the
best tailor in town make him 30 suits. Then he decided that even
his shirts would be made-to-order.&quot;Okay,&quot;sai the shirt maker,&quot;let&apos;s get your measurements. Hmmm.... 34 sleeve, 16 collar....&quot;&quot;Ah, that&apos;s &apos;fifteen collar&apos;,&quot;the man corrected him.&quot;Nope!
Sixteen collar,&quot;the shirt maker repeated, measuring once again.&quot;But I&apos;ve *always* worn a 15 collar,&quot;said the man.&quot;Look,&quot;the
shirt maker says,&quot;I&apos;m warning you... You keep wearing a 15 collar
and your eyes will pop and you&apos;ll have ringing in your ears!&quot;_________________________________________________________



In the mid-1950s my father completed a tour of duty at Elmendorf
Air Force Base in Anchorage, Alaska. We were stationed with him and
returned to Seattle aboard the troopship USS Funston. As troop
commander, Dad was charged with conducting daily inspections of the
men&apos;s quarters, galley and mess hall. My four-year-old brother,
Stuart, tagged along one day. As usual, the galley gleamed, the
floors were spotless, and the mess-hall tables and condiment
containers were aligned with military precision. My father was
about to pass the inspection when Stuart piped up,&quot;Daddy, look at
all the gum under the table!&quot;Dad bent down to the eye level of a
small child, and was horrified to see years&apos; worth of petrified
chewing gum covering the bottoms of the tables. The mess hall did
not pass inspection until later that day and the troops who scraped
off all that gum could happily have thrown my little brother in the
brig.

=-=-=-

Abe is a new arrival at a retirement community and is passing the
morning sunning himself on a bench near the garden. Becky is out
for her morning constitutional, spies Abe, and says&quot;Do you mind?&quot;&quot;Not at all&quot;Abe says, so Becky sits down on the opposite end of
his bench.&quot;So, you&apos;re new here&quot;says Becky.&quot;Yes&quot;Abe nods.&quot;So,
where are you from?&quot;asks Becky.&quot;Washington&quot;Abe answers.&quot;The
state or the capitol?&quot;asks Becky.&quot;The state&quot;replies Abe.&quot;So how
old are you ? asks Becky.&quot;I&apos;ll be 52 in October.&quot;. Abe replies&quot;What did you do in Washington?&quot;asks Becky.&quot;I was in prison&quot;Abe
says.&quot;Really!&quot;says Becky,&quot;what did you do?&quot;&quot;My wife was always
asking stupid questions, so I chopped her up and put her down the
garbage disposal&quot;he says.&quot;Sooo,&quot;purrs Becky,&quot;you&apos;re single?&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1334 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Feb 7, 2006 5:19 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, February 06, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

We had a great time watching the Super Bowl on Sunday. I made a
`bet&apos; with one of my 12 year old Scouts of a candy bar. (I told
him,&quot;I want a big fat one-pounder if I win!&quot;) It was a little
discouraging when my boys gave me a hard time after I won.&quot;Dad,
you&apos;re not supposed to bet! Gambling is wrong...&quot;Sheez, who
raised these little boys anyway?

It was funny during the half time show, I had to explain to my
boys who the Rolling Stones were, and that they were once (still?)
a really popular band. I don&apos;t think they believed me. Then I told
them what Keith Richards was famous for. Then they saw how old the
stones were. Every time 62 year old Mick would wiggle his hips,
son #1 would laugh and say,&quot;LOOk! there, he did it again! That&apos;s
so funny!&quot;Then son #2 said,&quot;I&apos;ll be he&apos;s wearing a lot of make
up!&quot;I said,&quot;Why?&quot;He laughed and said,&quot;To cover up all of his
liver spots!&quot;I think they need someone half way in between Janet
Jackson and Mick Jagger. Maybe the Mo-Tabs? Ha... I don&apos;t think
so.

You&apos;ve got to admit, Mick did look a little dated. So, tell me,
who would you pick if you could have anyone for the Super Bowl
half time?

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

All Quiet today...
_________________________________________________________



After watching the movie Cinderella, five-year-old Sarah started
using her pinwheel as a magic wand, pretending she was a fairy
godmother.&quot;Make three wishes,&quot;she told her mother,&quot;and I&apos;ll
grant them.&quot;Her mom first asked for world peace. Sarah swung her
wand and proclaimed the request fulfilled. Next, her mother
requested a cure for all ill children. Again, with a sweep of the
pinwheel, Sarah obliged. The mother, with a glance down at her
rather ample curves, made her third wish:&quot;I wish to have a trim
figure again.&quot;The miniature fairy godmother started waving her
wand madly.&quot;I&apos;ll need more power for this!&quot;she exclaimed.

=-=-=-

A young ventriloquist is touring the clubs and stops to entertain
at a bar in a small town. He&apos;s going through his usual run of
stupid blonde jokes when a large, blonde woman in the fourth row
stands on her chair and says,&quot;I&apos;ve heard just about enough of
your denigrating blonde jokes! What makes you think you can
stereotype women that way? What does a person&apos;s physical
attributes have to do with their worth as a human being?&quot;The
ventriloquist looks on in amazement.&quot;It&apos;s guys like you who keep
women like me from being respected at work and in my community,&quot;she continued,&quot;and of reaching my full potential as a person
because you and your kind continue to perpetuate discrimination
against not only blondes but women at large... all in the name of
humor.&quot;Flustered, the ventriloquist begins to apologize. The
blonde interjects,&quot;You stay out of this, mister. I&apos;m talking to
that little guy on your knee!&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;My wife and I were sitting in the living room and I said to her,&quot;Just so you know, I never want to live in a vegetative state,
dependent on some machine and fluids from a bottle. If that ever
happens, just pull the plug.&quot;She got up, unplugged the TV and
threw out all of my beer!

=-=-=-

Today we mourn the passing of a beloved old friend, Mr. Common
Sense.

Mr. Sense had been with us for many years. No one knows for sure
how old he was since his birth records were long ago lost in
bureaucratic red tape.

He will be remembered as having cultivated such valuable lessons
as knowing when to come in out of the rain, why the early bird
gets the worm, and that life isn&apos;t always fair.

Common Sense lived by simple, sound financial policies (don&apos;t
spend more than you earn) and reliable parenting strategies
(adults, not kids, are in charge).

His health began to rapidly deteriorate when well-intentioned but
overbearing regulations were set in place.

Reports of a six-year-old boy charged with sexual harassment for
kissing a classmate, teens suspended from school for using
mouthwash after lunch, and a teacher fired for reprimanding an
unruly student only worsened his condition.

Mr. Sense declined even further when schools were required to get
parental consent to administer aspirin to a student, but could not
inform the parents when a student became pregnant and wanted to
have an abortion.

Finally, Common Sense lost the will to live as the Ten
Commandments became contraband, churches became businesses, and
criminals received better treatment than their victims. Common
Sense finally gave up the ghost after a woman failed to realize
that a steaming cup of coffee was hot, then she spilled a bit in
her lap and was awarded a huge financial settlement.

Common Sense was preceded in death by his parents, Truth and
Trust; his wife, Discretion; his daughter, Responsibility; and his
son, Reason. He is survived by two stepbrothers: My Rights and Ima
Whiner.

Not many attended his funeral because so few realized he was gone.

_________________________________________________________



Mr. Swiller was known far and wide as a hard-nosed boss who
watched his employees like a hawk. He was making one of his
regular tours of the factory when he spotted a young man leaning
against a pile of boxes just outside the foreman&apos;s office. Since
George, the foreman, wasn&apos;t around, Swiller stood off to the side
and watched to see just how long the young man would stand around
doing nothing. The young man yawned, scratched his head, looked at
his watch, and sat on the floor. He took out a nail file and began
cleaning his nails. Then he stretched, yawned again, and leaned
back on the pile of boxes. Swiller stepped from his hiding place
and walked up to the young man.&quot;You!&quot;he boomed.&quot;How much do you
make a week?&quot;The young man looked up indifferently.&quot;Two hundred
and fifty dollars,&quot;he said. Swiller swooped into the cashier&apos;s
office, took $250 from the cash box, and returned.&quot;Take it,&quot;he
said,&quot;and get out! Don&apos;t let me see you around here again!&quot;The
young man took the cash, put it in his pocket, and left. Swiller
snorted at his lack of remorse, embarrassment, or any other
feeling. Then he went looking for George. When he found him,
Swiller was red with anger.&quot;That idler in front of your office,&quot;Swiller said.&quot;I just gave him a week&apos;s pay and fired him. What&apos;s
the matter with you, letting him stand around as though he had
nothing to do?&quot;&quot;You mean the kid in the red shirt?&quot;George asked.&quot;Yes! The kid in the red shirt!&quot;&quot;He was waiting for the twenty
dollars we owe him for lunch,&quot;George said.&quot;He works for the
coffee shop around the corner.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (9) #1335 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Feb 8, 2006 5:48 am
 Subject: Tuesday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Tuesday, February 07, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

My sweet wife sat down with son #4 today, and asked him,&quot;So, how
is school going? Do you like it? Are you doing ok?&quot;He said,&quot;Yeah, most of it is fun, but sometimes I have to sit
down even when I don&apos;t want to, and pay attention. Sometimes it&apos;s
even boring.&quot;Hmm... Welcome to the real world kid.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Still quiet today

_________________________________________________________



During a tour of duty as a security specialist in the 379th
Security Police Squadron at Wurtsmith Air Force Base, Mich., I
broke my right hand. As I was fitted with a cast that stretched
from mid-arm to the middle of my fingers, I was told that I
couldn&apos;t be issued a weapon while taking the prescribed pain
medication. I would be posted at the main gate, instead of my
normal duty station. That afternoon, dressed in blues -- complete
with beret and crisp, white ascot -- I was in my glory, proudly
waving people through. My exalted feelings were cut short,
however, when an officer drove up to the gate. After checking his
I.D., I stepped back, gave him my best&quot;polished&quot;salute -- and
soundly smacked myself in the head with my cast.

~Wanda D.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;My kindergarten-aged daughter suddenly announced just before
school that she needed to take a clean tee shirt to class. She
told us the teacher was going to iron an anti-drug message on it.
My wife frantically swept through my daughter&apos;s room, finding
nothing usable but one tee shirt that already had something
printed on one side. She sent it off to school with my daughter.
That afternoon, my daughter returned and happily showed off her
shirt. On one side it said,&quot;Families are Forever.&quot;And on the
other,&quot;Be Smart, Don&apos;t Start.&quot;_________________________________________________________



Women have strengths that amaze men.
They bear hardships and they carry burdens,
but they hold happiness, love and joy.
They smile when they want to scream.
They sing when they want to cry.
They cry when they are happy
and laugh when they are nervous.
They fight for what they believe in.
They stand up to injustice.
They don&apos;t take&quot;no&quot;for an answer
when they believe there is a better solution.
They go without so their family can have.
They go to the doctor with a frightened friend.
They love unconditionally.
They cry when their children excel
and cheer when their friends get awards.
They are happy when they hear about
a birth or a wedding.
Their hearts break when a friend dies.
They grieve at the loss of a family member,
yet they are strong when they
think there is no strength left.
They know that a hug and a kiss
can heal a broken heart.
Women come in all shapes, sizes and colors.
They&apos;ll drive, fly, walk, run or e-mail you
to show how much they care about you.
The heart of a woman is what
makes the world keep turning.
They bring joy, hope and love.
They have compassion and ideas.
They give moral support to their
family and friends.
Women have vital things to say
and everything to give.
HOWEVER, IF THERE IS ONE FLAW IN WOMEN,
IT IS THAT THEY FORGET THEIR WORTH.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1336 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Feb 8, 2006 4:00 pm
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Special Morning Edition martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ******************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ******************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, February 08, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Special Morning Edition;

Ok, every year I get a little annoyed with one of my local radio
stations. They always have a fund raising Radio-thon for a day in
February for Primary Children&apos;s hospital. This hospital doesn&apos;t
turn anyone away for lack of money. But, I was always a little
calloused and just flipped the channel to one of my other stations.

Well, things have a way of changing your mind, now don&apos;t they? I&apos;ve
told you all of our wonderful miracles that have happened in this
hospital, and son #4&apos;s tumor. This year I think maybe we ought to
show our support by donating a penny for each reader who reads my
column. Today we have 5,739 readers. So, I&apos;m challenging each of
you to donate $57.39 to this worthy cause. I did!

You can donate by going here http://www.ksl.com/index.php?sid=158958&amp;nid=352 And you can listen to them on-line at http://www.ksl.com/?nid=21 Marty

=-=-=-
Here&apos;s a note I put in with my donation;

My PCMC Story;

Since March of 2000 I&apos;ve written&quot;Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day&quot;, a
humorous Internet blog about raising 4 boys in Utah with&quot;my sweet
wife&quot;. In August of 2005, Doctors at PCMC found a lemon-sized brain
tumor in my 4-year old son. When my 5,739 readers across the world
found out about his tumor, everyone prayed for help during his 2
surgeries. I&apos;m convinced that because of these prayers, with divine
intervention, and the skill of the surgeons at PCMC, my 4 year old
is making a wonderful recovery. Two weeks ago he even started
preschool at the Utah&quot;preschool for the blind&quot;. I&apos;m donating
$57.39 for each of my readers, and challenge each of them to donate
the same amount to this wonderful hospital.

You can read our story here http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/2005/08/81-start-here.html or here http://groups.yahoo.com/group/martysjotd/ Marty martysjotd@... 
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #1337 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Feb 9, 2006 5:43 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, February 08, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

While my sweet wife ran to school to pick up son #1 today, son #2
called her and&quot;freaked out&quot;on the phone because son #4 had a
nose bleed. Son #2 was really worried about it and told my sweet
wife to hurry home as fast as she could. When she got home, she
took care of everything.

Last year we signed our other 3 boys up for Super Sibs. It&apos;s a
group that helps siblings of kids who have cancer, so they don&apos;t
feel left out. ( http://www.supersibs.org/ ). Anyway, they sent son
#2 a book called Drums, Girls, and Dangerous Pie. It&apos;s a story
about a typical 8th grader whose 4 year old brother has a nose
bleed, and it turns out to be leukemia.

So, I guess we&apos;re still just a little jittery here...

On the lighter side, son #4 has been asking my sweet wife to drive
him to school every day. She was worried that he was starting not
to like school, and wanted her with him all day long. After she
talked to him today, she found out the truth. It turns out that
after he gets dressed in the morning and eats breakfast, he runs
to the window to look for the school bus/van. If it isn&apos;t there,
he just wants a quicker way to school. Apparently he&apos;s too
impatient to wait. http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0439755190/sr=1- 1/qid=1139462365/ref=sr_1_1/002-5009514-5830421?%5Fencoding=UTF8

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:


_________________________________________________________



Mr. Peterson, a tourist from Toronto, arrived in Israel. In an
airport taxi cab, Peterson asked the driver,&quot;Say, is this really
a healthful place?&quot;&quot;It sure is,&quot;the cabby replied.&quot;When I came
here I couldn&apos;t say one word. I had hardly any hair on my head. I
didn&apos;t have the strength to walk across a room, and I had to be
lifted out of bed!&quot;&quot;That&apos;s wonderful!&quot;said the tourist,&quot;How
long have you been here?&quot;&quot;I was born here.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A Sunday School teacher was trying to explain about saying grace
before meals. One of the pupils was the young son of the minister
of that church, so she started the discussion by asking him,&quot;Jerry, what does you father say when the family sits down to
dinner?&quot;Jerry answers. . .&quot;Dad says &apos;Go easy on the butter,
kids. It&apos;s three dollars a pound!&quot;_________________________________________________________



A wealthy playboy met a beautiful young girl in an exclusive
lounge. He took her to his lavish apartment where he soon
discovered she was not a tramp, but was well groomed and
apparently very intelligent. Hoping to impress her, he began
showing her his collection of expensive paintings, first editions
by famous authors and offered her a glass of wine. He asked
whether she preferred Port or Sherry and she said,&quot;Oh, Sherry
by all means. To me, it&apos;s the nectar of the Gods. Just looking at
it in a crystal-clear decanter fills me with a glorious sense of
anticipation. When the stopper is removed and the gorgeous liquid
is poured into my glass, I inhale the enchanting aroma and I&apos;m
lifted on the wings of ecstasy. It seems as though I&apos;m about to
drink a magic potion and my whole being begins to glow. The sound
of a thousand violins being softly played fills my ears and I&apos;m
transported into another world... On the other hand, Port makes me
fart.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1338 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Feb 10, 2006 5:32 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, February 09, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Here&apos;s a little joke.

=-=-=-

Dad,&quot;said Little Johnny,&quot;I&apos;m late for football practice. Would
you please do my homework for me?&quot;The father said irately,&quot;Son, it just wouldn&apos;t be right.&quot;&quot;That&apos;s okay,&quot;replied Little Johnny,&quot;but you could at least give
it a try, couldn&apos;t you?&quot;=-=-=-

Speaking of homework; Each year about this time, our elementary
school has a science fair. Son #2 really wanted to do good this
year, so he thought long and hard about his science experiment.
Then, every other night at 8PM he&apos;d run downstairs and yell,&quot;I&apos;ve
got to do my homework!&quot;When I walked by, he&apos;d be playing on his
computer, and I figured he was done.

The other night son #2 and #3 got in a pretty big fight. I
grounded them both from their computers, and told them that they&apos;d
also have to clean up their rooms before I&apos;d consider letting them
back on. Son #2 was devastated.&quot;How am I going to do my science
project?!&quot;It was then that I learned what his experiment was.

He wanted to see which activity would make him go to sleep faster;
Reading a book for 90 minutes, or playing on his computer for 90
minutes. He got about half way done with his experiment when dad
put the kybosh on his computer playing. (Or is it that he caused
this consequence because of his actions...?)

Anyway, these kids will come up with just about any excuse to play
on their computers.

Hmm... so what to do what to do... Oh darn. He still hasn&apos;t
cleaned his room. So, he&apos;s not played his computer either. I&apos;m so
mean.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

p.s. Have a Great weekend!

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Thanks Marty!!! That last part about women forgetting their worth
is great. [on yesterday&apos;s JOTD] I was looking for something to top
off my Valentine&apos;s gift to my wife. That will do nicely.
~Todd H.

Hi Marty,
It&apos;s wonderful that [son #4] is so happy going to school and can&apos;t
wait to get there each day! I pray that his vision improves and
he can have a long and wonderful life. He is such a little doll
and is so lucky to have such loving and caring brothers (the nose
bleed) and parents. I think of you so often and pray that all goes
well for you.
With love, Betty H.

_________________________________________________________



A frog goes into a bank and approaches the teller. He can see from
her nameplate that her name is Patricia Whack.&quot;Miss Whack, I&apos;d
like to get a $30,000 loan to take a holiday.&quot;Patty looks at the frog in disbelief and asks his name. The frog
says his name is Kermit Jagger, his dad is Mick Jagger, and that
it&apos;s okay, he knows the bank manager.

Patty explains that he will need to secure the loan with some
collateral. The frog says,&quot;Sure. I have this,&quot;and produces a
tiny porcelain elephant, about an inch tall, bright pink and
perfectly formed.

Very confused, Patty explains that she&apos;ll have to consult with the
bank manager and disappears into a back office. She finds the
manager and says,&quot;There&apos;s a frog called Kermit Jagger out there
who claims to know you and wants to borrow $30,000, and he wants
to use this as collateral.&quot;She holds up the tiny pink elephant.&quot;I mean, what in the world is this?&quot;The bank manager looks back at her and says...&quot;It&apos;s a knickknack, Patty Whack. Give the frog a loan. His old
man&apos;s a Rolling Stone.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A couple goes for a meal at a Chinese restaurant and orders the&quot;Chicken Surprise.&quot;The waiter brings the meal, served in a lidded
cast-iron pot.

Just as the wife is about to serve herself, the lid of the pot
rises slightly and she briefly sees two beady little eyes looking
around before the lid slams back down.&quot;Good grief, did you see that?&quot;she asks her husband.

He hasn&apos;t, so she asks him to look in the pot. He reaches for it
and again the lid rises, and he sees two little eyes looking
around before it slams down.

Sputtering in a fit of pique, he calls the waiter over, describes
what is happening, and demands an explanation!&quot;Please sir,&quot;says the waiter,&quot;what you order?&quot;The husband replies,&quot;Chicken Surprise.&quot;&quot;Ah... so sorry,&quot;says the waiter,&quot;I bring you Peeking Duck.&quot;~Debi S.

_________________________________________________________



A pastor asked a little boy if he said his prayers every night.&quot;Yes sir,&quot;the boy replied.&quot;And, do you always say them in the morning, too?&quot;the pastor
asked.&quot;No sir,&quot;the boy replied.&quot;I ain&apos;t scared in the daytime.&quot;=-=-=-

One day a gentleman walked into one of Ben Franklin&apos;s book stores.
As one of the clerks went to assist him, the gentleman asked the
clerk the price of the book he wished to purchase. The young clerk
looked at the price posted on the book and said,&quot;That book is one
dollar, sir.&quot;The gentleman began to haggle with the clerk over
the price. The clerk assured him that the correct price for the
book was one dollar and no lower. As the man realized that his
efforts to haggle with the clerk were going nowhere, he insisted
on speaking with Ben Franklin directly. Franklin stopped his work,
walked out to the storefront and the gentleman asked,&quot;What is the
price of this book?&quot;Franklin answered,&quot;One dollar and a
quarter.&quot;The gentleman was confused and replied,&quot;Your clerk just
said it was a dollar.&quot;Franklin looked at the book again and
answered,&quot;Yes, it was a dollar. But now you&apos;re wasting my time.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (18) #1339 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Feb 14, 2006 5:53 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
February 13, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

On my way home from work my sweet wife asked me to stop and get
some valentines for son #2 for tomorrow. While I was at the store
I called and confirmed with him that I was getting the right ones.
When I got home, my sweet wife said that son #2 had asked her to
make 4 more big&quot;special&quot;valentines.&quot;Oh, and who are these for?&quot;she asked him.&quot;Just some friends&quot;he replied. She pressed
further,&quot;So, are they for boys or for girls?&quot;&quot;Just some friends
mom.&quot;Was his reply. Like any mom, my sweet wife zeroed right in.&quot;Ok, are they at least cute girls?&quot;I think he turned beat red at
being `found out&apos;.

*sigh* Not two of `em at the same time. I keep telling myself,&quot;They tell me girls are worse, they tell me girls are worse...&quot;For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

p.s. We went to see Chicken Little tonight at the dollar theater
for family night. An interesting movie, but it was a little
intense for son #4 in the middle. He laid his head down on me and
covered his eyes at one point. Other than that, it was great.
However, I was a little disappointed at the very end. Usually we
stay until the credits are over to catch the little `extras&apos; that
they always have. Well, most always. Nothing but credits this
time. Darn.

p.p.s. This weekend we trekked another 4 hour round trip up to my
dad&apos;s house in Randolph for more cleaning. (It was my 6th trip
since Christmas day.) The talk of the town was that their town of
340 voters made the national news for voting 95% for our President
in 2004. It was the highest percentage in the country. That sure
beats their previous claim to fame as always being the coldest
spot in Utah, and often the coldest spot in the country.

( http://deseretnews.com/dn/view/0,1249,635181622,00.html )

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Hi Marty! Just want to tell you about a fabulous book I just read
called&quot;Marley and Me&quot;: Life and Love with the World&apos;s Worst Dog,
by John Grogan. I laughed and cried and recognized my own little
guy on every page! Grogan writes a lot like you do, and makes
common everyday things into hilarious stories. I think you and
your family would enjoy it.
~Betty

[I&apos;ll have to borrow it. I&apos;m too cheap to pay $16 on eBay! (grin)]

Marty,
Maybe we should have a new kids book like the &apos; Where&apos;s Waldo&apos; but
substitute Justin&apos;s name. He seems to be among the missing.
~Wanda

[Good observation Wanda, where IS that boy?]

_________________________________________________________



After an overnight flight to meet my father at his latest military
assignment, my mother wearily arrived at Rhein-Main Air Base in
Germany with my eight siblings and me -- all under age 11.
Collecting our many suitcases, the ten of us entered the cramped
customs area. A young customs official watched our entourage in
disbelief.&quot;Ma&apos;am,&quot;he said,&quot;do all these children and all this
luggage belong to you?&quot;&quot;Yes, sir,&quot;my mother said with a sigh.&quot;They&apos;re all mine.&quot;The customs agent began his interrogation:&quot;Ma&apos;am, do you have any weapons, contraband or illegal drugs in
your possession?&quot;&quot;Sir,&quot;she calmly answered,&quot;if I&apos;d had any of
those items, I would have used them by now.&quot;The official allowed
us to pass without opening a single suitcase.
~Wanda&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;At the construction site of a new church, the contractor stopped
to chat with one of his workmen.&quot;Paddy,&quot;he asked casually,&quot;didn&apos;t you once tell me that you had a brother who was a bishop?&quot;&quot;That I did, sir.&quot;&quot;And you are a bricklayer! It sure is a funny
world. Things in life aren&apos;t divided equally, are they?&quot;&quot;No,
that they ain&apos;t sir,&quot;agreed Paddy, as he proudly slapped the
mortar along the line of bricks.&quot;Me poor brother couldn&apos;t do this
to save his life!&quot;_________________________________________________________



Jack is telling Harry about a weird dream he had last night.&quot;I
had a dream that I was in the old West riding in a stagecoach.
Suddenly, a man riding a horse pulls up to the left side of the
stagecoach and then a riderer-less horse pulls up on the right
side! All of a sudden the man on the horse on the left, leans
down, pulls open the door, and jumps off his horse into my
stagecoach. Then he opens the door on the other side and jumps
onto the other horse! Just before he rode off, I yelled out,&quot;Hey! What was *that* all about?&quot;Harry asks,&quot;Well, did he say
anything to you?&quot;&quot;Yeah,&quot;Jack replies...&quot;he said. &apos;Nothing. It&apos;s
just a stage I&apos;m going through.&apos;&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (6) #1340 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Feb 15, 2006 5:30 am
 Subject: Tuesday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Tuesday, February 14, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Happy Valentines Day!

Son #1 got home and said that he got several nice valentine gifts
today. 3 friends (all girls) decorated his locker at school. And
he said one girl told him today that she had a crush on him. At
dinner I asked him,&quot;Son #1, are all three of these girls cute?&quot;Without much hesitation he said,&quot;They&apos;re all beautiful in their
own ways dad.&quot;Hmm... With that silver tongue, he&apos;ll do just fine.

Son #2 raced home and told mom all about his day. When I got home
he ran to the door,&quot;Dad, I got to dance today!&quot;&quot;There were 16
songs, and I danced with girls on TWELVE of them!&quot;(Wow, with
GIRLS even! I assume he sat out 4 songs [grin]) 3 of the 12 dances
were with the same girl.&quot;Dad, she even gave me a candy-gram!&quot;Oh, to be twiterpated by a candy-gram again...

Son #3 also ran up to me when I got home.&quot;Dad, look! I have a
secret admirer.&quot;He showed me a valentine card with a sucker (Yet
untouched I might add) that had&quot;From: ?&quot;and&quot;To: Son #3&quot;and at
the bottom it had&quot;XXOO&quot;.
Let&apos;s see, you&apos;re only half dating age. What are you doing getting
excited about girls?

Son #4 has been running up to mom for the last 3 days.&quot;Mom, did
you get my stuff in the mail?&quot;He LOVES the mailman, but would
never tell my sweet wife what was in the mail. Songs of Love even
put his wish of being a mailman in his special song. Today we got
a valentine from son #4 in the mail. Simple, but he thought it was
the coolest thing since propathal.

Tonight was Scout night, and months ago the scouts planed doing
service for the single sisters in the ward. We baked 10 dozen
cookies and gave them out in heart shaped baskets. Only, by the
time 6 hungry scouts were done making cookies, there were only 7
dozen left. That was just the perfect amount.

So, my sweet wife and I agreed that tomorrow night would be our
Valentines date night. I promise, no going to the genealogy branch
library for a date. (&quot;Oh, boy, what an exciting date night!&quot;said
Son #1 sarcastically a few weeks back.) I think we&apos;re just getting
old and can&apos;t think of cool things to do on date night.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Hi Marty!
Are you still happy with Vonage? I&apos;m thinking of signing up.
Sandra

[Yup! Vonage is the coolest thing since sliced bread! Click here
to check them out. Note: Self serving link. If you sign up with
this link, I get a free month... (But then, so do you) http://www.vonage.com/?refer_id=3vent33e1-7vplcbpgmy ]


_________________________________________________________



[This joke reminds me of a town just west of Salt Lake. Tooele.
Any one want to take a shot at pronouncing it?]

Two tourists were driving through Wisconsin. As they were
approaching the town of Oconomowoc, they started arguing about the
pronunciation of the town. They argued back and forth until they
stopped for lunch. As they stood at the counter, one tourist asked
the pretty blonde employee,&quot;Before we order, could you please
settle an argument for us? Would you please pronounce where we
are...very slowly?&quot;The blonde leaned over the counter and said,&quot;Burrrrrr , gerrrrr, King.&quot;~Justin&apos;s Dad LaMonte... (Where is your boy?)&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;If my body were a car, this is the time I would be thinking about
trading it in for a newer model.

I&apos;ve got bumps and dents and scratches in my finish and my paint
job is getting a little dull, but that&apos;s not the worst of it.

My headlights are out of focus and it&apos;s especially hard to see
things up close.

My traction is not as graceful as it once was.

I slip and slide and skid and bump into things even in the best of
weather.

My whitewalls are stained with varicose veins.

It takes me hours to reach my maximum speed.

My fuel rate burns inefficiently.

But here&apos;s the worst of it -- almost every time I sneeze, cough or
sputter.....either my radiator leaks or my exhaust backfires!
~LaMonte H.

_________________________________________________________



There were four country churches in a small Texas town:
The Presbyterian Church,
the Methodist Church,
the Baptist Church,
and the Catholic Church.
Each church was overrun with pesky squirrels.

One day, the Presbyterian Church called a meeting to decide what
to do about the squirrels. After much prayer and consideration
they determined that the squirrels were predestined to be there
and they shouldn&apos;t interfere with God&apos;s divine will.

In the Methodist Church, the squirrels had taken up habitation in
the baptistery bowl. The deacons met and decided to put a cover on
the baptistery bowl and drown the squirrels in it. The squirrels
escaped somehow and there were twice as many there the next week.

The Baptist Church got together and decided that they were not in
a position to harm any of God&apos;s creation. So, they humanely
trapped the squirrels and set them free a few miles outside of
town. Three days later, the squirrels were back.

But the Catholic Church came up with the best and most effective
solution. They baptized the squirrels and registered them as
members of the church. Now they only see them on Christmas and
Easter...
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (18) #1341 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Feb 16, 2006 5:50 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
February 15, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

I forgot to tell you my funny story that happened at the dollar
theater Monday night. We were running a little late, (ok, as a
family we ~always~ run a little late.) But, after everyone got
seated in the theater, I decided to run out and get a couple of 32
oz drinks. The total was $7. I had a lot of $1 bills, so I
thought,&quot;Let&apos;s see how smart the counter lady is.&quot;I handed her a
$20 bill two $1 bills for the $7 charge. That&apos;s pretty easy right?
Not so. She put the $22 down on the cash drawer, and looked at it
for a long time. She pulled out $15 to give me as change, but then
grabbed it back just as I was about to take it. She put the money
in the cash drawer again made a strange face while looking at the
money. Then reluctantly she handed me the $15 again and said,&quot;Is
that the right amount?&quot;I played dumb.&quot;Um, I don&apos;t know. You tell
~me~ if that&apos;s the right amount.&quot;(Thinking to myself, uh huh,
that&apos;s why a 50 year old woman is working at the dollar theatre.
If I were dishonest, I&apos;d have said, `No, you owe me $2 more.&apos;)
Anyway, she said,&quot;Oh, I think that&apos;s right.&quot;I said, in a
praising tone of voice,&quot;Yes, you&apos;re right. That ~is~ the correct
change.&quot;She said with a half smile,&quot;Oh, you were just giving me
a hard time, weren&apos;t you?&quot;Oh, no duh.

So, tonight was our Valentines dinner out because of Scouts
yesterday. Our waitress also added our ticket up incorrectly. She
over charged us by $2. After she brought back my card, we never
saw her again. I thought,&quot;No big deal&quot;I just circled the mistake
and gave her $2 less on the tip.

I think people should carry calculators.

Anyway, after dinner I didn&apos;t want to go to the genealogy library
for fear of teasing from son #1 (or from my readers...) so we
snuck back inside the house, while the boys were playing
downstairs, and played a rousing game of Mexican Train Dominos. (I
got a set yesterday as a Valentine gift.) But, I lost... I need a
calculator. http://www.boardgamegeek.com/image/66125 For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

My guess is that Tooele is pronounced &apos;Two-will-uh&apos;
~Katrina B. from &apos;Ver-jin-ee-yuh&apos;

[Nice try. You must have ties to Ewe-taw]

_________________________________________________________



There&apos;s one good thing about snow, it makes your lawn look as nice
as your neighbor&apos;s. -Clyde Moore&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A city boy, Kenny, moved to the country and bought a donkey from
an old farmer for $100.00.

The farmer agreed to deliver the donkey the next day.

The next day the farmer drove up and said,&quot;Sorry son, but I
have some bad news, the donkey died.&quot;Kenny replied,&quot;Well then, just give me my money back.&quot;The farmer said,&quot;Can&apos;t do that. I went and spent it already.&quot;Kenny said,&quot;OK then, just unload the donkey.&quot;The farmer asked,&quot;What ya gonna do with him?&quot;Kenny,&quot;I&apos;m going to raffle him off.&quot;Farmer,&quot;You can&apos;t raffle off a dead donkey!&quot;Kenny,&quot;Sure I can. Watch me. I just won&apos;t tell anybody he is
dead.&quot;A month later the farmer met up with Kenny and asked,&quot;What
happened with that dead donkey?&quot;Kenny,&quot;I raffled him off. I sold 500 tickets at two dollars a
piece and made a profit of $898.00.&quot;Farmer,&quot;Didn&apos;t anyone complain?&quot;Kenny,&quot;Just the guy who won. So I gave him his two dollars
back.&quot;Kenny grew up and eventually became the chairman of Enron

_________________________________________________________



You have to be old enough to remember Abbott and Costello, and too
old to REALLY understand computers to fully appreciate this. For
those of us who sometimes get flustered by our computers, please
read on... If Bud Abbott and Lou Costello were alive today, their
infamous sketch,&quot;Who&apos;s on First?&quot;might have turned out something
like this:


ABBOTT: Super Duper computer store. Can I help you?

COSTELLO: Thanks. I&apos;m setting up an office in my den and I&apos;m
thinking about buying a computer.

ABBOTT: Mac?

COSTELLO: No, the name&apos;s Lou.

ABBOTT: Your computer?

COSTELLO: I don&apos;t own a computer. I want to buy one.

ABBOTT: Mac?

COSTELLO: I told you, my name&apos;s Lou.

ABBOTT: What about Windows?

COSTELLO: Why? Will it get stuffy in here?

ABBOTT: Do you want a computer with Windows?

COSTELLO: I don&apos;t know. What will I see when I look at the
windows?

ABBOTT: Wallpaper.

COSTELLO: Never mind the windows. I need a computer and software.

ABBOTT: Software for Windows?

COSTELLO: No. On the computer! I need something I can use to write
proposals track expenses and run my business. What do you have?

ABBOTT: Office.

COSTELLO: Yeah, for my office. Can you recommend anything?

ABBOTT: I just did.

COSTELLO: You just did what?

ABBOTT: Recommend something.

COSTELLO: You recommended something?

ABBOTT: Yes.

COSTELLO: For my office?

ABBOTT: Yes.

COSTELLO: OK, what did you recommend for my office?

ABBOTT: Office.

COSTELLO: Yes, for my office!

ABBOTT: I recommend Office with Windows.

COSTELLO: I already have an office with windows! OK, let&apos;s just
say I&apos;m sitting at my computer and I want to type a proposal. What
do I need?

ABBOTT: Word.

COSTELLO: What word?

ABBOTT: Word in Office

COSTELLO: The only word in office is office.

ABBOTT: The Word in Office for Windows.

COSTELLO: Which word in office for windows?

ABBOTT: The Word you get when you click the blue&quot;W&quot;.

COSTELLO: I&apos;m going to click your blue&quot;w&quot;if you don&apos;t start with
some straight answers. What about financial bookkeeping? You have
anything I can track my money with?

ABBOTT: Money.

COSTELLO: That&apos;s right. What do you have?

ABBOTT: Money.

COSTELLO: I need money to track my money?

ABBOTT: It comes bundled with your computer

COSTELLO: What&apos;s bundled with my computer?

ABBOTT: Money.

COSTELLO: Money comes with my computer?

ABBOTT: Yes. No extra charge.

COSTELLO: I get a bundle of money with my computer? How much?

ABBOTT: One copy.

COSTELLO: Isn&apos;t it illegal to copy money?

ABBOTT: Microsoft gave us a license to copy Money.

COSTELLO: They can give you a license to copy money?

ABBOTT: Why not? THEY OWN IT!

(A few days later)

ABBOTT: Super Duper computer store. Can I help you?

COSTELLO: How do I turn my computer off?

ABBOTT: Click on&quot;START&quot;.............
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1342 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Feb 17, 2006 5:32 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 10:30 martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, February 16, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Today was son #4&apos;s day to go swimming with his visually impaired
pre-school class. He was really excited to go. They must have
played really hard, because when the bus pulled up to drop off son
#4, each and every kid was fast asleep.

But, things got back to normal at dinner time.&quot;Son #4, what did
you do at school today?&quot;I said, well knowing what he did.&quot;I
don&apos;t know dad...&quot;Funny, that&apos;s the same answer I get from every
boy in this house. It must be a male thing. So, we usually ask
what they ate for lunch, and that gets the ball rolling.

Have a great weekend!
For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Talk about innumeracy (illiterate with numbers) I stopped by a
drive up restaurant where the waiter came out on roller skates,
and takes my order. My order came to $1.98, I handed the waiter a
$20 bill, and his eyes glazed over! The 2 pennies was the easy
part, he clicked them off the changer on his belt, but when he
went into his pocket for change, he produced a wad of bills, all
jumbled together. After fumbling for about a minute, he handed me
28 one dollar bills, and then waited for my reaction to determine
if he was correct. I however have a moral obligation against
taking advantage of simple minds, so I gave back the $10. I then
went on to add fries to my order, and he looked devastated! He
ended up giving me the fries, because he didn&apos;t want to count out
change again! I guess the most important requirement was that he
could skate!
~Kenny M.

Marty,
I think what you did to the poor girl at the theater with the $20
and $2 was out right cruel. I used to work in fast food as a
teenager and we had people come in all the time trying to scam the
cashiers into giving them back the incorrect change doing just
what you did. This would always happen at peak times and we were
told not to handle money exchanges like you did just because of
that! Not everyone is as quick at math as you are and when you
are trying to give fast service and someone tries what you did it
throws the cashier off. What you did was uncommon, but please
don&apos;t act like the cashier was dumb, she may have never been
handed payment like that before.
Donna P.

[Oh?...&quot;out right cruel?&quot;... Anyone care to comment on Donna&apos;s
comments?]

_________________________________________________________



An elderly couple was attending church services when about halfway
through he leans over and says to her,&quot;I just had a silent
passing of gas. What do you think I should do?&quot;She leans over to
him and replies,&quot;Put a new battery in your hearing aid.&quot;~#1 Mom&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A city boy, Kenny, moved to the country and bought a donkey from
an old farmer for $100.00. The farmer agreed to deliver the donkey
the next day. The next day the farmer drove up and said,&quot;Sorry
son, but I have some bad news, the donkey died.&quot;Kenny replied,&quot;Well then, just give me my money back.&quot;The farmer said,&quot;Can&apos;t
do that. I went and spent it already.&quot;Kenny said,&quot;OK then, just
unload the donkey.&quot;The farmer asked,&quot;What ya gonna do with him?&quot;Kenny,&quot;I&apos;m going to raffle him off.&quot;Farmer,&quot;You can&apos;t raffle
off a dead donkey!&quot;Kenny,&quot;Sure I can. Watch me. I just won&apos;t
tell anybody he is dead.&quot;A month later the farmer met up with Kenny and asked,&quot;What
happened with that dead donkey?&quot;Kenny,&quot;I raffled him off. I sold
500 tickets at two dollars a piece and made a profit of $898.00.&quot;Farmer,&quot;Didn&apos;t anyone complain?&quot;Kenny,&quot;Just the guy who won. So
I gave him his two dollars back.&quot;Kenny grew up and eventually
became the chairman of Enron

_________________________________________________________&quot;Thanks for the harmonica you gave me for Christmas,&quot;little
Joshua said to his uncle the first time he saw him after the
holidays.&quot;It&apos;s the best Christmas present I ever got.&quot;&quot;Hey,
that&apos;s great,&quot;said his uncle.&quot;Do you know how to play it?&quot;&quot;Oh,
I don&apos;t play it,&quot;the little fellow said.&quot;Mom gives me a dollar a
day not to play it during the day and my dad gives me five dollars
a week not to play it at night.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (2) #1343 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Feb 21, 2006 6:49 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s Issue - 11:45PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, February 20, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Oops, since its President&apos;s day and I had the day off, I almost
forgot that it was time to do a blog entry. We had planned on
going to Randolph for our 7th two-hour trip since my dad died, to
do more cleaning, searching for tax papers, hauling stuff home,
etc. But since the weather report was for 15 below zero, and
snow, we decided at the last minute to stay home. That left a
whole 3 day weekend with nothing planed. This was a complete and
utterly strange experience for me. Since the middle of August when
son #4 had his tumor, I think every minute of every day of every
week has been scheduled. To compound that, when my dad died,
things just got worse. So, an empty three day weekend was
something welcomed.

But, this unscheduled weekend came with some guilt. A week or so
ago our Gospel Doctrine teacher called me up.&quot;Hey Marty, I&apos;m
going to be gone on President&apos;s day weekend. Can you substitute
for me on Sunday?&quot;There are two callings in the LDS church that
scare me more than anything else in the world; Gospel Doctrine
teacher is one of them. Gospel Doctrine is an hour long Sunday
school class where you learn different aspects of the Gospel. This
year we are studying the Old Testament, next year is the New
Testament. It goes on a 4 year rotation. Gospel Doctrine is where
all of the adults in the ward go for Sunday school. These are the
folks who stick around after sacrament meeting. Not the ones who
head home for football or a nice Sunday nap. These are the folks
who want to learn. So, they ask the instructor all sorts of
questions, and if you happen to be teaching, you&apos;d better be
prepared with some good answers or you&apos;re in trouble. I
substituted for this class several years ago and I can remember it
like it was yesterday. It wasn&apos;t pleasant. I don&apos;t mind teaching
12 and 13 year old boys (more my level anyway) but big people
scare me. Anyway, I told the instructor that I was going to be in
Randolph cleaning out my dad&apos;s house for the entire weekend. So,
when we showed up to our church on Sunday anyway, I had pangs of
guilt. My sweet wife said he&apos;ll never know, because he was gone
anyway. So, Shhh... no one tell ok?

Anyway, on Saturday because I had all of this time off, I had to
have a project to keep me busy. I decided that laundry was my
goal. I started at 7:15, and by the time Saturday night came
along, I had done 9 loads. It&apos;s amazing we have that many clothes!
There were clothes under the kids&apos; beds, hiding here, hiding
there. It was mind boggling. I know my sweet wife appreciated it,
because she had 3 hours of play practice with son #2 on Saturday,
and couldn&apos;t help much.

But, I&apos;m not sure she showed her appreciation very well. When I
went to bed, she rolled over to cuddle, and elbowed me in the face
just under my eye.&quot;OUCH!&quot;I yelled. She apologized, and we fell
asleep. I had forgotten about the whole thing until the next
morning when I looked in the mirror. I now have a huge black eye.
When I showed her, I laughed, and she felt terrible.

Maybe that will get me out of laundry duty next weekend `eh?

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

p.s.
I put a Vonage logo on the blog page. Reader Sandra B. signed up
this weekend and got a free month, and gave me one too! Thanks!

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Lots and Lots of Comments today.

The Abbott and Costello bit was better than the original. I have
tears in my eyes from laughing so hard.
~Jody H.

I&apos;ve been reading your daily entries on your blog starting in
August&amp;I&apos;ve both laughed&amp;cried. Thank you for sharing your
story. I liked the story your mom posted about Jim `duhing&apos; the
RN about the little doctor comment: ) You have a truly amazing
family. If you were here or I was there I would give you a great
big hug.
~Addie V.

[About Donna P&apos;s comments last Thursday]

Donna,
If [Marty] wasn&apos;t as honest as he is, THEN it would be cruel. What
he did, was send a reminder to watch out for that type of stuff.
Her manager didn&apos;t get involved, so she&apos;s not in any trouble, but
yet she is smarter for having met Marty, as am I. And this is from
someone who worked in fast food for 5 years. Frankly though, if
you can&apos;t give change correctly, you shouldn&apos;t be working the
register.
~Jody H.

To Donna.
If you work with money You should be able to count. What is so
difficult about that? If I have to pay R12 and I give an R20 + R2
that just mean I want R10. It also mean I don&apos;t want to walk
around with a bag full of coins!
Kobus B.

I do NOT agree with Donna&apos;s statement! People today have come to
rely on calculators to do their math for them. Come on folks!
How hard is it to add and subtract whole numbers in your head!!!
Vickie

Hi Marty,
I&apos;m replying to your story about the cashier in the concession
stand. I work for a supermarket in my area (not as a cashier), but
I find myself simply amazed by the lack of basic math knowledge
when I&apos;m checking out. Last week, my total at the checkout was
$20.51. I handed the cashier $21.01. He looked at me as if I was
mentally challenged and proceeded to ask me if I had another $.50.
He stood there while the line behind me backed up and I searched
through my purse and pockets for 2 more quarters. I tried
explaining to him that he was the one that owed me $.50, but he
wouldn&apos;t budge. I finally handed him another dollar bill, he
punched $22.01 on the cash tendered button and proceeded to hand
me back my $1.50 in change. Thank goodness the registers
automatically figure out the correct change when the cash is
tendered! Thank you for a funny and entertaining newsletter. May
God keep you and your family well.
~Paula M.

I really want to disagree with Donna P. This is whats wrong with
education today, the kids today can&apos;t seem to do simple math! What
with pictures on the registers instead of numbers and machines
telling them how much change to make on a transaction, they
haven&apos;t learned to make the simple transactions theirselves. So
how are these poor kids going to know when they are shorted on
thier pay checks or if billing errors are being made on their
charges? And people wonder about these kids who will be replacing
older professionals in the job market?...
~Ruth J.

Marty,
You mentioned the story about&quot;son #4&apos;s&quot;day at the pool and when
you asked what did you today...then you commented and said it
must be a male thing...well, guess what it&apos;s a girl thing
too...every time my husband and I ask or if anyone asks my niece
(who is now 10) what did you do today, she says the same
thing...maybe it&apos;s their generation...BTW: I&apos;m 46....just thought
I&apos;d add my two cents... BTW: Love you letters...and oh yea, where
is Justin? Take care
~Jim M

Marty,
I just read the email about the person who complained that you
were cruel to have given that cashier at the movies a hard time. I
must agree that if a cashier is feeling that a scam is going that
they have the right to not make a sale or better yet, call the
manager over to deal with it. On the other hand modern cash
registers, even old ones, have a feature on them called &apos;Cash
Tendered&apos;. Even if a cashier is too overworked or otherwise
confused, all they have to due after entering the sale is to also
enter the amount that they are given. The &apos;Cash Tendered&apos; feature
will provide the correct change amount and it is all printed on
the reciept/journal of the register. No math skills required. Just
count the money.
~Keith H.

Marty - I think anyone that works with cash should be able to make
change- people these days are too used to working with calculators
and cash registers that figure out the change. People are not
taught to think with their own brains- we are living in a society
when too much is done for us. I always believed that we should be
able to use the brains that God gave us to figure out something so
simple as making change. If a person is not able to do it on their
own, then they should not be working in that type of job. It must
be very stressful on them, as well as the customer. I do not think
you did anything wrong. When we make a purchase, we should, at the
very least, be sure of getting back the correct change.
~Rowena C.

Re:Giving change
I don&apos;t think what you did is cruel, but as someone who worked fast
food many years ago, I know it can be tough to do math on
demand when you&apos;ve got people staring at you. I was good at math,
but I&apos;d get flustered when people would try to throw me off, just
because they were sitting there staring at me. And cash registers
make it too easy for you to not have to do the math yourself
anymore. You punch in the amount the person gave you, and it
tells you the change you should give, then if the person tried to
give me more money after that, it would screw everything up. But I
agree, if you&apos;re going to work in the business, learn how to count
change back. And for customers, once they&apos;ve figured out how much
to change to give you, don&apos;t try and give them more money - it&apos;s a
pain!
~Anonymous

Hey Marty,
I would like to comment about what Donna had to say. Come on
people, cruel? Marty? Don&apos;t they have buttons on the cash
register that allow you to enter the amount you got as payment&amp;then it tells you the amount of change to give back? It is not
Rocket Science. It just takes a little thought. No one said the
girl was dumb.
~Jennifer K (AZ)

[Thanks everyone!]

_________________________________________________________



My husband grew increasingly displeased as our teenage daughter
and her boyfriend studied in her room late one evening. Finally
losing patience shortly after midnight, he knocked sharply on her
door. Her boyfriend immediately opened it and asked if something
was wrong.&quot;I have to ask you to move your car,&quot;my husband told
him.&quot;Oh, sure. Is it in someone&apos;s way?&quot;&quot;No,&quot;he replied,&quot;it&apos;s
parked at the wrong address.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;&quot;That was nice of you to set up a blind date for your ex-
boyfriend.&quot;&quot;I know, but I don&apos;t hold any grudges.&quot;&quot;I&apos;m
surprised he trusted you enough to agree to go out with her.&quot;&quot;Well, I had to swear to him she&apos;s Jennifer Lopez&apos;s double.&quot;&quot;Wow!
Is that true?&quot;&quot;I wouldn&apos;t lie. She&apos;s twice her weight and twice
her age.&quot;_________________________________________________________



My little niece, Kelly, went with a neighbor girl to church for
First Communion practice. The pastor has the children cup their
hands, and when he gives them the&quot;Host,&quot;in this case, a piece of
bread, he says,&quot;God be with you.&quot;Apparently this made quite an
impression on my niece. She came home and told her mother to cup
her hands and bend down. Kelly took a piece of bread from her
sandwich, placed it in her mother&apos;s hands, and whispered, in her
most angelic voice,&quot;God will get you.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #1344 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Feb 22, 2006 5:52 am
 Subject: Tuesday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Tuesday, February 21, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Not too much to talk about today. For some dumb reason, I kept track
of all the people who asked me what happened to my eye today. They
all ranged from,&quot;Oh, that&apos;s too bad&quot;to&quot;You&apos;d better keep in line,
or she&apos;ll pop you in the other eye!&quot;After I told her that 14 people
asked me what I did to get my black eye, My sweet wife said,&quot;I&apos;m
never going to be able to show my face at your work again...&quot;I felt
a little bad for her, but that I realized I was the one with the
shiner! She did admit that it was probably better that I have the
black eye and accuse her of beating me, than the other way around.

I posted a picture of me and the eye on the blog site.
( http://martysjotd.blogspot.com ). I also found a picture of son #4
back when he got his songs of love CD. I posted that one too. It&apos;s a
cute picture.

Tonight Son #4 was pretty upset when Sons #1 and #2 and I were going
to Scouts with me. We told him that we were going to build and igloo
and have a snowball fight. He wanted to go with us in the worst way.
But, it was probably better that he didn&apos;t. The snow was too crunchy
and we just ended up playing capture the flag.

Anyway, have a great night.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Marty:
Nine loads of laundry in one day? Nine? OH my heavens! I will
never complain again if I find clothes hiding in my older
daughter&apos;s room and get stuck doing 4 loads in one day, which has
happened to me more than once. But nine loads? I am speechless.&lt;grin&gt;Your poor sweet wife must feel horrible about the black
eye, but I&apos;d lay a lot of money on the fact that she loves and
appreciates you more than she can ever say for doing all that
laundry.
Shannon in Nevada

_________________________________________________________



Two sea monsters were swimming around in the ocean, looking for
something to do. They came up underneath a ship that was hauling
potatoes. Bob, the first sea monster, swam underneath the ship,
tippedt over and ate everything on the ship. A little while later,
they came up to another ship, again hauling potatoes. Bob again
capsizes the ship and eats everything onboard. The third ship they
found was also hauling potatoes and Bob once again capsized it and
ate everything. Finally his buddy Bill asked him,&quot;Why do you keep
tipping over those ships full of potatoes and eating everything on
board?&quot;Bob replied,&quot;I wish I hadn&apos;t, but I just can&apos;t help myself
once I start. Everyone knows you can&apos;t eat just one potato ship.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;I was working in the sun all day, putting finishing touches on the
new deck outside my house. My sister pulled into the driveway,
greeted me, and looked over my work.&quot;Wow, Steve,&quot;she gushed,&quot;you&apos;re an expert.&quot;Gloating, feeling like the king that I am,
but.... trying not to seem egotistical, I responded. . .&quot;Once you
get going, it&apos;s pretty easy!&quot;She looked puzzled and I then wondered
if I&apos;d misunderstood her. So I asked,&quot;What did you just say, Jen?&quot;She replied. . .&quot;I said, your neck&apos;s burnt!&quot;_________________________________________________________



A student wished to make some potassium hydroxide solution (aqueous)
and decided to throw a large lump of potassium into a bucket of
water. Out of the corner of his eye, the professor observed what the
student was about to do and hurried over. After confirming this was
what was intended, he asked the student to first to stir the water
in the bucket for five minutes before adding the potassium. Puzzled,
the student followed after him to ask the purpose of this &apos;stirring&apos;
action.&quot;Heh heh... It will give me time to run,&quot;said the
professor.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1345 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Feb 23, 2006 5:37 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, February 22, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

First, I want to tell you I&apos;ve found an unorthodox way of getting
my children to bed at an early hour.&quot;HEY!&quot;I yelled at them while
walking in the computer room about 8:45 tonight. They were all
playing one sort of game system or another.&quot;None of you are
supposed to be playing games. Your rooms aren&apos;t clean!&quot;(Oh, so
what good is grounding them from games if they all sneak down to
play anyway? I need to find a better way to police this.)&quot;Ok, all
of you, turn off the computers and MARCH to your rooms and CLEAN
for 20 minutes. Now!&quot;Funny, by 9PM they were all in bed saying they were tired. Maybe I
should get them to `clean&apos; their rooms more often.

Second, I&apos;ve been thinking of Jim in Indiana&apos;s comment today.&gt;Hey Marty, Would you like some cheese with that wine? What black&gt;eye? I could see it with my magnifying glass. Otherwise that&apos;s&gt;just a &apos;love pat&apos;.&gt;Love your stories,&gt;jim in Indiana

Yeah, well, it might not have looked ~that~ big, but I thought it
was big enough. (grin). Then I thought about getting a better
picture of me (son #1 took the shaky one on the blog) and having my
sweet wife doctor it up in Photoshop (she&apos;s a master photoshopper!)
to give me a proper black eye. But I couldn&apos;t find a good enough
picture. I went through the hundreds of pictures we&apos;ve got, and
thought,&quot;Hey, I bet everyone would like to see that one, oh, and
that one too.&quot;There are tons of cool pictures for you. So, I put
a dozen or so pictures of us up on the blog site with some
explanations.

Count today as a photo blog.
( http://www.martysjotd.blogspot.com )
Enjoy.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:


_________________________________________________________



TEACHER: Maria, go to the map and find North America.
MARIA: Here it is.
TEACHER: Correct. Now class, who discovered America?
CLASS: Maria.

TEACHER: Glenn, how do you spell&quot;crocodile?&quot;GLENN: K-R-O-K-O-D-I-A-L&quot;TEACHER: No, that&apos;s wrong
GLENN: Maybe it s wrong, but you asked me how I spell it.

TEACHER: Donald, what is the chemical formula for water?
DONALD: H I J K L M N O.
TEACHER: What are you talking about?
DONALD: Yesterday you said it&apos;s H to O.

TEACHER: Millie, give me a sentence starting with&quot;I.&quot;MILLIE: I is...
TEACHER: No, Millie..... Always say,&quot;I am.&quot;MILLIE: All right...&quot;I am the ninth letter of the
 alphabet.&quot;TEACHER: Clyde, your composition on&quot;My Dog&quot;is exactly the
 same as your brother&apos;s. Did you copy his?
CLYDE: No, teacher, it&apos;s the same dog.

~Wanda D.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;HOW TO CLEAN THE HOUSE
1. Open a new file in your PC.
2. Name it&quot;Housework.&quot;3. Send it to the RECYCLE BIN.
4. Empty the RECYCLE BIN.
5. Your PC will ask you,&quot;Are you sure you want to delete
 Housework permanently?&quot;6. Calmly answer,&quot;Yes,&quot;and press the mouse button firmly......
7. Feel better?

Works for me!

[Not often do I get the same joke from 3 people the same day!]

~My #1 Mom
~Wanda D.
~Betty H.

_________________________________________________________



Hillary and Bill Clinton and Al Gore die in a car accident and
suddenly find themselves in heaven. God addresses Al first.&quot;Al,
what do you believe in?&quot;Al replies,&quot;Well, I believe I won that election, but that it was
your will that I did not serve. And I&apos;ve come to understand that
now.&quot;God thinks for a second and says,&quot;OK, very good. Come and sit at
my left.&quot;God then addresses Bill.&quot;Bill, what do you believe in?&quot;Bill replies,&quot;I believe in forgiveness. I&apos;ve sinned, but I&apos;ve
never held a grudge against my fellow man, and I hope no grudges
are held against me.&quot;God thinks for a second and says,&quot;You are forgiven, my son. Come
and sit at my right.&quot;God then addresses Hillary.&quot;Hillary, what do you believe in?&quot;Hillary says,&quot;I believe you&apos;re in my chair.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (9) #1346 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Feb 24, 2006 5:21 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, February 23, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Well that was fun. I put 8 pictures of my family on the blog, and
my sweet wife said 7 of them were really cute. She said,&quot;Now
people will know why I smacked you in the eye; For putting
pictures of me making faces on your site!&quot;Oops...

But, I don&apos;t feel ~too~ awful bad about putting that picture up.
Tonight they called everyone for play practice to come in for
promotional portraits. I thought, cool! This is actually big time
production stuff. I&apos;ll have professional portraits done of son #2,
my sweet wife, and me. Hmm... a portrait of me. Me and my black
eye. The photographer promised me that she could Photoshop out a
simple black eye for me. I hope she&apos;s as good as my sweet wife!

At lunch today my sweet wife and I were chuckling over some of the
pictures that I put up last night, and she mentioned that I
skimped a little on son #3 in the photo line up. So, for tonight&apos;s
issue, I&apos;ve put up a funny photo and we&apos;re going to have our first
photo caption contest. Head on over to the blog
( http://martysjotd.blogspot.com ) and check out the picture, and
send me a funny caption to go along with it. It&apos;s Thursday, so
I&apos;ll give you the weekend to email me captions.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

p.s. BTW, I was over at Justin&apos;s dad&apos;s house last Friday. Justin
was on the phone talking with his mom. His mom looked at me and
said,&quot;Hey wait, Justin has something for you...&quot;She said he was
looking around for it. He didn&apos;t find it, and then said he didn&apos;t
want to talk to me on the phone. Bummer. But I know Justin is
somewhere. He might be back in Canada saying hi to friends. I
think they have internet connections in Canada. Don&apos;t they?

If anyone knows where Justin is, say&quot;Hi&quot;for me!

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Marty,
Thanks alot, FOR ALL OF YOUR&quot;JOTD&apos;s, and extra kudos for &apos;photo
blog&apos;. kutgw!
Bob B.

_________________________________________________________



If you have a lot of tension and you get a headache, do what it
says on the aspirin bottle:&quot;Take two aspirin&quot;and&quot;Keep away from
children&quot;!
~LaMonte H.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A couple of fun sites;

I&apos;ve been getting a lot more urban legends lately. This link from
Betty H. made me smile...
softlab.ece.ntua.gr/~sivann/pub/swf/may02-smilepop-soapbox4.swf

=-=-=-

This one shows the ACLU is a bit paranoid, but still funny http://www.aclu.org/pizza/images/screen.swf _________________________________________________________



A woman called VCU medical center.&quot;Hello. Could you connect me to
the person who gives information about patients. I&apos;d like to find
out if a patient is getting better, doing as expected, or getting
worse.&quot;The voice on the other end said,&quot;What is the patient&apos;s
name and room number?&quot;&quot;Sarah Finkel, room 302.&quot;&quot;I&apos;ll connect you with the nursing station.&quot;&quot;3-A Nursing Station. How can I help You?&quot;&quot;I&apos;d like to know the condition of Sarah Finkel in room 302.&quot;&quot;Just a moment. Let me look at her records. Mrs. Finkel is doing
very well. In fat, she&apos;s had two full meals, her blood pressure is
fine. She is to be taken off the heart monitor in a couple of
hours and, if she continues this improvement, Dr. Cohen is going
to send her home Tuesday at noon.&quot;The woman said,&quot;What a relief! Oh, that&apos;s fantastic... that&apos;s
wonderful news!&quot;The nurse said,&quot;From your enthusiasm, I take it you are a close
family member or a very close friend!&quot;&quot;Neither! I&apos;m Sarah Finkel in 302! Nobody here tells me anything!
~Jan D.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (2) #1347 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Feb 28, 2006 5:38 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, February 27, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

I told you a few weeks ago to stay tuned, and I would tell you
about our trip to the Make-a-wish&quot;wishing place&quot;( http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/2006/01/124-casting-error.html )
Well, they granted son #4 a wish to go to Disney World with the
whole family. (With some coaxing from his brothers, just days
before his choice...) But he seemed genuinely happy with the wish.

But, a week ago Sunday, one of the wish grantors came by the house
to deliver some stuff. They brought him some small toys to open,
one a week, until his wish date. They also brought him a special
Make-a-wish hat that only `wish kids&apos; get. It&apos;s got a picture of
Aladdin on it, and he loves it. He wears that thing all the time,
and won&apos;t even take it off when he goes to bed. (Even though he
doesn&apos;t know who Aladdin is. Apparently we haven&apos;t kept up with
the Disney indoctrination in a timely manner.)

Anyway, when she pulled out our itinerary she told us the dates
that we&apos;re leaving, and then said,&quot;You&apos;ll get on the plane at
7:50AM...&quot;and that&apos;s all it took. Son #4&apos;s eyes got really big
and he yelled,&quot;I GET TO GO ON A PLANE! Yahoo!!&quot;then he started
jumping up and down on the couch,&quot;I get to go on a plane!&quot;Ahh... there&apos;ll certainly be more than that little one...

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty
p.s. For those of you who missed it last week, here&apos;s the feel
good story of the basketball kid from last week. http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UBYPaNc57Ik&amp;search=autistic% 20basketball%2

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:


Loved the photo blog, especially the Va Va Voom photo. Wow. (Boy,
is she going to get you for that!) But that&apos;s how I remember her
from high school, but you wouldn&apos;t let anyone else date her!
~DAVE C.

[You know old friend, I knew even back then, what a catch I had!]

Georgous picture of your &apos;sweet wife&apos; that was taken for her
birthday! And by the way, yes we Canadians DO have the internet!
You may have wanted to build igloos but we don&apos;t live in any! At
least not in the few houses around where I live. I obviously live
in Canada but I don&apos;t know where Justin is!
~Paulette D.

[And here are the captions for our first caption contest from the
picture on the blogsite. ( http://martysjotd.blogspot.com ]


Is this all we get for dinner, Big Daddy?
~#1 Mom


Do they expect us to eat every single one of these crackers?
 ~Serena S. from NC&quot;Watch this first...&quot;~Bob B.

Marty,
Good morning! I looked at that cute picture, and the first thought
that came to mind was, with all those you-have-got-to-be-kidding-
me expressions, was,&quot;You want us to build THAT with these
crackers???&quot;Have a great weekend!
~Diane W.

Hello Marty,
I love your stories, keep it up! Here&apos;s one for the caption
contest :
Can we eat now? Can we eat now? CAN WE EAT NOW???
Hugo R.
Montreal QC, Canada

[Thanks all who sent in suggestions!]

_________________________________________________________



WAITER:&quot;Yes, sir, is there something wrong?&quot;CUSTOMER:&quot;The soup. Taste it.&quot;WAITER:&quot;I beg your pardon, Sir?&quot;CUSTOMER:&quot;Taste it.&quot;WAITER:&quot;But, Sir, I can assure you that the soup is excellent.&quot;CUSTOMER:&quot;Taste it.&quot;WAITER:&quot;Sir, the soup was made this morning of the finest
ingredients.&quot;CUSTOMER:&quot;Taste it!&quot;WAITER: exasperated,&quot;All right, Sir, I&apos;ll taste it.&quot;Then after a pause he said,&quot;Where is the spoon?&quot;To which the customer replied triumphantly,&quot;Ah ha!!&quot;~Wanda D.

=-=-=-&quot;As I was walking through a variety store, I stopped at the pet
department to look at some parakeets. In one cage a green bird lay
on his back, one foot hooked oddly into the cage wire. I was about
to alert the saleswoman to the bird&apos;s plight when I noticed a sign
taped to the cage: &apos;No, I am not sick. No, I am not dead. No, my
leg is not stuck in the cage. I just like to sleep this way.&apos;&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;My 50-something friend Nancy and I decided to introduce her mother
to the magic of the Internet. Our first move was to access the
popular Ask Jeeves site, and we told her it could answer any
question she had. Nancy&apos;s mother was very skeptical until Nancy
said,&quot;It&apos;s true, Mom. Think of something to ask it.&quot;As I sat
with fingers poised over the keyboard, Nancy&apos;s mother thought a
minute, then responded,&quot;How is Aunt Helen feeling?&quot;_________________________________________________________



My 20th high school class reunion was held at a hotel on the same
night that another school&apos;s 10th-year reunion was taking place.
While my girl friends and I were in the rest room talking, some
unfamiliar women entered. After their stares became uncomfortable,
we turned toward them. One of the women said,&quot;Don&apos;t mind us. We
just wanted to see how we&apos;d look in another 10 years.&quot;=-=-=-

My brother adopted a snake named Slinky, whose most disagreeable
trait was eating live mice. Once I was pressed into going to the
pet store to buy Slinky&apos;s dinner. The worst part of this wasn&apos;t
choosing the juiciest-looking creatures or turning down the clerk
who wanted to sell me vitamins to ensure their longevity. The
hardest part was carrying the poor things out in a box bearing the
words&quot;Thank you for giving me a home.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (9) #1348 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Mar 2, 2006 5:50 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, March 01, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

I skipped an issue last night. I know I know; I&apos;m getting lazy.
But, I think I got an extra 30 minutes of sleep. And that&apos;s always
a good thing!

My sweet wife and I were talking to a friend tonight about needing
some time together to rejuvenate. I her that we&apos;re going as a
family to Disneyworld compliments of the Make-A-Wish foundation.
She said,&quot;You know, you&apos;re not going to be rested after that
trip.&quot;I agreed. She suggested that my sweet wife and I sneak off
somewhere and take a weekend break. That sounded like a welcome
suggestion, so sometime this month we&apos;re going to do it!

Son #4 update; He&apos;s going snow skiing with the school for the
blind next week. Man, where was that stuff when I was little.

He&apos;s also got a 5th birthday party coming up in a couple of weeks.
There was a time in the last year... that we thought he might not
make it to 5. We&apos;re glad he did.

And, lastly, at the dinner table tonight son #4 took off a ring
and showed it to me.&quot;Here dad, look what I got.&quot;I examined it
carefully. It was a plastic 10 almost-working compass ring. I
said,&quot;Hey, that&apos;s really cool. You can tell where you are with
it. Where did you get it?&quot;Without missing a beat he said,&quot;From my finger.&quot;Ask a silly question...

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Don&apos;t you know we all worry about you and your family when you
skip a night???? Oh, I guess it&apos;s okay once in a while. I know I&apos;m
late because somehow I missed reading about the caption contest.
But better late than never, how about,&quot;Okay guys, on the count of
three, I want you each to eat 20 crackers, and whistle when you&apos;re
finished. The first one to whistle is the winner.&quot;We&apos;ll all look
forward to hearing from you tonight!
~Betty H.

Sorry I missed your contest... better late than not at all... here
is what I first thought of..&quot;You want me to put those crackers
WHERE?&quot;and I don&apos;t mean it bad, for those of you that might have
that onery sense.. haha
~ Debi S.


[And some sad news from Justin&apos;s family]
Hey Marty, I just wanted to make sure you had heard about my and
Justin&apos;s brother-in-law that was killed in Iraq last week. Here&apos;s
a story on it in case you missed it. http://deseretnews.com/dn/view/0,1249,635187246,00.html http://www.legacy.com/DeseretNews/Obituaries.asp? Page=Lifestory&amp;PersonId=16890546

~Justin&apos;s Sister

[The last link has information about donating to his wife and 4
little children]

_________________________________________________________



Sam was out shopping in the mall when he meets his friend Abe
outside the jewelers. Sam notices that Abe has a small gift-
wrapped box in his hand.&quot;So what have you just purchased Abe?&quot;Sam asks.&quot;Well, now that you&apos;ve asked,&quot;replies Abe,&quot;it&apos;s my
Wife&apos;s birthday tomorrow and when I asked her this morning what
she wanted for her birthday she said, &apos;Oh, I don&apos;t know, dear,
just give me something with a lot of diamonds in it.&apos;&quot;&quot;So what
did you get her?&quot;Sam asks. Abe replies, smiling,&quot;I bought her a
deck of cards.&quot;~Wanda D.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;Four Religious Truths

1. Muslims DO NOT RECOGNIZE Jews as God&apos;s chosen people.

2. Jews DO NOT RECOGNIZE Jesus as the Messiah.

3. Protestants DO NOT RECOGNIZE the Pope as the leader of the
 Christian World.

4. Mormons DO NOT RECOGNIZE each other at the grocery store on
 Sunday

~Stan d.

_________________________________________________________



A battalion conducted winter patrols of the Korean Demilitarized
Zone. On a blustery morning, a senior officer known for his off-
the-wall questions was inspecting an outgoing squad.&quot;Private,&quot;he
demanded of one soldier,&quot;if you were on patrol and saw some tanks
barreling over that ridge, what would you do?&quot;&quot;Sir, I would call
in a squadron of Apache attack helicopters,&quot;was the private&apos;s
quick reply.&quot;Where in hell are you going to get a squadron of
Apaches?&quot;&quot;The same place you got your tanks, sir.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1349 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Mar 3, 2006 5:34 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, March 02, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Today was Dr. Seuss day at son #4&apos;s school. When my sweet wife
told him and then said,&quot;I have the perfect outfit for you!&quot;He
seemed excited. She got out his Cat in the Hat sweatshirt and
pants, but when she started to dress him, he refused. He explained
that if it was Dr. Seuss day, he was going to wear his Doctors
outfit. So that&apos;s what he wore today.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:


_________________________________________________________



Our five-year-old son went to a church conference with my wife and
me. He got restless, so my wife handed him a pad and pencil and
suggested he mark down every time the speaker said the word&quot;and.&quot;After a while, he grew bored, and I asked,&quot;Would you like to
listen for a different word?&quot;&quot;Yes,&quot;he whispered.&quot;I&apos;d like to
listen for &apos;Amen&apos;.&quot;~Wanda D.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;The pastor of our church began his sermon with this story:&quot;I was on a plane last week, from Chicago to California, when we
ran into some very severe turbulence. As it got worse, the
passengers became more and more alarmed, and even the flight
attendants began to look concerned. Finally, one of them noticed
that I had &apos;Rev.&apos; in front of my name on the passenger list, came
over to me, and said, &apos;Sir, this is really frightening. Do you
suppose you could, I don&apos;t know...do something religious?&apos;&quot;&quot;So I
took up a collection.&quot;_________________________________________________________



I was living in the mountains above Denver when my college buddy,
Gary, arrived in his ancient Maserati sports car. He had just
driven it from Ohio, and as he pulled into my driveway, the car
broke down. Calls to auto-supply houses and garages in search of
replacement parts proved futile. The 1962 model was simply too
rare. Responses ranged from&quot;Mas-a-what?&quot;to&quot;You&apos;ve got to be
kidding.&quot;One guy just laughed. I was at the end of the listings
in the Yellow Pages when I dialed Victor&apos;s Garage.&quot;Vic,&quot;I said,&quot;you&apos;re my last hope. Do you carry any parts for a 1962
Maserati?&quot;There was a long pause. Finally, Victor cleared his
throat.&quot;Yes,&quot;he replied.&quot;Oil.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (18) #1350 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Mar 14, 2006 5:14 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s Issue - 10:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, March 13, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Ok, as you might have noticed, I took a week off. Things are
starting to get extremely stressful dealing with my dad&apos;s estate.
Like 6 years worth of back taxes, property maintenance, a filthy
home that&apos;s two-hours drive away, and family in different states
that are also stressed. I won&apos;t bore you with all of the details,
but suffice it to say, it&apos;s not been a pretty week.

Anyway...
On the other hand, I have lots of stories to tell. That is if I can
remember them. Not only did son #4 go skiing last week, but he&apos;s
going skiing a total of 4 or 5 more times! They go to Park City and
have a one-on-one instructor teach these little kids can ski.

When they were picking out skis, son #4 was talking to the ski tech.
She asked him a question and he said,&quot;Oh, I&apos;m blind&quot;The tech
looked at him with wide eyes and said,&quot;Oh no sweetheart, you&apos;re not
blind. You&apos;re visually handicapped.&quot;Then she said very slow,&quot;Can
you say that? V-i-s-u-a-l-l-y H-a-n-d-i-c-a-p-p-e-d.&quot;My sweet wife
laughed at her and said,&quot;Please, he&apos;s only 4.&quot;She said she thought
about telling her what to do with her politically correct mumbo
jumbo, but decided to hold her tongue.

When he got his equipment, he picked up his two little skis and
tried to use them as a gun. (See picture on the blogsite. (Along
with some other pictures.) He kept pointing the skis at my sweet
wife and said,&quot;Bang!&quot;She said he looked so cute in his hat that a
reader from South Africa sent him!

When they got on the slopes, Son #4 loved it! The class was only on
there for about 90 minutes, but he went up and down the lift 4
times, while the rest of the class only made it down once or twice.
At the end he finally said,&quot;My legs need a rest!&quot;Anyway, he had a
great time.

I think I&apos;ll take a day off of work and go up with him next week.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

To Justin, Sister, and Entire Family of Greg Gourley; As an
American, and Viet Nam veteran, I salute Staff Sgt. Gregson Glenn
Gourley and his service to defend our nation. Please express my
sympathy and gratitude to his family. May our merciful Lord
comfort them in their grief and provide for every need.
James D. A.

Reading these articles makes my heart ache. I&apos;d like to offer my
condolences to Justin and his family, particularly his sister and
the children. This is, and will be, so hard on them all. May God
bless and watch over them.
~Shannon

=-=-=-

It is one thing when Justin disappeared but now Mary is among the
missing!!! Where is Marty????
~Wanda D.

I hope all is well with you and your family. I&apos;m missing your
stories and jokes. Hope you come back soon! :o)
Shay

I just sent an email from your blog. I have been missing your
emails and I went to checked at yahoogroups and nothing has been
sent since last Thursday. Then I went to the blog to see if
something was there if there was a problem with yahoogroups like
some time ago. But, nothing new there either. How are you and your
family? I hope you are all well. Please let us know. I am a bit
worried and I would think that others are also.
Kathy G.

Dear Marty,
I am extremely concerned that something really bad has happened.
Please let us know how we can pray for you&amp;your family.
Sincerely, ~Anne R.

[Thank you to the 4 of you who wrote in asking about me]


_________________________________________________________



Helpful Hints for the Inexperienced Traveler:

* Be very suspicious if the advertised price of a Caribbean
cruise includes the phrase&quot;Free Ammo&quot;* Consider carefully before visiting a country where the license
plate motto is Die American Pig.
* There is no legitimate reason for a travel agent to need to
know if you have experience in jungle warfare.
* On a trip to Canada, your travel agent should not charge you
for an interpreter.
* While in the Vatican, do not refer to St. Peter as&quot;Petey-Boy.&quot;* Do not board a cruise ship if passengers are being issued oars.
* Avoid any Latin American Tour named Bay of Pigs, Two.
* In South America, say no to anyone wanting you to deliver a
suitcase of powdered sugar to their grandmother in Miami.
* Legitimate travel agents do not dress in foreign military
uniforms.
~Ruby C.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;&quot;I hear the First National Bank is looking for a new teller.&quot;&quot;I thought they just hired a new teller last week.&quot;&quot;Right. That&apos;s the one they&apos;re looking for.&quot;~Ruby C.

_________________________________________________________



A young monk arrives at the monastery. He is assigned to helping
the other monks by copying the old canons and laws of the church
by hand. He notices however, that all of the monks are copying
from copies, not from the original manuscript. So, the new monk
goes to the head abbot to question this, pointing out that if
someone made even a small error in the first copy, it would never
be picked up and the error would be perpetuated forever in all of
the subsequent copies.&quot;That could be a terrible thing for all
time,&quot;he exclaimed. The head monk, says,&quot;We have been copying
from the copies for centuries, but you make a good point, my
son.&quot;So, he goes down into the dark caves underneath the
monastery where the original manuscripts are held as archives in a
locked vault that hasn&apos;t been opened for hundreds of years. Hours
go by and nobody sees the old abbot. So, the young monk gets
worried and goes down to look for him. He sees him banging his
head against the wall and wailing,&quot;We missed the&quot;R,&quot;Oh no, we
and left out the&quot;R.&quot;His forehead is all bloody and bruised and
he is crying uncontrollably. The young monk asks the old abbot,&quot;What&apos;s wrong, father?&quot;With a choking voice, the old abbot
replies,&quot;The original word from God to his servants was
celebrate.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (4) #1351 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Mar 15, 2006 5:36 am
 Subject: Tuesday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Tuesday, March 14, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Tonight we took the Scouts for our bi-annual scuba experience. It&apos;s
where you pay $15, go to the dive shop, get some instruction, and
play under the water until it&apos;s time to go. We had a great time! It
was kinda funny; we all got weight belts to hold us down. (I got a
few extra on my belt) When son #2 let all of the air out of his BCD,
he was still floating. Without missing a beat, the instructor took
off the weights from his belt, and stuck a couple more weights in
son #2&apos;s pockets. He sank with the rest of us and didn&apos;t even notice.

Last Sunday was fast Sunday. I haven&apos;t done interviews for awhile,
so I thought it was a good time to start again. I interview each of
the boys, alone, and ask them what&apos;s up with their lives, how things
are going, and just talk. When it was son #1&apos;s turn, I asked him
about girlfriends.&quot;Dad, you know I&apos;m not supposed to have a girl
friend until I&apos;m 16.&quot;I said,&quot;Ok, tell me who is a good friend,
who&apos;s a girl.&quot;He replied,&quot;There are a couple of them.&quot;&quot;Ok,&quot;I
said,&quot;name 3 friends who are girls.&quot;Fully expecting him to pause
for a second or two. Without a beat he said,&quot;Adrian, Alicia, and
Angel.&quot;I said,&quot;Ok, that&apos;s not bad. Hey, that&apos;s funny. Did you
notice that all 3 of those girls&apos; names start with the letter A?&quot;He grinned at me and said,&quot;I know dad. I was just listing them
alphabetically.&quot;Yikes...

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Dear Marty, Welcome back -- we all missed you! We hope some of the
stress eases up soon. Be sure you and your sweet wife take care of
YOURSELVES because stress can effect you in many, many ways... I am
so glad that [son #4] is lovin&apos; his ski lessons. What a terrific
hat!! He is such a doll and we hope he enjoys life to the fullest!
Love, Betty H.

Marty, Been there; done that with the estates of both my Mom and
my Uncle (surrogate father). It is not fun. I will keep you in
prayers during this stressful time. Best wishes,
~Eddie

Yeah I am pleased that you feel that you can write again. I didn&apos;t
realize how much I had missed it until it was not there. Thanks,
~#1 Mother in law


_________________________________________________________



I pulled up to the drive-thru of a fast-food restaurant and
ordered coffee. I asked the clerk to put some ice cubes into the
cup so that I could drink the cool coffee quickly. At the window,
there was a delay. Finally, a teen-aged girl came to the window
looking frustrated.&quot;I&apos;m having a problem,&quot;she announced.&quot;The
ice keeps melting.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;A college student at a recent USC football game challenged a
senior citizen sitting next to him, saying it was impossible for
their generation to understand his.&quot;You grew up in a different
world,&quot;the student said loud enough for the whole crowd to hear,&quot;today we have television, jet planes, space travel, man has
walked on the moon, our spaceships have visited Mars, we even have
nuclear energy, electric and hydrogen cars, computers with light-
speed processing... And uh....&quot;Taking advantage of a pause in the student&apos;s litany, the old
geezer said,&quot;You&apos;re right. We didn&apos;t have those things when we
were young; ......so we invented them, you little twit! What are
you doing for the next generation??&quot;_________________________________________________________



A group of professional people posed this question to a group of 4
to 8 year-olds,&quot;What does love mean?&quot;The answers they got were
broader and deeper than anyone could have imagined. See what you
think:&quot;When my grandmother got arthritis, she couldn&apos;t bend over and
paint her toenails anymore. So my grandfather does it for her all
the time, even when his hands got arthritis too. That&apos;s love.&quot;Rebecca- age 8&quot;When someone loves you, the way they say your name is different.
You just know that your name is safe in their mouth.&quot;Billy - age 4&quot;Love is when a girl puts on perfume and a boy puts on shaving
cologne and they go out and smell each other.&quot;Karl - age 5&quot;Love is when you go out to eat and give somebody most of your
French fries without making them give you any of theirs.&quot;Chrissy - age 6&quot;Love is what makes you smile when you&apos;re tired.&quot;Terri - age 4&quot;Love is when my mommy makes coffee for my daddy and she takes a
sip before giving it to him, to make sure the taste is OK.&quot;Danny - age 7&quot;Love is when you kiss all the time. Then when you get tired of
kissing, you still want to be together and you talk more. My Mommy
and Daddy are like that. They look gross when they kiss&quot;Emily - age 8&quot;Love is what&apos;s in the room with you at Christmas if you stop
opening presents and listen.&quot;Bobby - age 7&quot;If you want to learn to love better, you should start with a
friend who you hate,&quot;Nikka - age 6&quot;Love is when you tell a guy you like his shirt, then he wears it
everyday.&quot;Noelle - age 7&quot;Love is like a little old woman and a little old man who are
still friends even after they know each other so well.&quot;Tommy - age 6&quot;During my piano recital, I was on a stage and I was scared. I
looked at all the people watching me and saw my daddy waving and
smiling. He was the only one doing that. I wasn&apos;t scared anymore.&quot;Cindy - age 8&quot;My mommy loves me more than anybody You don&apos;t see anyone else
kissing me to sleep at night.&quot;Clare - age 6&quot;Love is when Mommy gives Daddy the best piece of chicken.&quot;Elaine-age 5&quot;Love is when Mommy sees Daddy smelly and sweaty and still says he
is handsomer than Robert Redford.&quot;Chris - age 7&quot;Love is when your puppy licks your face even after you left him
alone all day.&quot;Mary Ann - age 4&quot;I know my older sister loves me because she gives me all her old
clothes and has to go out and buy new ones.&quot;Lauren - age 4&quot;When you love somebody, your eyelashes go up and down and little
stars come out of you.&quot;Karen - age 7&quot;Love is when Mommy sees Daddy on the toilet and she doesn&apos;t think
it&apos;s gross.&quot;Mark - age 6&quot;You really shouldn&apos;t say &apos;I love you&apos; unless you mean it. But if
you mean it, you should say it a lot. People forget.&quot;Jessica - age 8
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (18) #1352 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Mar 16, 2006 5:33 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, March 15, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

[Oh, it&apos;s the Ides of March. We were going to have Caesar Salad
today, but didn&apos;t have time. We did have a pie yesterday. Why a pie?
Because it was 3.14 (pi) that&apos;s why!]

The other day I was feverishly typing away on my computer, and
noticed that it was almost time for play practice. I asked son #2 to
run a message up to my sweet wife and to tell her that if we were
going to make play practice on time, that we&apos;d better have dinner
fairly quickly. When he arrived with the message he said,&quot;Dad said
if we&apos;re going to make play practice on time, dinner needs to
hurry.&quot;She said,&quot;Go back and tell your dad that dinner is almost
ready, and we&apos;ll be eating in 15 minutes.&quot;He replied,&quot;I&apos;m not
going to tell him, I&apos;m not a messenger.&quot;Oh, just when you want to be I guess.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Love the sking photos! He looks SO cute! So it&apos;s not ok to say
&apos;blind&apos; eh? I work with all ages that have various challenges in
their lives and we are not meant to say &apos;handicapped&apos;at all! A
handicap is seen as something less that desirable - almost
derogatory, so we have to say &apos;challenged&apos; as in &apos;visually
challenged&apos; mmmm.... does that mean you can be &apos;verticly
challenged&apos; if you are short? or &apos;folicly challenged if bald&apos;? wow
this is limitless! :-)
Jen

I&apos;ve really missed your JOTD. Good luck with your dad&apos;s estate.
Thanks for returning and for the brief explanation--you were
greatly missed. I&apos;m glad that Son #4 is enjoying his ski lessons.
He is adorable.
--Justin&apos;s Mother-in-Law

_________________________________________________________


[A little kitchen or camping hint from the neighborhood Cub Master
LaMonte]

Subject: ZIPLOCK OMELETS*

(Be sure your ziplocks can go in the hot water.)

Have you ever heard of this? This works great! Good for when all
your family is together and no one has to wait for their special
omelet.

Have guests write their name on a quart-size ziploc freezer bag
with permanent marker.

Crack 2 eggs (large or extra-large) into the bag (not more than
2) shake to combine them.

Put out a variety of ingredients such as: cheeses, ham, onion,
green pepper, tomato, hash browns, salsa, etc.

Each guest adds prepared ingredients of choice to their bag and
shake, make sure to get the air out of the bag and zip it up.

Place the bags into rolling, boiling water for exactly 13 minutes.
(You can usually cook 6-8 omelets in a large pot.)

For more, make another pot of boiling water. Open the bags and the
omelet will roll out easily. Be prepared for everyone to be
amazed. Nice to serve with fresh fruit and coffee cake; everyone
gets involved in the process and a great conversation piece


[Let me know if any of you try this...]&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;While in the Navy my primary duty was to sight guns. Wanting to
move up in the military, I went to law school and applied for the
Judge Advocate General&apos;s Corps. My hopes of being a Navy lawyer
were shot down, however, when I was rejected. It seems I suffered
from poor vision.

_________________________________________________________



Thoughts for 2006

Number 8 - Good health is merely the slowest possible rate at
which one can die.

Number 7 - Give a person a fish and you feed them for a day; teach
a person to use the Internet and they won&apos;t bother you for weeks.

Number 6 - Some people are like a Slinky...not really good for
anything, but you still can&apos;t help but smile when you see one
tumble down the stairs.

Number 5 - Health nuts are going to feel stupid someday, lying in
hospitals dying of nothing.

Number 4 - All of us could take a lesson from the weather. It pays
no attention to criticism.

Number 3 - Why does a slight tax increase cost you two hundred
dollars and a substantial tax cut saves you thirty cents?

Number 2 - In the 60&apos;s, people took acid to make the world weird.
Now the world is weird and people take Prozac to make it normal.

AND THE NUMBER 1 THOUGHT FOR 2006 - We know exactly where one cow
with mad-cow-disease is located among the millions and millions of
cows in America but we haven&apos;t got a clue as to where thousands of
illegal immigrants and terrorists are located. Maybe we should put
the Department of Agriculture in charge of immigration and
homeland security.
~Jan D.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (9) #1353 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Mar 17, 2006 6:15 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, March 16, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Happy St. Paddy&apos;s day! Don&apos;t forget to wear your green tomorrow!

It&apos;s been a long day. I got home just in time to wolf down some
dinner, then it was off to a 3 hour play practice. Since I only
have a few lines, I thought I&apos;d bring the trusty camera and snap a
bunch of pictures. (A few of them are at the blog site.)

I have one scene with Frau Schmidt. And, since I&apos;m really bad with
names, after the scene, I leaned over to my sweet wife and
said,&quot;What&apos;s Frau Schmidt&apos;s name?&quot;She looked at me and said with a
slow and deliberate voice,&quot;F-R-A-U S-C-H-M-I-D-T&quot;.

Thanks, that&apos;s not quite what I meant.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

[and about those eggs in a bag...]

I&apos;ve done this many times before, and it works really well - the
omelets come out perfect. But you need to be really sure that the
ziplocks can survive the boiling water - the first bags I tried it
with totally disintegrated!
Jason A.

Marty.. this went around here last year at Church and several of
my friends tried it..they had a blast..said it definately
works..JUST make SURE the bag is sealed.. it makes a wonderful
mess in the boiling water if you don&apos;t!!! Would be wonderful on a
camping trip and you can put their names on them if someone
doesn&apos;t want the same things in their Omelet..
Debi S.

Marty... I have not tried the Omelets in a Bag, but I know folks
who have and they say it works great.
Linda B.

_________________________________________________________



Spanish singer Julio Iglesias was on television with British TV
host Anne Diamond when he used the word &apos;manyana&apos;. Diamond asked
him to explain what it meant. He said that the term means&quot;maybe
the job will be done to-morrow, maybe the next day, maybe the day
after that. Perhaps next week, next month, next year. Who cares?&quot;The host turned to Irishman Shay Brennan who was also on the show
and asked him if there was an equivalent term in Irish.&quot;No. In
Ireland we don&apos;t have a word to describe that degree of urgency.&quot;,
replied Brennan.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;Racehorse doping is not unknown in Ireland. One day, the Clerk of
the Course spotted a trainer giving something to a horse just
before the start of a race. He went over and said,&quot;Doping?&quot;The
trainer said,&quot;Indeed not, Sor. &apos;Tis just lump sugar. Look, I&apos;ll
take a bit meself.....see?&quot;The Clerk of the Course said,&quot;Sorry,
but we have to be careful. As a matter of fact, I like a bit of
sugar meself.&quot;So the trainer gave him a piece. When the Clerk of
the Course disappeared, the trainer gave his jockey his last
minute instructions,&quot;Don&apos;t forget the drill. Hold him in &apos;til the
last four furlongs. Don&apos;t worry if anything passes ye, it&apos;ll be me
or the Clerk of the Course!&quot;_________________________________________________________


Two men were sitting next to each other at a bar. After a while,
one guy looks at the other and says,&quot;I can&apos;t help but think, from
listening to you, that you&apos;re from Ireland&quot;The other guy responds proudly,&quot;Yes, that I am&quot;The first guy says,&quot;So am I And where about from Ireland might
you be?&quot;The other guy answers,&quot;I&apos;m from Dublin , I am.&quot;The first guy responds, and so am I&quot;Sure and begora, And what
street did you live on in Dublin ?&quot;The other guy says,&quot;A lovely little area it was, I lived on
McCleary Street in the old central part of town.&quot;The first guy says,&quot;Faith&amp;it&apos;s a small world, so did I!
So did I. And to what school would you have been going?&quot;The other guy answers,&quot;Well now, I went to St. Mary&apos;s
of course.&quot;The first guy gets really excited and says,&quot;And so did I. Tell
me, what year did you graduate?&quot;The other guy answers,&quot;Well, now, let&apos;s see, I graduated in
1964.&quot;The first guy exclaims,&quot;The Good Lord must be smiling down upon
us! I can hardly believe our good luck at winding up in the same
bar tonight. Can you believe it, I graduated from St. Mary&apos;s in
1964 my own self.&quot;About this time, Vicky walks into the bar, sits down, and orders a
beer. Brian, the bartender, walks over to Vicky, shaking his head&amp;mutters,&quot;It&apos;s going to be a long night tonight&quot;Vicky asks,&quot;Why do you say that, Brian?&quot;&quot;The Murphy twins are drunk again.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (4) #1354 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Mar 21, 2006 5:35 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s issue - 10:20PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, March 20, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

My dad was a hunter. Not just any hunter, but a BIG game hunter.
Not the elephant or whale big hunter, (although Moose and Elk were
among his prey) but hunting was a huge part of his life. It was
second only to raising and training his Brittany spaniel bird
dogs. (That&apos;s how we got buddy, our 14 month old dog.) A few days
after he died at my house on Christmas, we made the trek up to his
found a real mess. Among his mess, we found guns, lots of guns;
shotguns, rifles, and pistols. Some of them were old, some not so
old. Some of them are extremely valuable, some not worth a tank of
gas. And, since I&apos;m the only sibling in Utah and pretty much the
only one with an interest in guns, I voted myself dad&apos;s armory.
With his weapons stock, he had ammunition. Oh boy, did he have
ammunition. He had shells and cartridges in every conceivable
place you could think of. After days of cleaning, we had more than
a 100 boxes of shotgun shells (25/box) and a lot of rifle
cartridges.

Then I came to the stark realization that 4 boys, a few dozen
guns, and 2500 rounds of ammunition might be cause for a wee bit
of concern. Although I had enough trigger locks for the guns I
already owned, putting them all of the guns just wasn&apos;t a long
term solution. So my sweet wife and I put the guns in our bedroom
and locked the door morning noon and night. Then, with everything
else going on in my life, I went shopping for a gun safe. I had to
be a good sized one so all of the guns and ammo would fit. A few
weeks ago I found a very nice used one at a gun shop. It took 6
men to pull it off, but it&apos;s now in my basement. It&apos;s a tight
squeeze, but it fits all of the guns and ammo. Now I can sleep
better. (You can see a picture of it, and the antelope head I
inherited, on our blog site. [ http://martysjotd.blogspot.com ]

So, a few Saturdays ago I grabbed son #3, the pee wee .22 rifle
for him, and some shot guns for me, and we headed off to the
range. We had another great Saturday. That is until I pulled out
the 12 gauge shotgun. I must confess; I didn&apos;t know there was such
a difference in 12 gauge shot gun shells until that morning. I put
in 2 heavy 4 shot goose (or was that moose) shells and shot at a
clay pigeon. I dusted the pigeon; and my shoulder with it. It was
like a mule kick.&quot;OUCH!&quot;I yelled. Son #3 giggled.&quot;No, really;
that hurt a LOT!&quot;I thought maybe I held the gun wrong, or did
something wrong. So I moved it over and held a little tighter this
time.&quot;PULL!&quot;I said. I completely missed the clay pigeon, and got
slammed hard with another mule kick. The next morning as I was
getting ready for church and showed my sweet wife the 2 large
bruises on my shoulder. Needless to say, I put it away and didn&apos;t
shoot the 12 gauge again.


But, last Saturday I thought, `after falling off the horse&apos; I&apos;d
better get back on. So Friday night I got everything ready. Pee
wee rifle for the little ones, .410 and 20 gauge for the boys, and
the 12 gauge for me. I got the clay pigeon thrower ready, the
pigeons, the ammo, the rifle targets, everything. When we arrived
at the range and started setting up, I realized I forgot one
important thing; the spring to the clay pigeon thrower. You can&apos;t
throw pigeons very well without that spring. But, since we were 45
minutes away from home, we tried. We threw an entire box of
pigeons by hand. (no little plastic thrower either. We threw them
just like a baseball.) We had another great Saturday, but now my
arm is sore for throwing all of those stupid clay pigeons.

And yes, this time I brought 12 gauge 8 shot for dove, quail, and
squirrel. I didn&apos;t kick at all. Son #2 said it was his favorite
gun for the day.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Dear Marty, I have made many omelets in a bag. They are great!
They cook perfectly without burning, there is no dirty skillet or
mixing bowl, and I use paper plates when we have a large group, so
there is very little clean up. Some variations we use are:
chopped onions, chopped green bell peppers, chopped chili peppers,
chopped pre-cooked sausage, chopped ham, shredded cheese, and
tater tots. Salsa and ketchup are reserved for toppings.
~Lester M. 

_________________________________________________________



No doubt about it, the new temp didn&apos;t have a clue about
computers. Since part of her job was directing calls to our
technical support department, I gave her simple instructions:&quot;When people call with computer problems, always ask which
operating system they&apos;re using--Windows, Macintosh or UNIX.&quot;Later, she handed a technician this phone message...&quot;Call
immediately. Customer has problem with eunuchs.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;My husband had reluctantly agreed to come shopping with me. But
when he found himself stuck in a lingerie shop while I tried on
one garment after another, he regretted his decision. Impatient
and bored he asked a salesclerk,&quot;Is there anything in the store
for men?&quot;&quot;Sir,&quot;she said,&quot;everything in this store is for men.&quot;_________________________________________________________



A U.S. Marine squad was marching north of Faluijiah when they came
upon an Iraqi terrorist, badly injured and unconscious. On the
opposite side of the road was an American Marine in a similar but
less serious state. The Marine was conscious and alert and as
first aid was given to both men, the squad leader asked the
injured Marine what had happened. The Marine reported,&quot;I was
heavily armed and moving north along the highway here, and coming
south was a heavily armed insurgent. We saw each other and both
took cover in the ditches along the road.&quot;I yelled to him that
Saddam Hussein is a miserable, lowlife scumbag, and he yelled back
that Senator Ted Kennedy is a good-for-nothing, fat, left wing
liberal drunk. So I said that Osama Bin Ladin dresses and acts
like a frigid, mean spirited lesbian!&quot;He retaliated by yelling,&quot;Oh yeah? Well, so does Mrs. Clinton!&quot;&quot;And, there we were, in the
middle of the road, shaking hands, when a truck hit us&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #1355 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Mar 22, 2006 4:57 am
 Subject: Tuesday&apos;s Issue - 10:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Tuesday, March 21, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

I was really excited to go skiing up at Park City with Son #4 and
his class today. But, Murphy&apos;s Law kicked in, and he came down
with some nasty gomboo. High fever, sore throat, cough, runny
nose, and the runs. Son #1 went to the instacare on Saturday with
the same stuff, and they said it was probably a virus. Now son #3
and #4 have it. I&apos;m sure the rest of us aren&apos;t far behind.

But, since I had the day scheduled off anyway, I thought I&apos;d spend
the time doing my own taxes. Then, at noon I had a mediocre lunch
at the elementary school with sons #2 and #3. The company was
great, but the food wasn&apos;t. It wasn&apos;t what I remembered when I was
in elementary school. Of course, the lunch lady and I were good
friends back then...

Not much else happened today. Although the youth of our church
went downtown to a homeless shelter tonight. We had a game night
with the kids who were there. It was a pretty good experience for
most everyone. And an eye opener for some of our kids.

And, last but not least; my sweet wife is in a contest with other
artists on ebay, trying to sell art collector cards with this
week&apos;s them,&quot;Its not easy being green&quot;She&apos;s trying to get as
many bidders as she can to win. You can check out her at here. http://search.ebay.com/_W0QQfgtpZ1QQfsooZ1QQfsopZ1QQsassZmelQ2dann For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Marty: Since you have inherited your Fathers gun collection and
are a hunter, and Scouter, please be advised that there is (was?)
a Merit Badge for both Black Powder and Rifle and Shot Gun in Boy
Scouts... ...No matter what, working on the Merit Badges will
teach&quot;Gun Safety&quot;. Worth a try.
John C.
(Former BSA Troop226,
Golden Empire Council
Sacramento, CA)

[Yup, they still have rifle shooting and shot gun shooting merit
badges. Something to look into!]


Marty, It is so neat that you take the time in your busy life to
put on pictures and stories on your website. Keep up the good
work.
Love Mom G...
~#1 Mother-in-law...
[Thanks Mom!]

_________________________________________________________



The bride was anything but a tidy housekeeper. It didn&apos;t bother
her much until one evening when her husband called from the hall,
somewhat dismayed:&quot;Honey, what happened to the dust on this
table? I had a phone number written on it.&quot;&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;After many years of faithful duty with the US Forest
Service, their beloved fire prevention mascot was unceremoniously&quot;re-tired.&quot;Still in the prime of his life and bearing one of
the world&apos;s most recognizable faces, he quickly found work as a
spokesman for the world&apos;s leading exporter of diamonds. He&apos;s now
working as&quot;Smokey DeBeers.&quot;_________________________________________________________



I had just moved into a new apartment and was having problems with
the mailman, who was delivering the previous tenant&apos;s mail to my
address. Hoping to resolve the situation, I enlarged my name on
the mailbox, but he still kept giving me the wrong letters.
Finally, I left a note saying that he was delivering the mail
incorrectly. The next day I went to the box to find this addition
to my message:&quot;Sir, I am delivering the mail correctly. You&apos;re
just living at the wrong address.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (5) #1356 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Mar 23, 2006 6:10 am
 Subject: Wednesday&apos;s Issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Wednesday, March 22, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Today at son #1&apos;s school, it was&quot;Reality Town&quot;. This is a one day
program where they take the students&apos; classes, interests, and most
importantly, their GPA, and give them a `life&apos;. They take on a
career, salary, and family responsibilities. They have to write
checks to pay the bills for housing, food, transportation, and
entertainment. They have a bank where they deposit their checks,
or they can get a loan. It&apos;s kind of like the game of life without
the stupid spinner. http://www.uba.org/displaycommon.cfm?an=1&amp;subarticlenbr=31 Son #1 got a fairly good paying job with his GPA at $50K/Yr. He
had some sort of computer job. He said he gave his `wife&apos; their
only car, and he took the bus because it was cheaper. (That might
get old fast...) He said he was doing really well but then said,&quot;I got board and decided to take another wife... uh hum, I mean
another job.&quot;Watch it youngster...

Although it is funny being from Utah, and the stereotypical ideas
people have about Utah and polygamy. When my sweet wife and I
travel (rarely) to far away places, I&apos;ve even introduced her
saying,&quot;This is my ~first~ wife.&quot;It&apos;s funny to see people&apos;s
reactions. (And yes... for those wondering, she is my only
wife...)

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:&gt;Marty, It is so neat that you take the time in your busy life to&gt;put on pictures and stories on your website. Keep up the good&gt;work. Love Mom G... ~#1 Mother-in-law...

To Mom G...
Would this be because he doesn&apos;t have time to send family
pictures? I know this feeling all too well..even the grandbaby
that lives close by..but then, my camera&apos;s not broke..but I just
forget to take pics, since I&apos;m busy on the floor playing with
him..haha Keep up the great work Marty...we luv ya and your
family!!!
~Debi s.

_________________________________________________________



An old man is celebrating his 50th wedding anniversary. His young
grandsons asks him how it feels to be married this long! He says
fine. Then he is asked how he made it so long? What is the secret?
The old guy looks at his grand sons and says&quot;We always follow the
happy home rule!&quot;&quot;What is that&quot;? asks the boy?&quot;The rule is. If
mom ain&apos;t happy, Ain&apos;t no one allowed to be happy!&quot;~Don W.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;We went to the movie the other night. I sat in an aisle seat as I
usually do because it feels a little roomier. Just as the feature
was about to start a blonde from the center of the row got up and
started working her way out.&quot;Excuse me, sorry, oops, excuse me,
pardon me, gotta hurry, oops, excuse me.&quot;By the time she got to
me I was trying to look around her and I was a little impatient so
I said,&quot;Couldn&apos;t you have done this a little earlier?&quot;&quot;No!!&quot;she
said in a loud whisper,&quot;The TURN OFF YOUR CELL PHONE PLEASE
message just flashed up on the screen and mine is in the car.&quot;~Jan D.

_________________________________________________________



A judge enters the courtroom, strikes the gavel and says,&quot;Before
I begin this trial, I have an announcement to make. The lawyer for
the defense has paid me $15,000 to swing the case his way. The
lawyer for the plaintiff has paid me $10,000 to swing the case her
way. In order to make this a fair trial, I am returning $5,000 to
the defense.&quot;~Wanda D.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (7) #1357 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Mar 24, 2006 5:47 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 10:45PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, March 23, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Aren&apos;t taxes fun? We just submitted ours, and we should get a
refund back in a couple of weeks. There&apos;s always a two pronged
debate going on in my head at tax time. The first is,&quot;if you get
a rebate, dummy, why don&apos;t you file on way back in January?&quot;I
never could answer that one. Laziness I guess. The other side of
the debate is, if you get such a large refund, why do you let the
government use your money all year? You could be getting that
money back during the year. I guess some people (me?) like a
forced savings program.

But what really gets me, is during the year when people say,&quot;Oh,
I don&apos;t want to work overtime. Because when I get that paycheck,
it always throws me in a higher tax bracket and the government
ends up taking more of my money.&quot;If they saw the big picture, and
realize that taxes are calculated at the end of the year taking
total income, minus all the deductions you can find, multiplied by
a tax rate, minus what you paid in taxes. That extra 50 bucks you
get on overtime isn&apos;t going to affect your overall taxes that
much.

But, I&apos;m a computer guy, not a tax man. If I were, I would
probably just tell everyone to claim zero dependants on their W4
forms, and wait until April 15th to file and get a fat refund.

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

p.s. Sorry, not one of my better posts, but, it&apos;ll have to do.

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:&gt;Yup, they still have rifle shooting and shot gun shooting merit&gt;badges. Something to look into!


This kinda brings back memories back in &apos;59 or &apos;60 when me&amp;ole
John were shootin flaming arrows straight up and into the Little
Wichita River, down @ Blakes Farm on a 2 nighter and one of the
flaming arrows set the Scoutmaster Ed Homcomps tent on fire. Ah!
such memories
Norman O.
Former Troop 136 - Wichita Falls, Texas - Life&amp;Order of The
Arrow Brotherhood

[I had a Scoutmaster with the same last name as yours. Your email
brought back a lot of good memories...]

_________________________________________________________




Recently a group of art experts were studying the Mona Lisa.
Gradually, one by one, they started sneezing. Some of them had
watery eyes and some had a fever. It turned out that they
contracted the mysterious Da Vinci Cold.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;Widowed for the second time, my grandmother told me she probably
would not remarry.&quot;You&apos;re still young,&quot;I said.&quot;Why not?&quot;&quot;When
I married your dad&apos;s father I became a Smith. Then I married your
Grandpa Ernie and became Schmidt. I&apos;m afraid of what&apos;ll happen
next.&quot;_________________________________________________________



With his squad at attention, my father&apos;s drill sergeant began
inspecting their rifles. Grabbing one soldier&apos;s M-1, he peered
down the barrel only to be stared back at by a spider.&quot;Two
demerits,&quot;yelled the sergeant.&quot;Why two?&quot;asked the private.&quot;One for keeping an unclean weapon,&quot;said the sergeant.&quot;And one
for keeping an unauthorized pet.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (3) #1358 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Mar 28, 2006 6:19 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s Issue - 11:15PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, March 27, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

On Saturday we had our annual Scouting for Food drive. I always
get a little nervous before the Scout show up. I never know how
many to expect. We only had 3 from the troop show up, but with my
sweet wife, son #3 and a couple of other leaders, it went pretty
quick. The night before the food drive, I told son #3 that we
could go shooting when we were done, but it turned out to be too
windy. Son #3 was pretty disappointed, but we&apos;ll get him next
weekend. So then I stayed home and painted our new front door. I
even stayed pretty clean and didn&apos;t get too much on the porch!

After that, we had to go to play practice. Since I&apos;ve been to
almost every practice, and when I don&apos;t have lines I just kind of
hang around and watch the rest of the cast do their parts, the
director keeps adding extra lines to my part. I was doing pretty
well until I got up to do one of my scenes and I was totally lost.&quot;Um, where ~are~ we?&quot;I said. Funny, after that the directory
didn&apos;t have any extra lines for me. We&apos;re supposed to have all of
our lines memorized by Thursday. I think I&apos;ll need you guys to
wish me luck!

Now, I just need to find an internet site that will teach me how
to do a thick German accent. Any ideas?

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

None today.
_________________________________________________________



My husband and I had just finished tucking our five young ones
into bed one evening when we heard sobbing coming from three-
year-old Billy&apos;s room. Rushing to his side, we found him crying
hysterically. He had accidentally swallowed a penny and was sure
he was going to die. No amount of talking could change his mind.
Desperate to calm him, my husband palmed a penny that he happened
to have in his pocket and pretended to pull it from Billy&apos;s ear.
Billy was delighted. In a flash, he snatched it from my husband&apos;s
hand, swallowed it and demanded cheerfully,&quot;Do it again, Dad!&quot;Shannon in Nevada&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;As an airline reservation agent, I took a call from a man who
wanted to book a flight for two but wasn&apos;t happy with the price of
$59 per ticket.&quot;I want the $49 fare I saw advertised,&quot;he
insisted, saying he would accept a flight at any time. I managed
to find two seats on a 6 a.m. flight.&quot;I&apos;ll take it,&quot;he said,
then worried his wife might not like the early hour. I warned
there was a fee of $25 per person if he changed the reservation.&quot;Oh, that&apos;s no problem,&quot;he said dismissively.&quot;What&apos;s fifty
bucks?&quot;_________________________________________________________



I couldn&apos;t find my luggage at the airport baggage area. So
I went to the lost luggage office and told the woman there
that my bags never showed up. She smiled and told me not to worry
as they were trained professionals and I was in good hands.&quot;Now,&quot;she asked me,&quot;has your plane arrived yet?&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (2) #1359 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Mar 29, 2006 5:42 am
 Subject: Tuesday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Tuesday, March 28, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Today is the 27th anniversary of the 3 mile island nuclear
accident. It is the worst nuclear accident in US History.
www.nrc.gov/reading-rm/doc-collections/fact-sheets/3mile-isle.html
The accident didn&apos;t kill anyone, and only released a small amount
of off-site radioactivity, but it brought about sweeping changes
in nuclear energy regulatory oversight.

And speaking of radiation; that reminds me of son #4. He has
his 2nd post-op MRI next Monday. My sweet wife and I have the Pre-
MRI Jitters. I don&apos;t think there&apos;s any way we can get used to
this. We had a clean scan and a 5th birthday with him since the
end of his treatments in December. So that&apos;s got to mean good
results on Monday... Right?


Last night for family night we went to see the Lion, the Witch and
the wardrobe.
( http://adisney.go.com/disneypictures/narnia/index.html ) We all
thought it was really, except for son #4 who fell asleep in my
sweet wife&apos;s lap about an hour in After the movie, when we were
walking to the car, son #1 said something about,&quot;Wow, that was
really a cool religious movie!&quot;I said,&quot;Huh?&quot;He said,&quot;Yeah dad,
remember; the lion died for someone else&apos;s sins. He came back to
life and fought against Evil.&quot;Then he said,&quot;C.S. Lewis&apos; books
are even in the religious section at the library.&quot;I said,&quot;Oh,
yeah, that makes sense...&quot;I guess my mind is on MRIs...

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:


[&gt;Now, I just need to find an internet site that will teach me]
[&gt;how to do a thick German accent. Any ideas?]

A thick German accent requires a lot of phlegm. Eat some candy
and drink sone OJ. Good luck.
~Justin H.

A German accent? That&apos;s EASY! Watch a couple of hours of&quot;Hogan&apos;s
Heroes&quot;! You could do Schultz, the dumb German, Klink, the wimp
German, or Hoffsteder, the stereotypical mindless, ruthless,
Gestapo movie German.
Jeff G. Pittsburgh

Rent German movies or WW2 movies
Kobus B.

[Thanks all!]

_________________________________________________________



At R.O.T.C. summer camp at Eglin Air Force Base in Florida, we
were nervous about our approaching survival training, for we would
be pitching our tents in a snake-infested swamp. Our instructor,
advising us on the treatment of snake bites, explained that the
venom of rattlesnakes, copperheads and water moccasins affected
the circulatory system. Their bites were to be treated with
tourniquets, incisions and suction. The poison of the coral snake,
on the other hand, affected the nervous system. At this point he
closed his manual.&quot;Sir,&quot;asked a cadet,&quot;what do we do if a coral
snake bites one of us?&quot;&quot;Turn to page A1-7 in your manuals.&quot;There
was a flurry of activity as we flipped through the guides. When we
looked up, our smiles were sickly. Page A1-7 consisted entirely of
interdenominational prayers.
~Wanda D.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;My dear friend, a divorcee, never remarried, and her daughter
wanted to know why.&quot;The men I know would bring too much heavy
baggage to the marriage and I simply don&apos;t want to put up with
it,&quot;she explained. Taking her mother&apos;s hand in hers, my friend&apos;s
daughter said sweetly,&quot;I hate to break the news to you, Mom,
but you&apos;re not exactly carry-on yourself.&quot;_________________________________________________________



The flight home from a recent business trip was pretty empty. So
the pilot made a simple request of the passengers.&quot;We have a
little extra room tonight, folks,&quot;he said over the PA system.&quot;So
if you wouldn&apos;t mind, please take a window seat so the competition
thinks the plane is full.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (18) #1360 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Mar 31, 2006 5:27 am
 Subject: Thursday&apos;s Issue - 10:30PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Thursday, March 30, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Dija miss me? I didn&apos;t think so.

With everything so booked up with Scouts, play practice, trips to
Randolph for cleaning and packing, and son #4&apos;s upcoming MRI,
there isn&apos;t much time for just my sweet wife and me. She never
says so, but I think she envies my Saturday outings with the boys.
So, as a stress reliever we decided to take one night off.

We got grandma and grandpa to watch the 4 boys over night, (THANK
YOU GUYS!) and we decided to go to the Castle Creek Inn.
( http://castleutah.com ) It&apos;s a pretty cool bed and breakfast inn
not too far from home. It&apos;s a small castle with 10 theme rooms. We
spent a night in the base of one of the towers. Last night we had
a nice dinner and got to spend some really quiet time together.
It&apos;s amazing how quiet it gets without 4 little boys running
around.

Anyway when we told son #1 where we were going he said,&quot;Why are
you doing that? It&apos;s just like a hotel room.&quot;Yeah, give it a few
years youngster...

Anyway, I took the day off from work and we spent the day together
doing just... stuff. We looked for entry way lights, stopped at
the bank, the post office, bought some shoes, you know, all the
boring stuff. But, it was nice to spend some time along, plus, for
me it was a welcome break from work.

So, if you can plan a mid-week break with your spouse away from
the kids, do it. It&apos;s worth it!

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

p.s. I think I told you last week that Son #4&apos;s MRI was on Monday.
I goofed. I think it&apos;s ~my~ noodle that&apos;s messed up, not his. His
MRI is actually Tuesday at 8AM, not Monday. That&apos;ll give all of us
an extra day to pray for a clean scan!

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

Marty,
I will be keeping son #4 and your family in prayer that the test
results are good. God bless you!
Eddie

Marty -- I took German in school, (many moons ago) and our teacher
always told us to get the &apos;fish bone&apos; sound. I guess another way
to put it would be a &apos;rolling&apos; sound in the throat.. Can&apos;t expain
it, but I sure remember she corrected our pronounciation no matter
where she met us, even during off school hrs.!! She even corrected
our English and I&apos;m so glad b/c at my age (and it&apos;s old) I still
have a good handle on using proper words/ distinction, etc. etc.
Have a great day and good luck on the German sound!! :-)
~Cathy

_________________________________________________________



Imponderable questions;

If a deaf person has to go to court, is it still called a hearing?

Why are you IN a movie, but you&apos;re ON TV?

Why do doctors leave the room while you change? They&apos;re going to
see you naked anyway.

Why is&quot;bra&quot;singular and&quot;panties&quot;plural?

Why do people point to their wrist when asking for the time, but
don&apos;t point to their crotch when they ask where the bathroom is?

Why do toasters always have a setting that burns the toast to a
Horrible crisp, which no decent human being would eat?

Can a hearse carrying a corpse drive in the carpool lane?

What do you call male ballerinas?

Did you ever notice that when you blow in a dog&apos;s face, he gets
mad at you, but when you take him for a car ride; he sticks his
head out the window?&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;The Drug Problem in America


The other day, someone at a store in our town read that a
methamphetamine lab had been found in an old farmhouse in the
adjoining county and he asked me a rhetorical question, &apos;&apos;Why
didn&apos;t we have a drug problem when you and I were growing up?&apos;&apos;

I replied: I had a drug problem when I was young:

I was drug to church on Sunday morning.

I was drug to church for weddings and funerals.

I was drug to family reunions and community socials no matter the
weather.

I was drug by my ears when I was disrespectful to adults.

I was also drug to the woodshed when I disobeyed my parents, told
a lie, brought home a bad report card, did not speak with respect,
spoke ill of the teacher or the preacher, or if I didn&apos;t put forth
my best effort in everything that was asked of me.

I was drug to the kitchen sink to have my mouth washed out with
soap if I uttered a profane four-letter word.

I was drug out to pull weeds in mom&apos;s garden and flower beds and
cockleburs out of dad&apos;s fields.

I was drug to the homes of family, friends, and neighbors to help
out some poor soul who had no one to mow the yard, repair the
clothesline, or chop some firewood; and, if my mother had ever
known that I took a single dime as a tip for this kindness, she
would have drug me back to the woodshed.

Those drugs are still in my veins; and they affect my behavior in
everything I do, say, and think. They are stronger than cocaine,
crack, or heroin; and, if today&apos;s children had this kind of drug
problem, America would be a better place.
~author unknown~

_________________________________________________________



When our lawn mower broke and wouldn&apos;t run, my wife kept hinting
to me that I should get it fixed. But, somehow I always had
something else to take care of first, the truck, the car, and
fishing, always something more important to me. Finally she
thought of a clever way to make her point. When I arrived home one
day, I found her seated in the tall grass, busily snipping away
with a tiny pair of sewing scissors. I watched silently for a
short time and then went into the house. I was gone only a few
minutes. When I came out again I handed her a toothbrush.&quot;When
you finish cutting the grass,&quot;I said,&quot;you might as well sweep
the sidewalk.&quot;The doctors say I will walk again, but I will
always have a limp.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (18) #1361 From: &quot;martysjotd&quot;&lt;martysjotd@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Apr 4, 2006 5:05 am
 Subject: Monday&apos;s issue - 11:00PM martysjotd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 ****************************************************************
Welcome to: Marty&apos;s Joke of the Day

Don&apos;t Forget to Read my BLOG at http://martysjotd.blogspot.com/ To ensure delivery of Marty&apos;s Joke of the day emails,
please add `martysjotd-owner@yahoogroups.com &apos; to your approved email
sender list.

If you&apos;d like to receive daily emails from us, send a
blank email to martysjotd-subscribe@yahoogroups.com or
visit http://www.egroups.com/group/martysjotd ****************************************************************

~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Monday, April 03, 2006
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Well, tomorrow&apos;s the big day. Son #4 is getting his 2nd post op MRI
tomorrow. I&apos;ve got a little uneasy feeling about this one, but we&apos;ll
just have to wait and find out what the scan shows.

It&apos;s a good thing that we&apos;ll have to leave pretty early with him
tomorrow, because he&apos;ll get no breakfast. He gets a little cranky
when he doesn&apos;t get breakfast. But then again, so do I.

Not much else to write, I&apos;m busy holding my breath.

Wish us luck!

For those of you who get this as email...
Enjoy today&apos;s Jokes!
Marty

=-=-=-
Reader Comment Section:

On Wednesday of this week, at two minutes and three seconds after
1AM in the morning, the time and date will be;

01:02:03 04/05/06.

That probably won&apos;t ever happen again in your lifetime!
~Sandra B.

It;s soo hadr to tpye wtih my fnginers corossed, but tehy will be
corossed utnil we haer that all is wlel whith [sno 4#].
(I;ll tpye slwoer....) There are so many people praying for him,
I KNOW everything will be fine!! So glad you and your sweet wife
could get away for a day, and what a fabulous place! Who knew we
had something that nice so close to home?? Prayers and love to
[son #4] and all of you.
~Betty H.


_________________________________________________________



If the Commandment to Love one another as thy self were kept,
there would be no crime in the world. This may come as a surprise
to those of you not living in Las Vegas, but there are more
Catholic churches there than casinos. Not surprisingly, some
worshippers at Sunday services will give casino chips rather than
cash when the basket is passed. Since they get chips from so many
different casinos, the churches have devised a method to collect
the offerings. The churches send all their collected chips to a
nearby Franciscan Monastery for sorting and then the chips are
taken to the casinos of origin and cashed in. This is done by the
chip monks.
~Jan D.&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;~&lt;&gt;&quot;To me, boxing is like a ballet, except there&apos;s no music, no
choreography and the dancers hit each other.&quot;~Jack Handy, Deep Thoughts

_________________________________________________________



When a customer left his cell phone in my store, I scrolled
through his saved numbers, stopped at&quot;Mom&quot;and pushed send. His
mother answered, and I told her what happened.&quot;Don&apos;t worry,&quot;she
said,&quot;I&apos;ll take care of it.&quot;A few minutes later, the cell phone
rang. It was&quot;Mom.&quot;&quot;Martin,&quot;she said,&quot;you left your cell phone
at the convenience store

=-=-=-

After learning the Lamaze method of natural childbirth, I was
admitted to the delivery room with my wife. It seemed like an
eternity before the doctor finally announced,&quot;I&apos;ve got the head
now; just a few more minutes.&quot;&quot;Is it a girl or boy?&quot;I asked
excitedly. The doctor replied,&quot;I don&apos;t know. It&apos;s hard to tell by
the ears.&quot;
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (6) 
 
 Messages 1332 - 1361 of 1600  Oldest  |  &lt; Older  |  Newer &gt;  |  Newest 

 
      What&apos;s This? Actions Start Topic 
Just address an email to martysjotd@yahoogroups.com

 Jump to a particular message Message # Search Messages Advanced 
SPONSOR RESULTS
 
 Double Your Book Sales DoubleYourBookSales .com - Free articles share latest self-publishing success techniques 
 

 Huge humor shirt www.roadkilltshirts .com - Roadkillshirts.com has humorous tees for everyone - men&apos;s ringers and 
 

 Humor SnorgTees www.snorgtees. com - Funniest humor t-shirts by SnorgTees. 
 
 
 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
