<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005442" url="http://foodallergies.about.com/" time="2012-07-12-21:59" support="5" score="0.022048401772616716" bingtitle="Food Allergies About.com" webtitle="Food Allergies About.com">
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>Home page for food allergies and food sensitivities on About.com</description>
	<body>
		Health 
 
 Food Allergies 
 Search 
 Food Allergies Symptoms / Treatment By Allergy Coping 

 Share 
 Must Reads 
 First Steps: Food Allergies Anaphylaxis: What You Need to Know Most Common Food Allergies Food Allergy Signs and Symptoms Safety Tips for Kids with Food Allergies 
 
 Jeanette Bradley 
Food Allergies Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter My Bio 
 
 Headlines Forum 
 Browse Topic 
 Allergies Age By Age Food Allergy Basics Reading Labels Diagnosing Food Allergies Common Food Allergies Treatment Living with Food Allergies Cooking Tips Emergency Treatment Allergy Recipes Glossary Blogs 
 Recipe of the Week Dairy-Free Corn on the COb 
You&apos;ll never miss the butter in this spicy take on the classic taste of summer.
 Read More Allergy-Friendly Summer Meals 
 Middle Eastern Chickpea Salad Egg-Free, Dairy-Free, Soy-Free Potato Salad Fun Gelatin Shapes 
 
About.com Health&apos;s Disease and Condition content is reviewed by our Medical Review Board 
 
 Including Kids with Food Allergies 
 
How to include children with food allergies in your group, school, or camp - while keeping them safe.
 Read More Safety for Kids with Food Allergies 
 Raising a Peanut-Free Child Safety Tips Top Food Allergies for Kids 
 Food Allergies Spotlight 10 
 Easy, Allergy-Friendly Summer Foods 
 Thursday July 5, 2012 
 

When the temperature climbs and you don&apos;t even want to be in your kitchen, let alone turn on the oven, what are you going to eat? Turn to these easy, allergy-friendly summer recipes for your next cool-down snack or cold summer meal:

 Fruit kebabs . Simply slice, chop, and thread on skewers. Popsicles. From Vegan Fudgesicle s to Cantaloupe , popsicles are easy to make and are both a cooling treat and a way tore-hydrateon a hot day. Salads - tossed salad, no-mayo potato salad , or gluten-free pasta salad are all simple to make, allergy-friendly standbys. Or try something new, like this Avocado Grapefruit Salad that is free of the big 8 allergens. Lettuce wraps. Inspired by Thai food, these Raw Lettuce Wraps are free of the big 8 allergens, and the dipping sauce can be modified to be as well by removing the soy sauce. But really, you can wrap anything you want in lettuce and call it a lettuce wrap - from pulled pork to chickpea salad . 

Remember to follow the guidelines for safe grilling if you plan to attend a cookout or host one at home. And enjoy your summer of safe eats!
 
 Comments (0) Permalink Share 

 Red, White, and Blueberry 
 Thursday June 28, 2012 
 

Are you planning or attending a 4th of July picnic? Try one of these new cupcake recipes to create an all-natural, allergy-friendly red, white, and blue dessert. These recipes are all free of dairy, eggs, soy, nuts, peanuts, and artificial colors and flavors. They can be modified to be wheat-free as well by using a wheat-free flour mix.

Bake one dozen of each of these cupcakes:

 All-Natural Strawberry Cupcakes Blueberry Cupcakes with Blueberry Frosting Lemon-Vanilla Cupcakes 

Using natural food colorings and sprinkles, decorate your cupcakes in red, white, and blue to celebrate the day. Arrange your cupcakes in stripes of color on the serving platter for maximum effect.

If you want to go all out, print out tiny American flags that can be wrapped around toothpicks or strung together in a banner. So cute, and so delicious!
 
 Comments (0) Permalink Share 

 Common Household Chemicals Linked to Children&apos;s Allergies 
 Wednesday June 27, 2012 
 Another study has found a link between common antibacterical chemicals and the risk of allergies in young children. Researchers at Johns Hopkins Medical School looked at over 10,000 children enrolled in a national study and found that the higher the level of exposure to triclosan and parabens that these children had, the higher the risk of having at least one food or environmental allergy.

Triclosan and parabens are found in everything from anti-bacterial hand soap to shampoo and toothpaste. They are even added to products like kitchenware, clothing, cosmetics, and toys to prevent bacterial and fungal growth. Both chemicals are known endocrinedisruptors .

So, should you toss out your hand sanitizer and anti-bacterial soap if you have a child at risk of food allergies ? Maybe. Soaps containing triclosan don&apos;t clean any better than regular soap and water, and hand sanitizer doesn&apos;t remove food allergerns . Buying regular soap will only reduce your exposure to these chemicals, however. They are in so many consumer products that it is impossible to completely avoid them.

There does seem to be a growing body of evidence that there is another side to the classic &quot; hygiene hypothesis &quot; of food allergies. In addition to not having enough exposure to good bacteria, too much exposure to anti-bacterial chemicals at an early age can increase the risk of developing allergies.



 
 Comments (1) Permalink Share 

 When Things Go Wrong (With the Best of Intentions) 
 Wednesday June 13, 2012 
 

I picked my daughter up from school yesterday and she was wearing a different shirt. A shirt I&apos;d never seen before. I asked what had happened and she told me there had been a mayonnaise explosion in the lunch room that had hit her in the back, but, as she said: &quot;It&apos;s OK because it only had vegetable oil in it.&quot;

&quot;Vegetable oil is soybean oil,&quot; I said.

She burst into tears. &quot;I knew it! I knew I was allergic to it but no one would believe me!&quot; And the story came out. How the lunch aide hadn&apos;t believed her but had read the ingredients anyway. And hadn&apos;t seen any soy in the ingredient list , so had decided the mayonnaise was fine.

Part of the unique challenge of soy allergies is that, despite soy being a big 8 allergen, the food allergy labeling law (FALCPA) has a special exception for soybean oil and soy lecithin. Manufacturers do not have to provide an allergen warning or even list these ingredients in &quot;plain English&quot; as required for other common allergens.

Some studies have found that most people with soy allergies can tolerate the small amounts of soy protein that remain in processed soy oil. But not everyone can. Similar studies have found that refined peanut oil is safe for people with peanut allergies, but there is no exception in the labeling law for certain peanut ingredients. I can only speculate on the politics behind that ruling.

Our story ends well. My daughter ended up with a contact reaction, but nothing more serious. I was proud that our role play practice paid off and she insisted on seeing the school nurse, even after being told the food was OK for her. The Emergency Action Plan we wrote wasn&apos;t implemented exactly how it should have been (I didn&apos;t get a phone call) but she did get a clean shirt and a check up. And everyone involved learned something from the incident.

What haunts me though is that all the adults involved in this situation had the best of intentions and yet were unable to keep my daughter safe because of this legal loophole.

FALCPA is not enough. It has too many exceptions and only covers 8 of the thousands of foods that are potential allergens.

We have the right as consumers to know what we are putting into (or on) our bodies. Every ingredient of every food needs to be disclosed, and it needs to be listed for what it is. No more &quot;modified food starch&quot; or &quot;natural flavorings.&quot; No &quot;vegetable oil&quot; with pictures of lettuce and tomatoes on the label. Tell us what is really in our food, and then we can decide if we really want to eat it.

Every ingredient of every food. A radical idea? Or one whose time has come?
 
 Comments (13) Permalink Share 
 See More Free Food Allergies Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 Explore Food Allergies Must Reads 
 First Steps: Food Allergies Anaphylaxis: What You Need to Know Most Common Food Allergies Food Allergy Signs and Symptoms Safety Tips for Kids with Food Allergies 
 Most Popular 
 Shellfish Allergy Wheat Ingredient List Egg Allergies Alcohol Allergies/Intolerances Wheat Allergy 
 Free Food Allergies Newsletter! Sign Up By Category 
 Allergies Age By Age Food Allergy Basics Reading Labels Diagnosing Food Allergies Common Food Allergies Treatment Living with Food Allergies Cooking Tips Emergency Treatment Allergy Recipes Glossary Blogs 
 
 Food Allergies 
 
 About.com Health Food Allergies 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 Also from About.com: 
 Calorie Count - Nutrition Database 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
 We comply with the HONcode standard
for trustworthy health information: verify here .
	</body>
</document>
