<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005346" url="http://azcuisine.net/archives/category/condiment" time="2012-07-12-21:53" support="16" score="0.05203393964267724" bingtitle="Cuisine Around the World » condiment" webtitle="Cuisine Around the Worldcondiment">
			<query id="000010" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001478" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="001257" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001351" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000007" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000597" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>... the crownius region of the chicken, the fast food restaurant has ... the Kung Pao if I were ever at a loss for condiments ... With a name like that, it could deliver any number ...</description>
	<body>
		Cuisine Around the World 
 
 Home About Contact Us Declaimer Privacy 
 

 05 Jun 
 &gt;Jif Chocolate Hazelnut and Mocha Cappuccino Hazelnut Spread 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 7 , chocolate , condiment , dessert , snack 
&gt;Pro tip: You can measure a company’s branding success in two easy steps. I call this test the NOCRUS exam, or the Nutella or Coconut Runoff Usage Simulation. It can be implemented by asking this question: does your product successfully utilize either Nutella-based, i.e., chocolate and hazelnut, or coconut-water/coconut inspired flavoring? If so, it’s likely that it’ll catch on like hotcakes and iPods. If not, it’ll be as successful as hotcake-flavored iPods. Terrible idea. Syrup everywhere. My point is, these two components are the new Jonas Bieber Anistons of the food world and companies everywhere are vying to get in on the action. 
In Jif’s case, we have two new heavy hitters in the spread market, Chocolate and Mocha Cappuccino hazelnut-based spread. Both flavors are smooth and creamy, almost pudding-like and thick in texture. Of the two, the chocolate hazelnut is definitely the more classic example. It’s less muted in scent than Nutella (I had a jar on hand- strictly for comparative purposes) and has a stronger, more cocoa and vanilla-forward flavor.  
 
 As much as it pains me to say it, having been practically weaned on Nutella as an infant, this is superior. It lacks the gummy elasticity of the former, and offers a bolder, less saccharine flavor. 
 The mocha cappuccino has some issues. Not quite to the level of product abomination parent issues, but just mild stuff. It just wants to talk. Conceptually, it seems like it would work. It follows a correct conditional proof. A, hazelnut, and B, chocolate, go together. B, chocolate, and C, coffee, also go together very well. So it logically follows that A, hazelnut, and C, coffee, go together. Which they do. But unfortunately, you can’t eat logic, and that’s why A, B, and C, together, taste pretty strange. The coffee is the dominant flavor, but hazelnut follows closely behind, unfortunately more reminiscent of coffee flavoring than the plain chocolate flavor. It has a similarly beguiling texture, but falls short of expectations and leaves a bitter taste in your mouth. Not unlike formal logic.
 
Overall, though, the branding is successful and catchy enough that I could definitely see the original flavor catching on. With Nutella’s various lawsuits and health finger-pointing, as well as its notorious reputation as an ex-pen-seeeef European brand, this might just be the campaign to sway America to the Jif side. And based on the quality and flavor of these products, it’s not a bad side to be on. Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 02 Jun 
 &gt;Pig of the Month Key West in a Bottle Citrus Grilling Sauce 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 10 , condiment , hot , sauce 
&gt; People go on quests for the perfect type of food all the time. America’s best burger, the most extravagant red velvet cupcakes Venus has to offer, the types of things that reality television shows and type 2 diabetes are made of. I have some staples that I find always need improvement, but when it comes to barbecue sauce, I’m a closeted settler. I find that in most cases, it’s so slanted toward the mediocre that finding a sauce that doesn’t send me into a Tazmanian devil-esque frenzy makes my pants tent. 
 I thought it was crazy to want more out of barbecue sauce, and had been perfectly happy with either ignoring it or using it as an industrial-strength paste for my wallpaper, until I found this. Buyer’s Best Friend sent this summery sauce over by Pig of the Month. Initially, I looked at it and could almost taste the sugar and molasses-heavy flavors through the glass, like a useless sixth sense. However, since my father was coming by, we decided to throw caution to the grill and use it as a marinade and glaze for chicken, and boy, are we glad we did that. 
Pig of the Month specializes in cutting out the middleman and sending dismembered animal parts right to your door, fresh for consumption and ritual sacrifice over fire pits. In addition to controlling the meat racket, they also sell bottles of their homemade sauces. We tried the Key West Citrus sauce and it was divine. I think I’ve used this on no less than three dishes in the last two days. Dumplings. An omlet sandwich. Grilled chicken. Turkey burgers.
 
Holy cow. BB-who, now? This sauce is silky. This sauce is sweet, but nowhere near unctuous. It has a spicy, bold pepper kick. Exceptional really isn’t a strong enough word for this sauce. Stupendous? Finger lickin’good? Doesn’t hold a candle to how it really tastes. Instead, I’ll casually mention that by accident- I cannot stress that enough, a few drops of this made it onto a spoonful of peanut butter I was eating. And I kept eating it. And it was freaking awesome. That good enough for you? 
Point is, this has the best balance and fruitiness of any barbecue sauce I’ve had. It eschews the unwritten philosophy that meat needs copious amounts of sugar, salt, and bland spices to handle a six-hour ride in a smoker and instead, soaks a bright, clean set of fruit juices (grapefruit comes out especially well here) and bold cayenne and cumin into the meat. It’s both a wonderful marinade and glaze as well as a drizzled sauce. If you’ve tried any other sauces from Pig of the Month (or any of their delectable porky products) let us know how you like them! Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 25 Apr 
 Tabasco Buffalo Style Hot Sauce 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 8 , condiment , hot , sauce My life is flaming right now. And I don’t mean in a listening to Elton John more than usual, leather jacket wearing, pompadour sort of way , because that would imply that I hadn’t already been doing those things. Ahem. What I mean is that things are coming together all at once and the hours in the day just aren’t feeling long enough. Cooking, blogging, and overall enjoyment of life have been pushed aside for finals preparation and LSAT cramming, as well as the ensuing therapy that comes with both, and I’ve barely had time to eat a full meal on an honest-to-goodness table, as opposed to the pile of papers that typically serve as my plate, much less prepare one for Miss Love and I. Imagine my joy when the newest sauce from Tabasco came to the house today- Buffalo style, no less. Easy to use and easy to enjoy…or was it? I was initially skeptical, but then again, due to the aforementioned LSAT prep, I’ve been initially skeptical about everything I’ve been doing lately. Reading traffic signs. Watching television. Even a simple question from Miss Love about dinner will elicit a stern discussion about whether or not her suppressed premise includes not wanting to eat chicken for the sixth night in a row and determine if her argument to do so is structurally flawed.   So reading on a package that something is“Buffalo style”rather than“Buffalo”in name gets my brain racing. And calorie-free Buffalo to boot- now that’s something to tweet about. 
 Luckily, my fears were for naught. While I was initially put off by the scent , a combination of regular Tabasco and an underlying nose of spicy musk, as well as its ability to tattoo the skin with its signature orange brand, a sure sign that tells everyone you see that you’re well on your way to obesity and are proud of it, the flavor carefully mimicked buffalo wings without the usage of butter . Or witchcraft.
 It’s less spicy than Tabasco but spicy enough to leave a good tingle on the lips and tasted amazing with our homemade chicken patties. It’s also thicker than regular Tabasco, which makes it easy to toss wings or chicken pieces in and not have to worry about the sauce dripping off. It’s got a good texture and easily adheres. This will definitely be a key player in our dinner condiment lineup. Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 21 Mar 
 Burger King’s New Chicken Strips and Roasted Jalapeno BBQ and Kung Pao Sauces 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 5 , chicken , condiment , fast food , hot , sauce 
Now that the iconic fear-paralyzed face of the Burger King royalty is gone, who will usurp the noble throne? Built on ketchup slicks and nuggets seized from the crownius region of the chicken, the fast food restaurant has decreed a complete overhaul of its restaurants. My local BK, not a king, but not yet a lounge, has been partially remodeled but is stuck in a strange dead zone where the only recognizable theme is the leftover St. Patrick’s Day decorations from last week. 
 Aside from the new menu cards, BK has introduced a few new menu items, expanding to the cafe-style foods and coffee beverages to garner business from some of their obvious competition from Ronald the Court Jester. I guess if they play their cards right and assume that the law of gravity holds, it would be the most obvious and closest place for me to go for a mediocre frappe. But only if my Rascal stopped working and I had to…walk. Along with these, they’ve introduced a new chicken strip to go along with their new chicken tenders, released around this time next year. T’wasn’t the poultry that intrigued me, but rather, the debut of their two newest sauces, Kung Pao and Roasted Jalapeno BBQ , that carried me into my local establishment on this, the day of the newly released chicken strip.
 Touting the strips in both a 3 and a 5 pack for $3.29 and $4.49, respectively, it works out to just over a dollar a strip if you’re going for the small pack . Not the most economical choice unless you’re just really, really into chicken strips. The strips are billed as being marinated and breaded in a seasoned coating, but eaten plain, salty, mediocre chicken was the only noticeable flavor . The breading was crisp, but lacked the crunchiness its counterparts have in abundance and clung closely to the chicken like a too-tight tube top on a girl making a duck face on Facebook. It was surprisingly devoid of oil, but left a very salty, onion-heavy aftertaste and had a bone-dry chewiness more appropriate on jerky than chicken . Only one of the strips was longer than a ballpoint pen and all were tough in texture. Hideously underwhelming, and they made me glad I’d anticipated the worst and bought a cheeseburger to eat instead.
 I figured the sauces would be my saving grace for these strips, and let’s face it, they were really just a vehicle for them anyhow. Boasted as being“totally sweet”by my server, the new sauces don’t try to mimic anything I’ve seen from the competition. They blaze their own trail. The roasted jalapeno barbecue suffered from a lack of two things- enthusiasm and proper nomenclature. Assuming that titles as well as ingredients are listed in their order of amount from largest to smallest, I came into this carrying the expectation that“roasted jalapeno barbecue”would be peppers first and barbecue second. Not a chance, unfortunately. It was gummy and sweet when sampled on a spoon, with a heavy brown sugar assault and the clean, lingering bite of jalapeno peppers after. But eaten with the chicken strips or spread on a little bite of burger, the spiciness drowned in the rich ingredients that outnumbered it, leaving a generically sweet flavor with a touch of cayenne , like Sweet Baby Ray’s. I would have loved if there had been chunks of fresh pepper in this or even pickled rings.
 The Kung Pao sauce, on the other hand, was perfectly executed and tasted like delicious, cheap Chinese takeout sauce with a more pronounced set of flavors. Hell, this even encompassed some of the cheaper takeout chicken sauces, at least around here. Wafting sharp, sweet pickled ginger aromas from the moment I opened the packet, I knew this would be a great addition to the sauce line. I’ll give it this- it completely blows McDonald’s Sweet Chili out of the water. This sauce had large pieces of ginger, garlic, and crushed red pepper flakes and brought an umami-laden depth to the traditional flavor profile of sweet and sour with an aggressive, lingering spice. Slightly tinny at first, but nothing repulsive. This was the only sauce we went back for seconds on.
 I’m not typically crazy about fast food chicken as I’ve started making my own nuggets at home, but the new sauces are unique enough that I’d definitely consider getting the Kung Pao if I were ever at a loss for condiments around the house . Not that that will ever happen, but it’s a pleasant deviation from the standard ketchup‘n’mustard set. 
 Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 07 Feb 
 Hot Squeeze Sweet Heat Chipotle Sauce 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 4 , condiment , hot , sauce 
Like Junk Food Guy , I need to start unsubscribing from junk email. It’s really wreaking havoc on my dopamine receptors . I’ll open my iPod in ecstasy and see that I have seven new emails- ooh! Is it a book offer? A modeling contract? Does someone finally want to buy my third kidney off of craigslist? Oh, wait, nope, it’s a desperate promotional coupon for everything percent off from Radio Shack, when I was gullible enough to not give the haggard employee a fake email address. And a monthly newsletter from Krystal, the closest location a cool 643 miles away, or a now defunct film festival whose creepy emails contain no body, just a sad title.
 Lately the biggest offender has been Hot Squeeze, the hot sauce/slather that I might have checked out on Amazon in mid-2006, my sixteen year old self giggling mindlessly at the euphemistic name before clicking off to Neopets and AIM. For whatever reason, I ended up on the mailing list for this sauce and since then have received no less than three emails a month in spam-like proportions, with titles ranging from the downright non sequitur, like“how about a Hot Squeeze of summer”to subjects that would make Howard Stern blush. Today, I decided to buck up and try the damned sauce, if only to satisfy my boundless curiosity and unsubscribe from that mailing list once and for all.
 It’s an aromatic hybrid between a chipotle barbecue marinade and a smoky hot sauce. Loaded with red pepper flakes and boasting an almost malted scent from all the sugars, it seemed like it would go well with the raspberry jalapeno shredded chicken I’d made earlier that day. Eaten plain, it’s a bit overwhelming. It has an intensely umami-laden nose and flavor, with a base Worcestershire edge and a mild spiciness. Unfortunately, the“sweet”in sweet heat was a lie. It wasn’t sweet at all, but it did paired well with our nachos, lending a smoky flavor to the mild cheese and enhancing the fruit in the chicken.
 However, if sauces were woman, this would be the quintessential fat girl who hangs out with all the other attractive ladies in the refrigerator and makes them look gourmet in comparison. Somehow, that analogy serves to make me look even creepier. While I love a full-bodied sauce with a sassy, bold flavor, the texture of this is an absolute trainwreck. It’s chunky and viscous, with a property similar to mucous in that regardless of how you poured it, it seemed to want to shrink back to its original shape and adhere stickily to the chip or bowl. Très clingy. It left sticky, gummy trails of its sauce wherever we put it. The texture was a real turn-off for me. It’s a sauce that would be absolutely embarrassing to serve to guests, as it’s impossible to dip food in without having your dish turn into an interactive Sarlacc pit. 
 Hot Squeeze says it has hundreds of uses, but I believe that to be an insufficient claim as its limiting flavor profile confines it to only neutral and bland selections. While the flavor was excellent, I can’t see any other practical applications for it outside of using it as a cooking sauce as its stickiness would ruin everything else. 
 Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 17 Oct 
 Frontera Limited Edition Chipotle Pumpkin Salsa 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 9 , condiment , dip , hot , lunch , sauce 
As I’ve mentioned, I’m moderately obsessed with the chill of autumn. Now that it’s getting to be time for gloves and huddling, though, I’m finding out, as I do every year, that I’m only obsessed with the idea of looking moody and lost in thought in the chill of autumn. After that one perfect profile picture is snapped, I’m cursing and looking for the nearest shower to warm up in. I needed a snack tonight and found myself longing for the salsa and chip appetizer generally accompanying warm, summer nights out in the yard. And then I remembered this crazy salsa we had in the back of the fridge. I grabbed this at a time, mid-July, at the Fancy Food Show when eating it seemed a little blasphemous with all the green and red salsas lying around. But I’m good enough at planning ahead that when I see freaking pumpkin chipotle salsa, I know that come October, I’m going to be nomming for eight because it’s so good. And this was a Rick Bayless creation that seamlessly bridges the gap between summer and fall , a man whose takes on Mexican have been salivated over many an afternoon in Whole Foods. I met chef Bayless, strongarmed a jar of this, and waited four months to write about it. That’s dedication. You’ll notice this jar is propped up like a taxidermied Anne Geddes baby. I don’t give a crap. Inside that jar, which, mind you, is clearly the more boss of seasonal flavors- eff you, heirloom tomato, is a smoky, sweet combination of chunks of peppers, tomatoes, and pumpkins bathed in a perfectly executed chipotle sauce. Chipotle is incredibly overrated, but when paired well, it’s transcendental. And this is paired very, very well. It’s not so much a smoky flavor as it is charred, with bits of blackened pepper and tomato skin floating around in the sauce, giving it a deep, rich flavor and an intensely smoked bite. At first, there’s no heat, and I didn’t expect there to be with all of the pumpkin spices, like nutmeg, cinnamon, and brown sugar, giving it a rounded, sweet potato-like flavor , but after a few bites, a lingering heat emerged and persisted for quite some time. Like some of the other pumpkin products I’ve sampled, this manifested its fall colors in the spices it used rather than the ingredients, despite there being actual pumpkin in this . I’ve come to realize that that’s a boon rather than a bust, because the texture of pumpkin could upset the balance of a salsa with its heavy, wet mouthfeel and is pretty flavorless on its own. Though admittedly, a little thickness couldn’t hurt. This separates very easily, even after thoroughly shaking in the jar . If watery salsa annoys you, these are not the droids you’re looking for. With such an emphasis on utilizing pumpkin, this had the thin consistency of a heavily tomatillo based salsa, which it was. It wasn’t very enhanced by the gourd at all. It’s worth noting, however, that Bayless not only used pumpkin in his salsa, a feat unto itself, but used a special Mexican variety of pumpkin called the calabaza. It’s part melon, part gourd. You know it as the plant that produces the popular squash blossom. It’s still a pumpkin. Don’t say the guy didn’t try. The only element this is missing is the crunch of toasted pepitas on top, an easy hack that will turn this into the perfect fall appetizer. I can’t wait to try this as a heated sauce over pasta or on top of pulled chicken tacos. 
 
 Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 01 Mar 
 A. Fieschi Mostarda di Cremona 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 9 , condiment , cooking , fruit , pizza 
Where did all the apothecaries go? As I write this I feel like I’m giving the weltschmerz laced air of a woman who has seen it all and bought the t-shirt. Granted, I have never seen an apothecary, but I would trade the sterile, monochromatic blandness of Walgreen’s Pharmacy for those musty coiffers. The closest thing I’ve found lies in foreign groceries, the kinds in small cities where dust comes free with every purchase and meat comes in alive and often leaves alive as well. This particular treat resembles those murky jars with mysterious contents and comes from First Tracks as an intriguing gift. With a little research, we found that mostarda di Cremona is a condiment from Northern Italy consisting of preserved fruits in a mustard powder sauce. Despite looking a lot like alien eggs, it’s quite a unique regional product. It’s one of those things that has been around for centuries, unbeknownst to most of the American population. I had not heard of this prior to receiving it, making it that much more intriguing. First Tracks advised us to consume the little fruits with preserved Italian meat, like proscuitto, but before that, we had to perform an initial investigation. In other words, I needed to touch that fruit. It’s not every day you get to pry tiny fruits out of a gel-filled jar. The fruits inside were mainly stone fruits- peaches, nectarines, pears, and such, but also included a tiny orange. The consistency was thicker than a standard canned fruit syrup and more like a corn syrup texture- just as sticky. It had a spicy, sweet scent. The strangest thing about it, though I suppose this was more disorientation strange than actually strange, was that it tasted exactly like mustard, though with this thick, syrupy mouthfeel. Definitely unique.
 The little fruits inside were surprisingly firm with mushiness only from the baby pear. When we cut into them, they harbored a crystalline, jellied texture reminding me of solidified polymers and tasted like the sauce in varying degrees. Out of all the fruits, the orange worked best with the spicy gel, the rind infused with a bitter, sweet flavor and a citrusy zing from the oils. I’d definitely try chopping this up in sesame noodles or on top of some roasted chicken. It was the kind of flavor that really seems to impart its sensations on other foods. We wanted to try these in a traditional application, so for dinner tonight we made a prosciutto and fresh mozzarella pizza with a few sliced fruits on top. Keepitcoming snacked on a few slices with some pieces of prosciutto as an antipasto. To drink, we took the cava and basil cocktail from The Roost and tweaked it to our liking. The end result was casual, and yet decadently sophisticated, something I could see myself eating out of the fridge as a snack or serving as a light summer lunch to friends. We extracted the little gems and sliced them into translucent wedges on top of the pie. Though we tried to wash some of the syrup off for fear of burning, a good deal of it seeped through the pizza crust and caramelized into a sticky area underneath. However, this was no problem- it transformed an unseasoned crust into a delicious, savory sweet treat! It did make it a bit difficult to handle. The flavor of the fruits really changed during the cooking process. The orange still remained the most intense and sauce-infused, but the peaches were gelatinous and juicy. The overall flavor was a charred, meaty, juicy spiciness, like pineapple ham or citrus marinated meat. On top of the pizza with crispy mozzarella, it was absolutely heavenly. A natural combination- meat, fruit, and cheese, just seemed to be bumped up another level as it was paired with peppery, piquant flavors. The heating element seems to be tricky- heating it too much dilutes the full spectrum of flavors. If I hadn’t already loved such a combination, this would have rendered me into a convert for sure. I was surprised at how versatile a condiment it was. I think my next step would be to incorporate this into a dessert, perhaps as a key ingredient in an individual crisp or mixed in with some ice cream. It really defied its hyper-specific ingredients, creating a delightful and universal set of flavors for all seasons. 
 Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 12 Feb 
 SPICY WEEK PART 5: Spicy Ketchups 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 5 , 6 , 7 , 8 , 9 , condiment , hot , sauce , spicy 
Keepitcoming and I just returned from a little vacation, so that explains for the lag in posts. But never fear, Spicy Week will persevere! Before we left, we made a batch of fries for dinner and tested out our five spicy ketchup contenders.
 Surprisingly, none of the national brand ketchup manufacturers, like Heinz and Hunt, opt to sell a commercially viable spicy ketchup. The closest I could find to a widely recognized brand was the UK subsidiary of Heinz, which makes a “twisted”ketchup with both mild and spicy chilies, but since that wasn’t easy to procure, I turned to the smaller brands. To test our ketchups on, we made a mild, baked fry with a flavor that balanced out the ketchups. We chose a blue and white cornmeal crusted french fry, and they turned out to be quite tasty and served as a good base for our testing.
 Our first ketchup was a jalapeno ketchup from Spice It Up. It smelled good and was very thick, but had a bland, salty flavor with a small heat at the start and little depth. It didn’t compliment nor enhance the fries and toned down to a plain ketchup flavor by the end of the bite. The heat gradually grew, but the seasoning stayed the same, and in the end, it just tasted a little too plain.
Heat- 2
Flavor- 1
Appearance- 2
Label- 1
OVERALL- 6 We then moved on to a ketchup from Intensity Academy. With a name like that, it could deliver any number of things. To our surprise, the ketchup we tried didn’t live up to its moniker. This was the chai chipotle‘chup, and it has to be consumed immediately upon pouring. We learned this the hard way, for as soon as we looked the other way, the ketchup separated. The flavor was nice, if a little mild, but didn’t really taste of chipotle or chai, and was pretty soupy.
Heat- 1
Flavor- 2
Appearance- 0
Label- 1
OVERALL- 4
 The next ketchup came in a different bottle from the others, and that was Big Paw ketchup. Strange name and a moderately strange ketchup. It was extremely difficult to extract this from the bottle. It was a very thick ketchup, but somehow had issues adhering to the french fries. I suspect this is from a high oil content that did not mix very well. The flavor was delicious, though, with a strong, smoky chipotle flavor and a bold fruitiness from the‘mato. Too bad the texture makes it impossible to dip with.
Heat- 3
Flavor- 3
Appearance- 0
Label- 1
OVERALL- 7 We were nearing the last of our test subjects. This next ketchup featured not hot peppers, but more of an Indian spice selection. Maya Kaimal’s ketchup informed us that this would be“a little sweet, a little spicy, and a little Indian.”It had a zesty bite of curry at the beginning of the taste, and a really nicely defined, sweet cumin flavor. Unfortunately, the lines defining“spice”and“spicy”seemed to have been slightly blurred. This was more of a spice-heavy sauce than a heat intensive one, but still delicious nonetheless.
Heat- 1
Flavor- 3
Appearance- 3
Label- 1
OVERALL- 8 The last ketchup of the night was Juan’s Fiesta Ketchup. This was a no-brainer as far as our favorite, because it was perfectly scoopable and smearable in its texture, with a distinctly peppery and distinctly tomatoey flavor within its overall composition. This was the ketchup we kept dipping in over and over after our testing and dredging up the final smears because it was so good. It was smoky, but not overbearing, and had a natural, sweet base. The burn was fantastic, because it was built up and then cooled down by the tomato. Really tasty and really well-crafted.
Heat- 2
Flavor- 3
Appearance- 3
Label- 1
OVERALL- 9

 TOP SPICY KETCHUPS 
 Juan’s Fiesta Ketchup (9) 
 Maya Kaimal’s Spicy Ketchup (8) 
 
 Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 11 Feb 
 SPICY WEEK PART 4: Spicy Mustards 
Posted by: Admin / Category: 10 , 5 , 6 , 7 , 8 , 9 , condiment , hot , spicy 
Day three. We’ve gotten past the tough stuff and are now sailing smoothly. I neglected to inform our participants that this would probably be the hardest category to do well in, as I consider myself a highly professional mustard connoisseur. But with seven contenders for the prize of best mustard, I found myself up against a team of seasoned and spicy surprises… Like last time, we judged on four categories, with three points for heat, three points for flavor, three points for appearance, and a point for a label,’cause that shit is for real. To accurately measure the saucy spiciness of the Mustard Carbohydrate Soakage Scale, we swapped out our wing hack, McNuggets, for something a little more traditional: soft pretzels, son.
 Our first mustard was another selection from Crooked Condiments, an ale-based mustard. It was smooth in its appearance, but had an acrid, grainy texture like lumpy gravy and a one-noted bitterness that overwhelmed the pretzel and somehow rendered it mushy. It didn’t taste like mustard or ale and didn’t have the heat we expected it to have, instead carrying more of an astringent sting. It didn’t really didn’t go well with the snack and left a bad aftertaste in our mouths.
Heat- 1
Flavor- 0
Appearance- 2
Label- 0
OVERALL- 3 The next mustard we tried was another condiment from Saucy Mama. As you know from our last tasting, Saucy Mama represented one of the top three condiments in the regular hot sauce category, so we were excited to see if their quality carried on in between sauces. This was a chipotle mayonnaise in a squeeze bottle, with the same clean label of the wing sauce. This had a nice texture and flavor, but for the first few dips, had a viscous feel that made it a little difficult to adhere to the pretzel. I had to employ a“scoop method,”one that I rarely use for its difficulty in execution and high tendency to ruin clothes. But the result was worth the risk. The mustard was smoky and creamy, with a nice textural irregularity and chunkiness to it.
Heat- 2
Flavor- 3
Appearance- 2
Label- 1
OVERALL- 8
 After that, we sampled a most unusual condiment. Here’s a riddle for you: What’s bright red, smells like peppers, but isn’t peppers? It’s Dave’s Gourmet Hurtin’Habanero Mustard, with slogans and flames and spice all up in this bitch. This dog’s bark was worse than its bite. Everything about this screamed pain and agony, but it was really a lot of smoke and mirrors. The heat burnt a little, but was pretty mild and clean, with very little aftertaste. The sauce was bright red and would probably make an outstanding topping for a fancy appetizer, but isn’t best for heat aficionados. It was more of a presentation-based condiment than one that relied on heat. Decent.
Heat- 1
Flavor- 2
Appearance- 2
Label- 2
OVERALL- 7 It would seem we’d entered the realm of zany and strangely colored mustards, because up after Dave’s was a cranberry mustard from Up the Creek. Like Dave’s, this was bright and sassy, with a nice pink tinge and an almost jammy texture, like a home-canned preserve. It had a sweet, tangy cranberry flavor and a nice salty balance, but lacked that zip that I so desire in a good mustard. It wasn’t spicy at all, and I found myself craving a little heat to go with the sauciness of the berries.
Heat- 0
Flavor- 3
Appearance- 3
Label- 0
OVERALL- 6 After the last few, I was craving something with a decent heat to it, so we turned to the Food and Wine jalapeno mustard aioli. This reminded me of the Saucy Mama in its appearance, but had a creamier, more uniform texture and milder flavor. It must have been the added cream in the aioli, but this just didn’t deliver the spice I wanted it to, despite boasting a sweet tanginess.
Heat- 0
Flavor- 2
Appearance- 2
Label- 1
OVERALL- 5 We then came to another repeat offender, a different selection from Dr. Gonzo’s. This time, it was their Drunk Stunt mustard. From the moment we opened the jar, we knew this was going to be special. The mustard was not blended, far from it- it was a seedy study in autumnal colors, held together by minimal liquid, and stuck to the spoon as we scooped it onto the pretzel. From the first bite, it was clear that this was no ordinary mustard. It was dizzyingly smoky and flavorful, with a bite and spice that kept growing. At the end, the smoked heat, a palatable and savory burn, lingered for about a minute. I feel like I could put this on anything and it would make it instantly gourmet. It was like the golden touch of mustard. The depth of the flavors kept growing with each sampling, each new thing it was paired with. It was perfect, and I will savor my small jar as though I would a fine wine.
Heat- 3
Flavor- 3
Appearance- 3
Label- 1
OVERALL- 10 Following that was tough, but we remembered that Pain is Good gave Dr. Gonzo’s a run for their money in the regular sauce round and swept the death category, so that was our last mustard. This was less of a mustard and more of a pourable sauce, so it might be less optimal for sandwiches and better as a dipping sauce. As soon as we opened the bottle, we noticed how smoky this was, on par with Dr. Gonzo’s. While it lacked a distinctly mustardy texture, it had the tang to make up for it and a powerful, clean burn. Definitely jalapenos.
Heat- 3
Flavor- 2
Appearance- 2
Label- 1
OVERALL- 8

TOP THREE
Dr. Gonzo’s Drunk Stunt Mustard (10)
Pain is Good Jalapeno Mustard Sauce (8)
Saucy Mama Chipotle Mustard (8)

The top three are neck and neck! Who will win the prestigious award of Best of Spicy Week? Stay tuned, hotheads…
 Comments (0)  /  Add Comment 
Social Bookmarking
 
Advertisements
 
Streaming Video
 
Pages

 About Contact Us Declaimer Privacy 
 
Categories

 0 1 10 2 215 Festival 3 3 musketeers 4 5 6 7 8 9 A- Acapulco aero Afghan almond altoids amaretti American annie&apos;s anniversary Anthony Bourdain apollo appetizer apple Argentinian Asheville asian Asian fusion Asian market Austin australian austrian avocado Avondale azuki B+ baba ganoush bacon bagel baked beans bakery baking banana banana pudding banh mi bar barbecue basil bay leaf beach beer beet beets belgian belgian beer Belize Bella Vista berry beverage bibimbap biscuit bissinger black currant black eyed peas black sesame seed black tea blackberry bloggers blogiversary blueberry BoBerry Bojangles&apos; Bon Appetit booze Boston cream bourbon Bowling bread breakfast british brownie brownies brunch bubble yum bun burger Burmese burrito butter byob C+ cabbage Cabo cachet cadbury cafe cafeteria caffeine cake CakeKraft calpis camille bloch camping canadian candy candyfreak cane syrup canning caper caplico cappucino caramel caramel corn cardamom Caribbean carrot carrots casali cashew casserole castella catering Center City Chain challah champagne charleston Cheddar cheese cheese steak cheesecake cheesesteak cheetos cherries cherry Chester County chestnut Chick-O-Stick chicken chili chilis Chinatown Chinese chipolline chips chocolate chocolate week chocolife chocolove choxie Christmas chuao chutney Cincinnati cinnamon cinnamon roll claytonia coconut coconut milk coffee coke cola coleslaw collards collon Columbia comic condiment Cook-Off cookbook cookie cookie dough cookies cooking cooking class Cooks Illustrated coriander corn cornbread Corpus Christi cotton candy country ma&apos;am couscous cracker cranberry cream puff cream soda Crepe crumpet crunky CSA Cuban cupcake curry custard D D.C. Dad dagoba dairy damian allsop dare dark chocolate dars DC Delaware deli dessert desserts diet diner dinner dip divine dolfin donut doritos dosa doughnut drink earl grey eclipse egg eggplant Egyptian English Exton extra F Facebook Fairmount/Art Museum falafel Family farmer&apos;s market fast food fat free faux turkey ferrero festival fifty shades fig Filipino Firefly Fish Fishtown flax seed fondue food blogger food cart food swap food truck Franklin Square French fried fries frito-lay frosting frozen frozen yogurt fruit fruit punch fruitcake fudge fujiya galaxy gandour garage sale gardening gastropub gazpacho gel gelato german Germantown ghirardelli gimbals gin ginger giveaway glico gluten-free goat cheese gobstoppers godiva gourd Graduate Hospital gran soleil granita granola grape grapefruit grapes Grays Ferry Greek green Blacks green tea greens grilling gross week guava gum gummy hachez hageland halloumi hard candy haribo harissa paste hazelnut Headhouse Square herbs hershey hi-chew hoagie honey hoppin&apos;john hot hot dog houjicha hubba bubba hummus ice breakers ice cream ikea Indian Indonesian interviews ishiya Italian Italian Market iwatsuka jam Jamaican Japanese jello jelly jelly beans Jerusalem artichoke jicama jolly rancher juice juicy fruit just born kabaya kale kanro Kansas kasugai keepitcoming&apos;s cocktails Kennett Square Kensington key lime kinako kinder kinoko no yama kirin kitchen kitchen gadget kitkat kitty kiwi koala&apos;s march koeda kokutou Kool-Aid Korean kosher kugel laffy taffy lake champlain latin lavender lawsuit lebanese Lee Brothers lemon lemonade lentil libel licorice lime lindt lion log cabin Longwood LOOK lotte low fat lunch mac and cheese macadamia madecasse magic spice Malaysian mamba manayunk mango map maple mariebelle market Market East marmalade mars marshmallow marzipan matcha matzo mayonnaise meal delivery meat meatball Mediterranean meetup meiji melon melonpan meltyblend meltykiss membrillo mentos Menu for Hope metromint Mexican Mexico Mexico City Middle Eastern Midtown Village mike and ike milk milk tea mint miracle fruit mircle fruit mobaccho mochi mojito molasses Momofuku morinaga mountain dew muffin mulberry mushroom nabisco Native American nerds nestle New Castle New Jersey New Year&apos;s New York Newark Newbold news newtree nibs niederegger nikkou No Reservations nobel non-review noodle norman love North Carolina Northern Liberties nostalgia week nougat nutmeg nutritional yeast nuts NYC okra old city olive oil omelette onion oral fixation orange orbit oreo organic outdoor dining pad thai paleta Pan Asian panko papaya parmesan passion fruit Passover Passyunk Ave. Passyunk Square pastry peach peanut butter peanuts pear pecan Penn&apos;s Landing Pennsport Pennsylvania pepper peppercorn peppermint peppers pepsico personal chef Peruvian pesto petit four pheasant Philadelhia philadelphia Philippine pho photos pickle pie Piggly Wiggly pilsbury pimento pimento cheese pina colada pineapple Piroshki pistachio pizza pocky Point Breeze pomegranate popcorn popsicles port port-salut Portland portugal Portuguese pot pie potato pretz Pretzel pretzels pucca puccho pudding puff pastry pumpkin pupurun pure Queen Village quince raisin ramune rant raspberry raw razzles Reading Terminal Market recipe recipe site recipe. lemon red velvet reese&apos;s relish restaurant restaurant review rhubarb Ribs rice risotto Rittenhouse ritter sport roast rolls rose rosemary rum saffron salad salsa salt sandwich sandwiches sanko sauce sausage Savannah schakolad scottish scrapple Seattle seattle chocolates seaweed seeds seitan senbei shake shameless foodette shiitake shikwasa Shore side signs skittles slaw smarties smoothie snack snackdown snacks Society Hill soda soil Sonic sorbetto sorghum soup sour sour patch South Carolina South Philly South Street Southern soy soy sauce Spanish spearmint spice spicy spinach squash St. Martin starburst stew storck strawberry street food streusel stride sukiyaki summer summer pudding sunkist superstar sushi swap sweet potato sweet tarts sweet tea swiss Synsepalum dulcificum syrup tacos taffy tahini takenoko no sato tamarind tangerine tapas tart Tastebook tasting menu tea tempeh Texas Thai Thanksgiving The New York Times The Perfect Scoop thorntons tic tac tiramisu tirol tivon toffee tofu tohato tomato tomatoes too haute cowgirls too tarts tootsie roll toppo Tortilla tour Trader Joe&apos;s trident Trolley Square tropical truffle Turkish twix U.K. udon uha ume Uncategorized University City urban gardening vacation vanilla vegan vegan treats vegetarian Venezuelan Vietnamese vinegar vintage vinyard vitamin vitamingum vodka vosges vrapple wafer waffle Wahington Square West walkers walnut wasabi Washington Avenue Washington Square Washington Square West watermelon weevil West Chester wheat berries white chocolate Whole Foods wilmington wine wings wintergreen wonka wrigley yan yan yellow layer yogurt yuki no yado Zingerman&apos;s 
 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 
 
Blog Roll

 Documentation Plugins Suggest Ideas Support Forum Themes WordPress Blog WordPress Planet 
 
Advertisements
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 &gt;Zotter Mitzi Blue Hemp Plantation Bar &gt;Bissinger’s Porcini Mushroom Truffles &gt;Justin’s Nut Butter Peanut Candy Bar &gt;SNACKDOWN: Chocolove Pretzel in Milk Chocolate vs. Zoe’s Pretzel Bar &gt;Chuao Ravishing Rocky Road Bar 
 
Recent Comments


 
Archives

 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 
 
Categories

 0 1 10 2 215 Festival 3 3 musketeers 4 5 6 7 8 9 A- Acapulco aero Afghan almond altoids amaretti American annie&apos;s anniversary Anthony Bourdain apollo appetizer apple Argentinian Asheville asian Asian fusion Asian market Austin australian austrian avocado Avondale azuki B+ baba ganoush bacon bagel baked beans bakery baking banana banana pudding banh mi bar barbecue basil bay leaf beach beer beet beets belgian belgian beer Belize Bella Vista berry beverage bibimbap biscuit bissinger black currant black eyed peas black sesame seed black tea blackberry bloggers blogiversary blueberry BoBerry Bojangles&apos; Bon Appetit booze Boston cream bourbon Bowling bread breakfast british brownie brownies brunch bubble yum bun burger Burmese burrito butter byob C+ cabbage Cabo cachet cadbury cafe cafeteria caffeine cake CakeKraft calpis camille bloch camping canadian candy candyfreak cane syrup canning caper caplico cappucino caramel caramel corn cardamom Caribbean carrot carrots casali cashew casserole castella catering Center City Chain challah champagne charleston Cheddar cheese cheese steak cheesecake cheesesteak cheetos cherries cherry Chester County chestnut Chick-O-Stick chicken chili chilis Chinatown Chinese chipolline chips chocolate chocolate week chocolife chocolove choxie Christmas chuao chutney Cincinnati cinnamon cinnamon roll claytonia coconut coconut milk coffee coke cola coleslaw collards collon Columbia comic condiment Cook-Off cookbook cookie cookie dough cookies cooking cooking class Cooks Illustrated coriander corn cornbread Corpus Christi cotton candy country ma&apos;am couscous cracker cranberry cream puff cream soda Crepe crumpet crunky CSA Cuban cupcake curry custard D D.C. Dad dagoba dairy damian allsop dare dark chocolate dars DC Delaware deli dessert desserts diet diner dinner dip divine dolfin donut doritos dosa doughnut drink earl grey eclipse egg eggplant Egyptian English Exton extra F Facebook Fairmount/Art Museum falafel Family farmer&apos;s market fast food fat free faux turkey ferrero festival fifty shades fig Filipino Firefly Fish Fishtown flax seed fondue food blogger food cart food swap food truck Franklin Square French fried fries frito-lay frosting frozen frozen yogurt fruit fruit punch fruitcake fudge fujiya galaxy gandour garage sale gardening gastropub gazpacho gel gelato german Germantown ghirardelli gimbals gin ginger giveaway glico gluten-free goat cheese gobstoppers godiva gourd Graduate Hospital gran soleil granita granola grape grapefruit grapes Grays Ferry Greek green Blacks green tea greens grilling gross week guava gum gummy hachez hageland halloumi hard candy haribo harissa paste hazelnut Headhouse Square herbs hershey hi-chew hoagie honey hoppin&apos;john hot hot dog houjicha hubba bubba hummus ice breakers ice cream ikea Indian Indonesian interviews ishiya Italian Italian Market iwatsuka jam Jamaican Japanese jello jelly jelly beans Jerusalem artichoke jicama jolly rancher juice juicy fruit just born kabaya kale kanro Kansas kasugai keepitcoming&apos;s cocktails Kennett Square Kensington key lime kinako kinder kinoko no yama kirin kitchen kitchen gadget kitkat kitty kiwi koala&apos;s march koeda kokutou Kool-Aid Korean kosher kugel laffy taffy lake champlain latin lavender lawsuit lebanese Lee Brothers lemon lemonade lentil libel licorice lime lindt lion log cabin Longwood LOOK lotte low fat lunch mac and cheese macadamia madecasse magic spice Malaysian mamba manayunk mango map maple mariebelle market Market East marmalade mars marshmallow marzipan matcha matzo mayonnaise meal delivery meat meatball Mediterranean meetup meiji melon melonpan meltyblend meltykiss membrillo mentos Menu for Hope metromint Mexican Mexico Mexico City Middle Eastern Midtown Village mike and ike milk milk tea mint miracle fruit mircle fruit mobaccho mochi mojito molasses Momofuku morinaga mountain dew muffin mulberry mushroom nabisco Native American nerds nestle New Castle New Jersey New Year&apos;s New York Newark Newbold news newtree nibs niederegger nikkou No Reservations nobel non-review noodle norman love North Carolina Northern Liberties nostalgia week nougat nutmeg nutritional yeast nuts NYC okra old city olive oil omelette onion oral fixation orange orbit oreo organic outdoor dining pad thai paleta Pan Asian panko papaya parmesan passion fruit Passover Passyunk Ave. Passyunk Square pastry peach peanut butter peanuts pear pecan Penn&apos;s Landing Pennsport Pennsylvania pepper peppercorn peppermint peppers pepsico personal chef Peruvian pesto petit four pheasant Philadelhia philadelphia Philippine pho photos pickle pie Piggly Wiggly pilsbury pimento pimento cheese pina colada pineapple Piroshki pistachio pizza pocky Point Breeze pomegranate popcorn popsicles port port-salut Portland portugal Portuguese pot pie potato pretz Pretzel pretzels pucca puccho pudding puff pastry pumpkin pupurun pure Queen Village quince raisin ramune rant raspberry raw razzles Reading Terminal Market recipe recipe site recipe. lemon red velvet reese&apos;s relish restaurant restaurant review rhubarb Ribs rice risotto Rittenhouse ritter sport roast rolls rose rosemary rum saffron salad salsa salt sandwich sandwiches sanko sauce sausage Savannah schakolad scottish scrapple Seattle seattle chocolates seaweed seeds seitan senbei shake shameless foodette shiitake shikwasa Shore side signs skittles slaw smarties smoothie snack snackdown snacks Society Hill soda soil Sonic sorbetto sorghum soup sour sour patch South Carolina South Philly South Street Southern soy soy sauce Spanish spearmint spice spicy spinach squash St. Martin starburst stew storck strawberry street food streusel stride sukiyaki summer summer pudding sunkist superstar sushi swap sweet potato sweet tarts sweet tea swiss Synsepalum dulcificum syrup tacos taffy tahini takenoko no sato tamarind tangerine tapas tart Tastebook tasting menu tea tempeh Texas Thai Thanksgiving The New York Times The Perfect Scoop thorntons tic tac tiramisu tirol tivon toffee tofu tohato tomato tomatoes too haute cowgirls too tarts tootsie roll toppo Tortilla tour Trader Joe&apos;s trident Trolley Square tropical truffle Turkish twix U.K. udon uha ume Uncategorized University City urban gardening vacation vanilla vegan vegan treats vegetarian Venezuelan Vietnamese vinegar vintage vinyard vitamin vitamingum vodka vosges vrapple wafer waffle Wahington Square West walkers walnut wasabi Washington Avenue Washington Square Washington Square West watermelon weevil West Chester wheat berries white chocolate Whole Foods wilmington wine wings wintergreen wonka wrigley yan yan yellow layer yogurt yuki no yado Zingerman&apos;s 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
Recent Articles

 &gt;Zotter Mitzi Blue Hemp Plantation Bar &gt;Bissinger’s Porcini Mushroom Truffles &gt;Justin’s Nut Butter Peanut Candy Bar &gt;SNACKDOWN: Chocolove Pretzel in Milk Chocolate vs. Zoe’s Pretzel Bar 
 
Recent Comments


 
Theme Credits

Designed by: Audi 

 Acai 
 Logo Ontwerp 
 Folder Ontwerp 
 (c)Copyrighted Cuisine Around the World Theme, All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
