<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005219" url="http://chelles.hubpages.com/hub/Mountain-Dew-Addiction" time="2012-07-12-21:45" support="3" score="0.0013955560381702485" bingtitle="Mountain Dew Addiction - Chelles on HubPages" webtitle="Mountain Dew Addiction">
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>I didn&apos;t drink coffee so Dew was my morning beverage. I would choose a fast food restaurant simply because they offered Dew to drink. I&apos;ve given it up a couple times ...</description>
	<body>
		HubPages 
 explore 
 topics hubs answers forums 
 sign in join now 
 flag 
 Explore  » Health (127,635) » Nutrition (6,863) » Nutritional Advice and Tips (1,175) 
 by Chelles 
33 Followers 
Mountain Dew Addiction
 
Is Mountain Dew Addictive?
 
For years I was a Mountain Dew Addict. I&apos;m not sure how it happened, but I found myself easily drinking a six pack of 16 ounce bottles every single day. Most people crave coffee in the morning - for me it was good old Mountain Dew!

Many people do not think that Mountain Dew is addictive, and it certainly does not have any disclaimers on the bottle that addiction may occur after prolonged or excessive consumption of this soft drink manufacturered by Pepsi.

Before I learned about sugar addiction I didn&apos;t ever think that I had a problem with Mountain Dew. Oh sure, I knew I craved it, got headaches without it, was tired or lethargic a lot of the time - but I never thought it had anything to do with Mountain Dew!

But after learning that for some people sugar can be an addiction, and that a 12 ounce can of Mountain Dew has 46 grams of sugar...well, it made sense to me pretty quick!

 
Signs&amp;Symptoms of Mountain Dew Addiction
 
The signs and symptoms of Mountain Dew Addiction may be difficult to recognize and many people may not realize just how much Mountain Dew they drink or that they are becoming dependent on it.

Here are some signs to help you recognize if you could be addicted to the soft drink:

1. Friends and family will automatically order it for you at restaurants, knowing it is your favorite thing and the only thing you drink.

2. You consume more than 24 ounces of the beverage each day

3. You wake up wanting a Mountain Dew.

4. You are VERY grumpy if you do not get it.

5. You seek other sweet foods if you do not get Mountain Dew, such as cookies, candy bars, doughnuts, etc.

6. You keep an emergency reserve stash in your car and in your home so you never run out of it.

7. People shake their heads and laugh when they see you with Mountain Dew because you always have it with you.

8.Despite the high caffeine content in Mountain Dew, you are often tired or groggy, which is a result from changes in your blood sugar.




 
The Effects of Mountain Dew Addiction
 
Drinking Mountain Dew for a prolonged time or excessively can lead to many potential health problems. Here are just a few to be concerned about:

1. Cavities : Nobody really enjoys going to the dentist, but the sugar content from the Mountain Dew can cause cavities and other teeth and gum problems, even with the best of dental hygeine practices.

2. Drowsiness : Drinking high sugar content beverages can cause a quick change in your blood sugar from your body releasing insulin to help stabalize it back to normal. Unfortunately, this can also cause you to become extremely drowsy or sluggish. Being drowsy can make it dangerous for you to operate a vehicle, as well as affect your ability to concentrate, focus, and perform.

3. Health Problems : Many people may develop health problems from drinking too much soda. Obesity and weight gain is one concern - another is the way the body deals with sugar and releasing insulin to control gluclose levels. Some of the other associated health problems: Urinary tract and kidney infections, acne, stomach cramping, irritable bowel syndrome, and others. Diabetes is also a major risk factor since the sugar content and can cause problems with insulin production and blood sugar levels.

4. Cost : It is very expensive to keep up a habit. A six pack of Mountain Dew retails for $4.49 and a 2 liter bottle is around $2.09 in some areas. If you are drinking this much every day, you could be spending $60-$140 a month on your favorite beverage. Meanwhile, water is free and much healthier for you.

5. Mood Swings : Going from lots of caffeine and sugar to no caffeine and sugar can cause crazy mood swings. You may find yourself being happy and excited one minute, screaming at someone the next. This is because your body is constantly at war with itself with too much sugar, not enough sugar.

6. Insomnia : While drowsiness is common, so is insomnia, since Mountain Dew does contain stimulant drugs. It is not unusual to find oneself awake at odd hours or have a hard time falling asleep.
 
Where to Get Help
 
If you believe you may have an addiction to Mountain Dew or other soft drink, the good news is that it is much easier to quit than marijuana, alcohol, cigarettes, and heroin. There are no dangerous withdrawal symptoms that anyone is aware of (though you may be awfully irritable for a few days!)

 Here are some things you can do to get help: 

1. Stop Buying It: This is difficult, we know. Don&apos;t walk down the aisle that has it in the grocery store. Do Not Under Any Circumstance go into a convenience store. In fact, if possible for a week try not to go anywhere that has it.

2. If You Do Buy It : If you find yourself unable to control yourself and the craving, buy the diet version instead. Everybody knows diet Mountain Dew tastes terrible in comparison to the real thing, so this is a good compromise to help you not want to drink it as much but while still weaning yourself from the sugar. If you make the switch to diet, it&apos;s not really a whole lot healthier for you, but at least it will help you avoid all the extra sugar. If you buy one, do not buy a second one! Only buy in small quantities - do NOT be tempted to buy a 6 pack or 24 pack case because it&apos;s on sale.

3. Avoid Other Sweets : You may crave other sweets when you stop drinking Mountain Dew. Arm yourself with some other snacks and plenty of water to help avoid the sweets until you&apos;ve overcome the addiction to the soft drink. If you are really craving sugar, you may wish to eat something small and sweet tasting but not full of sugar. For example, a piece of chocolate.

4. Speak to a Professional : You can always speak to your doctor or a therapist if you have severe concerns about your dependence on Mountain Dew. They may be able to give you medical advice or the resources and tools to better help and understand your situation. For example, you may have diabetes and if that is the case medication may help you.

5. Ask for Family and Friends Support: Your family and friends can help you stay on track. Ask them to make sure you never, ever drink it. Give them explicit instructions on what they can do to help you overcome your cravings and dependence. Request they do not serve it at parties or gatherings.

6. Get Some Exercise : Getting exercise while avoiding mountain dew and other soda products will help teach your body to burn fat instead of sugar for energy. It will also help relieve stress.

7. Understand Why You Are Addicted to It : Addiction is a physical condition and an emotional one, that can happen with just about any type of substance. Physically, Caffeine is an alkaloid, so it effects the body just as drugs such as nicotine and cocaine and heroin. Many people who are dependent on mountain dew have also addictions to other alkaloid substances - such as cigarettes, potatoes, tomatoes, peppers, and more. Alkaloids make people feel good, this is why they are used in excess or abused! In addiction to the effects of caffeine consumption, your body also craves it because it requires the high sugar content. Your body needs it to help regulate your blood sugar, because excessive use can cause your body dependence because it may stop producing insulin the way it should in a healthy body. Emotionally, you may use mountain dew as an escape for stress or to make you feel better after a long day.

8. Eat Healthier: Drinking excessive amounts of soda can often leave you malnourished, because you are getting your energy from sugar instead of protein and fats. You may not eat much because caffeine is usually an appetite suppressant. So, eat tons of vegetables. Get foods with healthy fats such as salmon, tuna, raspberries, eggs. Foods that contain protein can also be helpful because it will help regulate with your blood sugar. A nutritional expert can be very helpful in helping you learn which foods are best for you to eat, will help regulate blood sugar, and also determine whether you made need vitamins and supplements.

 Remember: You do not have to face addiction alone! Help is always just a phone call away, no matter what your situation may be.
 
 
Mountain Dew Anonymous Song
 
Useful Books About Addiction to Sugar, Caffeine, and Alkaloids

 Allen Carr&apos;s Easyway to Stop Smoking While you may or may not be a smoker or want to quit smoking, this is a great book to read because it will help you get in the right&quot;mindset&quot;to quit - without feeling like you are giving something up. It&apos;s not perfect, but it&apos;s a start toward deciding whether you are ready to quit Mountain Dew. Amazon Price: $10.35
List Price: $16.99 Overcoming Sugar Addiction: How I Kicked My Sugar Habit and Created a Joyful Sugar Free Life A great book to read for those who do not believe sugar is just as addictive as other substances. Amazon Price: $16.85
 Killer Colas: The Hard Truth About Soft Drinks Don&apos;t believe soda is bad for you? Having problems convincing family and friends you have a problem? This book is for you! Amazon Price: $8.30
List Price: $15.95 How To Quit Without Feeling S**T: The Fast, Highly Effective Way To End Addiction To Caffeine, Sugar, Cigarettes, Alcohol, Illicit Or Prescription Drugs Another good book that helps explain why you are addicted to soda (as well as covers more alkaloids and sugar drugs). It has a focus on how changing your diet and lifestyle can make a big difference. Amazon Price: $18.42
 
 
This Hub was last updated on December 9, 2011
 
You can help the HubPages community highlight top quality content by ranking this article up or down.
 Useful  {12} • Funny  {8} • Awesome  {2} • Beautiful  {1} • Interesting   Discover More Hubs 5 Most Healthy Beverages to Drink How To Stop Sugar Cravings - It Is Easier Than You Think Sugar and Sugar Substitutes Soft Drinks and Obesity: 6 Reasons to Stop Drinking Sugared Beverages Is Sugar Sensitivity Making You Sick and Tired? Symptoms and Suggestions. How to make healthy Kombucha Tea! 
 Loading... Is Mountain Dew Addictive? Share Your Thoughts 70 comments 
 Go to last comment 
 waylan  3 years ago
 
yes mt dew is defidently addictive. i fit all of the above in symtomes.

oh and also, my body went into a full body cramp, and i think it was due to a combination of 3 cups of dutch coffie(yum) a crapload of M.D. and stupid drama stress all at once.

it really sucked. alot.

but some simple water seemed to help alot.
 
 alan  3 years ago
 
Dew is definatly addictive. I am semi-addicted myself! I acually found this while looking for Mountain Dew recipies.
 
 holly  2 years ago
 
I believe it is. I think it was causing me to be overly hyper and have anxiety attacks. I was having anxiety attacks for no reason at all. And haven&apos;t had any since I quit drinking MD.
 
 elisabethkcmo   2 years ago from Just East of Oz
 
I&apos;ve read that this is a huge problem , you may already know about this also

 http://abcnews.go.com/m/screen?id=6863173&amp;pid;=26 

great hub with important info, thanks!
 
 Dean  2 years ago
 
Mountain Dew is very addictive, I have had moderate to severe stomach pain, headaches, mood swings, anxiety as a matter of fact as I am typing this my legs are bobbing up and down and I have also gone from 160lb to 203lb over the past couple years of MD consumption and after all of that I still am unable to quit drinking this stupid soda, not to mention I am going broke from it as well. If anyone knows how to stop without feeling like you are going to leap out of your skin, please let me know....
 
 Mav Kouratha  2 years ago
 
You are all soft, MD is a good soda but you guys just are stupid if you buy it all the time. Man up, stop buying it easy as that. Your all pussies for saying you have an addiction to soda. And if your going broke from get a new job, Or drink more of it and get DM end up on dialysis and die within 5 years. Fund the health care system, and don&apos;t try to sue PEPSI. They make products, you drank them your fault! And last word of advice &quot;keep your chin up&quot;...
 
 Sean Dastardly  2 years ago
 
My friend Brandon is an addict. This is also hilarious. Mountain Dew isn&apos;t a drug you retards.
 
 Kristal  2 years ago
 
You know I don&apos;t see where you guys get off telling everyone to man up or calling us names. Have you ever had a problem quitting something? There are people out there that have addictive personalities and have problems with things. I have quit alot of things and still baby dew as my last thing to let go of. This is my last vice and its hard to let go of something I love so much. But in time I will as I have other things. I am just looking for some pointers so I don&apos;t loose my mind. With 5 kids and long days Give me a break an take your ability to verbal lash to your parents house.
 
 Tamararivella   2 years ago
 
Dr. Pepper Coke and any soft drink containing sugar and caffiene are horrible and addictive. Mountian Dew is the worst. Headaches are a significant sign, caused by blood vessel contriction.

I hate to see parents give this stuff to kids. It causes behavior problems, insomnia, headaches and obesity
 
 amanda  2 years ago
 
Wow seriously? Pussies, righhhht. How about you drink it for 14 years and then try to break the habit? Because I&apos;m sure you can oh so easily deal with killer headaches and and an upset stomach and all the other side effects that come with it. It is a serious medical condition, caffeine addiction, ask any doctor. So before you go around calling people &quot;retards&quot; and &quot;pussies&quot; do some research because you sound dumb right now. Oh and by the way, this is about caffeine addiction. If you don&apos;t have it or don&apos;t think it&apos;s real, then you can just get off the page.
 
 Lovely Zit  2 years ago
 
hit me up wida mtn dew moda fukka!!
 
 Gazinta  2 years ago
 
I&apos;ve been addicted to Mtn Dew for years. My consumption of Dew was very different from any other soda. It became the only thing I wanted to drink. I didn&apos;t drink coffee so Dew was my morning beverage. I would choose a fast food restaurant simply because they offered Dew to drink. I&apos;ve given it up a couple times but always came back again. I&apos;ve never felt addicted to anything like I feel addicted to Dew. What I finally realized was that I was addicted to the caffeine more than the sugar. I found a caffeinated water product called Water Joe and that has helped me greatly. I drink the caffeinated water for the energy boost and to avoid the headaches and then I allow myself one soad a day but it cannot be Mtn Dew. So far that is working for me. I really believe that I have to give it up completely - trying just to cut back has not worked.
 
 Megan mcclure  2 years ago
 
i drink about the same amount as you, i drink eassssily, 6 or m ore a day and dont even think its a problem, i cant stop, ive tried and when i do i get really irritated and cant sleep and its like nothing will help me, i cant drink anything else im not satisfied with it, ive even been to the doctor for a kidney infection and still...probably the next day i was drinking it again, i dont know what to do because i dont really like anything else to drink...and ive been drinking it about 8 years i dont think its going to be so easy for someone to help me or me ever stop.
 
 Cayden Ryan   2 years ago from Strasburg
 
Well, I&apos;m screwed, I have every symptom. In fact, I&apos;m drinking one right now, making my total a whopping 92oz today...

just tastes so good.... :(
 
 marek  2 years ago
 
hey does anyone here know where i could purchase a semi full of mountain dew im looking everywehre but cant find it!! ??? :(
 
 hotrod mania  2 years ago
 
I was told thet if drinking MD for a prolonged period time that it could cause ur sperm count to drop. Has anyone heard of such a thing?
 
 dew addict  2 years ago
 
I have all the signs and symptoms listed above. I have Dew in my car and in my bedroom. This stuff rules my life. I tried diet dew and went back to the real thing. Even my cavities have cavities now, so my dentist is probably happy about my habit. My doctor told me I have to give it up due to constant UTIs.

I need help!
 
 dew addict  2 years ago
 
Mountain dew is very addictive!!! i probably drink 2 to 4 liters every day. I have gotten 3 root canales in the past 2 months and if i dont drink it every day i get very cranky. I have to stop.
 
 Joe  2 years ago
 
It&apos;s just good
 
 katie  2 years ago
 
I just love Mtn dew...It soo good..I cant seem to live with it..I do drink others stuff though..But can mtn dew give u a headache?
 
 Lee  23 months ago
 
I am officially 9 days off the Dew, after 25 years. It is the only beverage I would drink, morning noon and night. I now feel much better, the first couple of days were awful!! Headaches, depression, you name it!! I now have a cup of green tea to help with the withdrawal.

It really is a drug, the sugar alone is a powerful drug, let alone all of the additives thrown in there. As a bonus I have lost 7 lbs. without changing anything else!!
 
 Amber  23 months ago
 
I dropped 50 pounds after 8 months of substituting tea for mountain dew. Yes, it has caffeine, but not as much. And yes it contained sugar, but something about this high fructose corn syrup packed on the pounds. After going with tea for about a year...I then substituted water. After all these years...I got back on mountain dew...the ol &quot; one can&apos;t hurt you&quot; and with my addicted personality...gained 50+ pounds back...I actually got nauseated and felt like I had the flu after going without it the first day. I drink atleast a 6 pack of cans a day. My advice...and I&apos;m taking it myself. Bite the bullet and don&apos;t get back on it.
 
 greg  21 months ago
 
i drank a 24 pack and a 12 pack of mt dew all in one day and i was running throgh town like a wild animal
 
 kj  19 months ago
 
yea i mean i don&apos;t drink that much of it, like only 3 cans a day, but i drink the stuff like mountain dew voltage. i know i have to completely avoid energy drinks (like monster) because if i started drinking those more than like 1 in a few MONTHS i would probably get even more addicted to caffeine. and no i dont drink a 2 liter a day but when i don&apos;t drink caffeine it screws me up...
 
 Nick  19 months ago
 
I know how everyone feels. You all call us &quot;pussies&quot; or names but when you think about it, this is a MEDICAL CONDITION... (Sorta) While it is easier for some people to quit then others, its still hard either way. I&apos;m 14 and have been a Dew addict for 4 years!!! I still sometimes take a bottle and smuggle it into school because I&apos;m addicted to it! Drinking it throughout class periods and then chugging the rest before basketball practice... My parrents have already yelled at me several times because I constantly leave MD bottles around my room. Not to mention I&apos;ve got in trouble a few times in school resulting in a detention once (but that was because I got wrote up by a hard ass) It IS addictive. So try it, use it for 2+ years, then tell me its a &quot;pussy&quot; addiction... Good day to your sir and burn in hell for making fun of addicts.
 
 dauntlessds  19 months ago
 
I seriously have decided to quit drinking Mountain Dew because I was drinking nearly 4-Liters a day. What makes this even harder is my job always has fresh baked cookies that we serve to our guests. Fighting the sugar cravings is traumatizing sometimes. One day I got a flutter in my chest and started feeling cold and shaky. My left foot and leg are swollen more-so than my right and it&apos;s making my shoes harder to put on. I have a problem... I NEVER in a million years thought I would be addicted to a soda. I wish all of you the best of luck and hope that everything bad this has brought onto me is reversible in at least a small portion. It&apos;s a shame when the will to LIVE is not even enough to sway you away from a beverage. I would take a drug addiction compared to this any day for one simple reason. Jailtime will HELP keep you away from the stuff but you can&apos;t even go to jail without having access to Mountain Dew. They keep it in the canteens! LOL
 
 Jake  18 months ago
 
I&apos;ve managed to quit smoking after nine years, cold turkey, but I&apos;m much more upset about my need to get of the Mtn. Dew. It&apos;s just as others have said. I drink it almost exclusively, having hardly drank water for years. My weight hasn&apos;t been helped by it but after smoking cessation I just want to keep the ball rolling and get off this crap once and for all and feel good about my physical being.
 
 Levi  18 months ago
 
No joke, Mt Dew is highly addictive. It&apos;s all fun and games until you are waking up at night craving the stuff. I see all of these posts on here and I feel even worse about my personal situation. I am hooked on Diet Mtn Dew, or Dt Mtn Dew Code Red (depending upon the day). I wake up thinking about it, drink it all throughout the day and cannot sleep at night until I have had my night cap of the stuff. All in, I drink anywhere between 5-7 liters per day.........yes, you read that right. I have tried repeatedly to lay off the stuff but always come back to it. I know it sounds silly but it has almost become ritualistic for me in how I go about my daily business and just don&apos;t feel right without it. I am currently in the process of trying to quit, what has worked so far is switching to another Dt beverage which I don&apos;t like as much (Dt Dr Pepper, Dt Coke etc.) and trying to reduce intake a little bit at a time. I simply cannot quit cold turkey.
 
 Nathanael  18 months ago
 
Oh wow. Im definitely addicted. I refused to believe it but i am.
 
 Ericka  17 months ago
 
I always think about Mt. Dew. its scarey. I go through times that I allow my self to have one here and there but mostly i try to avoid it. its so hard. A Dentist once told me to use a straw so it does not touch your teeth. Good luck.
 
 christina smith  17 months ago
 
I drink 10 cans of mountain dew in a day.addiction?definatly!I have seriouse kidney problems.Stones in both kidneys,they are so large i cannot pass them, a lipitripsy is required for each kidney.I have had kidney stones, 14 times,i have already had 4 lipitripsy&apos;s.my dr. bills are outragouse.I smoke,have had no lung issue&apos;s.Why does Pepsi not have to label there cans like ciggarett companies label cigaretts?My dr.&apos;s state the stones are caused by Mountain dew&amp;Mountain dew ONLY!Any thing addictive should have a warning label.Pepsi will say, it&apos;s the sugar.So, cigarett companies have to label that tabacco is addictive,I can quit smoking, have done it, yet cant quit the Mountain Dew?Does there need to be several lawsuites to get the label?thats what happend with cigarett companies.People-Please,research soda-before you drink.id be healthier if
 
 Jonathan Fox  17 months ago
 
Yes, I was a big idiot with Mountain Dew. I would drink two 44 ounce cups a day for months - granted with about half ice or so, but still. I&apos;m just now stopping but I still drink it a day or two of the week, which I&apos;m hoping I can stop soon too. I think I may be suffering from some diabetic symptoms despite my doctors telling me I have no diabetes, too...

Like dauntlessds and Jake said, this stuff just destroys lives and health. I just wish I could go back in time and never have gotten into it in the first place. I don&apos;t know if my body is recoverable. Everyone do themselves a favor and stay away from the stuff.
 
 The Tyler Polich  17 months ago
 
well Jr iam going to tell you that u have no problem with drinking 2 44 oz drinks boy i drink 12 to 14 cans of MTN a day so get off me now some might say i have a addiction but that a load of #$%# and do what makes you happy so drink up boys
 
 Real Man  16 months ago
 
All you dew junkies are a joke!!! Why would you ever let yourself drink 4+ bottles a day??? Are you retarded?? Pop is about the worst thing you can drink - it&apos;s all sugar and calories! Don&apos;t you ppl know how to read?? And a special shout out to the 14yro kid - your partents must be even more retarded than you! Why in the hell would they keep wasting money buying your overweight ass more pop?? What&apos;s next? They&apos;re gonna let you drop out of school cause you get picked on too much for being overweight? Just stop drinking the crap already! Be a man!!
 
 Rick  16 months ago
 
Mountain Dew is no more addictive than any other soda. It contains sugar, high fructose corn syrup, and citrus juices among other things. There is nothing unique in Mountain Dew that makes it addictive other than the increased amount of caffeine it contains. To sit around and blame health issues on the product is silly. I know of no studies that link any illnesses with this product at all. Caffeine withdraw is probably the only issue you will have if you stop drinking the product, same issue you would have if you stopped drinking coffee, tea, and other caffeinated beverages. Have problems with it? Learn a little self control. Caffeine is not mind altering, so how much you take in is totally within your control.
 
 ashleighhhhhhhh  15 months ago
 
I love mountain dew. Its really not that hard for me to stay off of it though.
 
 Samantha  15 months ago
 
I have drank several cans of Mt. Dew a day for a few years now. I was always in very good shape and pretty healthy but in the last 2 years have gained 40 pounds and have been hospitalized for several days at a time due to kidney infections! I finally said enough is enough! It wass very hard and I had headaches that I thought I would die from but I have stopped drinking it! I lost 6 pounds in the first week and feel so much better! I am not a big water drinker so I have started drinking Propel Fitness Water, it has a good taste while still getting the water you need! I recomend to anyone to stop drinking it or at least slow down. I have 3 young children and almost lost a kidney because of this and no telling what the future effects it is going to have on me! I need to be here for my kids so I suffered through the headaches and am now feeling 100% better!
 
 Clare  14 months ago
 
Okay. Mountain Dew&apos;s addictive. I go through about a two liter every 24/48 hours, depending on what else is going on in life. It f***ed me up for a little while, but I&apos;m stubborn and decided I was going to beat it without having to give up the Dew.

Here&apos;s how you handle your addiction without giving it up:

1. Brush your f***ing teeth you nasty b*tch. Twice, even three times a day. For like two minutes at a time. Make sure you do this, it helps.

2. Don&apos;t give it up, but for every 2 liter you drink, drink a 2 liter of water. It helps keep me from getting sluggish and it&apos;s actually stopped and helped reverse the weight gain. And I still drink as much as I did before.

Give it a shot. It helps.
 
 Dammit  12 months ago
 
I don&apos;t understand mountain dew...it&apos;s soooo hard to quit for me, I&apos;ve done many differant drugs, became addicted and in the end finally quit it. But, with mountain dew I can&apos;t, it&apos;s been 5 years&amp;I&apos;m still going with it. About 2-4 liters a day. If I could kick marijuana, vicodin, Oxis, etc. Then why not this!!!!!
 
 Bobby  12 months ago
 
This stuff is.highly addictive no matter what people say it classified as one of the worst drinks out thier. I smoked for 11 years and never had the problems associated with this drink .point blank this stuff is as bad as beer,pot, you name it it has the dyes in it and sugar galore fact is I drink about 2 1/2 2 liters a day and its taking over my life just like with a drug got to have on stand by stock up for fear of running out this.shit iscrazy going to talk to my doctor about getting off this shit worst stuff i&apos;ve ever been on and I.ve drank,smoked,smoked pot,and this stuff is worse than that.and for the smart asses leaving you&apos;re little messages about pussies,retards you are just little bitches. If you have no care about people with this problem take ur asses on down the road nobody wants to hear ur shit. And for the people with the same problems as me talk to you&apos; rd e doctor about whats going on thats what they get paid to do better to get it now before its to late with you&apos;re health. Peace and prayers. Bobby
 
 Liquidcrack  11 months ago
 
Lol I came across this lookin up UTI from dew...

As my name suggests this stuff is liquid crack, I was known at my old job for the fact of how much of this crap I drink. I would stack huge pyramids of cans n bottles on my desk within a week or so.

I easily drink 8-12 cans EVERY day this is for idk 15 yrs or more every single day. I haven&apos;t yet to have kidney problems but I&apos;m pretty sure I have a UTI n I&apos;m also pretty freaking sure if not caused by dew it&apos;s increased by it.

Also see I&apos;m not alone in the fact I quit cold turkey cigs but still crush dew continually. Am I addicted prob but I haven&apos;t actually made an attempt to stop.

Considering it feels like I&apos;m pissing fire now I think it&apos;s time to stop drinking this stuff like I do, as others said it&apos;s the ONLY thing I drink. Idk WTF water is, if it&apos;s not green idk if it should be consumed lol

Seriously dew is liquid crack but i&apos;m not gonna get crappy w pepsi I know it&apos;s horrible for me I chose to injest it, and well every human that knows me says dude ur gonna die from it. Lol if they see it blatantly then for me to act like I don&apos;t is BS. I&apos;m hooked on liquid crack but time to actually stop drinking this green death lol

Good luck to everyone who struggle w the most addictive substance in liquid form known to man ;)
 
 Alan B.  10 months ago
 
8/31/2011

Here is my story on Good ole Mountain Dew.

I was born with Atopic Dermatitis and was allergic to almost everything, especially grass but it did not prevent me from playing football through high school.

At age 4 or 5, I was told by doctors to drink MD because there was nothing in it I was allergic to. I am now 48. That makes over 40 years of heavy consumption never less than 6 a day, sometimes more than 12. Absolutely nothing for me to go through a case in 2 days.

I just visited the dentist day before yesterday, not pretty. 12 cavities and a root canal needed.

It is nothing for me to get up in the middle of the night, kill a 16oz to 24oz MD in 3 gulps in less than a minute and go right back to sleep. I think I am immune to caffeine, if that is possible.

Here is a site I found yesterday describing some affects on the body.

 http://www.naturalthyroidchoices.com/MtDew.html 

2 days ago, I decided to quit smoking, drinking alcohol, and stop drinking Mountain Dew which I most usually mixed with vodka (double whammy.)

A very impossible task for an addictive personality such as mine.

The money I have blown on these products over the years is both staggering and astounding.

What I have decided:

Instead of smoking a pack to 2 packs a day, limit myself to 5 cigarettes a day.

Instead of drinking 6 to 12 MDs a day, limit myself to 24oz a day.

Instead of consuming alcohol 29 of 30 days a month, limit myself to once or twice a week and limit the amount to half.

I am not overweight, never have been.

I presently find myself with a headache and assuming it it is from caffeine withdrawal.

For those that do not believe it is an addictive substance that is no good for the body at all, you need to re-evaluate your thoughts on the substance.

Is MOUNTAIN DEW addictive?

Is the Pope a Catholic?
 
 Shannon  9 months ago
 
I am a MD addict. I fit all the catagories above. I consume 8 to 12 a day. I can even drink an intire can in the middle of the night and go back to sleep in less then 5 minutes been like this for going on 15 years. I do not tho crave any sweets actualy hate candy and other sugary snacks. So i yes i belive that MD is addictive and i have no clue how to stop without making my family suffer i am a mother of 4.
 
 Jeremy  9 months ago
 
Ok, well for all of you that are saying mountain dew is not a drug, heres the thing.... IT IS. caffeine is as much of a drug as alcohol... sure its not illegal but it is a drug.

And fuck... my stomach is killing me..... i switched to diet MD and i love it! ... so not much help on that last tip there buddy... ughhh no seriously, its killing me.... better go get some more dew from the fridge...

*it sucks cuz im seriously hurting right now.... and im seriously about to go get up and drink some more MD
 
 Darragh  9 months ago
 
Tried mtn dew voltage for the first time yesterday and then last night I woke up with vibrations and insomnia. Really weird...
 
 MD  9 months ago
 
I have all the symptoms. I wanna give it up but at the same time I can&apos;t! It&apos;s gotten so bad where I HAVE to drink at least almost 6 or more cans a day, and I can&apos;t stop. I tried moving on to tea but now I not only drink tea but ALSO mountain Dew. I wanna give it up, but I don&apos;t at the same time. My friends call me MD because I&apos;m an addict...It&apos;s HORRIBLE. I&apos;m not overweight, as I excercise (not a lot but enough to keep me in shape) etc...And whenever I don&apos;t get MD to drink I get so depressed, and tired...But maybe if I limit myself...But it&apos;s hard because on the weekends no one s here to forbid me from drinking more than two...It&apos;s HORRIBLE. Right now I&apos;m even drinking Mt dew and I&apos;ve noticed that my heart feels heavier also. Idk if that&apos;s bad or even connected to mt. Dew but my friends all joke I&apos;m gonna die by the stuff. Even now my heart is clenching...Not a heart attack or anything, just a mild pain in my chest...
 
 Ox  8 months ago
 
Mountain dew gives me a sustained hard on for new hours he st a time
 
 Cracky  8 months ago
 
Its addictive because of the brominated vegetable oil. Thats why Mello Yello still doesn&apos;t quite cut it for you in a pinch.
 
 mossman  7 months ago
 
why does the article say about sugar addiction? the caffeine makes it addictive..
 
 Sean  7 months ago
 
Absolutely agree. in fact i searched for &quot;mt dew addiction&quot; today because i was going through what i really considered withdrawl simptoms. Shakes, cold sweats, hot sweats, pounding headache, upset stomach, etc. but now that ive drank about half a bottle of &quot;Dew&quot; i feel 100 percent better. I&apos;m more than a little worried, and i think i will drastically cut down on my Mt. Dew intake.
 
 greg  7 months ago
 
12 cans a day and hellacious headaches when i try to stop drinking it
 
 Chad Campbell  7 months ago
 
Yo if anyone can help me with my addiction to volt (mnt dew voltage) plz text me 1 360 621 4363 . Plz anyone. I&apos;m in really good shape right now and I don&apos;t want to fuck it up. Like its very hard for me to gain weight but I&apos;m just worried still.
 
 Chad Campbell  7 months ago
 
Yo if anyone can help me with my addiction to volt (mnt dew voltage) plz text me 1 360 621 4363 . Plz anyone. I&apos;m in really good shape right now and I don&apos;t want to fuck it up. Like its very hard for me to gain weight but I&apos;m just worried still.
 
 UGH  6 months ago
 
I have a six pack of dew before lunch, every day. Tried to stop several times, but i always get a headache by 10am if i don&apos;t have at least one.
 
 DugL  5 months ago
 
Been drinking it since I was 16. I am 51. I drink a firm 12 pack a day. I admit my addiction. I have 4 wonderful children. My work has a ship mechanic is physically demanding. I honestly cant think of one day I havent had mountian dew. I will tell you this. The Product is being blamed. Just like Cigs, you choose to put it in your mouth. Just Don&apos;t. its 50/50 blame here. I am in great physical shape and still keep up with the 20 year olds however, its not how much of this you consume, its how much you can burn off that you consume. Exercise people! the best way to exercise is play basketball with the kids or friends, clean the house, yard, cars office. build a tree house have lots of s*x just do something physically demanding. If your lazy Mountian Dew is not going to help you. If you sweat for 12 hours a day and drink water a 12 pack a day is not going to hurt you. I am living proof. PS drink cans not bottles and save the aluminum. I save 75% on Mountian dews by buying them in Az then driving into Ca to recycle them.
 
 Mandy  5 months ago
 
I have been drinking Mt Dew for many years and have put on weight can&apos;t sleep at night yet i feel so very tired all the time..I am a stay at home mom i keep my house clean i do all the yard work but still don&apos;t loose a single pound..If i don&apos;t have the dew i get migrains to where i&apos;m sick..I don&apos;t know what to do i don&apos;t hardly drink anything else and water just tastes so bland..I never beleaved i could ever get addicted to pop how in the world could this ever happen :( i&apos;m so lost i want to stop and get it over with but i have to admit this is one of the hardest things i have ever went through..I have thought about taking caffine pills just to avoid the headaches but then i don&apos;t want to be addicted to a pill either ugg so stressed over this, anyone have any advice please email me.. mandy26519@yahoo.com
 
 Sarah  5 months ago
 
Im horribly addicted to it i dont eat much but all i mainly consume is mt dew i fainted going 1 day without it sounds silly but when ppl tell me to stop i get a axienty breakdown cant shake it. My dr and family think im nuts. Agh zero support and zero help
 
 Tom  5 months ago
 
the sugar addicts total recovery program by kathleen desmaisons totally changed my life. its totally doable. now i have energy and i am not depressed. im in full control of what and when i eat. my head is clear. i can handle problems. my emotions are appropriate. i havent gotten sick since i started 9 months ago; my immune system even seems stronger without those constant withdrawal cycles. and there is room in my diet for tasty healthy things now. you can get this book used on amazon for a few dollars.
 
 Tom  5 months ago
 
(continued) I&apos;d guess the caffeine has a lot to do with it, but for me it is mainly sugar. Sugar affects some people much more than others and is obviously addictive to them. quitting really wasnt that hard. it takes commitment; that is all. like this guy says, its about your blood sugar. You probably wont be able to quit by will power. you need a plan. eating 3 meals a day and getting a good amount of protein in them is key. its not really just sugar though; its anything with empty calories (calories without fiber and other nutrients). these things spike your blood sugar. avoid them. They include sugar, beer, wine, liquor, white bread, white rice... . all processed foods are seemingly designed to spike your blood sugar level. Education is key. you need to have a very very clear idea of what food is helpful in reducing cravings and what food causes them. check out kathleen desmaisons. good luck!
 
 Amber  5 months ago
 
This is a real addiction. It really gets under my skin that people laugh about it. I have had about a cup of mtn dew today (because its all i had left) and I have been groggy all day with a headache and mood swings. And I have 2 young children to take care of! So, no.. it is not the least bit funny! If I didn&apos;t have to go through this I wouldn&apos;t! I drink about a 2 liter a day... give of take... since I had my last child... SHE IS 3! I first drank it for the energy boost because I was sleep deprived... then i just started drinking it more and more until i needed it everyday! Its like my body is just giving up on me! Does anyone know about how long it takes to kick this??? I feel like I might die!! THANK GOODNESS I am home without a car right now or i would have already given in!
 
 Yates  5 months ago
 
Mt.Dew is not addictive, it is the caffiene in Mt.dew that is highly addictive. All the symptoms listed are caused by caffiene. Yes the sugar is bad to, but it does not cause all of the problems that are listed. I drink Diet Dew, switched from regular because I didn&apos;t want the massive sugar intake anymore for the simple fact that I wanted to lose weight. I drink up to 3 liters of Diet dew a day, I am not obese,I am not tired and or lethargic, and my energy levels are consistant. I don&apos;t get insomnia, I don&apos;t have sugar crashes and never have, The only cavities I&apos;ve ever had is two from when I was a child before I even drank mt. dew. Caffiene is the addiction,when you are addicted to caffiene and you go without, you get massive headaches because the caffiene makes your blood vessels expand, when you don&apos;t have caffiene they contract causing headaches, usually severe that can last up to 5 days in some people. It&apos;s just like any drug, when you cut it from your system your body goes into shock for a while until it can normalize itself. Sugar is not bad unless you eat it from a bag with a spoon. Also as far as kidney stones and such, like I said I drink up to 3 liters a day, I have had kidney stones in the past but that was when I was drinking coke. Since I stopped drinking coke and picked up mt. dew I have not had one kidney stone. Kidney stones are caused by a lack of water, not caffiene or anything else in mt.dew, dark colas and teas have oxilates which cause kidney stones. Don&apos;t be hating on mt.dew without the facts!
 
 yates  5 months ago
 
Also I&apos;ve stopped drinking dew on several occasions, i have a headache for about 3 days then it&apos;s gone and I am caffiene free and feel fine. Those of you who &quot;can&apos;t&quot; quit, it&apos;s because you don&apos;t want to not because your addicted. Everyone thinks it&apos;s strange you drink so much dew, that you start to think it&apos;s strange so you try to convince others that you are addicted and can&apos;t quit rather then tell them you don&apos;t want to quit drinking it. Either that or you are all just very weak willed people. Caffiene takes 2 hours to affect your body after consumption, it then takes 6 hours after the affects begin for your body to rinse it all out. Myself and DugL are shining examples that you are all full of shit.
 
 yates  5 months ago
 
Also the comment at the end of the article about Dew being easier to quit then things such as marijuana, are you kidding me? Marijuana has been proven not to be addictive and has more health benefits then most manufactured drugs. Marijuana is not easy hard to quit in the least bit. I&apos;m an avid smoker, I smoke for anxiety symptoms and pain relief, when I go without smoking I don&apos;t feel bad at all, I feel fine. I&apos;m a little more stressed out but thats it. Whoever wrote this article needs to do some real research before writing stuff like this, wikipedia doesn&apos;t cut it.
 
 Mikey  4 months ago
 
For all my fellow addicts out there, Put it in the freezer, let it freeze almost fully...dump the syrup it leaves before its completely frozen...this is what I call mountian dew concentrate. lol! Drink a cup full of that shit...it&apos;s like super dew. What happens is the water freezes before all the good shit does..and its pure 100% columbian mountian dew.
 
 Jessica  4 months ago
 
I am glad I am not alone. I&apos;m sick of the stares from my family and friends. But that first bubbly cold gulp down my throat will send me into complete bliss. Okay, my stomach hurts sometimes after and I can crash, i&apos;m showing signs of diabetes even though i weigh 103lbs. But it&apos;s everywhere and so cheap. Can&apos;t I have just ONE smut habit. I&apos;m so healthy, but the Dew is holding me back.... :(
 
 juggaloPYROnigga  3 months ago
 
mtn dew is one of the most addicdive soft drinks out there i have been addicted to dew sence i was 8 or 9 an i really havent drank anything else but a gator aid here or there just when i was feeling really dehidrated other then that dew dew dew an oh yes more dew i cant go a day with out it i have masive headachs i cant eat i feel so groogy cant even get out of bed or off the couch an this happens all the time any more weather i have it or not i have tryed a few times to stop drinkin it but i just feel so horrible i end up braking down an goin to the store to buy me a 44oz. mtn dew runs my life now an i dont think ill ever stop drinkin dew but i would love to slow down as of now i go thru a 24 pack in 1 1/2 to 2 days tops an thats just me like an thats a slow day i can drink a hole 24 pack in a 12 hour period dependin opon what ive done an how thirsty i am(like if i have cotton mouth) ive been addicted to herion meth coke hallusanigins(lsd shrooms stuff like that sorry i cant really spell right now) an ive got off it all except mtn dew its just to hard to quit doin somethin when your body is like dependint on the caffien an sugar just to get up an move around an i no what it feels like to withdraw from somethin an dew deffintly has a crash an idc what anyone says you can withdraw from mtn dew(just like dope)an it sucks its way worse to fiend for mtn dew then any dope ive ever done

mtn dew should have some tipe of warning lable somethin as simple as a lil square on the bottom side of the can that says somethin like warning addictive or a list of side efects that could happen or somethin along thous lines i just dont think its fair that every day a new person trys mtn dew an if there like me they fall crazy in love with it i mean its not that hard just to even put just warning on the side of the can. cigarettes an alcohol have to have a warning lable why not mtn dew i meean mtn dew has a lot of side efects other than just addiction it will rot your teeth right out of your mouth its got enugh sugar in it to put a diabetic in a comma an it can give you diabeatis in time obesity all kinds of things like that its amazeing that the gov has such strict rules an regulations over somethin as harmless as marijanna but they wont even make soda companys put a warning sticker on it i mean if i could chose i whould say legalize canibas an put strict rules on soda so people dont over do it an end up like me and another thing i dont think that mtn dew should have nutrition facts it should have at the verry least suplement facts instead theres not one thing nutrisous about dew 170 calories 65mgs of sodium 46gs of sugar 0 protein 0 every thing thats good for you but its got plenty of stuff to make you fat an diabetic for sure dude if you really just read that hole rant pat you&apos;er self on the back an thank you for reading i love mtn dew addicted or not i dont im gunna drink it till the day i die probably but im gunna quit smoking cigarettes i dont drink alcohol i dont do any other drugs anymore(with the exseption of pot witch isnt a drug if you ask me any way its a herb)an maybe after all that ill be able to kick mtn dew to the curb an start livein a helther life wish me luck

WHOOP WHOOP MMFWCL
 
 john  2 months ago
 
I love mountain dew! I drink a 24 pack a day of it every day. I don&apos;t drink anything else. it has everything I need in it. Alot of times I dont even eat because it has so many calories in it that it fills me up. Im not over weight and i have no side effects from it. i have a normal job and a normal sleep schedule.
 
 The Smurfinater  2 months ago
 
Its not mountain dew your addicted to. its the magic smurfs put in it (p.s. its yellow..............)
 
 Dylan  2 months ago
 
I am drinking my 5th 2 liter today as I&apos;m reading this, lol. I do have an addiction. When I run out of money I find myself doing anything for my parents to earn that $2.00 for a 2 liter, since I&apos;m only 15
 

 
 Sign in or sign up and post using a HubPages account.
 8192 characters left. Post Comment 
No HTML is allowed in comments, but URLs will be hyperlinked. Comments are not for promoting your Hubs or other sites.
 working 

 
 Like This Hub? 
Over 50 Million people discover HubPages every month.
 HubPages 
 about us blog advertise faq link to this page copyright 

Copyright©2012 HubPages Inc. and respective owners. All rights reserved.

Other product and company names shown may be trademarks of their respective owners.

HubPages ® is a registered Service Mark of HubPages, Inc.

 terms of use privacy policy (0.15 sec) HubPages Health 
 working
	</body>
</document>
