<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005844" url="http://www.crestcapital.com/tax/history_of_the_assembly_line.html" time="2012-07-12-22:31" support="2" score="0.0025972468111925906" bingtitle="History of the Assembly Line - Equipment Financing. Equipment ..." webtitle="History of the Assembly Line">
			<query id="000588" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="6"/>
	<description>... van financing business working capital loans ice cream ... air hockey financing heavy truck financing business credit card ... in which individual parts of a larger product are put ...</description>
	<body>
		Equipment Financing and Leasing 
 petroleum gasoline station financing hot drinks machines commercial tow truck leasing striper and paver truck financing automotive frame machine vehicle leases video arcade machine business van financing business working capital loans ice cream vending machines business tractor trailer financing wood shaper industrial equipment finance industrial pressure washer closed circuit tv leasing skid steer equipment financing equipment lease calculator rear loader truck financing farm tractor leasing woodworking equipment leasing grapple truck leasing leasing restaurant equipment commercial optical lab equipment rooftop hvac financing tow truck leasing portable pressure washer financing mulching equipment leasing side loader truck leasing air hockey financing heavy truck financing business credit card terminal financing business phone financing commercial amusement equipment sonogram equipment office building financing color digital press lease cold food vending machine financing corporate generator financing restaurant pos equipment commercial articulating boom truck leasing used broaching machines modular school building farm equipment embroidery equipment leasing business shelving equipment leasing patient transport ambulance lease bulldozer financing floor scrubbing equipment financing landscape equipment easy furniture financing business exercise bike financing sweeper truck leasing general business equipment financing telescoping boom truck financing vertical panel saw leasing commercial storefront sign computer hardware instant financing exotic limousines leasing retail display cabinet telephone switch lease billiards financing glass etching equipment portable church building financing commercial plate punch medical accounting software media replication hardware financing knuckleboom truck leasing fire truck financing and leasing corporate telecommunication equipment leasing pressure washer lease brake lathe leasing document binding machine financing food vending machine data storage equipment commercial limo leasing overhead truck leasing business tow truck financing canning machine leasing gym rack leasing agriculture equipment financing retail store equipment financing business atm machine leasing business excavator leasing large document scanner leasing business key card entry emission testing equipment aeration equipment financing corporate telecom equipment leasing companies capital lease software corporate laser equipment financing business audio recording gear business forklift financing crane financing food service equipment financing lease automotive tools store front sign inline boring machine dentist financing auto diagnostic equipment glass cutting equipment lease color copier financing healthcare equipment financing corporate lab equipment financing collating machines lowboy trailers financing corporate hvac financing wheel loader equipment lease office equipment leasing corporate green house equipment commercial vehicle financing leasing capital equipment optometry equipment large format plotting printer lease tax deduction software carpet cleaning equipment leasing back lit signage catering truck financing corporate copier leasing flatbed tow truck laminating machine business software lease business medical imaging equipment financing financing heavy equipment dry cleaning equipment financing milk vending machine leasing commercial mixer trucks business retail pos equipment chiropractic equipment financing telephone transformer equipment leasing business equipment finance corporate manufacturing equipment leasing rolloff trucks semi liquid vacuum truck lease transportation equipment leasing and financing self service kiosk leasing car wash financing farming harvesting machine industrial microwave 
 
 
The History of the Assembly Line
 
An assembly line is a manufacturing process in which individual parts of a larger product are put together in a specific order. Today this process is usually performed by computers, but in its early days it required human hands. The assembly line sped up the manufacturing process dramatically. It allowed factories to churn out products at a remarkable rate, and it also managed to reduce labor hours—benefiting many workers who used to spend 10 to 12 hours a day in the factory trying to meet quotas. The Ford Motor Company adopted the assembly line between 1908 and 1915, and it helped the company become a significant force in the United States economy.

 Assembly Line : An article that discusses how important the assembly line was to the advancement of the auto industry. Mechanization of the Assembly Line : A page that explains how assembly lines were used in industries other than the auto industry. Mass Production : The first section of an article on the&quot;Roaring Twenties&quot;that examines the historical importance of mass production by assembly lines. 

A number of industries, including the meatpacking, artillery, and auto industries, use the assembly line process. The meatpacking industry was already using assembly lines by the 1860s. Workers would stand in stations and operate a pulley system to bring over each animal carcass in turn. They would cut the meat as needed, then move on to the next animal. The firearms industry started using the idea around the same time, allowing weapons to be assembled much more quickly. But those weren&apos;t the only industries to use assembly lines. As time went by, other smaller industries—such as the clock-making industry—started using them as well.

 Assembly Line : An article that explains what assembly lines do and how they work. History of the Assembly Line : A brief summary of the use of the assembly line in the meatpacking industry, and of its later presence in the auto industry. Henry Ford Creates the First Assembly Line : A page that discusses Henry Ford&apos;s implementation of the assembly line, and how it revolutionized his industry and all others. 

During the 1920s, the United States was on the verge of a massive change. As more and more machines were being invented and used all around the country, people continued looking for ways to increase productivity. One of the most significant inventions to come out of that time was the assembly line. This process spread to many different industries, and it helped turn the United States into a major economic power.

 First Ford Assembly Line : A page that discusses how important Ford&apos;s assembly line was to his company and to industry as a whole. Henry Ford Changes the World : An article that includes an account by a real individual who saw how the assembly line improved the Ford company&apos;s productivity. The 1920s : A look at the 1920s and the importance of assembly lines in that period. Ford&apos;s Assembly Line : A discussion about the importance of the assembly line that hypothesizes where the world would be without it. 1920s : An article that briefly discusses how the assembly line revolutionized the 1920s. 

Today most assembly lines are automated, and they require a human worker only at the end of the process—to inspect the products to make sure they are not defective. This is why the assembly line is a valuable part of every major manufacturing industry in the world. These assembly lines operate in manufacturing plants that require goods to be produced on an&quot;as-needed&quot;basis. Effectively, the plants have a two- or three-day supply of the parts they need. A worker watches over the assembly line as machines attach parts together: The human hand is only needed at certain stages. The modern assembly line focuses on speed and quality, so that finished products can be put out on a regular basis.

The assembly line was not invented by one single person. It grew out of a combination of smaller advancements and discoveries. Various people invented cogs, fixtures, and machine tools. By the time Henry Ford started using the assembly line in his company, it had already evolved. Today, almost everything goes through an assembly line at some point. Without it, the world would still be constructing everything by hand.

 Meat Packing : A brief discussion of factory workers and assembly lines in today&apos;s meatpacking industry. The Assembly Line : A museum page that deals with the history and importance of assembly lines. Industry Takes Center Stage : An overview of the importance of the Industrial Revolution. From the American System to Mass Production : An article that explains the history of mass production and how it became so important. 

Though the assembly line&apos;s history is not very long, the world can hardly function without it now. From major automobile makers to fast food chains to clothes manufacturers, our world&apos;s most integral industries use this process to increase their speed and accuracy—profoundly impacting the lives of nearly 7 billion people. It will continue to be a valuable asset to the manufacturing industries. The ease and uniformity it produces has helped manufacturers provide standardized products for their customers, and has made constructing replacement parts very simple. The very simplicity of the assembly line makes it one of the most useful and inspiring inventions ever.
 About the Author : Written by Michael Marcin of Crest Capital . Michael oversees all operations and finance for this national equipment finance lender. He is an excellent technical writer on topics including equipment, vehicle, and software finance and associated tax implications . 
 Home Media Center Contact Crest Capital Terms of Use 
 PO Box 88233•Atlanta, GA 30356•800-245-1213•fax 888-391-6728 | Copyright©1989-
 
, Crest Capital. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
