<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005813" url="http://hotasianwomen.typepad.com/blog/2011/05/can-the-perfect-pick-up-line-get-you-laid-.html" time="2012-07-12-22:27" support="1" score="0.0015441940364162635" bingtitle="Can The Perfect Pick Up Line Get You Laid? - How To Get Girls" webtitle="Can The Perfect Pick Up Line Get You Laid?  - How To Get Girls">
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="203"/>
	<description>Learning how to use pick up lines on girls might ... time it is or if they know where the nearest fast-food restaurant ... the time comes to ask a woman for her phone number ...</description>
	<body>
		How To Get Girls 

Learn Tips And Advice On How To Pick Up Girls Fast...
 Home 
05/18/2011
 
Can The Perfect Pick Up Line Get You Laid?
 
Can The Perfect Pick Up Line Get You Laid?
 
A lot of guys think you&apos;re supposed to use some type of &quot; cute pick up line &quot; when you try to approach a girl.

Learning how to use pick up lines on girls might sound like a difficult and painful process. You have to gather up the confidence to walk up to a woman and introduce yourself, and then get her phone number. If the thought of randomly approaching women and striking up conversations makes you feel anxious, I understand that this process can be hard at first, and I&apos;ve been there myself.

But the bottom line is, you&apos;ve got to learn how to approach women if you&apos;re going to expand your social life and elevate your dating life. Approaching women is something that most men are afraid of. . If this is how you feel, then you should change your ways so that you can start having the success that you desire.

What you ought to know is that your fear of rejection can be overcome, and it can be overcome simply and easily. Maybe you&apos;re reluctant to approach hot girls because you&apos;re worried about rejection, or that something could go wrong -- but hey, guess what? That&apos;s life, and things do go wrong! It really doesn&apos;t matter in the long run. All that matters is that you harness the energy and power to walk up to a woman and introduce yourself.

Practicing in the mirror, and performing some mental exercises, is one way to build up your confidence with approaching women. Talking to yourself in the mirror will allow you to see how you look and to build up the confidence you need to approach someone. If you can first be comfortable with yourself, then you will more than likely be comfortable with talking with a woman too.

I&apos;m sure you&apos;ve heard of men approaching women and seducing them instantly. Those kinds of aggressive tactics will only get you a drink thrown in your face, or you&apos;ll simply turn her off quickly and she&apos;ll walk away. But when you do approach a woman, you need to have no fear of rejection. Not being intimated of rejection is a skill that you need to develop, and you can begin by walking up to women and asking them a simple question.

I suggest taking some &quot;batting practice&quot; -- approach some random women and ask them a sincere question. Your question could be if they know what time it is or if they know where the nearest fast-food restaurant is. This will help you to get into the habit of naturally approaching women so when the time comes to ask a woman for her phone number, it won&apos;t be as hard to do.

Your chances of succeeding with women are going to skyrocket if you can get past your &quot;approach anxiety&quot; and fear of rejection. When practicing what I suggested above, you should only practice walking up to beautiful women. You can walk up to any girl and ask her where the nearest mall or supermarket is. You&apos;d be amazed at the responses and some of these women will even start up conversations with you!

The time is now for you to start learning the secrets of how to talk to girls. Work on building up your confidence by talking to yourself in the mirror and getting comfortable with who you are. Here&apos;s an extremely powerful book for you to check out:

Click Here To Grab Your Copy Of The Infamous Guide: What To Talk About With A Girl &amp;Seduce Them In Minutes

Do corny or cute pick up lines really work when you&apos;re trying to approach women? When you envision a guy using pick up lines, you probably picture some sleazy wanna-be Casanova, his shirt unbuttoned to reveal a gold chain and a furry chest. As a Barry White song plays on the soundtrack, he lurks in the bar seeking for his next conquest...

Then, his gaze locks on his next target and he moves in for the kill...he approaches her and uses some cheesy pick up line that causes her to groan (or throw her drink in his face...)

I&apos;m talking about pick up lines like these...

&quot;I sure hope you know CPR, because you are taking my breath away.&quot;

&quot;Can I borrow a quarter? [What for?] I want to call my mom and tell her I just met the woman of my dreams.&quot;

&quot;Do you have a map? I keep on getting lost in your eyes.&quot;

&quot;Somebody better call God, cuz he&apos;s missing an angel -- so what time do you have to be back in heaven?&quot;

&quot;Sorry lady, but you owe me a drink. [Why?] Because when I looked at you, I dropped mine.&quot;

&quot;Hello. Cupid called. He says to tell you that he needs my heart back.&quot;


&quot;I play the field, and it looks like I just hit a home run with you.&quot;

&quot;Your legs must be tired because you&apos;ve been running through my mind all night.&quot;

&quot;If this bar is a meat market, you must be the prime rib.&quot;

&quot;I was so mesmerized by your beauty that I ran into that wall over there...I&apos;m going to need your name and number for insurance purposes.&quot;

You actually CAN use a funny pick up line to approach women, and not all of them are that lame. Here are a few that women may actually find charming or flattering -- IF you follow them up correctly (which I&apos;ll explain how to do in a moment).

&quot;Wouldn&apos;t we look cute on a wedding cake together?&quot;

&quot;Do you know karate? Because your body is really kickin&apos;.&quot;

&quot;Your daddy must have been a baker, because you&apos;ve got a nice set of buns.&quot;

&quot;If a thousand painters worked for a thousand years, they could not create a work of art as wonderful as you.&quot;

(You shouldn&apos;t use this pick up line on girls who are very attractive and KNOW it. This line is more effective when you approach women who appear to be a bit shy and don&apos;t have a stuck-up attitude.)

Now here&apos;s the next type of pick up lines. You can call these ones...

Pick Up Lines That Might Get You Kicked In The Crotch

Use this last type of pick up line with extreme caution. A woman with a sense of humor might find them amusing, but you also run the risk of getting hit or having a martini tossed in your face. (Especially if her boyfriend the UFC fighter happens to be standing nearby.) Use them with caution...

&quot;Do you know what has 142 teeth and holds back the Incredible Hulk? [What?] My zipper.&quot;

&quot;Your daddy must play the trumpet, because he sure made me horny!&quot;

&quot;That&apos;s a nice set of legs, what time do they open?&quot;

The Truth About Pick Up Lines

But are all pick up lines only good for laughs? Do successful pickup artists ever use them to approach women and start conversations? I have authored a few books on picking up girls, which teach many different ingenious approaches to starting conversations with girls. I personally feel that if you&apos;re learning how to approach women, using pick up lines is NOT the way to go.

I teach a style of approaching women that I refer to as &quot;going under the radar&quot;. This means you use a clever, unexpected comment or question to get her interest and engage her in a conversation WITHOUT signaling that you like her. These methods of approaching women feel more casual and natural to both you and her.

For instance, when you approach a woman you might ask for her opinion on an unexpected topic -- one that women are of course going to have strong feelings about.

Opener #1: &quot;Quick question -- would you allow your boyfriend to go to a bachelor party if you knew there were going to be strippers there? My friend Samantha asked me for my opinion.&quot;

Opener #2: &quot;Hi, quick question -- I need your help to settle a debate. How long do you need to be dating someone before you change your status on Facebook from &quot;single&quot; to &quot;in a relationship?&quot; Because my friend Jennifer has been going out with a guy for a month and SHE thinks it&apos;s an exclusive thing, but he hasn&apos;t changed his &quot;single&quot; status and she&apos;s wondering if she should say something...&quot;

These openers are especially effective because they&apos;re based on what I call &quot;relationship grey areas.&quot; Men and women tend to have their own ideas about what&apos;s allowed in a relationship, and what is unacceptable. Here&apos;s another line you can use when you approach women: &quot;does it count as cheating if a guy has lunch with his ex-girlfriend, and doesn&apos;t tell his new girlfriend about it?&quot;

The bottom line is, when you are approaching women a good opener is going to make her WANT to respond. Here&apos;s another line I use to approach women, which always seems to get a good reaction:

&quot;Do I look gay? Because this guy was TOTALLY hitting on me in the men&apos;s room a minute ago. Be honest, is it my shirt?&quot; (Or, &quot;is it the way my butt looks in these jeans?&quot;)

Those don&apos;t count as &quot;pick up lines,&quot; really. But I&apos;m not saying you should NEVER use a corny pick up line when you approach women.
In some cases I&apos;ve actually said some of those corny pick up lines when approaching women, and they sparked a conversation and got me the result I wanted -- which means I scored her phone number, or hooked up with her that night).


It was because I made fun of the fact that I had USED a pick up line! After delivering it, I followed up with &quot;I know that TOTALLY sounded like a pick up line...but I want to talk to you for a second and I couldn&apos;t think of what else to say. By the way, you can call me Dean...&quot;

At that stage, I used my Mack Tactics -- I asked a few &quot;strategic&quot; questions to get her in a fun mindset, and sharing information about herself...I used tactics such as Teases, Hypotheticals and Cold Reads and at all times, I stayed in control of the interaction and guided it down the correct path.

The truth is, you can get away with using a corny pick up line and actually make women laugh (in a good way). The trick is knowing how to follow it up with something clever that makes her want to talk to you.

And hey, this one has worked for me several times...

&quot;You&apos;re so cute that you made me forget my pickup line.&quot;

(Girls always find that one cute and funny!)

Now, before I explain how to FOLLOW UP and get her to start feeling FAST ATTRACTION, I ought to warn you about something...

The strategies in our FREE guide to approaching women will affect females on a subconscious level and tap into their deepest desires. We ask you to please use this information responsibly! These are basically the most powerful tactics if you want to learn how to approach women, move past cute pick up lines, and make women feel powerful sexual attraction to you.

If you&apos;re ready to take your approach skills with women to the ultimate level and learn the very best pick up lines to use on girls, download your FREE guide to approaching women -- along with a bunch of awesome free bonuses -- at our How To Appproach Women website.

 


 May 18, 2011 10:54:08 PM | Weblogs 
 Comment 0 Reblog It 0 
 
Verify your Comment

Previewing your Comment
 
Posted by:  |  
 
This is only a preview. Your comment has not yet been posted.
 Your comment could not be posted. Error type: Your comment has been posted. Post another comment 
The letters and numbers you entered did not match the image. Please try again.

As a final step before posting your comment, enter the letters and numbers you see in the image below. This prevents automated programs from posting comments.

 Having trouble reading this image? View an alternate. 
 
 
 
 
Leave a comment
 Sign in: TypePad Facebook Twitter and more... 
 You are currently signed in as (nobody) . Sign Out 
Please sign in before leaving a comment.
 
(URLs automatically linked.)
 
Your Information

Name and email address are required. Email address will not be displayed with the comment.

 Name is required to post a comment 

 Please enter a valid email address 

 Invalid URL 
 
This weblog only allows comments from registered TypeKey users. To comment, please enable JavaScript so you can sign into TypeKey.
 
 NEXT POST http://www.asiandatingpro.com/datingjapanesegirls PREVIOUS POST How To Get Beautiful Girls To Like You - Three Attraction Secrets How To Get Beautiful Girls To Like You - Three Attraction Secrets I receive emails every day from guys who are desperate for answers on how to get girls, and trying to figure out what to talk to about with a girl. Women can be complicated and difficult to figure... 
 
 Hotasianwomen 

Learn my secret tips and advice on how to use pick up lines on girls
 1 Following 0 Followers 
Search
 
Recent Comments
 
 Steve Brad: What a good blog I never thought I could get so... | more » On Best Pick Up Lines and Meeting Women Tom Baron: Wow! Nice post. What a great information on how... | more » On Things to Talk About With A Girl You Like Aiden Wood Aiden Wood: Subject of this post is very interested. I am v... | more » On A Lowdown on Dating Beautiful Asian Women 
 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed Powered by TypePad
	</body>
</document>
