<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005811" url="http://blogs.e-rockford.com/comingsandgoings/2011/02/16/loves-park-vietnamese-restaurant-closes-bistro-taking-its-place/" time="2012-07-12-22:27" support="2" score="0.0014369945147249966" bingtitle="Loves Park Vietnamese restaurant closes, bistro taking its place ..." webtitle="Loves Park Vietnamese restaurant closes, bistro taking its placeComings and Goings - Rockford, IL - Rockford Register Star">
			<query id="000681" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>Whether it&apos;s a new boutique popping up, a fast-food restaurant closing down or a progress ... in Loves Park closed recently but another restaurant will soon take its place.</description>
	<body>
		Site Print archives Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Jobs 
 Cars 
 Homes 
 Classifieds 
 Apartments 
 Coupons 
 Subscriber Services 
 Home News Obituaries Business Sports Entertainment HealthyRockford Insight Rockford Woman Special Sections 
 
 Facebook Twitter Mobile E-mail headlines Local Loop Calendar Newspaper Ads Newspaper Archives Contests Contact Us 

 Your Town Public Safety Schools Real Estate Transactions Nation/World Celebrations Calendar 

 Real Estate Transactions Face of Business On the Move Say Cheese Star 60 Markets Stocks 

 Hoops Preps College Sports Bears IceHogs Twitter 

 Movies Music&amp;Arts Food&amp;Dining My Last Bite Life&amp;Style; Georgette Braun Will Pfeifer Twitter Calendar Contests 

 Health care jobs Health Directory 

 Problem Tracker Submit letter or guest column Opinions What You&apos;re Saying Blogs Bruce Quast Cartoons Videos 

 Facebook Twitter 

 Local Loop Reader Content Daily Deals People Living Spaces Branded Content 
 Comings and Goings Keep track of the latest business openings and closings. Whether it&apos;s a new boutique popping up, a fast-food restaurant closing down or a progress report on a major development, you&apos;ll find all the latest bits of information here. See something while you&apos;re out and about? Leave a comment or send an e-mail to business@rrstar.com and we&apos;ll check it out. Read more Follow @mlwestphal Skip to content 
Loves Park Vietnamese restaurant closes, bistro taking its place
 Posted on February 16, 2011 at 11:58 am by Melissa Westphal Tweet 
A Vietnamese restaurant in Loves Park closed recently but another restaurant will soon take its place.

Saigon Vietnamese Noodle Soup Restaurant, 6164 E. Riverside Blvd., closed after just about a year in business. It opened Sept. 9, 2009, near Riverside and Mulford Road, and its menu featured noodle soups and dishes like pad Thai.

Signs are up at the space that say a new bistro will open there this spring. The restaurant is called Bistro108, and it’s an American-style bistro that will feature casual dining and fresh food.

Tom Seeling and Jennie Braun are the owners. I’ll be chatting more with them and will update the blog soon.

 Related posts: 

 Saffron Bistro closing its doors Wednesday Thai restaurant in Machesney Park closes Pho Square Restaurant opening next month New restaurant opening at A Perryville Place in Rockford Sonic Drive-In open in Loves Park 
 This entry was posted in Uncategorized and tagged Restaurants . Bookmark the permalink . ← Rockford Borders store safe for now Charming Charlie boutique opening at CherryVale Mall → 
8 Comments

 Quentink says: February 16, 2011 at 12:43 pm 
I liked Saigon and was hoping they would make it. Well Pho Square
is still serving up some fantastic pho right down the street so I can still get my fix when I’m on Riverside.
 Commenter says: February 16, 2011 at 1:43 pm 
Pho Square is awesome, and I hope they are doing well, and if so, continue doing well in this area, it\’s some good stuff.
 NEJ6719 says: February 16, 2011 at 4:05 pm 
I can’t wait to see what this new Bistro has to offer! That area needs some more good dining.
 Milton Waddams says: February 16, 2011 at 4:45 pm 
I went to Saigon a couple of times, it was good. Shame they didn’t make it. I’ll have to try pho square.
 greggy says: February 16, 2011 at 7:29 pm 
Looking forward to a new restaurant that is not a chain or an Italian restaurant as this seems to be what we have most in the area.
 Michelle says: February 17, 2011 at 7:55 am 
Thai Cuisine, in the mall with Choices Natural Market, has some good vietnamese entrees. They have pho and vietnamese spring rolls. Spring rolls are good–a bit big to handle without making a mess. Their Tom Yum soup is awesome!
 NEJ6719 says: February 17, 2011 at 11:24 am 
I’m looking forward to some choices at the new restaurant. It’s great to see more locally owned and operated businesses coming to the area rather than more chains.
 Melissa Westphal says: February 17, 2011 at 1:08 pm 
Milton: Definitely give Pho Square a try. I agree with Quentink and Commenter—the food there is great, especially the pho and the spring rolls. I’ll have to try the pho and spring rolls at Thai Cuisine. Thanks for the tip, Michelle!
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via email. You can also subscribe without commenting. 
 
   
Search This Blog
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Red Mango yogurt shop opening in Machesney Park BP gas station on Charles Street in Rockford converting to Mobil Kochi Japan restaurant opening next week in Rockford Salon open at Stewart Square Pacemaker grocery store adds fuel pumps in Poplar Grove 
 
Recent Comments

 Norma on Closure of Ello Furniture is end of an era Jeff on BP gas station on Charles Street in Rockford converting to Mobil Patti V. on Molly’s Attic hosting grand opening Saturday in Roscoe Martink on Gray’s Foods grocery store on Auburn Street closing Anna Carlson on Olive oil store opening in Loves Park 
 

 
Recently Shared
 
 
 Melissa Westphal’s Stories 

 Closure of Auburn Street driving facility angers local officials Rockford driver&apos;s license facility moving over needed upgrades Illinois cemetery industry hit with new licensing rules Americans boost charitable giving in 2011 OSF on Cloud 9 over better pictures from new MRI machine 
 
 
Archives
 Select Month December 2011 (4) November 2011 (5) October 2011 (8) September 2011 (8) August 2011 (9) July 2011 (12) June 2011 (13) May 2011 (9) April 2011 (6) March 2011 (16) February 2011 (17) January 2011 (10) December 2010 (10) November 2010 (9) October 2010 (12) September 2010 (8) August 2010 (14) July 2010 (12) June 2010 (4) May 2010 (5) April 2010 (8) March 2010 (6) February 2010 (4) January 2010 (10) December 2009 (7) November 2009 (8) October 2009 (5) September 2009 (6) August 2009 (1) July 2009 (5) June 2009 (6) May 2009 (1) April 2009 (2) March 2009 (7) January 2009 (8) December 2008 (3) November 2008 (10) October 2008 (8) September 2008 (11) August 2008 (1) July 2008 (1) April 2008 (7) March 2008 (5) February 2008 (6) January 2008 (5) December 2007 (9) November 2007 (11) October 2007 (3) 
Categories
 Select Category Business move  (2) Cherry Valley  (1) Coming  (26) Going  (5) Health  (1) Machesney Park  (1) Restaurants  (12) Retail  (22) Retail expansion  (5) Retail move  (4) Rockford  (3) Uncategorized  (160) 
Tags
 Select Tag Business move (3) closings (51) Expansion (3) openings (99) Restaurants (12) Retail (12) Subscribe to Posts    Subscribe to Comments Marketplace • Classifieds • Find Rockford jobs • Cars • Homes • Coupons Site services • Subscribe • Place an Ad • Buy a photo reprint • Newspaper Archives • Weddings/Engagements • Anniversaries Your Town • Belvidere • Boone County • Cherry Valley • Loves Park • Machesney Park Your Town • Rockford • Rockton • Roscoe • South Beloit • Winnebago County Submit content • Calendar listing • Letter to the Editor • Press release • News tip Our sites • BusinessRockford.com • Go.rrstar.com • HealthyRockford.com • RockfordWoman.com • RockfordHomeOnline.com • RockfordWheels.com • m.rrstar.com 
 Contact us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | About our Ads 

Rockford Register Star |
 99 E. State St. Rockford, IL 61104

Copyright©2006-2012 GateHouse Media, Inc. Some Rights Reserved.

Original content available for non-commercial use under a Creative Commons license, except where noted.
 SEO by eLocalListing | Advertiser profiles | RadarFrog Merchant Directory
	</body>
</document>
