<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005463" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/60633933/PCOS-For-Dummies" time="2012-07-12-22:01" support="1" score="0.0009567807878093624" bingtitle="PCOS For Dummies - Scribd" webtitle="PCOS For Dummies">
			<query id="000868" bing-rank="88"/>
	<description>Meal Planning the Low-GI Way; Constructing a meal; Other Advice for Healthy Eating ... It Says You Have to Eat Loads of a Particular Food; It’s Very Low in Calories</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Buy Now You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Page 9 is not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 22 to 55 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 64 to 282 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Page 291 is not shown in this preview. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
PCOS For Dummies
 Practical advice and information for living with Polycystic Ovarian SyndromePolycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS) is a condition in which there is an imbalance of a woman&apos;s female se... ( More ) Practical advice and information for living with Polycystic Ovarian SyndromePolycystic Ovary Syndrome (PCOS) is a condition in which there is an imbalance of a woman&apos;s female sex hormones, and affects an estimated 10% of all women. This hormone imbalance may cause changes in the menstrual cycle, acne, small cysts in the ovaries, difficulty conceiving, high blood pressure, and other problems. It is treatable, but not curable, and sufferers have to rely on themselves for the long-term management of their condition. If you&apos;re living with PCOS, this guide gives you the latest information concerning treatments and research into Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome. PCOS For Dummies gives you a practical, plain-English guide to living with and managing Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome. In addition to providing valuable information concerning the causes and symptoms of Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome, PCOS For Dummies gives you the facts about the various treatment options that are available, including both traditional medical treatments and alternative therapies.Discusses the causes and symptoms of PCOSAdvice for dealing with this disorderCovers the treatments and medicine available in the United StatesPCOS For Dummies is an invaluable resource for the millions who are suffering from this condition. ( Less ) 1,495 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 07/22/2011 Copyright: Traditional Copyright: All rights reserved Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
