<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005925" url="http://www.dailyrecord.co.uk/news/scottish-news/2010/08/31/gang-of-40-youths-trash-kfc-restaurant-in-dundee-86908-22527019/" time="2012-07-12-22:35" support="3" score="0.002046373108106459" bingtitle="Gang of 40 youths trash KFC restaurant in Dundee - The Daily Record" webtitle="Gang of 40 youths trash KFC restaurant in Dundee - The Daily Record">
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>A LARGE gang of youths rampaged through a fast-food restaurant ... took place at about 10pm in Camperdown Leisure Park. ... Car hire in Glasgow. Central heating in Glasgow ...</description>
	<body>
		1 June 2012: 10:07pm 
 
Visit our other sites:  The Sunday Mail The Glaswegian Business 7 Daily Mirror Scotcareers Daily Record Bingo Daily Record Casino Local Mole Scotland Record Shopping Daily Record Dating   
   jobs in scotland    Used Cars    find your dream date    bingo    business directory    shopping    How we use cookies    
 
 Listen to us on iTunes 
 
 Overnight weather in Central Scotland 
 15°C
 - Mainly clear with plenty of sunshine 
 
 Home News Football Sport Showbiz Life Opinion Business Dating Jobs Directory DIY Donny Bingo Offers Holidays Used Cars 
 
 Scottish News UK&amp;World News Politics News Health News Science&amp;Tech Business&amp;Consumer News Weird News Real Life Special Reports 
  Site  Web 
 RSS News for you  |  What&apos;s this? 
 
 Home News Scottish News 
 
Gang of 40 youths trash KFC restaurant in Dundee

 Aug 31 2010 

A LARGE gang of youths rampaged through a fast-food restaurant, breaking doors and smashing windows, police said today.

Between 30 and 40 youths entered the KFC branch in Dundee and began overturning chairs on Monday evening.

They kicked and struck at the doors and windows with what is thought to have been a metal pole, prompting staff to call the police.

The gang fled when officers arrived at the scene and it is unclear what prompted the disturbance - but police are pursuing all lines of inquiry to try to identify the culprits.

The incident took place at about 10pm in Camperdown Leisure Park. Officers are examining CCTV footage from the area and have contacted local schools


 
Share
 
 
 
 Scottish News 
 
 Man found guilty of killing university lecturer who was stabbed to death in his Edinburgh home 

A MAN has been found guilty of killing university lecturer Roger Gray, pictured, who suffered an &quot;extremely violent&quot; death. Read 
 
 Woman rescued after falling 50ft down hill and injuring her spine 

EMERGENCY services were called to Loudoun Hill, near Darvel, Ayrshire, when the woman, in her 60s, fell while out walking today. Read 
 
 Health probe at world-famous Gleneagles Hotel after 100 people struck by vomiting bug 

NHS and environmental health officers are investigating suspected cases of novovirus at the five-star Gleneagles Hotel, which said almost everyone affected had now recovered. Read 
 
 Health probe at world-famous Gleneagles Hotel after 100 people struck by vomiting bug Police appeal for witnesses after two lorry drivers die in head-on collision on A9 near Blair Atholl Police launch probe into Edinburgh pensioner carjacking Creditor owed cash by Rangers blasts smirking Craig Whyte as former Ibrox owner laps up luxury in France Wife of Scottish sailor missing in Dubai reveals family is &apos;going crazy&apos; with worry about his safety Lord Gill appointed as new head of judiciary in Scotland by Queen Woman&apos;s body found in Clyde following rescue operation College music courses saved after protesters create wall of sound in protest Signed Beatles concert programme bought in 1963 for two shillings up for sale.. for£6000 Read more Scottish News 
 

 
 
Share
 
 More 
 
 Related Tags 
 
 kfc 
 
 (What&apos;s this) 
 
Your DailyRecord
 
Get involved...

We want your local stories, videos&amp;pics.
 
 Send your stories Send your pics Send your videos 
 
Reader Panel
 
 Click to register and you could win a cash prize 

We are looking to our readers to give us valuable feedback through a series of online surveys Read 
 

 loading... 
Look no further
 
 Your search is over 

All you need from Valentines to Holidays... visit LocalMole.co.uk Read 
 

 
 Business Finder 
 
Please enter a Business and Location.
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 
 Aerials in your area 

 Bathroom showrooms in your area 

 Blinds in your area 

 Builders in your area 

 Central heating in your area 

 Dentists in your area 

 Double glazing in your area 

 Estate Agents in your area 

 Florists in your area 

 Garages in your area 

 Hairdressers in your area 

 Health Clubs in your area 

 Hotels in your area 

 Hotels in your area 

 Kilt hire in your area 

 Kitchen showrooms in your area 

 Letting Agents in your area 

 Plumbers in your area 

 Pubs in your area 

 Removals in your area 

 Restaurants in your area 

 Satellite TV in your area 

 Skip hire in your area 

 Solar Panels in your area 

 Solicitors in your area 
 

 
Insurance
 
 Finding The Right Life Insurance Provider 

Searching for any insurance provider can often be a tricky. Read 
 

 
No Win No Fee
 
 National Accident Helpline 
 

 
 
 2nd hand cars Scotland 

 Used cars in Scotland 

 2nd hand cars Glasgow 

 Used cars in Glasgow 

 Used cars in Edinburgh 

 Used cars in Scotland for sale 

 Used cars in Glasgow for sale 

 Buy used cars in Scotland 

 Sell car in Scotland 
 
 
 
 
DIY Donny
 
 Need DIY Help? 

The perfect source for DIY tips, questions&amp;answers and step by step guides. Read 
 

 
 Copyright and Trade Mark Notice ©2012 owned by or licensed to Scottish Daily Record and Sunday Mail Ltd. Please read our Terms and Conditions and Privacy Statement before using this site.
 
 Site sections: Scottish football Scottish news Podcasts Music Celebrity news Opinion Blogs Women Food and Drink Used cars Popular tags Contact us Advertising Terms and Conditions Cookie Policy Privacy Policy Accessibility Site Map Competitions and Offers 
 
 Our sites: Sunday Mail The Glaswegian Business 7 Used cars ScotCareers Bingo Casino LocalMole Scotland Shopping Dating Daily Mirror 
 
 Restaurants in Glasgow Garages in Glasgow Builders in Glasgow Roofers in Glasgow Central Heating Engineers in Glasgow Central Heating Installers in Glasgow Plumbers in Glasgow Joiners in Glasgow Skip Hire in Glasgow Pubs in Glasgow 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 DailyRecord.co.uk, the Daily Record newspaper online. Best coverage of Scottish news and sport. All the latest on Celtic FC, Rangers FC, Scottish football, entertainment, jobs, videos, pics and lots more.
	</body>
</document>
