<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005841" url="http://foodenglish.wordpress.com/author/jbunt/" time="2012-07-12-22:30" support="2" score="0.0017920688982871985" bingtitle="jbunt | Composing on Food" webtitle="jbunt | Composing on Food">
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>... local grocery store for lunch instead of a fast food ... 1 cup flour; 2 eggs; ½ cup of milk; ½ cup of water; ¼ ... for the year, also known as a cap, they receive an ...</description>
	<body>
		Composing on Food Just another WordPress.com weblog Skip to content 
 Home About 
 
Author Archives: jbunt 
 
 A French Exchange 
 Posted on May 6, 2010 | Leave a comment 
The summer before I left for college, my family hosted a French exchange student for three weeks. She was an 18-year-old Parisian and her name was Anne-Sophie. I decided to tag along on one of her class’s excursions to Philadelphia so I could get to know Anne-Sophie better and her friends. We had a blast all morning talking about the differences between our cultures while visiting historical sites.

When it turned lunch time, we were able to venture off from the group to find something to eat. I was looking forward to making a pit stop at a McDonald’s for a large bag of crispy, golden fries and a soda; all of that walking made my stomach feel as if it were eating itself. I was surprised when the girls stopped at a local grocery store for lunch instead of a fast food restaurant. As Charlotte, Anne-Sophie’s 16-year-old sister, sat on a bench and munched on a green bell pepper, something I’ve never seen before, Anne-Sophie explained that it is typical for the French to eat small meals, almost like snacks, throughout the day.

The French way of eating smaller meals throughout the day eventually made sense to me. If we don’t eat so much, we are less likely to overindulge at meals. Skeptical at first, I have found that the French way is beneficial to the body and relationships I have with others by giving my body more time digest and giving myself more time to indulge in conversation with those around me. I feel healthier and calmer since meals are not so large and rushed.

One signature French meal that has become my favorite, and can be very filling after eating very little, is crepes. The great thing about crepes is that you are able to get creative with what goes into it. A crepe is usually described as a thin pancake; it’s as thin as a tortilla and is eventually folded, not wrapped like a tortilla, to hold its contents inside. You can add anything like chicken, fresh vegetables or fruit, turkey, cheese, or even peanut butter and jelly. My ultimate favorite crepe is the Nutella crepe.

 

 Crepe avec Nutella (recipe taken from allrecipes.com ) 

 1 cup flour 2 eggs ½ cup of milk ½ cup of water ¼ teaspoon salt 2 tablespoons melted butter 

-          Whisk the flour and eggs together in a large mixing bowl. While stirring, slowly add in the milk and water. Next, add the salt and butter. Whisk until the batter appears smooth in texture.

-          Lightly oil your griddle or frying pan and set to medium high heat. Pour ¼ cup of your batter onto the surface. Continue tilting the griddle/pan in a circular motion so the batter spreads evenly.

-          It should take 2 minutes for the bottom of the crepe to turn light brown. Flip the crepe with a spatula and let it cook for another 2 minutes.

-          Once the crepe is done cooking, let it cool on a plate for a minute. Now it’s time to spread the Nutella evenly on one side of the crepe. (You can add slices of banana, strawberries, or powdered sugar on top of the Nutella if you wish.) Finally, fold the crepe in half and in half again. You can eat your Nutella crepe with your hands or silverware.

-          Serves four

Fresh crepes are great for any meal; they are great for breakfast, lunch, dinner, or desert.   It is easy to see why the French value a simple crepe. A crepe is certainly a smaller meal than a steak with a side of whipped mashed potatoes and steaming green beans and, in my opinion, just as filling. Smaller portions give time for our bodies to digest both our food and conversations we have with those around us. Over a light breakfast, Anne-Sophie explained, in her thick French accent, the importance of each meal in France. “We value good food that is good for our health. We eat smaller portions because it is good for our bodies and the relationships we have with each other. My family eats three meals a day together and we are always talking and building our relationships that we have with one another.”

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Be Yourself 
 Posted on April 13, 2010 | Leave a comment 
“Don’t alter your voice to fit your subject (231).”Zinsser gives good advice in chapters 20 and 25 that I can easily incorporate in my writing. I found four points in these two chapters that I will attempt to use in my research paper.

Breeziness–“There is a kind of writing that sounds so relaxed that you think you hear the author talking to you (231).”This makes me think of what Zinsser says earlier in his book about clutter. By reducing unnecessary words in our writing, the text will flow easily. Also, by adding personal experiences and personal voice in our writing,the reader will feel as though the writer it talking to them.

Cliches–Zinsser does not recommend using cliches because they are not fresh and genuienly from the writer. I agree that cliches should be avoided. A writer’s own words should be used to add a freshness to their paper and it also makes the paper more personal by using the writer’s own words.

Entertainment - A writer’s text should be interesting and entertaining to the reader and not a complete bore. In my research paper, I will try to make the information that I am writing about more interesting for the reader by drawing on personal experiences and also adding graphs displaying the information that I am talking about.

Defend–Zinsser recommends to writers that we defend what we write. There will be editors that will try to completely rearrange what the initial story was. He encourages us not to be a push over and not accept what an editor tells us completely. He encourages us to defend our work and the ideas that we are trying to get across in our writing.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Finding Our Voice 
 Posted on April 1, 2010 | Leave a comment 
In Sommers’ Between the Drafts , she explains how academic writing is often viewed as a high authority that hangs over the writer’s head dictating how to write and what words are appropriate in sentences. When talking about her own writing, she says”I, like so many of my students, was reproducing acceptable truths, imitating the gestures and rituals of the academy, not having confidence enough in my own ideas, nor trusting the native language I had learned. I had surrendered my own authority to someone else, to those other authorial voices.”In her essay, she encourages her students, and writers in general, to try and personalize our writing and stop being so rigid in our style and in our revisions. By doing so she says,“students can claim their stories as primary source material and transform their experiences into evidence.”Personal experiences certainly add a personal touch to dry, academic writing that we are taught in schools.  Sommers also wonders why teachers can’t teach their students to be personal in their academic writing. Why do they have to teach academic writing and personal writing separately? She encourages us to explore the gray area of the black and white of writing.

I agree with her idea that writers need to not be so afraid to add a personal touch to academic writing. My teachers from high school also used to stress this idea; just because it’s an academic paper, doesn’t mean it has to be boring, it can be fun. I think by doing our interviews for our research papers, we have a personal experience to draw from and include in our papers to make them more personal than a dry, research paper.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Kingsolver: The Beginning 
 Posted on March 17, 2010 | Leave a comment 
Kingsolver clearly knows what she is talking about in her book“Animal, Vegetable, Miracle.”She doesn’t blindly go into describing a topic without knowing background information. For example, she knows the complete history of asparagus. She writes,“The earliest recipes for this vegetable are about 2,500 years old , written in ancient Greek and Egyptian hieroglyphics, suggesting the Mediterranean as the plant’s homeland.”Kingsolver also helps the reader relate to the lengthy information that she writes.“Asparagus even inspired the earliest frozen-food industry, in the first century, when Roman charioteers would hustle fresh asparagus from the Tiber River Valley up into the Alps and keep it buried there in the snow for six months, all so it could be served with a big ta-daa at the autumnal Feast of Epicurus.”Her husband’s and daughters’input also helps the reader to view their adventure in a different light and learn about new topics.

The genre of this book is clearly non-fiction. There is also a great deal of food writing throughout and a lot of history about the foods. It may be a stretch, but this book could also be  a how-to book that teaches the reader how to create their own farm and live off of what is grown.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 King Corn. 
 Posted on March 4, 2010 | Leave a comment 
I never realized how important corn is in today’s society until I watched King Corn. I thought that since I don’t eat corn on the cob, I wasn’t a corn consumer but I was wrong. I learned that corn is a key ingredient in high fructose corn syrup, which is commonly found in sodas; and I drink a lot of soda.

I have a few ideas for my research project: follow the growth of farms over the century, what foods are the most important to be produced on farms for society, or follow organic farming. With all of these I could either interview local farmers, farmers at local farmers markets, or companies that produce the foods that we consume.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Two Friends. 
 Posted on March 3, 2010 | Leave a comment 
Dwight Garner asks honest, fair questions in his friendly interview with Ruth Reichl. He clearly knows her beyond being the New York Times’ restaurant critic. He knows where she came from, the name of the first restaurant she co-founded, and the different reviews she wrote in the Times. It is clear that he admires Reichl and is not out to portray her as an evil food critic. The questions that he asks give Reichl the opportunity to show who she is; and that is a reliable food critic who loves her job.

I really liked how she responded to the question about justifying the Times’ decision to have ten or more food reporters than the few who cover a subject like Bosnia. She could’ve said she can’t justify it and that Americans need to care more about what is going on in the world, however, Reichl puts a positive spin on the subject. She says “The hospitality industry supports a large part of this country. Just in terms of sheer economics, we would be very remiss not to cover it. I think we don’t cover it as well as we ought to, in terms of business and so forth.” This made me realize how important the hospitality industry is in America and how Reichl writes for the common interests of readers.

-Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Thinking Organic. 
 Posted on February 25, 2010 | Leave a comment 
The phrase “eating is an agricultural act” didn’t mean much to me until I read Wendell Berry’s explanation of the idea. Wendell Berry sees society as eating industrial produced foods in a fast paced world without giving any thought as to where it came from or how it was produced. Berry explains, “Eaters, that is, must understand that eating takes place inescapably in the world, that it is inescapably an agricultural act, and that how we eat determines, to a considerable extent, how the world is used.” I can agree with Berry’s idea that we should all give more thought and consideration as to where our food comes from and what goes into creating it, however, for me, it would be nearly impossible to be organic because everything I eat is processed. According to Wendell Berry, I am being persuaded by the industrial food industry to eat certain foods but that doesn’t bother me like it bothers Berry.

My definition of “organic food” has a few similarities with Michael Pollan’s. I believe that organic food should be pesticide free and all ingredients should be all natural, no fake additives. Pollan believes this and more. He believes animals and vegetables should be “humanely raised” unlike how they are raised on industrial farms, poorly taken care of and overcrowded.  I didn’t like Pollan’s description of the organic food sold in Whole Foods. He talks about how the store offers a little explanation of where the food comes from. He explains, “One of the key innovations of organic food was to allow some more information to pass along the food chain between the producer and the consumer – an implicit snatch of narrative along with the number.” This makes it seem like organic food consumers need a story inorder to be statisfied with their food. Who’s to say the story isn’t completely made up?  I see the organic food movement as another money making scheme that people buy into.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Carbon Foot. 
 Posted on February 23, 2010 | Leave a comment 
Michael Specter writes about cutting back on our carbon footprint in his article “Big Foot.”  He begins the article by recognizing this will not be a simple task. Specter says, “We are going to have to rethink the way we live and work.” Throughout the article, he mainly focuses on the carbon footprints that are made by the food industry. I believe that it is important for consumers to become aware of the carbon footprint of products that they consume because the production, distribution, and exhibition of these products are destroying the earth. Specter also writes about an organization called Chicago Climate Exchange (CCX) and how it allows its members to buy and sell the right to pollute. If companies fall below their agreed emissions for the year, also known as a cap, they receive an allowance. If these companies exceed their limit, they are fined. I found the cap and trade idea confusing. I do not see how such a market could be invented where nothing existed before and still thrive. I cannot see how an organization like CCX can profit from this without going bankrupt.

Specter writes about the benefits of being a locavore, someone who eats locally produced foods. By being a locavore, one’s carbon footprint will decrease, mainly because the food will not have had to travel thousands of miles on a refrigerated truck or on an airplane. On the contrary, Specter points out that being a locavore will not always reduce one’s carbon footprint. He writes, “Researchers at Lincoln University in Christchurch, found that lamb raised in New Zealand and shipped eleven thousand miles by boat to England produced 680 kilograms of carbon-dioxide emissions per ton, about a fourth the amount produced by British lamb.” Clearly, a lot goes into calculating the carbon footprint of products and purchasing locally produced foods doesn’t always decrease one’s carbon footprint, even though it logically sounds like it would help.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 Leave them Wanting More. 
 Posted on February 12, 2010 | Leave a comment 
Different genres of writing are complied in Ruth Reichl’s Garlic and Sapphires . In class, we discussed how the varieties of genres can make the reader confused. I personally think Reichl transitions between genres very well. Typically in every chapter, she draws on her experiences in each restaurant and either ends with the review of that particular restaurant or a recipe, which are two different genres in themselves. I can see where the reader can become confused, however, I do not think it is because of the blended genres throughout the text; I believe it is the wordiness and unnecessary language used throughout. I think her descriptions are useful in her restaurant reviews, but I think it would be better if she was not so descriptive in her experiences in the restaurant because it takes away from the review.

I am not sure if there is such a thing as a “normal” review. I read a review about a pizza shop located in Philadelphia for our one assignment in class and I feel I learned a great deal about the food, staff, and history of that restaurant while craving the dishes being described. In the chapter titled “Finding Umami” from Garlic and Sapphires , I received the same information about the food, staff, and history in her review of the sushi restaurant that she takes Claudia to. I do not personally like sushi but the descriptive language that she used made me crave what she was eating. I feel a review is successful when the reader is informed about the service and history of the restaurant and food, but most importantly it should leave the reader wanting more and wanting to go to that restaurant to have a taste of what the reviewer is writing about.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 The Love of Abundance. 
 Posted on January 28, 2010 | Leave a comment 
Lynn Bloom illustrates throughout her essay what goes into food writing. She begins by showing that a food writer’s goal is to show the reader their value for food. The writer’s value is shown through their love or appreciation for the food in which they are writing about. I agree with Bloom; as a reader, I am more drawn into food writing that has a personal touch and shows the writer’s enjoyment with the food. According to M.F.K. Fisher, food, security, and love are all interrelated. Fisher’s quote made me think of the homemade baked macaroni and cheese my mom used to make when I was growing up; and still does! She knew it was my favorite meal and the fact that she knew that made me feel loved and secure.  Bloom then goes on to talk about picking peas on a farm in Switzerland. The paragraph starts out describing the food, but later brings forth the people involved and their relationships with one another. Bloom shows how this simple act brings together the love of a community.

Bloom also writes about how skinny food writers should not be trusted. Her reasoning is that food writing should stress overindulgence, abundance, and appetite; not dieting, scarcity or moderation. A.J. Liebling’s efforts as a food writer are shown, as well as Calvin Trillin’s. Bloom lists the variety of foods that they both have consumed and the ways in which they allow their readers to taste what it is that they are eating through their own sight, scent, and taste. I agree that a food writer should be able to eat massive quantities of food and to have a palette for just about anything. If they did not have a taste for a variety of food, how do they know what they are writing about? Readers rely on food writers to show what’s worth trying and what works best.

- Jillian Bunting
 
 →Leave a comment 

 Posted in Uncategorized 
 
 
Search It!
 Search for: 
Recent Entries

 A French Exchange Do I Have to Eat it? Learning to Love Summer Scottish Alement The food that binds Toots’Expected Masterpiece Growing Up Scottish Crunchy Cookies My Love is at Steak The French Toast Catastrophe of 2009 
 
Links

 &quot;Between the Drafts&quot;by Nancy Sommers A French Exchange by Jillian Bunting Advanced Composition Syllabus An Edible Experience by Krista Zimmerman animal, vegetable, miracle website/research resources Barbara Kingsolver Interview (with Bill Moyers) Bill Moyers Interview with Michael Pollan Chips vs. Fries by Gabriella Lee College English 70.4 (Mar. 2008) Food Anecdote by Danielle La Rue Food at High Steaks by Daniel Ramos Frontline Interview with Michael Pollan about Meat Grandma&apos;s House by Megan Colyer Just Try It by Tara Rohrbach Local Restaurant Reviews–by Advanced Composition Spring 2010 March Assignments Molly Wizenberg&apos;s Food Blog On Your Mark. Get Set. Eat! by Adam Feldon Quiet Creek Farm Really Good Chocolate Chip Cookies Research and Interview Projects Restaurant Review Restaurant Review Ruth Reichl Interview with Salon Ruth Reichl Interview with Salon Continued Spelt and Family by Amanda Shrawder Thanksgiving Dinner by Heather Romeo The Food that Binds by Brandon Haines The Organic Food Systems by Nowacek and Nowacek The Way It Was On Day One by Jaclyn Hardgrove Tilapia and Meatloaf by Alexandra Doyle Uneasy Taste of Success by Jordan Eckenrode WordPress.com WordPress.org 
 
 Theme: Coraline by Automattic . Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“Composing on Food” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
