<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005308" url="http://difficult-cooking-games.cooking-games.biz/" time="2012-07-12-21:51" support="3" score="0.005359136007297203" bingtitle="Search Results - Cooking+Games - Difficult Cooking Games" webtitle="Search Results - Cooking+Games - Difficult Cooking Games">
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000776" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000401" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>Cut the ingredients in the proper order quickly so ... until your soup boils and put the pot on the tray! ... shop and learn to fill orders quickly for a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Home | Members | Tell a Friend | Links 
 Find Games: 
 All Cooking Games 
 Game Sections 
 
 Bakery Games 
 
 Breakfast Games 
 
 Burger Games 
 
 Cafe Games 
 
 Cake Games 
 
 Dessert Games 
 
 Dining Room Games 
 
 Egg Games 
 
 Fast Food Games 
 
 Food Games 
 
 Fruit Games 
 
 Funny Games 
 
 Grill Games 
 
 Ice Cream Games 
 
 Kitchen Games 
 
 Pizza Games 2 
 
 Restaurant Games 2 
 
 Sue Games 2 
 
 Waitress Games 2 
 
 Members Username: 
Password: 
 
 Lost your password? You have only couple of credit(s) left before you must log in or register . 
 New Games Popular 
 
 New Dress Up Games 
 01.   Bread Maker 
 02.   Gingerbread Men Cookies 
 03.   Crazy Crossings 
 04.   How To Make Pumpkin Pan Cake 
 05.   Sweet Date 
 06.   Wack o Ween 
 07.   Blueberry Muffins 
 08.   Beautiful Cake 
 09.   How to Make Fried Ice Cream 
 10.   Catch the Sweet 
 11.   Bake Chocolate Chip Cookies 
 12.   Hannah Montana Beach Cafe 
 13.   Goofy Kitchen Chef 
 14.   Breakfast Kitchen 
 15.   Kitchen Design 
 16.   gimme5: movie! 
 17.   Cubiz! 2 
 
 Popular Games 
 01.   Hot dog Bush 
 02.   Cake Factory 
 03.   How to Make Fried Ice Cream 
 04.   Design A Cake 
 05.   Easy Bake 
 06.   Ice Cream Shop 
 07.   Making Cheesecake 
 08.   Cake bakery 
 09.   How to Make Christmas Cake 
 10.   Birthday cake 
 11.   Frosty freakout 
 12.   Pies 
 13.   China icecream 
 14.   Cakes 
 15.   Icecream service 
 16.   Holly Hobbie Muffin Maker 
 17.   Eggs 
 18.   Eggs 
 Site Statistics Registered Users: 50083
 Total Games: 5877
 Views Today: 256219402
 Total Views: 256219384

There are 1119 users online:
 0 Members , 1119 Guests. Top Players 01.   AiNoKaikoroku - 5331
 02.   sephybaby - 4455
 03.   miss_fabolous97 - 4158
 04.   Sakuralinh - 3264
 05.   Mondstein - 3202
 06.   HessieNae - 3120
 07.   nicole990248 - 2914
 08.   ducky3gal - 2848
 09.   valval - 2411
 10.   alliemae - 2168
 Cool Links 
cooking-games.biz
 01.   Roiworld 
 02.   Disney Games 
 03.   Up To Ten Games 
 04.   Dress Up Games 
 05.   Star Doll 
 07.   Dress Up Me 
 More Cool Links» 
 Search Results - Cooking+Games 
 Cooking School 
Enroll at classes in cooking school and learn all new recipes. Learn how to be a chef by taking cooking classes and entering competitions with your meals, practice cooking food and then pass your tests at cooking school. How to make a chicken burger 
Free Cooking Games for those who love cooking and prepare chicken burger from ingredients given. Cooking Doll 
This sweet little cooking doll spends all her time in the kitchen preparing meals for her owner. Pick out a chef outfit for her to wear while she is cooking in the kitchen with a special apron. Bread Maker 
Have you ever baked bread, learn what ingredients you need for this old bread recipe and impress your family this holiday with freshly baked bread. Cooking games can teach you new recipes and how to use new cooking appliances. Cooking Championship 
Get ready for the chef cooking championship, practice some great recipes in this game. Follow the instructions to match your opponents speed as you create a delicious dish. Cut the ingredients in the proper order quickly so you can show off your great cooking ability and win the cook-off. Cooking Mexican Food 
Cooking Mexican food in the kitchen, find the right ingredients to complete the recipe in this cooking game. Follow the recipe to find cheese, salsa, peppers, and tortillas to make delicious fajitas in cooking Mexican food game. Ratatouille Cooking Game 
Ratatouille works at a restaurant and needs your help in this ratatouille Cooking Game. Help Ratatouille slice these things to prepare for his cooking recipe. Ratatouille needs to make his French restaurant have delicious food. Sandwich cooking 
Sandwich cooking Game - Quickly create eighteen sandwiches withous messing up. Sandwich cooking 
Sandwich cooking Game - Quickly create eighteen sandwiches withous messing up. Grandmas Cooking 
Get in the kitchen and help Grandma with her cooking, find the right ingredients to help Grandma cook this fruit salad. Follow clues to solve the mystery of the recipes and have Grandma make you a delicious homecooked meal. Ramen Cooking 
Ramen Cooking Cooking Game Banana Pancakes 
Learn how to make banana pancakes on the cooking show. Prepare the ingredients like flours and bananas and mix them in a bowl by following the instructions of your cooking teacher. Yum! Babu.A 
Play cooking games and create wonderful cakes and become the best cook by preparing a choclate cake. Sue Cooking 
Sue Cooking Game Fast Fish Cooking 
Cook fast food on the street and serve your fast food customers in this fast fish cooking game. Make the best fast food fish in this cooking game. How to cook a Chicago hot dog 
Try at our online cooking games and prepare your favorite Chicago hot dog from the recipe given and have fun. Dessert Chef 
Become a dessert chef, practice new dessert recipes in this delicious cooking game with ingredients for chocolate cake and peanut butter brownies. Learn how to bake a cake and a dessert recipe for your favorite sweet in cooking class. Romantic Dinner 
Learn to prepare a romantic dinner for you date in this fun interactive cooking game. Learn some new recipes to show off your cooking skills and impress someone on a date. Cheese Omelette 
Learn to prepare the best cheese omelette, beat the eggs and add the cheese at the right time to create a delicious fluffy breakfast. Follow the recipe and learn new cooking skills in the cheese omelette cooking game. Cooking Bunnies in Kitchen 
Cooking bunnies in the kitchen, help these cute bunny chefs prepare for a big birthday party celebration. Bake bunny birthday cakes and bunny cookie treats for all the guests. Sandwich Stacker Cooking Game 
Whats faster food than a sandwich, make a sandwich in this sandwich stacker cooking game. Catch ham and cheese and delicious sandwich items to put on bread. How to make a bread pizza 
Learn how to cook pizza and prepare the best pizza by playing the online cooking games and have fun. Sushi Chef 
In this game you will be cooking your sushi specials for your customers, when a customer comes into your restaurant you should take their order then create the order and finally serve it. Try not to take too long or the customer will get angry and leave. Cooking sushi is really easy and fast if you know what your doing. If you get it wrong, try again until you learn how to play, once you the game you will have lots of fun making sushi. Cooking food 
Cooking food Game Fairy cooking 
Fairy cooking Game Fast cooking 
Fast cooking Game How to Make Fried Ice Cream 
Play free cooking games and prepare a delicious Deep-Fried Ice-cream for the kids and have fun. How to bake a chocolate cake 
Play cooking games and create wonderful cakes and become the best cook by preparing a chocolate cake. How to Make Fried Ice Cream 
Play free cooking games and prepare a delicious Deep-Fried Ice-cream for the kids adn have fun. Sweet Apple Pie 
In this fun cooking game you will learn how to bake the most delicious apple pie you have ever tasted. Learn how to make this yummy pie from scratch, from mixing the dough mixture to baking the pie. If you have a sweet tooth and like cooking this game is just right for you! The delicious crunchy crust and sweet sugary warm apples will melt in your mouth, and would go great with a scoop or two of vanilla ice cream. Cooking Show Sushi Rolls 
Learn how to make sushi on the cooking show, follow the step by step instructions to become an expert sushi chef. Try out new sushi recipes after you learn the basics, how to cook rice and cut fish for sushi rolls. Bunnies Kingdom Cooking 
Bunnies Kingdom Cooking Game Work at a Cafeteria 
Work at a cafeteria is difficult, and fast food cooking is not fun when your customers get angry. Play in the cafeteria and serve fast food to customers in this fun cooking game. Sandwich Shop 
Sue Sandwich Shop is open for business, help Sue make sandwiches ready to order. Cooking games are fun, pick a bread and filling for these sandwiches. Emma&apos;s Christmas Sweets 
It&apos;s holiday time and customers are rushing to Emma&apos;s Sweets shops to get their friends and loved ones a sweet treat. Unlock every level in the Christmas tree by completing cooking and serving tasks at Emma`s Christmas Sweets restaurant. You are in charge with cooking and serving clients with Christmas sweets and drinks. Cook the ordered sweets, add drinks and serve it to the client to fully decorate the Christmas Tree. How to make chocolate chip cookies 
Prepare chocolate chip cookies from the fun online cooking games and create wonderful cookies. Sue Cooking 
Sue Cooking Sue Cooking 
Sue Cooking Top That 
Top That Cooking Game Fast cooking 
Fast cooking Cooking food 
Cooking food Sandwich cooking 
Sandwich cooking Fast cooking 
Fast cooking Tea 
Tea Cooking Game Ramen Cooking 
Ramen Cooking Cooking Master 
Cooking Master Fairy cooking 
Fairy cooking Cooking Master 3 
Cooking Master 3 Cooking Master 2 
Cooking Master 2 Cooking Fish 
Cooking Fish Cooking Decorate 
Cooking Decorate Bunnies Kingdom Cooking 
Bunnies Kingdom Cooking Bunnies Kingdom Cooking 
Bunnies Kingdom Cooking Sue&apos;s Cooking Game 
Put all ingredients in the pot, pour hot water, wait until your soup boils and put the pot on the tray! Become a Bartender 
Become a bartender extrodanaire in this fun cooking game. Mix cocktails and be the bartender specialist in liquors and mixers. Making Ice Cream 
Learn to make ice cream from scratch in this fun cooking game. Beat together the eggs and milk and add your favorite flavors to create your perfect ice cream. New Kitchen Decor 
It&apos;s time for a kitchen makeover, spruce up your cooking area with some new countertop, new counters, and a new fridge. What kind of kitchen would you like? A tiled floor and a modern stove might just be the change you are looking for. Obama Burgers 
Obama is cooking burgers on the grill! He said he needs some help making enough for everyone so you are invited to the White House for Obamas first burger bbq cookout. Italian Dinner 
You and your boyfriend are on vacation in the beautiful country of Italy. You are cooking a delicious meal to eat with your boyfriend and it has to be perfect. See how well you can make Italian food. Pancake Maker 
Learn to make delicious breakfast pancakes in this fun cooking game. Combine all the ingredients in a bowl and mix together things like flour, milk and sugar and then fry them on the pan for the correct amount of time for perfect pancakes. How to Make Madeleine Castles 
Prepare Madeleine Castles and learn how to cook well and develop your cooking skill. Hot Dog Bush 
Hot Dog Bush Cooking Game Fruits 
Fruits Cooking Game Pancake Day 
Pancake Day Cooking Game Mr Meaty 
Mr Meaty Cooking Game Pie Picture 
Pie Picture Cooking Game Breakfast 
Breakfast Cooking Game Barmaid 
Barmaid Cooking Game Cakes 
Cakes Cooking Game Meal 
Meal Cooking Game Ratatouille 
Ratatouille Cooking Game Quick N Mix 
Quick N Mix Cooking Game Papas Pizza 
Ever wanted to try running your own pizzeria? Figure out how the pizza business works in this cooking game, run your own pizza shop and learn to fill orders quickly for a fast food restaurant. Crazy Cup Cakes 
Prepare Crazy Cup Cakes and learn how to cook well and develop your cooking skill. Star Chef 
This cute girl is going to be the next big celebrity chef, so help her get ready behind the scenes for her huge on-screen appearance. She is in Sydney, Australia hosting her TV cooking show, and she will be making a wonderful meal for her audience to win her international acclaim. How To Make Vegetable Salad 
Let play how to prepare the Vegetable Salad and you will learn cooking well. Fruit Cake Decorating 
Decorate a fun fruit cake in this cooking game. A lot of fruits and delicious icing to choose from to cook up a cake and make it pretty. Diner Dash 
Open up your own business and a new diner restaurant to serve your customers delicious food and sandwiches with their meals. Act as a waitress for your dining staff in this diner dash cooking game. Sweet Pink CHef 
Sandra is training to be a chef, and she likes to look cute while getting her hands dirty in the kitchen. Dress her up in an adorable chef attire so that her family is impressed with how beautiful she looks while cooking in the kitchen. Magical Wizard Potion 
Harry and his wizardly friends Hermoine and Ron are cooking up something in their cauldron for their potions class. They want to charm a student to join their group, see if you can recreate the right magical potion from the textbook to win the game on this spooky magic evening. Falafel King Cooking Game 
Falafel is a very popular Middle-Eastern snack - usually served in pita bread with humus, salad and french fries. Here is your chance to experience the difficulties of a falafel vendor dealing with impatient customers while trying to keep them all satisfi Grill the Skewer 
Ready to have fun outside and start grilling, learn how to grill the skewer and catch your meats and vegetables on the grill. Make kebabs in this fun grill cooking game. Job as a Waiter 
Find waiter jobs and get a job as a waiter, serve customers in a restaurant in this cooking game. As a waiter keep track of their orders and bring customers the right food. Family Dinner 
Quick get ready for family dinner in a flash, cook food and serve your family and their guest feast, learn new recipes to impress your friends. Make sure to not leave a mess in the kitchen while cooking for your guests. Cake Decorating Contest 
Are you ready to create the most amazing, most tasty and most beautiful cake ever? If you like cooking cakes and you like creating works of art out of frosting and sprinkles, you have found the right game. Choose exactly how to bake your cake, the colors and decorations. Take your time and you will come up with an awesome cake for everyone to enjoy! What&apos;s for Dinner? 
Learn how to cook dinner in this extensive cooking game, where you can chose the meal you will make, get the recipe and instructions on how to prepare it. Follow the directions to learn how to make anything from Caesar salad to pasta. Salad Maker 
Learn to make a salad by chopping vegetables to combine into a salad bowl. Chop them correctly and create a delicious healthy diet food in this salad maker cooking game. How to make Banana Lollies 
Prepare Banana Lollies and learn how to make desert food and develop your cooking skill. Complete Breakfast 
Learn how to cook a complete breakfast from scratch, follow a recipe for making pancakes and then make delicious eggs with bacon, ham and cheese on the side. It&apos;s the perfect breakfast and you can impress all your friends with your cooking skills after you try this fun interactive game. Cheesy Chicken Balls 
Prepare Cheesy Chicken Balls and learn how to cook well and develop your cooking skill. New York Pizza 
Everyone knows that you can find the best slice of pizza in New York City. The thin crust New York style pizza, is something the best chef wishes to copy and you can learn how to many a pizza from scratch using all the ingredients in this fun cooking game. Rasgulla Dessert 
Find out the recipe for Rasgulla, a sweet Southasian dessert. Learn how to make the cheesy Bengali dessert step by step in this great interactive cultural cooking game. Indian Food 
Have you ever tried Indian food? Delicious fried rice and baked goods from an Indian restaurant, learn how to cook Indian food in this great cooking game. Cake Bakery Game 
Original cooking game - follow the instructions to create 20 cakes. Click on the helper to get different plaincakes. Most cakes use plain white cake, yet some require chocolate or icecream cake. Cake Bakery Game 
Original cooking game - follow the instructions to create 20 cakes. Click on the helper to get different plaincakes. Most cakes use plain white cake, yet some require chocolate or icecream cake. Stuffed Mushrooms 
Try out this delicious recipe for stuffed mushrooms, a great appetizer that will feed your guests and show off your cooking skills. Follow the instructions to make this appetizing dish and learn a new recipe for a wonderful and simple vegetarian hors d&apos;oeuvre. How to Make One Fish Two Fish 
Prepare How to Make One Fish Two Fish and learn how to cook well and develop your cooking skill. Making a Pizza 
This game is full of steak cutting, ingredient chopping, dough pounding fun. Get through each of the unique cooking challenges to win this pizza game. Before you can make the pizza, you have to chop the ingredients, roll the dough, and even boil water. Have some fun in the kitchen! Barbie Baked Potato 
Barbie is getting ready to cook a baked potato, and she can show you how easy it is to make this tasty and delicious snakc, or side dish. Just clean the potato and follow Barbie&apos;s instructions to cooking it perfectly and preparing it with the right toppings. Cooking Family Dinner 
Help girl cook a meal in her kitchen, pick out the vegetables for family dinner. Click on the ingredients to cook a meal and follow the recipe. 
 
 virtual cuisine   |   Wolf Drawing Anime   |   Www 18girlonly Com   |   Girl Without Drees Poto   |   Candydoll Tv Photos   |   Libby Turner Forum   |   Game2girl Com   |   Sign In Games   |   Hot Mexican Bitches   |   Mobi Hot Info   |   Sixpicher   |   Indian Girls Feets   |   Mcdonald S Cashier Game   |   Hayden Panettiere Fakes   |   Shortskirtoops   |   Longhaircut China   |   Www 18 To 19 Com   |   Cute Indian Girls Feets   |   Www 18to 19 Com   |   Cute Girls Com   |   Free Top Dolls Net   |   
 Home - Submit - RSS - Copyright Disputes - Privacy Policy - Sitemap Copyright©2005-2012 Cooking Games.
	</body>
</document>
