<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005700" url="http://www.powells.com/biblio?inkey=6-1931686076-1" time="2012-07-12-22:17" support="5" score="0.012963319035913554" bingtitle="Field Guide to Stains: How to Identify and Remove Virtually Every ..." webtitle="Field Guide to Stains: How to Identify and Remove Virtually Every Stain Known to Man by Virginia M. Friedman - Powell&apos;s Books">
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000626" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>Staff Picks; New Favorites; Staff Top 5s; Indiespensable™ ... essence: Fruits and Vegetables, Sauces and Condiments ... cubicle, glove compartment, visit to the fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		All Books Used New eBooks 
   advanced 
 Discover 
 New Arrivals Bestsellers Award Winners Signed Editions Sale Books Daily Dose Indiespensable™ Newsletters Browse in... Children&apos;s Cooking Literature Mystery Poetry Sci-Fi&amp;Fantasy Textbooks Young Adult See All Subjects Audio Books DVDs Blu-ray 
 Used Books 
 Used Books by Subject Recently Arrived Used Newsletters Rare and Collectible Browse in... Literature Poetry Children&apos;s Mystery Cooking Sci-Fi&amp;Fantasy Textbooks See All Subjects 
 eBooks 
 eBooks by Subject Google eBooks™ Adobe Digital Editions DRM-Free PDF 
 Staff Picks 
 Staff Picks New Favorites Staff Top 5s Indiespensable™ Browse in... Literature Poetry Children&apos;s Mystery Cooking Sci-Fi&amp;Fantasy See All Subjects 
 Gifts&amp;Gift Cards 
 Gift Cards&amp;eGift Cards Powell&apos;s Souvenirs Moleskine Notebooks 
 Sell Books 
 Sell Books Online Sell Books in our Stores 
 Stores &amp; Events 
 City of Books on Burnside Bldg. 2 Cedar Hills Crossing Hawthorne Home and Garden Portland Airport See All Store Locations Events Calendar Portlanders&apos; Page 
 
 
 
 Don&apos;t Miss

 Save 30%! At Home and Away: Pacific Northwest Announcing Indiespensable #35! Europa Editions Sale: Save 30% Powell&apos;s Meridian App for iPhone and Android 

More at Powell&apos;s

 PowellsBooks.Blog Interviews | Q&amp;As; | Essays 
 
Recently Viewed clear list 


 Original Essays | June 28, 2012 
 Does God Go on Manhunts? 
 0 comments By Deanne Stillman 

More specifically, was he involved with the one I wrote about in my new book, Desert Reckoning ? Before I answer those questions, let me tell you... Continue» 
 $ 18.20 Sale Hardcover add to wish list 
 Desert Reckoning: A Town Sheriff, a Mojave Hermit, and the Biggest Manhunt in Modern California History 
 Deanne Stillman Deanne Stillman 9781568586083 
 $15.95 New Trade Paper Ships in 1 to 3 days 
 Qty Store Section 9 Local Warehouse Cooking and Food- Household Management 
 
 Receive an email when this ISBN is available used. 
 
Field Guide to Stains: How to Identify and Remove Virtually Every Stain Known to Man
by Virginia M. Friedman 

 
 Comment on this title and you could win free books! Synopses&amp;Reviews Comment on this title and you could win free books! 

 ISBN13: 9781931686075
 ISBN10: 1931686076
 All Product Details 
 
 
 
 
Synopses&amp;Reviews

 Publisher Comments:
 At last, a field guide to identifying and doing battle with more than 100 stains, from tomato juice and tar to avocado and urine! Field Guide to Stains is divided into handy sections for easy access to information about stain removal when time is of the essence: Fruits and Vegetables, Sauces and Condiments, Garage and Yard, Office and School Products, and more. But readers will learn more than just areas of occurrence, plus other essential information. A full-color insert features 100 photographs for easy identification, and each photograph is cross-referenced to the stain&apos;s in-depth description and step-by-step removal advice. This hilarious handbook is essential reading for everyone about to venture out into the wild, to the kitchen, or to a night on the town! 
 Synopsis:
 A step-by-step guide to stain removal is divided into such sections as Fruits and Vegetables, Sauces and Condiments, Garage and Yard, and Office and School Products, in a resource complemented by one hundred cross-referenced photographs for easy identification. Original. 
 Synopsis:
 This field guide has a sturdy, stain-proof exterior - making it a necessity for every cubicle, glove compartment, visit to the fast food restaurant, and college dorm. A must-have for everyone about to venture out into the wild, to the kitchen, or to a night on the town! back to top 
About the Author
 Virginia M. Friedman, Melissa Wagner, and Nancy Armstrong are freelance writers living in Philadelphia. They have been studying stains in their natural environment for the last 12 years. back to top 
What Our Readers Are Saying

 Be the first to add a comment for a chance to win! 
 back to top 
Product Details
 ISBN: 9781931686075 Author: Friedman, Virginia M. Author: Armstrong, Nancy Author: Wagner, Melissa Publisher: Quirk Books Location: Piladelphia Subject: General Subject: Cleaning&amp;Caretaking - Household Hints Subject: Spotting (cleaning) Subject: Spotting Subject: Cleaning&amp;Caretaking - General Subject: Do-It-Yourself Subject: Cooking and Food-Household Management Edition Description: Trade paper Series: Field Guide Series Volume: GTR-525 Publication Date: 20020931 Binding: TRADE PAPER Grade Level: General/trade Language: English Illustrations: Yes Pages: 352 Dimensions: 6.00x4.50x.98 in. .72 lbs. back to top 
Other books you might like

 $ 10.95 Used Spiral/comb add to wish list 
 The Bathroom Planner: Hundreds of Great Ideas for Your New Bathroom 
 Suzanne Ardley Suzanne Ardley 9780811831161 $ 4.98 Used Hardcover add to wish list 
 The builder&apos;s book of bathrooms 
 Andrew Wormer Andrew Wormer 9781561582303 $ 5.95 Used Trade Paper add to wish list 
 Bathrooms: Plan, Remodel, Build 
 Jerry Germer Jerry Germer 9781580111386 $ 1.48 Used Trade Paper add to wish list 
 Bathroom Idea Book 
 Andrew Wormer Andrew Wormer 9781561586004 $ 4.50 Used Hardcover add to wish list 
 The Fireplace Book: Designs for the Heart of the Home 
 Miranda Innes Miranda Innes 9780670893805 $ 7.50 Used Trade Paper add to wish list 
 Papal Sin: Structures of Deceit 
 Garry Wills Garry Wills 9780385494113 
 back to top 
Related Subjects

 Cooking and Food»Series»Miniature Cookbooks 
 Home and Garden»Household»Household Management 
 Languages»Foreign Languages»Spanish»Home and Garden»Household»Household Management 
 Field Guide to Stains: How to Identify and Remove Virtually Every Stain Known to Man New Trade Paper Virginia M. Friedman 0 stars - 0 reviews $15.95 In Stock Product details 352 pages Quirk Books - 2002-09-00 English 9781931686075 Reviews: &quot; Synopsis &quot; by Gardners , A step-by-step guide to stain removal is divided into such sections as Fruits and Vegetables, Sauces and Condiments, Garage and Yard, and Office and School Products, in a resource complemented by one hundred cross-referenced photographs for easy identification. Original. &quot; Synopsis &quot; by Libri , This field guide has a sturdy, stain-proof exterior - making it a necessity for every cubicle, glove compartment, visit to the fast food restaurant, and college dorm. A must-have for everyone about to venture out into the wild, to the kitchen, or to a night on the town! 
 
 
 
 
 back to top 
 Follow us on... 
 
 
 
 
 Help Security and Privacy Shipping Money Back Guarantee Newsletters Contact Us 

 About Us In the Press Partner Program Employment Green Initiatives at Powell&apos;s 
 
 RSS 2.0 Log Off Copyright©1994-2012 Powells.com Terms of Use 
 Powell&apos;s City of Books is an independent bookstore in Portland, Oregon, that fills a whole city block with more than a million new, used, and out of print books. Shop those shelves—plus literally millions more books, DVDs, and eBooks—here at Powells.com.
	</body>
</document>
