<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005510" url="http://www.floradelaney.com/tag/merchandising/page/2/" time="2012-07-12-22:04" support="2" score="0.0024668167831665864" bingtitle="Merchandising | Delaney Consulting and Creative - Part 2" webtitle="Merchandising | Delaney Consulting and Creative - Part 2">
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000147" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>Recent trends indicate that rate is hovering near 5 ... give them a reason to hate it when they have a credit card ... me a salad on a beautiful plate with a colorful napkin.</description>
	<body>
		Home 

 About Clients Offerings News Contact Blog 
 
Upcoming events

 
Document Links

 Assortment/Space Integration Building Multinational Governance&amp;Performance Metrics Integrating Space Management Creating a Sales&amp;Operations Planning Platform Building a Collaborative Supply Chain Re-Launching a New Business Retail Comp Sales History-february2012 Retail Comp Sales History-March2012 Supermarket&amp;Retail Mar 2012 KVIs Retail Comp Sales History-April2012 Retail Comp Sales History-june 
 
Articles

 All MN Marketing Joint Calendar No Excuses Marketing Scenario Planning by ROIG Variable Retail Resources in MN 
 
Subscribe2
 
 Your email: 
 

   
 
Tags
 Apple Assortment Best Buy Best Practices Category Management Communication Comp Store Sales Customer Service Investments Leadership Managing People Marketing Merchandising Networking Pop Up Stores Project Management Retail Consulting Retailing Apps Retail Technology Social Media Space Management Supply Chain Technology Implementation Trendspotting Visual Merchandising 
Google Adsense
 
Posts Tagged‘Merchandising’
 «Older Entries Newer Entries» 
 Matching Messages and Locations in Stores 
 Friday, February 3rd, 2012 
 The last post “Moving Marketing Messages in Store” talked about the importance of matching the marketing message to the right store location.  If marketing messages have one of these three main goals: attracting people into the store, making a sale in the store and building loyalty for a return visit ; the location of where the customer intersects with the message needs to match.

To attract people into the store you have three main locations: outdoor messaging, storefront windows and the front door itself.  Outdoor messaging can be a sign with changeable letters, a sidewalk sign or even colored chalk.  Depending on your brand’s “voice” you can be very business-like or fun and approachable.  Match your voice, the message and the way you talk to your customers.  The same “half-off all sweaters” message can be written on a scrolling LCD panel, posted as a limerick on your changeable store sign or drawn as a psychedelic graphic on a sidewalk chalkboard depending on your brand voice.

Storefront windows are the first test of shoppers.  The tone of the windows begins the promise of the experience inside.  You can place a sign in the window that says you have creative paper solutions or hang fifty folded paper cranes in different sizes and colors to say the same thing. Not sure you have the creative chops to do it yourself?  Hire a part-time local art student to help change the windows once a month if you are not so creatively inclined.

If your message is about making a sale to people already in the store, use ceiling signs and the counter to deliver the message. But beware of how your store space is used. This is the message area that is most likely to become cluttered with overlapping messages. Look at the store with a critical eye and always focus on only one or two crisp messages.  A sales call to action and perhaps a reinforcing loyalty message is common.  Beware if there are overlapping messages like a spring clean up sale, we carry your favorite brands, become a preferred customer, sign up for a service plan and a charitable event message in multiple signs around the store.  Rotate which message is primary and be focused.  Be vigilant in removing old signs by making it a part of a standard first of the month opening checklist item.

Remember that your sales associates are also a part of harmonizing your brand message.  If your target market is small businesses, a store uniform should probably consist of a button down shirt with an embroidered logo instead of a T-shirt.   Your store associates should look trustworthy and approachable to your target market.  Which means that a written policy on appearance and hygiene may be in order.  Reinforce messages with buttons or lanyards worn by your sales associates when appropriate.

For messages that are meant to build loyalty for a return visit; use your checkout, register receipts, bag stuffers and the front door (again.)  At checkout, there should be a pleasant exchange with the cashier that includes an earnest request to visit again.  Consider a counter mat that allows you to insert a changing message under its transparent cover to keep it up to date.  Here is where a customer is most likely to entertain an offer for a loyalty program, a service plan or appreciate the offer for home delivery.  It is also where you can deliver a longer message about community programs or sponsorships.  Have brochures or other marketing materials available to the cashier so that they can quickly give the customer more information if there is interest in a detailed program.  Use acrylic document holders to make organization easy and swift.

If you have a recent POS system, you can deliver changing messages on customer receipts.  Have cashiers remind customers of any offers on their receipts as they conclude the transaction.  Bag stuffers should either be calls to action for future sales events or reminders about home delivery or online shopping.

Finally, there should be a message that gives a customer a reason to return as they leave through the front door.  This is your very last chance to communicate the brand to a customer – so please make it more creative than “Have a nice day.”
 
Tags: Best Practices , Communication , Customer Service , Marketing , Merchandising 
Posted in Communication , Retail Merchandising | 2 Comments» 
 
 Moving Marketing Messages In Store 
 Tuesday, January 31st, 2012 
 Marketing may seem like it all happens outside the store, in media or cyberspace -but great retailers make sure their exterior messages are unified with their in-store experience.  It’s a disappointing slide for customers who have been promised “the widest selection” and then see a limited range of products or to quickly realize the “best prices of the season” are only on a couple of items.  There are some critical ways to make sure your store’s external messages are harmonized with the in-store experience.

Keep your employees in the know.  Each week, every sales associate should know the current key marketing messages.  It should be a topic of the weekly sales meeting (You do have one, right?) and a prominent message on the backroom message board.  Help store employees by integrating the current marketing message with “say’s and do’s” each week.  Sales and sponsorships should be a part of the front door greeting as well as the way the phone is answered.  Create a message that associates can feel natural saying like “Welcome to our store – If you’re here for our February Clearance Sale, all of our sale products are in this aisle.”   Stay away from things like “Welcome to our store where this week we are featuring a buy two get the third half off on every toner cartridge over $25.”  The same is true for a phone message.  Keep it short and helpful.  But make it clear that marketing messages are a non-negotiable requirement for answering the phone.

Match the marketing message to the right message location.  Think of marketing message as having one of three main goals:

 1. Attracting people into the store –this will primarily occur outside the store: in windows, doors and the visible area within the storefront.
 2. Making a sale in the store - these are the messages that should lead a customer from consideration to purchase.  Keep messages focused and updated.
 3. Building loyalty for a return visit –often forgotten, this is the opportunity to ratchet up your brand and make your store top of mind for future purchases.

Then match your locations to each message.

Our next Blog Post– Matching Messages and Locations in Stores –is all about the best practices for doing exactly that.
 
Tags: Best Practices , Communication , Marketing , Merchandising 
Posted in Communication , Retail Merchandising | 2 Comments» 
 
 Chinese Beauty Retail: Where the Manufacturer is King 
 Friday, January 27th, 2012 
 For all of the rise of consumerism that is happening in China, there is an astounding difference in the approach when it comes to beauty retail (cosmetics and the like.)  For the Chinese beauty care customer, comparing products across brands is simply impossible.  In malls, high-end beauty lines such as Shiseido, Clinique and Estee Lauder are separate stores which are usually – but not necessarily–near one another.  Comparing something as simple as mascara is impossible in this brand driven environment.

The same approach is true for everyday brands such as Olay, Neutrogena or Revlon in HBA stores such as Mannings or Watsons.  Each brand is its own section (sold space by the retailers typically in half meter increments.)  Let me give you an example of how this approach is purposefully made to frustrate customers and keep them from making well-informed choices about product attributes and price.

I entered a shop to purchase two things: black mascara and nail polish remover.  In the US (say, CVS or Walgreens) all I would need to do is head to the mascara section to see all my choices, compare the assortment to my needs and budget and make my selection.  Then off to the nailcare section where I would find remover in plastic bottles – probably underneath the polishes and near some cotton balls (a complete solution, if you will.)

In Hong Kong and China, I enter the store and find half-meter sections separated by brands.  Aisles are narrow and the stores are ALWAYS crowded, so taking time to comparison shop is difficult.  I must navigate along several aisles to see mascara choices by Maybelline, Revlon, L’Oreal, Cover Girl, and many foreign brands and try to remember the prices and attributes of the various brands in my head to make an informed selection.  Picking up one or more items in my hand will invariably mean that a store woman will follow close beside me to ensure I pay for the item.

What this means is that the “Customer is King” Category Management philosophy so widely touted by US manufacturers (I’m talking to you, P&amp;G) is mysteriously missing in Asia.  Lifting the veil off this Category Management retail approach, it is easy to see that the only barrier that sits between customers being herded into single-brand merchandising strategies and having an actual ability to make an informed choice is the retailer who stands up for the needs of the customer in the US.  Given an unfettered ability to merchandise their products as they wish, manufacturers would abandon the category approach to merchandising in a heartbeat.

For my associates who labor in Category Management and Space Management departments in the US and wonder if their work is meaningful, you need only travel to Asia to realize that your work makes a difference for shoppers.
 
Tags: Category Management , Merchandising 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | No Comments» 
 
 How Retail is like Dating 
 Tuesday, January 17th, 2012 
 I am not so old that I don’t remember the self-absorbed struggles of my dating years.  Enticing suitors, evaluating their worth and allocating time and resources spent may sound clinical–but it is a way of describing the dance of dating for singles who are looking for partners.  Looking back now with the wisdom of the ages (or at least decades) of life, I am struck by the parallels of dating and retail.

Why should someone pick me?  Building a strong foundation with a partner is first an exercise in discovering who you are.”Love yourself first”sounds trite, but let’s face it: it is pretty hard to love someone who is unformed.  Same is true in retail.  Until a retailer knows who THEY are, what they stand for and what makes them special, it is pretty hard for shoppers to love them.  So, dating and good retail both need good BRANDING.

Is this person worth my time?  How much time to invest in a partner that may never be a good match is a tricky decision.  Nice enough is not the same as Mr. or Ms. Right.  But for singles who don’t know what they are looking for, drifting from one person to the next is a track that can last for years on end.  Same in retail.  Retailers who create a target market that is too large or too small may find they never really mean anything to anyone.  Successful dating and retail then both need a DEFINED TARGET MARKET.

Can I date on a budget?  Dating is expensive.  Sure, you can stay in with Netflix and popcorn every weekend.  But that predictability will get tiresome and no matter what Hollywood says, a home made gesture is never going to stack up against a blue Tiffany box.  For couples to make things work, they have to know when to save, when to splurge and how to savor both choices.  Retailers know all about that.  Keeping customers happy with great prices on a few things and letting them feel OK about paying full price on most things is the great balancing act that separates the black ink from the red.  Dating couples and retailers need to SET SUSTAINABLE PRICING.

Finally, ask any woman who packs herself into a pair of Spanx before a date and she will tell you: its all about merchandising.  Playing up your assets may be a Cosmo or Glamour headline, but for retailers, it is a way of life.  Making those $19 sweaters look like they should cost $79 or shining up produce is second nature for great retailers.  Once the customers go home with their goods, we keep our fingers crossed that they are happy with their purchase and they believe they got a good deal.  Oh so true for dating as well.  Its all about GREAT MERCHANDISING!
 
Tags: Merchandising , Visual Merchandising 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | No Comments» 
 
 How to Value Slow Turning Inventory 
 Friday, January 13th, 2012 
 In Tuesday’s post “Best Practices for End of Year Closeouts” the first step was Principle #1 – Re-valuing your inventory. Sounds simple enough, but as you look upon the price you paid for the inventory and the hopes you had for its high-margin sale, it is often difficult to put a fair market value on product your customers just aren’t buying.  Here are the various“lenses”to use to look at the inventory you have and objectively value its worth:

 Elasticities: Highly elastic products will require a dramatic cut in prices to sell.  Examples would include sweaters at the end of the winter or Christmas décor after Christmas.  You will need to mark prices down to perhaps 75% off just to entice customers to consider a purchase.  Contrast that with inelastic products (like iPhones) which don’t require much of a discount at all to activate demand.

 Seasonality : If the merchandise is highly seasonal, determine when the next season of demand is likely to occur and determine if the storage costs outweigh the clearance discount.  Expect damage to a percentage of the inventory to occur in the transition and remember that labor and handling costs are not free.  Store associates who pack up and store product are not available for customer service and sales. If you received product too late to meet the current season’s demand, it may be worthwhile* but if the school pencil pack was in your store for the entire back to school season and did not sell – chances are it will not sell next year either.

 * Personal note: The ONLY time I would recommend storing seasonal product from one year to the next would be if the product had a very high value, an evergreen appeal AND was not in the store during the peak seasonal period this year. For example, a crystal Christmas ornament that was not put on the sale floor until December 21 might be a good candidate for storage.  But not gift tags (low value) nor a dated ornament (will not be appealing next year) nor the same crystal ornament if it was on the sale floor from November 15 – Dec 31.

 Basic Needs: If the merchandise is a basic need item – birthday wrapping paper, black toner, shampoo – there is an ongoing need for the item.  Excess inventory on a product like this is an excellent candidate for a promotional price – instead of a clearance or closeout price.  Slow but eventual sales may outweigh speedy liquidation costs.

 Technology Changes: If the product supports a technology in retrograde (typewriter ribbons anyone?) you may have an opportunity to keep the product on your shelves at regular cost if you have the patience for recouping your investment.  According to “long tail” theorists, selling products at the very end of their market lifecycle is not a matter of reducing price to incite demand as much as targeting your offering to the interested few who are willing to pay any price to stay supplied.

Keep in mind that it doesn’t matter what value YOU put on the slow turning product in your stores.  Only customers know the value of that product.  And if it’s not selling, it’s not worth keeping.
 
Tags: Best Practices , Merchandising , Supply Chain 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | No Comments» 
 
 Best Practices for End of Year Closeouts 
 Tuesday, January 10th, 2012 
 Try as you might, it is impossible to perfectly predict the fickle desires of customers when selecting assortments.  Add to that the churning lifecycles of technology like printing or cameras and your job as sales fortune teller becomes more difficult.  With the holidays behind us, you may have excess product sitting on your sales floor and tying up inventory dollars.  Here are good practices for moving out clearance goods from your store.

 Principle #1 – Re-valuing your inventory. This is possibly the most difficult transition to make psychologically as a retailer.  You bought a case of goods months ago at  $150– let’s say, planning to sell if for  $300.  Customers have not been interested in the product and today you still have nearly all that product on the sales floor.  Remember that inventory is not like fine wine – it does not get better with age.  If your customers were not interested in the product in November, it is highly unlikely they will like it any better in February.

At this point you must try to determine what price will move the products off your shelves and into your customers’ baskets.   Instead of thinking “I have  $300 or $150 worth of product on my shelves” you need to dramatically shift your view.  If the customers are not buying the product, you actually have a product worth  $0.00 and your goal has to be how far from $0 do you have to price the product to recoup some portion of your initial investment.  Actually, one could argue that non-selling merchandise has a negative value since every day your inventory is locked in product that is not selling, you give up future sales potential you could get if you could invest your money (and your shelf space) in more appealing stock. I’ll explore how to revalue that inventory in next week’s post.

 Principle #2–Merchandising: Clearance and closeout merchandise is an ongoing retail dilemma.  A best practice by most retailers is to create a permanent clearance or closeout location in the store with clear signs shouting out the value.  Examples include using a back facing endcap or stand alone display rack and placing a permanent  “Up to 75% off” sign over it.  Some retailers keep the bottom right or left corner of the category “home location” available for clearance or closeout product.  But gathering all of your clearance product together creates a “treasure hunt” destination for bargain shoppers in your store and generally yields better sales results.

Even if the product is marked for final sale, remember that it is still your job to make the product as appealing as possible. Half opened cartons, dusty or dirty products and broken goods create a negative halo over all of the product marked for final sale.   Even an item in pristine condition will look tawdry in such conditions.

 Principle #3 – Returns Policy: If your store will not accept clearance or closeout products for future returns it is good practice (and possibly a legal requirement in your jurisdiction) to publish this statement to the customer.  Consider at least these three locations:

 At the point of sale fixture On receipts and bills of sale Online and websites 

At the end of the day, your goal is to keep your store inventory fresh and compelling.  Once you see slow sales, take proactive steps to address any obvious issues: poor positioning, poor signage, non-competitive pricing.  But if the product is simply not of interest to your shoppers, come to terms with your customer’s decision and move quickly to liquidate the product and move on to something more appealing.
 
Tags: Best Practices , Merchandising , Supply Chain 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | 1 Comment» 
 
 How to Create a Pop Up Store in 2012 
 Friday, January 6th, 2012 
 I continue to be asked how clients can test and learn from pop up stores.  My earlier post Learning From A Pop Up Store had some good beginning advice for creating the strategy form a corporate point of view.  For those of you more interested in the tactical steps, here’s some advice:

First, decide if you need the store to generate revenue and profit or just visibility and buzz (say in advance of opening a more permanent location.)  Sure, it would be nice if it did both–but select ONE primary goal and you can make other decisions and delegate more easily.  A scaled down example is the recent Peeps store at Mall of America that opened with several kiosks in advance of the permanent store location.

The steps are the same as for a permanent store:

 Plan (set the strategy, timeline and budget)–Will this model be repeated? Find the location, complete landlord negotiations. Begin high level design, pull permits Define product assortment Define marketing strategy* (advertising, PR, Social Media) Complete temp shop design Define  and hire required staff&amp;security. Set training plan.  Security in a temp location is tough.  Don’t leave it until the last minute. Define payment procedure–how will you accept payment? Open, Sell, Close. 

Critical differences between a Pop Up store and a normal store opening include:

1* The Marketing is CRITICAL.  You only have a few days or weeks to make a BIG impact,  Make sure there is plenty of COMING SOON and buzz being generated before the opening.  Spend resources on signs and visual impact.  People in the area need to be aware that the store is opening in XX days and be ready to stop in once it opens.

2. For added buzz and exposure, offer products that are different from the ones offered in other classic retail channels i.e. limited edition, special series, product launch, special service.  Customers will have a reason to stop by and brand loyalists will clamor for limited goods.

3. Get your best and brightest sales team into the store.  A temporary store is no place for unexperienced  sales staff.  Determine how to reward them for being great brand ambassadors as well as great sales people. Traffic is likely to be difficult to predict so make sure you err on the side of over-staffing versus under-staffing.

4.  If your strategy is to sell a volume of goods, , make sure you have enough stock space inside the temp shop or in a nearby location.  Have a plan for a fast reaction replenishment process.   (I’ve seen plenty of operations like this running out of stock in a couple of hours!)

5. Finally, if you plan to get really good at this, consider contacting me about helping with the first store.  Not only will you get reliable guidance to avoid costly mistakes, but you can be assured that there will be documented good practices in place to repeat and succeed in the future.
 
Tags: Best Practices , Merchandising , Pop Up Stores , Project Management 
Posted in Managing Projects , Retail Merchandising | No Comments» 
 
 The Best Holiday Merchandising of 2011 
 Friday, December 23rd, 2011 
 Looking for ways to prove that I still really love retail merchandising (I really do!) I headed out into the stores this year looking for my favorite seasonal displays.  I really wanted something that would capture the vibe of Holidays 2011: gift giving that is anchored in value.  A quasi-retro feel that permeates most urban design that feels a little like a throwback to DIY 1970′s but still has the funky edginess of today.  That meant every luxe looking display was out.  So too the traditional displays, anything crystal, Victorian or high end.  Maybe it’s my locale, but Nordic was int he air this year.

I found the right look at the GAP.  Sure, their numbers are down, but the merchandisers at the GAP are getting it right with this happy palette of bright Christmas red, Fresh pink and Hanukkah blue.  Plus, the look was decidedly budget-conscious DIY. Yarn and Nails reinforced the holiday message: Joy It Up.  A call to action that is upbeat and tells customers they can create their happiness at the holidays. The look was fresh and still clearly focused on gift giving.

Here’s more, if you missed it.  Which retailers had your favorite seasonal merchandising this year? Let me know or reply below. 

 

 

 
 
Tags: Marketing , Merchandising , Trendspotting , Visual Merchandising 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | No Comments» 
 
 Retail Accounting: the Root Cause of So Many Bad Choices 
 Friday, December 9th, 2011 
 When retailers begin in business, there is one fundamental decision they all make when setting up their books: How will they report the value of the Inventory they carry?  In “Cost Accounting” the inventory value is the same as the cost paid for the product.  Profit is not realized until the item is sold at a price above that cost.  In “Retail Accounting” the inventory is valued at the amount it is expected to sell for.  It instantly recognizes the enhanced value of the product based on the expected profit upon sale.

In other words, if I buy 100 peaches for 10¢ each and expect to sell them for 25¢ each, my books may either reflect that I own $10.00 worth of peaches (in Cost Accounting) or $25.00 worth of peaches (in Retail Accounting.)  Both methods are used throughout the retail industry, are legal and have their proponents.

It may seem like a rather insubstantial decision for a retailer opening the company, but as someone who has been thoroughly versed in retail practices using both methods, I can tell you that the legacy of Retail Accounting leads to some very bad behavior.  Behaviors which at times are at odds with the best interest of customers and shareholders.

Specifically, when cost accounting retailers have old inventory (euphemistically called “Aged Inventory” in the industry – as if it were fine wine that somehow increases in value!) they mark down the product to find the point where customers will take the product home in shopping bags instead of disposing of it.  So my 25¢ peaches may become 5/$1.00 then 2/30¢ and finally, perhaps, 10/$1.00–at which point I am selling them at cost and basically making no profit on the transaction.   I may eventually have to sell them below cost, but that is a very rare occasion.  My margin rates suffer and I may not be pleased, but now that I have recovered my $10.00 I originally spent on the peaches, I can try to find something else that I can buy for $10.00 that my customers will pay me $25.00 to purchase.  In retail terms, I have freed up my  “open to buy” to acquire more productive inventory.

Given the same situation in retail accounting, I have very different financial decisions.  My peaches are worth $25.00 according to my books.  If I mark them down to 5/$1.00, I have to restate my inventory value by -$5.00 and show a decrement in value.  If I have to sell them at cost, I have to reduce the value of my inventory by $15.00.  In deciding to sale price my peaches I have reduced the value of my company because inventory is an asset on my balance sheet, whereas unrealized profit (in cost accounting) does not show up until it is cash on my income statement.  A decision to mark down the price of my goods will affect my profit rate in cost accounting – but that same decision will affect the value of my company in retail accounting.

It is a deep psychological chasm for most retail accounting merchants to see markdowns as a way to recover unproductive inventory dollars to redeploy on better performing inventory instead of a failure that will cost the company money.  Cost-based merchants tend to be much better able to test and learn from their buying mistakes and to see markdowns as a part of the retail lifecycle.  Retail-based merchants are nearly always penalized for marking down goods at the end of a season or moving out of goods through price reductions.

Over time, retailers who become immobile on this issue find their stores filling with stagnant inventory that customers do not want.  It may seem a generalization, but as a student of the industry I have seen this time and again.

My advice for any prospective retailers is to always choose Cost Accounting.  Your legacy company will thank you decades from now.
 
Tags: Category Management , Merchandising , Retail Consulting , Technology Implementation 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | No Comments» 
 
 A Shameful Retail Practice 
 Tuesday, November 29th, 2011 
 Generally I am proud to be a part of the retail industry.  It is a common theme of my conversations with people outside of the industry to point out that the competencies and skills required to be a successful retailer are as diverse and challenging as any other profession.  I urge our industry to actively attract the best and brightest from America’s business schools.  To be a successful retail executive is as demanding as leading any multi-billion dollar company in the world.  And a professional career anyone should be proud of.

But there is a practice among America’s retailers that I find shameful.

As any good pricing practitioner will tell you, the way to maximize profit is to raise prices to the level that you can remain competitive within the marketplace yet still retain your customers.  Over the past decade, pricing optimization tools and point of sale technology has advanced to the extent that retailers can tailor pricing zones to take advantage of those markets where prices can be adjusted upward and still be competitive to maximize margin dollars.

This is the free market in action.

So where can prices be raised and still be competitive?  Not in America’s suburbs where big boxes battle it out with regional grocery chains and miles of strip malls attest to a previously optimistic belief that growth would never end.  No, there is too much competition there and prices are usually very competitive to stave off dueling retailers.

Higher prices are tolerated where competition is thin and Americans have no other choices.  Look to the inner cities where grocery stores, Wal-Mart, Target and the rest will not operate.  Look to America’s small towns where the only other options are a gas station or a 30-mile drive to Wal-Mart.  Look at the stores within Indian reservations.  There you will find retailers taking advantage of the lack of competition to raise prices on those least likely to be able to afford it.  I am talking about Detroit, Harlem, East LA, the south side of Chicago, St Louis – all places where our sense of fair play should be outraged to learn that people who already have been dealt a tough hand must pay 50¢ to $1.00 more for laundry detergent, hot dogs, diapers and toilet paper than the soccer mom in the same greater metropolitan area.

I know why retailers do it: theft is high, distribution costs are high and with few other options there is no reason to run Sunday ads with deep price cuts.

It just makes me ashamed of my industry.
 
Tags: Customer Service , Merchandising , Retail Technology 
Posted in Retail Merchandising | 7 Comments» 
 «Older Entries Newer Entries» 
©2012 Flora Delaney | Website by Art of Rogue | Log in
	</body>
</document>
