<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005262" url="http://www.unitedwayofjacksoncounty.org/uwjc-blog" time="2012-07-12-21:47" support="1" score="0.0023486608085901274" bingtitle="Blog — The United Way of Jackson County, Oregon" webtitle="BlogThe United Way of Jackson County, Oregon">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>Hope is something a lot of Jackson County residents ... buildings, a convenience store, and a fast-food restaurant. ... The Day of Caring saw a major change as it was ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content. Skip to navigation Search Site Advanced Search… 
 Home Contact Us Site Map 
 
Sections

 Blog Get Help About Us 990s and Annual Reports Give Advocate Volunteer Advancing the Common Good Partners and Programs Emergency Preparedness Day of Caring Day of Action Funding Campaign [···] Women Living Leadership - WiLL News and Events Archived News Items 
 
Personal tools
 
 
 Home Blog Get Help About Us 990s and Annual Reports Give Advocate Volunteer Advancing the Common Good Partners and Programs Emergency Preparedness Day of Caring Day of Action Funding Campaign Contact Us Women Living Leadership - WiLL United Way Video News and Events Archived News Items 
 What&apos;s Happening... Cardio Bellydance Workshop 60 Crater Lake Ave, Central Point, Oregon,
2012-07-14 Lovebite Benefit for SMART Eden Vale Winery, 2310 Voorhies Rd. Medford, Oregon,
2012-07-19 FREE Family Night at the YMCA RV YMCA, 6th Street, Medford,
2012-07-20 Art for SART EdenVale Winery, 2310 Vorhies Road, Medford, Oregon,
2012-07-29 Restorative Justice Training Contact Mediatioin Works,
2012-08-17 Upcoming events…   home &gt; Blog 
Document Actions

 
 
Blog

d24b0a64525d2311ea7c42f67d2a960e
 
2012-06-01
 
 Sing-a-long 

A life of ease in prison he sings.
 


Wow. I was
driving to work this morning and I’m one of those channel changers of the radio
stations way back to my teenage years. This
morning wasn’t different except even though it’s Friday morning and I’m tired, I
listened to a song. It was on a
contemporary station. It was called “We
are Young” by Fun. Do you know it? I have hummed along and sung along, in the
car privately of course! And this
morning, I listened. Here’s the opening
verse…

Give me a
second I,
I need to get my story straight
My friends are in the bathroom getting higher than the Empire State
My lover she’s waiting for me just across the bar
My seat’s been taken by some sunglasses asking &apos;bout a scar, and
I know I gave it to you months ago
I know you’re trying to forget
But between the drinks and subtle things
The holes in my apologies, you know
I’m trying hard to take it back



The chorus of the song is “Tonight we are young. So let’s set the world on fire.
We can burn brighter than the sun.” Here’s
what I think. I think the chorus should be…tonight
we are stupid and violent. Why in the
world is this song popular? Is it
because the chorus is catchy? Is it
because it’s cool to still get bombed and stoned? It is because it’s okay and cool to scar
someone you care about? I don’t get it. Really it’s by a group called Fun. Someone’s messed up here and I don’t believe
it’s me.

I got
pissed off and switched to an old stand by for me, country music. The next song I hear is Old Red by Blake
Shelton. I like this guy. He’s cool, funny, good and seems like a happy
guy. Well here’s the opening to Old Red…

Well I caught my wife with another man
And it cost me ninety nine
On a prison farm in Georgia
Close to the Florida line
Well I&apos;d been here for two long years
I finally made the warden my friend
And so he sentenced me to a life of ease
Taking care of Ol Red



Charming. In this song the guy kills his wife, buddies
up to the warden and gets to take care of the dog. A life of ease in prison he sings. I’ve known some folks who did time and I have
say they’ve never talked about buddying up to a warden or getting to care for a
dog. And it wasn’t easy for any of
them! But I don’t know anyone who went
to prison for killing their wife, husband or partner. Maybe it’s different. I’m guessing not. The song ends with the line, “Love
got me in here and love got me out.” Guess what? Love doesn’t make
people kill people. These are popular
songs in two different genres. Really popular
songs. Seriously. Do we listen to music? Do we sing along? Do we understand what we’re saying? How do these things become part of the culture?

Onward, Dee Anne
 
2012-05-22
 
 Was it worth the doing? 
 
It’s been a remarkable week. Moving Day of Caring to May has afforded many opportunities including stress relief for United Way staff, more access to students because May seems easier than September, and it has opened my eyes in a way that they weren’t in September because of our annual campaign.

Watching Providence employees plant and nourish flowers and herbs at Lithia Place, a beautiful Living Opportunities development, was a site to behold. Was it because they were having fun getting dirty, planting a garden and building a gazebo? Nope. For me it was because they did it with people who live there. These residents fulfill Living Opportunities’ mission beautifully because people with disabilities just want to live where they want, do what they want, work where they want and even plant gardens with Providence employees! Sheer beauty.

Day of Caring volunteers painted, weeded, shoveled bark and gravel and sand and dirt, laid sod, painted fences, scrubbed and painted floors, cleaned a commercial kitchen and more. Each site was special in its own way. Women of WiLL (Women Living Leadership) were working at the OnTrack Home program helping other women become healthier. St. Mary’s students worked at Addictions Recovery Center’s Naumes Cottage laying sod so little kids have grass to play on. Teams from Target, PremierWest Bank, Regence BlueCross BlueShield, Chase Bank, Rogue Creamery, Wells Fargo, Harry&amp;David, US Bank, Rotary After 5, the Medford Active 20-30 Club, and Washington Federal worked all over town doing great things. Rogue Federal Credit Union employees trudged, toted and toiled (literally) at Family Nurturing Center. A special shot out to those individuals not associated with an employer who just can’t help but spend the day doing a great thing – thanks Doris and Shelly! And you’d think it was all in day’s work. Well it is but not without the help of a great committee, 300 people, amazing in-kind donations and deals from sponsors and incredible staffing. Special thanks to the United Way staff for working hard on Saturday ensuring volunteers had a great time, agencies got the help they needed and supplies were rounded up.

Earlier last week, three Crater High School students brought in money they raised for HOPE Chest. They learned about HOPE Chest from one of the parents and they needed to get hopping on their senior project. Michael reached out and asked if they could help. Really, can you help? Let me say for sure, you don’t need to ask if you can help! Just help. And Michael, Terrance and Jesse did just that. They raised money for HOPE Chest and they understood what they were doing and why. It was nice to be around them. They have plans. Michael’s headed into work. Terrance is planning to join the military and Jesse, he’s going to RCC. He’s the first person in his family to graduate high school, never mind entering college! They were amazing.

Is every day this great? No. Some days are hard and still worth having. My favorite question about our work is Goethe’s question “Was it worth the doing?” Day of Caring is easy to answer. HOPE Chest is easy to answer. Well, almost easy to answer. Does everyone we help get better? No. Sometimes it doesn’t work. Yesterday I attend Robin’s memorial service. HOPE Chest helped him. St. Vincent de Paul helped him. Jackson County Mental Health helped him. The Ashland United Church of Christ helped him as did many of the individual members. My friend Randy really helped him. And still, Robin died. Robin’s first attempt to commit suicide was when he was 5. And last Thursday, Robin died well into his adult years. He spent much of his time without a home, not eating, addicted to drugs and alcohol. And still, he was a bright light, challenging all of us to learn, to understand, to know it was always worth the doing. Of course. As Samuel Beckett said, “Fail once. Fail again. Fail Better.”

It is worth doing and thank you for doing it with us.

Onward,


 
2012-05-11
 
 What breaks your heart? 

I learned so much but one thing will stay with me forever.
 


What breaks your heart? Last week I had the incredible opportunity to hear Dr. Terrari Trent
speak at the United Way Worldwide Community Leaders Conference. I learned so much but one thing will stay
with me forever. There was a moment when
she was sharing a story about her village and she paused, her breath caught and
she held her hand to her heart. She
said, “This, this breaks my heart.” I’ve
never heard someone speak who could both break my heart and heal it in the same
speech. She did. She can fill your heart with joy even though
she was raised in desperate circumstances in an African village. She is the reason Oprah builds schools in
Africa.

Where are we willing to draw lines in the sand over what
breaks our hearts? What does break your
heart? I hope you’ll tell me because I believe
what breaks our hearts we can change. Did you know that the US ranks 30 th in the world in infant
mortality! How is that possible?! Did you know that 1 million, yes, 1,000,000
students drop out of high school every year in the US? How is that possible?! If one can’t read at 4 th grade by
4 th grade they have a 75 percent chance of being in prison? Seriously we’ll create jobs for prison
guards, construction, prison bed makers and more to create prison space instead
of teach kids to read?!  One in five
children in the US lives in poverty? One
in four is abused before their 18 th birthday? What breaks your heart? 

Sometimes we see the tragedy of places away from home and
feel the sorrow that is theirs because it’s safer than looking around and
feeling our own sorrow. The latest
Status of Oregon Children’s book is out and the data on Jackson County is hard for
me to look at. Here’s a snapshot:

·        158 babies were born with low birthweight.

·        696 kids were in foster care at least once in
the past year.

·        12 kids aged out of foster care.

·        56 percent, yep more than half, of our kids are
on free and reduced lunch at school.

·        51 percent of the founded cases of child abuse
and neglect were on children younger than 5.

Overall what’s worse? Infant mortality, teen pregnancy, uninsured children, abuse and neglect victims,
threat of harm victims, childhood poverty, child support payments, unemployment,
3 rd grade math proficiency, 3 rd grade reading
proficiency, early prenatal care, 8 th grade math proficiency, 8 th grade reading proficiency, high school drop outs, homeless students.

Overall what’s better? Immunizations, foster care placement stability, recurrence of
maltreatment, child care supply.

What’s unchanged? The
cohort graduation rate.

What breaks your heart? There are so many opportunities to help. But when we work together we change things. If you’re not involved now, why? Is your heart protected? Grand jury broke my heart. It’s why I started CAN (Child Abuse
Network). What I know for sure is that
we CAN change things not because we are able to, should, or must but because we
CAN! There is much to do and you know what, there are many of us! Let’s go!

Dee Anne
 
2012-04-16
 
 Guest Blogger, Diane Bennett 

We both won.
 
This week&apos;s guest blogger is a rock star mom, Day of Caring volunteer, former campaigner and still on the Board of United Way. She always makes beautiful connections be it in thinking about the holidays or in playing games with her sons. Welcome Diane Bennett...

I was playing the
classic board game Monopoly with my son the other day and &quot;United
Way&quot; kept coming to mind as I struggled to remain solvent through the
game. As I was setting up the game and placed the &quot;Community Chest&quot;
cards on the board, I was reminded of the campaign meeting which I sat in over
12 years ago and learned the correlation between those game cards and what was
to become the United Way that grew roots in the early 1900s. One of the
campaigners reminisced the days when she went door-to-door collecting for the
Community Chest. As I struggled with rent and went to jail on several
occasions, once after rolling three doubles in a row of all things, I was
noticing how real-to-life the game was starting to feel. I had just been on a
roll and now I was flat on my face. Fortunately, my mogul son was adamant about
not wanting me to fail. He lent a hand by giving me his &quot;get out of jail
free&quot; card and helped me pay my &quot;Electric Company&quot; bill. Because
of his generosity. Because of his very big heart. I was able to make it around
the board many number of times. We ended the game when I was a property owner
again and had some money from passing &quot;Go&quot;. I even got $25 from
&quot;Community Chest&quot;. It was a great way to end the game. We both won.
We all win when Diane&apos;s on our team! Onward.

 
2012-04-09
 
 Guest Blogger, Deelia Warner 

She had her hood down over her face as much as she could and something about the way she held her chin up but looked so sad at the same time just went right through me, I had to catch my breath.
 


Hi all! Welcome back! This week&apos;s guest blogger is a remarkable leader. Sometimes she still wonders why and none of us do. She brings her whole self to volunteering either through her community Cave Junction or to the larger work affecting community change with us. She&apos;s been a great loaned executive, campaign chair and now serves as United Way&apos;s board president. She&apos;s a remarkable woman. Enjoy her blog post and see how she makes sense of Living United! Here&apos;s Deelia...

Several times over the past few months there have been ‘aha’
moments when I’ve either observed something that touched me or interacted with
someone and I’ve said to myself, I need to share this. And I’m not talking about major life events
or anything earth shattering; no, I’m talking about everyday moments that
happen to all of us, I suppose, but somehow they were significant to me. So lo&amp;behold, here’s my chance to share after all…

 

I was sitting in my very warm car at the intersection of Crater Lake Ave.
and Stevens St. It was a particularly nasty, rainy day. A mom and her two little girls walked right
in front of me, the littlest one closest to my bumper looked to be about six. She had her hood down over her face as much
as she could and something about the way she held her chin up but looked so sad
at the same time just went right through me, I had to catch my breath. They
were walking as fast as they could in the rain and as I turned onto Stevens I
thought ‘I need to give that family a ride’ but they were on the other side of
the street and I couldn’t yell to them. I turned around as fast as I could but
it did take a few minutes and by the time I got back I couldn’t see them
anymore. I actually drove up and down
Stevens and Biddle to see if I could find them. Obviously they either caught a
bus or ducked into a business in the shopping center. But it really, really bothered me that I
wasn’t able to help them, it bothered me all day.

 

My daughter Nisha and I had spent a lovely day
together. We went to the Cheese
Festival, then we went shopping at the mall and she was really excited about
her new outfits and shoes. We stopped on
the way home to do some grocery shopping and as I was putting the bags in the
car, an elderly woman came up to me, excused herself, then started to explain
that she needed some help getting her laundry done. It took me a minute to understand what she
meant, but it became obvious she didn’t have enough money to take her clothes
to the Laundromat. This woman was
dressed very conservatively; she held her purse on her arm primly, just like
someone you would sit next to in church. I could tell it was mortifying for her to have to ask for money. She wanted to show me the laundry baskets in
her car to prove that she wasn’t making up a story. I thought, what a shame,
someone’s Grandma has to take her laundry to the Laundromat. Have you been to a
Laundromat lately? It’s not cheap or
convenient or pleasant in any way. Of course I helped her. She was so surprised that I would give her
what she needed, she told me, “God Bless You” with tears in her eyes and gave
me a big hug. I was speechless, it was
such a little thing. Nisha heard the
whole exchange and asked me how much I had given her. I said, “I gave her enough so she wouldn’t
have to ask anyone else for money”. My
daughter said, “You did a good thing, Mom”. No, I’m the one who was blessed, I
thought to myself.

 

And finally, last week I was in Portland visiting my oldest son and
grandson. We were at OMSI and out of the
corner of my eye, I saw a woman wearing a Live United shirt. I was tickled, and
pointed her out to Nisha, who also thought it was cool! I meant to go up to her and introduce myself
as a fellow United Way lifer, but I had to chase Jonah (my grandson) before he flew
down the stairs, and then I lost track of her. But how cool was that! It still
makes me smile.

 

I’ve heard many times (on the John Tesh radio show, no less)
that people who volunteer time and/or donate to charities or live some kind of
philanthropic lifestyle, modestly or otherwise, are happier with their lives
and live longer than those who do not. Well, I can’t say for sure yet about the living longer part, but I
certainly agree with the statement about living happier.

 

A few weeks ago, my fellow board member Jon Eldridge blogged
about the power we all share in our daily interactions with others. I echo his
statements about the community impact our United Way makes and I couldn’t be
prouder to serve on the board with so many amazing folks I’ve come to know just
a little bit more. And every time I bring Nisha with me to the Day of Caring,
or other UW events, I’m thankful I have those opportunities to show her that
the world can be changed, little by little. I hope she grows up to be someone
who wants to change the world, big and bigger!

 

I feel blessed to be part of the United Way family, and I
thank you all for everything you do, every day.

Onward...
 
2012-03-30
 
 Another Vigil 

The candles didn’t lose anything by lighting other candles, if fact candles sharing light create more light.
 


A candle loses nothing by lighting another candle. – James Keller

Last night I was at the latest, yes the latest, vigil in our
community remembering the deaths of the two latest victims of domestic violence. For me, it has caused many questions. I know so little about domestic
violence. For me, I see so much pain,
anger, and vigilance. And it makes sense. The quote above helped substantiate my own observation
last night that when it came time for the lighting of the candles. The candles didn’t lose anything by lighting
other candles, if fact candles sharing light create more light. I think people are drawn to light and putting
the tragedy of domestic violence in the light removes the cloak of darkness,
removes the veils of secrecy and removes some opportunities for domestic
violence to happen. In the light of day,
in public, we rarely see people striking other people. So why not? Why not make the light so bright and so shared that it becomes harder
and harder and harder still to be violent to those we supposedly love or more
true those we are attempting to control. Without the cloak, the veil and the opportunity, could we reduce
domestic violence? Could we? Let’s try. Dee Anne
 
2012-03-29
 
 Guest Blogger, Dennis Morgan 

Whenever you asked him how he was his standard reply was &quot;Never had a bad day.&quot;
 
Sometimes in the nonprofit world you&apos;re lucky enough to meet someone who cares so deeply about your work and has cared about it in every community he&apos;s lived in. That person is Dennis Morgan. I spoke at a 7 am Rotary meeting and he shared he&apos;d been on the United Way board in Las Vegas and been a dedicated IBMer to United Way all over this country. We met after that and since that day our organization has been blessed with a great board member with perspective that is rich and deep. And I have made a friend. Here&apos;s Dennis...

Doug was my best friend. My wife, Victoria, and I met him shortly after we moved to Las Vegas. We lived in the same neighborhood and shared many wonderful times together.
Doug owned a construction company and he was very involved in a number of community organizations. We had a bit of a game going for a while. He would get me on the board of an organization that he was involved in and I would return the favor by getting him on the board of one that I was involved in. Whenever you asked him how he was his standard reply was &quot;Never had a bad day.&quot;
Doug sold his company is 2000, bought a hay ranch outside of Ely, Nevada and eventually moved there. My wife and I stopped by for a brief visit when we moved to the Rogue Valley in 2003.
While we stayed in contact, we missed having some real quality time together. So, in January of last year Victoria and I drove to Ely for a visit. We spent a few days on the ranch and then we all drove up to the Cowboy Poetry Gathering in Elko, Nevada. We had glorious time!
There were numerous reasons to cancel or postpone the trip - the press of business and other obligations, the uncertainty of the weather, etcetera, etcetera. I am so thankful that we made that trip.
In May, Doug was diagnosed with t cell blastic lymphoma. He died in July just after his 61st birthday. As I was preparing his eulogy, synchronicity which often blesses me, provided these words written by Jack London that so aptly describe my friend Doug.
&quot;I would rather be ashes than dust! I would rather that my spark should burn out in a brilliant blaze than it should be stifled by dry-rot. I would rather be a superb meteor, every atom of me in magnificent glow, than a sleepy and permanent planet. The function of man is to live, not to exist. I shall not waste my days trying to prolong them. I shall use my time.&quot;.
Embrace and spend time with your friends and family. Don&apos;t let the pressures of the day keep you from the quality moments and relationships in life. Live and use your time!

Thank you Dennis!

 
 
2012-03-12
 
 Guest Blogger, Jonathan Eldridge 
 
Wow, our guest bloggers are rocking these days. If you&apos;re interested, give me a shout. We want people to share their thoughts about how they Live United! This week&apos;s guest blogger is Jonathan Eldridge. Jon&apos;s a great asset on the United Way board because he&apos;s a great thinker and he&apos;s in touch with young people every single day through his work at Southern Oregon University. Thanks Jon! Here we go...

Although I didn&apos;t
recall it, apparently a year or so ago I bought lunch on campus for a student
who was struggling to find enough change at the cashier stand. But last week I
was told that this student, now a campus tour guide, answers the question by
prospective students and parents, &apos;What makes Southern Oregon University
special?&apos; with this story. She uses it as an example of the personal nature of
the education and experience she gets at SOU.

I have to admit, I was a bit embarrassed for not remembering this incident. As
I tried to recall it I began to consider the hundreds of interactions we all
have each day--passing others on the street, greeting colleagues and friends,
making transactions over phone, email, in person. Every one of these
connections--even if only a seconds in length--can have ripple effects. And
while we often won&apos;t ever know the impact of our actions (or inaction), the way
we choose to interact with one another, however fleeting that interaction, can
have long-lasting effects.

I many not remember buying lunch for this student, but I do recall times in my
life where I was affected significantly by others and their words and deeds.
Our attitudes, prejudices, outlooks, and even our sense of worth are massaged
over time by these interactions. Sometimes we are told we can reach further.
Other times we are told, perhaps implicitly, that we can&apos;t. Collected together,
they all have an impact.

This is why I am so impressed and encouraged by Hope Chest, WiLL, CAN, YES, and
other endeavors here in the Rogue Valley that the UWJC fosters. While each is
an effort to make the whole greater than the sum of its parts relating to
specific community needs, their strength really lies in the connections they
make between people. Each of these efforts (and many others I haven&apos;t named
here) provide something concrete--money, awareness, education, etc. But they
also provide a platform for the caring people of the Valley to have pivotal
interactions. And every time someone receives the message that they matter,
that they are cared about, that they have worth--no matter how brief or
unremarkable the interaction itself may seem in that moment--we all benefit.
These organizations do great things by doing a lot of very important little
things--they provide countless little pivot points for people.

This is one of the many reasons why I am honored and humbled to be on the
United Way Board. And why I try every day to pay a little more attention to the
quality--and potential impact--of the interactions I have.

Thanks again! Onward,
 
2012-03-07
 
 Guest Blogger, Kent Brown 
 


Welcome back! Our guest blogger this week is Kent Brown. He&apos;s our second vice president and head of Rogue Valley Medical Center. Kent came to us from a United Way in Florida and has been connected to United Ways for many years. This is one of the really cool things about United Ways. People move around our country and are able to connect to community in strong and powerful ways. Kent is a great thinker, has a great sense of humor and at a recent board member raised money right there in the moment for racks in our storage room. He&apos;s an all around great guy! Here&apos;s Kent...

 

I was in Ohio
a couple of weeks ago. You might be thinking why would anyone go to Ohio in February?! Well,
that’s a story for another day but I will say this- having grown up in the
Midwest and not having been back in the winter for several years makes me really
appreciate how good we have it here in Southern Oregon. We are very fortunate
to call this beautiful corner of the world home!

 

So, anyway, I was at a friend’s home in Youngstown. In some ways, Youngstown
is like Southern Oregon. Much in the same way
that our area never really recovered from the collapse of the timber industry, Youngstown never really recovered from the collapse of the
US
auto industry. In both communities, the social and economic needs are great.

 

On the hallway wall in my friend’s home is a photo of a
billboard from a couple of years ago. The billboard shows my friend and four of
her co-workers wearing Live United shirts. Every year, she organizes a group of
co-workers from her hospital to participate in the Day of Caring.

 

I couldn’t help but think what a powerful influence she must
have on her daughters. When I was their age (yeah, I know, like a 100 years
ago!), my mother served as a role model demonstrating just how powerful
community involvement can be. I’d like to think that at least a little of it
rubbed off on me.

 

Whether you live in Youngstown,
Ohio or Southern Oregon,
when you Give, Advocate and Volunteer, you Live United. The next time you
volunteer, think about including a young person. Who know? They might just end
up with their picture on a billboard recognizing their volunteerism.

Thanks Kent! Onward,
 
2012-03-04
 
 Guest Blogger, Michele Jones 
 


United Way is so fortunate to have so many great volunteers and even two board members who used to be employees. Michele Jones is one of those. After leaving United Way, she went on to serve with Rogue Valley Manor Community Services as deputy director for many years. Michele is all about service and optimism as you can see in her blog. She wrote this last week before the cold and snow hit and still she saw signs of spring. Today, we can all see the crocus and the daffodils and also read this to catch Michele&apos;s remarkable enthusiasm. Thank you Michele....

Signs of spring are all around us with a few sunny and warm
days, daffodils ready to bloom, rose bushes budding out and, for those who are
baseball fanatics, it also means spring training.  For me spring means hope of better things to
come.

 

Hope is something a lot of Jackson County residents could
use. For people trying to cope with the loss of job and/or home, rising prices
on food, gas and other essentials or fighting addition, their outlook on life
may seem pretty bleak. My suggestion for
giving hope is donating money and/or your time and talents. I personally happen to do both. If you can afford it, donate to United Way’s
HOPE (Helping Out People Every Day) Chest, which provides emergency funds for
people who have no other place to turn to keep their lives moving forward. If not money, I would encourage finding some
time, hopefully an hour or two each month, to volunteer at a non-profit
organization. This could involve working
with youth, delivering meals to homebound seniors, being involved in the arts
or whatever awakens your passion. My
husband tells me I need to learn to say no more often instead of complaining I
don’t have enough personal time. The
needs are great and if everyone pitches in we can make a positive difference
and provide hope to those who need it the most. When a pebble is thrown into the pond, the ripples radiate
outwards. By touching someone else’s
life, your involvement will help increase these ripples. Besides, you will feel amazingly good about
your efforts and studies have shown that it is good for your health. 

 

So here’s to giving the gift of hope and to your own good
health!

Thanks again Michele. On to a new week...

 
 
2012-02-29
 
 Guest Blogger, Julie Brown 

... I might make the impact in their life that changes the course they were traveling on.
 


Welcome back! Today&apos;s guest blogger is Julie Brown. Not that one but just the same Downtown Julie Brown style. She&apos;s the general manager of RVTD and holds in her heart all those in need in this community. Julie is one special person. She&apos;s a former campaigner for United Way and today she serves as a board member. Julie Brown rocks! Here&apos;s Julie...

The one thing I find most distressing is there is so much
need in our community and so many times we feel lost in the shuffle. Recently my grandchildren brought it into
perspective. Papa and Grrrma (that’s me)
love to spend every extra minute we can with our grandkids. Just recently my granddaughter talked us into
playing the game TROUBLE. As we took
turns pushing the bubble and moving the pieces around the board I noticed our
Grandson (2 years) was watching. All of
a sudden he wanted a turn. Luke pressed
real hard but couldn’t get the bubble to pop the dice. He asked us to help and then when we told him
the number on the dice he picked up the game piece and moved all around the
board. All of a sudden we weren’t
playing the game by the rules but engaging in laughter and face to face
communication. Luke was so excited and
was yelling yea and clapping his hands. His joy and excitement was infectious and made me think that if I
applied this little technique to someone in need (a little laughter, some one
on one communication and playing outside the box) I might make the impact in
their life that changes the course they were traveling on.

Thanks Julie! Onward...

 
2012-02-15
 
 Guest Blogger, Charley Bolen 
 
Charley Bolen is our guest blogger this week. He&apos;s been an amazing, available and accessible and 
he&apos;s brilliant -- a great package in a board member. And he&apos;s a mean 
fence stainer. Welcome Charley...

As Dee Anne noted on the United
 Way website, this year&apos;s campaign has been
incredibly successful, especially in light of our current economy. As a
member of the United Way Board of Directors, I wanted to say
how grateful I am for the donations from our community, but I also
wanted to thank the volunteers who made the campaign a resounding
success. Without them, there would not be a United Way of Jackson County.

 

Before I joined the United Way Board, I would see the end results
of the campaign and I would be happy that the United Way had met its goal, or
disappointed that it had not, but I really had no idea about the journey
involved in the life of every campaign. However, since joining the
Board, I have seen how hard these volunteers work and the passion that they
bring to the United Way. Their dedication and enthusiasm is inspiring. They work tirelessly in
support of the United Way
and its goal of improving the community in which we live. Although the
campaign officially runs from early September through November, their work
never really ends. I know that they are not given enough credit for
the work that they do. I would like to thank the United Way staff, this year&apos;s campaign
chair, Marsha Billeci, her cabinet and every local employer and employee
volunteer for their time and dedication. What they have done this year
will truly bring lasting change for our community.

 

If you have a moment, please click on the Campaign link and view
the inspirational life stories from our campaign speakers. My hope is
that their stories will inspire you as much as they have inspired me. I
am so very proud to be part of the United
 Way and grateful that we live in a community that
realizes that when we reach out to one of us, we influence the condition of all
of us.

 

 
 
2012-01-04
 
 Guest Blogger, Anne Ashbey Pierotti 
 


This week&apos;s guest blogger is Anne Ashbey Pierotti. She&apos;s the new executive director of the Ashland Independent Film Festival and if you&apos;re not met her, you must. She&apos;s brilliant, a marketing expert, social media wiz and great human being. Being appointed executive director of AIFF allowed Anne to blend her avocation and her vocation. We&apos;re lucky enough to have her on our board. Here she is on gratitude.

Gratitude

 What an incredible year it’s been for our United
Way! As you read in Dee Anne’s holiday post, the accomplishments this year are
impressive to say the least. Add to that an incredibly successful campaign
which will exceed it’s target – and we are well positioned to continue this
good work into 2012. Way to Live United, Rogue Valley!

 The spirit of generosity and compassion that is evident
in these success stories is what drives my own involvement in United Way.
Whether through HOPE Chest or CAN, WiLL or Day of Caring, I feel blessed to
have come to know many of the individuals whose tireless efforts make this work
possible. Thank you for inspiring and educating me, and reaching a helping hand
to those in need.

 For my annual blog reflection, I offer this video
meditation on Gratitude from award-winning cinematographer Louis Schwartzberg,
presented at TEDxSF: http://youtu.be/gXDMoiEkyuQ . It’s worth
ten minutes of your time, and I hope it inspires you to make every day of the
coming year a good day.

From Schwartzberg&apos;s Ted talk, “You think
this is just another day in your life. It&apos;s not just another day. It&apos;s the one
day that is given to you – today. It&apos;s given to you. It&apos;s a gift. It&apos;s the only
gift you have, right now. And the only appropriate response is gratefulness. If
you do nothing else but to cultivate that response, that unique gift that this
day is; if you learn to respond as if it were the first day of your life, and
the very last day, then you will have spent this day very well.

 Begin by opening your eyes and be
surprised that you have eyes you can open, that incredible array of colors that
is constantly offered to us, for pure enjoyment. Look at the sky. We so rarely
look at the sky. We so rarely note how different it is from moment to moment with
clouds coming and going. We just think of the weather, and even of the weather
we don’t think of the all the many nuances of weather, we just think of good
weather and bad weather. This day, right now, has unique weather, maybe a kind
that will never exactly in that form come again. The formation of clouds in the
sky will never be the same as it is right now. Open your eyes, look at
that.
Look at the faces of people whom you
meet. Each one has an incredible story behind their face, a story that you
could never fully fathom, not only their own story, but the story of their
ancestors. They all go back so far. And in this present moment, on this day,
all the people you meet, all the life from generations and from so many places
all over the world, flows together and meets you here, like a life giving water
if you only open your heart and drink.
Open your heart to the incredible gifts
that civilization gives to us. You flip a switch and there&apos;s electric light. You
turn a faucet and there&apos;s warm water and cold water, and drinkable water, it&apos;s
a gift that millions and millions in the world will never experience.
These are just a few of an enormous
number of gifts to which we can open your heart, and so I wish you that you
will open your heart to all these blessings, and let them flow through you,
that everyone whom you will meet on this day will be blessed by you, just by
your eyes, by your smile, by your touch, just by your presence. Let the
gratefulness overflow into blessing all around you.
And then it will really be a good day.”

Thanks Anne! Onward to a really good day!
 
2011-12-29
 
 Guest Blogger, Sue Slack 

We have just concluded the holiday season. A season that offers much, but most of all inspires us to be generous.
 


Sue Slack&apos;s originally posted blog was incomplete. She is a real champion. She&apos;s willing to do everything from policy research to schlepping Day of Caring Materials. Thanks to Sue for this guest entry and now to Sue...

 

Throughout 2011, you have read blogs from my fellow United
Way Board members. The blogs are eloquent, inspiring and loving; just
like the people who write them. Before we look to 2012, allow me to thank each
of you on the Board for the gift of your friendship and the privilege to work
with you. 

We have just concluded the holiday season. A season
that offers much, but most of all inspires us to be generous. Regardless
of our means or beliefs, the holiday season has given each of us an opportunity
to be grateful for what we have and helpful to others. Now what? Several years ago, I found the words of Howard Thurman that seemed to sum up
where we go from here. It’s a poem about Christmas, but I believe it
applies to all of us in our human community.

The Work of Christmas

 When the song of angels is stilled,

When the star in the sky is gone,

When the kings and princes are
home,

When the shepherds are back with
their flock,

The work of Christmas begins:

                      to find the
lost,

                      to heal the
broken,

                      to feed the
hungry,

                      to release
the prisoner,

                      to rebuild
the nations

                      to bring
peace among the brothers,

                      to make
music in the heart.

 That’s a pretty tall order; it’s a good thing big goals get
met with tiny steps.  Everyday we can give a gift and take a
step. We can give the gifts of time, support, friendship, personal
dignity, self-esteem, wisdom, courage, kindness, love, compassion, shelter,
service, joy, laughter, high spirits, miracles and music in the
heart.  We’re all in this together.  Take a moment each
day to consider your gift and to appreciate the gifts you receive. A new
year is upon us, a perfect time to recommit to what is important.

I sincerely hope your 2012 is the best possible for you and
your family. May you all be blessed. 

 

 Give generously, accept graciously and Live United 

Thanks Sue. Onward to 2012.
 
 
2011-12-26
 
 Guest Blogger, Sue Slack 
 
Sue Slack is a champion volunteer. She shows up, the real number one test of a great volunteer. Sue is always willing to help with everything from policy rese

Throughout 2011, you have read blogs from my fellow United
Way Board members. The blogs are eloquent, inspiring and loving; just
like the people who write them. Before we look to 2012, allow me to thank each
of you on the Board for the gift of your friendship and the privilege to work
with you. 

 

We have just concluded the holiday season. A season
that offers much, but most of all inspires us to be generous. Regardless
of our means or beliefs, the holiday season has given each of us an opportunity
to be grateful for what we have and helpful to others. Now what? Several years ago, I found the words of Howard Thurman that seemed to sum up
where we go from here. It’s a poem about Christmas, but I believe it
applies to all of us in our human community.

 

The Work of Christmas

 

When the song of angels is stilled,

When the star in the sky is gone,

When the kings and princes are
home,

When the shepherds are back with
their flock,

The work of Christmas begins:

                      to find the
lost,

                      to heal the
broken,

                      to feed the
hungry,

                      to release
the prisoner,

                      to rebuild
the nations

                      to bring
peace among the brothers,

                      to make
music in the heart.

 

That’s a pretty tall order; it’s a good thing big goals get
met with tiny steps.  Everyday we can give a gift and take a
step. We can give the gifts of time, support, friendship, personal
dignity, self-esteem, wisdom, courage, kindness, love, compassion, shelter,
service, joy, laughter, high spirits, miracles and music in the
heart.  We’re all in this together.  Take a moment each
day to consider your gift and to appreciate the gifts you receive. A new
year is upon us, a perfect time to recommit to what is important.

 

I sincerely hope your 2012 is the best possible for you and
your family. May you all be blessed. 

 

 Give generously, accept graciously and Live United 

 

 

Onward, heading in to 2012. Take this week and reflect, rejoice and be present. Like Sue.

arch to schlepping bricks for Day of Caring. I&apos;ve never known a volunteer like her. And here&apos;s Sue&apos;s guest blog. Enjoy!

 
 
2011-12-22
 
 Holiday Greetings 
 
On this third night of Hanukkah, the day after Solstice, and
a few short days to Christmas, I wanted to take the time to wish you the best
of happiness, health and prosperity this season can bring.

It&apos;s been a big year. Many wonderful things have happened and we&apos;ve had some great success in
these times of great challenge. I&apos;d like
to recap a few of the victories...

We launched our first VITA (Volunteer Income Tax Assistance)
site at Harry&amp;David. Both United
Way and Harry&amp;David were given the Crystal Groundbreaking Award from the
IRS! We were awarded our first grant for
CASH this month from the Leightman Maxey Foundation and our coalition is
expanding.

HOPE Chest continues to fill a staggering need of emergency
assistance for rent, utilities, car repair, medical supplies and more. We now only take request the first few days
of the month because the demand is so great. HOPE Chest received grants from Anna May Family Foundation, Robert&amp;Frances Chaney Family Foundation and the Walker Fund of the Oregon Community
Foundation. Through HOPE Chest, we now
give away bus passes for 20 rides every other month to people in need. We&apos;ve given away more than 1,500 since
January. We partner with Jackson County
on the Access to Recovery grant for HOPE Chest as well.

FamilyWize Prescription Assistance has saved people more
than $283,827 in 2011!

Jackson County CAN (Child Abuse Network) has had great
success with raising awareness to prevent child abuse. We held our annual event in Vogel Plaza and
watch for next April. We endorsed
legislation against sex trafficking and 3 of the 6 bills introduced passed into
law! We held an early childhood book
drive in memory of Kacy Sue Lunsford who died of child abuse. This gathered more than 1,250 books for
children. And both the Mail Tribune and
KOBI won Oregon media awards for public service for our Don&apos;t Turn Away
campaign! Congratulations and thanks to
them!

Our volunteer base continues to grow and we have 150 people
help with allocations giving over 1,000 hours in the spring.

The Southern Oregon Meth Project is in its 5th year
continuing to raise awareness about meth -- not now, now ever!

United Way has become the distribution site for Medford Food
Project bags. If you live in Ashland,
Talent or Medford, sign up! It&apos;s an easy
way to give food to your neighbors in need.

We&apos;ve had lots of administrative success too, including
strengthening our staff, changing our fiscal year, amending our articles of
incorporation and bylaws, getting all new hardware and software (thank you
Meyer Memorial Trust) and more.

The campaign rocked! We are already at 89 percent. This is unheard of at this time of year and we&apos;ve received an incredibly
generous anonymous gift that will help us to exceed our campaign goal
significantly. Watch for more exciting
news on this one!

All this success came in a year when people we care deeply
for lost husbands, wives, brothers, sisters, sons, and daughters. All this success came when unemployment
exceeded 13 percent for a year. All this
success came when more people needed rides on the bus, food in their bellies, a
roof over their head and health care. All this success came because people saw the need, felt the need and
responded. When all else is stripped
away, we are our most present. There&apos;s
plenty more to do and many exciting projects well underway for next year. Join us! Not only is there room, we need you to make it work. So along with my best wishes for the
holidays, here&apos;s to a great 2012. Thanks
for the privilege of being here, working with you to create community.

Dee Anne

 

 
 
2011-12-10
 
 Guest Blogger, Rick Rankin 

Little did I know that I was about to learn the real joy that comes from being involved with the United Way.
 


This week&apos;s guest blogger is Rick Rankin. He tells the story of his arrival. My memory is not so different. At Loaned Executive training, he came in late. His head was down and then he began to learn, the smoldering started and by mid afternoon, the full flower was in bloom. Of course he&apos;d be a future chair. He&apos;s a dear man, willing to be real. This is his journey, his blog. A gift to each of you. Rick...

What a pleasure it is for me to
write a few words about what the United Way of Jackson County means to me and
how it has impacted my life since my first experience as a loaned executive so
many years ago. Up until that time, I really had no idea what United Way
was or how very special it is for so, so, many individuals in the
community. Like most, I reluctantly volunteered to represent my company, as their loaned executive, feeling very much like I had drawn
the “short” straw. What I did know however, was that part of my reason for
selecting Jackson County as our new home was because I felt like it was the
kind of community that I could become more personally involved in “giving back” through community volunteer work as a way of saying “Thank You” in return
for the gift of my family and the many years of joy that we had the
opportunity to share together. It did not take long for me to learn about
United Way and the breadth of services that the organization was involved
in. The more time I spent around the organization, the more impressed I
was with the many programs and services that are impacted throughout our county
by those who “give” through United Way. 

Just two short years after
serving as a loaned executive, I was asked by Dee Anne if I would be interested
in serving as the campaign chair for 2001. After getting over my initial
shock, I of course said yes and off I went on my continued journey of learning
about the so many more ways of being able to give back to the community we had
come to love so much. The more I learned about the various agencies,
programs, and services, touched by this amazing organization, the more excited
I was to have continued opportunities to “give back”. Little did I know
that I was about to learn the real joy that comes from being involved with the
United Way. You see, the real joy does not come from what you are able to
give, the real joy comes from what you are able to receive from being around
those individuals who make up the United Way of Jackson County.  Allow me to explain…..

United Way was not about what I
could give, but it became for me, a very personal journey of also how important
it is to receive. Two years after having been the campaign chair, in April
of 2003, I was diagnosed with stage IV metastatic melanoma, a very deadly
cancer, and was given less than a 5% chance of survival. The cancer was a
gift that taught me the importance of being able to receive. My family
and I were surrounded with the love and prayers from so many individuals that I
had come to know during my years of doing volunteer work for United Way. I received telephone calls, cards, prayers and visits from all over the
community. From the On-Track home for juvenile boys came video recorded
messages of hope and prayers from many of the boys that I had shared “fishing
trips” and barbecue lunches together. From all across the county
came support and prayers from my now very large family of volunteers and
agencies that I have had the pleasure of knowing and working together with for
these many years. I was amazed at the many visits at the hospital from my
“Day of Caring” working buddies as well as the individuals representing those
programs that we had volunteered to work for. The many telephone calls, cards,
letters and continued prayers that I received from fellow board members was
simply amazing.  I had no idea that so many people cared about
me. You gave me your love, your prayers and you took the time to tell me
you cared. 

Your acts of caring and the
sharing of your love and prayers gave me life. I know that I am here
today because God was listening while you took time from your busy life to do
so. As most of you reading this know, just recently, I was once again
faced with some difficult news regarding my health. And once again, my
United Way family stepped up and gave the continued prayers and support that
only can come from those you love and who love you. And once again, the
news looks great. Once again, you have demonstrated the healing power of
the support and prayers from family and friends. Once again, you have
given me so much. United Way will never be about giving. It will always
be about teaching me the joy of being able to receive. As we enter this
very special holiday season together, please know how much each of you mean to
me and how much joy you allow others to receive through your continued acts of
service and kindness. My best wishes and prayers for a very healthy and happy
holiday season and my heartfelt thank you for all I have received from you.

Rick Rankin

 
 
2011-12-06
 
 Guest Blogger, Raf Mesta 

As far back as I can remember, I have only been afraid of 2 things my whole life. One happens to be mice or any kind of small rodent for that matter.
 


Raf has been a United Way board member for a short time and in that time has taught me so many things. He&apos;s a remarkably honest fellow, engaged, inspired and inspiring. It&apos;s Raf&apos;s week to guest blog...

As far back as I can remember, I have only been afraid of 2
things my whole life. One happens to be mice or any kind of small rodent for
that matter. I know what you might be thinking. “Wait a second, Raf is a big
Marine and he’s scared of little mice?” Yeah, it’s true…and just thinking about
their little tongues and their little “squeak” raises the hair on my neck and
brings a shivering feeling down my back. I don’t believe this fear will ever go
away.

My other fear was there for a long time and after going to
war, it disappeared, but it has recently returned. I was very afraid of dying.
I would always ask myself: is it gonna hurt?, what happens after I die?, Have I
done everything that I’ve always wanted to do on my bucketlist? Then something
happened; I came very close to death from an explosion. Now, you might think
that it was extremely painful or that I saw my whole life flash right in front
of me…It didn’t. In fact, I didn’t feel a thing and from that point forward I
wasn’t afraid.

We would go on patrols, combat missions, rescue missions,
getting into “fire fights” along the way and I noticed myself not only become unafraid
of death, but almost to the point of not minding if something bad happened to
me.

I spoke to an acquaintance a while back and he made a
comment: “I guess you needed to face death in order to overcome it”. His
comment made a lot of sense and I truly believed it…..until now.

Again, I am afraid of dying. But this time around, it’s for
completely different reasons and those reasons want me to stick around.

Reason #1: Wife Mandy

Reason #2: Daughter Gianna 

Thanks. Raf

So what are you afraid of? Onward...
 
2011-11-29
 
 Guest Blogger, Jason Lukaszewicz 

Following Thanksgiving and as we start the holiday season, I am pausing to give thanks.
 
Welcome back from Thanksgiving. Sometimes our volunteers have dramatic reasons for being involved and sometimes it&apos;s less so. Sometimes it&apos;s because it&apos;s the right thing to do and because you&apos;re a husband and father and want a better community. Our treasurer, Jason Lukaszewicz, is our guest blogger. He&apos;s the strong, silent, tall type. He&apos;s a gift to our United Way. Here&apos;s Jason...



Giving Thanks

I do not have a great introspective blog as the past ones
have been. Following Thanksgiving and as we start the holiday season, I am
pausing to give thanks. Most of all, of course, I am so thankful for my
wonderful family and great friends. Thanks to United Way, my circle of friends
is that much greater. I am thankful that I am one of the lucky ones with a job
in my chosen profession, a career that has treated me well. As United Way’s
treasurer, I am thankful to all of those who worked so hard resulting in
significant growth in this year’s campaign, which will allow United Way and its
partners to have an even greater impact on the community. I am also very
thankful that Southern Oregon has an organization such as United Way, with its
great staff and volunteers who work so hard to positively impact the lives of
those in our community.

Thanks Jason! Until next time...
 
2011-11-14
 
 Guest Blogger, Doug Nash 
 


This week guest blog is the most honest, most trusting, most special I&apos;ve posted. I am fond of saying we all walk with a story. The glory of this job for me lies in being told these stories. Several months ago, Doug was asked to write and he couldn&apos;t find the time. The time is worth waiting for. Doug is a very special man. Doug Nash, United Way board member...

In writing this, I cannot help but think of my brother, who
died six years ago last month.

Five years my senior, Richard was a good person. He was intelligent and had a great sense of
humor. Growing up, he had always been
what one would want from an older brother: protective, caring, and there to
help when I needed it.

He was also homeless virtually all of his adult life. 

Richard had been very sick as a newborn and in his early
childhood, having suffered from various medical issues. Later, as a young adult, he was in a serious
car accident that injured his brain stem. The accident left him in a coma for about a week and a half. As with many who suffer brain injuries, he had
to learn over again how to do those things, like walking, that most of us take
for granted. His recovery was far more
successful than the doctors initially had expected, but it was never
complete. Among other things, for the
remainder of his life he walked in a lurching manner, with a very pronounced
limp. He struggled throughout his life
with addiction, and physical and emotional challenges, that were far greater
than most of us have to face. 

For whatever reason – the lingering effects of his injury,
the many demons that haunted him, nature or culture (and really, I’ve learned,
it doesn’t matter) – Richard couldn’t cope in the “normal” world. He couldn’t hold down a job or live under a
roof for any extended period. Untold
times he tried, and his family around him tried, to turn his life around –
different programs, jobs, opportunities, approaches. Nothing stuck. I will never believe that he truly “chose”
this lifestyle – at least not in the traditional, rationalistic, free-will
sense of choice -- but it was the lifestyle he was most able to live. For most of us, living and sleeping on the
pavement or in a park for even a day or two, let alone decades, is not only
hard to imagine but just plain too hard.  But Richard seemed to feel most at home when he was homeless. 

Obviously, this was also difficult for those who loved
him. Although he periodically would get
in touch with my parents, my other brother and the rest of my family, most of
the time we didn’t know where he was or if he was dead or alive. Family members spent countless hours looking
for him -- in shelters, on the streets, anywhere we thought he might be. And once he was found, the anxiety around not
knowing his condition or location was simply replaced with the challenges that
existed in trying to get him the help he needed.

For a number of years, Richard and I resided in the same
city: I, in a home, and he, on a street or in a homeless shelter. It was a big city, but not so big that I
didn’t run into him from time to time. Each time this happened, I was suddenly pulled out of my world and
forced into another. For example, on my
way one day to a job interview, dressed in a suit and tie, I glimpsed out of
the corner of my eye a disheveled shape sitting on the steps of a public
square. On another occasion, driving to
work one morning, I stopped my car at a crosswalk to let a person – whom I felt
pity for but initially did not recognize -- push his shopping-cart full of
cans, bottles and belongings across the street in front of me. Each time, it took me a moment to focus, to
realize that this person, unlike the vast numbers of homeless in urban America
whom we see, but really don’t see,
was my brother.   

When these encounters occurred, we would usually talk for a
while and perhaps meet later for a meal or a cup of coffee.  We would get caught up on each other’s
lives. I, as with the rest of my family,
would do what I could to persuade him to get the assistance he needed. Many times he tried, and many times he
struggled to change. But ultimately he
would return to his life and I would return to mine.

What most struck me about Richard was that he was always
willing to help others, even when he was the one who most needed help.

For example, for a number of years, he volunteered regularly
for a weekly event that used donated food to feed the homeless. Also, when one of my daughters, shortly after
her birth, became seriously ill and needed surgery, he daily, for about a week,
rode the bus across town in order to be with and comfort us in the
hospital. He brought us food he had
purchased using money he had saved from the deposits on the cans and bottles he
collected. We didn’t need the food, but
he gave it to us out of a strong urge to show his love and support. When he was around us for the holidays, he
would always make sure to have presents for his nephews and nieces.

A day or two after Richard’s death, my parents and other
family members visited the place where he had died. It was a busy, nondescript street lined
mainly with commercial buildings, a convenience store, and a fast-food
restaurant. On the sidewalk, we found
his glasses and his shopping cart, the latter violently bent from the impact of
the traffic accident that had killed him. 

We stood there for quite some time, alone in the grayness of
the street, trying to make sense of it all.  Then something magical happened. A number of people from the surrounding businesses came out to talk with
us. They pointed to the place, under an
awning, where Richard had slept during the last weeks of his life. They talked about what a nice and caring
person he had been. One of them, choking
up, said he had been the last person to have spoken with Richard prior to his
death. 

Later, we received a call from a man who said he had known
Richard in his final months and had read in the paper of his passing. This man lived in an affluent part of the
city. He said Richard had come by his
neighborhood about once a week, picking up cans and bottles, and that the
neighbors were so fond of him that they would save their cans and bottles for
his weekly rounds. This man also said
that Richard had befriended his young son, who had cried at the news of his
death. 

I think about these memories often. We should never forget that homeless people
are someone’s brother, sister, child, parent or friend. They deserve dignity. They are not at fault for their
circumstances. 

Richard taught me that there truly are no separate worlds,
that there is no other choice than to “Live United.” He remains for me an ever-present reminder
that we all have something to give.

 

 
 Next
 20
 items» [ 1 ] 2 3 4 
 Gratitude 
 Posted by Dan at 2011-06-22 15:09 Dee Anne,

Thanks so very much for your truly unstinting advocacy for those most vulnerable.

And, thank you for being the authentic, transparent, and life-loving and life-giving leader you are in our community.

Let&apos;s keep putting one foot in front of the other, trusting that our good intention and commitment to what&apos;s right will ultimately make a real difference.

Best to you,

Dan 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
   
 
 Give  |  Advocate  |  Volunteer  |  About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Site Map  |  Login 

 
United Way of Jackson County - 769 Spring Street, Medford OR 97504 - (541)773-5339
 site by netCorps 

 
 Powered by Plone, the Open Source Content Management System Section 508 WCAG
	</body>
</document>
