<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005300" url="http://ontario.jobs-open.ca/jobs/on-newcastle-at-3459-hwy-1589602-ontario-c-harveys-food-assembler-fast-food-8z8mc.php" time="2012-07-12-21:50" support="12" score="0.03774919350802698" bingtitle="Food assembler - fast food, Newcastle at 3459 Hwy 115/35, Ontario ..." webtitle="Food assembler - fast food, Newcastle at 3459 Hwy 115/35, Ontario, 1589602 Ontario Inc. o/a Harveys">
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000170" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>Bussing Skills: Clear and clean tables, trays and chairs, Replenish condiments and ... Shell Gas station and Harvey’s fast food restaurant. This job in no longer available</description>
	<body>
		Jobs Open


 
 

 
1589602 Ontario Inc. o/a Harvey’s

is looking for
a

Food assembler - fast food

(Cashier, garnishee, cleaner)
in
Newcastle at 3459 Hwy 115/35, Ontario
to start as soon as possible



 
Sorry!

This job in no longer available

 
 Terms: This is a permanent, full time job, which requires working days, evenings, and weekends. Shift work is involved.

 Salary: will be negotiated and depends on the skills and experience of the applicant.

 Education: The applicant should have some high school.

 Experience: is an asset.

 Type of Equipment: Deep fryer, Grill, Cash register

 Work Setting: Fast food

 Counter Attendant and Food Preparer Skills: Take customers’orders, Prepare, heat and finish simple food items, Stock refrigerators and salad bars

 Kitchen Helping Skills: Wash, peel and cut vegetables and fruit, Clean and sanitize kitchen including work surfaces, cupboards, storage areas, appliances and equipment, Receive, unpack and store supplies in refrigerators, freezers, cupboards and other storage areas, Remove kitchen garbage and trash, Handle and store cleaning products, Sweep and mop floors

 Bussing Skills: Clear and clean tables, trays and chairs, Replenish condiments and other supplies at tables and serving areas

 Dishwashing Skills: Sanitize and wash dishes and other items by hand

 Weight Handling: Up to 9 kg (20 lbs), Up to 13.5 kg (30 lbs)

 Security and Safety: Bondable

 Transportation/Travel Information: Own transportation, Public transportation is not available

 Essential Skills: Numeracy, Oral communication, Working with others, Problem solving, Decision making

 Profile: for 1589602 Ontario Inc. o/a Harvey’s 

Shell Gas station and Harvey’s fast food restaurant.

This job in no longer available

The contact information has been removed

Order Number: 5155353

Post date: 2010-07-19
 

 
 source HRSDC 
 
 
 
Please use your back button.
 
 

 Canada Jobs    WebMaster    About Jobs Open    Privacy Policy    Advertising on this Site    Disclaimers    FAQ.
	</body>
</document>
