<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005377" url="http://www.examiner.com/restaurant-in-dallas/wendy-s-turns-up-the-heat-with-its-new-spicy-chicken-guacamole-club-review" time="2012-07-12-21:55" support="1" score="0.001710175462580979" bingtitle="Wendy’s turns up the heat with its new Spicy Guacamole Chicken ..." webtitle="Wendy’s turns up the heat with its new Spicy Guacamole Chicken Club - Dallas restaurant | Examiner.com">
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="76"/>
	<description>Why don’t I just say fast food restaurant? Because there’s more ... Get updates on his condition; North Korea&apos;s missile ... Food &amp; Drink | © 2006-2012 Clarity Digital Group ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content 
Follow us
 
 Follow @examinercom 
 Examiner.com 
 Log in Sign up 
 
 Arts&amp;Entertainment Cultural Arts 
 Arts&amp;Exhibits Performing Arts 
 Music Attractions Bars&amp;Clubs 
 Nightlife 
 Food 
 Recipes Restaurants 
 More 
 
Wendy’s turns up the heat with its new Spicy Guacamole Chicken Club
 
 spicy guacamole chicken club March 31, 2012 By: Sandra Perez 
 Tweet 0 Email 
Get Restaurants alerts!
 E-mail * do not change Contact Email Contact Email2 Contact Url Subscribe to Blog Remember my Info 1 photo View the full slideshow » 
Related topics

 wendys Dallas restaurants 
 
Rating for Spicy Guacamole Chicken Club 
 5 Advertisement 
I’ve always thought of Wendy’s as a speedy, casual restaurant. Why don’t I just say fast food restaurant? Because there’s more to it than that. Wendy’s has some of the highest prices in the fast food business. I mean, you can get almost anything for a dollar at McDonalds or Burger King. The prices represent something though: quality, and sometimes, quantity, too.

Sure, you can snag a cheap meal at other locations, but that’s exactly what it will be – cheap. Wendy’s offers you great valued meals well worth their price, and that’s why it’s so successful.
 View slideshow: Wendy&apos;s 
Recently, Wendy’s added a new addition to their star menu: the Spicy Guacamole Chicken Club. Wendy’s invited me to try out this new club and I couldn’t refuse. I ordered this sandwich along with a small vanilla frosty, something I can’t help but get every time I visit Wendy’s.
 Wendy&apos;s Spicy Guacamole Chicken Club Photo credit:  Wendy&apos;s Location: Wendy&apos;s 32.858682 ; -96.768355 
When I got my order, I realized its long name suits this large sandwich. The size of the Spicy Guacamole Chicken Club is very generous.

Its generosity doesn’t stop there though. It contains a good amount of guacamole spread across its bulky buns, ranch dressing throughout, two pieces of crispy bacon, lettuce, a slice of tomato, pepper jack cheese, and, of course, a large piece of spicy chicken fillet secured in the middle. Prepare for a carnival of flavors in your mouth. While it is a bit spicy, you should be just fine with a drink. If you’re just not into spicy foods, or just don’t want to risk it, substitute the fillet for regular chicken, but you gotta try this sandwich out.

Wendy’s locations in Dallas price the sandwich at $4.79 for the club alone, and $6.79 for the combo. Worth it.

Try it out at your local Dallas Wendy’s restaurant :

4018 Lemmon Ave.
Dallas, TX 75219

510 South Beckley
Dallas, TX 75203

6011 Greenville Ave.
Dallas, TX 75206

For more Dallas locations, click here. 
 
 Facebook – Twitter – Email 

For business inquiries/promotions, suggestions, and more, email Sandra.
	</body>
</document>
