<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005068" url="http://www.wickedlocal.com/woburn/newsnow/x1551228246/Police-log" time="2012-07-12-21:35" support="1" score="0.0012411998926050852" bingtitle="Police log - Woburn, MA - Woburn Advocate" webtitle="Police log - Woburn, MA - Woburn Advocate">
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="65"/>
	<description>... with a credit card. 9:29 p.m., Montvale Avenue, Civil matter. A woman reported she was asked to leave a fast food restaurant because ... m., Rumford Park ... their unlocked cars ...</description>
	<body>
		Search our print archives» 
 Jobs 
 Homes 
 Cars 
 Classifieds 
 Subscribe 
 Deals 
 Ads 
 Homepage News Opinions Sports Lifestyle Entertainment Obituaries Multimedia City Info Community Blogs 
 
 Calendar Submit your news Facebook Twitter Apps Email alerts Contact Us Photo Reprints 

 Police and Fire Politics Business Education Police&amp;Fire Scanner 

 Religion Seniors Health Food 

 Photos Videos 

 School Info City Info History Organizations Government 
 HOT LINKS Police&amp;Fire Scanner Election 2012 Reader callout 
 Send us photos of your favorite car 
 
Police log
 By Anonymous GateHouse News Service Posted Oct 04, 2010 @ 03:34 PM 
 
 Woburn, MA— 
Saturday, Sept. 11

 12:58 p.m., Stoddard Street, Larceny over $250. A man reported his wallet containing $550 was taken from the night stand of his bedroom.

Monday, Sept. 13

 5:22 a.m., Wheeling Avenue, Larceny from truck. A man reported the theft of a catalytic converter from his work truck.

 12:57 p.m., Wheeling Avenue, Taking and stealing motor vehicle parts. Another man reported the catalytic converter had been cut off and stolen from his work truck.

 9:40 p.m., Locust Street, Domestic incident. Police responded to a verbal dispute between husband and wife.

 11:57 p.m., Cambridge Road, Larceny from person. A man reported a friend took $400 from him and ran away.

Tuesday, Sept. 14

 12:13 a.m., Kilby Street, Domestic incident. Police responded to a verbal dispute between husband and wife.

 12:49 p.m., Main Street, Credit card fraud over $250. A woman reported someone stole her wallet and made a fraudulent purchase with a credit card.

 9:29 p.m., Montvale Avenue, Civil matter. A woman reported she was asked to leave a fast food restaurant because she had her service dog with her.

Wednesday, Sept. 15

 11:49 a.m., Salem Street, Breaking and entering a building in the daytime, larceny over $250. A man reported someone broke into his apartment and stole a laptop and cell phone.

 11:51 p.m., Middlesex Canal Park, Assist citizen. Police responded to a call from a woman who said her friend’s former boyfriend would not let them leave an establishment without taking her with him.

Thursday, Sept. 16

 4:42 a.m., Rumford Park Avenue, Breaking and entering a vehicle in the nighttime. A couple reported someone broke into their unlocked cars overnight and took $30 and a stereo.

 7:44 a.m., Highet Avenue, Larceny under $250. A woman reported someone stole a GPS from her car.

 8:24 a.m., Quail Run, Larceny over $250. A maintenance supervisor reported someone stole a $6,000 utility cart.

 12:32 p.m., Lexington Street, Malicious damage to motor vehicle. A woman reported someone sprayed a white substance on her vehicle while it was parked in the lot of her residence.

 1:29 p.m., School Street, Harassment. A man reported being harassed by neighbors over his dogs.

Friday, Sept. 17

 12:41 p.m., Garden Terrace, Breaking and entering a vehicle in the nighttime. A man reported someone stole his cell phone from his vehicle overnight.

 1:49 p.m., Commerce Way, Domestic incident. Police responded to a dispute between a man and his former girlfriend.

Saturday, Sept. 18

 12:07 a.m., Montvale Avenue, Domestic incident. Police assisted a woman who had had a verbal dispute with her boyfriend.
 
Saturday, Sept. 11

 12:58 p.m., Stoddard Street, Larceny over $250. A man reported his wallet containing $550 was taken from the night stand of his bedroom.

Monday, Sept. 13

 5:22 a.m., Wheeling Avenue, Larceny from truck. A man reported the theft of a catalytic converter from his work truck.

 12:57 p.m., Wheeling Avenue, Taking and stealing motor vehicle parts. Another man reported the catalytic converter had been cut off and stolen from his work truck.

 9:40 p.m., Locust Street, Domestic incident. Police responded to a verbal dispute between husband and wife.

 11:57 p.m., Cambridge Road, Larceny from person. A man reported a friend took $400 from him and ran away.

Tuesday, Sept. 14

 12:13 a.m., Kilby Street, Domestic incident. Police responded to a verbal dispute between husband and wife.

 12:49 p.m., Main Street, Credit card fraud over $250. A woman reported someone stole her wallet and made a fraudulent purchase with a credit card.

 9:29 p.m., Montvale Avenue, Civil matter. A woman reported she was asked to leave a fast food restaurant because she had her service dog with her.

Wednesday, Sept. 15

 11:49 a.m., Salem Street, Breaking and entering a building in the daytime, larceny over $250. A man reported someone broke into his apartment and stole a laptop and cell phone.

 11:51 p.m., Middlesex Canal Park, Assist citizen. Police responded to a call from a woman who said her friend’s former boyfriend would not let them leave an establishment without taking her with him.

Thursday, Sept. 16

 4:42 a.m., Rumford Park Avenue, Breaking and entering a vehicle in the nighttime. A couple reported someone broke into their unlocked cars overnight and took $30 and a stereo.

 7:44 a.m., Highet Avenue, Larceny under $250. A woman reported someone stole a GPS from her car.

 8:24 a.m., Quail Run, Larceny over $250. A maintenance supervisor reported someone stole a $6,000 utility cart.

 12:32 p.m., Lexington Street, Malicious damage to motor vehicle. A woman reported someone sprayed a white substance on her vehicle while it was parked in the lot of her residence.

 1:29 p.m., School Street, Harassment. A man reported being harassed by neighbors over his dogs.

Friday, Sept. 17

 12:41 p.m., Garden Terrace, Breaking and entering a vehicle in the nighttime. A man reported someone stole his cell phone from his vehicle overnight.

 1:49 p.m., Commerce Way, Domestic incident. Police responded to a dispute between a man and his former girlfriend.

Saturday, Sept. 18

 12:07 a.m., Montvale Avenue, Domestic incident. Police assisted a woman who had had a verbal dispute with her boyfriend.

 8:38 a.m., Warren Avenue, Larceny. A woman reported someone stole a lawn ornament from her yard.

 11:34 a.m., Montvale Road, Larceny under $250. Another woman reported someone stole a lawn ornament from her yard.

 10:22 p.m., High Street, Disturbance. Police responded to a house party where teens were drinking alcohol.

Sunday, Sept. 19

 8:48 a.m., Commerce Way, Larceny over $250. A woman reported someone stole her iPhone from her shopping cart while she was shopping.

 12:15 p.m., Edgehill Road, Breaking and entering a building in the daytime, larceny over $250, uttering a false check. A couple reported someone stole checks from their checkbook and fraudulently cashed one for $300.

 1:02 p.m., Mishawum Road, Larceny under $250. A couple reported someone stole the wife’s wallet while they were at a restaurant and made fraudulent charges with a credit card.

 1:48 p.m., Day Circle, Assist citizen. A man reported someone shot a hole in his screen with a BB gun.

 8:13 p.m., Fowle Street, Disturbance. Police responded to an incident where an apparently intoxicated man said he’d been beaten.

 10:21 p.m., Main Street, Armed and masked robbery. Police responded to a convenience store robbery where a white male about 30 years old with a shaved head presented a knife and demanded money.

Monday, Sept. 20

 12:34 a.m., Willow Street, Disturbance. Police responded to a dispute between an estranged man and wife.

 12:06 p.m., Main Street, Larceny over $250. Gas station employees reported the theft of cash from a cash register.

 1:14 p.m., Washington Street, Vandalism. The city building inspector reported all the windows of a former car dealership had been smashed out.

 2:57 p.m., Central Street, Vandalism. A groundskeeper at a cemetery reported vandalism to grave markers and the cemetery lawn.

 7:05 p.m., Cabot Road, Identity fraud. A man reported someone fraudulently used his identity at a veterinary hospital.

Tuesday, Sept. 21

 12:53 p.m., Salem Street, Criminal harassment. Police responded to a dispute between neighbors.

 1:29 p.m., Gill Street, Larceny over $250, malicious damage to motor vehicle. A man reported someone sawed off and stole the catalytic converter from his vehicle.

 3:36 p.m., Montvale Avenue, Robbery. A woman reported a male presented a gun and robbed her of her purse and its contents, including $300, while she was waiting at a bus stop.

 10:47 p.m., Federal Street, Armed robbery. A woman reported a man with a gun approached her as she was leaving a club and demanded her purse.

 11:10 p.m., North Warren Street, Armed and masked robbery. A woman reported a masked man approached her with a gun as she was getting into her vehicle and demanded her purse but she scared him off when she beeped her car horn.

Wednesday, Sept. 22

 9:46 a.m., Presidential Way, Malicious damage to motor vehicle. A woman reported someone keyed her car.

 3:51 p.m., Spring Court Extension, Identity fraud. A woman reported the use of her identity information for fraudulent purposes.

 11:40 p.m., Lexington Street, Disturbance. Police responded to a dispute between a property owner and another man over his property being toilet-papered.

Thursday, Sept. 23

 11:11 a.m., Main Street, Suspicious activity. Police responded to a verbal dispute between a man and a woman.

 2:03 p.m., Richardson Street, Criminal harassment. A woman reported unwanted calls on her cell phone from a blocked number.

Friday, Sept. 24

 6:42 a.m., Lexington Street, Larceny over $250. A car dealership service manager reported the theft of four tires from the property.

Saturday, Sept. 25

 10:15 a.m., App Court, Criminal harassment. A woman reported unwanted visits from neighbors.

 7:16 p.m., Prospect Street, Malicious damage to motor vehicle. A man reported someone smashed the windshield of a company truck.

Sunday, Sept. 26

 9:52 a.m., Elm Street, Malicious destruction of property under $250. A couple reported someone egged their vehicle.

For this week&apos;s arrests, pick up a copy of the Woburn Advocate.
 Next  » 1 | 2 | 3 Copyright 2010 Woburn Advocate. Some rights reserved 
Popular Videos
 Shark Steals Woman&apos;s Catch Penn State Students, Alumni Wary of Report Tom Cruise May Sue National Enquirer Over &quot;Monster&quot; Story Pulling a rock from a tragedy Kim K. Shares Racy, Unretouched Pic Fowl Problem at the OKC National Memorial Loading commenting interface... Comments Thank you for the abuse report. We will review the report and take appropriate action. Loading comments... Site Services • Submit Your News • Archives • Subscribe Market Place • Find Woburn jobs • Homes • Cars • Classifieds • Coupons • Woburn Business Directory Community Info • City of Woburn infomration • Woburn Public Schools • Woburn Historical Society • Woburn Public Library • Woburn Senior Center Organizations • Woburn Business Association • Woburn Historical Society • Woburn Kiwanis Club • Woburn Host Lions Club • Woburn Breakfast Lions Club • Woburn Middlesex Lions Club • Woburn Lodge of Elks • Social Capital Inc. Sports • Woburn High sports schedule • Woburn youth hockey • Bob Hurkett&apos;s photos Public safety • Woburn Police Department • Woburn Fire Deparment • Woburn Board of Health • Woburn Department of Public Works 
 Contact us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service |

Woburn Advocate |
 Woburn, MA 01801

Copyright©2006-2012 GateHouse Media, Inc. Some Rights Reserved.

Original content available for non-commercial use under a Creative Commons license, except where noted.
 Advertiser profiles | Cherrp Local | Woburn Real estate | Find your Wicked Local Town | Internet Marketing by Propel Marketing | RadarFrog
	</body>
</document>
