<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005295" url="http://www.websitebabble.com/ideas-topic-choice-brainstorming-before-you-begin/13632-fast-food-menu-item-prices.html" time="2012-07-12-21:50" support="1" score="0.0019034737709553756" bingtitle="Fast Food Menu-Item Prices - Website Babble Webmaster Forums" webtitle="Fast Food Menu-Item Prices">
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>... never list the prices for the items on their menu? ... gain the info they are looking for (specific fast-food restaurant ... Other Contextual Ad Programs; Accepting Payments (PayPal ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 Website Babble Moderators:
James of Douglas County Master Gardeners 
TechieGuy of Technically Easy 
Scott (k2zs) of k2zs.com 
 Home 
 New Posts FAQ Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 Today&apos;s Posts View Site Leaders 
 
 What&apos;s New? Posting Guidelines&amp;Forum Help Top Posters 2 Create a Website Blog 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum Creating a Website Ideas, Topic Choice&amp;Brainstorming (Before You Begin) Fast Food Menu-Item Prices 
 
 
 
 Welcome! Website Babble is a friendly place for discussion, learning and help. Watch a video tutorial on how to join and use this forum .

By joining WB you understand that promoting your site is not allowed and you will be banned if you are caught spamming or posting links to your site. Please register first so you can post. All new member posts are moderated. 
 Results 1 to 3 of 3 
Thread: Fast Food Menu-Item Prices 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Email this Page… Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 05-31-2010,  10:55 PM #1 xmjm924x 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Junior Babbler Join Date Jan 2009 Posts 17 
 Fast Food Menu-Item Prices
 Have you ever noticed that Fast Food websites never list the prices for the items on their menu? How about creating a website that lists all the most current, up-to-date prices for the menu-items of various fast food chains?

Example:

John wants to know how much a Big Mac from McDonald&apos;s costs. He goes to their website to find out the price, but is dissapointed to find that the price for a Big Mac is not listed. John goes to google and types in,&quot;How much does a Big Mac cost?&quot;. The first hit that comes up is my site. He clicks on it and navigates to the McDonald&apos;s page within my site. He scrolls down the page to find that a Big Mac costs $3.95.

How is a commission earned? Let&apos;s say that while wandering my site, John notices an ad for,&quot;Suzan&apos;s Healthy Gourmet&quot;. He is curious as to what Suzan&apos;s Healthy Gourmet is all about and he decides to click on the ad, thus earning me a small commission. I could have ads for various different food services or businesses throughout my site.

The reason why this site could potentially earn so much traffic is because of the fact that an enormous amount of people are curious about fast-food prices for various chains throughout the country, and they use the internet as a means to try and gain the info they are looking for (specific fast-food restaurant prices).

I hope this summary was easily understandable. If not, please let me know what you are confused about.

Thanks! Last edited by xmjm924x; 05-31-2010 at 11:35 PM . Reply With Quote 10-15-2010,  01:44 AM #2 bairsmith 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Visit Homepage 
 Junior Babbler Join Date Oct 2010 Posts 1 
 
 Ya, I noticed as above mention that there are a number of sites which not display menu prices, I am also love to eat food but sometimes i can not got the right prices on net. last time i visited the website named venetispizza.com for the online ordering of pizza and i got quick and best services from them. It is situated in Vancouver and in Vancouver pizza is more popular than other fast foods. Reply With Quote 10-16-2010,  11:50 PM #3 nickywilliam 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Junior Babbler Join Date Oct 2010 Posts 24 
 
 Yeah! i also observe other fast food that they didn&apos;t put the price of the food on their menu but it has not a big deal to me all i want and expect that their food will make my day complete because i really love eating. Reply With Quote 
 Quick Navigation Ideas, Topic Choice&amp;Brainstorming (Before You Begin) Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums Welcome, Archives&amp;More 
 New Member Welcome&amp;Forum Announcements The Learning Center (WB Archive) 
 Topic Choice&amp;Brainstorming Archive Web Design&amp;Code Archive Blogging Archive Google AdSense Archive Making Money Online Archive Traffic Help (and SEO) Archive Content, Copyright&amp;Legal Archive 
 The Website Babble Lounge Website Success Stories 
 Creating a Website 
 Ideas, Topic Choice&amp;Brainstorming (Before You Begin) Domain Names Web Hosting Web Design&amp;Development Software (Including CMS) Custom Design/Code Work Requests - Contest Forum HTML, PHP, CSS, Javascript&amp;Coding/Programming Topics Tutorial Town (Code Tutorials and How-To&apos;s) Uploading Files / FTP Images/Graphics, Photos, Music&amp;Video (YouTube, Vimeo, etc.) Blogging&amp;RSS (WordPress, Blogger, etc.) Site Build It! (SBI!) Discussion Site Reviews The Content Corner Creating Forums&amp;Social Networking/Media Sites Miscellaneous Questions and Discussions 
 Website Promotion 
 General Promotion Topics Search Engine Optimization (SEO)&amp;Directories Social Media, Forums, Bookmarking (Twitter, Facebook, Digg, etc.) Link Development / Popularity Pay Per Click Advertising (PPC) AdWords, MSN AdCenter, etc. 
 Making Money 
 General Money Making Topics Affiliate Programs&amp;Affiliate Marketing Hard Goods (Online Stores), E-Goods (e-Books, etc.) AdSense, AdBrite, Kontera&amp;Other Contextual Ad Programs Accepting Payments (PayPal, etc.) 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts   
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On [VIDEO] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 

 -- vB4 Default Style -- Default Mobile Style 
 Contact Us Website Babble Webmaster Forums Archive Top 
 All times are GMT -6. The time now is 01:50 PM . Powered by vBulletin® Version 4.2.0
Copyright©2012 vBulletin Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.
Extra Tabs by vBulletin Hispano
	</body>
</document>
