<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005605" url="http://www.merchantcircle.com/business/Jerrys.Restaurants.Corporate.Office.480-874-0977" time="2012-07-12-22:09" support="1" score="0.004842421723800539" bingtitle="Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office, Scottsdale AZ 85251" webtitle="Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office, Scottsdale AZ 85251">
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>I had to leave but the other lady wanted desert so she stayed. I told ... Organic Foods Produce Retailers Restaurants Specialty Food Stores Beverage &amp; Drinks Fast Food Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Loading... Autos Home&amp;Garden Real Estate Health&amp;Beauty Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining All Join Now Login Help Dashboard Sign Out Autos Business to Business Community Education Electronics Entertainment and Arts Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Professional Services Real Estate Recreation Retail Shopping Travel&amp;Lodging Find A Merchant Find A Deal Get Advice 
Find
 Merchants Deals Advice 
In or Around
 I&apos;m Insured I&apos;m Uninsured National  AZ  Scottsdale  85251 
 Food&amp;Dining | Restaurants | Family Style Restaurants 
 Circle Up 
Follow this Merchant
 Circle Up! 
Follow this Merchant
 Claim Your Business Claim Your Business Update Your Picture 
 Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office 
 
           
 ( 3 ) reviews Write a Review Scottsdale , AZ 85251 480-874-0977 Get Directions 
Write A Review

Write a review about this merchant!
 
Write A Review

Write a review about this merchant!
 
About Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office
 
Categories: Food&amp;Dining | Restaurants | Family Style Restaurants 
 Add An Image 
Tags: restaurants , family , style , restaurant , scottsdale ,
 Sponsored Links 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed 
 5.00 Mosaic Restaurant 480-563-9600 Scottsdale, AZ, 85262 3.00 Voltaire Restaurant 480-948-1005 Scottsdale, AZ, 85250 0.0 Remington&apos;s Restaurant 480-951-5101 Scottsdale, AZ, 85253 0.0 IHOP 480-661-8998 Scottsdale, AZ, 85258 Local Businesses 
Related Businesses
 
Write a review about Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office
   Rate:
           
 Review I would recommend Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office to my Facebook Friends 
 

 
 
Reviews about Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office
 Sort by:  Most Helpful | Highest Rated | Most Recent Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office 1 
Not Happy
 
I went to your restaurant twice and each time the service was not good. I had a lunch meeting with someone and we went to Jerry&apos;s we had to wait for a very long time and watch our food sit on the counter. I had to leave but the other lady wanted desert so she stayed. I told the lady ringing me up that she was staying to have desert but i had to get back to the office. She called me and told me that she had to wait 15 mins before anyone asked her if she needed something. That should have never happen. Then i went agin on th11/27 and ordered steak well done not much to my surprize it wan&apos;st the way i asked. then the lady spilled a whole cup of soda on my son at the end the lady took of the steak but charged me for my sides? Really!!!
 By Cheryl on November 28, 2011 at 12:44 PM Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office 1 
Jerry&apos;s restaurant in Safford , AZ
 
My experience @ the Jerry&apos;s in Safford was horrible. I watched the servers remove dirty plates from tables not wash their hands before grabbing plates of food from the window. Looking at the cook you could see he wasn&apos;t wearing gloves while prepareing food. And the manager when in the kitchen helping the cook was not wearing a hat or a hair net that you could notice. The manager seemed very rude when my husband and I said something about it. He told us that if we didn&apos;t like the way his restaurant was run we could go to Denny&apos;s. If all your managers are like that then I don&apos;t think I will ever go to any Jerry&apos;s again.
 By Sandra Tillman on May 14, 2009 at 03:04 PM Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office 1 
the worst service and food I have ever had at Jerry
 
We were in Mt Serling, Ky.
It was right after MSU&apos;s Graduation. So it was busy.We had a short wait ,that was fine.The drink order was taken ,the poor girl got wrong ,no big deal.We sat there for 45 min,no refills until asked.
she fin. took our order another 30min passed. The people that orded breakfast everything was ok but the people that ordered hamburger, it was burnt My steak was so tuff I could not eat it. My husband steak was raw.We asked the Manager to come over He asked us to leave.Before you ask, we were not Rude or loud. we were more than willing to get another dish.There were 11 people at our table. We left the waitress a tip and left.We were there for over 2hrs
 By TYNA BABBITT on May 10, 2009 at 12:27 PM Jerry&apos;s Restaurants Corporate Office 1.00000000000000000000 out of 5 3 3 
Browse By Category 
 Banquet Rooms Beverages Candy&amp;Sweets Catering Services Culinary Schools Grocery Stores Meats Organic Foods Produce Retailers Restaurants Specialty Food Stores Beverage&amp;Drinks Fast Food Restaurant Equipment&amp;Services view more 
Is This Your Business?
 
Claim this listing now and grow your business
 
Related Businesses
 
Sponsored Links
 
Other Local Businesses 
 
Follow Us
 MerchantCircle on Facebook Twitter @merchantcircle MerchantCircle Blog Home | About Us | Blog | Forums | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Support | Answers | Advertise with Us | Developers | Expert Articles Our Partners: Ask Answers  |  Life 123  |  Citysearch  |  Insider Pages  |  Urbanspoon MerchantCircle is a Reply! Inc. property. Other Reply! sites include: Bloglines | iMotors | Contractors.com | EducationHub ©2012 Reply! Inc. All Rights Reserved. CLOSE
	</body>
</document>
