<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005967" url="http://interpret.zar.vg/art/Travel-and-Leisure/Outdoors/picnic_ideas_tips_and_hints.php" time="2012-07-12-22:38" support="12" score="0.016415049981796853" bingtitle="Picnic Ideas, Tips, And Hints - Online language translation from ..." webtitle="Picnic Ideas, Tips, And Hints">
			<query id="000692" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000650" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001006" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000019" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>... months, save the individual condiment packets (mustard, ketchup, relish, onion, etc.) you pick up at your favorite fast food restaurant. ... for Sydney Taronga Zoo Park ...</description>
	<body>
		Picnic Ideas, Tips, And Hints
           By Pietschoice1 
     keywords: picnic ideas picnic hints picnic tips picnic suggestions romantic picnic ideas for a picnic           Ideas for picnics are virtually endless when you consider
that every outdoor meal is a picnic. From backyard family
picnics to large company picnics, the basic ingredients are
the same: Good Food, Good Company, and Good Times. A simple
picnic lunch when camping or in your RV can be as memorable
as a romantic picnic on a secluded beach.

 Have a plan. Whether your picnic is an intimate meal
for two or for a lorge gathering such as a family reunion or
a company picnic, the basics of planning are the same. As
you plan your picnic, don&apos;t hesitate to ask family and
friends to help. After all, a picnic is usually a casual
occasion and when everyone pitches in.....it builds lasting
memories for all.

 Location, Location, Location. With a little planning,
friends and family, good food, and the right location, the
picnic experience can be a memorable one. A picnic can be
held almost anywhere. It is the situation that dictates
where. Consider how long your picnic is going to last; you
will want to be where you can relax and enjoy the
surroundings for an extended length of time. Just a few of
the many places to consider when you want to have that
special picnic with your family or friends: A park, a beach,
an outdoor concert or festival, a lake or stream, a meadow
or field, your own backyard, a local winery (many encourage
picnics and have set aside tables or areas exclusively for
your picnic), a rest area while traveling, tailgate party,
or even a outdoor potluck.


 Make sure that you have packed everything that you
will need for the picnic. Once you are at your destination
and realize that you have forgotten something, well, it&apos;s
too late. That is the importance of a picnic checklist. You
might also want to consider making up a picnic kit and
having it ready to go at a moment&apos;s notice. This will enable
you to follow up on those spur of the moment picnic
ideas.

 If you are using a blanket for your picnic, you might
want to consider packing a plastic tarp to place under the
blanket should the ground be wet or damp. The tarp can be
hosed off when you get home and folded up for your next
picnic. If you don&apos;t want to go through the trouble of
bringing along a tarp, the picnic blanket will be what you
need. It is specifically designed with a waterproof backing
and available with it&apos;s own carrying case. 

 On the other hand, if you are the type that prefers
to be off of the ground and there are no picnic tables
readily available, a portable folding table with seats that
hold up to four adults and fits conveniently into the trunk
of the car is one item you will be glad you brought with
you.

 When packing condiments for your picnic, try this:
During the winter months, save the individual condiment
packets (mustard, ketchup, relish, onion, etc.) you pick up
at your favorite fast food restaurant. When spring time
comes and you are biting at the bit to go one the first
picnic of the year, your will have all the condiments packed
and ready to go.

 Remember to plan some activities or bring along some
outdoor games. A picnic is more than just about the food.
Planning age appropriate games and activities encourages
your guests to interact with others and keeps the children
occupied.

 Having a backyard picnic? This will keep you from
running back and forth to the house to get the refrigerated
foods. Fill the bottom four inches of a child&apos;s wading pool
with crushed ice. Foods like salads, eggs, desserts, and
condiments can be ;placed directly on the ice to be kept
chilled. Drain off the water as the ice melts and add more
ice as needed. A word of precaution, however, don&apos;t let the
food stay out longer than two hours (one hour if the
temperature is over 90) 

 The key to stress-free picnics is to pack easily
prepared foods. There are literally thousands of picnic
recipes available on line.

 Hint: Don&apos;t forget to check the weather forecast for
the date of your picnic


     keywords: picnic ideas picnic hints picnic tips picnic suggestions romantic picnic ideas for a picnic     Article Source: http://interpret.zar.vg             About The Author 
Piet Van Lier is the owner of a small business that
manufactures the Picnic Placemat, the newest and most useful
accessory for picnics, rv&apos;s, camping, etc. Mr. Van Lier
enjoys leisure outdoor activities and spends much of his
time traveling with his wife and family in their motorhome. 
He is the writer of www.picnicplacemat.com site. If you
find this article useful visit our site for more
information.           
 
 More Articles about: Outdoors 
 
      Little Cave, Big Experience! What To Look For In Ski Vacation Rentals The Majesty Of Live Golf Things to Know About Snorkeling on Vacation Chattahoochee Bend, Georgia s Newest State Park When To Go Fishing What To Visit In Miami And Miami Seaquarium And Useful Guide What To Expect From And How To Handle Fire Ant Bites Choosing Curtains To Insulate Hotel Bedrooms Touring The Smokies From The Back Of A Harley Davidson The North Alabama Birding Trail Be Sure To Watch The Miles On Your Next Rental Vehicle Aluminium Seats Provide The Perfect Solution for Sydney
Taronga Zoo Park Visitors Tips And Advice Making Ice Driving More Fun Gaining A Wonderful Experience By Ice Driving Anyone Can Enjoy A Ski Vacation Pondering About Summer Camp?Consider Rochester NY! Scuba Diving: A Combination Of Danger And Thrill Scuba Diving: A Marvelous Water Sports Activity Scuba Diving: A Must For Tourists To Enjoy Awesome Vacation Teach Tennis At Summer Camp Linen And Cotton Care Advice For Hotels And Restaurants World Health Organisations Recommends Use of Mosquito Nets 7 Ways Light is Helpful in Survival Situations Practical Uses For Light In Survival Situations                     2012 interpret.zar.vg   
 
 
 
 
 
  
 
 
 Translator 
 Dictionaries 
 Slang Dictionary 
 Links 
 Contact Us 
 Exchange Links 
 Article Categories 
 Software 
 Most Recent Articles 
 Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
