<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005620" url="http://au.news.yahoo.com/thewest/a/-/wa/12930296/man-knocked-unconscious-by-king-hit/" time="2012-07-12-22:11" support="1" score="0.0012644371581010299" bingtitle="Man knocked unconscious by &apos;king hit&apos; - The West Australian" webtitle="Man knocked unconscious by &apos;king hit&apos; - The West Australian">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>... an unprovoked attack on two men in a Perth fast food restaurant ... HSBC Credit Card -... low rate 17.99%; Virgin No Annual... ... Place an Ad in the paper; Competitions; FAQ; TAB Form</description>
	<body>
		Sign In or Sign Up Yahoo!7 Mail 
 Classifieds Real Estate Announcements Jobs Bloo Newsletters Home Delivery WestRewards Place an Ad Events Competitions Footy Tipping 
 
 The West Powered by Yahoo!7 News 
 Search Search Web 
 
 HOME OLYMPICS AFL SPORT BUSINESS LIFE + STYLE ENTERTAINMENT TRAVEL MOTORING REGIONAL REAL ESTATE JOBS WEATHER 

 Breaking WA News National World Offbeat Full Coverage Galleries Video Opinion Crime Stoppers RSS Announcements 
 
 Search The West SEARCH 
 
Man knocked unconscious by &apos;king hit&apos;
 RONAN O&apos;CONNELL, The West Australian February 16, 2012, 2:57 pm 

 

Police have released graphic security footage of an unprovoked attack on two men in a Perth fast food restaurant which left one of the victims unconscious.

The victims, both aged in their early 20s, were buying food at Hungry Jack’s on William Street about 11pm last Wednesday when two men started to harass and intimidate them.

More than 10 minutes later one of the men king hit one of the victims, causing him to slump to the ground unconscious.

The men then attacked his friend, leaving him with a broken nose and other facial injuries.

The victim who was knocked unconscious escaped any significant injury.

The attackers were described as being of Asian appearance, aged in their 20s, of a medium height and medium build.

Anyone with information on the assaults is asked to call Crime Stoppers on 1800 333 000.
 
A group attacks two men in a Perth fast food restaurant. Picture: WA Police
 
 
 Follow thewest.com.au on Twitter 
Explore More
 
 
 Teenager dies after being king-hit 
 
 Hunt for men after blind woman bashed 
 
 Man unconscious after bottle attack 
 
 Armed robber hits pharmacies 
 
 Attack on good samaritan 
 
 Man in hospital after fight 
 
 King-hit killer in CCTV of earlier attack 
 
 
SPECIAL PROMOTION
 Try our Colour Selector 
Planning a fresh coat - get the creativity flowing before you open a single can.
 Try it now [ Change Location ] 
Perth
 
 Currently 
 
 3.8° 
 
 Today&apos;s forecast: Mostly sunny

 3° - 18° 
 7 day forecast » 
West Rewards
 
Most Viewed
 
 Will and Kate&apos;s honeymoon pics published Dying Diana image seen in documentary Divers&apos; close call with a great white The one that got away Plane wreck found at Cable Beach, one dead Town designates tricky parking spots as &apos;men only&apos; Young pilot dies in Cable Beach tragedy Evans moves up in Tour de France Explosion at Riverton ATM Movie Review: Not Suitable for Children 
 
Breaking
 
 4:00 am GP shortage blamed for flu rush 3:40 am Stars lured to Winton movie 3:30 am WA jobs boom widens national gap 2:55 am Eagles players help fire-ravaged school 2:45 am Experts to comb air crash 2:43 am Death falls out of sky at beach paradise 2:41 am Mate mourns &apos;good pilot&apos; 2:35 am Armadale &apos;at risk from booze&apos; 2:33 am WA drinking out of control 2:25 am Labor revisits ban on logging 
 More Breaking News » COMPARE&amp;SAVE 
Saving Accounts
 
 USaver (Base Rate... max rate 5.71% Citibank Online... max rate 5.70% RaboDirect Savings... max rate 5.60% Maxi Saver (5.35%... max rate 5.35% Savings Maximiser... max rate 5.35% HSBC Serious Saver... max rate 5.30% Maxi Saver (NSW... max rate 5.30% ANZ Online Saver... max rate 5.25% TeleNet Saver (6... max rate 5.25% NAB iSaver (1.50%... max rate 5.00% Virgin Saver max rate 4.50% Achieve Saver... max rate 4.20% 
 COMPARE MORE 
Credit Cards
 
 bankmecu Low Rate... low rate 10.49% Bankwest Breeze... low rate 10.99% Citibank Clear... low rate 11.99% Virgin Low Rate... low rate 12.99% NAB Low Rate Visa... low rate 12.99% St.George Vertigo... low rate 13.24% Bank of Melbourne... low rate 13.24% BankSA Vertigo... low rate 13.24% bankmecu VISA... low rate 13.49% Citibank Clear Card low rate 15.99% St.George Gold Low... low rate 15.99% Bankwest Zero... low rate 17.99% St.George Amplify... low rate 18.74% Virgin No Annual... low rate 18.99% Bankwest More... low rate 19.24% Woolworths Everyday... low rate 19.84% Coles MasterCard low rate 19.99% BP-Citibank... low rate 20.89% Virgin Flyer Credit... low rate 20.99% 
 COMPARE MORE 
Home Loans
 
 UHomeLoan -... variable rate 5.62% Dream Loan Express variable rate 5.75% State Custodians... variable rate 5.82% Premium Plus... variable rate 5.97% goGreen Home Loan variable rate 5.98% State Custodians... variable rate 6.07% NAB National Choice... variable rate 6.08% Member Package... variable rate 6.08% MyRate.com.au -... variable rate 6.12% Fixed Home Loan variable rate 6.28% MyRate.com.au... variable rate 7.15% 
 COMPARE MORE 
iPhone 4S Cheapest Plans
 
 $29 Plan $180 incl. value 200 MB incl. data $47.00 /mth min cost $1,128.00 $29 Business Plan $180 incl. value 200 MB incl. data $47.00 /mth min cost $1,128.00 Big Plan 29 $450 incl. value 2304 MB incl. data $48.00 /mth min cost $1,152.00 $35 Optus Plan $200 incl. value 200 MB incl. data $53.00 /mth min cost $1,272.00 Big Plan 39 $650 incl. value 2560 MB incl. data $54.00 /mth min cost $1,296.00 $39 Plan $300 incl. value 500 MB incl. data $55.00 /mth min cost $1,320.00 $39 Business Plan $300 incl. value 500 MB incl. data $55.00 /mth min cost $1,320.00 $49 Plan $550 incl. value 1024 MB incl. data $57.00 /mth min cost $1,368.00 Fair Go Plan 49 $400 incl. value 2048 MB incl. data $57.00 /mth min cost $1,368.00 $49 Business Plan $550 incl. value 1024 MB incl. data $57.00 /mth min cost $1,368.00 $59 Plan $750 incl. value 1536 MB incl. data $64.00 /mth min cost $1,536.00 Fair Go Plan 59 $700 incl. value 3072 MB incl. data $64.00 /mth min cost $1,536.00 $59 Business Plan $750 incl. value 1536 MB incl. data $64.00 /mth min cost $1,536.00 $60 Optus Plan $650 incl. value 1536 MB incl. data $65.00 /mth min cost $1,560.00 $50 Optus Plan $500 incl. value 1024 MB incl. data $65.00 /mth min cost $1,560.00 $60 Every Day Connect Plan $600 incl. value 1024 MB incl. data $67.00 /mth min cost $1,608.00 $79 Infinite Business Plan Unlimited 2048 MB incl. data $79.00 /mth min cost $1,896.00 $79 Infinite Plan Unlimited 2048 MB incl. data $79.00 /mth min cost $1,896.00 $80 Optus Plan $850 incl. value 2048 MB incl. data $80.00 /mth min cost $1,920.00 $80 Every Day Connect Plan $800 incl. value 1536 MB incl. data $80.00 /mth min cost $1,920.00 $49 Plan $550 incl. value 1024 MB incl. data $81.00 /mth min cost $972.00 $49 Business Plan $550 incl. value 1024 MB incl. data $81.00 /mth min cost $972.00 $59 Plan $750 incl. value 1536 MB incl. data $86.00 /mth min cost $1,032.00 $59 Business Plan $750 incl. value 1536 MB incl. data $86.00 /mth min cost $1,032.00 89 Topless Unlimited 4096 MB incl. data $89.00 /mth min cost $2,136.00 $89 Optus Timeless Plan Unlimited 2048 MB incl. data $89.00 /mth min cost $2,136.00 $99 Optus Timeless Plan Unlimited 3072 MB incl. data $99.00 /mth min cost $2,376.00 $99 Infinite Business Plan Unlimited 4096 MB incl. data $99.00 /mth min cost $2,376.00 $99 Infinite Plan Unlimited 4096 MB incl. data $99.00 /mth min cost $2,376.00 $100 Every Day Connect Plan $900 incl. value 2048 MB incl. data $100.00 /mth min cost $2,400.00 $79 Infinite Business Plan Unlimited 2048 MB incl. data $106.00 /mth min cost $1,272.00 $79 Infinite Plan Unlimited 2048 MB incl. data $106.00 /mth min cost $1,272.00 $99 Infinite Business Plan Unlimited 4096 MB incl. data $119.00 /mth min cost $1,428.00 $99 Infinite Plan Unlimited 4096 MB incl. data $119.00 /mth min cost $1,428.00 $129 Optus Timeless Plan Unlimited 4096 MB incl. data $129.00 /mth min cost $3,096.00 $130 Every Day Connect Plan Unlimited 3072 MB incl. data $130.00 /mth min cost $3,120.00 
 COMPARE MORE 

 
Sponsored links
 

 
 THE WEST NEWS HOME 

 Breaking WA News National World Off Beat 

 Galleries Crime Stoppers Business Sport Life + Style 

 Entertainment Travel Opinion Video RSS 
 
ALSO ON THE WEST
 
 Advertising Corporate Editorial Policy Editorial Complaints Careers Digital Editions Current Digital Editions Past Place an Ad in the paper Competitions Contact 
 
 FAQ TAB Form Home Delivery Newsletter My Resources Newspaper Print Tours WA FM Red FM Spirit Network 
 
 Quokka Jobs Newspapers in Education Regional News Events bloo Twitter Facebook 
 
&apos;The West Australian&apos; is a trademark of West Australian Newspapers Limited 2012.

All rights reserved.

 Advertise with Us Privacy Policy Terms of Service Help 
 
The West News Preferences
 Close 
Select your state to see news for your area.
 Save
	</body>
</document>
