<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005445" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-Food-Restaurant&amp;id=2760772" time="2012-07-12-22:00" support="22" score="0.11009548042018867" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant - EzineArticles Submission - Submit Your Best ..." webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant">
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000107" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000950" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000732" bing-rank="15"/>
	<description>A Fast Food Restaurant is a quick service restaurant QSR. ... through facility enables customers to place an order and ... On August 14, 2009. Viewed 266 times. Word count ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Food and Drink John Cheesman 
 Platinum Author |   195 Articles 
 Joined: April 21, 2009 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Fast Food Restaurant

 By John Cheesman 
 
A Fast Food Restaurant is a quick service restaurant QSR. They are a specific type of restaurant and well known for fast food and minimal table service. The food served in these restaurants is very often offered from a limited menu, and typically cooked and prepared in advance, kept hot and when an order is placed, it is then ready to be served. If the food is to be taken away, it will be packaged.

These restaurants are very often part of a restaurant chain, and the provisions they use are standardized ingredients and sometimes partially prepared food will be supplied to them through controlled channels. The first one most likely originated in the United States. Another variation of this is a catering van or truck, which has the advantage of mobility.

At the time of writing this article there are around 58 popular restaurants, and totalled together they offer almost 3000 menu items, and the number is still rising.

These restaurants are generally located in towns, cities, along major roadways, leisure parks and other easy to get to locations. Many of these restaurants provide drive through facilities. A drive through facility enables customers to place an order and then pick it up at the customer service bay without leaving their vehicle.

Some of these restaurants provide dining areas where food can be ordered and eaten on the premises, and a few will even take orders by phone and deliver the food to the required address. Many pizza restaurants provide this delivery service at no extra cost to the customer, however a minimum order must be adhered to.

Fast food is any food that is quick, convenient and usually inexpensive. Fast food can be bought just about anywhere that sells food and snacks. Vending machines, drive through restaurants and 24hr convenience shops are the most common places to obtain fast food.

Fast food is generally cheaper because it is made with cheaper ingredients such as, refined grains, added sugar and high fat meat. Many of these quick and convenient meals contain a high amount of sodium which can increase the risk of high blood pressure. Sodium can also lead to build-up of fluids in case of people with congestive heart failure, cirrhosis or kidney disease.

Today most fast food chains are responding to customers comments by changing their menus to more healthy alternatives, and these can include more fruits and vegetables, and reducing the amount of fat, salt and added sugar on many of their menu items.
 
If you are in need of this service check out our product pages, they contain many companies that specialize in this. John Cheesman writes about Fast Food Restaurant . Visit the Businessmagnet product page for details and suppliers of Fast Food Restaurant .
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=John_Cheesman 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Food and Drink 
 John Cheesman 
 Email Address: Subscribe Food and Drink Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Starting Your Own Restaurant Guide - Ten Easy Steps to Start a Restaurant Use Restaurant Nutrition Analysis to Test Restaurant Menu Items Red Lobster Restaurant Recipes Revealed - How to Copycat Your Favorite Red Lobster Menu Items! Have You Tried the Sonic Menu Items? 5 Restaurant Secrets You Should Know About and Tips to Save Money by Eating at Home Point Of Sale Software For Restaurants What Factors Make a Successful Restaurant? Fast Food And Restaurant Secret Recipes Healthy Fast Food Options For Eating on the Go How to Find Healthier Fast Foods 
 
Recent Articles

 Commercial Kitchen Crises: Damage Control Catering for Any Event A Quick Crash Course in Bread Machines and Why You Need One The Logic Behind Drinks Packaging Green Party Foods Easy Pumpkin Pie Crust For Thanksgiving Dinner Summer Burgers, And How To Stop Feeling Guilty Eating Them Protein - How Much Do You Need And Where to Get It? Restaurant Budget Techniques to Save Money Added Conveniences of Owning a Portable Bar 
 
Submitted On August 14, 2009. Viewed 275 times. Word count: 417.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Cheesman, John &quot;Fast Food Restaurant.&quot; Fast Food Restaurant .
 14 Aug. 2009 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-­Food-­Restaurant&amp;id=2760772 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Cheesman, J. (2009, August 14). Fast Food Restaurant .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-­Food-­Restaurant&amp;id=2760772 Chicago Style Citation: 
Cheesman, John &quot;Fast Food Restaurant.&quot; Fast Food Restaurant EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-­Food-­Restaurant&amp;id=2760772 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
