<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005164" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/nf/55/5525/5411/Rochester/Pittsford/Ice-Cream-Desserts" time="2012-07-12-21:42" support="1" score="0.0011805463432962274" bingtitle="Pittsford Ice Cream &amp; Dessert Shops | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Pittsford Ice CreamDessert Shops | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>It&apos;s not just about the ice cream ... Only odd thing - is this is not a fast food restaurant, they are making your order ... props for the food, but you would expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Rochester » Greater Rochester » Pittsford » Desserts&amp;Ice Cream 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Baltimore Buffalo Los Angeles New York Philadelphia Pittsburgh Toronto More... 
 
 Add Restaurant Pittsford Ice Cream&amp;Dessert Shops 
 
Prices

 $$$ Higher priced (1) $$ Moderately priced (3) $ Cheap eats (3) 
 
Neighborhoods

 
 Greater Rochester 

 Canandaigua (4) Fairport (9) Henrietta (6) Penfield (4) Pittsford Spencerport (3) Webster (8) Williamson (4) 
 Show all 
 Rochester 

 Alexander (5) Cobbs Hill (4) Grove Place (3) Northeast Quadrant (11) Park Ave (3) Southeast Quadrant (5) Southwest Quadrant (7) Upper Monroe (3) 
 Show all 
 
Cuisines

 American (13) Bagels (3) Bakery (6) Breakfast&amp;Brunch (2) Burgers (3) Coffee (8) Desserts&amp;Ice Cream Diner (3) European (2) Greek (2) Italian (6) Japanese (2) Mexican (2) Pizza (7) Pub Food (1) Salads (4) Sandwiches&amp;Subs (7) Smoothies (2) Steakhouse (2) Sushi (2) 
 Show all 
Features

 Gluten-Free Frie... (2) Kid Friendly (3) Romantic (1) 
 Remove: Pittsford | Desserts/Ice Cream Sort: Best
| Alphabetical | Recently added 
 1 Bill Wahl&apos;s Ice Cream&amp;... 91% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 45 Schoen Pl 2 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s 86% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream, Greek, Smoothies 5 S Main St 3 Cold Stone Creamery 85% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 3349 Monroe Ave 4 Pomodoro 72% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Pittsford - American, Desserts/Ice Cream, Italian 3400 Monroe Ave 5 Abbott&apos;s Frozen Custard 79% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 624 Pittsford Victor Rd 6 The Cheesecake Factory 69% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream, Italian, Modern American 3349 Monroe Ave 7 Port of Chocolates I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 10 Schoen Pl 8 Watson&apos;s Chocolates of... I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$ Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 725 Pittsford Victor Rd 9 Larosa&apos;s (Brookwood Inn) I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $$$ Pittsford - American, Desserts/Ice Cream, Italian 800 Pittsford Victor Rd 10 Brad&apos;s&amp;Dad&apos;s Ice Cream I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 119 Brook Rd 11 D P Berens I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 9 Office Park Way 12 Dolce Cupcakery 48% I like it I don&apos;t Clear vote $ Pittsford - Desserts/Ice Cream 50 state street 
 « Previous Page
1 Next » 
Critic reviews

Pittsford, Desserts/Ice Cream

 May 19, 2010 The Cheesecake Factory By Zagat &apos;Humongous portions and humongous lines&apos; characterize this American... Full review 
 4.5/5.0 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s By Citysearch It&apos;s not just about the ice cream. Ben and Jerry, two childhood friends from Vermont, built their empire on a great... Full review 
 4.0/5.0 Cold Stone Creamery By Citysearch Crowds of couples, teenagers and parents with toddlers press up against the long refrigerated display case at this... Full review 
 
Diner reviews

Pittsford, Desserts/Ice Cream

 June 20, 2012 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s by blondyskigirl ( 2 reviews ) I would always suggest Ben&amp;Jerry’s for ice cream around Pittsford. They have all different flavors and their ice cream is always delicious. If you are a fan of sundaes, I would definitely recommend the Cookie Cookie Sundae. It has cookies, hot fudge and ice cream! The staff at Ben&amp;Jerry’s in Pittsford is always friendly – and who doesn’t love ice cream?! June 7, 2012 Bill Wahl&apos;s Ice Cream&amp;Yogurt Yum yum yum by Skip ( 51 reviews ) There is nothing more I can say. Bring the whole family and enjoy the made on site ice cream. Puts the top brands to shame. May 21, 2012 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s Great Options by bbzdick ( 15 reviews ) They had great options available, as they do in the stores, and then some! Almost wasn&apos;t able to choose because they all looked and sounded so great. Had nice quick service without a long wait in line as you can experience at some ice cream joints. This will be my new go to summer ice cream place, try it! 
 
 
Name and save this location
 
 
 Add Restaurant Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
