<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005827" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/200542-2-Magazine-Subscriptions-YMMV" time="2012-07-12-22:28" support="3" score="0.004408521448131747" bingtitle="$2 Magazine Subscriptions - YMMV - Welcome to Your Daily Freebies ..." webtitle="$2 Magazine Subscriptions - YMMV">
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>I got this in an email as part of my order confirmation with Snapfish. It says you can order up ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons; Military ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals $2 Magazine Subscriptions - YMMV 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Results 1 to 2 of 2 
Thread: $2 Magazine Subscriptions - YMMV 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 12-01-2006,  09:25 AM #1 vegasbrat 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries Visit Homepage View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Nov 2006 Location Las Vegas, NV Posts 244 
$2 Magazine Subscriptions - YMMV
 I got this in an email as part of my order confirmation with Snapfish.

It says you can order up to four of the following:

Time
Woman&apos;s Day
PC Photo
Reader&apos;s Digest
National Geographic Adventure
National Geographic Traveler
PC World
Southern Living
Interview
Horticulture
Fast Company
Giant
Nursing Made Incredibly Easy
Computer Shopper
The Magazine Antiques
Workbench
Cigar Aficionado
Baseball Digest
Car and Driver
Electronic House

It&apos;s a yearly subscription with a $2 processing fee per magazine title.
 The catch is: they will automatically renew your subscription at the end of the year and charge your credit card.

My suggestion is to use a one-time use credit card or use a card that you know you will no longer have by the end of the year. For instance, I used my Wells Fargo debit/credit card because I know I am closing that account soon and will cancel the card.

Either that or mark it in your calendar in time to call their customer service and ask them to cancel your subscription.

Here are the FAQs:

GENERAL FAQs:

Can I see a bigger picture or description of the selections?
Sure. Simply click on any picture or item to see a detail view and description.

Will I be charged for wrapping?
No. Please keep in mind that magazines, software and DVDs cannot be wrapped, but for all other items wrapping is complimentary.

ORDERING:

Can I have my selections sent to separate addresses?
No, we can send your selections to one address only.

What if I want to use a different address for my order?
If you would like your order sent to an address different than the one that appears on your order confirmation, place your order and then contact our customer service center.

Can you ship my selections express?
No. While we do make every effort to send your selections as quickly as possible, we are unable to accommodate special shipping arrangements.

Do I have to provide my account number?
Yes. We are not able to process your selections without a valid debit or credit card account.

CONTACT US:

If you have further questions that were not answered in the above FAQs, please contact us according to the nature of your inquiry. Well be happy to help you.

 PROGRAM AND DELIVERY DETAILS 

Delivery Details
We begin processing your selections as soon as they are received and make every effort to deliver them quickly.

Magazines:
Allow 4 to 10 weeks for magazines to start.

At this time, subscriptions are available only to residents of the 50 U.S. States, Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia. For APO/FPO addresses, please contact Customer Service at 1-800-927-9578 to place your order. Not all titles are available for delivery to APO/FPO addresses. If a title is not available, you will be notified.

Magazine Offer Details

First Year Purchased on Your Behalf
Enjoy your magazines with the first year purchased on your behalf. For each selection your credit/debit card you provide will be charged just $2 for processing. This offer comes with automatic renewal benefits as described below.

Automatic Renewal Benefits
As an additional benefit, after the first year, your magazines will continue. Each year, you&apos;ll receive a reminder notice and you authorize your account to be charged the rate on the notice for the next year of issues until you tell us to stop. If a title ceases, it will be replaced with one of equal or greater value.

Minimum Software System Requirements:
PC with Pentium 300 MHz or better processor. 128MB of RAM recommended. 4X CD-ROM Drive. Windows 95, 98, ME, 2000 or XP. Minimum 100MB of free hard disc space required. Direct X version 7.0 or higher. VGA video card recommended.


Customer Service Toll Free Number:

Magazines: 1-800-927-9578
Software: 1-800-586-5298

Order Processing:
Your account information will be forwarded to or collected by SynapseConnect to process your selections. A valid account is required for these offers. Your account will be used to process your selections as described in the offer details.

Vendor Information

SynapseConnect, Inc., 225 High Ridge Road, East Building, Stamford, CT 06905, is the vendor for this offer. SynapseConnect and its partners reserve the right at any time and without notice to limit, refuse, cancel, modify, restrict or terminate orders. All magazine titles, logos, graphics, text, cover images and marks in this offer are the property of their respective owners Third Party Marks. Users may not reproduce or use any part of this offer or any Third Party Marks for any purpose without the express written permission of SynapseConnect or appropriate Third Party, as applicable. You may not create hypertext links to or from the site without SynapseConnect, Inc.&apos;s express or written consent and SynapseConnect, Inc. reserves the right to disable any unauthorized links or frames. Any dispute arising under this offer will be governed by New York law without reference to conflict of law principles and must be brought in the state or federal courts located in New York County, New York. Copyright 2006. SynapseConnect, Inc. All rights reserved.

Privacy

The Program is governed by the terms and conditions set in our privacy policy. Please see the SynapseConnect Privacy Policy.

Disclaimers and Limitations of Liability

THE SITE, INCLUDING ALL CONTENT, PRODUCTS AND ANY SERVICES PROVIDED ON OR THROUGH THE SITE ARE PROVIDED AS IS WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, AND YOU USE THE SITE AT YOUR OWN RISK. NEITHER SYNAPSECONNECT, INC., NOR ITS PARENT, AFFILIATES, OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, THIRD PARTY CONTENT PROVIDERS, MERCHANTS, SPONSORS, LICENSORS OR THE LIKE MAKE ANY REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES WHETHER EXPRESS, IMPLIED OR STATUTORY, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE, NON-INFRINGEMENTS, THAT THE SITE WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR FREE; NOR AS TO THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY OR CURRENCY OF ANY INFORMATION, SERVICE OR MERCHANDISE, OR GUARANTEE ANY CONTENT, PRODUCT OR SERVICE, INCLUDING THE ACCURACY OR CORRECTNESS, OFFERED BY A THIRD-PARTY THROUGH THE SITE, AND WILL NOT BE A PARTY TO OR IN ANY WAY MONITOR ANY TRANSACTION BETWEEN ANY USER AND THIRD-PARTY PROVIDERS OF PRODUCTS OR SERVICES. YOU UNDERSTAND THAT NO ORAL ADVICE OR WRITTEN INFORMATION GIVEN BY ANY PARTY SHALL CREATE ANY WARRANTY; AND YOU AGREE NOT TO RELY ON SUCH INFORMATION OR ADVICE. UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES SHALL SYNAPSECONNECT, INC. OR ANY OTHER PARTY INVOLVED IN CREATING, PRODUCING OR DISTRIBUTING THE SITE, ITS CONTENT, MERCHANDISE OR SERVICES AVAILABLE THROUGH IT, BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES THAT RESULT FROM THE USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE THE SAME, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO RELIANCE BY ANY USER ON ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED THEREFROM; OR FROM MISTAKES, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS OR DELETION OF FILES OR EMAIL, ERRORS, DEFECTS, VIRUSES, DELAYS IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION, OR ANY FAILURE OF PERFORMANCE, COMMUNICATIONS, THEFT, DESTRUCTION OR UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS TO RECORDS, PROGRAMS OR SERVICES. IN STATES THAT DO NOT ALLOW EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF LIABLITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, LIABILITY IS LIMITED TO THE FULLEST EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW. IN ALL EVENTS, ANY LIABILITY OF SYNAPSECONNECT, INC. AND ANY OTHER PARTY INVOLVED IN CREATING, PRODUCING OR DISTRIBUTING THE SITE, IF ANY, SHALL BE LIMITED TO REPLACEMENT OF APPLICABLE SUBSCRIPTION(S) OR PRODUCT(S), AS APPROPRIATE.

Good luck! 

 http://xp3.mybonuscenter.com/ixp/spl...l?afk=05007301 Reply With Quote 12-01-2006,  09:55 AM #2 whyme 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2005 Posts 125 
 
 Thank you for the great find!!! I just ordered and got my confirmation email right away!! Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
