<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005471" url="http://www.bvblackspin.com/2010/02/19/fast-food-and-food-stamps/" time="2012-07-12-22:02" support="33" score="0.08767412294223909" bingtitle="Fast Food and Food Stamps: A Recipe for Disaster - BV Black Spin" webtitle="Fast Food and Food Stamps: A Recipe for Disaster  - BV Black Spin">
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001523" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001299" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000049" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>... and everyone else, to eat healthy and prepare healthy meals for their ... what they can get at the average fast food restaurant. ... Star Card and it is like a credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Click here to visit the new home of Blackvoices! 
HOT ON HUFFPOST BLACKVOICES:

 Record Number Of Felons Denied Right To Vote Ohio Man Sheds 200 Pounds To Join Army 
   
Categories
 
 Most Recent News (3540) President Obama (839) Politics (1394) Interviews (127) Profiles (214) Race and Civil Rights (1251) Health Care Debate (153) 
 
Contributors
 
 Carmen Dixon Madison J. Gray Denver Louis Paul Shepard Alexis Garrett Stodghill Abena Agyeman-Fisher Dr. Boyce Watkins Jeff Mays Laura Adibe Ruth Manuel-Logan 
 
Other BV Blogs
 
 Entertainment Newswire Style Beauty Wellness Sports Movies Money Love Hair Talk BVBuzz Books Spirituality Feedback Blog 
 
 Fast Food and Food Stamps: A Recipe for Disaster 
 
 By Jam Donaldson on Feb 19th 2010 3:34PM 
Filed under: News 

 Comments (23) 
 Email This 
 

 

It may come as a surprise to most that the U.S. Department of Agriculture&apos;s federal food stamp program authorizes the use of &quot;food stamps&quot; at restaurants. The restaurant food stamp program, however, has been in effect since 1974 for elderly and disabled patrons, and since 1992, for homeless people. The creation of &quot;Restaurant Meals&quot; under the USDA&apos;s food stamp program began with a noble mission: It&apos;s goal was to assist the poor elderly and disabled, who were unable to cook their own meals. The benefit was then extended to the homeless, who had no access to kitchens or storage facilities, making it unfeasible to shop at grocery stores and prepare food.

The Food Stamp Restaurant Meals program is a voluntary part of the program. States decide independently whether they will participate. According to &quot;Nation&apos;s Restaurant News,&quot; a news magazine dedicated to news and trends in the restaurant industry, as of 2004, almost half the country was participating in the restaurant program.

Initially, few restaurants participated in the program, but now there has been an explosion in the number of restaurants who now accept &quot;food stamps.&quot; This increase has been driven primarily by the program&apos;s conversion from physical paper stamps to debit cards, often referred to as &quot;EBT cards&quot; or electronic benefit cards. Restaurants process EBT cards like any other debit card, and the state reimburses them generally within two days. And whereas the program was originally designed for the elderly, homeless and disabled, most states now offer the restaurant component of the program to all categories of food stamp recipients.

There has been controversy over the implementation of this program. Many critics cite the increasing number of fast food restaurants that are accepted in to the program. The L.A. County Department of Social Services counts Jack-in-the-Box, Papa John&apos;s, Popeye&apos;s, Subway, El Pollo Loco and Domino&apos;s as some of its participants. Glancing at the complete list of EBT restaurants, you also see smaller stores like Louisiana Fried Chicken and Fish, Hong Kong Express and Wing Stop.

The addition of pizzas and fast food has generated criticism that the program is not offering food stamp recipients healthful choices, but Leo O&apos;Farrell , food stamp manager for the San Francisco County Department of Human Services, disagrees.

In an interview with &quot;Nation&apos;s Restaurant News&quot; in 2004, he stated, &quot;We have to find restaurants that are low priced and in areas where homeless, disabled and elderly live,&quot; adding, &quot;fast food offers people more choices. They can make a decision on where to eat based on their mood.&quot;

I have to give this whole concept the much-cliched side-eye. Although the intentions behind the original restaurant program were noble, this seems to have the potential for disaster. Since most states have offered this service to all food stamp recipients, it seems to have the potential for abuse. While it is a reasonable and logical solution that offers the elderly, homeless, disabled and families who may not have access to kitchen facilities a way to get a hot meal, can the increased government subsidization of fast food consumption in communities that are already struggling with an epidemic of obesity and related health problems really be a good idea?

We all know that our urban centers, sit-down restaurants, farmer&apos;s markets and grocery stores rarely offer healthy choices. It is rumored that Pizza Hut and Burger King are in talks with several state governments to add their chain to the list.

The recession has hit families hard. According to the USDA, between 2008 and 2009, more than 7 million people were added to the food stamp rolls. A 2010 study by the Brookings Institution and First Focus, a bipartisan child advocacy group, estimated the total number of people currently on food stamp rolls is 36.5 million with half of those estimated to be children.

With our current health care crisis, the poor health in our urban centers and the lack of adequate health care for low-income communities, to legitimize fast food as a viable option for food stamp use seems irresponsible. While Michelle Obama plants a garden to emphasize to the country the importance of eating fresh vegetables and highlighting the problem of childhood obesity, our states are allowing the fast food industry even more access to the waistlines of its residents.
States should be encouraging food stamp participants, and everyone else, to eat healthy and prepare healthy meals for their children. The thought that our tax dollars our subsidizing bad-eating habits that we all ultimately have to pay for in the cost of health care just doesn&apos;t make much sense. Fast food and food stamps? I&apos;m not lovin&apos; it. Tagged as: economy , fast food , health , health care , HealthCare , obesity , recession Email This 
Comments: (23) 

 Add a comment 
 
By: jeromequigley on 2/19/2010 6:07PM 
 Neutral 
Jam, first off I love reading your articles. You are one of the main reasons I come to BV. You always address &quot;real&quot;issues. As for the EBT at Fast Food joints, at this point what can you say? They take them here in VA at 7-11, which you know has mostly junk food and any thing that is a real &quot;grocery item&quot; is going to be 3x higher than at a grocery store! And then you have the ultimate down fall that has always been around in life. If some one wants some thing bad enough they will figure out a way to get it!!! You know as well as I do that the people who are sceaming(hmm not sure spelled right)the system have always been able to find a way to convert their FS money into cash. Little harder with the card but it can still be done. But then they have to trade it for a lost, then spend that money on fast food but have less money. So it is such a frustrating situation!! Do we truely watch the people on this program and crack down on the one&apos;s abusing it?? I say YES!!! But is that really going to happen with OUR government? Doubt it!! People are so engulfed with blacks hating white&apos;s and white&apos;s hating black&apos;s and any other race hating combo that you can put together that we are to divided to stand up the them and take our country back. Now any one who knows my user name knows I&apos;m white, when I say take our country back I mean the people, all people. That is why I voted for Prez Obama, he is the first man in years and years that I feel cares about us and is doing every thing above the table for once and that is why he gets halted at every turn! But will let that angry conversation go for another day. Point is, BROKE AND ALMOST BROKE don&apos;t know color! Any one who things they don&apos;t have anything in common with some one of another race, HA!! If they took time to talk to each other they would find out that have WAY more in common then they ever imagined. Sorry got side tracked a little! But as you can understand, till we team up together we will never be able to clear out the crooks in the government and fix things like the EBT situation. But as always, very good article on a very important subject!!!!!!!

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: lisa marie on 5/24/2011 7:31PM 
 Neutral 
this would benefit me for I am currently homeless as a result of a medical condition and a bad accident. With limited income and lack of assistance services. I wish i could if only temporary the benefit of eating from fast food restaurants with my foodstamp card. Its cheaper and would last longer, instead i run out of food because now walmart is beginning to be expense.

  Report This 
 
By: MS PEGGY on 2/20/2010 1:34PM 
 Neutral 
I think that allowing food stamp recipients to buy hot meals is an excellent idea. There is a convenience market in my city which has a kitchen in the back. They prepare dishes such as cabbage, greens, hot wings, pork chops, chicken&amp;dressing, green beans, broccoli casseroles, potatoes etc. on a daily basis. When I go there to buy a plate I notice that food stamp recipients who can&apos;t use their card to buy a plate are buying items like cookies, chips, ramen noodles and cold bologna. Young mothers with three or four children aren&apos;t at home cooking a three course balanced meal for their children every day like bureaucrats would like to believe. You can&apos;t force individuals to make healthy lifestyle choices and cook just as you can&apos;t force them to stop making babies.

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: Nicole on 12/16/2010 6:52PM 
 Neutral 
Actually, autonomy and dependence are polar opposites. Once a person requires society to pay for them to eat, live, etc. they lose the claim to autonomous decision making. Therefore, their choices should be made for them.

  Report This 
 
By: Audrey Harrell on 2/20/2010 3:46PM 
 Neutral 
Wow!We have to have food to live, bottom line. There are so many people that are so unfortunate in so many ways, homeless, elderly, disabled just to name a few and lets not forget people who don&apos;t have gas and electricity for some reason or another. At first I thought it&apos;s just not right for restaurants to be accepting food stamps but when I look at the bigger picture, I have to say who am I to make that judgement when so many people don&apos;t have a choice. So let the people eat,atleast it&apos;s food and that&apos;s what food stamps are for.

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: tastykake on 2/20/2010 7:00PM 
 Neutral 
After reading this article&amp;comments;, all I can say is...Wow!

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: Laina on 2/20/2010 10:16PM 
 Neutral 
I understand your concern, but the reality is that the people who are truly concerned are not on food stamps, elderly or homeless. Junk food and other types of unhealthy food is being bought at supermarkets all over this nation everyday, with and without the benefit of food stamps.

Granted fast food it is not the healthiest, but people like the homeless, do not have to worry about the logistics of what it would require to store perishables and to prepare a meal. Homeless people have much bigger issues besides eating nutritous meals. So many are drug addicted, have hepatitis, TB and/or mentally ill... For most, they will end up in jail(where a lot of addicts and the mentally ill end up anyway)or some state run facility. At least the meals at these facilities will be more nutritious then what they can get at the average fast food restaurant.

As far as the elderly, some don&apos;t have any business trying to operate a stove. Furthermore, some of these fast food restaurants are a meeting/socialization place for the lonely and elderly. The rare times that I do go to a fast food restaurant for breakfast, I see the same cars and people at their usual table. At least these people can socialize and get meal at the same time and not have to stretch a cup of coffee for 2 hours.

Also, people have been getting over on food stamps forever. In Texas, recipients use what is called a Star Card and it is like a credit card. Anyone wanting to earn extra cash will use their card to buy groceries for someone for a nominal fee, whether it is for cash or something else. There are no guarantee that people will use their benefits for what it was meant for.

Furthermore, if people are bent on eating mystery meat hamburgers/chicken patties/pieces, then their isn&apos;t a whole lot we can do about it anyway.

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: wilson on 2/21/2010 1:51AM 
 Neutral 
Does it make sense for taxpayers to reimburse multi billion dollar companies like Mcdonalds and Jack in the Box, for feeding people unhealthy food which will cause health problems, so the taxpayers can then pay out prescription health care to billion dollar Phamaceutical companies?? And you wonder why the rich get richer!!

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: Jessica on 2/22/2010 7:08AM 
 Neutral 
In my opinion this is just another form of genocide. Black people WAKE UP!!!!

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 
By: marylandman003 on 2/22/2010 8:39AM 
 Neutral 
negroes love and demand their food stamps. go into any food store and every field negro uses them.

 Reply to this Comment  |  Report This 
 Page 1 of 3 
 1 2 3 Last 
 
Add a Comment
 
 New Users BV Black Spin Log-In Use AOL Screenname 
 
First time? A confirmation email will be sent to you after submitting.
 Name:
 E-mail:
 
Please enter your email address and password. You should have received a password in a previous confirmation email
 E-mail:
 Password:
 
If you have an AOL or AIM screenname, you can use it to add a comment.
 

 Your comments: Remember me E-Mail me when someone replies to this comment 
Please keep your comments relevant to this blog entry. Email addresses are never displayed but they are required to confirm your comments . When you enter your name and email address, you&apos;ll be sent a link to confirm your comment, and a password. To leave another comment, just use that password.&quot;
 More on Black Voices 
Follow Us
 
 Newsletter Facebook Twitter RSS 
 
Most Commented Articles

 24 Hours 
 
 7 Days 
 
 30 Days 
 
 
 
Daily Drama
 The Best Clips From TV&apos;s Hottest Shows 

 

 More Daily Drama &gt;&gt; 
 
 
 feed 

 Dr. Jekyll and Mr. Romney Watch This: Biden&apos;s NAACP Speech Obama Authorizes Emergency Funding for Mali Meek Mill and Drake&apos;s Gospel Song: &apos;Sinful&apos;? Watch This: Kobe&apos;s Team vs. Dream Team 
 More Headlines from The Root 
 
 feed 


 More Headlines from Atlanta Post 
Find a Message Board
 
Discover conversations on everyone from Barack to Beyonce. There are nearly 50 forums, so click on a category below and find the right one for you.
 
 Entertainment Living&amp;Loving Mahogany Love Welcome Forum BV Caucus 
 
 Faith&amp;Religion Ebony&amp;Ivory Parenting Top News General 
 Around the Web Also on AOL 
 Entertainment Newswire | Black Voices
	</body>
</document>
