<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005114" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/60/1490033/restaurant/Northeast-Heights/California-Pastrami-Albuquerque" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="7" score="0.015005815297034335" bingtitle="California Pastrami - Northeast Heights - Albuquerque | Urbanspoon" webtitle="California Pastrami - Northeast Heights - Albuquerque | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000377" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000538" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>Waste of time and money ... About 10 minutes later (yes, 35 minutes to make a sandwich) I recieved my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Albuquerque » Northeast Heights » California Pastrami 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Denver Las Vegas Los Angeles New York Phoenix Salt Lake City Tucson More... 
 
California Pastrami
 
(505) 872-9253
 Northeast Heights 6125 Montgomery Blvd NE 
 Albuquerque , NM 87109 
 californiapastrami.com 
 on facebook.com 

Added by Chris Iller 
 See all 21 reviews Cuisine Sandwiches/Subs , Mexican , Tacos Features Delivery , Free Wi-Fi , Kid Friendly , Late Night Menu $ Under $10 per entree View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late               
   123 people have voted 76 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Olympia Cafe 79% $$ University Heights - Mediterranean, Greek 2210 Central Ave SE 
 
 Red Lobster 54% $$ Northeast Heights - Seafood 5555 Montgomery Blvd NE 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 January 20, 2010 Likes it Gil&apos;s Thrilling (And Filling) Blog Having lived in the East Coast and traveled extensively in the Golden State, the term “California pastrami” gave me nightmarish visions of pesto packed pastrami desecrated with sushi... More from Gil&apos;s Thrilling (And Filling) Blog 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 22, 2012 missed the mark by Morgain ( 8 reviews ) I&apos;m on the fence about this place. My sandwich wasn&apos;t bad (if a bit soggy), but for $13 (included fries and a drink), I&apos;m not sure I&apos;ll be back. Seems like there are better options out there, for the price. May 13, 2012 Mobile review by Samantha Sonntag Olivas ( 1 review ) This was the only Reuben I have ever had where they actually put enough thousand island. I loved the food and the girl who worked the register was super friendly and sweet. June 3, 2012 by Josh R ( 1 review ) I drive by Calfornia Pastrami everyday on my way home and have been meaning to stop in and give it a try. Well I finally did and I gotta say I wish I hadn&apos;t waited so long. The food was awesome, the place was clean, the people were friendly and accomadating. I&apos;ve been back on several times now and tried 4 or 5 different items and have yet to be dissapointed. I highly recommend you give this place a try the food is wonderful, especially the pastrami sandwiches. . March 8, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Horrible customer service from owner!!!! by Katrina ( 1 review ) The cook (who was also the owner) messed up my order, when i asked if I could get a new order without mustard I could hear him complaining then he looked over the counter and in a rude tone asked&quot;So what do you want me to do switch out the bun?&quot;I told him if it was an issue to make a new burger then I just wouldn&apos;t eat it. He then turned around and proceded to cook. About 5 minutes later he returned my same burger with a new bottom bun but the mustard still on the burger. I have never seen an owner of a buisness treat a customer with so much disrespect. What would have cost him $2 to remake, actually cost him a potential life time customer. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful September 27, 2010 Onion Rings Soggy! Fries Raw! very Disappointed! by Tom Henderson - Rio Rancho ( 1 review ) Albuquerque location. Pastrami was as anticipated,&quot;like California&quot;. Good stuff. Will give them another shot IN SPITE OF THE RAW FRIES and SOGGY ONION RINGS. Overall my much anticipated lunch was salvaged by the great pastrami - which reminded me of Douglas Burgers on Cherry Avenue in Long Beach, CA! If the pastrami had not been SO GOOD - I would never go back after gagging on the fries and onion rings (GREASE CITY). 2 out of 2 found this review helpful May 21, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Chris ( 10 reviews ) Good pastrami sandwich, service a little slow, but not horrible, only complaint is fresh squeezed lemonaid is $2.50 with no refill. A refill is another $1.60. February 13, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Brandi Channon ( 1 review ) The food is WAY over priced. The sign said they had Iced Tea the cashier charged us for it but the didn&apos;t make it that morning and basically said they were not going to make it anytime soon and to drink something else. When we complained he said I am the owners son and we have lunch rush sorry and that was it. If you like a good value, good food and or good customer service DON&apos;T eat at California Pastrami October 15, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Jandro ( 12 reviews ) The pastrami here is great! I just had the pastrami burger which was huge. I agree that the prices are a little high, but this isn&apos;t cheaply made fast food. It is fresh and flavorful and very filling. Definetly worth a try! December 20, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Waste of time and money by Robert ( 5 reviews ) Poor customer service, over-priced sandwiches (though they are good), slow service. My friend and I went and waited and waited.....finally, we had to ask where our food was. Only to find that our order had been sitting at the counter for ten minutes. When we asked for the manager to address the issue, we were blown off. Will not visit again. July 3, 2010 Great Pastrami by AndrogynousPenguin ( 12 reviews ) Great pastrami on rye. Will be going again. October 14, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Justin Martinez ( 1 review ) Best pastrami in Albuquerque by far! I&apos;ve searched everywhere for a REAL pastrami sandwich with real pastrami here in Albuq. and finally found it. Please eat your California Classic like it should be! Musturd and pickles only! You won&apos;t regret it! August 13, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by chris ( 1 review ) The food is ok but way overpriced. The also charged me more than what the price depicted on their menu and when I brought it to the staffs attention they said,&quot;sorry there is nothing we can do, looks like we need a new menu.&quot; April 28, 2011 Great Place!!!!!! by Gabe ( 1 review ) I have ate at California Pastrami many times. They have always treated me with the utmost respect. The food is always delicious there and I always take friends who are looking for a good little place there to try something new. As the owner said don&apos;t let a few bad comments on here scare you away from trying the place out. July 18, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Rod ( 1 review ) I went for the first time last week. The worker was very polite and courteous. After asking if it was my first visit, she offered suggestions and shared what the most popular items were. I ordered the classic. The food was excellent and I will be going back. March 25, 2010 Likes it Amazing by Judie A ( 1 review ) Advise by my daughters, Mom you have to go there! OH MY GOD............. its was so great and reminded me of calif style eatery............Thank God for you I have not had a good pastrami since I left home and that was 6 yrs ago. Today was a taste from the past, keep the good food coming............ February 8, 2011 NEVER AGAIN!! by Adam Gates ( 1 review ) I visited the California Pastrami on San Pedro and Montgomery on 2/8/2011. I placed my order for a Reuben combo, even though I was a little put off by the $11.25 price tag. The place was busy, but as I waited for my order, I noticed that 3 people who had placed thier orders AFTER me had already gotten thier food. About 25 minutes later, I went up to the counter and asked wnhen my order would be ready, and the owner (I&apos;m assuming) told me very rudely,&quot;we&apos;ll get to it when we get to it&quot;. Unbelievable!! About 10 minutes later (yes, 35 minutes to make a sandwich) I recieved my food and left. Several other things about my visit: 1. My order had 13 french fries. That was it...13 fries. 2. Thier grill hood was not working, so the smoke from the food being cooked filled the restaraunt. I am sitting at my desk at work typing this review smelling like I was the one cooking. 3. The sandwich that i waited 35 minutes for was incredibly SOGGY. I will NEVER visit this place again. I am a very patient person, and I don&apos;t typically complain or make a lot of noise, but this was absolutely rediculous. NEVER AGAIN. May 29, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it WORST EXPERIENCE EVER by brandi channon ( 1 review ) DO NOT I repeat DO NOT eat at California Pastrami. The food is decent but not for 12 dollars a person. The service is HORRIBLE. There was a huge sign on the front of the register saying they have iced tea when they did not. When I told the lady we were unhappy she blew us off and when I called to complain they said they were busy and made NO effort whatsoever to try and keep us as a customer. I AM VERY UNHAPPY. It is obvious they do not care about their customers or know how to run a business April 26, 2011 Likes it We regret the negative remarks by Joe ( 1 review ) As the owner of California Pastrami, I would like to let those of you that have not tried of food to come by and try our Sandwiches. We do our best to give superior service and a quality product . I will be the first to admit that in the past we had some employees that make mistakes, and may have not haddled things properly. . Most people love our food. Please dont let a couple of customers out of thousands of satified customers Keep you from eating the best Pastrami in New Mexico . February 9, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Not worth yet by robert ( 1 review ) Not happy at all, the prices were crazy this isnt california you cant charge the same here as there. the wait was long, it took about 40 min to get the food. i ordered a carna asada burrito cause it was one of the cheaper items on the menu. when i got it i found mold on the tortilla so had to take it back and wait another 5 min to re make it. The grill hood wasnt working or something and the whole restaurant was smokey. I&apos;ll never go there again! April 17, 2011 by Brant Palley ( 6 reviews ) Walked into a scene of a customer who had been charged twice on his CC, nobody had any food, the manager looked upset... The cheerful server took my order and smiled, the staff is well trained and dedicated. After a long wait I got my Crazy Pastrami Sandwhich! (The Ruben) What a mess! Rye bread, swiss cheese, thousand island dressing and loads of pastrami. At $9.90 the most expensive sandwich i can remember. But it was good and i ate it all. This is not a chain restaurant, but it looks like it is and it wants to be. Why? 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Joe Pastrami Burger by Joe Eastern Pastrami 
 All 5 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Wing Stop 75% $ Northeast Heights - American Little Caesars Pizza $ Northeast Heights - Pizza Subway $ Northeast Heights - Sandwiches/Subs Ho Ho Chinese 69% $ Northeast Heights - Chinese Viet Q 94% $ Northeast Heights - Vietnamese 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 california pastrami california pastrami albuquerque menu pastrami best hot pastrami in albuquerque best pastrami in albuquerque 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
