<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005881" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20081108133304AAjqM27" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="1" score="0.0012260537482017188" bingtitle="Showing Picky eaters pictures of starving children? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="Showing Picky eaters pictures of starving children? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>... don&apos;t want to eat what I put on the table I excuse them from the table and offer them nothing else until the next meal. My house is not a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Pregnancy&amp;Parenting &gt; Grade-Schooler &gt; Resolved Question 
 educated... Member since: October 08, 2008 Total points: 720 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Showing Picky eaters pictures of starving children?
 Would you consider show a child who is a Picky Eater pictures
of Children Starving to death in other countries child abuse
(I have never done this cause my Daughter is only 1 years old)
I just wanted to find out how others feel about it 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 LET ME CLARIFY MY DAUGHTER IS NOT A PICKY EATER I WAS JUST SIMPLY CURIOUS TO KNOW HOW OTHERS FEEL ABOUT IT 
 4 years ago 
 by gyt Member since: September 01, 2008 Total points: 25,805 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 A young child won&apos;t make the connection. An older child will offer to send the dinner you made to Africa.

Here&apos;s what we did to solve our picky eaters. Serve them the food and give them time to eat it. If they don&apos;t, take the food and put it in the fridge. When they come back saying they are hungry and want a snack, heat the food back up and give it to them again. A child won&apos;t starve himself and will learn to eat.

We had one child that didn&apos;t like anything we served. So, I told him that he would be cooking dinner the next night. He complained that the only thing he knew how to do was put the tomatoes in the veggie dicer. (It&apos;s that kitchen gadget you see on tv where you put the item on the blade and then smash the lid down and the pieces fall in the cup. He was only 5. The next night all we had for dinner was diced tomatoes. He never complained again. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: hahaha when I will definitely put
that in my arsenal for when my daughter
gets older thanks!! 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (14)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by asusan48 Member since: October 18, 2008 Total points: 1,691 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I don&apos;t think this would work. The child is not a picky eater because they want to be - sometimes it&apos;s just a matter of them simply not liking the foods they are offered. Some children refuse to eat vegetables or meats, some refuse to eat certain foods or casseroles. They will eventually outgrow their dislike of certain foods and start eating the majority of foods. (Note, I didn&apos;t say ALL foods, because everyone is an individual, and will retain a dislike for certain things their entire life!)

I have a picky eater myself, who will not eat ANY vegetables, and only recently started eating meats (other than hotdogs and chicken nuggets). I don&apos;t think showing him pictures of starving children would have any effect at all, other than to show him that there are starving children in the world. It wouldn&apos;t affect his eating habits at all. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Mama to 2006&amp;2008 Member since: March 31, 2008 Total points: 12,210 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It depends on the age of the picky eater... If they&apos;re in upper elementary, then no, I&apos;d consider it educational. If they&apos;re in preschool and it&apos;s done in a way that torments them or causes nightmares, then I&apos;d say it&apos;s not the way to go. But then again, my response to picky eaters is to not offer anything special. I don&apos;t know any child who will truly starve themselves. Yes, they might go without a meal or two, but they&apos;ll just eat more at the next meal and once they know that they won&apos;t get something special no matter how much they whine or what fit they pitch, then it cuts down on the mealtime problems. Then again, I also believe in kids trying a bite of everything offered them and saying&quot;I&apos;d prefer more carrots, please&quot;instead of&quot;I hate that chicken, it&apos;s disgusting!&quot; 
Source(s):
 Mom of two little ones and elementary teacher 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Aslan Member since: April 17, 2006 Total points: 15,141 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 why burden a child who has particular tastes with adult issues such as world poverty?

it isn&apos;t as if the child could box up the foods they don&apos;t like and send it over to india or africa to the areas of greatest need is it?

realistically speaking the issues behind starvation among children have little to do with what your own child does or does not eat - it has far more to do with politics and distribution and NOTHING to do with something your own child has any control over 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Olivia J Member since: November 14, 2007 Total points: 57,173 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I don&apos;t know if a young child would really make the connection - and the child may become extremely upset. My parents took my siblings and I all over impoverished areas of Asia and North Africa when I was a young child and I was always a picky eater - I didn&apos;t waste food ever, but I would only eat a select few things. It also turned out that I had multiple food intolerances which was part of my picky-ness. Maybe your daughter is picky because some foods hurt her stomach? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Zeena Member since: March 25, 2008 Total points: 16,394 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No.

I personally don&apos;t think that picky eating has anything to do with being a brat.

I am a VERY picky eater lol.

I am aware of the starving children around the world and I&apos;m glad that I have the opportunity to eat whatever I want however I want.

I would only think about doing that if a kid is being a brat about food rather than being picky about it.


 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by jody Member since: October 22, 2008 Total points: 1,186 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Are you insane? Why would anyone show their child the horror of starvation? Do you really think children will process the image and immediately devour dinner? What&apos;s next? They forget to feed Fido and you show a picture of all the euthanized dogs at the shelter? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Stormy Member since: February 01, 2008 Total points: 27,409 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 That is a dumb idea. I don&apos;t put up with&quot;picky eaters&quot;
If they don&apos;t want to eat what I put on the table I excuse them from the table and offer them nothing else until the next meal. My house is not a fast food restaurant, there are no arches over the roof of our home. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Sue R Member since: September 09, 2008 Total points: 152 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 My 8 year old daughter was a very picky eater. She wouldn&apos;t eat any meat other then chicken. I let her be herself and eat what she likes. Now she eats almost everything. She love fruits and beef. I never made her eat anything she didn&apos;t like. I would never show her pictures of starving children. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Rainia W Member since: August 29, 2007 Total points: 6,602 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Naw. I don&apos;t think that would work. I am a picky eater (extremely picky) and when I am hungry enough I will still eat stuff I don&apos;t like. Don&apos;t force a kid to eat, but also don&apos;t let him have whatever he wants. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by MG Member since: June 12, 2006 Total points: 2,925 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No, I don&apos;t think that&apos;s appropriate. It&apos;s too much for little kids to process and it&apos;s not fair to put them in that position. Lastly, it&apos;s unlikely to change their picky eater habits. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by misskayl... Member since: November 13, 2007 Total points: 1,398 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 That would be an extreme, unless they were picky to the point where they were starving themselves I guess. Explaining to them that there are children around the world who don&apos;t get food to eat might work a little bit better. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by ozboz48 Member since: January 25, 2008 Total points: 81,898 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No, I wouldn&apos;t.

Attempting to induce guilt does not increase children&apos;s appetites.

All the best. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Summer SnowFae Member since: December 25, 2007 Total points: 294 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No Absolutely Not! And that is NOT going to make them eat anymore either! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by sammi Member since: September 05, 2006 Total points: 23,116 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 NO! no body should ever do that that is just sick and wrong! 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Grade-Schooler 

 How do I get my 5 year old to take her meds? Should my 8 1/2 year old have his own gaming computer? Is this kid my cousin or what? How can I report her for doing this to this child? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 
 Adolescent Adoption Baby Names Grade-Schooler Newborn&amp;Baby Other - Pregnancy&amp;Parenting Parenting Pregnancy Toddler&amp;Preschooler Trying to Conceive 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
