<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005354" url="http://www.ehow.com/cooking-techniques/" time="2012-07-12-21:54" support="14" score="0.012262111614180195" bingtitle="Cooking Techniques - How To Information | eHow.com" webtitle="Cooking Techniques - How To Information  | eHow.com">
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001262" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000854" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000352" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001513" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001105" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>Obviously, it&apos;s a simple enough task to go down to the local fast-food restaurant or vending… ... online role-playing game (MMORPG). Unlike in similar MMORPGs, you do not pick ...</description>
	<body>
		food section 
 Basics 
 Cooking Techniques Food Prep Grilling Guide Soups&amp;Sauces 
 Family Cooking 
 Easy Recipes Family Meals Snacks Vegetables 
 Daily Dishes 
 Appetizers&amp;Sides Desserts&amp;Baking Breakfast Entrees World Cuisines 
 Entertaining 
 Beer&amp;Wine Cocktails Party Food Party Tips 
 Rachael Ray 
 
 More eHow 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Food&amp;Drink Cooking Techniques 
 
Cooking Techniques

 
 RSS Show Newest in Cooking Techniques 
 Is Hamburger Meat Spoiled When It Turns Grey or Brown Before Cooking? 
When hamburger meat gets spoiled it will display a few pretty clear signs that you should watch out for. Find out if hamburger meat is spoiled when it turns grey with help from an author and culinary specialist in this free video clip.
 Rubs for Cooking Meat&amp;Seafood 
Different rubs are used for different purposes when it comes to cooking meat. Find out about rubs for cooking meat and seafood with help from an author and culinary specialist in this free video clip.
 Southern Cooking: Carrot Souffle 
A nice carrot souffle is a staple of any good southern menu. Learn about carrot souffle and find out how to bring southern cooking to your own kitchen with help from a personal chef in this free video clip.
 How to Make Sauteed Salmon 
When making sauteed salmon, you&apos;re going to want to keep a few key things in mind. Find out how to make sauteed salmon with help from a talented and dedicated Manhattan chef in this free video clip.
 How to Cook Hulled Buckwheat for Breakfast 
Hulled buckwheat needs to be cooked in a very specific way, especially if you&apos;re cooking it for breakfast. Cook hulled buckwheat for breakfast with help from a teacher of therapeutic nutrition in this free video clip.
 No-Bake, No-Cook&amp;Kid-Friendly Recipe for Fruit 
You can do a lot of different things with fruit that don&apos;t involve any of the normal hassles associated with cooking. Learn about a no bake, no cook and kid friendly recipe for fruit with help from a certified nutritionist in this free video clip.
 How to Make Sure Your Hamburger Is Cooked in the Middle? 
Making sure your hamburger is cooked in the middle is something you need to do to make sure the burger is healthy. Make sure your hamburger is cooked in the middle with help from a celebrity chef in this free video clip.
 Rules for Cooking Medium-Rare Burgers 
When cooking medium rare burgers there are a few rules that you&apos;re going to want to observe. Learn the rules for cooking medium rare burgers with help from a celebrity chef in this free video clip.
 Homemade Five-Spice 
Homemade five-spice is a lot easier to make than you might be assuming. Learn to prepare homemade five-spice with help from a passionate cook obsessed with spices in this free video clip.
 How to Make Cajun Roux for Gravy 
Making Cajun roux for gravy requires you to keep a few key things in mind. Find out how to make Cajun roux for gravy with help from a celebrity chef and cookbook author in this free video clip.
 Science of Flavor 
Raw beef is flavorless.

Chris Loss, director of menu research and development at the Culinary Institute of America, suggests tasting a piece of uncooked hamburger meat.“Besides being a little grossed out by that, you will notice that there’s not a lot in raw meat from a flavor standpoint,”he said.“Think about tartar. You don’t just give somebody a pile of raw meat. You give them capers and some mustard and pepper, something to give it some flavor.”It’s the cooking process that creates all of those familiar flavors, textures and aromas. But there is more to cooking than…
 The Best Method of Cooking Pancakes at Home 
Not all methods for cooking pancakes at home are created equal. Learn about the best method for cooking pancakes at home with help from a longtime kitchen employee in this free video clip.
 Oven Roasted Sweet Potato Salad 
Oven roasted sweet potato salad is a great way to breath new life into an old dish. Make oven roasted sweet potato salad with help from the owner and operator of a variety of food businesses in this free video clip.
 How to Make Food Cook Faster on &quot;Restaurant Story&quot; 
Restaurant Story is an online simulation and role-playing game similar to the Farmville line of games on Facebook. Players build their own restaurant or restaurant empire by creating their restaurant concept, building the restaurant infrastructure and maintaining the kitchen. The goal is to build a restaurant business and make as much money as possible. One way to make more money is to cook the food as quickly as possible so that your restaurant can serve as many customers as possible.
 Brining Potato Wedges 
Potato wedges, sometimes referred to as jojos or mojos, are a large, thick type of french fries. A crust of seasonings and salt often gives potato wedges their flavor and crisps their exteriors. Soaking potato wedges in brine increases their internal steam point by around 10 degrees Fahrenheit, creating a fluffier interior.
 How to Braise Meatballs in the Oven 
Braising any type of meat begins with high heat and ends with meat smothered in sauce. Meatballs are a well-known accompaniment to several sauces, which makes them the perfect candidates for braising. In addition to combining the meat and sauce to achieve more complex flavors, braising is also a slow cooking method that allows home chefs to focus their attention elsewhere during meal preparation. To begin braising the meatballs, you must first choose your favorite meatball recipe then a braising liquid.
 How to Make Chicken Maple Gravy 
Maple syrup offers an unexpected flavor surprise in chicken gravy by adding a touch of sweetness to an otherwise savory dish. As with any recipe that calls for maple syrup, chicken maple gravy tastes best when made with true maple syrup rather than imitation syrup that has artificial flavors and preservatives. Chicken maple gravy begins as a simple sauce made with equal parts butter and flour to which chicken stock is added. While additional seasonings enhance the gravy, such as onions, shallots, rosemary or thyme, maple syrup is the only other ingredient needed for chicken maple gravy.
 Cooking Toys for the Kitchen 
Just because you&apos;re cooking doesn&apos;t mean you can&apos;t have a little fun along the way. Learn about cooking toys for the kitchen with help from a chef and culinary instructor in this free video clip.
 How to Clean Baked-On Grease From Cooking Pans 
Cooking pans accumulate grease quickly, and over time that baked-on grease becomes more difficult to tackle. Get rid of baked-on grease with the help of a cleaning coach in this free video.
 What Helps Clean Pots Used to Cook Pasta? 
The pinnacle of what defines Italian cuisine, pasta cooks up quickly and easily with minimal mess. After the pasta is drained from the pot and dinner is served, cleaning up is normally the next step. At a glance, a pot that pasta was cooked in may not appear that dirty, but once you touch it the starchy film left behind is all too apparent. Eliminating the leftover starches from your pot takes little time with a few household items.
 Secrets to Drying Pasta 
The same dried pasta found in stores can be made at home with ingredients found in most households. Pasta dough is made from grains, water and eggs, and the dough is pressed and cut into different shapes. Dried pasta can be stored for up to three years and must be cooked in water to soften it. Pasta is sometimes laid on flat surfaces to dry, which is a difficult task in smaller homes. A few secrets can help you dry your pasta regardless of how much space you have.
 Sanyo Microwave Power Adjustment 
Sanyo offers many microwave models, which feature several ways to control the power level for a cooking cycle. While power adjustment isn’t always necessary, you can adjust the power down for more delicate foods. The units also come with preset food buttons that automatically adjust the power level for certain foods.
 The Best 36 Inch Gas Cook Tops 
Cook tops are flat appliances that function much like a traditional stove. They fit into your countertop for a stylish, slim look in your kitchen and don&apos;t include an oven. Most 36 inch gas cook tops are made of stainless steel and include controls to help you set your burner temperature precisely where you want it.
 How to Cook Food on &quot;Sims World Adventure&quot; on the IPod 
&quot;The Sims 3: World Adventures&quot;for the iPod touch, iPhone and iPad features many of the same features as its PC and console counterparts. For example, players must keep an eye on their Sim&apos;s needs at all times, such as hygiene, social and hunger. To satisfy a Sim&apos;s hunger need, they must eat food daily by preparing themselves a meal. You can prepare a meal for your Sim at any location that features the necessary appliances, such as a stove or a microwave, with the most common location being your house as it starts with all the necessary appliances.
 How to De-Ice a Driveway With Boiling Water 
During the cold, winter months, your driveway can turn into an icy area that is dangerous to your safety and to those who come in contact with it. Several commercial products will melt the ice. However, these commercial deicing products are often expensive and can sell out during the height of the winter season. Instead, use boiling water, which is a safer and cheaper alternative to expensive driveway deicers.
 Alternatives to Downdraft Vents Required for Cooktops 
Proper ventilation in the kitchen is critical to prevent cooking grease from accumulating on surfaces and gases from remaining indoors. Cooktops are counter-placed ranges, separate from an oven. These can be placed anywhere in the kitchen, but a ventilation system must accompany the cooktop. Downdraft ventilation is the usual means of removing excess heat, moisture, grease and odors, but there are alternatives to this if you choose not to use it.
 Information About HVAC Superheat&amp;Subcooling 
Heating, ventilation and air conditioning systems, or HVAC, contain all the elements in your home that provide heating, cooling and air circulation. HVAC technicians monitor these systems through a variety of methods, including superheat and subcooling. These terms relate to temperatures found in systems using refrigerant and compressors, such as an HVAC system. Superheat and subcooling relate not just to temperatures in a system, but also pressure.
 Sanitation for Cooking Meat 
Bacteria, parasites and viruses can contaminate meat products, which can cause diarrhea, vomiting, cramps and other serious illnesses. Since 5,000 persons in the United States die from food related pathogens every year, you should follow proper sanitation methods when cooking meat to kill meat-borne pathogens, according to the Centers for Disease Control.
 Hoosier Cabinet Types 
A Hoosier cabinet is more than just a cabinet; it is an entire kitchen workstation. From its earliest incarnation, it was designed to help the cook do his job more efficiently -- and with less help. Once you know what identifying features to look for in a Hoosier cabinet, it is easy to recognize one.
 How to Cook Bratwurst 
Bratwurst can be cooked in a few different ways depending on your preferences. Learn how to cook bratwurst with help from an author and a chef in this free video clip.
 How to Cook Filo Dough on the Stove Top 
Filo dough, also spelled Phyllo, is made up of layers and layers of buttery dough. It cooks up very flaky and it is similar in many ways to puff pastry. It is also normally cooked in the oven. However there are methods you can use to cook filo dough on the stove top. The first way is to fry the thawed filo dough, and the second way is to poach it in broth or water. The first is probably the more preferred method, because it resembles the oven method, although it will be a bit crisper and have a slightly…
 How to Make Tomato Chutney 
Using tomatoes in chutneys can really add different flavor and texture. Make tomato chutney with help from a celebrity chef who trained at the Culinary Institute of America in this free video clip.
 Wine-Braised Short Ribs 
Join Josh Ozersky as he makes his favorite breakfast, lunchtime and dinner meal – braised short ribs. They get better overnight so be sure to make enough for leftovers.
 How to Make Pan Gravy 
An essential on the holiday table, Josh Ozersky’s turkey pan gravy, starts with the bird’s meaty dregs and ends with a beautiful homemade sauce.
 How to Grow&amp;Cook Tomatillos 
Tomatillos need to be grown and cooked in a very specific way. Learn how to grow and cook tomatillos with help from a social entrepreneur in this free video clip.
 How to Reheat Tamales Using a Steamer 
There&apos;s a reason that tamales are the food of choice for large gatherings and celebrations. You can make them weeks or months in advance, freeze them and reheat just before you need them. You can microwave tamales, but they tend to dry out. Reheating tamales in a steamer helps keep them moist and firm while ensuring that they are heated through. If you don&apos;t have a steamer, you can use a 
steamer insert in a deep pot.
 How to Cook a Good Seasoned Hamburger on a Stove 
Hamburgers are a simple snack food made almost worldwide with a variety of meats and in numerous styles. Burger patties can be enhanced in a number of ways by adding ingredients to the meat itself. Fresh herbs, seasoning mixes and even cheese can be combined with the ground meat to customize the burger&apos;s final taste. On the simplest level, a mixture of lean and fatty ground meat with basic seasoning and a good technique creates a tasty burger.
 The Igniter Is Not Working on My Kenmore Gas Cook Top 
When you turn the burner control knob on a Kenmore gas cook top, you should hear a ticking noise, which is the ignitor sparking. When the ignitor sparks, the circuit broad is sending a message to the gas flow line to open up and let gas flow. The sparking ignitor will ignite the gas and produce a flame on the burner. Ignitors that don’t spark could have one or more problems preventing the cook top from igniting.
 How to Cook Oatmeal on the Stove Without Scorching the Milk 
Oatmeal is among the healthiest of breakfasts, a hearty and filling hot meal to fuel your body for a busy day. Most standard recipes call for the oats to be cooked in water, then dressed at the table with milk, cream, sugar or whatever other topping appeals to you. However, some prefer their oatmeal cooked in milk, rather than water, which results in a richer and creamier porridge. Unfortunately, the milk tends to scorch on the bottom of the pot. There are several ways to minimize this.
 What Can Be Used As a Thickening Agent in Sauces? 
Sometimes it seems like a sauce can simmer forever without reaching the right consistency. The ideal standard is a sauce that&apos;s thick enough to stick to the back of a spoon, called nape. If your sauce is too thin, add a thickening agent to achieve a sauce that will cling to pasta, meat and vegetables.
 What Is a Code F8 on a GE Profile Range From 1994? 
GE Profile ovens come with a removable meat probe. You can plug the meat probe in when you are cooking meat and insert it into the meat so your oven will keep track of the meat&apos;s proper temperature. This feature is available on older GE Profile units, including the one from 1994. If the meat probe doesn&apos;t work properly, the GE Profile displays an error code of F8.
 How to Set Up for a Chili Cook-Off 
A chili cook-off provides friends and neighbors an opportunity to relax, spend time together, enjoy good food and participate in some friendly competition. A well-organized event will help both the competitors and the guests relax and get the most out of the event. Set up one table for each team or competitor. Ask each competitor to submit the name of his chili recipe ahead of time, allowing you to create a reference list for tasters to take notes on.
 How to Cut Eggplant When Sauteeing 
Eggplant is not exactly a staple at American dinner tables, though some people are big fans of the dark purple plant. Eggplant originated in India and was introduced to North America by Thomas Jefferson, who planted it in his native Virginia. As a result, the vegetable is more popular in the southern region of the United States. But you&apos;ll also find it in dishes of Italian, French and Asian origin throughout the nation. Consumers can use eggplant many ways, including sauteing it. The quickest way to saute eggplant is to cube it prior to cooking.
 How to Darken Brass Furniture Nails 
Antique brass has a deep and rich patina that covers the original shiny brass. Manufacturers add a special topcoat to brass furniture nails that mimics the richness of the antique style. When you clean the nails, you may remove some of that coating. Even if you have brass nails on an existing piece of furniture, you have the option of darkening the brass. Adding a dark coating to the nails changes the look of the brass and gives the piece a slightly antiqued look.
 Opening&amp;Closing an Oven When Cooking 
Cooking instructions will state to avoid opening the oven repeatedly during cooking. Not following this instruction can cause problems when cooking or baking and may make your energy bills rise. Depending on the food in the oven, opening the oven during cooking even just once could cause irreversible damage to the food, especially with airy dishes like angel food cakes, meringues and souffles. Reduce the negative consequences of opening the oven door while cooking by properly checking on the food that&apos;s in the oven.
 How Do I Unlock My GE Oven So I Can Cook Food Again? 
Some models of GE stove ovens come equipped with locks that prevent them from opening during high-temperature cleaning cycles. This safety feature can sometimes malfunction, however. Sometimes a door lock will engage accidentally during a regular cooking cycle, preventing you from cooking more food. Another situation with an unlocking oven can occur after a cleaning cycle. To be able to cook food again, there are several things you can do to try to unlock the door without having to call for professional service.
 How to Advertise for a Chili Cook-Off 
A chili cook-off allows entrants to compete against other chili makers locally, regionally, nationally and even internationally to see who has the best chili. Chilis are judged on several factors, such as flavor, consistency, color and heat. Traditional chilis are made without beans or pasta and made with meats, tomatoes, tomato sauce and some form of heat, whether in fresh or powder form. Advertising your chili cook-off requires getting the word out through local media outlets and other avenues.
 Fun Invitation Ideas for Chili Cook-Offs 
A chili cook-off has an assortment of flavors as people create their own interesting recipes, but the creativity of the event doesn&apos;t have to end there. Get the most out of your cook-off by creating interesting and fun invitations to whip your guests into an excited mood before they even arrive.
 How to Protect the Cabinet From a Gas Cook Top 
Ideally, an exhaust hood should be installed between a gas cook top and any overhead cabinetry, or there should be no cabinets over the cook top at all. If neither option is possible, there should be a clearance of at least 24 inches between the cook top and the bottom of the cabinet. You&apos;ll also need to add some extra protection to the cabinet bottom to prevent damage from heat, steam and cooking oil.
 How to Bleach Khakis White 
Bleaching khakis can be a very complicated process because of the different fibers used to make khakis. Though the color khaki is so often used to describe a kind of pant that it has become a catch-all phrase for the garment, it is still a color and not a fabric. Khaki-colored clothes are made from all kinds of natural and synthetic fibers, some of which cannot be bleached. If the khakis are made from cotton, wool or a blend of both, it is possible to bleach them completely white. Cotton blends with nylon or silk cannot be bleached.
 
 
Narrow Your Selection

 Boil Water Cook in a Pan Learning to Cook Cooking Basics Cook Meat Add Flavor Make Gravy Cook Rice Cooking Methods Cook Pasta Cook on a Stove Cook with a Dutch Oven Cook Fresh Foods Cook Dried Beans Cook for Kids Cook a Ham Cook in Clay Pots Cook in a Rice Cooker Cook Mexican Food Oven Roast Cooking Classes Cook Vegetarian Cook Tofu Cook with Herbs Wet Ingredients Cook in a Microwave Braising Culinary Arts Cook Soup Cook Outdoors Cook Grain French Cooking Save Time in the Kitchen Cook Frozen Foods Cook with Gas Cook with Salt Cook Safely Recipe Substitutions Cook Hamburgers Recipe Books Substitute Ingredients Steam Rice Cook Burgers Thicken Sauce Cook with Bananas Cook with Infrared Cook with Convection Cook Perfect Rice Solar Cooking Cook Stuffing Cook Southern Food Other Cooking Techniques Cook Deer Microwave Rice Macrobiotic Cooking Cook Garlic Cook Chili Cook Pumpkin Cook in a Crockpot Toast in an Oven Cook Breakfast Cook a Pie Boil Pasta Sauteeing Cook Lasagna Pan Fry Burgers Cook Lentils Microwave Fudge Create Appetizers Cook Curry Sautéing 
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
