<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005041" url="http://www.whptv.com/content/Archive/default.aspx" time="2012-07-12-21:34" support="18" score="0.018303742708468514" bingtitle="CBS 21 News Coverage By Date - CBS 21 News - Breaking news, sports ..." webtitle="CBS 21 News Coverage By Date - CBS 21 News - Breaking news, sports and weather for the Harrisburg -York -Lancaster -Lebanon Pennsylvania area">
			<query id="000593" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001316" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001429" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000406" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="001442" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001474" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001002" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>... at local fast food restaurant Upon arrival of officers, two females were found to be actively fighting behind the front counter and ... cash, a credit card and ... after he put ...</description>
	<body>
		Search CBS21.com Search the Web Search Video 
 
 Home News Weather Sports Traffic VIDEOS Entertainment Business Keys to Caring Slideshows Seek It Local Daily Deals 
 
 Top Stories 
 Sandusky Scandal Capital City In Crisis R.J. Harris Commentary Face The State Special Reports News By County Cool Schools Crime Report Election 2012 Find It Help Wanted Living Well News By Date OMG! Political Insiders Spot Crime Technology News 
 Sandusky Scandal Capital City In Crisis R.J. Harris Commentary Face The State Special Reports News By County 
 Adams County Berks County Cumberland County Dauphin County Franklin County Lancaster County Lebanon County Mifflin County Perry County Snyder County York County 
 State News National News 
 Political News Product Recalls 
 World News OMG! Gas Prices Product Recalls Health News 

 Tech News Most Popular Gas Tracker Send us photos or video Of Interest 
 Environmental News Fascinating Facts Slideshows Spot Crime This Day In History 
 
 Home : News : Top Stories : News By Date 
 Breaking News 
 
 LIVE STREAMING COVERAGE: SPECIAL COVERAGE : Penn State Board of Trustees news conference 
 + - LIVE STREAMING COVERAGE: SPECIAL COVERAGE : Penn State Board of Trustees news conference Watch live streaming coverage of the reaction of the Penn State Board of Trustees to the release of the Freeh Report on Penn State. 
 
 
CBS 21 News coverage by date
 
July, 2012
 

 07/12 
 SPECIAL COVERAGE : Penn State Board of Trustees news conference 
Watch live streaming coverage of the reaction of the Penn State Board of Trustees to the release of the Freeh Report on Penn State.

 Governor Corbett reacts to the information released in the Freeh Report 
Governor Tom Corbett says he has yet to read the report into the Jerry Sandusky child sex scandal at Penn State.

 New Salem Borough enacts burn ban 
New Salem Borough in York County has enacted a burn ban as of July 11, 2012.

 PetSmart to build new distribution center in Berks County 
PetSmart Inc., a national retailer with more than 1,200 stores, will locate its new distribution center in Berks County and create at least 500 jobs.

 Paterno son: Joe took no part in abuse cover-up 
Joe Paterno&apos;s son denies the late coach took part in a cover-up of child sex abuse, saying his father never attempted to conceal reports of abuse by longtime assistant Jerry Sandusky.

 Some call for Paterno statue to be removed 
As the details from the Freeh Report come to light, there are some calling for the removal of the Joe Paterno statue.

 FOR SALE: $50K drones for &apos;monitoring capabilities&apos; 
Not just for military use, drones turn civilian.

 Man eaten by tigers after he broke into zoo 
Suicide by tiger: Man, 20, eaten alive in big cat enclosure after breaking into zoo at night

 Attorney General says Freeh report won&apos;t hinder jury&apos;s work 
Pennsylvania&apos;s top prosecutor says the newly issued report into how Penn State handled the Jerry Sandusky child molestation matter won&apos;t harm the work of an investigative grand jury.

 Former Pa. special ed prof faces more porn counts 
A former university professor who specialized in special education faces additional federal child pornography charges.

 Manheim Township incident report 07.12.12 

 USDA declares biggest disaster ever 
One-third of America&apos;s counties now natural-disaster areas.

 The web&apos;s first photo 
It was an instantly forgettable, poorly Photoshopped publicity shot of an uber-nerdy novelty musical act called Les Horribles Cernettes.

 UPDATE : Robbery-shooting victim shot three times 
During the robbery a shooting occurred and a person was shot.

 The high privacy price of auto insurance monitoring discounts 
Data about location and driving habits speak volumes about drivers&apos; personal and private lives.

 Paterno family releases comment on the Freeh Report 
&quot;From the moment this crisis broke, Joe Paterno supported a comprehensive, fair investigation. He always believed, as we do, that the full truth should be uncovered.&quot;

 VIDEO : Complete news conference on release of the Freeh Report on Penn State 
If you missed the live coverage, watch the entire news conference here.

 VIDEO : Louis Freeh comments on PSU report 
Watch Louis Freeh&apos;s comments on the report from this morning&apos;s news conference.

 Upper Allen Township Police incident report - 07.12.12 

 PSU trustees to hold news conference on report 
Penn State&apos;s Board of Trustees have scheduled an afternoon news conference to discuss the findings of former FBI director Louis Freeh&apos;s report on the Jerry Sandusky child sex abuse scandal.

 York County woman arrested after stealing more than $300,000 from elderly aunt 
A York County woman was arrested last week on charges that she stole more than $300,000 from her elderly aunt.

 Man gets 30 to 60 years for 5-hour long car raping 
A man will spend 30 to 60 years in prison for repeatedly raping and beating a woman in her own car after she left a bar nearly four years ago.

 Louis Freeh&apos;s comments on the report 
Remarks by Freeh on the investigation.

 The Freeh Report on Penn State 
The report on the investigation is now available.

 50th anniversary of first TV satellite 
Fifty years ago today a beach ball-sized satellite carried the first television images across the Atlantic, kicking off a new era of global communications decades before the Internet.

 Eight-year-old killed when engine parts fly through windshield 
Authorities say an 8-year-old girl was killed and her mother lost part of an arm when engine parts fell off an oncoming semitrailer and crashed through the windshield of their SUV.

 Prosecutor set to release Zimmerman evidence at 10 a.m. 
Report to include a first look at what FBI agents have turned up in their civil rights investigation.

 Man charged for torturing, chaining woman for nearly 10 years 
He is accused of keeping his wife captive and torturing her for the better part of a decade — beating and burning her and even leaving her shackled during childbirth.

 Penn State&apos;s Sandusky report will draw scrutiny 
The results of Penn State&apos;s internal investigation into the Jerry Sandusky scandal are about to be released, in the form of a report that could answer many of the troubling questions swirling around one of the darkest scandals in sports history.

 More reason to cheer: Cardinals cheerleader now beating rheumatoid arthritis 
Cortney Timmons from Chambersburg was in so much pain once, she could barely brush her own teeth. It&apos;s hard to believe that a 21-year-old could be diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis, reports CBS 21 News Sports Director Jason Bristol.
 07/11 
 Nelo gives up winning hit at Eastern League All-Star game 
The East Division All-Stars defeated the West Division All-Stars 5-4 on Wednesday at the Eastern League All-Star game in Reading.

 Harrisburg School Board votes to reinstate programs, teachers with extra money 
In addition to fundraising, the school district received $1.7 million additional dollars from the state.

 Actress knocked unconscious in accident on the set of &apos;The Good Wife&apos; 
Actress Kristin Chenoweth was on set for a guest appearance in New York.

 Freeh Report expected to reveal details in to Penn State&apos;s involvement in scandal 
We are just hours away from hearing the details on PSU’s internal investigation.

 Penn State approves new policy for athletics access 
Penn State has approved a new policy that limits the use of athletic facilities to players and athletic department personnel during normal operating hours.

 Construction set to close Windy Hill Road for four months 
Windy Hill Road in Shrewsbury Township, York County, will be closed to through traffic for nearly four months starting on Monday, July 16.

 Ephrata fire displaces residents after porch goes up in flames 
On Wednesday around 2 p.m., a fire on the front porch of a home in the first block of South Maple Street was reported.

 Dauphin County allocated over $6.4 million in disaster recovery funds 
“This much-needed funding will help us cope with unmet housing, business and infrastructure needs beyond those addressed by other forms of public and private assistance,” said Commissioner Jeff Haste.

 Penn Staters for Responsible Stewardship release checklist for Freeh Report 
The organization has developed a comprehensive checklist of information that we not only expect -- but demand -- to be covered in the report

 UPDATE(2): Man killed just feet from his own home in motocycle crash 
A motorcycle crash that occurred just after 5 p.m. killed one.

 Jury selection underway for teacher who allegedly had sex with pupils 
Christy Smith was an English teacher at McCaskey High School when she was arrested for having sex with a student.

 Having sex up to seven times a day helping world&apos;s largest woman slim down 
A 643-pound-woman, has lost 100 pounds thanks to marathon sex sessions with her ex-husband.

 Man who pointed gun at pizza delivery man has charges dropped 
After hearing testimony Wednesday afternoon, Judge Jessica Brewbaker dropped the simple assault charge.

 Animal advocates say dog fighting is a big problem in local cities 
A pitbull named “Honey&quot; has brought new attention to dog fighting.

 Harrisburg Mayor, residents go at it in meeting over city&apos;s finances 
Things got rather heated during the regularly scheduled financial recovery meeting.

 Paterno letter focuses on upholding PSU football name 
The letter doesn&apos;t give details about what Paterno said before the Grand Jury.

 Capitals Re-sign Center Zach Hamill 
The Washington Capitals have re-signed center Zach Hamill to a one-year contract.

 Penn State defends themselves against Spanier&apos;s email request 
Paperwork filed by Penn State University defends their response to a law suit involving former President Graham Spanier.

 No trial date set after hearing for Tim Curley and Gary Schultz 
Tim Curley and Gary Schultz were not in Dauphin County for the hearing.

 Cumberland County to investigate death of young woman in prison 
Cumberland County Commissioners are conducting an investigation into the tragic death of 20-year-old Taylor Bolen.

 Neely Spence named PSAC Scholar-Athlete of the Year 
Shippensburg&apos;s Neely Spence and West Chester&apos;s Joe Wendell named 2011-12 PSAC Scholar-Athletes of the Year.

 Caught in Act: Police nab man trying to escape from attempted burlgary in Susquehanna Township 
A man in Susquehanna Township was caught by police trying to escape from a home he was burglarizing, after the resident came home to the incident.

 Pennsylvania plans trial smoking ban in state parks 
State officials are planning a trial smoking ban next year in two Pennsylvania state parks as they deal with complaints about litter.

 Joe Paterno pens letter to former players before his death 
The following column was written by the former Penn State coach in late December and early January, less than a month before he died of lung cancer.

 Arrest made in several burglaries in Lower Paxton Township 
Kristopher Whitcomb was arrested for several burglaries that occurred recently in Lower Paxton Township.

 Child found in North Middleton Township 
Police reported to a home in North Middleton Township, after a person found a child wandering in the area. The mother and child have been reunited.

 Police release photo of suspect vehicle in York County puppy-napping 
Police have released a photo of the vehicle that suspects used, after stealing a puppy from a car.

 Carlisle man charged for concealing heroin in underwear 
A Carlisle man is facing multiple drug charges, after a police search finds him hiding 199 baggies of heroin in his underwear.

 2 killed in vehicle accident in Perry County 
Two people were killed, after their vehicle was struck by a tractor trailer, Tuesday morning.

 UPDATE: Man killed after vehicle strikes tree in York County 
Police are investigating a fatal crash in Windsor Township.
 07/10 
 Senators&apos; Rahl wins bizarre Eastern League HR derby 
The Reading Phillies put together a wild, wacky Eastern League home run derby -- with an intern in a dunk tank; a bouncing man on a trampoline and a wet bar in the infield.

 Calling 911 could save your life 
RJ Harris suffered a mild stroke last Friday morning on his radio show, but the key is that he realized the symptoms.

 Could Harrisburg City Council members go to jail for not following receiver&apos;s plan? 
At the heart of the matter, a huge tax increase he wants to put on the city residents.

 Homes evacuated as police get involved in standoff with mental health patient 
Holy Spirit Hospital called police for help just after 3:30 Tuesday afternoon.

 Dog injured in dogfighting ring on its way to a long recovery 
Doctors taking care of her say Honey was so beat up, bone was actually showing on the one side of her jaw.

 Additional $2 million will help Harrisburg School District 
A business manager for the school says that cash could be used to bring back the athletics program.

 Brewers to recall Lampeter-Strasburg&apos;s Bianchi from minors 
Jeff Bianchi, a middle infielder, hit .351 for Double-A Huntsville in 19 games before earning a promotion to Triple-A Nashville, where he was hitting .305 in 174 at-bats.

 Joe Paterno family releases statement on his role in investigation 
Over the last nine months Joe Paterno has been praised by some in near saintly terms and criticized by others as a villain. He was neither.

 Lawmakers pushing to get rid of law preventing gay men from giving blood 
The push is on to change the law which prevents gay men from donating blood.

 Freeh report to be released Thursday as Penn State braces for feedback 
We&apos;ll know Thursday if Penn State made bad decisions in the Sandusky investigation.

 York man arrested for raping several girls who were not even 10-years-old 
Police arrested, 32-year-old Anton Carter, who lived in the city of York.

 Old baseball cards in Ohio attic might fetch millions 
Two cousins came across the cards from 1910 in a soot-covered box last February in the Ohio town of Defiance. They say the cards belonged to their grandfather, who died in the 1940s.

 DA says access to synthetic drugs is too easy for teens 
Police in Cumberland County have seized more than a half million dollars in illegal synthetic drugs from two Carlisle convenience stores.

 Lawsuit filed against man who lied about being abused by Sandusky 
A federal judge is throwing out a lawsuit filed by a man claiming he was sexually abused by Sandusky back in 2002.

 &apos;Freeh Report&apos; on Sandusky investigation to be released Thursday at 9:00 a.m. 
Judge Louis Freeh announced today that the reort will be available on-line Thursday morning.

 Eagles extend deal for training camp site 
The team announced on Tuesday it extended its deal with the school for one more year. The Eagles have been training at Lehigh every summer since 1996.

 UPDATE(3): Suspect from BELCO robbery taken into custody by police after standoff 
A bank robbery took place around 2 p.m. at the BELCO Credit Union on Second Street.

 Former Penn State President Spanier met with Freeh investigators 
Attorneys for Dr. Graham Spanier Tuesday confirmed that Dr. Spanier was interviewed at length on Friday by representatives of the Freeh Investigative Group

 UPDATE(3): Lancaster fire sends five to the hospital, displaces dozens 
A fire in Lancaster Township at the intersection of Misty Road and Kensington Road has reached four alarms.

 Local soldier killed in Afghanistan in the line of duty 
A Pennsylvania soldier from York County has been killed in Afghanistan.

 Penn State physics professor helps keep world on schedule 
How much is a fraction of a second worth? It could cost millions of dollars during a crash of the stock market, when panic selling causes investment values to plummet.

 Spanier says never told of abuse 
Lawyers for Graham Spanier say the former Penn State president has told investigators hired by the university that he was not told of an incident involving former assistant coach Jerry Sandusky that described child abuse, sexual misconduct or&quot;criminality of any kind.&quot;

 Couple accused of trying to smuggle infant onto plane in luggage 
An Egyptian couple is accused of trying to smuggle their 5-month-old child in their luggage.

 Man kills Pa cop in high-speed chase, just after being rejected for job on police force 
Police say man who wanted to become a cop was driving the car that struck a police cruiser, killing a cop.

 UPDATE: Large synthetic drug bust takes in Carlisle seizes half a million 
Seizure is largest in Cumberland County history.

 Wisconsin federal judge dismisses Sandusky lawsuit 
A federal lawsuit filed by a man alleging that former Penn State football coach Jerry Sandusky sexually abused him during a Wisconsin Badgers home football game in 2002 has been dismissed by a judge who called the allegations frivolous and malicious.

 Grandma says daughter took kids to buy drugs 
A woman has been charged with endangering her three children after the children&apos;s grandmother told police the woman had taken the children with her when she&apos;d buy and use drugs.

 Manheim Township Police incident report 07.10.12 

 Big 33 holding &apos;Night at The Vineyard&apos; at Hershey 
The Big 33&apos;s &apos;A Night at the Vineyard&apos; will include tastings of world-class wine, along with an outdoor concert by Not Quite Einstein. The festivities kick off at 6:30 p.m.

 North Lebanon Township Police incident report 07.10.12 

 No Chronic Wasting Disease so far in Pa deer herd 
Chronic wasting disease (CWD) was not found in samples taken from hunter-killed deer during the state’s 2011 hunting season, according to Dr. Walt Cottrell, Pennsylvania Game Commission wildlife veterinarian.

 Crime Stoppers of Dauphin County offering reward for information 
If you have information on any fugitives or crimes, please call Det. Sgt. Dave Hodges at Crime Stoppers of Dauphin County at 1-800-262-3080

 Are Jon and Kate Gosselin reuniting as a couple? 
It’s not just Kate who daydreaming about happier days. Jon Gosselin seems to be warming up to reconciliation too.

 Illusionist rushed to hospital after &apos;hook from eye&apos; trick goes hideously wrong 
Russian illusionist Ilya Safronov was rushed to hospital after swallowing a razor sharp hook during a magic trick that went horribly wrong.

 Are we safe from the sun? 
Solar flares keep on getting stronger - with latest hotspot the size of 15 Earths strung together.

 Sitting too much may shave years off our lives 
Sitting too much is a serious health threat, a new study suggests.

 School is too easy, students report 
Millions of kids simply don’t find school very challenging, a new analysis of federal survey data suggests.

 Alligator bites off teen&apos;s forearm in attack during swim 
A teenager has lost his right arm below the elbow to an attacking alligator.

 Woman killed in Union Township crash on Moonshine Road 
A woman was killed while driving through Union Township Monday afternoon.
 07/09 
 Rahmer captures Speed Week crown, Stevie Smith wins Mitch Smith Memorial 
Fred Rahmer didn&apos;t win a race during PA&apos;s Speed Week. It didn&apos;t matter, though. He was consistent enough in all eight races to claim the points championship.

 Groff goes deep for first Midwest League HR 
Eric Groff, playing for Arizona&apos;s Midwest League farm team, went 2-for-4 with a home run Monday in South Bend&apos;s 10-2 win over Fort Wayne. Groff graduated from Northern Lebanon High School.

 Eash claims 358 feature win at Lincoln; Armstrong slips past Knaub at Trail-Way 
Hanover’s Cris Eash tied Doug Esh for second on Lincoln&apos;s all-time win list after taking Saturday’s 358 sprint car feature; Tyler Armstrong claimed Friday&apos;s 358 late model at Trail-Way Speedway.

 Court date set to hear Graham Spanier&apos;s lawsuit against PSU 
Former Penn State President Graham Spainer will be in court next month.

 Young girl turns on refurbished Nintendo DS, find pornography on it 
Six-year-old Seleina was a little too shy to tell us what she found on her Nintendo.

 Credit union debit card scam texting many, claiming many victims 
It&apos;s a scam that is spreading across the Commonwealth and gaining momentum and victims.

 Construction on Interstate 83 set to cause traffic delays 
For the next several nights, motorists on Interstate 83 in York County are advised they may encounter short-term traffic stoppage

 Lancaster Crime Stoppers searching for two suspects in Columbia stabbing 
On June 17 at approximately 3:16 a.m., Jose Rivera, 22 years of age, was stabbed during an altercation.

 Reading Royals join Bears, Capitals family 
The Washington Capitals have agreed to an affiliation agreement with the Reading Royals of the East Coast Hockey League (ECHL), the team announced.

 Nine killed statewide in Fourth of July crashes investigated by State Police 
Nine people were killed and 312 people injured in crashes investigated by the Pennsylvania State Police during the Fourth of July holiday.

 UPDATE: Warm weather brings out burglars to Lancaster City 
During the recent hot weather, Lancaster City Police saw an increase in the number of burglaries in Lancaster.

 Freeh Report to play a big role in the civil cases against Penn State 
Both attorneys we spoke to Monday nave not been contacted by Penn State.

 PNC Bank on Carlisle Street in Hanover robbed Monday afternoon 
The PNC Bank on Carlisle Street in Hanover was robbed on Monday around 225 p.m.

 Bethesda Mission holds golf tournament to help substance abuse program 
Monday was the 22nd tournament to benefit &quot;Helmsman,&quot; Bethesda&apos;s long-term substance abuse program.

 Corn crop could be drying up if we don&apos;t see some rain 
This hot and dry weather we’ve been having lately is really taking its toll on local crops.

 Firefighters arrive home to Central PA after battling Colorado wildfires 
Monday afternoon a charter flight brought 60 Pennsylvania fire fighters back home.

 Nine people taken into hospital after van gets slammed into by tractor-trailer 
State Police are investigating a crash on Interstate 81 near Carlisle that resulted in multiple injuries.

 Two men who ran over a police officer set to surrender 
One turned himself in already, the other is expected to Tuesday along with his attorney.

 Bed bugs disturbing a family, property manager says they&apos;re taking action 
The mom we spoke to says her four kids are covered in bites from bed bugs.

 Donation of $10,000 to help Harrisburg get illegal guns off the streets 
A program to get illegal guns off the streets of Harrisburg has gotten a boost thanks to an anonymous donation.

 York County woman gets up close encounter with young bear 
The bear, believed to be about two to three years old, walked right up on her porch.

 UPDATE: Police name several suspects in early Sunday stabbing in Lancaster 
Police say there was some sort of fight that broke out after the victim was approached by a large group.

 Man gets more than he bargained for while trying to steal copper from couple 
A member of a Camp Hill family reportedly fired shots at a criminal fleeing from their home early Sunday.

 Woman attacked with knife and brick in wild fight at Chuck E. Cheese 
A woman was taken to jail after a wild fight this weekend inside a Chuck E. Cheese’s restaurant.

 2012-13 tuition rates set by board 
Board of Governors: Increase matches inflation rate for fifth time in eight years, honors commitment to Legislature and Governor

 New mosquito collections from York County test positive for West Nile 
For 2012, fourteen mosquito collections have tested positive for West Nile Virus in York County.

 Harrisburg City police incident report - 07.09.12 

 PSU: Donations 2nd highest in school history 
Penn State received more than $208 million in donations last fiscal year, the second-highest total in university history despite the upheaval after the arrest of Jerry Sandusky on child sex abuse charges.

 Lebanon Police investigating armed robbery by police impersonators 

 Marine goes undercover to expose girlfriend&apos;s rapist 
Befriends alleged perpetrator Elric Shawn Millner.

 The Dark Knight Rises - and crashes: Students discover Batman&apos;s cape gliding technique is fatally flawed 
Batman returns to cinemas for the Dark Knight Rises this month (July 20) - but unless he has invested in a new cape, he may fall into some trouble.

 Manheim Township incident report 07.09.12 

 State Police to close Ephrata barracks, keep Lancaster 
The Ephrata State Police Station will close effective August 17.

 State Police release holiday enforcement numbers 
Troopers working during the holiday period engaged in high visibility enforcement efforts.

 &apos;Internet Doomsday&apos; virus fizzles, web traffic flows 
Fears that a computer virus might cut Internet access around the world appeared to be overblown.

 Caught on video: News crew attacked with fireworks 
A news crew was on location along with a couple of police officers, for a story about a house that had hit by Roman Candles when they were attacked with fireworks.

 Farm Aid benefit concert heading to Hershey, Pa. 
The annual Farm Aid benefit concert is coming to Hershey in September.

 Police: Hug triggers officer&apos;s gun, kills woman... 
A woman celebrating the weekend before her 25th birthday was fatally shot Sunday when she hugged an off-duty police officer while dancing at a party.

 Board to weigh tuition hike at state universities 
Students and their families will soon find out whether they&apos;ll have to pay more in tuition at Pennsylvania&apos;s 14 state-owned universities.

 Bret Michaels meets with fans, shows off &apos;Pets Rock&apos; collection 
If Bret Michaels has his way, every rose will have its thorn and every dog owner that shops at PetSmart will buy one of his new rock &apos;n&apos; roll-themed pet products.

 Kate Gosselin cries while watching &apos;Jon and Kate Plus 8&apos; 
Kate tweeted, &quot;We are watching the St Jude&apos;s episode... I am crying... Happy and sad tears.. Old episodes of Jon&amp;Kate;+8 warms our hearts...&quot;

 Pa. elections website maintains old info on ID law 
Pennsylvania&apos;s votespa.com website continues to maintain information suggesting that general election voters don&apos;t need to show photo identification, although a new law requires specific kinds of photo ID to ensure their ballots are counted in November.

 East Lampeter Township police incident report 07.09.12 

 Face The State: Governor Tom Corbett 
Pennsylvania Governor Tom Corbett is this edition&apos;s guest

 Woman attacked with knife and brick in wild fight at Chuck E. Cheese 
A woman has been jailed on charges she attacked her ex-boyfriend&apos;s new girlfriend and other women with a knife and a brick at a pizza restaurant during a party for her son.

 Probe eyes Paterno&apos;s preference for handling problems internally 
Former FBI Director Louis Freeh&apos;s investigation into possible wrongdoing at Penn State University appears to be examining football coach Joe Paterno&apos;s apparent preference for handling scandalous issues internally.

 Dogs may protect babies from some infections: study 
Babies who spend time around pet dogs have fewer ear infections and respiratory ailments than those whose homes are animal-free.

 Privacy risk from ads in apps rising: security firm 
Some advertising networks have over the last year started to secretly collect app users contacts or whereabouts.

 Internet goes offline for thousands as DNSChanger cleanup peaks 
Thousands of internet users are waking up to no web connection this morning.

 Would-be thieves use front-end loader, dump truck to steal ATM machine 
The two men who stole a front-end loader and a dump truck and then used them to try and steal an ATM cash machine.

 Man nears 3 millionth mile in beloved &apos;66 Volvo 
It just keeps going, and going, and going.

 Gift cards for the needy taken from Calvary U.M. in Lemoyne 
Police say someone broke into a central Pennsylvania church and made off with $1,000 in gift cards that were supposed to go to the needy for help buying groceries.

 Toddler dies in dirt bike crash 
Officials say a Pennsylvania toddler is dead after a dirt bike he was riding on crashed into another vehicle over the weekend.

 UPDATE: Sawmill fire causes damage, injures firefighter 
Officials in York County are trying to figure out what sparked an early morning sawmill fire.
 07/08 
 Oscar-winning film star Ernest Borgnine dies at age 95 
His longtime spokesman, Harry Flynn, says that Borgnine died at Cedars-Sinai Medical Center with his family by his side.

 Mom kills 9-year-old son with hammer, then attempts suicide 
A 40-year-old Brooklyn mother called 911 late Friday saying that she had killed her son and had taken pills to end her own life.
 07/07 
 City Islanders manage tie against Barracuda FC 
Harrisburg&apos;s Sainey Touray dove for a long cross from fellow sub Colin Zizzi and scored in stoppage time as Harrisburg tied Antigua Barracuda FC 1-1 on Saturday at the Skyline Sports Complex.

 Bryce Harper to All-Star game; Desmond out due to injury 
Atlanta Braves outfielder Michael Bourn and 19-year-old Washington phenom Bryce Harper are going to the All-Star game after all.

 Barnstormers bullpen gets down to &apos;Call Me Maybe&apos; 
The Lancaster Barnstormers bullpen shows off its choreography skills; dancing to &apos;Call Me Maybe&apos; during a game on July 6, 2012 against the Long Island Ducks.

 Capitals sign forward Ryan Stoa for Hershey Bears 
Stoa, 25, has played all three of his professional seasons with the Colorado Avalanche organization. He also has 37 games of NHL experience.

 Car chase causes police officer to crash into center barrier 
A fleeing SUV caused a State Trooper to crash on Saturday around 910 a.m.

 Black Bandit Stevie Smith wins Speed Week&apos;s Mitch Smith Memorial 
Hanover native Stevie Smith grabbed the lead from Shane Stewart with ten laps remaining and went on to win PA Speed Week&apos;s Mitch Smith Memorial Friday at Williams Grove Speedway.

 Police investigating burglary of appliances, construction items 
The incident occurred in the 3400 block of Pricetown Road in Ruscombmanor Township, Berks County.

 Star NFL running back Adrian Peterson charged with resisting arrest 
Minnesota Vikings star Adrian Peterson was arrested Friday night in Houston, according to CBS Sports.

 Police investigating stolen Harley-Davidson motorcycle 
State Police are investigating after a Harley Davidson was stolen from the curb in Dauphin County.

 Forecasters warn of heat, humidity danger in Pa. 
The National Weather Service has issued an excessive heat warning for eastern and central Pennsylvania areas where triple-digit temperatures and heat indexes are expected.

 Second alarm house fire tests fire crews on warmest day of the year 
A house fire at 17 Parkview Drive in Mount Joy Township went to second alarm Saturday.

 The former home of Boyd&apos;s Bear Country is up for sale 
The former home of Boyds Bear Country in Gettysburg, is currently on the real estate market.

 Bus driver claims excessive caffeine from coffee made him grope girls 
A school bus driver who was convicted of assault for groping teens and women claims an excessive intake of caffeine drove him to the acts.

 Teen suffers injuries after striking guardrail in accident 
Two teens were involved in an accident Wednesday on Doubling Gap Road in Lower Mifflin Township.

 Ephrata Police report several cases of heat exhaustion from Friday 
Ephrata Police Department&apos;s log from Friday includes several cases of heat exhaustion.

 Lancaster man gets 10 to 20 years in roommate&apos;s death 
A central Pennsylvania man has been sentenced to 10 to 20 years in the shooting death of his roommate two years ago.

 UPDATE(2): Name of man killed in accident on Interstate 81 released 
A fatal accident that occurred just before 7 a.m. has closed one lane of Interstate 81 northbound.
 07/06 
 Barnstormers dance, then easily demolish Ducks 13-1 
The Lancaster Barnstormers amassed 17 hits, drew nine walks, had one batter hit by a pitch and two more reach on errors for a total of 29 baserunners in a 13-1 win over Long Island Friday at Clipper Magazine Stadium.

 Penn St. inquiry nears end, findings expected soon 
Penn State&apos;s internal investigation into the Jerry Sandusky child sexual abuse scandal is drawing to a close, and the findings could be released within weeks.

 Man approaches couple, lies about being a police officer 
Derry Township Police are investigating an incident where a man identified himself as an officer as he interacted with a couple.

 Suspects break into church, steal gift cards for those in need 
The incident occurred at the Calvary United Methodist Church located at 700 Market Street in Lemoyne.

 Two arrested for numerous burglaries after lengthy investigation 
Numerous police agencies worked together to arrest two serial burglars in Harrisburg City Friday.

 UPDATE(2): Woman struck and killed while walking along Route 30 Friday identified 
The accident occurred just after 8 p.m. in the 5000 block of Lincoln Highway, or Route 30.

 City Islanders game-used jerseys up for auction 
The City Islanders are auctioning off special game-worn, red, white and blue jerseys from this Saturday&apos;s game on Military Appreciation Night.

 Fast-food store employees robbed as they close up 
Employees were leaving the fast-food store when a man walked up to them with a gun and demanded money.

 Lancaster County serial burglar now behind bars 
James Jones Jr., 44, was arrested at his place of employment in West Hempfield Township.

 UPDATE: State Capitol deemed safe, bomb scare over 
CBS 21 has learned that a credible bomb threat has the State Capitol evacuated.

 As Hersheypark Arena is cleaned up, it is clear they dodged a bullet 
While Thursday’s fire gave many people a big scare, Friday it was a sigh of relief.

 Community angered after over 30 gravestones are toppled 
Some of these stones weigh hundreds of pounds, so police think more than one person was involved.

 Hershey Bear great speaks to CBS 21 about the history of Hersheypark Arena 
While the fire at the historic Hersheypark Arena didn’t cause too much damage, it did create a few moments of fear.

 Pizaa shop owners become heroes by protecting robbery victim 
The owner of the store used a pizza tray to hold the men back and keep them out of the kitchen and away from the victim.

 Former Penn State President again asks University to give him access to emails 
“Dr. Spanier has every right to review his own decade-old emails, so that he can be adequately informed.&quot;

 City Islanders push back Saturday game time due to heat 
The City Islanders will kick off at 8 p.m. on Saturday instead of 7 p.m., due to the high temperatures forecasted, the team announced.

 CBS 21 looks at how to recognize signs of heat stroke 
When it gets this hot we all need to be careful and look out for one another.

 Taking steps to prepare for flu season should begin now 
Health experts say you should get the flu shot every year.

 Top attorney says an investigation should occur into the death of Taylor Bolen 
West Shore attorney Bill Costopolous says the death of Taylor Bolen of Mechanicsburg is a tragedy.

 Heroin addictions destroying the lives of many mid-state youth 
That addiction may have led a 20-year-old Cumberland Valley High School graduate to take her life.

 Two arrested with synthetic pot at Adams County convenience store 
Mohammah Asharaf Veriatch , age 49, and his son, Usman Asharaf Veriatch, age 20were arrested.

 Researchers develop new Facebook app to detect pedophiles and criminals 
The Social Privacy Protector (SPP) can help parents adjust their children&apos;s profiles in one click.

 Simple steps can shield children from dog bites 
Over 4.7 million people, mostly kids, are bitten every year, experts say.

 Annual gold, silver &apos;deposits&apos; in new high-tech goods worth $21B 
A staggering 320 tons of gold and more than 7,500 tons of silver are now used annually to make PCs, cell phones, tablet computers and other new electronic and electrical products worldwide.

 UPDATE: Man wanted for homicide, investigated for another arrested Friday 
A 17-year-old juvenile wanted on an outstanding Attempted Homicide warrant was taken into custody today.

 Cold turkey for Tori the smoking orangutan 
Tori has smoked for 10 years as visitors throw her lit cigarettes.

 Dismal U.S. hiring shows economy stuck in low gear 
Employers hired at a dismal pace in June, raising pressure on the Federal Reserve to do more to boost the economy and dealing another setback to President Barack Obama&apos;s reelection bid.

 Manheim Township Police incident report 07.06.12 

 Drunk thief falls asleep in the middle of burglary 
Cops find Russian man passed out in apartment owner&apos;s bed

 Wormleysburg resident finds naked man in his bathroom 
Ryan Daniel Stroup insisted he was at his friend&apos;s house.

 Hot? Stay-cool tips from desert-savvy Phoenix 
People in Phoenix have learned a thing or two about surviving scorching summer days.

 Pa. accused of violating US voter registration law 
A new lawsuit says Pennsylvania&apos;s state government isn&apos;t living up to the requirements that public assistance agencies distribute voter registration applications to clients.

 Man beats homeowner, then steals wooden alligator 
A central Pennsylvania man is jailed on charges that he walked into an unlocked mobile home and beat up the resident before stealing the man&apos;s wooden alligator.

 Silver Spring Township incident report 07.06.12 

 Northern York County Regional Police incident report 07.06.12 

 PA State Police paid $85K to settle shackled suspect&apos;s suit 
The Pennsylvania State Police paid $85,000 to settle claims that troopers pepper sprayed and urinated on a woman shackled hand and foot.

 Woman kills herself inside police car with the cop&apos;s own gun 
A mentally ill woman committed suicide by shooting herself in the head with a police officer’s gun while getting a ride to a hospital in a squad car on Wednesday.

 Man pays off mortgage with 800 pounds of pennies 
He says it became an obsession, but a 35-year-old dream became a reality as he paid off his mortgage with pennies.

 Are you infected with DNSChanger malware? 
You might want to double check because come July 9, you might lose access to the Internet.

 2-year-old boy drinks beer from sippy cup, mom arrested 
A mother has been arrested after authorities say she put beer in her 2-year-old son&apos;s sippy cup.

 New sunspot group bombards Earth with solar flares 
One blast disrupts radio communications in Europe.

 Casey Anthony verdict anniversary: Key moments in the dramatic murder case 
This week is the anniversary of Florida mother Casey Anthony&apos;s acquittal in the death of her 2-year-old daughter Caylee

 Hero turns down offer to return to lifeguard job 
A lifeguard who was fired after he left his post to help a distressed swimmer outside his assigned zone turned down an offer on Thursday to return to his old job.

 Police: Potato chip trail led to Pa. suspect 
Police say they followed a trail of potato chips to catch a burglary suspect.
 07/05 
 Durbin tosses complete game, blanks Long Island 3-0 
Right-hander J.D. Durbin had his best start as a Barnstormer, tossing nine shutout innings Thursday in a 3-0 win over Long Island at Clipper Magazine Stadium.

 Defending defense attorneys: Someone has to do it 
But frankly, I am tired of the hypocrites who go after defense attorneys.

 Teens crash truck into occupied home, no one injured 
Quite a sight after a car drove right up onto the porch and through the front door of a home in West Earl Township.

 Governor Corbett signs numerous pieces of legislation Thursday 
Governor Tom Corbett signed into law the following bills on Thursday

 Cumberland County to offer cooling center Friday and Saturday 
Monroe Township will provide a cooling center at the township building on Friday, July 6 from 8:30AM until 4:30 PM.

 Lancaster&apos;s Cam Gallagher drills first two pro HRs 
Manheim Township graduate Cameron Gallagher finished 4-for-5 on Wednesday in the Burlington Royals&apos; 17-2 win over the Bristol White Sox in Burlington, North Carolina.

 Big Spring&apos;s Baker named to MaxPreps All-America softball team 
Senior Ashley Baker led the Bulldogs to a state championship, hitting .471 with eleven home runs.

 Revolution sending six players to All-Star game 
The two-time defending Atlantic League champion York Revolution will have six All-Star representatives, including York County resident Corey Thurman.

 Man arrested for sexually assaulting family member 
A Mechanicsburg man was arrested Thursday for a sexual assault incident that took place on March 20.

 Heat plus a large fire makes it difficult on fire fighters 
Officials say the Hersheypark Arena fire went to five-alarm not because of the severity of the fire, but because of the heat and the worry that fire fighters would suffer heat exhaustion.

 York row home fire leaves many homeless, causes over $300,000 in damage 
A fire that tore through at least four row homes was an arson.

 UPDATE: Armed and dangerous man wanted for robbery and burglary arrested 
Police in Lancaster County need your help to find a man who has recently gone on a crime spree with a gun.

 Businesses unsure of next step to take regarding Affordable Care Act 
It’s now been about a week since the U.S. Supreme Court upheld President Obama’s signature healthcare bill.

 Lawyer tries to get evidence against accused killer suppressed 
The lawyer for a York accused murderer wants evidence against his client thrown out.

 Another shooting in Carlisle, this time of a man who just got out of prison 
Sylvester &quot;Tiger&quot; Anderson was shot multiple times in the 200 block of West North Street.

 Capitals re-sign former Hershey C Perreault to 2-year, $2.1M deal 
The Washington Capitals have re-signed restricted free agent Mathieu Perreault to a two-year contract worth $2.1 million.

 Duncannon residents asked to conserve water 
Duncannon Borough is currently dealing with a water leak.

 UPDATE(6) : Over 200 firefighters manage to save legendary Hersheypark Arena 
Authorities have now called a five-alarm response to the flames.

 Boy bitten on neck by man in &apos;vampire&apos; attack 
Teen was bitten on the neck as he walked down the street.

 Jerry Sandusky&apos;s adopted son E.J. no longer coaching at West Chester 
E.J. Sandusky, an adopted son of convicted child sex abuser Jerry Sandusky, is no longer an assistant football coach at Division II West Chester University, CBS 21 News Sports Director Jason Bristol has learned.

 Volunteer dies during cleanup when unexploded firework goes off 
A volunteer was killed Wednesday night while cleaning up after a fireworks show when one exploded near him.

 York&amp;Lancaster County senior centers to extend hours 
The York County Area Agency on Aging and the Lancaster County Area Agency on Aging today announced that four additional senior centers are offering extended hours this week to provide relief from the heat for residents age 60 or older.

 Judge sets George Zimmerman&apos;s bail at $1M 
A judge set George Zimmerman&apos;s bond at $1,000,000 Thursday.

 Mid-west drought stalks the food supply 
Stockpiles of corn in the U.S. tumbled 48 percent between March and June, the biggest drop since 1996.

 Mortgage rates smash old record 
Mortgage rates fell again this week, smashing previous record lows, according to a regular weekly release from mortgage giant Freddie Mac.

 Pa. slots revenue up 5.5 percent last fiscal year 
Pennsylvania gaming officials say gross revenue from slot machines rose more than 5 percent for the fiscal year that just ended.

 Police: New mom smoked bath salts while still in the maternity ward 
A new mother has been charged with smoking the powerful synthetic stimulant known as bath salts two days after she gave birth, while still in the maternity ward of a central Pennsylvania hospital.

 Derry Township police investigating reports of a police impersonator 
The incident occurred early this morning in the area West Caracas Avenue and Ridge Road.

 Susquehanna Twp Police incident report - 07.05.12 

 Cop&apos;s life saved by bulletproof vest, manhunt for shooter 
Officer Brian Groves, who will turn 31 later this month, was saved by his bulletproof vest.

 Harrisburg City police incident report 07.05.12 

 Man arrested for attacking pregnant woman with a sword 
A man faces numerous charges after a bizarre confrontation outside of his mobile home.

 3 children dead after yacht capsizes, 24 others rescued 
Preliminary causes for the accident &quot;could be a combination of the weather and a wake from another vessel,&quot;

 Woman scalped at work when hair catches in machine 
A woman is hospitalized after her scalp was ripped from her head when her hair became caught in a machine during her shift at an automotive parts company.

 Lifeguard fired for helping to save swimmer&apos;s life 
Executives of an aquatics company will review whether the firm was justified in firing a lifeguard earlier this week for leaving his zone to help rescue a nearby swimmer.

 Mechanicsburg man charged In Lemoyne assault 
Christion Andrew Reese is charged with simple assault.

 Dad delivers baby in parking lot of 7-Eleven 
Nine pound, 10 ounce Cais is doing just fine.

 Help Wanted - Decorating Den 
A Harrisburg Division is expanding and looking for people with a sense of style

 Manheim Township incident report 07.05.12 

 VIDEO : San Diego Bay fireworks all go off at once 
There was a technical problem and ALL of the fireworks went off within 30 seconds. The original Big Bay Boom was set to last about 15 minutes.

 COPS: Cook gunned down over restaurant&apos;s long wait time 
Police released surveillance images of two suspects in the shooting death of a cook and father of five who was gunned down at the restaurant where he worked.

 VIDEO : Angry customer goes on rampage, smashes displays at T-Mobile store 
A man, apparently unhappy with service at a T-Mobile store in Manchester, England, went on a rampage, destroying store displays.

 Malware may knock thousands off Internet 
The warnings about the Internet problem have been splashed across Facebook and Google. Internet service providers have sent notices, and the FBI set up a special website.

 Deadbeat dad expected Jennifer Aniston, got the boys in blue 
A man has been ordered to pay more than $32,000 in back child support after being lured back to Pennsylvania with the promise of a bogus role in a Jennifer Aniston movie.

 South Middleton Township police report an assault with a car 
State Police say a New Jersey man was arrested in Cumberland County for allegedly hitting a woman with his car.

 Williamstown burglary under investigation 
State Police are investigating a burglary in Dauphin County.

 Mystery illness kills 61 kids 
Health officials are searching for the cause of a mystery disease that has killed more than 60 children over the past three months.

 Three children found dead in river 
The children — two girls, ages 9 and 7, and a 7-year-old boy — were not identified, but they were related,

 Man kills himself outside PSP barracks 
Authorities are trying to determine why a 65-year-old man apparently killed himself outside a Pennsylvania State Police barracks.

 Obama opening bus tour of Ohio, Pennsylvania 
President Barack Obama departs on a two-day bus tour of Ohio and Pennsylvania on Thursday, defending his economic policies and his decision to rescue U.S. automakers while raising questions about Republican Mitt Romney&apos;s business record.

 UPDATE(4): Four-alarm York row-home blaze ruled an arson 
The fire marshal has declared the fire an arson.
 07/04 
 Harrisburg Senators win their fourth straight with a late rally 
In front of a large 4th of July crowd in the Bowie, the Senators took a big early lead, then rallied for a 7-6 win over Bowie.

 VIDEO: Mother egging on fighting children sparks outrage in parents 
Many people just couldn&apos;t believe their eyes, when we showed them video showing two toddlers fist-fighting.

 Mother arrested for driving under the influence with children in the car 
The driver did not pull over when the officer activated both lights and siren.

 Governor released from the hospital after choking on carrot 
Gov. Terry Branstad was briefly hospitalized Wednesday after choking on food during a ceremony.

 Orioles option Chris Tillman to Double-A Bowie after win 
The Orioles announced after Wednesday’s game that they have optioned RHP Chris Tillman to Double-A Bowie.

 Boy electrocuted while swimming in marina, others shocked as well 
A sheriff in says one boy swimming in a marina at Cherokee Lake was electrocuted.

 Amputee Pistorius selected for Olympics in 4x400 
Double-amputee runner Oscar Pistorius is going to the London Olympics after being selected for South Africa&apos;s 1,600-meter relay team.

 Kate Gosselin shares tips for a 4th of July with fun memories 
Each year, we get especially excited for our favorite summer holiday, Fourth of July!

 Oprah buys Dad&apos;s barbershop from foreclosure 
Oprah Winfrey is now the owner of a barber shop.

 Middletown could be the next local town to file for Act 47 
The Borough of Middletown has filed a letter of intent for Act 47 to receive financial protection from the state.

 More questions into the tragic death of a young woman in prison 
Taylor Bolen was battling an addiction to heroin that she was struggling with.

 Leaked emails bad news for Penn State administrators as hearing approaches 
New developments could mean some really bad news for not only Curley and Schultz, but for former PSU President Graham Spanier as well.

 Fireworks set to light up City Island and Harrisburg Wednesday night 
The shores of the Susquehanna River are the places to be if you want to end your Fourth of July festivities with a big bang.

 Gas prices continue to drop across the midstate 
Gas prices continue to drop across the country and in PA, the average is sitting at $3.31 a gallon.

 Tips to keep you safe while setting off fireworks 
It’s estimated that 90 percent of all fireworks are sold this time of year, and they can be dangerous.

 Anything floats competition brings unique floating rafts to local lake 
Can you use duct tape and cardboard to make a boat? How about barrels and wood?

 Animals may not enjoy the fireworks as much as you do 
One report suggests 30 percent more pets go missing between July 4th and the 6th.

 Hot dogs or hamburgers: Which is healthier and what do you prefer? 
We went out to get the tale of the tape and find out whether people prefer hot dogs or hamburgers when they grill.

 Toddler fight: Mother screams &apos;ball up some fists!&apos; 
Video posted to Facebook is causing outrage in many circles.

 Fireworks and your eyes 
A study that shines a new spotlight on the dangers of fireworks on the human eye.

 A typo in the Declaration of Independence? 
Dissemination of public documents was slow and labor-intensive in 1776.

 UPDATE(2) : Two injured when they stir up a wasps nest while climbing Chiques Rock 
Two rock climbers on Chickie&apos;s rock in West Hempfield township fell about 30 feet.

 Fireworks explosion sets house ablaze; 9 hurt including 2 toddlers 
Police say the nine injured people range in age from infant to adult. They say two children have been taken to hospitals for treatment.

 Pa. says 758,000-plus voters lack PennDOT photo ID 
State officials say that more than 758,000 registered voters in Pennsylvania do not have photo identification cards from the state transportation department, leaving their ability to vote in November in doubt unless they have another acceptable form of identification

 Sun fires off Fourth of July solar flares 
The sun is unleashing some powerful solar flares today in an impressive celestial fireworks display.

 PA prison inmate tries to hail taxi from hospital 
A Beaver County Jail inmate, clad in an orange-and-white striped jumpsuit, tried to hitch a ride with a cab company after escaping from a local hospital, according to the Beaver County sheriff’s office.

 Attorney: Casey Anthony&apos;s car trunk &apos;smelled like a dead body&apos; 
Casey Anthony’s attorney Jose Baez,in a shocking revelation, says that when he first looked into his client&apos;s car he thought he smelled a “dead body!”

 Apartment bloodbath: 2 adults, 7-year-old boy shot to death 
A violent ex-con turned his apartment into a bloodbath, fatally shooting his wife and her 7-year-old grandson before committing suicide.

 Body of missing 3-year-old boy found in trash dumpster 
The child went missing Sunday night. His Father is in jail on a million dollar bond, but not yet charged with murder.

 Cop to women: Give me sex, no arrest! 
Prosecutors accused a 47-year-old police officer of having sex with two women in exchange for not arresting them.

 Cops: Hit-and-run driver left accident, &apos;I did not want my ice cream to melt&apos;... 
A driver told cops that she fled the scene of an accident Sunday night because she was concerned that, if she stopped, ice cream she was carrying home would melt, according to police.

 Fireworks industry in biggest slump since Vietnam War era 
As millions of Americans celebrate Independence Day on Wednesday, there are some whose holiday won&apos;t be going off with a bang.

 Face The State: Inside the Sandusky trial 
A look inside the Jerry Sandusky trial.

 Face The State: Governor Tom Corbett 
Pennsylvania Governor Tom Corbett is this edition&apos;s guest.

 Face The State: Lt. Gov. Jim Cawley 
Lt. Governor Jim Cawley is this edition&apos;s guest

 VIDEO : Wimbledon line judge hit in face by 118 MPH serve 
Monday wasn&apos;t just another day at the office for one unlucky Wimbledon line judge.

 Homeland Security report lists ‘Liberty Lovers’ as terrorists 
Americans who are “suspicious of centralized federal authority, reverent of individual liberty” deemed domestic threat.

 ACLU launches app to secretly record police stops 
The ACLU has released an app called “Police Tape” that lets users secretly record police stops.

 4th of July by the numbers 
Amateur pyros shelled out a smoking $649 million for their own personal fireworks shows last year, according to the American Pyrotechnics Association.

 Scorching heat, dry conditions stifle July 4 celebrations 
ourth of July revelers will be met by another day of scorching temperatures on Wednesday, prompting many U.S. communities to cancel annual fireworks celebrations amid fears of heat-related dangers.

 Fourth of July grilling tip: Don&apos;t swallow the wire brush. (Seriously.) 
&quot;Persons who grill should be aware of the risk for ingestion of wire bristles from grill-cleaning brushes,&quot; the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention advised.

 10 things you didn’t know about the Fourth of July 
Americans consume more hot dogs on July 4th than on any other day of the year:

 4th of July deadliest day on US roads 
Independence Day is no time to forget about road safety, AAA warns.

 Stolen car investigation 
Police say they followed a stolen car out of Harrisburg, that crashed on the West Shore.
 07/03 
 The United States is the greatest country on God&apos;s great Earth 
This is a country where anyone who has the will can soar like an eagle.

 Do bears and fireworks mix? Lebanon County residents don&apos;t want to find out 
Wednesday, fireworks will fill the sky and some don&apos;t know if that&apos;s a good or bad thing for the bear lurking in the woods.

 Punishment handed down for those arrested in large drug bust 
Twenty people were arrested as part of a major drug ring bust in Carlisle in 2011.

 UPDATE: Family of young woman who died in prison shares their pain 
It wasn&apos;t much more than a family dispute that sent Taylor Jean Bolen to the Cumberland County Prison.

 NCAA investigation could lead to sanctions against Penn State teams 
When the NCAA punishes schools, it usually is for paying athletes or recruiting violations.

 More issues for Carlisle Regional Medical Center, this time over wait times 
Long wait times are causing patients in one emergency room to leave without ever receiving treatment.

 UPDATE: Arrest made in Lancaster stabbing over beer 
Officers responded to a stabbing - robbery that had just occurred in the area of N. Market St. and W. James St.

 Penn State fans continue to support former coach Joe Paterno 
Monday, Paterno&apos;s family called on the AG&apos;s office and Penn State to release all of the emails.

 York School District passes budget, but soon could be taken over by the state 
If the bill is signed, York City, Harrisburg and two other districts would become financially distressed.

 With July 4th around the corner, don&apos;t drink and boat 
Boaters operating under the influence are risking not only their lives, but their passengers and other boaters.

 Governor signs bill allowing expert testimony in sex abuse cases 
House Bill 1264 was passed unanimously by the General Assembly, and the governor actually signed it on Friday.

 Mother charged after dropping her daughter, friend off along I-83 
Police say on June 18 Jones, her 17-year-old daughter and a friend of the daughters were in the car.

 Pregnant woman bites off fingertip of knife-wielding attacker 
Reginald Gefferie, 22, was charged with aggravated battery on a pregnant female and false imprisonment.

 Digital Camera Tip: How to photograph fireworks 
A good fireworks photo can be quite striking, but it can also be a very tough shot to get.

 Mother claims fight with hospital to keep toddler on life support 
The mother of a toddler claims she has had to fight hospital administrators to keep her son on life support.

 Mom who locked boys, 3 and 5, in a dog kennel gets probation 
The mother of two boys reportedly found by police locked in a dog kennel on Oct. 24, 2011, has received two years of probation.

 &apos;They&apos;re evil. They&apos;re witches!&apos; says lawyer for teacher accused of sex with 14-year-old girls 
A teacher is charged with having sex at least three times with a 14-year-old girl and performing a sex act with another in an empty classroom.

 19 children found living alone in sweltering house 
Authorities on Monday night removed 19 juveniles that they said were left unattended for about a week in a sweltering home.

 Fire at smoke-grenade plant closes roadways 
Emergency crews have closed a western Pennsylvania highway near a fire at a plant that produces nonlethal weapons, including smoke grenades.

 Ex-FBI employee claims she saw angels at Flight 93 
A former FBI employee who retired due to post-traumatic stress disorder linked to time spent as a liaison between law enforcement and families of United Airlines Flight 93 victims has written a book about seeing legions of angels guarding the site after the hijacked airliner crashed on Sept. 11, 2001.

 Fireworks display will close streets in Harrisburg 
The annual display will close Front st. and the Market St. Bridge.

 This U.S. summer is &apos;what global warming looks like&apos; 
If you want a glimpse of some of the worst of global warming, scientists suggest taking a look at U.S. weather in recent weeks.

 The age of rage: psychiatrists battle over teen anger diagnosis 
Intermittent explosive disorder, marked by outbursts of uncontrollable rage, is so common among adolescents it affects one in 12 teens, a large new study finds.

 Granny’s pot cookies land 3-year-old boy in hospital 
Police said the grandmother was fighting cancer and had a prescription for medical marijuana to ease her pain and help her sleep.

 Marijuana without the high 
Researchers claim they have developed marijuana that can help ease the symptoms of ailments without getting patients high.

 Pa. elections webpage doesn&apos;t mention new ID law 
Pennsylvania elections officials continue to maintain a webpage that says non-photo identification can be used as proof of identity by first-time voters, even though a new law in effect for the November election dictates that all voters must show a certain kind of photo ID.

 Chambersburg Hospital workers ratify new contract 
Over 1,300 nurses and frontline healthcare professionals ratified a new contract.

 Giant recalls dog food 
The voluntary recall is of Pedigree Weight Management canned dog food.

 Woman tried to drown two-year-old son in hotel bathtub 
A West Virginia woman is jailed on attempted homicide and other charges that she tried to drown her 2-year-old son in a Pittsburgh-area hotel room.

 Der Harrisburg Maennerchor to donate $10,000 to save Harrisburg schools’ athletics and music 
Der Harrisburg Maennerchor has pledged to donate $10,000 to the Harrisburg Public Schools Foundation in their bid to make up the $336,000 Harrisburg School District budget shortfall.

 &apos;I just shot my grandson!&apos; 74-year-old grandmother to stand trial for murder 
Judge orders trial for grandmother in teen&apos;s death, cites 911 call.

 Andy Griffith dead at 86 
Andy Griffith, an icon of TV, has died ... this according to Andy&apos;s close friend, former UNC President Bill Friday.

 Plane hijackers &apos;beaten to death by passengers&apos; 
Two of the suspects died in hospital from injuries they suffered during the ensuing fight with passengers and crew on board.

 Workers on federal &apos;disability&apos; exceed population of New York City 
A record of 8,733,461 workers took federal disability insurance payments in June 2012.

 VIDEO : Naked, ninja zombie attack 
A naked man went on a rampage against police officers, doing ninja-like flips and ignoring stun gun shocks -- and it was all caught on video.

 More than 2,000 heat records matched or broken 
June saw more than 3,200 records topped.

 Police make arrest in Dover Twp. stabbing investigation 
24-year-old Benjamin Black has been arrested in the incident.

 Crime Stoppers of Dauphin County update 
If you have information on any fugitives or crimes, please call Det. Sgt. Dave Hodges at Crime Stoppers of Dauphin County at 1-800-262-3080.

 Child treated for rabid bat bite at home 
Pennsylvania Department of Agriculture officials say a child is being treated for rabies after being bitten by a bat in the child&apos;s home.

 &apos;Cat ladies&apos; more likely to commit suicide, scientists claim 
The risk of self-directed violent behavior was increased 95% for women who tested positive for the antibody compared with those testing negative

 Anger festers in sweltering mid-Atlantic 
From the Midwest to the mid-Atlantic, almost two million homes and businesses are still in the dark, and the heat, four days after violent storms caused heavy damage.

 Talking urinal cakes help fight DUI 
Keeping keep drunks off the road with the help from a special message in men&apos;s bathrooms featuring an attention-getting woman&apos;s voice.

 Police embrace crime-predicting algorithm 
Burglary reports dropped after officers began taking patrol orders from computers.

 Real &apos;Hot Wheels&apos;! 
Those giant Hot Wheels loops from your childhood? Totally possible in real life.

 Conduct code for unmanned aircraft is unveiled 
A trade group for drone aircraft manufacturers and operators is releasing the industry&apos;s first&quot;code of conduct,&quot;partly in response to growing privacy concerns as the industry expands into civilian aviation.

 Man stabbed in head&amp;torso 
Lancaster City Police say stabbing stemmed from attempted robbery.
 07/02 
 With the release of Penn State emails, Paterno name dragged back into investigation 
The fallout from the Sandusky verdict continues as the Paterno family goes on the offensive.

 Rep. Depasquale proposes retroactive bill that would take Sandusky&apos;s pension 
Depasquale says hearings could take place over the summer.

 DUI checkpoint app shows users areas to steer clear of 
What you may be surprised at is that the PA DUI association isn&apos;t upset by these apps.

 Manor Township Police Log - July 2 
Manor Township in Lancaster County are investigating the following incidents:

 Northern York Police searching for Turkey Hill armed robber 
On June 30 police responded to a robbery at the Turkey Hill Store located at 2820 Carlisle Road in Dover Township.

 Officers justified in killing of man in incident of suicide by cop 
The community has a legitimate interest in being apprised of the circumstances which lead to the shooting and subsequent death of the suspect.

 Dauphin County to spray for mosquitoes in Washington Township 
Dauphin County’s West Nile Virus (WNV) Control Program staff will apply treatments, weather permitting, to control adult mosquito populations in Washington Twp.

 UPDATE: Arrest made of teen who punched officer who was breaking up underage party 
Susquehanna Township Police are investigating several incidents that occurred recently.

 Arrests made of possible subjects in Harrisburg bar robberies 
The Harrisburg Police Captain stated, “There have been arrests made and we&apos;re moving forward to more arrests.&quot;

 NCAA re-releases statement on investigation into Penn State 
The NCAA re-released a statement on Monday regarding whether they will take action against Penn State and their athletic teams.

 Paterno family calls for all Penn State emails to be released 
From the moment the Jerry Sandusky crisis erupted, Joe Paterno patiently and persistently called for a thorough and professional investigation.

 Tips on safely beating the heat in the Susquehanna River 
Have fun, but be careful this holiday week if you enter the river.

 Penn State emails could lead to more charges for top officials 
Schultz and Curley are facing charges, but will Spanier now be included?

 Hot, dry weather forecast beginning to concern farmers 
This year&apos;s relatively mild weather and warm spring and summer have many farm crops confused.

 Alleged armed robbery of cab driver turns into a false police report 
Police say a woman said she crashed the cab she was driving because she was being robbed.

 Supreme Court&apos;s ruling on juvenile killers could set some of them free 
The high court ruled that it is unconstitutional to sentence a juvenile offender to life in prison without parole.

 Effort underway to save sports and band in Harrisburg School District 
Members of the community are trying some creative ways to save athletics in the upcoming school year.

 Stiffer penalties coming for those who drink and drive with kids in the car 
The new law sends a compelling message to people who would be foolish enough to drive drunk with young passengers.

 Woman puts child&apos;s life in danger by firing gun while high on bath salts 
A Lancaster County woman has been arrested for shooting at imaginary burglars and nearly hitting her own child.

 Father kicked 3-year-old son in the face at Disney World 
Dario Napolitano was freed on $2,000 bond over the weekend.

 Susquehanna looks easy, but don&apos;t give in to temptation 
Many of us see the Susquehanna every day, last year for much of the summer going in the river was out of the question because of high water levels.

 Area fireworks schedules 
Scheduled fireworks displays for our area.

 Police searching for two men involved in Friday night home invasion 
It happened late Friday in the 300 block of East Burd Street in Shippensburg.

 Wife of budget secretary sentenced for DUI charge 
The wife of Pennsylvania’s Budget Secretary was sentenced for one of her drunk-driving charges.

 10-year-old boy stabbed while fighting off registered sex offender in Wendy&apos;s restroom 
Adam Lee Brown, 49, grabbed the boy and forced him into the restroom.

 No prison time for preschool teacher who threw teen sex parties 
A former preschool teacher will serve probation and perform public service.

 Casey Anthony wants to be a &apos;bad girl&apos; reality TV star 
From prison to primetime . . .

 Corbett signs six bills 
Governor Tom Corbett signed the bills into law on June 30th.

 Harrisburg City police incident report - 07.02.12 

 Pennsylvania to receive more than $13 million as part of judgement 
Pennsylvania will receive more than $13 million as part of the largest healthcare fraud settlement in United States history.

 61-second minute crashes websites 
One tiny little second managed to bring down a number of the Web&apos;s more well-known sites as soon as the clock hit &quot;61&quot; instead of &quot;60&quot; yesterday.

 For youth, political action is online 
A new survey of US youth offers the most complete picture to date of how young people are using new media to participate in politics.

 Pa. high school puts itself up for sale on eBay 
Forget magazine drives and candy sales. A cash-strapped high school near Philadelphia hopes to raise funds by auctioning itself on eBay.

 Lancaster City/County Crime Stoppers looking for leads in home invasion 
The suspects held the homeowner at gunpoint and demanded money.

 Naked photos of former NBA star used in extortion scheme 
-Former NBA star--and current Golden State Warriors head coach--Mark Jackson was the target.

 Family of 7-year-old girl to accused killer: &apos;I hope you die slow&apos; 
Jerrell Dorsey is charged with shooting Heaven Sutton

 Retired astronaut dies in jet ski crash 
Capt. Alan G. Poindexter, 51, had been riding on a personal watercraft with his 22-year-old son, Samuel.

 UPDATE(3) : Police have closed their investigation into a deadly deer attack 
Natalie Shaffer of Wrightsville died Friday after being gored by a buck in rut.

 Three Boy Scouts, toddler killed in head-on crash 
The scouts and their scoutmaster were killed Saturday when their car collided head-on with an RV.

 Domestic Violence Services of Cumberland&amp;Perry Counties receive grant 
Grant award will be used for general operating support for Domestic Violence Services of Cumberland&amp;Perry Counties Emergency Shelter Program that provides a safe house.

 Battle over Suri&apos;s future: Katie says no to radical Scientology indoctrination 
Katie Holmes is afraid Tom would ship Suri
to a radical Scientology organization.

 Mechanicsburg man arrested for domestic assault 
47-year-old Daniel Miller was arrested for assaulting his wife.

 Governor Corbett announces confirmations 
Governor Corbett announced confirmations of his nominees by the Pennsylvania Senate.

 Human head found, may be linked to &apos;Canadian cannibal&apos; 
Authorities discovered possible human head in park. It could be the head of Chinese student Jun Lin,

 &apos;Octomom&apos;s&apos; new boyfriend has a secret past 
TMZ Exclusive: The Secret Dating Show Past

 Woman charged with using shovel during domestic dispute 
A woman has been jailed on charges she stabbed her husband in the back and hit him on the head with a shovel during a domestic dispute.

 Manheim Township incident report 07.02.12 

 UPDATE (3) : Dauphin County fatal accident victim identified 
Authorities have released the name of the victim.

 You puke, you pay! $50 fee for taxi riders who vomit in cab 
Cab drivers have for years complained about having to clean up after passengers, most of whom vomit after consuming too much alcohol.
 07/01 
 Teenage boy pulls trigger, dies playing Russian roulette 
A 17-year-old Largo boy who apparently shot himself in the head in a game of Russian roulette Friday night has died.

 Convicted sex offender, girlfriend arrested for sex with 4-year-old girl 
It started out with a cell phone found in a shopping cart, and ended with a couple arrested on charges that they engaged in sexual acts with a 4-year-old girl.

 Police captain accused of performing &apos;sex exam&apos; on 15-year-old girl 
A Florida Police captain was arrested Friday on charges he made a 15-year-old girl strip naked in the back seat of a car for a &quot;sex check&quot; to prove she wasn&apos;t having sex, reports said.

 Woman jumps from 35th-floor hotel balcony as cops bust into room 
The woman was wanted for several fraud and theft charges to the MGM Grand hotel.

 Toddler found dead under pile of clothes in grandmother&apos;s closet 
A small makeshift memorial now sits outside of the home where little Ziya Turner was found dead.

 Pa. House approves red light camera expansion 
A bill to expand the use of red light cameras to catch traffic violators in Pennsylvania is on its way to the governor&apos;s desk to be signed into law.
	</body>
</document>
