<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005217" url="http://www.sbireports.com/prod-toc/Foodservice-145342/" time="2012-07-12-21:45" support="5" score="0.008192939590156571" bingtitle="Foodservice Industry : SBI - Industrial, Construction &amp; Materials ..." webtitle="Foodservice Industry : SBI">
			<query id="000732" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000115" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="182"/>
	<description>Table 3-2 Number Of U.S. Adults Purchasing From A Fast-Food Restaurant And Their Likelihood To Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (number, percent, and ...</description>
	<body>
		Foodservice Industry
 Jun 1, 2000
240 Pages - Pub ID: SB364 $1,575.00 Online Download $1,575.00 Hard Copy Mail Delivery $3,150.00 Global Site License $1,750.00 Online Download plus 1 Hard Copy 
  Ask a question about this report  Email a colleague  Printer format  Order by fax 
 
 
 Abstract Table of Contents Search Inside Report Buy By the Section Related Reports 
 

 Section 1 - Executive Summary and U.S. Foodservice Industry Trends 
 Foodservice Industry Sales And Growth Trends Commercial Foodservice Sales Opportunities Noncommercial Foodservice Sales Opportunities Target Demographic Markets Growing Competitive Pressures Industry Cost Structure And Profit Margins Competitors Extend Menus And Create New Formats Multi-Branding To Expand The Customer Base Acquisitions And Refranchising Activity Outlook
 Scope and Methodology Table 1-1 U.S. Spending On Food And Beverages Away-From-Home, 1977-2005 (dollars): Food Sales, Food Supplied And Donated, Alcoholic Drink Sales, And Total Figure 1-1 U.S. Spending on Food and Beverages Away-From-Home, 1990, 1995, 2000, and 2005 (dollars) Table 1-2 U.S. Spending On Food And Beverages And Percent Spent On Away-From-Home Consumption, 1977-2005 (dollars and percent) Figure 1-2 Away-From-Home&apos;s Share of Total U.S. Food and Beverage Spending, 1990, 1995, 2000, and 2005 (percent) Table 1-3 Per Capita Away-From-Home Food Sales In Current And Real Dollars, 1982-2005 (dollars) Table 1-4 U.S. Away-From-Home Food Sales For Twenty Types Of Outlets, 1987-2000 (dollars): Commercial And Noncommercial Outlets Figure 1-3 U.S. Away-From-Home Food Sales For The Top Ten Types Of Outlets, 2000 (dollars) Table 1-5 Percent Total U.S. Away-From-Home Food Sales For Twenty Types Of Outlets, 1987-2000 (percent): Commercial And Noncommercial Outlets Table 1-6 U.S. Sales Of Prepared Meals And Snacks By U.S. Retail Hosts By Type Of Outlet, 1987-2000 (dollars): Supermarkets, Gasoline Stations, Convenience Stores, General Merchandise Stores, Drug Stores, Other Food Stores, Liquor Stores, And Other Retailers Table 1-7 U.S. Sales Of Alcoholic Drinks Consumed Away-From-Home By Type Of Outlet, 1987-2000 (dollars): Eating And Drinking Places, Hotels And Motels, And Others Table 1-8 Consumer Price Trends For Food At-Home And Food Away-From-Home, 1982-2000 (index)


 Section 2 U.S. Household Away-From-Home Food and Beverage Spending 
 Summary Of Major Findings Household Spending Growing Target Markets Daypart Analysis
 Table 2-1 U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Food And Alcoholic Beverages By Type Of Purchase, 1995-2000 (dollars): Lunch, Dinner, Snacks, Breakfast, Board, Catered Affairs, Food On Trips, School Lunches, Meals As Pay, And Alcoholic Beverages Table 2-2 Percent Total U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Food And Alcoholic Beverages By Type Of Purchase, 1995-2000 (percent): Lunch, Dinner, Snacks, Breakfast, Board, Catered Affairs, Food On Trips, School Lunches, Meals As Pay, And Alcoholic Beverages Table 2-3 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Food And Alcoholic Beverages By Type Of Purchase, 1995-2000 (dollars): Lunch, Dinner, Snacks, Breakfast, Board, Catered Affairs, Food On Trips, School Lunches, Meals As Pay, And Alcoholic Beverages Table 2-4 U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Food And Alcoholic Beverages By Demographic Characteristic, 1985-1998 (dollars): Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-5 Percent Total U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Food And Alcoholic Beverages By Demographic Characteristic, 1985-1998 (percent): Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-6 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Food And Alcoholic Beverages By Demographic Characteristic, 1985-1998 (dollars): Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-7 Away-From-Home&apos;s Share Of Total U.S. Food And Alcoholic Beverage Spending By Demographic Characteristic, 1985-1998 (percent): Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-8 Percent Distribution Of U.S. Household Spending On Meals And Snacks By Place Of Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (percent): Limited-Service Restaurants, Full-Service Restaurants, Vending Machines And Mobile Vendors, And Employee And School Cafeterias; Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-9 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Lunches By Place Of Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (dollars): Limited-Service Restaurants, Full-Service Restaurants, Vending Machines And Mobile Vendors, And Employee And School Cafeterias; Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-10 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Dinners By Place Of Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (dollars): Limited-Service Restaurants, Full-Service Restaurants, Vending Machines And Mobile Vendors, And Employee And School Cafeterias; Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-11 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Snacks By Place Of Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (dollars): Limited-Service Restaurants, Full-Service Restaurants, Vending Machines And Mobile Vendors, And Employee And School Cafeterias; Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-12 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Breakfasts By Place Of Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (dollars): Limited-Service Restaurants, Full-Service Restaurants, Vending Machines And Mobile Vendors, And Employee And School Cafeterias; Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-13 Average U.S. Household Spending On Board, Catered Affairs, Food On Trips, School Lunches, And Meals As Pay By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (dollars): Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-14 Average U.S. Household Spending On Away-From-Home Alcoholic Drinks By Type By Demographic Characteristic, 1998 (dollars): Beer, Wine, Other, And Purchased On Trip; Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Size Of Household, And Region Table 2-15 Percent Of U.S. Adults Purchasing From A Fast-Food Restaurant Or Family Restaurant/Steak House By Daypart By People Visited With, Fall 1999 (percent): Alone, With Husband/Wife, With Children Under 12, With Children 12 To 17, With Friends, With Co-Workers, And Other; Breakfast, Lunch, Dinner, And Snack Table 2-16 U.S. Real Disposable Personal Income Trends, 1980-2000 (dollars) Table 2-17 U.S. Female Labor Participation Rate, 1977-2000 (percent) Table 2-18 Distribution Of U.S. Households By Demographic Characteristic, 1985-1998 (percent): Household Income, Age Of Household Head, Region, Size of Household, And Total Households


 Section 3 - U.S. Fast-Food and Family Restaurant Purchaser Demographics 
 Summary Of Major Findings Fast-Food Restaurant Customer Demographics Family Restaurant And Steak House Customer Demographics Demographics Of Leading Fast-Food Brands Demographics Of Leading Family Restaurant/Steak House Brands
 Table 3-1 Ranking Of Likelihood To Purchase From A Fast-Food Restaurant And Family Restaurant/Steak House For The Top Fifteen Demographic Characteristics, Fall 1999 (percent and index) Table 3-2 Number Of U.S. Adults Purchasing From A Fast-Food Restaurant And Their Likelihood To Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (number, percent, and index): Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-3 U.S. Adults&apos; Likelihood To Purchase From A Fast-Food Restaurant By Daypart By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (index): Breakfast, Lunch, Dinner, And Snack; Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-4 Demographic Groups Most Likely To Purchase From A Fast-Food Restaurant For The Top Six U.S. Chains Most Often Visited By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (characteristic): Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, And Region Table 3-5 U.S. Adults&apos; Likelihood To Purchase From A Fast-Food Restaurant For The Six Chains Most Often Visited By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (index): Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-6 U.S. Adults&apos; Likelihood To Visit A McDonald&apos;s By Frequency By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (index): Light, Medium, And Heavy Users; Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, Children By Age, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-7 Number Of U.S. Adults Purchasing From A Family Restaurant And Steak House And Their Likelihood To Purchase By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (number, percent, and index): Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-8 U.S. Adults&apos; Likelihood To Purchase From A Family Restaurant And Steak House By Daypart By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (index): Breakfast, Lunch, Dinner, And Snack; Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-9 Demographic Groups Most Likely To Purchase From A Family Restaurant And Steak House For The Top Six U.S. Chains Most Often Visited By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (characteristic): Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-10 U.S. Adults&apos; Likelihood To Purchase From A Family Restaurant And Steak House For The Six Chains Most Often Visited By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (index): Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region Table 3-11 U.S. Adults&apos; Likelihood To Visit An Applebee&apos;s By Frequency By Demographic Characteristic, Fall 1999 (index): Light, Medium, And Heavy Users; Sex, Age, Race, Marital Status, Household Income, Education, Occupation, Household Size, With Children, Kind Of Residence, And Region


 Section 4 - Foodservice Industry Sales By Type of Outlet and Menu 
 Summary Of Major Findings Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales And Growth Trends Industry Sector Analysis Menu Mix Take-Out Business
 Table 4-1 Sales Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places, 1977-2005 (dollars) Table 4-2 Monthly U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales, 1998-2000 (dollars) Table 4-3 Sales Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Type, 1977-2005 (dollars): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars, Foodservice Contractors, Caterers, Cafeterias, Ice Cream And Frozen Yogurt Shops, And Drinking Places Table 4-4 Percent U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales By Type, 1977-2005 (percent): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars, Foodservice Contractors, Caterers, Cafeterias, Ice Cream And Frozen Yogurt Shops, And Drinking Places Table 4-5 Sales Of U.S. Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars By Type, 1997 And 2000 (dollars): Fast-Food Restaurants, Donut Shops, Coffee Shops, Bagel Shops, Cookie Shops, And Other Snack Bars Table 4-6 Sales Of Meals And Snacks, Alcoholic Drinks, And Other Revenues By U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Type, 1982-2000 (dollars): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants, Cafeterias, Other Eating Places, And Drinking Places Table 4-7 Meal And Snack Sales Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Type For On- And Off-Premise Consumption, 1982-2000 (dollars): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants, Cafeterias, Other Eating Places, And Drinking Places Table 4-8 Percent Meal And Snack Sales Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Type For On- And Off-Premise Consumption, 1982-2000 (percent): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants, Cafeterias, Other Eating Places, And Drinking Places Table 4-9 U.S. Eating Place Sales By Principal Menu Type, 1992-1999 (dollars): Hamburger, Pizza, Mexican, Seafood, Italian, Steak, Chicken, Sub Shop, Chinese, American, And Others


 Section 5 U.S. Foodservice Industry Cost Structure and the Competitive Environment 
 Summary Of Major Findings Number Of U.S. Foodservices Foodservice Profit Margins Food And Labor Costs Industry Concentration And Consolidation
 Table 5-1 Number Of U.S. Commercial And Noncommercial Foodservices And Drinking Places, 1987-2000 (number) Table 5-2 Number Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Type Of Outlet, 1987-2000 (number): Fast-Food Outlets, Restaurants, Cafeterias, Caterers, Hotels And Motels, Retailers, Amusement Places, Drinking Places, Schools, Military, Plants And Office Buildings, Medical Facilities, Transportation Services, And Others Table 5-3 Average Away-From-Home Food Sales Per U.S. Commercial And Noncommercial Foodservice And Drinking Place For Twenty Types Of Outlets, 1987-2000 (dollars) Table 5-4 Income Statement For U.S. Eating And Drinking Place Corporations, 1990-2000 (dollars and percent): Total Receipts, Cost Of Goods Sold, Salaries And Wages, Officer Compensation, Employee Benefit Programs, Rent, Repairs, Advertising, And Others Table 5-5 U.S. Producer Price Trends For Processed Foods And Feeds, 1987-2000 (index) Table 5-6 Employment And Earnings Trends For U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places, 1977-2000 (number, percent, and dollars): Total Employees, Percent Nonsupervisory Workers, Average Hourly Wages, And Average Weekly Hours Table 5-7 Payroll As A Percent Of Sales For U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By State, 1987-1997 (percent) Table 5-8 Capital Expenditures Of U.S. Eating And Drinking Places, 1982-2000 (dollars): Total, New Structures, New Equipment, And Used Structures And Equipment Table 5-9 Number Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Employee Size, Sales Size, and Multiunit Chains, 1987-1997 (number) Table 5-10 Share Of U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Outlets And Sizes By Company Group Category, 1987-1997 (percent): 4, 8, 20, And 50 Largest Companies


 Section 6 - U.S. Foodservice Industry Food And Related Product Purchases 
 Summary Of Major Findings
 Table 6-1 Purchases Of Fifty Types Of Foods And Other Manufactured Products By U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places, 1982-2000 (dollars) Table 6-2 U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales As A Share Of Total Shipments For Thirty-One Types Of Foods, 1982-1997 (percent) Table 6-3 U.S. Producer Price Trends For Thirty-Two Types Of Foods Purchased By Foodservices And Drinking Places, 1996-2000 (index) Table 6-4 U.S. Per Capita Consumption Of Thirty Types Of Foods And Beverages, 1982-1999 (pounds) Table 6-5 Sales And Profit Trends For Sysco Corporation, 1997-2000 (dollars and percent): Sales, Cost Of Sales, Operating Expenses and Income, And Capital Expenditures Table 6-6 Distribution Of Sysco Corporation Sales By Type Of Customer And Product, 1997-1999 (percent) Table 6-7 Number Of U.S. And Canadian Distribution Facilities And Self-Serve Centers Occupied By Sysco By State And Province And The Aggregate Cubic Footage Devoted To Cold And Dry Storage As Of September 10, 1999


 Section 7 - Regional Foodservice Trends 
 Summary Of Major Findings Sales And Growth Analysis Per Capita Sales Trends Number Of Outlets And Average Sales Regional Sector Mix
 Table 7-1 Regional U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Growth Analysis, 1982-2000 (percent): Sales, Population, And Number Of Outlets Table 7-2 U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales By Region And State, 1977-2000 (dollars) Table 7-3 Percent Total U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales By Region And State, 1977-2000 (percent) Table 7-4 Number Of U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Places By Region And State, 1977-2000 (number) Table 7-5 Average Sales Per U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place By Region And State, 1977-2000 (dollars) Table 7-6 Per Capita U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales By Region And State, 1977-2000 (dollars) Table 7-7 Population Per U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place By Region And State, 1977-2000 (number) Table 7-8 U.S. Population By Region And State, 1977-2000 (number) Table 7-9 U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales By Region And State By Type, 1997 (dollars): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars, Foodservice Contractors, Caterers, Cafeterias, And Drinking Places Table 7-10 Percent Total U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place Sales By Region And State By Type, 1997 (percent): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars, Foodservice Contractors, Caterers, Cafeterias, And Drinking Places Table 7-11 Number Of U.S. Foodservices And Drinking Places By Region And State By Type, 1997 (number): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars, Foodservice Contractors, Caterers, Cafeterias, And Drinking Places Table 7-12 Average Sales Per U.S. Foodservice And Drinking Place By Region And State By Type, 1997 (dollars): Full-Service Restaurants, Limited-Service Restaurants And Snack Bars, Foodservice Contractors, Caterers, Cafeterias, And Drinking Places


 Section 8 - Major Brand Sales, Market Share, And Number Of Units 
 Summary of Major Findings Sales And Growth Trends Market Shares Number Of Units And Average Sales Profit Margins
 Table 8-1 U.S. Systemwide Foodservice Sales For The Top Twenty-Five Chains, 1995-1999 (dollars) Table 8-2 Growth Of U.S. Systemwide Foodservice Sales For The Top Twenty Chains, 1995-1999 (percent) Table 8-3 Share Of U.S. Spending On Food And Beverages Away-From-Home For The Top Twenty Chains, 1995-1999 (percent) Table 8-4 Share Of Top Four Foodservice Chains By Menu Type, 1999 (percent): Hamburger, Pizza, Chicken, Mexican, Family Restaurant/Dinner House Table 8-5 Number Of U.S. Systemwide Units For The Top Twenty Foodservice Chains, 1997-1999 (number) Table 8-6 Average Sales Per U.S. System Unit For The Top Twenty Foodservice Chains, 1997-1999 (dollars) Table 8-7 U.S. Systemwide Foodservice Units For The Top Twenty Chains For Company And Franchised Units, 1997-1999 (number) Table 8-8 Operating Profits As A Percent Of Sales For Thirteen Leading U.S. Foodservice Chains, 1997-1999 (percent) Table 8-9 Percent Of Total U.S. Adult Fast-Food Visitors For The Top Twenty-Five Chains, Percent Primary Visitor, And Percent Frequent Visitor, Fall 1999 (percent) Table 8-10 Percent Of Total U.S. Adult Family Restaurant And Steak House Visitors For The Top Twenty-Five Chains, Percent Primary Visitor, And Percent Frequent Visitor, Fall 1999 (percent)


 Section 9 - Profiles of Major U.S. Foodservice Companies 
 Advantica Restaurant Group, Inc.
 Denny&apos;s U.S. System And Sales Franchised And Company Units Denny&apos;s U.S. Customer Demographics Growth Strategies Profit Margins And Recent Developments
 Allied Domecq Plc
 Dunkin Donuts U.S. System And Sales
 Applebee&apos;s International, Inc.
 Applebee&apos;s U.S. System And Sales Small-Town Prototype Applebee&apos;s U.S. Customer Demographics Franchised And Company Units Advertising Profit Margins And Recent Developments
 Aramark Corp
 Aramark Food And Support Services Group Expands Sports And Entertainment Business
 Bain Capital, Inc
 Domino&apos;s Pizza U.S. System And Sales Profit Margins
 Berkshire Hathaway, Inc.
 Dairy Queen
 CKE Restaurants, Inc.
 Hardee&apos;s U.S. System And Sales Growth Strategy Profit Margins
 Darden Restaurants, Inc.
 Red Lobster U.S. System And Sales Olive Garden U.S. System And Sales Red Lobster And Olive Garden U.S. Customer Demographics Profit Margins
 Diageo Plc
 Burger King System And Sales Franchised Units Burger King&apos;s U.S. Customer Demographics Advertising New Products And Restaurant Concepts International Developments Profit Margins
 Doctor&apos;s Associates, Inc
 Subway&apos;s U.S. System And Sales Expanding Menu
 Jack In The Box, Inc
 Jack In The Box System And Sales New Programs And Strategies Company And Franchised Units Advertising Profit Margins
 McDonald&apos;s Corp
 McDonald&apos;s U.S. System And Sales Franchised And Company Units McDonald&apos;s U.S. Customer Demographics International Operations Profit Margins
 Outback Steakhouse, Inc.
 Outback Steakhouse U.S. System And Sales Line Extensions Company And Franchised Units International Operations Profit Margins
 Sodexho Marriott Services, Inc
 Sodexho Marriott Contract Foodservices Business Segments Profit Margins
 Triarc Companies, Inc.
 Arby&apos;s U.S. System And Sales International Expansion
 Tricon Global Restaurants, Inc
 KFC U.S. Systems And Sales Pizza Hut U.S. System And Sales Taco Bell U.S. System And Sales Tricon Restaurants&apos; U.S. Customer Demographics Refranchising U.S. Growth Opportunities International Sales And Growth Opportunities Profit Margins
 Wendy&apos;s International, Inc.
 Wendy&apos;s Restaurant U.S. System And Sales Franchised and Company Units Wendy&apos;s U.S. Customer Demographics Advertising International Operations Operating Costs And Profitability
 800.706.8242 Int&apos;l: +1.240.747.3097 Questions? Contact a research specialist&gt; 

 Most Popular Research Algae Biofuels Production Technologies Worldwide SBI Bulletin: Waste to Energy Technologies, Market Size and Growth: 2006-2021 
 
 

 Privacy Policy   |   Terms and Conditions   |   Site Map   |   Return Policy   |   Press   |   Help FAQs 
 Copyright© 2012 SBI. All Rights Reserved.
A division of Market Research Group, LLC 7/12/2012 - 40 
 SSL 
 Contact Us: 800.706.8242 (U.S.)
or +1.240.747.3097 (Int&apos;l)
Hours: Monday - Thursday: 5:30am - 7:00pm EST
 Fridays: 5:30am - 6:00pm EST
	</body>
</document>
