<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005550" url="http://restaurantworkerspayattention.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:06" support="2" score="0.00265644998044981" bingtitle="Restaurant Workers Pay Attention to Everything" webtitle="Restaurant Workers Pay Attention to Everything">
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>... restaurants there are designated areas for trash. ... leave larges messes everywhere or let random condiments ... Be it we where at a fast food restaurant: McDonald&apos;s, Burger King ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Workers Pay Attention to Everything
 
 
 
Fish
 
 Saturday, April 14, 2012 
 
 &quot;Tell the nice man what you want dear.&quot; 
 First off thank you to everyone who has checked out the blog so far, it has been very encouraging to see all the views. Now to the matter at hand. As previously stated I myself have two children, my four year old son James, and my one year old daugther Sarah. Now James is at the age where he wants to do everything for himself; pick out his own clothes, putting on his own shoes, order his own food when we go out, typical child like ideas to show they are big and can do it all by themselves. Now I do encourage parents to let their kids order, it helps them become more aware of what they can and can not do. But there is a time and place for everything. And a long dinner rush line is not the time nor place to apply this teaching. When you see you are in a line full of hungry other customers,who do not wish to wait in line the extra 5 minutes it takes junior to order two or three things, pleasea order for your child. It helps the line move so much faster. Now when you come in and its just you or just a few people in-line, by all means let your child order for themself. But if you see a line, speak up for them, you know what the like and do not like. Don&apos;t tell them to &quot;Speak up, they can&apos;t hear you&quot; or &quot;Tell him/her what you want&quot; just say &quot;They want, this, and this, and that on there and that will be all.&quot; So please do us all a favor and just order for your kids. Just remeber we&apos;re always watching Posted by The watchful eye at restaurants No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Wednesday, April 11, 2012 
 
 Let me do my job please 
 First of, thanks to everyone who has checked out the blog! You guys are awesome! It&apos;s good to know people out there have worked the same crappy jobs I have. Now todays post is geared to those of us who have worked in any sort of restaurant that has a line where you start to order on one end, go down the line, and pay at the other end. Now don&apos;t get me wrong I appreciate a person trying to help out but, I the one who is at that restuarant six days a week thru lunch and dinner rush. I think I know what our menu consits of. So please don&apos;t tell me what you had when I ask &quot;Hi, how are you doing today?&quot; I clearly see what yuo have I have watch you top it with everything under the sun all the way down the line. Now sometimes I may not catch it that is when telling me what you had comes into play. The correct question for that answer would be &quot;Hi, what did you have today sir/mama?&quot; So please be concious of what is being asked of you. It takes 2-4 minutes to get your order ready so plays just focus for that little amount of time. Is that too much to ask? Again thank you to everyone who has checked out the blog. Please pass it along to your friends. Who knows maybe we can really go somewhere with this! And never forget customers....We are always watching Posted by The watchful eye at restaurants No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Tuesday, April 10, 2012 
 
 Please get off your phone! 
 Yes, believe it or not it is possible to live without your cell phone for five minutes to place an order for your food. No, it is not ok while during the lunch rush to stop searching for you card in that unnecesarly large purse; to look in four seperate wallets to answer a cell phone call about &quot;did you hear about sally and tim?&quot; or somoe other usless bit of gossip. Let it ring you can call them back after you sit down.You are not the only one person in the line. Other people actualy want to get through the line and get their food. So please b respectful. Drop you phone of five minutes and get through the line. Thanks have a great day! Posted by The watchful eye at restaurants No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Monday, April 9, 2012 
 
 We are not maids 
 Yes, it is understood that at most restaurants their is designated personal to clean the dinning area. Be it bus boys/ bus women, servers, gss (guest service specialist) or what ever you wish to call them. At most quick serve restaurants there are designated areas for trash. Now you are not expected to wipe off table, sweep and mop your area, or any detailed cleaning. But please use common sense. Now if we go out to eat my 4 year old knows to clean up after himself. Not to leave fries everywhere on the floor or not get ketchup everywhere. Would you while your at home leave larges messes everywhere or let random condiments stick to the table? I would surely hope not. Yes, part of mine and every other restaurant workers&apos; pay is some way or another tied to cleaning. But please be conscious of the person who has to clean up behind you. I would thourghly be imbarassed by some of the comments I hear that are shared between the fraternity of restuarant workers about &quot;ditry&quot; customers. Always keep the old saying in the back of your mind &quot;Someone is watching, even when you think there is no one around&quot; Posted by The watchful eye at restaurants No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 Sunday, April 1, 2012 
 
 Contrary to popular belief, we are not baby sitters 
 Now I, myself, have two wonderfully great children. A son, and daughter, four and one respectively. When I went out with my family, where ever be, to eat I was on my best behaviour. Be it we where at a fast food restaurant: McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, etc. or going to a a sit down restaurant: O&apos;Charley&apos;s, Olive Garden, etc. It did not matter. I knew if I acted up I was going to get into trouble. I was a belt fearing child. Parents now a days are terrified of their own shadow if they try to &quot;discipline&quot; their child. An because of this fear they will let their child act as if they &quot;own the place&quot;. Children throwing tantrums, running around the restaurant, and making any mess they can. Now there are times when a child will be a child, but there is no reason for a child to be yelling at the the top of their lungs at the parent. If I had ever attempted to do so would have immediately have a swift pop to my mouth. There is no reason to let them run all across the dinning room. It is a safety hazard and down right disrespectful to the other paying patrons of said restaurant. It shows you have no control of your child or you lack the motivation to care. And at home do you just let your children throw food all over the place? Now I understand children between the ages of nine months and twenty months are still trying to get feeding themselves down, their mess is understandable, but do you just leave it laying around at home? I&apos;m quite certain your mother does not work with me, so why should have to clean an unnecessary mess? Yes I am a paid to clean up after you, but please be respectful to those who are cleaning up after you. With that being said most children are great, well behaved, and respectful. But just like the old saying goes &quot;One bad apple can spoil the bunch&quot;, the same applies here. So mom and dad, sitting at your table playing with your cell phone, please put the phone down for twenty or so minutes and spend some family time together and watch your children. It would be greatly appreciated by everyone here. Posted by The watchful eye at restaurants No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (6) 
 ▼  April (5) 
 &quot;Tell the nice man what you want dear.&quot; Let me do my job please Please get off your phone! We are not maids Contrary to popular belief, we are not baby sitter... 
 

 ►  March (1) 
 Welcoming Post 
 
 
 
About Me
 The watchful eye at restaurants View my complete profile 
 
 Simple template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
