<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005847" url="http://mumbaiboss.com/2010/10/11/mb-maps-lower-parel-lunching/" time="2012-07-12-22:31" support="1" score="0.0013027379198350681" bingtitle="MB Maps: Lower Parel Lunching | Mumbai Boss" webtitle="MB Maps: Lower Parel Lunching | Mumbai Boss">
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>Shop No. 7/8, Wadachi Chawl, NM Joshi Marg. 2297 ... Fast food restaurant that serves a wholesome paratha thali. ... Leave a comment Cancel reply</description>
	<body>
		rss Twitter Facebook Flickr Search for: MUMBAI BOSS Jul 12, 2012 Please enable Javascript to view the weather. Front Page News Culture Events Food&amp;Nightlife Shopping&amp;Fashion Guides 
MB Maps: Lower Parel Lunching
 October 11, 2010 8:20 am by Purva Mehra 
 DOWNLOAD THE MAP HERE . 

 A. Rajnanda 
 Shop No. 7/8, Wadachi Chawl, NM Joshi Marg. 2297 8484 .
Malwani restaurant known for pomfret masala, bombil fry, pomfret chilli and surmai thalis.

 B. Swami Snacks 
 Shop No. 1/2, Saksham Building, SB Marg, opposite Kamala Mills. 99672 45999 .
Vegetarian take-out best for veggie grilled sandwiches, cheese frankies, pav bhaji and chaat.

 C. Jai Hind Lunch Home 
 7/8 Madhav Bhavan, B Block, SB Marg, opposite Kamala Mills. 2493 0010 .
Popular lunch home chain that specialises in coastal cuisine from Goa, Karnataka and the Konkan belt.

 D. The Mumbai Deli 
 6 Madhav Bhavan, SB Marg, opposite Kamala Mills. 6529 3154 .
Ideal for quick sandwich and salad lunches. Serves an excellent barley and zucchini salad, and Italian spicy grilled panini.

 E. Shri Krishna 
 1/2 Madhav Bhavan, opposite Kamala Mills, SB Marg. 3255 2327. 
Standard Udipi fare such as dosas and uttapam, as well as thalis and biryanis.

 F. Ext. 202 
 New Mahalaxmi Mills, Mathuradas Mill Compound. 2492 6202. 
A vegetarian cafeteria that serves good pasta in pesto sauce, Maggie in alfredo sauce and cream cheese bagels.

 G. Srinathji’s Taste the Nectar 
 Jagdamba Bhavan, opposite Matulya Centre, SB Marg. 2498 5857 .
Indianised versions of Lebanese, Mexican and Italian cuisines. Also has a bakery section with cookies, farsan, breads, Bengali sweets and pastries.

 H. Paninaro 
 Peninsula Corporate Park, Ganapatrao Kadam Marg, off SB Marg. 6151 9999 .
Salad and sandwich truck that specialises in gourmet sandwiches like smoked scarmoza and tomato, avocado and olives, and smoked chicken and bacon.

 I . Ramnath Damoodar Sandwich 
 197 Shenoy Building, Ganapathrao Kadam Marg, opposite Peninsula Corporate Park. 6427 5698 .
Popular sandwich and juice stall known for its capsicum cheese toastie and chilli-cheese grilled sandwich.

 J. Modern Family Restaurant 
 B-184 Jodia Mansion, Ganapathrao Kadam Marg, opposite Peninsula Corporate Park. 2492 2585 .
Restaurant and juice centre that serves non-veg paratha rolls and a great prawn biryani.

 K. DP’s Wok Hei 
 Khimji Nagji Building, opposite High Street Phoenix, SB Marg. 2495 4627 .
A wide mix of cuisines including Mangalorean, Mongolian, Tibetan and Chinese. The chilli beer chicken, and Mangalorean kori roti and chicken curry are popular.

 L. Maroosh 
 High Street Phoenix compound, SB Marg. 98333 97060 .
Well known for its chicken shawarma. But also serves Mughlai food like kebabs and curries.

 M. Trupti 
 Unit 12-B, Palladium, High Street Phoenix. 2490 2211 .
Snack shop that delivers veg sandwiches and fresh Gujarati farsan like kachori, dhokla, kandvi and handvo.

 N. Komala’s 
 Below PVR cinema, High Street Phoenix. 4347 3929 .
South Indian fast food chain that serves great rasam, bisibelebath, rasam vada and South Indian thali.

 O. Wich Latte 
 Phoenix Mills food court, SB Marg. Tel: 6510 0719 .
Try their turkey sandwiches or bagel pizzas. They also do an excellent Swiss chocolate mousse.

 P. Indigo Deli 
 First Floor, Palladium, High Street Phoenix. 2498 6262 .
Bagel and lox, burgers, chorizo pizza and red currant cheesecake are must-haves at this popular eatery.

 Q. Grass Root 
 Opposite High Street Phoenix, SB Marg. 2491 3131 .
Fast food restaurant that serves a wholesome paratha thali.

 R. Da Vinci’s Express 
 Raghuvanshi Mills, next to Tata Power Gate, near High Street Phoenix. 93201 36611 .
Take-out place that has a limited range of paninis, Greek and Italian salads and also pizza by the slice.

 S. Little Italy 
 Raghuvanshi Mills, SB Marg, Lower Parel. 6615 9988 .
Popular Italian restaurant chain that specialises in veggie pizzas and pastas.

 T. The Tasting Room 
 First Floor, Good Earth, Raghuvanshi Mills. 6528 5284 .
An airy restaurant and wine bar best known for its grilled chicken breast, Moroccan tagine, and dessert counter.

 SEE ALSO 
 MB Maps: Crawford Market 
 MB Maps: Colaba Causeway 
 Tags: Da Vinci&apos;s Express , DP&apos;s Wok Hei , Ext 202 , Grass Root , High Street Phoenix , Indigo Deli , Jai Hind Lunch Home , Komala&apos;s , Little Italy , Lower Parel , Maps , Maroosh , MB Maps , Modern Family Restaurant , Palladium , Paninaro , Rajnanda , Ramnath Damoodar Sandwich , Shri Krishna , Special Top Story , Srinathji&apos;s Taste The Nectar , Swami Snacks , The Mumbai deli , The Tasting Room , Trupti , Wich Latte 
Comments (2)

 Hari | October 11, 2010 at 10:16 am 
This is a great list, Thanks!
 Sanjana | October 13, 2010 at 4:00 pm 
Hey, I loved the Crawford map–had some gems and this one’s awesome as well. I love Mumbai Boss!
 
 
Leave a comment Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Featured Articles
 
 The Weekend Guide 
 July 12, 2012 by  Editors 
 Tic TAAQ Toe 
 July 11, 2012 by  Amit Gurbaxani 
 Stalled City: Five Major Infrastructure Projects In Limbo 
 July 11, 2012 by  First Post 
 Q&amp;A With‘Cocktail’Director Homi Adajania 
 July 10, 2012 by  Editors 
You Might Also Like...
 
 Most Viewed Most Commented 
 
 Is the Masala Dosa India’s Most Iconic Dish? The Vigil Idiot: Bol Bachchan Dhoble To Ease Up On Raids Until Tuesday Pest Control: How Restaurants Keep Flies Away Get The New Auto-Rickshaw Tariff Card Here 
 
 TV Review:‘Coke Studio @ MTV’Season Two First World Problems Nita Ambani Opens Up (A Little) About Antilia Get The New Auto-Rickshaw Tariff Card Here MB Maps: Crawford Market 
 
Mumbai Boss On The Go
 © 2010 Kaisar Media Private Ltd. Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Advertise with Us | About Us | Contact Us Partners: 
 Zomato Mumbai Guardian Travel Network
	</body>
</document>
