<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005824" url="http://local.stv.tv/east-kilbride/place/1099640-dlish/offer/38/" time="2012-07-12-22:28" support="14" score="0.039477775872290476" bingtitle="D&apos;Lish Cafe-Deli | Place | East Kilbride | STV" webtitle="DLish Cafe-Deli | Place | East Kilbride | STV">
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000985" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000672" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000954" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000809" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000265" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001394" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>Great place to sit at bar and enjoy hustle of ... The Thai claims not to be a fast food restaurant, they ... of experiences when bill had items on them that we didn&apos;t order.</description>
	<body>
		STV East Kilbride 
 Change town 
 Medium-level cloud 
 Navigation↓ 
 Home News Directory Events Info Groups Video 
 
East Kilbride in video
 
 
STV News (Central edition) 1.55pm - Thursday, July 12
 
STV News (Central edition) 10.40pm – Wednesday, July 11, 2012
 
STV News at Six (Glasgow&amp;West) – Wednesday, July 11, 2012
 
 
 Eating&amp;Drinking Health&amp;Well-being Hotels&amp;Accommodation Learning&amp;Education Professional Services Public Services Shopping Sport&amp;Leisure Things to see Trades&amp;DIY Transportation Venues&amp;Nightlife 
 
 Cafés&amp;Coffee Shops 

 Add a place 
 
D&apos;Lish Cafe-Deli
 5 
 15 St. James Avenue, St James Retail Park, Hairmyres, East Kilbride, G74 5QD 

 01355 239687 Website 
 55.7604561 -4.2282615 
Welcome to D&apos;Lish Cafe-Deli tucked away in St James Retail Park, 5 minutes walk from Hairmyres Station. Home baking, sit in or takeaway, catering on your doorstep.

New evening menu in our licensed premises from 21st June.

With home baking made daily on the premises, why not pop in for a tea and a scone?

With a full menu of both hot and cold food available for sit-in or to go, all freshly made, D&apos;Lish is a hidden treasure.

Having a function?

Need a buffet lunch for that business meeting?

Let D&apos;Lish take care of all your catering needs with finger buffets, baguettes and wraps, soups, salads, cakes and patisserie.

Call for details: 01355 239687

Starting from 21st June, our new evening menu in our licensed premises is perfect for that special occasion.
 
 Map Similar Places 
 
 
 Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s 

 East Kilbride Shopping Centre, Olympia, East Kilbride, G74 1PG 

 
 0.000 55.7593956 -4.1756663 
 Berits And Brown 

 Centre West Shopping Centre, East Kilbride, G74 1LL 

 01355 266878 
 0.000 55.7598686 -4.1819887 
 Streat 

 Centre West, East Kilbride Shopping Centre , East Kilbride, G74 1LL 

 0135 522 7622 
 0.000 55.7598686 -4.1819887 
 The Diner 

 27 Main Street, The Village, East Kilbride, G74 2JT 

 01355 242 626 
 5.000 55.7665863 -4.1455545 
 BB&apos;s Coffee&amp;Muffins 

 East Kilbride Shopping Centre, 4 Olympia, East Kilbride, Glasgow, G74 1PG 

 0135 522 5077 
 0.000 55.7593956 -4.1756663 
 Starbucks Coffee 

 East Kilbride Shopping Centre, Centre West, East Kilbride, G74 1LL 

 01355 579774 
 0.000 55.7598686 -4.1819887 
 @ The Diner 

 27 Main St, Village, East Kilbride, East Kilbride, G74 4JU 

 01355 242626 
 0.000 55.7663269 -4.1756697 
 Cafe India 

 East Kilbride Shopping Centre, Olympia, East Kilbride, G74 1PG 

 01355 236577 
 0.000 55.7593956 -4.1756663 
 Cafe Vienna 

 East Kilbride Shopping Centre, Princes Square, East Kilbride, G74 1LJ 

 01355 579563 
 0.000 55.7608261 -4.1775789 
 Coffee Stop 

 East Kilbride Shopping Centre, Olympia, East Kilbride, G74 1PG 

 01355 241882 
 0.000 55.7593956 -4.1756663 
 
Reviews

 
Fine Juke Box - or used to have in 1989 at least.
 3 Shaba 21/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice wee pub, with a cracking restaurant underneath.

Good quality Scottish fare.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 21/08/2009 Report this place 
Usual soulless Wetherspoons fare.

Cheap booze but nothing worth writing home about.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 21/08/2009 Report this place 
Glasgow institution, reputedly the longest bar in Western Europe or something, &apos;cos it goes around in a kind of double horse-shoe. often busy, specialyl after work, but plenty of banter
 3 cheekyweeman 23/08/2009 Report this place 
The best pub in Glasgow. Proper beer, good food (in the bar) no canned music, no beeping slots machines, life music sessions and a genuinely friednly atmospherem, not something you can say of every Glasgow boozer. My local - and I pass at least ten others en route to it.
 5 cheekyweeman 23/08/2009 Report this place 
If you are fancying value for money and rapid delivery then New Happy Palace is for you. Lemon Chicken is firm favourite for me and also Jongpo chicken with extra sauce.

The place is always busy and the service is friendly and efficient. Just remember Chinese New Year - it closes for good few days.
 4 CaseyJones 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Very fine single fish and a handy location at the top of Leith Walk.
 5 Shaba 24/08/2009 Report this place 
This Bier Halle chain continues is successful growth with this West End option. Found at the city end of Great Western Road, is a little different from the city centre sister bars in that it is above ground, with light pouring in through bay windows. It still serves similar quality beers, albeit a little over priced.




 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Bar Ten serves excellent food. Ciabatta sandwiches, Salads, Burittos (highly recommended) and specials can all be found on the menu.



Draught beer is a bit limited, but there&apos;s enough options behind the bar to keep even the most fussy happy.



It&apos;s located down Mitchell Lane, across from The Lighthouse and next to DLC Hairdressers.




 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Located in the heart of the Merchant City, one of the original style bars is still going. Although it still looks very nice inside, there&apos;s a general feeling of tiredness around this bar.



The food is pretty good, in particular the homemade burgers. The have Local brewery West on draught along side continental lagers and the usual spirits and bottles.
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
One of the worst bar/clubs in Glasgow. Head straight in if you&apos;re after the shirt and shoe brigade, the stag do&apos;s, the hen nights or the munters dancing round their hand bags to some of the worst tunes ever to be pumped out by a &quot;disc jockey&quot;.


 1 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
This is a decent addition to the Merchant City. It&apos;s one of the newer bars with floor to ceiling windows, leather couches, kitsch chairs, floral wallpaper adorned with pictures from the 80s and an outside sitting area.



The food isn&apos;t up to much but it does do 241 burgers during the week if you are interested in that kind of thing.



It has several large TVs which makes it ideal for watching football.
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
The Black Sparrow (and its sister bar next door, Chinaskis) is one of the best bars in Glasgow. An excellent setting with exposed brick and leather booths, it serves up some brilliant draught lagers and the usual bottled beers, wines and spirits.



At £4.50 a pint, it&apos;s a bit expensive but well worth it... especially on payday.
 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Overpriced, overcooked chips and cheese and other saturated fat goodness available for when you stumble home at three in the morning.
 2 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Oh, and it&apos;s not a Kitchen and it&apos;s not international. It&apos;s rubbish and it&apos;s a chippy.
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
This place is ruuuuuubish
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
This is one of the best restaurants in Glasgow serving up some of the best Scottish food you will find in the city.



Set in the Merchant City, it&apos;s in nice surroundings and excellent company with some other fine restaurants and bars close by.
 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Ad Lib is a funny restaurant. It should be excellent but always fails to hit the spot.



Saying that, it does serve up some of the best burgers you will find around town. The menu is varied, with burgers, fish, meats and pastas all found on the menu.



I think it&apos;s overpriced for what you get. Especially as the dishes are on the small side. However, it&apos;s still worth while checking it out.



It also does take-away, which is good if you live close by!
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Serving up some fine Italian food, tapas style!



This is a very cosmopolitan restaurant with very nice surrounding, attentive, polite and happy staff.



Tapas include fish dishes, Italian favorites like meatballs, small pizzas and much, much more.



This should be well up you list for checking out.
 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
The Restaurant is hidden at the back of the bar. It doesn&apos;t look much but it serves up some very tasty food.



This is a good choice if you fancy staying in the same place all night. the Bar to the front is decent, with a good playlist and it&apos;s open till 3am.
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
This is an utterly disappointing restaurant. The food is mediocre at best and the interior leaves a lot to be desired.



Head straight across the road to the Italian Kitchen for a better dining experience.
 2 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Good shop with lots of choice, especially for cheap suits and denims. Not the biggest Burtons around so it gets a bit crammed.
 4 Charlie 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Although it&apos;s part of a chain, this noodle bar never fails to disappoint. It has various rice, noodle and soup dishes. I recommend Salmon Ramen



Food is served up as it&apos;s ready in an informal, relaxed, kitchen environment.



It&apos;s well worth checking out.
 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
I prefer Oko to Wagamama because it&apos;s a smaller restaurant. It has a superb sushi menu along side various rice and noodle dishes.



If you have been to Wagamama and looking for an alternative, check it out. If you are looking to try out some Japanese and fusion dishes be sure to stop by.
 4 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Soba is a bar restaurant down Mitchell Lane across from Bar Ten. It&apos;s a decent bar with a good cocktail list.



The food is Japanese-fusion with various rice and noodle dishes. The burgers are brilliant, especially the veggie one!



This is a great place for an early dinner before heading out. It also does cocktail lessons downstairs.
 3 bambam 24/08/2009 Report this place 
A very hilly course with lots of challenging par 3&apos;s. You have to be fit to play here and take a pair of hiking boots with you! The course is best to play in the summer as it can get a bit boggy during the winter.
 4 Charlie 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Spent my youth in here, smoking fags and playing pool. The machines are about 10 years behind those found elsewhere so expect £2 jackpots to be the norm.
 1 Charlie 24/08/2009 Report this place 
The best Carbonara in Glasgow, and good for a wee takeaway after the dancing.
 4 Charlie 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Great deal on a baked tattie for lunch-time - £1.70 with 2 toppings.



Also offer the usual late night fare - kebabs, pizzas etc. Not too bad but not the greatest.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Some of the most awesome chips n cheese known to man can be obtained at Morello.



Rest of the scan is pretty standard fare tho.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Much like any other Subway,



Footlong meatball is my weapon of choice.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Wee bit more expensive than most places but you get to add as much as you want to your piece. And if you&apos;re sly you won&apos;t need to pay any extra.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Great place for a greasy roll the morning after a few beers.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Can feel a bit impersonal and a bit rushed sometimes but the food is more than worth it. So much to choose from.



Chicken Katsu Curry is amazing.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Never eaten in the restaurant but have attended some work christmas parties and the food was always decent - and not bad considering it was produced en masse.



Bit of an older crowd in the bar usually.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Ate in here once. Horrible service and some of the worst Fish n Chips i&apos;ve ever had the misfortune to consume.



Bar is not bad at night - but i wouldnt eat here again.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Great food in a really nice atmosphere. Invaluable wine knowledge from the waiter as well.



Seats overlooking Princes Square or out the huge windows at the back. Recommended.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Some of the best ice-cream in Glasgow can be obtained from Jaconelli&apos;s.



Get me a big tub with strawberry sauce.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice burgers.



The barbeque sauce is amazing.




 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Gin and Tonic for little more than a quid? Count me in!



The Bee is one of the most old-fashioned, traditional pubs in Perth and I wouldn&apos;t change it for anything. Home to some quality weekend music and some of the keenest prices in town, and a friendly clientelle.
 5 Big Baws 24/08/2009 Report this place 
&quot;Amusement Park&quot;? It&apos;s Perth&apos;s premier puggy emporium. Don&apos;t expect to find any rollercoasters.
 1 Big Baws 24/08/2009 Report this place 
You&apos;d be hard pushed to get a pint in this bar now - it&apos;s been knocked down :-(
 1 CaseyJones 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic place, always busy so book. Fish cakes are legendary. If you like space between tables then Fishers is not the place for you, but conversely if you like atmosphere of people enjoying great food then go for it.
 3 CaseyJones 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Want to spoil yourself then this is the place. Get one of the alcove tables with the chain curtains. Food is very good, especially the dessert platter. We had group of 3 and spent 10 mins spoons in hand trying variety of sweets - strawberries coated in chocolate, lemon cheese cake, ice cream. nothing left.



Bill was reasonable, but book ahead.
 3 CaseyJones 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Ornate bar full of character. Wide ranging clientele and good range of Malt Whiskies. Great place to sit at bar and enjoy hustle of a town centre bar.
 3 CaseyJones 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Not used to reviewing department stores, but great place to get suit shirt, good quality and often sales on. Wide range to choose from (short-sleeved, long-sleeved, button cuffs, cufflink cuffs).
 3 CaseyJones 24/08/2009 Report this place 
Just up from Tollcross and around the corner from the meadows - can be quite blokey despite being nextt door to the theatre - good beer and decent screen for football.
 5 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Great spot for a beer after a round of golf on the Meadows. Re-worked as &quot;sports bar&quot; but still a decent spot for a quick pint.
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
great chips and always busy - esp after last orders
 3 CaseyJones 25/08/2009 Report this place 
This is probably THE best place for karaoke in the entire world! The quality of singers is usually pretty high, and the audience is usually really receptive and welcoming! I even got a standing ovation myself a fair few times, and I can&apos;t sing! haha! Highly recommended!
 5 TheLittlerich 25/08/2009 Report this place 
&apos;Tis not a bad place. Pros: - it doubles up as a night club after normal pub hours finish. - It is near city centre, good for transport / food eatery places afterwards. Cons: The nightclub is a bit pricy.
 3 TheLittlerich 25/08/2009 Report this place 
No football colours and no trainers allowed. Is ok.
 3 TheLittlerich 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Cracking location right at heart of the City on George Street, between / parallel with Queen St / Princes Street - with good access to New and Old town. IMO the older rooms are better. Bar can be pretty full-on in term of noise - plush but pricey!
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Great value and atmosphere - perfect for a post match pint at Easter Road.
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Lively - yup - tiny upstairs bar and another space below - can get very busy but great late night venue for a night cap. Seems at times most other folk in Edinburgh have had the same idea - especially during the festival. Not every night but watch out for: the legendary six fingered lady folk guitarist, full-on Welsh male voice choirs, divas relaxing their vocal chords with a nip or two after late night performance, your mate giving impromptu chipmunk style version of &quot;Maggie May&quot; after one Deuchars too many!
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Always worth a quick stop off on the way up the hill.
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Formerly &quot;house&quot; pub for journalists and staff from The Scotsmannewspaper - you will still find the odd journo propping up the bar. Named after George Heriot - on his death Heriot left a considerable amount of cash for a hospital for the &quot;puir fatherless bairns&quot; this later became George Heriot&apos;s School.
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
AKA - The Heb - great, friendly pub and very handy for the station. Andy Chung plays a fine set every Thursday night - or used to at least !
 4 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Gallery is free and the main collection has some modern classics - Hirst, Warhol etc. As for the cafe - great freshly prepared food / cakes / scones etc. and relaxing outdoor space. Also has huge Teletubby style landscaped gardens out front for the kids to run wild on - myth persists that it was designed by architect / designer Charles Jencks but clearly inspired by the TV series.
 5 Shaba 25/08/2009 Report this place 
Fairly typical J D Wetherspoon pub, meaning that drinks are pretty standard, but reasonably priced.
 2 Blongs 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Jar is a fantastic Hairdressers with friendly and experienced staff - would highly recommend for colour, cut and special events.



Two enthusiastic thumbs up and five shiney *stars*!!
 5 Dan! 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Quite a small bar in the middle of the Merchant City area. Can get very busy especially when a football match is on, making getting a seat tricky (if not impossible). Interesting mixed shots available if you like that kind of thing!
 3 Blongs 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Great bar if you love shots and cocktails. Staff friendly and efficient, although it can get very busy on a Friday night. Plenty of cocktail menus about the place, which is better than the places that you have to ask for one (like it&apos;s a big secret).

They sell double measures of some spirits (including Jack Daniel&apos;s) for £1.50 extra which is always a benefit! They are also fine if you ask for an ingredient to be changed in one of their cocktails if you don&apos;t like something, great if you like keeping the wife happy!!!
 5 Blongs 26/08/2009 Report this place 
This bar is a hidden treasure on Sauchiehall Street. From the outside you may mistake it for a restaurant, but when you make it inside you a treated to a slightly gothic looking bar, with exposed brickwork and natural light coming in from skylights near the bar area.

This bar is part of the Social Animal chain, so most things fairly standard, but they do have a few cocktails that aren&apos;t on the standard Social Animal list.

Overall a hip and trendly bar with a great feel to it, perfect for an afternoon drinking session in nice sourounding or to set you up for a night of clubbing.
 5 Blongs 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Top barnet producers
 4 bambam 26/08/2009 Report this place 
I love Clone Zone. It&apos;s just the best darn clothes (read, sex) shop in Glasgow. My darlings and I shop in here for all our dancing gear and lots, lots more.



I bought my slave a rubber suit from here. It&apos;s a little small and we need to use a bit too much talc to slide (oh-er!) him in. However, I&apos;ll work him hard so he loses some of that extra blubber.



They sell the best magazines with some of the stiffest cocktail recipes you&apos;ll ever see in this darn city. I like a good hard cocktail.



They also sell vibrators (big ones, small ones, loud ones, colourfull ones), dildos (strap-ons, blow up ones, glowing ones, monster ones), handcuffs (steel, furry or pink) and all sorts of filthy, dirty sex toys that you can enjoy alone or with friends... in the privacy of your own webcam, I mean home.
 4 bambam 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Quality Fish&amp;Chips.
 4 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
The best veg pakora / spicy onions in the English speaking world. Well after a few beers anyway.
 3 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Great location in West End. Stripped down, no nonsense ...
 4 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Must be among the best beer in Edinburgh - including Deuchars.
 5 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Hidden gem down just off the High Street up near the castle. Seats outside for warmer nights.
 4 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Ask any local, Sunday nights in The Lorne are legendary!!
 5 GillP 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Great service - always deliver !
 4 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Lovely bar, really lively at weekends with great views of Oban Bay. Great food too.
 5 GillP 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Great wee cafe, brilliant for lunch
 5 GillP 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Great value and great fun. Firm family favourite - beef on the bone for two is fantastic as is the chocolate pudding to share.
 5 Shaba 26/08/2009 Report this place 
A great wee museum, don&apos;t miss the observatory behind it too!
 5 Buddy1 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Sadly burger King closed this branch at the start of August 09. Check before you head there.
 1 Buddy1 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Don&apos;t miss the Bull Inn if you like a mix of alcohol and architecture. It&apos;s an art nouveau gem by local architect WD McLennan and full of character.
 5 Buddy1 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic food, although Persian origins the Koolba specialises in Indian cuisine. It was voted Scotland&apos;s best Indian restaurant of the year and well worth a visit.
 5 Rob4955 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Very good Council run course. 18th used to be the longest hole in Scotland at 601 yds and is a mighty hike when the wind is against you. Book during summer, esp weekends as is popular and Golf Club have block bookings for medals / comps.

As it is a public course then you will occassionally get people walking across fairways, even jumping on and hitting random balls, bear that in mind as you line up your Cobra Driver ....

If you are playing on your own don&apos;t be put off when you&apos;re asked to join the group in front or behind you. It is a local course and there is a strong golf-loving feel to the place.
 4 CaseyJones 26/08/2009 Report this place 
One of the smaller pubs in town but one of the most welcoming. They used to say there were two doors - the wooden one and the &apos;smoke barrier&apos; once you were inside - thankfully no longer a problem.

The Kirky is home to a regular bunch but isn&apos;t cliquey and is one of the few places you&apos;ll still get a fantastic pint of Tartan Special. Always a pleasure.
 5 IBM 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Typical Wetherspoons stuff - real ales, cheap lagers, lots of colourful drink for the kids and microwave food.

The curry night is good (microwaved or not) and the bar is big enough to accommodate a good healthy gathering of neds and leave plenty room for the rest of us.
 1 IBM 26/08/2009 Report this place 
A proper old fashioned pub, with one of the last &quot;horseshoe&quot; bars in town - a real blast from the past.

As with most old working mens&apos; pubs, the ladies toilets are an obvious afterthought which sadly makes the bar a bit smaller, there&apos;s a massive brewery mirror on the wall, and of course the floor lino can get a bit sticky.

Having said all that, you&apos;ll never wait more than a couple of minutes to get served, there&apos;s a great selection of drink at keen prices and there&apos;s some real down-to-earth friendly punters in there most of the time. Visit and enjoy.
 5 IBM 26/08/2009 Report this place 
This isn&apos;t really a pub, it&apos;s a cocktail bar bolted onto a restaurant. It&apos;s also tiny but given some of the prices, it never gets all that busy!

The ladies love the cocktails - the bar has been known to offer cocktail lessons and some happy hours offering drinks for around £2. Bothy is in a good spot for going to the restaurant or as a starting point for a night in the centre of town.

Also very handy for the Theatre (next door the other way) and the Concert Hall along the road.
 4 IBM 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Wow, where do you start. Easily spend a day in here, loads of amazing displays. One plus is has over some stuffy museums is that it is &apos;child friendly&apos;. My son (3.5yrs) loves it. Behind the cafe (expensive and limited - so take your own food!) is the open area with lots of hands-on exhibits.

Don&apos;t just go here on a rainy day. Lots for all ages. Easy to get to as in centre of old town. Watch out for the Museum Shop which is strategically placed on one side of a surprisingly thin corridor - a definite trap I think as it is full of kids wining at their parents as to why they &apos;have to buy the woolly mammoth tea cosy&apos;.

Staff are very friendly and always on hand - one of best (FREE) attractions in Edinburgh, if you don&apos;t fancy visiting the Castle and taking out a second mortgage then the Museum is definitely worth a visit.
 4 CaseyJones 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Greyfriars is an odd mix. Despite being decorated like my mum&apos;s living room and having some odd Gaelic stuff painted on the wall outside (which also looks like it was based on buildings from a cowboys&amp;indians movie) - it&apos;s a good boozer.

The pub serves a host of local ales from the Inveralmond Brewery, which is a bonus for those who can stand them; otherwise there&apos;s a friendly welcome, some peace and quiet to have a blether and a keenly priced selection of booze.
 1 IBM 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Thrust into the spotlight recently after a high profile visit by cyclist Lance Armstrong, this hotel looks like it has been around for a hundred years. In fact it&apos;s a refurbished property and a daring venture into the boutique hotel market in the middle of paisley. Surprising, charming and worth a second look.
 4 Buddy1 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Not a real watermill, but an institution in Paisley for decades. Right in the middle of town, but in it&apos;s own quiet setting near the abbey and the old anchor mill at the Hammills waterfall. Not five star, but a decent hotel with nice staff and a good value carvery resturant.
 3 Buddy1 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Ok, I&apos;m biased because I&apos;ve known Joe for years, but he is brilliant, highly experienced and does pull out the stops when you need him. The downside might be the lengthy waiting list, but that kind of popularity is a pretty good reference. Book well ahead, unless you are a regular customer.
 4 Buddy1 26/08/2009 Report this place 
Good reliable service, decent value and good drivers with satnavs. Top tip: they seem to arrive really quickly if you phone from a landline instead of a mobile, especially once you are in the customer database. They must all hide round the corner from our house or something!

We use them from Glasgow airport to Paisley, because the regular cabs don&apos;t like to wait all day in the rank for a small fare, and sometimes it shows. Cabs called from a mobile seem to get to the airport in five minutes.
 4 Buddy1 27/08/2009 Report this place 
The Piazza is Paisley&apos;s real town centre these days: it seems to get busier all the time and appears to have a bit of pride and personality about it. Surrounded by bus stops, taxi ranks, a wee car park and a train station, it&apos;s a good, safe low carbon alternative to the car-oriented mega malls not far away. One day all town centres will be like this again.
 4 Buddy1 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Best barber in Glasgow. Great wee shop - friendly, helpful staff, and great haircuts at a reasonable price.

They&apos;ll even give you a beer while you get your hair cut.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
A strange hybrid of Di Maggio&apos;s restaurant and fast food joint but it seems to work. Pizza and chips is amazing and a good choice of pasta&apos;s.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Great choice of interesting Italian meals.

Good quality food although the service at lunchtime can vary a bit depending on how busy they get.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
A mainstay of post-shack eating, i was surprised on a recent night out to discover that Diablero had survived the aforementioned club&apos;s untimely demise.

Standard late night fare is up to scratch.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Good quality, reasonably priced food. The pizza&apos;s are great, as are the ribs.

Also handy for a takeaway if you want something a bit less dripping in fat.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
The bar is nice if you&apos;re looking for somewhere a little posher to have a drink - but the wait for food can be ridiculous.

We waited for 45 minutes for our food only to find out that the barman had not put it through to the kitchen - despite me questioning the whereabouts of it multiple times during that period.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Basically a trough of ok chinese/asian food. Nothing stands out quality wise but if you&apos;ve got a big appetite it&apos;s not hard to get value for money.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice wee local chinese. They do amazing chow mein.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Wee bit expensive for what you get but some of the best burgers in Glasgow - especially since the legendary Spy Burger is no longer available.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This place is rubbish. Even if you are walking home, blazing from Jumping Jacks, this place is rubbish.
 1 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Office always have some belter gutties. Some are exclusives too. The shop is very small so gets very busy, especially at the weekend.

However, we all need shoes, so give peace a chance.

Mad fer it.
 4 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Soul Trader is a decent wee shop. It doesn&apos;t seem to have the range that Office does and it&apos;s generally more expensive, but it&apos;s always worth checking out.
 4 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Tat for tadgers, innit?
 1 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Not the best pub in the world.

I&apos;ve twice had a refund on grub here because it&apos;s been up to 60 mins in arriving (and to rub salt in the wound, the starter and main course arrived at the same time).

The drink&apos;s pretty standard fayre for a chain pub - usual offers for youngsters etc - the real saving grace is the batch of big sofas you can use. They&apos;re not that easy to get hold of at the weekend though!
 1 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
What&apos;s not to love about IKEA? Nice, cheap furniture, perfect for the sub-prime market.
 5 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This place shut down years ago.
 1 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This place is similar to the Bier Halle only not as dark... and not as good. Still, it serves great draught and bottled beers from all over the world.

It&apos;s a good boozer to get a drink before or after dinner in the Merchant City
 3 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice place to grab a sandwich and soup for lunch. The choice of grub is a bit different from the usual sandwich shop and makes a pleasent change. Recommend the soup and a sandwich deal for a hearty lunch time fill up.
 5 Charlie 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This bar is absolutely rubbish! It&apos;s full of trendys or student paps. Both the bottled and draught beers are dull. The only good thing about it is the exposed brick walls.
 1 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This vodka bar used to be the place to be a few years ago. But now it&apos;s tired and boring. Not even the Cola-Cube Vodka can save this place.
 2 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Miso is oh so missed! It used to do some brilliant Japanese food.

It closed it&apos;s doors about two years ago.
 3 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Good for a pint before you catch the bus as its right at the main bus stop, but thats about it. I wouldn&apos;t spend a night in there.
 3 Charlie 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Mother India&apos;s Cafe is part of the successful Mother India group restaurants. It serves very nice Indian food, tapas style.

It is always very busy, doesn&apos;t take bookings meaning you often have to queue for a table. However, queues usually move quickly.
 3 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
2 for 1 pizza is the best thing since the wheel was made round, made out of dough, made horizontal, made with tomato and cheese and put in the oven for 15 minutes. No more need be said!
 5 Michael MacLennan 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Formerly an iron foundry producing man hole covers for the town and beyond; but it&apos;s certainly not a pub that grates.

The only drawback is the toilets - you have to climb up an iron staircase and over a bridge to get there, which is no mean feat.

It&apos;s ike a task from I&apos;m a Celebrity Get Me Out of Here, and although it&apos;s a celebration of the former foundry&apos;s ironworking history, it&apos;s a bit of a drawback at midnight on a Saturday.

Especially when someone&apos;s left a pavement pizza on the stairs.
 3 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This pub is actually called &quot;The Tavern&quot; nowadays, a tribute to the former St Johnstoun Tavern which stood in the building many years ago.

It&apos;s a run-of-the-mill high street boozer though, nothing much to report other than the nice restaurant upstairs, available for private dining.
 3 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This pub certainly ain&apos;t what it used to be. In days of yore it had a huge oval style bar, a legendary darts team and the cheapest beer in town.

The erstwhile landlord, “Auld McDougall”, also used to sell cuts of meat from behind the bar – including a legendary episode with a live lobster, and some top-rank white puddings.

Since then it’s changed hands and been done up – and nowadays is just a bog-standard town boozer with very little worth commenting on. It’s usually good for a quiet pint during the week and always shows the live football on Sky.
 3 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Formerly known as the place where you could get a pint when you were underage The Tams is basically a bigger version of The Grill (now The Retreat, but forever The Grill for our generation!).

There are a large variety of beers at the bar which can be enjoyed until slightly later than most pubs. The Tams also boasts a beer garden, one of the biggest in the town – a very welcome addition in the summer.

One of the better pubs in the town.
 4 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
A pub of two halves. The downstairs is a small but friendly mock-Irish watering hole, with a fireplace and comfy sofas all around - highly recommended if you can fit in.

Upstairs is a huge long space with a bar at either end, and often some music blaring away from somewhere in the centre. It&apos;s got little nooks and crannies throughout the standing area but not too many seats, sadly.

Not as good as it used to be in the good old days of the late 90s when it used to be absolutely mobbed - so much that the floor seemed to bounce...
 2 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This place is always mobbed, and you can never get a seat.
 2 Charlie 27/08/2009 Report this place 
For my money, this pub&apos;s an utter nightmare. Full of late-teenagers supping their first drinks en route to a club or alternatively the local park, and famous for its dance music.

There&apos;s also a sister club upstairs called The Loft which has a slightly different vibe and a bit older clientelle, but otherwise you wouldn&apos;t catch me going near the place.
 1 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
This is the best venue in Glasgow. It&apos;s an old ballroom that was more used to swing than rock and roll. It was rebuilt after a fire destroyed it back in the day and now stands proudly as Glasgow&apos;s best gig venue. It&apos;s a pity it&apos;s now being stalked by housing developers.

Some of the biggest bands from all over the world have played here and many have cited it as one of their best gigs.

As mentioned by Coco, the spring loaded floor makes it brilliant for jumping about on.
 5 bambam 27/08/2009 Report this place 
A very strange pub, this one. It looks like a castle from the outside – funny-looking brickwork and few windows. Things don’t change much once you’re inside either; the place is dark and imposing – the seating area, on two levels, is quite large as locals go.

Famed for a conversation in the late 90s when someone questioned their drink (under the previous management, it should be said):

&quot;The Special tastes like there’s something else in it?&quot;

&quot;Aye – Oxo, I think.&quot;

Note the decor on the walls too – somewhere between the Rovers&apos; Return and Caesar&apos;s Palace.

Add to that the lovely toilets, which are functional and comfortable, with added protection in the form of an extra gutter on the floor beneath the urinal, in case you &apos;miss&apos;, done out in fantastic Roman Bath style. Finally look out for the fantastic jukebox which used to be famous for having only one speaker - sadly now fixed.

Happily for local punters, the Abbotsford is now in the day-to-day management of legendary landlord Chick ‘Fae The Vic’ Doogan, after a brief stint at the Tilted Glass.

Howevver, memories remain of the old regime, and in memory, we can but leave the final word to an immortal regular.

&quot;This place has a certain je ne sais f*** all!&quot;
 4 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Famous for being the pub where a punter was barred for farting too much, too often.

Need we say any more? Must be a quality establishment.
 4 Bob Flaps 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Excellent fish and chips, black puddings and all suppers!
 5 GW 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Good Indian food at reasonable prices.

Watch out for the air conditioning being turned up too high!!
 4 GW 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Very good Italian food. Great value for money and very family friendly.

Well worth a visit
 5 GW 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Very good. Friendly and knowledgeable staff.

Good atmosphere and great service.
 5 GW 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Is ready for it&apos;s new home! But still OK for a visit given it is free (earns an extra star for this).
 3 GW 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Very good family friendly restaurant. Food is good quality and staff are very helpful.

Take away service is fast and efficient.
 5 GW 27/08/2009 Report this place 
Went here many times as a student when it first opened to try the various flavours of vodka. Unfortunately in the last few years it hasnt managed to evolve in any way and is just packed with post work call center crews getting wasted.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice, genuine old mans bar. Pretty relaxing, but can get pretty busy at the weekends with the old boys taking their missus out for a weekend sherry.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Good wee pub that does some great food at pretty reasonable prices.

Special deals during the week for the lunchtime muncher who fancies something a bit different.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Decent bar - if a bit poseurish at the weekends. Great selection of asian-fusion food that often makes it difficult to choose which of the awesome sounding dishes to choose from.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Usual Wetherspoons fare. Bland cheap food and bland cheap drinks served in a bland atmosphere.

Bland.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
A horrible, horrible club frequented by neds, kids, hen nights, stag do&apos;s and the call center crowd. Terrible music, terrible drinks, and an altogether terrible night out.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Decent wee bar for a spot of lunch during the week. Excellent selection of food - the chilli, in particular is fastastic. Can get a bit rammed at the weekend but an altogether decent place.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Horrible place. From the garish american theme to the terrible food. Steer clear.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Great addition to the Argyle St boozer scene. They serve a great selection of food - with the catch of the day fish special always being an excellent choice.

Comfy bar, with a nice, chilled atmosphere make this a great place to drink any day of the week.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
The Two Ways is now gone.

Famous for being the bar in Rab C Nesbitt, few souls dared enter the huge wooden doors is fear of being accosted by the man himself.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Friendly, scottish bar. Always a great atmosphere and part of the Argyle St teuchter triangle.

Good quality, hearty home made cooking for a spot of dinner or lunch and decent pints on tap.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Weird one Gazelle.. always seems to be changing or trying something new. Food can go from amazing to bland and bak within a few months.

Similarly the beer quality can very aswell.

Great if you get it on a good day.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Any time i go in here and ask for a chip buttie they&apos;ve never got any rolls and I just have to get chips.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Standard low-rent late night kebab house.

Nothing spectacular but nothing too terrible.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Much the same as any other KFC.

Awesome. I&apos;ll take a Zinger Tower Meal with beans and corn on the side.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Worst KFC in Glasgow. I don&apos;t know if its the proximity to the bus stop that does it but inside the place is always manky and the clientele tend to be mainly comprised of Glasgow&apos;s worst.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic after a night out in town or at the Strathclyde Student Union. The Sar Beni&apos;s are amazing. A giant nan, filled with wonderous kebab, sauce and salad.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
A poor mans KFC. Substandard chicken. Soggy chips. Bland food.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 28/08/2009 Report this place 
If you enjoy spending time with the down and outs of the town then this really is the place for you to visit! Looks like a funeral parlour from the outside and smells like a cludgie on the inside, mmmmmm
 1 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Good luck trying to find it!! The TIC is tucked away next door to a couple of fast food places and close to the Ramada Jarvis hotel at City Mills
 1 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Give them a very wide berth, bunch of real cowboys who will stitch you up rotten. Owner has appeared in court a few times
 1 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
This is a carbuncle and should be demolished and the area made into a plaza to show off St John&apos;s Kirk to it&apos;s best. The building is derelict and only used by pigeons so beware when passing, in case they are too!! Plans were to turn it into a shopping arcade but with so many shops shutting up in Perth it would not work. Wrangling by the Perth&amp;Kinross;Councillors has meant that we are stuck with this eyesore until someone makes a decision on what to do.
 1 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Used to be a very busy pub but easy to get a seat there nowadays. One of the few pubs with an island bar although the back of it is now sealed off so you can only buy drinks from three sides. Unusual collection of figurines playing musical instruments and one of the few places left with a golliwog on display! Drink here is not expensive and there are plenty of comfy seats, shows football on the televisions and puggies out the back.
 4 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Not sure if this is the current name or not, it changes more often than some change their underwear! Reasonable pub but nothing to write home about, you&apos;d probably need to be lost to find your way here.....
 2 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Recently refurbished and re-opened as a St Johnstone supporters pub where you can watch their live matches on the two televisions or hear commentary over the radio. Friday night has a quiz and happy hour.

One of the smaller pubs in town with three snugs along one wall with tables and chairs or benches in them. Very friendly pub and Mark the bar manager is always on hand to help you choose what you want be it a pint of tennents or a cocktail.
 5 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Used to be Scaramouche (see seperate entry) but recently done up and taken over by the owenr of That Bar and Teh Loft (see seperate entries) and has become a &apos;feeder pub&apos; for these two. Does basic bar food and trying to cater for a mixed age group but ultimately aimed at late teens!!
 2 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Rough and ready pub that serves the Friarton folk one of the pubs you should experience once in your life but don&apos;t stay too long....
 1 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Ideally placed for visiting St Johnstone FC just across the road. Large main bar which is often used for functions and also home to the 208/Jeanfield Supporters Club for nearby Saints. Good toasties and chips here as well as a decently priced bar tariff. Back bar has pool table, puggies and television and small outdoor area full of smokers
 4 kevtheref 28/08/2009 Report this place 
Great tasting juices and smoothies. Great variety of flavours.

A little expensive but worth while every now and then.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 30/08/2009 Report this place 
Great chippie. Does a cracking fish supper. Always generous with the portions.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 30/08/2009 Report this place 
Excellent chippie. Definately one of the best in the area.

Great quality food thats not too greasy and really tasty.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 30/08/2009 Report this place 
Quaint little cinema, nothing spectacular but does the job.
 3 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This course is situated in Dalmally which is about 30 miles south of Oban. The course is OK, not is the best of conditions especially in the winter when its waterlogged the majority of the time. Take some midge repellant with you.
 3 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A cool looking wee pub, that stays open late. The room is square, with a square bar making you within touching distance of getting a drink whereever you are.
 5 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Top boozer with craking views across Oban bay. Gets busy at the weekends.
 5 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Rumor has it that Aulays was once awarded a prize for the best pint of tennants. Not sure if thats true, but its a nice wee pub all the same.
 5 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Get you petrol here, it could be a while until you get any more.
 3 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
If I could eat here every night, I would do (and to be honest, that&apos;s not far from the truth). Perth&apos;s finest Chinese takeaway and a very good chip shop as well, Pete and the guys produce some fantastic food nice and quick. They also do outside catering!
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Firm favourtite for mussels and fries on Rose Street. Booths are great for keeping younger kids under close control - friendly laid back service.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A very convenient stop-off from the bus and train stations, and one I stop off at far too often for my weight&apos;s sake.

Happy Valley is open til shutting time for most of the pubs in town and sells the finest late-night grub; not to mention a great line in Cantonese traditional food.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Possibly the latest-opening chip shop in town and that&apos;s a godsend after a long night out :-) The food is quick but some of the customers leave a lot to be desired!
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Two traysh of double schips and scheese, my man... yer ma besht pal! Oh and a kebab with plenty onionsh and lots of spishy sausche....
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
One of the last surviving local bakeries after McIntyres and Montgomery&apos;s disappeared. Their rolls are fantastic but the pies are a wee bit too much like &quot;mince in a crust&quot; for my liking - too much meat and not enough elbow grease (you know, when the grease runs down to your elbow eating it...)
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Simply the best bakery in the world. Murrays Pies are legendary in Perth and a staple diet of half the town for as long as I can remember.

The pies are absolutely running with grease, as a good pie should do, and you never wait for more than about 30 seconds before being served.

They also do a good takeaway &quot;pie and beans&quot; service which is highly recommended.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Ewen runs the barber shop formerly operated by his dad George, and the family business continues to be in safe hands, so to speak.

A proper old-fashioned barber shop complete with the usual banter around the room when there&apos;s a queue formed on Saturday mornings. Also open at 6am each day to cater for tradesmen and farmers (and very good if you forget to get a haircut before going away somewhere!)

Happy customer of 30 years.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The Thai claims not to be a fast food restaurant, they say they produce &apos;good food as quickly as they can&apos;. That&apos;s certainly true of the takeaway option, and the grub itself is absolutely fantastic.

Very reasonable for a meal, and with a good selection of Thai curries and other dishes, highly recommended.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A great selection of traditional Indian fayre and unlike many of these buffet places, it&apos;s piping hot (as well as curry hot!)

Very enjoyable and if you get there early in the evening, it&apos;s a quid cheaper :-)
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Very good Indian restaurant, the best in the town. Dined here several times and also sampled the takeaway, and never been disappointed. They do a fine buffet selection and a great quick business lunch, but the best feature is the wide selection of curries and other dishes available - with the quality and size of the portions second to none in Perth.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
In a location where many businesses have tried and failed over the years, this Mexican has survived (despite a couple of name changes) through its quality of grub and its dedicated followers.

The food really is excellent and you&apos;ll certainly not go hungry.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Went through a dodgy phase a few years back with loud progressive rock, puddles of stale beer on/behind the counter and disinterested staff but appears to have got act together again. New Manager? Good Deuchars and selection of beer and lager.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Hard to fault. Great selection of real beer well cared for - right at the east end of Princes Street tucked in next to Sainsbury&apos;s and behind Jenners.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Very quick turnaround from measurement to fitting, and the quality is very good. Decent prices and they always seem to have offers on the go.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A family business going back many years, and a very good satellite / ariel installer. You should support your local Sky installer rather than going through the in-house Sky service, since you can count on them arriving on time; you know they&apos;ll do a good job; and they&apos;re just down the road if you need any follow-up work or extras.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The Grill Room is comfortable good quality and seems to be used primarily as a business venue - no complaints - just not inspirational. The main bar is high impact with huge &quot;dome&quot; - former bank I&apos;d guess - populated by business people of a certain age.
 3 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Cracking wee golf course which jumps between a true links and parkland course. The opening 8 holes are exposed to the sea and the gusting winds that come with it, then a small walk down the hill towards the 9th tee reveals a much tamer and unexposed setting. This is a good course and not too pricey to play.
 4 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A rare bag of chips, worth a visit.
 4 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Good healthy / hearty vegetarian food served in no frills canteen style basement - amazing range of salads. Not sure it is &quot;retro style decor&quot; - probably original as it has been around for years.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The town&apos;s finest provider of &quot;Lock and Lock&quot; containers, &quot;tupperware&quot; and similar items. They also sell some excellent bread-making kits which save you having to get your elbows dirty with dough!
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The official St Johnstone Supporters Club, on the site of the former Tay Motel. A great place to start before heading to away games (to which the club sends buses each week, at very reasonable rates for members) and as you&apos;d expect, it&apos;s a den of Saints memorabilia.

It&apos;s not in the best place in town for a quick pint of an evening, but once you get there on a Saturday they run buses up to McDiarmid which is not a bad thing, to be honest - especially given the keen prices at the bar!
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Clothes for students really, innit. Does have some nice hoodies and stuff but generally it&apos;s well overpriced.

Mad fer it.
 3 bambam 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Snooker halls are a rare attraction in Perth these days after the glory years of Park Ave, James Street and the Filling Station&apos;s upstairs den.

New Yorker is more of a pool hall although it does boast some great private snooker rooms with plenty room to get around. It&apos;s sadly filled with some nefarious individuals on the pool tables at times, but if you can get in on a quiet night, the tables are in good nick and the bar&apos;s not bad either.

Chips and cheese too!
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
MacSorleys has been taken over by the same mob who run the Sub Club. It&apos;s now a pre-club haunt for the Arches and Subby crews. Expect to find young upstarts through to retiring pint types.

They do decent food - all of it locally sourced I think - at reasonable prices.
 3 bambam 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Used to spend my Saturday mornings here years ago but haven&apos;t been in since I was 18. The burgers were legendary and although a couple of the tables looked more like a putting green at times, it was a great place to spend your weekends.

Sadly don&apos;t feel able to comment that much further nowadays :-)
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The best thing about this boozer is the fact you can phone ahead and book a booth to watch the footy on yer own private tv.

They serve the beers, wines and spirits you would expect to find in any boozer. The staff are chilled out and the food is supposed to be decent although I haven&apos;t tried it myself.
 3 bambam 31/08/2009 Report this place 
King James VI is a superb golf course, the only of its type in the country as it&apos;s situated on a self-contained river island.

A moderately challenging course with the occasional surprise in store, the Jimmy is enough to give both the beginner and the hardy hacker a good day&apos;s golf.

The clubhouse boasts a friendly atmosphere, with particularly good banter on a Saturday afternoon as the weekend regulars wait on their football coupons! The bar serves some excellent snacks and full meals, a great way to spend a day out. The club also boasts a good pro and a well-stocked shop.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
For the coffee addict, Nero is a well established chain (famed for always putting two shots in even their smallest coffee cups!).

Fast service and a good location - can&apos;t really do a lot better than that. Just wish they&apos;d sell the large &quot;Venti&quot; size available at Starbucks!
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The guy from stars in there eyes who won performing as Freddy Mercury was discovered here. Its a karaoke kingdom and you can get some cheep food too.
 4 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
With the feel of an old fashioned tearoom (and let&apos;s be honest, the clientelle often reflects that!) - Willows is a traditional restaurant for lunches, snacks and coffees.

Family run and long established, it&apos;s a good place to stop whether you just want a bacon roll or a full lunch off the specials board. As part of the St John&apos;s Square pavement cafe trend, they also offer seats outdoors all summer, when weather permits.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Scottish rivals to the mammoth Greggs empire and well worth your support. Their prices for morning rolls have delighted pensioners all over the country, and their bakery grub is as good as it gets for a chain store.

Given they have Greggs and another local rival for company in the same street, they do a good trade and although they&apos;re not Murrays, they are always worth a visit. The smell will get you as you walk down the High St.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I have to say, I find Domino&apos;s pizza with its horrible powder-laden dough, to be fairly repugnant. The fact they do a quick local delivery service doesn&apos;t make me want to eat from there.
 1 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
My local Indian takeaway and also a great pizza shop as well. Quick service and decent prices, as well as providing mammoth portions.

Try and munch your way through their 18&quot; kebab calzone pizza though, you&apos;ll have a hard job!
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I didn&apos;t know there was an &apos;old&apos; Wing Sing but to be honest it can&apos;t be any better than this. As a frequenter of single-fish purveyors, the Wing Sing does a great bag of chips and can take credit for their pickled eggs.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Perth&apos;s best professional football club. Can&apos;t say fairer than that.

Very good for lunch, dinner, functions and outdoor football on the astroturf. The matchday hospitality is fantastic as well.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Not sure why this is included in &apos;comedy clubs&apos; because it&apos;s a serious place filled with serious boozers (and that&apos;s a compliment, I&apos;ve tried and failed to keep up with them!)

Good prices, good location on the way to the football and if you can persuade a friendly member to escort you in, you&apos;ll have a fine time.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Stumbled across La Lanterna one Friday night when otherwise failing miserably to find a table anywehere in the George Street area. Great find with good seafood (which we stuck to) and ususal Italian staples. Made very welcome by the staff - the matriarch made sure all was in hand and the younger staff were also great.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Another converted bank in George Street - very well put together, spacious and comfortable. Perfect spot for lunch or to drop in for a coffee in the front bar area.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Knew it well when it was a cracking 9-hole course and spent many a long summer day there as a school boy. Mornings playing golf, lunch then couple of hours hunting for balls along the known hazards.

Now 18-hole and good course. Holes that stand out for me are from the original 9-holes:

#3 - blind par 3

#7 - par 3, down steep hill over the burn, looks easy and could probably throw it onto the green, but easy to over/under hit.

#18 - long par 5 into the clubhouse, hitting long is not always the best approach.
 3 CaseyJones 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Good takeaway, never had a meal from there that I&apos;ve been dissapointed with. Particuarly enjoy the lamb tika masala.
 4 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Decent bar with a nice view over the ice rink however I wasn&apos;t impressed with the food. I had chicken fajitas, which was more like hot slop on a plate.
 2 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Very good cooked breakfast, perfect for soaking up alcohol from the night before. They also have a good lunchtime offers for pizza and pasta. Always busy and a good standard of food at reasonable prices.
 4 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Great atmosphere and always busy before theatre opening times. Always a birthday happening with the waiters doing their rendition of &apos;happy birthday&apos;. Pizzas are favourite but menu is extensive and varied.
 3 CaseyJones 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Whether you have booked or not (best to book) this place is always heaving. Especially during rugby international weekends. Wide ranging menu plus open to the small hours for a late night supper.

One bad note - have had a couple of experiences when bill had items on them that we didn&apos;t order. So check before paying.
 3 CaseyJones 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Wow - pizzas are amazing. Had to take a doggy bag home as couldn&apos;t finish it. So take note, as might just want to share one with two if there for light meal.

Pizza toppings are varied and you get a real taste of italian cooking. You will need to book, but well worth it. Bit of pain with roadworks on Leith Walk right now, but don&apos;t let that put you off. They deliver as well.
 4 CaseyJones 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Before and after a rugby international this is a definite watering hole to stop at. They put on a bear tent in the hotel car park and you only get a choice of guiness, wine or lager - but if you&apos;re looking for a malibu and appletise then you&apos;re in the wrong place.

Wrap up well if you plan to stand in the open air after the match. But good place to stop for a couple while the murrayfield crowd make their way into the city centre, then hop on a bus yourself. Very civilised.
 3 CaseyJones 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Went to the No.5 for dinner on a busy Saturday night. The food was tasty, service was great and the cabaret was very entertaining.
 5 Southsider 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I love this place, everytime I&apos;m passing I have to indulge. Their ice cream is yum!!
 5 Southsider 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Great hairdressers with friendly staff.
 4 Southsider 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The Rod&amp;Reel is a great place for a reasonably priced meal and drink after a hard day up the hills.
 4 Southsider 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This pub has a wide selection of beers on tap, plays up to date independent music and serves very tasty food.
 5 Southsider 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A great place to be on a friday night after a hard week at work. It can be very busy and always plays great music.
 5 Southsider 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Generally an old mans pub. Good atmosphere and the locals are nice too. Also very good for a lunch time meal, with very reasonable prices.
 5 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Time stands still in this gem of a pub. Without doubt one of Glasgow&apos;s finest.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Lively pub with good food during the day. More of a young persons haunt at the weekends.
 4 Charlie 31/08/2009 Report this place 
As much as they like you to think that their goods are genuine one-offs and original pieces, most of it is just tat thats been bought in bulk from a wholesaler and can be found for half the price on the web.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I was finally dragged here for a night out by one of my friends who could not understand why I&apos;d never ventured inside in the past 4 years since turning legal...well I&apos;d never ventured in for a reason...it had reputation for being dead and who wants to dance about like a loon when the place is empty and everyone watching?!

So after one visit my opinion...its OK if you&apos;re desperate for a night out...

It was £5 entry...fairly empty...complete mixture of ages...typically about £3 per drink...I mean its the credit crunch...you might get more of a crowd if you lower prices!!
 2 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Stylish Mal in the heart of the city. Rooms are well appointed and the restaurant offers good local cuisine with a well stocked wine cellar.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Sugar and Spice...and all things nice!! Great little tourist shop full of different souvenirs...also good for stocking fillers at Christmas ;-) Can be a bit pricey for some things.
 4 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
They do a lovely hot chocolate on a cold winters day! Nice relaxed atmosphere...was very quiet last time I was in - only one other table.
 5 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
They do a lovely hot chocolate on a cold winters day! Nice relaxed atmosphere...was very quiet last time I was in - only one other table.
 5 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Great location just beside the Squinty Bridge and opposite the STV studios. Rooms are small but well designed. Make sure you ask for a river view.
 4 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A great pub, like most of the establishments in the West Port. Spent many an evening flitting between here and the Globe, talking about football with slack-jawed local yokels.

Good selection of drink, good music - just watch out for pesky students.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice accompaniment to the Ascot over the road. A deceptively big pub with a regular following and a good mix of decent beers and live music.

Watch out for pesky students though.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
You&apos;re right it&apos;s a comedy club!
 1 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Clothes are lovely, but pricey. More suited to people in the 30+ age range. Always worth a wander in though as you never know what you might find....mince pies and wine on Yule Tide night ;-)
 5 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Still one of the best hotels in Glasgow. Each room is individually styled and the hotel connects a number of terraced townhouses in the stylish West End. Excellent restaurant. One Devonshire is excellent but you pay it.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice for a wee spot of city centre drinking. Salubrious surroundings and a sense of befuddled grandeur. The food is definitely at the bar grub level.
 1 topspin 31/08/2009 Report this place 
With a McDonalds you would think you know what you are getting... Cheap burgers, cold fries and watered down soft drinks. And this place would be no exception. The drive through is laughable, with slow (and often rude) service. If you do decide to go inside, then expect long queues, screaming children and as many trackies as you can tolerate... I recommend avoiding McDonalds at the best of times, but this one especially.
 1 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Tom Brock fitted our wood burning stove a few years back and was an absolute star. We had built our own hearth and he was flexible enough to take on the installation of the flue/liner, chimney pot and actual stove. Also matched the best price I could find for the stove - a Morso. Has come back to maintain the stove since and sweep the chimney and has been great. Has also stepped into to rescue a neighbour from a dodgy installation by another aupplier.
 5 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The Pancake Place seems to have been around for donkey&apos;s years! It doesn&apos;t just sell pancakes, they&apos;ve been known to do a mean burger and a nice plate of macaroni.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Nice wee corner to sup a pint in. Great patter on sports occasions, and a typically dour barman/ owner to marvel at.
 1 topspin 31/08/2009 Report this place 
One of the best and friendliest restaurants I&apos;ve ever been to. Buongiorno has long been a nice family-run authentic Italian with some superb specials and a good atmosphere, day or night.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This cinema is pretty well located inside the main shopping centre. It has plenty of (pay and display) parking, however you don&apos;t need to buy a ticket after 7PM which is a nice incentive. The cinema is usually fairly busy, especially at weekends, and there tends to be a lot of mall rat types loitering about after dark. It is fairly expensive, but you can save a fair bit y visiting sainsburys in the shopping centre before going to the cinema for your food.
 3 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Some excellent pizza but a strangely varied menu (as the blurb says above) would serve to confuse. The curries are all right but stick to the pizza and puddings and you won&apos;t go far wrong.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Bit of a misnomer but a decent pub, especially when it&apos;s busier. If it&apos;s empty it&apos;s pretty desperate. If it&apos;s full it&apos;s great. It&apos;s not full often.
 3 topspin 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The Counting House is your bog standard Wetherspoons chain pub. I&apos;ve had good days and bad in there, but more of the latter.

Wipe your feet on the way out.
 2 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Superb old fashioned pub with a foodie bent. They do nice plain meals for lunch and afternoon tea, and there&apos;s a convivial atmosphere around the place all day long.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
It has the benefit of late night opening and there is an excellent contemporary bar upstairs. Well worth a visit. Friendly service and excellent Scottish food.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Another great pub in the West Port, where you could just about spend a whole night without travelling much more than 100 yards. The Westport was home to some pretty dodgy gigs down the years, including an ill-fated show by The Fall a few years ago, but nonetheless it&apos;s a nice place to spend an evening.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Bit of a student haunt, being right next to Dundee Uni&apos;s back door. Good pub though, and despite the presence of pesky students it&apos;s a good place for a work night out or a quiet-ish drink and a seat.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I remember when this was Tally&apos;s Russian Vodka Bar back in the day - one sorry episode led to me drinking a litre of blue vodka and waking up with blue clothing and pillows the next day.

Changed very little since then, good at the weekend and gets a bit busy.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
As newspaper shops go, the High Street RS McColl is second to none.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The mall is larger than you would expect and incorporates an Odeon cinema, Sainsburys supermarket, large food court, plenty of shops for a variety of items, including clothing, gadgets, mobile phones and shoes. There is also a fairly large ice rink, and at least two bars within the mall. Overall, Princes is a pleasant place to visit and shop, eat or just hang out.
 4 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I stayed here once after &quot;oversleeping&quot; on a late train and ending up in Dundee. The room wasn&apos;t that dear in the grand scheme of things but I can&apos;t really comment on breakfast as I just couldn&apos;t face it.

Also been here for a conference and for a visit to the cinema and it&apos;s been top notch.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Fairly decent size with good variety. Not bad for a chemists.
 4 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Great butcher in Portobello - natural meat company with free range chickens, pork and beef. Wide variety of sausages and award winning haggis, black pudding etc. Also a great deli next door. Can be pricey but this is a different planet from supermarket.
 5 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This really is a gem of a pub. Friendly timeless service. It has won a host of real ale awards but also stocks a wide selection of spirits from round the world. You won&apos;t be disappointed. One of a kind in Ayrshire.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This is a really nice bar, slightly hidden away downstairs in Miller Street. I first found it about a year ago and I go quite regularly. There&apos;s a nice selection of Italian food on offer at really good prices, and a large selection of bar snacks too if you just want something small to eat. Drinks are reasonably priced as well.

Cocktails are a bit more expensive, but that&apos;s to be expected (and at around £5 much cheaper than some places charge). They are properly made by staff who have obviously been trained in cocktail blending, and there&apos;s a good range of different ones to try.

Soho is fairly casual which is one of the things I like about it - it&apos;s smart, but you don&apos;t have to get really dressed up to go.

It&apos;s got quite a chilled out atmosphere, so it&apos;s good for after-work drinks or a nice low key meal, either with friends or your partner. I wouldn&apos;t feel out of place stopping by after a day of shopping either.

I&apos;d recommend it!
 1 Gillian Harvey 31/08/2009 Report this place 
On the sea front - ask for a window seat if you can, especially if it is a sunny day! Food is always good - have never been let down! Very friendly service and reasonably priced food.

:)
 5 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A great restaurant and bar with a very large garden. Superb for children. Food is local and great value for money. Highly recommended.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Went here the other night for dinner. Had booked a table for two in the conservatory the night before, but when I turned up the waiter said the booking hadn&apos;t been taken and instead we&apos;d need to sit in the back restaurant. We&apos;d specifically asked for the conservatory since it has more atmosphere and nice views, so we wanted a table there or not at all. The waiter was actually really quite rude and unhelpful, and acted as if we were in the wrong - not what you expect when you&apos;ve booked in advance!

Things got much better after that though. This hotel has a lovely restaurant/bar which does a really nice selection of food. It&apos;s not the cheapest place around for a meal, but the food is of a very high standard and you get good sized portions. The cosy surroundings (Battlefield/Shawlands) add to its charm - it&apos;s nice to find a place like this that&apos;s not in town.

There are also regular events put on in the bar - there was a folk night the evening we went and they also do jazz and folk nights.

I&apos;d go back - but expect better customer service next time!
 1 Gillian Harvey 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Meant to rate as four stars, not one!
 4 Gillian Harvey 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Not quite Kilmarnock but 2/3 miles outside. Good pub that does good food in the village of Symington.
 4 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s another Wetherspoons type place with all that they carry. You can expect drink offers, lots of people going out for 2 pints of vodka and Red Bull before they go on somewhere else.

The dodgy spelling of Capitol is meant to make it sound cosmopolitan, which in Dundee is something of an achievement.
 1 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Stumbled in here wearing the wrong football shirt once (let&apos;s not muddy the water by mentioning the club involved) but was met with a terrific welcome. Had a couple of pints with the locals and headed off with no bother at all.

Nice and near to the bus station if you fancy a pint in transit.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I used to stop in here on the way to work, to buy oranges for our office juice extractor. And as a supplier of cheap oranges, Weetabix and weekly offers on DIY equipment in the west end of Dundee, they don&apos;t come much better.
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Love it!!! Classy&amp;elegant! Food is delicious! We sat eating infront of a huge open fireplace - just what you need on a freezing cold day!!

Lounge is also good for a classy night out - they have a vast array of beers, spirits, wines and cocktails - something for everyone!!
 5 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s Starbucks - where can you go wrong! And what a Starbucks it is... within the shopping centre but full of the usual Starbucks goodness, including my favourite massive Venti takeaway cups.
 5 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This place is an utter treasure trove. If you&apos;re in Dundee - or more likely passing through on the bus, why not drop by and see some of the thousands of items on show. A genuine old fashioned &quot;hardware store&quot; where you&apos;ll find everything from sellotape to stepladders.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This is a fairly welcoming place. Not bad on a Saturday night, however there tends to be a fairly tight knit community of locals in the bar. Drinks are fairly cheap and the karaoke tends to be hit of miss. Not a bad venue to frequent pre-clubbing at the weekends.
 3 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Good food and friendly service, centrally located Indian restaurant...can&apos;t really fault it!
 5 hcan87 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The location of this pub is across from the main building of the Glasgow Metropolitan college, so this is an ideal student pub.

Cheap drinks, pool, cheap food and (loud) music.

NUS card friendly.

If you look young (I do and I&apos;m 28!) then make sure you have ID or you simply will NOT get served.

A good fun pub for the student comunity!
 4 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This is an interesting venue. When you enter, you can be mistaken for believing you have walked into a tree house. With lots of wood and natural esscence in the interior design, I&apos;d suggest that even Harry Potter would feel comfortable in this place.

Drinks are not bad, and the atmosphere is calm and relaxed, considering the city centre location.
 4 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Standard fare for one of these retail park based chain pub / restaurants.

Decent scran but nothing too special.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Located right on Buchanan St, it&apos;s pretty handy for a cheeky pint if the missus is dragging you round the shops and you need a breather.

Beer is nothing special but does the job.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Previously known as Strawberry fields, Ivory Blacks is a fairly well located club (5 minutes walk from Central station, taxi ranks and a main bus line or three).

To be honest, this is not the nicest of venues in Glasgow.

There is often an element of chav-esness, despite the fairly strict dress code, and as such this is more a club for young adults out on the pull. A &quot;meat market&quot; if you will.

There is usually fairly tight security, and trouble makers you will be quickly ejected from the place (and usually given a good kicking for their troubles).

With a kebab / chippy next door, the suggestion would be to leave at least half an hour before the 4am closing, grab a kebab and get a taxi home before the masses leave.
 2 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Usually packed with students.

Alright for the football tho.. beer is fairly cheap and there&apos;s plenty of tellies and couches.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Bizarre ramshackle of an interior but a decent pint in a fairly relaxed atmosphere.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Long gone.. but at one point did the best burgers in all of Glasgow.

Now replaced by the Pig and Butterfly which pales in comparison.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 31/08/2009 Report this place 
My favourite puggy merchant in Dundee, home of a mis-spent youth. I have fond memories of playing the Afterburner flight sim machine which was one of the few on this side of the country, and £1 a go in the days of playing Streetfighter for 10p!
 3 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
The good old Savoy (known affectionately as &quot;The Sav&quot;) is located within the Savoy shopping centre on Sauchiehall Street.

It is a rather larger place than you might expect, considering the size of the shopping centre.

The Sav is a good laugh, and is a fun club to go to during the week.

Drinks are very expensive, so if you simply must get drunk, have a few before you go to The Savoy, and save your energy for dancing.
 3 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This no longer exists under this name. See Ivory Blacks.
 1 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
+ Well located within the centre of Glasgow.

+ The service is not bad overall.

* The quality is fair, nothing above average.

- The staff seem to change on a weekly basis.

- Can be quite busy.

- Can be an expensive place to eat.
 3 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This is an invaluable shop for people who work at places like Argyll House and the nearby former warehouse offices.

Handy supplier of crisps, juice, milk and sandwiches and saves you walking into town unnecessarily.
 4 Bob Flaps 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A fairly busy local takeaway. It serves a good variety of food (such as pizzas chicken, kebabs, fish and chips etc), and delivery is fairly quick.

Really good on price, and the quality of food is not bad either.

There is also a sit-in part as well, if you want to use this, however being in Govanhill, it is not the best of areas to sit in and have a meal, so I would only recommend using it as a take away.
 3 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
This is my local chinese takeaway, and I use it on a weekly basis, and would recommend it if you are local.

This is surprisingly good chinese takeaway.

The portions are good for the money, and the delivery is fairly quick.

The staff are friendly enough when they answer the telephone, or you visit the shop.
 4 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Not a bad takeaway at all. The variety is fairly well cvered, and offer a good choice of curry, pizza, chips, burgers, baked potato meals or kebabs.

The staff are fairly friendly and the banter is usually pretty good.

The food is cooked on ordering, and the service is pretty quick too.
 3 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I love Ikea! It rocks!

The store is fun with a capital FUN!

Cheap furniture, hotdogs for 90p with lots of mustard and ketchup, free drinks refills and the chance to steal those mini pencils...

I&apos;ve bought so much stuff from Ikea my flat is starting to look like one of the displays. Only not as tidy...

Volvo&apos;s, Abba and Ikea... Sweden is just great at everything it does!!
 5 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Next Home offers a good variety of furniture, decorations and accessories for the home, however it is quite expensive.

The staff mostly seem to be pre-occupied and quite unhelpful when you ask for assistance.

If you wish to be a snob, then go here. If you want to have fun whilst shopping, visit Ikea.
 2 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
I really enjoy the transport museum, and eagerly await visiting it once the location changes.

Lots of history and fun things to do, including the 1930&apos;s street exhibition. Lots of displays you can get really close to (some allow you to get in them, such as the train exhibit) which is fun for children and adults alike.

Being free, you would think the car parking is expensive, but it really isn&apos;t! I was very surprised!
 4 TheLittlerich 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Fabulous country Inn on the best road to Skye - via the Glenelg to Kylerhea ferry. Great beer garden and good food.
 5 Shaba 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Quite simply the best smoked salmon you&apos;ve ever tasted. Everything is prepared by hand and smoked in the most traditional way. Once you&apos;ve tried this you&apos;ll be back for more. There is also a cafe where Donald and Veronica let you sample their produce. A must.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
A wonderful family run business serving the best selection of meat in Ayrshire. Try the British Saddleback pork, it&apos;s sensational. James and the team also offer a wide range of home made pies and other goodies
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Part of the Cosley group. A very ambitious thatched renovation in the heart of Kirkoswald. Always busy, excellent food and service.
 4 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Part of the Cosley Hotel Group. A great luxury hotel on the south side of Troon. First class experience all the way. The restaurant is excellent and the facilities are what you&apos;d expect from a top end hotel.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Buzzing modern bar/restaurant in the centre of Prestwick. Excellent food and great indoor/outdoor space. Really worth a visit.
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s been around for a time and Renaldos hasn&apos;t won the UK ice cream maker of the year award for nothing! The best.....
 5 Rob4955 31/08/2009 Report this place 
Quirky gifts ornaments and jewelery - great if you have someone&apos;s birthday coming up and you don&apos;t have a clue what to get them!! There is always something unusual to be found - I love just wandering in and having a look!
 4 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
I like the surroundings in here, gives the place a good atmosphere. Pints are usually of a high standard and its not too expensive.
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Great food in a nice surrounding at Ashton Lane. Pefect for something to eat before working you way round the bars of the west end. Food can be expensive, but worth it.
 5 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
The name says it all. DUMP.
 1 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Danger Danger, £4.50 a pint. Bring your wallet. Its a nice bar, but no pint should cost £4.50
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
I have enjoyed each time I have been here but I guess that really depends on the acts. The settings aren&apos;t the best and it gets really crammed especially at the intervals when its a mad dash for the toilet. Worth a visit though, and the local compere is very funny if you can understand her.
 4 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Its not just about the bowling at this bowling club. They reguarly show the football when its on and that&apos;s when I usually go there. Predomanently Rangers supporter go to this bar for the football and it can create a very good atmosphere. Friendly locals, and you need a member to sign you in.
 4 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
The ultimate old mans pub. The toilets stink but dont let that put you off, the locals are a great bunch and theres alwasy someone to talk too or get a game of pool with. Also good for watching the footy.
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
There are only two places to eat in Kippford and the Mariner is where sensible parents head. Its outdoor play area keeps under 10s entertained whilst mums and dads can supervise from a safe distance. Like other eateries in this region the healthy food revolution has passed the Mariner by. Expect a menu chock full of chips, deep fried fish, fries, burgers etc. Staff reasonably friendly but decor in desperate need of an overhaul. Great view of the Solway estuary from the garden/conservatory dining area - and you can sit and watch singletons and &apos;no kids&apos; couples making their way to the much more pleasant Anchor Hotel - a few yards down the street.
 1 Florence of Arabia 01/09/2009 Report this place 
They do one of the best take-away pizza&apos;s in Largs!
 4 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Its actually an OK sports complex for being in a small town! It has gym with fairly up to date equipment and a decent length swimming pool. £4.70 for the gym/ £4.30 for classes/ £2.70 for swimming. So fairly standard prices. I recommend the deep water aqua aerobics on a Monday night - its a good work out, its fun and you don&apos;t end up with aching muscles the next day (always a bonus)! There is also a soft play area for toddlers, a stage where various plays are held throughout the year and for the tourists you can go on the Viking Experience tour.
 4 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
I used to love going here when I was younger - you can have a nice cheap fun day out - from what I remember there are 4 pool tables and 6 or 8 snooker tables. Pool tables were only 50p per game. Drinks are fairly cheap, as are bar snacks.
 5 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
On a warm summer&apos;s evening there is no nicer place to sit in Scotland than outside of the Anchor Hotel. A picture postcard view and the subdued murmur of fellow eating companions can fool you into thinking you&apos;re actually holidaying abroad but then the food arrives and you wake up. Deep fried fish, mayo, chips &apos;n &apos; pizza gunk. Inside you might think about complaining. Outside you drink up the atmosphere and pray that Gordon Ramsay does a Kitchen Nightmares some time soon. Staff super friendly and good mix of foreigners, locals and uk holiday makers.
 2 Florence of Arabia 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Stunning inside! They frequently have weddings held here in the recently renovated conservatory.

Tables are nice and big and you are not too close to other diners which is good. I have eaten here twice. The first time I really enjoyed it, we sat through in the back of the restaurant, it was fairly busy but food still came quickly and was delicious!

The second time I went was a bit of a disappointment. This time I was at the front of the restaurant looking out on the beautiful sunset over the sea. The thing that annoyed me was that they advertised a special menu of 2 courses for £10, but there was no vegetarian option and when I asked would they mind if I swapped the burger option on the special menu with the vegetarian burger (which was the same price), I was made to feel like I was being a burden...not the best way to start off a meal. The next thing that annoyed me was there was only 8 tables in on a Friday night, 4 members of waiting/bar staff and it took 2 hours to be served our 2 courses.

Would I go back? Maybe - I would phone ahead first to find out what is on their menu.
 3 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
I quite like this place - its up a wee side street and you don&apos;t necessarily know its there which means it is a bit quieter than other coffee shops - good for when you&apos;re wanting a catch up with friends! Staff have always been pleasant and friendly when I&apos;ve been in.
 4 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Get on your bike, get the ferry over to Millport and cycle around Cumbrae!

Can be a bit pricey to travel though - if you are a foot passenger, it is £4.50 per person - bike is free. If you want to take the car over it is extortionate - £19.50 + price per passenger!
 3 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Bridge of Orchy Hotel is not five star but is in a fantastic location for the West Highland Way and offers comfortable good value accommodation and good quality food and very decent bar. Also has hostel style block for backpackers.
 4 Shaba 01/09/2009 Report this place 
YUM!

Ice cream, candy floss, sweeties - what more could anyone ask for on a hot summers day? (They also sell teas and coffees for the more common cold wintery days) There are two kiosks - one just as you come up off the ferry and the other one across the road from the Vikingar. Prices are fairly standard.
 5 hcan87 01/09/2009 Report this place 
The Dornoch Castle Hotel is in a great loction right in the centre of the town. Very comfortable and brilliant team who made us very welcome. The room we had was quite small but very comfortable and there is a very pleasant courtyard style garden off the dining / breakfast area.
 4 Shaba 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Good quality Mexican food - laid back atmosphere.
 4 GW 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Very good swimming pool and flumes - plus fitness suite.

Very good for kids, with flumes and pirate ship!
 4 GW 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Whoever your favourite band is, chances are they played one of their best ever gigs at the Barrowlands. Attending a Barrowlands gig should be a mandatory part of any application to use the word &apos;glaswegian&apos; to describe yourself.
 1 John Kilbride 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Best known as a club venue, but the Arches is a pretty under rated place if you ask me. Cafe bar is top notch, and it&apos;s a great place to see a live band or theatre. Don&apos;t expect it to be mainstream entertainment, it&apos;s mostly underground acts and shows - as you might expect from a venue that&apos;s literally underground.
 1 John Kilbride 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Adding to above - worth a visit at weekends, busy but not uncomfortable, good tunes and a relaxed and friendly vibe. Recommended.
 5 John Kilbride 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Bit of a characterless big shed, but it is the place you&apos;ll go and see your favourite arena-filling band. Not exactly the barrowlands in terms of atmosphere, but does better that it probably should does attract a decent number of acts that probably wouldnt otherwise play in Scotland.
 2 John Kilbride 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty decent food. Not too expensive.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Spacious pub, with good lager. Plenty of TV&apos;s for watching football and the pub grub is a decent standard.
 4 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Handy wee van that serves a good selection of different crepes - both sweet and savory.

The Radical Roast or the Terrific Turkey are my personal favourites.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Good selection of sandwiches and snacks. Little bit expensive but good quality food.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice wee place for a coffee. Good selection of food aswell. The selection of pizza&apos;s and the nachos go down very well and a are good bang for your buck.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice wee Japanese restaurant. Good selection of dishes.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 01/09/2009 Report this place 
This is not the place to go for a quiet drink. Its where you get every single tradesman or student in Glasgow on a Friday at 5. Not the most sophisticated of places, but fine if you are after a cheap pint in a central location.
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Average bar, grubs not up to much but the prices don&apos;t reflect it. A bit more cosy up the back.
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Good on Saturday afternoons when they get live bands in. Its usually full of older guys who have managed to ditch the wife and get away for a while. Watch out the the brass band they are really good.

Oh and a word of warning, the toilet doors can be misleading after a few drinks. So take care.
 4 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Good pub to start the night in, usually very busy on Friday and Saturday nights.
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Old mans pub. My father once played dominos with Ally McCoist and Ian Durrant in here.
 3 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Jump in here for a quick few beers before going to the game at Ibrox. Its always busy then but dont know about any other times. Decent enough bar, more of an old mans place.
 2 Charlie 01/09/2009 Report this place 
Auchrannie Spa Hotel is a very plush child friendly resort on the Islae of Arran. Also very handy for the ferry. Great base for exploring the Island and some excellent value deals.
 4 Shaba 02/09/2009 Report this place 
The Old Pier Tearoom is a bit of a Blast from the past - great cafe - a safe haven form the inveitable showers on Arran - steamed up windows in the rain etc.
 4 Shaba 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Roslin Glen Hotel is a comfortable country hotel - perfect for a well deserved rest after exploring the nearby Rosslyn Chapel, the castle and the glen.
 4 Shaba 02/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a really well stocked co. A good range of local newspapers and much thought given to the high number of holidaymakers passing through who need items like - torches, buckets and spades and sun lotions.
 1 Florence of Arabia 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Sitting in the front garden of the Lochranza Hotel overlooking the bay, sipping on a pint of Arran Ale and eating one of their fine lunches while enjoying the summer sunshine, watching the occasional deer stroll by...doesn&apos;t get much better than this.
 1 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Very good range of food and selection of real ales. Go for the Ploughman&apos;s lunch with Arran cheese washed down with a pint of Arran ale in the beer garden if you get the weather. Bar hosts live music and poker nights.
 5 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Accommodation in Kippford is at a premium during the holiday season but don&apos;t let desperation allow you to book the Rosemount&apos;s family annexe. It&apos;s situated in the garden and from the outside resembles a sturdy tree house. A double bed and kiddies bunk beds are squashed into a room the size of a small tent. Ok for one night maybe but any more and you&apos;ll develop cabin fever.
 1 Florence of Arabia 02/09/2009 Report this place 
An institution at the heart of the village. While it didnt do a wide range of food when we were there, toasties mostly, but it was comfortable and welcoming. Good range of whiskies and real ale. Bar has pool table, and has weekly tournaments and quiz night. Large beer garden outside with views over Firth of Clyde, enjoyed going here.
 5 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Full of to many &apos;wannabe&apos;s&apos; for my liking but the nacho&apos;s are top notch if you can pay an afternoon visit.
 1 Laura Boyd 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice wee shop, mostly ethnic/hippy/alternative clothes jewellery, nicknacks, gifts etc. Fair trade and good prices.
 5 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
ach, forgot to add stars to the review. No less than five.
 5 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
A Lanark institution. Good take away, pizza as well as fish and chip, Mr A&apos;s Cafe through the door. Can be busy at lunchtime.
 4 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
If you ask me, one of the best Chinese restaurants in Scotland. A wee bit pricier than your local place, but well worth the money. Thai and japenese items also on the menu. Does take away.
 5 John Kilbride 02/09/2009 Report this place 
great wee place to have a bite whilst looking out at a lovely beach!
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
maybe the best desserts on the island!!
 4 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Lethal cocktails can be found in the grapes!
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
amazing pizzas!
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Winner of UK Seafish Fish&amp;Chip Shop of the Year 2008/09, best fish supper around. What more can you say.

Don&apos;t go to the fancy restaurants in St Andrews, get down to this wonderful chippie and sample the delight of a classic - fish&amp;chips.
 4 CaseyJones 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Personally I think the fares are far too expensive, and there&apos;s always a problem with the gangway...however it&apos;s the only way to get on and off the island so I shouldn&apos;t really complain!
 1 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Down the High Street and off the beaten track this &apos;local&apos; chippie is great. Fish supper fantastic, easily on par with Anstruther Fish Bar.
 4 CaseyJones 02/09/2009 Report this place 
make a good cup of coffee! Plus the owners are lovely!
 4 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
if you like proper chunky, &apos;chippy&apos; chips this is where to go!
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
this place used to have the most delicious &apos;seasoning&apos;...wonder if they still have it?!
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
They set the standard for all butchers to be. Quality meat and specialising in haggis and sausages. It is quality so expect to pay on the higher side, but worth it. Great service and always queues coming up to Christmas.

Best buy - steak pie: but buy the extra gravy too
 4 CaseyJones 02/09/2009 Report this place 
The Arches has got to be near the top of my favorite places in Glasgow....food in the cafe bar is delicious, but mainly because I&apos;ve been able to dance the night away to the beats of some of the worlds superstar DJs, under the Arches roof....
 5 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Once you actually manage to find this place, it&apos;s worth the trek. Obviously not the glammest of places but it&apos;s not trying to be.
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
If I was off work every Monday then this is where you would find me every Sunday night....
 5 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Went in recently after 20 years and still the same - great beer (£2.50 for Deuchars) and friendly atmosphere. And even better the mutt is allowed.
 5 Shaba 02/09/2009 Report this place 
I dread to think how many times I ate in here after a Strathclyde Union night out.....in agreement with above re the Sar Beni&apos;s...
 3 KVF 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Cadenheads Whisky Shop has a wide selection of cask strength malt whisky and rum. Best value in Edinburgh. Also organise regular tastings in Canon&apos;s Gait pub along the street.
 5 Shaba 02/09/2009 Report this place 
live music is the order of the day in Hoots - with three floors filled with all kinds of bands every weekend, and entertainment throughout the week, there really is something for every musical taste, whether its local bands starting off, traditional musicians or big names - Hoots also boasts an authentic Thai chef and is known for its speciality cuisine.
 1 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
forgot to put a star rating!!
 4 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
under new management, the former Barbazza, on Young Street packs them in every weekend with dancefloor fillers and offers a variety of music throughout the week - also a great place for a lunchtime meal…
 2 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
you can barely swing a cat in here but its renowned for its live music, with many bands getting their first break in &apos;the Market&apos; - including a certain bespectacled brotherly duo from Auchtermuchty.....
 2 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
On the edge of Loch ness, newly re-vamped, its probably more renowned for its food than drink but a very pleasant place to sink a pint - not too many though or people won&apos;t believe you when you claim to spot Nessie!
 1 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
*
 3 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
3 stars for the coleslaw!!
 3 nicmac33 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Right in the heart of the shopping centre. Its good for a cheap bar meal and a pint.
 3 Charlie 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Council ran course so it usually pretty easy to get a game here (excluding weekends). The course is a decent parkland course, with a couple of reachable par 4s in 1 shot.
 4 Charlie 02/09/2009 Report this place 
Mmm Pizza. Typical Dominos, top pizzas and good delivery service especially if you order online.
 1 Charlie 02/09/2009 Report this place 
As a visitor to the city, I had a great night in this nightclub. Very small but music and punters alike were great!
 4 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
BEST butchers on the island. Steak Pies are second to none!
 5 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Pop into the Electric if you&apos;re passing - everything is delicious!
 4 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Lively pub - live music can be decent, can get ridiciously busy though!
 3 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Stumbled across this place one cold night, quite studenty but VERY cheap food and drinks!
 3 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I love Office Shoes, especially the really high heels. Would recommend this shop to anyone who loves heels.
 5 Loz 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I wouldn&apos;t go anywhere else for my fish&amp;chips.
 5 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great sandwich, fillings are a bit of a change from the normal and they even deliver.
 5 clare a bella 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Want to have a cuppa, some cake and chill out? I recommend here, if you walk far enough up the back of the shop theres additional seating where you get lost in a book etc
 4 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
AMAZING cupcakes!
 4 KVF 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Have been several times to the salon and the whole experience is very relaxing, with extra free treatments like scalp and hand massages. What&apos;s even better is when they have a 50% discount promotion. Great spa downstairs, everything a girl needs in one location.
 5 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Joyce does fantastic facials...you should try the Karin Herzog ones, they are amazing, especially the chocolate facial, yummy!

Only fault is the decor, salon could do with a makeover.
 4 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great quality meat. They also have a great range of slimming world food well worth a visit. There sometimes is a que but the staff are efficient and friendly and you don&apos;t have to wait that long.
 5 clare a bella 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is the very best hotel I&apos;ve stayed in (in the UK) and can never fault the service or food, nothing is too much trouble. Maybe a bit pricey but with their £29 meal deal for two, you won&apos;t get better value for money.
 5 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great restaurant the food is always fab never disappoints,the puff candy meringue with honeycomb icecream&amp;butterscotch sauce is to to die for well worth a visit.
 5 clare a bella 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Always worth a visit if you&apos;re looking for something a wee bit different.
 4 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Brilliant haircut from Dean the head stylist. Beautiful Salon albeit a little pricey but great when they have special offers!!
 4 colinda 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I wouldn&apos;t go anywhere else for a fabulous, quality handbag and their sales are the best ever.
 5 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Something for everyone here and definitely worth a visit, no matter what age you are.
 5 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Been here on a few occasions and never been disappointed, food superb, decor gorgeous and the service fab!
 4 colinda 03/09/2009 Report this place 
If you want a quick feed and great food, this place never fails to disappoint. Love their chicken tama rice.
 4 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A great, informal place to sit in or take away. The best pizza in the west end.
 4 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
If you want to be served quickly with fab Chinese cuisine and like service with a smile this is the place to go! Always left the building full and happy.
 4 colinda 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This place has now closed down, which is a shame.
 1 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Amazing deli&amp;cafe - normally you have to wait in the que but it&apos;s always worth the wait. Have never been disappointed with the food from here.
 5 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Very nice chinese restaurant with lovely decor.
 4 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The best pub in Falkirk, with different venues to suit all ages, including an ale house. Great restaurant and good for gigs. Go along and check out The Signals on Sat 7th November.
 1 NetGem25 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree with NetGem25 great salon, everything a girl needs the best facial I ever had.
 5 clare a bella 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic food, lovely surroundings Raymond and his staff are very friendly and attentive. I can&apos;t wait to go back.
 5 clare a bella 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I have also been here a few times and would agree that the food is superb, lovely decor and the staff are friendly and attentive.
 5 clare a bella 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is my favourite of the Nardini&apos;s chain - food is reasonably priced and delicious, staff are friendly and its a nice relaxed atmosphere inside. Its more of a cafe than a restaurant which means you don&apos;t feel underdressed if you turn up in jeans ;-)
 5 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I tend to go here on a Sunday for a nice warm hot chocolate. The staff are very friendly and accommodating - I&apos;ve been in as part of a large group before and they&apos;ve quite happily moved tables accommodate us. Drinks are fairly standard priced as you&apos;d expect to find in any coffee shop. Cakes are pretty yummy too!
 5 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Large selection of sweets, similar price as you would pay in any confectioners. Full of tourists in the summer getting their stick of Largs Rock.
 4 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Good for bread and milk emergencies if you can&apos;t be bothered trecking down to Morrisons, although are more expensive. They also have a good selection of plants and flowers.
 4 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Right on the seafront - perfect if you&apos;re starving and want a warm bag of chips on a cold day! They sell pizzas which are pretty yummy too. They also have special offers from time to time so keep your eyes peeled!
 4 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The food in here is delicious and reasonably priced - can&apos;t beat it!
 5 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Staff are friendly, keep your eyes peeled for bargains
 5 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Staff are polite. Keep your eyes peeled for offers on wine.
 5 hcan87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The place to be. Great music, great drinks prices and great indie boy talent if you&apos;re a girly. Look our for Franz Ferdinand and Glasvegas lurking in the corners. And just a stones throw from ABC - perfect!
 5 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Perfect place to discover the next big thing on the Glasgow music scene. With bands like Isosceles, Pooch and The Lava Experiments regulars at this dark and dingy cave, you can&apos;t go wrong with a night at Sleazys. Beware of the food though - it may be cheap but there&apos;s a reason for that
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Avoid like the plague. I was once chatted up here by a man who looked and sounded like a living leprechaun and the place now terrifies me. Supposed to be a great music venue but trust me, it&apos;s not, unless you like to hear 3 terrible Oasis tribute bands in a row.
 1 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The perfect place to get your frilly knickers for Glasgow&apos;s greatest night out - Club Noir. You may have to break the balance to shop here but it will be worth it... or so your boyfriend will tell you!
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Behind The Wall is a nice bar and restaurant which is always lively at the weekend. Different areas include a conservatory, beer garden and an area for live music upstairs. There&apos;s a restaurant which does a nice menu and this area&apos;s cleared in the evening to make way for a dancefloor. Good venue for a night out but drinks can be a bit pricey.
 4 GlasgowGirl 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Marvin you are so wrong. The crepes should be called crapes. They are gooey, stodgy and disgusting as are the shop bought stale croissants. Thumbs down from me.
 1 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great coffee and hot choc in massive mugs. Grab your friends and pretend your are in Central Perk - if you are that sad. But with bashed in comfy leather sofa&apos;s and the occassional skint student weilding an acoustic guitar, it&apos;s the closest your ever going to get to living like Ross and Rachel in Glasgow.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Expensive but worth it. Fantastic colour stylists who can transform your barnet from drab to &apos;daaaarrrrliiinng&apos; in just a few hours. Well worth a visit. Skint? Wander past the one on Great Wester Road and tell them you&apos;re willing to be a model. Free haircuts and colours if you&apos;re brave enough to let the stylists go wild.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
In a great central location but looks slightly scary from the outside. Don&apos;t be put off. The rooms are luxurious and modern and the bar is great for celeb spotting. May know someone who has partied with The Killers here... but that&apos;s another story. Also used in the filming of STV drama Missing, but don&apos;t worry Gregor Fisher will not be lurking in the corridors.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice bar with a good range of drinks, also a good place to get lunch.
 4 GlasgowGirl 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a great little cinema with loads of character. A fantastic festive experience is to go and see the original black and white film of &apos;It&apos;s a Wonderful Life&apos; that GFT screens in the run up to Christmas.
 5 GlasgowGirl 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This museum is good if it&apos;s raining outside and you&apos;re looking for somewhere to pass a couple of hours. Full of lots of interesting items - from historical to modern - there really is something for all ages. There&apos;s a nice little gift shop and cafe too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Lovely modern hotel with spacious rooms, a good restaurant and a lovely little bar. I agree with BCT babe - it&apos;s great for celeb spotting, a lot of them stay here if they&apos;re playing gigs at the SECC etc!

The main bar just off the reception is great for stopping for a coffee and watching the world go by.
 4 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Guys - once you get over the embarrasment of going into buy womens underwear, you will find this store is great.

You can get a good variety of underwear for your girlfriend / wife, at a good price.

Oh, and if you&apos;re in with your other half, then take the chance to try and persuade them to buy / let you buy the stuff you fantasise about seeing them in! Great stuff!

The prices are good, the staff are helpful, and they really amke a nice effort of wrapping up the items you buy nicely!
 5 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Really like this shop. It&apos;s over two floors so nice and spacious and a good mix of garments. They do most stuff from casual tops to business suits, as well as pretty dresses and skirts for nights out, nice shoes and accessories. Pricing is quite reasonable too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Like this bar. Wouldn&apos;t agree it&apos;s full of wannabes in all fairness though, it&apos;s chilled out and not a poser kind of place at all!

Nice food and drink, served till 3am. A nice place to go if you want to stay out late but don&apos;t fancy a club or really rowdy bar.
 3 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Pamper yourself when you are in Edinburgh at Claire&apos;s Beauty. Set in a gorgeous building it&apos;s the perfect place to relax and let the experts make you look your best.
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is pretty similar to the store in Argyle street, only larger.

The items are quite nice and are available at a good price. I can see why women love la senza, as the gifts are all wrapped up nicely, usually with scented balls to make the garments smell nice!

Oh, and you can go in here if you&apos;re a guy too! The don&apos;t just sell knickers and bras - I once bought a nice dressing gown for my mum from here! (please don&apos;t make any jokes about buysing stuff for my mum out of La Senza...!)

Check it out, especially if you are with your other half at the time!
 5 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Cheap, but hardly cheerful.

I am sure I saw a bloke wearing some of the stuff from here on Buchannan street once... He was selling the Big Issue.

It&apos;s a place to go if you are an... &quot;older person&quot; or someone who likes dressing up like they are from the 40&apos;s.

Shoes are minging and the price overall is a bit hefty!
 2 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Lovely cocktails in here - but take your credit card because they can be a bit pricey!

Having said that, Metropolitan deserves to charge a little more because it&apos;s a bar with a bit of class. You don&apos;t get a rowdy rough crowd in here - it&apos;s just a nice place to have a drink or dinner. There&apos;s a lovely section upstairs which you can book for a private party, and on some nights a pianist plays up there too, in the piano bar.

A good place to start off your night - and lovely for a first date!
 4 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Schuh is the place to shop for shoes. A Wag looking for Ugg&apos;s? A student looking for converse? Or someone had a baby and you want some mini Nike boots? Head to Schuh where you will find everything plus, if you are a student, youc an get 10% discount. Lovely!
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Not bad for choice or price...

Shame that the clothes in here are more intelligent than half of the staff.
 3 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Like this hairdressers. From the outside I wasn&apos;t sure, but they really know their stuff. I asked for a total transformation and they didn&apos;t disappoint.

Prices not bad for city centre too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Swanky and there is a word that rhymes with swanky I would prefer to use...

Its for posh toffs with waaaayyyy to much money and waaayyyy to little sense!
 1 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This restaurant used to be great about a year ago - lovely little restaurant snuggled away from the city centre. But it&apos;s gone downhill since then, quite considerably. I used to be a regular but I don&apos;t go any more.
 1 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I go horse riding and managed to get a cheap crop and horse brushes here the other week so both me and Pippa pony are a fan of this store. Ohhh and the cheap meat and strangely named German biscuits also make it a great option for weekly essentials.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I usually buy my shoes from here.

The choice is ok, and the price is good enough.

I wouldn&apos;t expect much help from the staff though.
 3 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice theatre, easy to get to as well, just off Sauchiehall Street.

Been to see a few productions here. The only thing I&apos;d say is the bar gets very crowded when shows are on - but really that&apos;s only to be expected.

Some good shows coming up soon - I&apos;ll definitely be going back.
 4 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Sorry, but Kerry Katona advertising prawn rings was enough to put anyone off this store, no matter how cheap it is. Maybe I will cheange my mind when Peter Andre starts advertising the mini frozen cheesecakes.
 1 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I wouldn&apos;t say &quot;Wide Range&quot; describes their stock... It is mostly overly fancy shoes at silly prices.
 2 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Avoid! This is ned city at the weekends. Food and drinks not a great quality either.
 1 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Is it just me or are there a lot of cheap food places in Dundee? Well bring it on, it&apos;s perfect for the student market. Costcutter is great for a bargain and handy for grabbing quick essentials when you don&apos;t need to do a big shop.
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I&apos;ve been here to see Within Temptation. Thought it was a pretty cool venue.

It was certainly large enough to get lost from my friends once the gig had started when I went to get some beers.
 1 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I love this restaurant. Really top quality Scottish food in nice, cosy surroundings. The other branch in Jordanhill is also lovely - slightly more intimate, and a nice place for couples.

It&apos;s fairly expensive, but nice for a special occasion, and there are regularly deals available for lunch and pre-theatres.

This is one of my favourite places to go for a meal in Glasgow.
 5 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Cute pub I have been dragged into by my Aberdeen supporting boyfriend. Almost makes going to see the Dons bearable. Cosy atmosphere and good hearty pub food. Like this one a lot, especially on a cold Aberdeen day.
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Bunker has actually had a refit recently and it&apos;s better than it was before. The interior, food and drinks have all been given a bit of a boost.

I like it because it&apos;s open till 3am and there&apos;s a little dancefloor, but also a section which is quite seperate from it - so it&apos;s like a bar and club in one.

Some of the bar staff aren&apos;t all that friendly and service can be quite slow, so there are poor points.

Overall though I think Bunker is worth a visit.
 3 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s ok, but more a conference centre than a place where large bands / singers ect should go. They are digging up all the car parks just now, so I&apos;d recommend you get a taxi there if you&apos;re seeing anyone perform.

Oh, and it&apos;s great around Christmas, when the Irn Bru carnival comes to the SECC!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
KVF and Marvin I feel your pain. TFI Friday then a kebab here. I once woke up after a party with a Sari Ben spread on my wall. Lovely - I didn&apos;t eat is obviously. Hard to give a review of this place as I haven&apos;t eaten here sober but after 50p beers at the Union, it certainly tastes good.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is good for location, as it&apos;s on the Quay, next to the cinema (Odeon) and a variety of places to eat.

You can go here and have a good evening, combined with the above mentioned places.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Another favourite on a drunken night out. Perfect for getting a roll and fritter on the way home from The Arches on a Saturday night out. Be warned though. The smell of chips on a Saturday afternoon as you walk down Buchanan St, is too tempting for words.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is now AMF bowling, I think...
 1 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Home of the finest fish suppers around - sometimes I lay awake at night, knowing Lorimers is shut and that thus my dreams will remain unfulfilled during the early morning, while also aware that only hours remain until I can again gorge myself on the delicacies that lie within a disarmingly humble building on Longman Road. It&apos;s provided my longest love affair, but also my bulging gut - still, I&apos;m eternally grateful for both, and wouldn&apos;t change anything for the world.

Oh, and the macaroni&apos;s not bad either.
 4 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This gym is OK. I liked the idea of it because it&apos;s solely for woman, and I don&apos;t like the idea of working out with men.

But it&apos;s a bit small and maintenance isn&apos;t great - one of the drinks machines broke down and they didn&apos;t fix it, they just removed it and never replaced it! Some of the machines don&apos;t work and they just leave them there, and the toilets are always out of order.

There are no cubicles to get changed either - making it a bit awkward if you go in for a shower after, with everyone trying to get changed under their towels! I know it&apos;s a women&apos;s gym, but we still like a little privacy sometimes!!

Classes don&apos;t go on past 8pm either, making it hard for me to get there in time after work.

Overall not all bad, but room for improvement.
 3 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Good for chinese buffets! Try the all you can eat, and then pick as many different dishes as you can!

Brilliant!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree - the best ice cream, it&apos;s great! You need to try it. This wee place has been around for ages and it&apos;s still the best place to go for a little ice cream fix.
 5 Gillian Harvey 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Peking inn. Unless you are inside. Then you are peeking out.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
You&apos;re in a train station with half-an-hour to spare before the 4-hour trip to Edinburgh, how to blot out the pain? Berties Bar, that&apos;s how.

It&apos;s within the station, it has the usual selection of drinks, it&apos;s a pub. It&apos;s that simple. And who doesn&apos;t appreciate the simple things in life?
 3 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A friendly little Chine take-away and you always get good banter with the guys who run. And it is right next door to the Crown pub, so you can’t complain!

Try the Special Fried Rice….
 3 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
That should read &quot;Chinese&quot; take-away and &quot;run it&quot;. I type too fast!!!
 1 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
It may not look like the most welcoming chippy, but don&apos;t let that put you off...

The food is actually of fairly high quality (well, as far as battered deep fried things go...)

The prices are great and the portions are good!

YUM YUM!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A good course, with some challenges all the way round, none more so than on the first. Make sure you get over the water!

Andy Goram is amongst the fine gents who have played here before.
 3 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
As you&apos;d expect from a Weatherspoons, it&apos;s cheap and therefore cheerful. Atmosphere&apos;s not too bad either, I&apos;d attribute that again to the cheapness.
 3 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Not bad for a bit of snooker-related banter.

This place used to be a bit run down but it is a lot better now.
 2 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice layout, pleasant atmophere, drink&apos;s a decent price and the food&apos;s good too - ideal for a few lunchtime pints before trying to get through the afternoon without the boss knowing you&apos;re hammered. Hasn&apos;t failed me yet!
 4 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great shop selling a wide range of yarns, knitting patterns, haberdashery, beads and also school wear. Friendly and knowledgeable staff.
 4 Maria de la O 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A nice enough setting, but the bar prices are a bit high
 2 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Good banter in this family-run bar and hotel.
 2 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This store is AWESOME! I love Apple stuff, and was really excited when this opened up in Glasgow!

Now you can get any mac or ipod stuff without having to order it over the website!

The store looks really nice, clean and modern, with lots of displays where you can try and play with the Apple stuff!

I would give this place 10 stars if I could!!!
 5 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the best places to catch a gig, if you can adjust to the &apos;cosy&apos; environs which necessitate that the band themselves will be only a few feet from where you stand, meaning that the bodily odour of any rock&apos;n&apos;roll oiks throwing themselves around the room will impinge itself upon your drinking experience...
 4 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A bit rough round the edges.
 2 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The place of choice if you are young and like rubbish music.
 2 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty basic and cheap.

Good if you know what you are looking for.

I bought a graphics card that was faulty, and they told me they needed to test it before they can relace it. They did, but it was a bit inconvenient.

If you are looking for somewhere in town for cheap kit, try either here, or Priceless computing.
 3 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The best pub in Penicuik, and that doesn&apos;t say much.
 1 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Budget computers by name, same applies by nature.

Great for cheap computer hardware. I&apos;d recommend you know what you are looking for though. If not, take along someone who does as they can be quite technical with you.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Still the best place to end your night out - though that might be more a reflection on the mediocre level of clubs in Inverness than it is a compliment for Hootenannys.

Still, lots of fun if you get yourself upstairs in time - three levels of differing entertainment, so e.g. if the music on the club level leaves a bit to be desired you can go upstairs and watch some poor sops embarrass themselves at open mic. Everyone&apos;s a winner!
 4 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I remember when this was the only priceless computing store there was.

It was cheap and cheerful, and I bought a lot of my computer stuff from here.

Now there are stores all over the place, making it easier to find a Priceless Computing store near you.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Gunny&apos;s is a mainstay of Inverness - if it was to disappear there&apos;d probably be a big vortex in the middle of the city centre that would drag all around it down into its grasp, until all that was left would be a resilient and steadfast Maccy D&apos;s. And that&apos;d be a sad day indeed.

Though having said that, I wouldn&apos;t actually go in there - Inverness karaoke seven days a week? I&apos;d rather wash my ears out with battery acid.
 2 Michael 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Oh the memories of my youth.

The less said about that the better!
 5 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
You would be surprised between the outside and inside of this shop. It is unassuming but once you get inside, Wow!

Some of this equipment is amazing! It looks beautiful, it sounds beautiful! Expect to re-mortgage your house to own some of it!

Still, I can dream!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A good Chinese. They have a bit you can sit in, but I have never seen anybody in it apart from a Saturday night.
 1 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Why get films developed nowadays? It&apos;s all digital nowadays, innit!?

Mind you, if you do, this is a cheap and cheerful place to go.

Oh, and quick! Have pictures in about 20 minutes!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic bead and jewellery making shop. Beautiful displays and original stock, I could spend hours browsing in this small shop!
 5 Maria de la O 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a fairly big shopping centre. It can be quite fun to visit, however expect a fair load of students loitering about... (I did when I was a student!)

Plenty to see and do and spend your money on.

Check out:

Oil and Vinegar - good place as they give free samples. Eat lots and it&apos;ll do you for a free lunch!

The bear factory (I think the name has changed) - Give the big bear a hug!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Crappy bar with a crappy crowd. I dunno anything about the food &apos;cause I&apos;ve never eaten there.

Mad fer it.
 1 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Went in here for an afternoon lunch and it was very nice. Loads of Italian atmosphere, reasonable prices and good food.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a quirky wee shopping centre, with more of an &quot;indoor market&quot; feel than a modern shopping centre.

It is worth checking out, as there is a huge variety of shops here, everything from lightbulbs to clothing to toys to household items to a variety of places to eat.

Some of the shops are not much cop, but others are great.

Check it out!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Craft boutique selling unique and original gifts made by artists and designers from Scotland and the UK. From contemporary jewellery to handbags, home accessories, ceramics, etc...

Offering a wide range of prices, it&apos;s a great shop if you are looking for a cute gift or a treat!
 5 Maria de la O 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Portions aren&apos;t the biggest but you can put up with that as the food is very good.
 5 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Typical Bella Italia chain restaurant, the food is reasonable but nothing to write home about. Its OK for grabbing a quick bite to eat.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Corinthian is a place for wannabe gangsters, trendy people who aren&apos;t trendy, old men and women.
 1 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Funky design in store with the usual support area upstairs. Usually have live DJs on a saturday too.
 5 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty small shop compared to the hoards of &quot;Game&quot; shops in Glasgow, however this place holds it&apos;s own.

Good variety of games on many formats, including PSP, XBox 360, PS2/PS3, Gamecube and Wii.

The prices are pretty pocket friends, and the staff seem to know what they are talking about.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the better boozers in the densely student populated end of Sauchiehall street. Good tunes, cold drinks and a good crowd.
 4 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
These shops are not too bad, as they stock all of the same games and new releases as the larger chains.

The prices are fair and they also sell a chunk of pre-owned games as well. Good if you want a bargin, but do check the surface of the CD/DVD&apos;s before you leave the shop.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The eye is always bigger than the belly when you visit these sorts of places. It not the worst buffett place and usualy has lots of good puddings to choose from.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
These shops are not too bad, as they stock all of the same games and new releases as the larger chains.

The prices are fair and they also sell a chunk of pre-owned games as well. Good if you want a bargin, but do check the surface of the CD/DVD&apos;s before you leave the shop.
 1 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
As good as the student hell hole that is the Garage. Make of that, what you will.
 1 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This place is good for a huge dose of noodles when you fall out of one of the many surrounding bars. Watch out for the sweet chilli sauce, it extra hot even after a few drinks.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Hotel wise, this is a small residence, but it offers affordable rooms in a setting not too far from the shopping centre, but far enough away if you want to escape it.

Da Vinci&apos;s is more than a hotel though. It boasts a new Italian restaurant which has proved popular with the locals. Its lounge bar offers affordable drinks all week long in a comfortable setting with snacks available up until 10pm. And lastly, Da Vinci&apos;s has a nightclub open on a Friday and a Saturday which is regarded as the alternative place in town to go, because literally it is the only alternative in town.

If you&apos;re heading to Livingston, definitely try out Da Vinci&apos;s, whatever you&apos;re after.
 4 Grant87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This place makes delicious pizzas. Thin based with a good and different choice of toppings.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
There are three pubs in close proximity but this one is the pick of the bunch by far. The Fox has a cosy lounge for relaxed chat and a bar that is really lively at weekends (and on Tuesdays for Quiz Night)but the restaurant upstairs is what really makes a difference. Never had a bad meal there and the special menu nights are superb. Has a Beer Festival twice a year that is worth checking out and you should sample the ales produced in the attached microbrewery.
 4 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
It seems there is a Game store almost everywhere nowadays. It is a hugely popular chain store for selling games and consoles.

Usually the prices are cheap (dare I say the cheapest) about, and they stock all of the latest formats including Xbox 360, Playstation 3, PSP, Wii and Nintendo DS.

Not a bad chain store, and they offer no quibble returns. Check out Gamestation and G Force if you are in the centre of Glasgow before commiting to making a purchase.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Travelodge is the more affordable town centre option, located right across the road from all the shopping Livingston has to offer.

Like most of the hotels in the chain, it has plenty rooms, often at knockdown prices if you book up well in advance. It&apos;s not the Ramada Jarvis by a long shot in terms of comfort, but it serves its purpose.

There is also an Italian restaurant located on the ground floor, although the drinks are pricey at any time of day.
 3 Grant87 03/09/2009 Report this place 
It seems there is a Game store almost everywhere nowadays. It is a hugely popular chain store for selling games and consoles.

Usually the prices are cheap (dare I say the cheapest) about, and they stock all of the latest formats including Xbox 360, Playstation 3, PSP, Wii and Nintendo DS.

Not a bad chain store, and they offer no quibble returns. Check out Gamestation and G Force if you are in the centre of Glasgow before commiting to making a purchase.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A place for old drunk women. Good if yer old, fat and desperate.

Not me, I&apos;m a rock n roll star. Mad fer it.
 1 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
It seems there is a Game store almost everywhere nowadays. It is a hugely popular chain store for selling games and consoles.

Usually the prices are cheap (dare I say the cheapest) about, and they stock all of the latest formats including Xbox 360, Playstation 3, PSP, Wii and Nintendo DS.

Not a bad chain store, and they offer no quibble returns. Check out Gamestation and G Force if you are in the centre of Glasgow before commiting to making a purchase.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
It seems there is a Game store almost everywhere nowadays. It is a hugely popular chain store for selling games and consoles.

Usually the prices are cheap (dare I say the cheapest) about, and they stock all of the latest formats including Xbox 360, Playstation 3, PSP, Wii and Nintendo DS.

Not a bad chain store, and they offer no quibble returns. Check out Gamestation and G Force if you are in the centre of Glasgow before commiting to making a purchase.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A lovely wee place. Thoroughly recommended.
 4 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Soon to be part of Trongate 103, this is a jewel in Glasgow&apos;s crown.

GPS offer different printmaking courses like screen printing and etching. I took a screen printing weekend course and subsequently became a member so I could use their facilities on a regular basis.

This should be used by the public more. Check them out for adult and children&apos;s classes. It&apos;s worth it!
 5 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Quite a nice place this, as it is big and friendly. Good for both Saturday nights and Sunday afternoons.
 2 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great pub this. You can’t beat a bit of banter with Tommy, Raul and Bubbles.
 5 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
You need to try the salad at this place. Fantastic!
 5 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Just your classic wee village cafe. Friendly staff, cracking cakes and a hot spot for all the local gossip.
 4 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree with Big Marv. How good pubs should be.
 5 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This magnificent building houses some amazing works of art including Salvidor Dali&apos;s, Christ of St. John on the Cross and various permanent and touring exhibitions like Doctor Who.

It&apos;s recently had a major renovation. This is a must for both tourists and residents of Glasgow.
 5 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Once the last pub on the walk from town to St Mirren&apos;s Love St stadium The Wee Barrel is still part of the pre-match ritual for some fans going to the new ground on Greenhill Road. Maybe a wee bit out of the way but a proper pub for your pre-match pint or commiserating with other disappointed Buddies after the final whistle.
 3 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A good old working mans bar with working mans prices in the centre of town.
 3 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Not too pricey and the food is good. Fast service if you are in a hurry or a take your time approach if you are having a chat. Nice selection of Japanese beers and the sushi is fantastic.
 4 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The original Bier Halle! This one of all three is the best serving cold beer in cold glasses and 2-4-1 pizza Sunday through Thursday.
 4 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The band I used to be in with my brother was signed by Alan McGee here. This legendary venue, get&apos;s all the great (and loads more terrible) bands before the make it big.

It&apos;s ok for a drink, much better seeing a band.

Mad fer it.
 5 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice quiet cafe for a cupp a or lunch. The food must be good because even after stuffing my face on every visit I end up taking some dolmades or baklava up the road with me. Music is a bit cheesy and tends to be either new age nonsense or 1970s love songs. Grub more than makes up for that though.
 4 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Used to shop in here all the time when i was a student but now the over abundance of self-righteous staff and head splitting music make me avoid this place.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Decent selection of clothes but targetted at a bit of a younger market than myself. Perfect for those trying to chase whatever is currently apparently in fashion at any moment.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Decent wee shop that often has a gem of a pair of trainers hiding away somewhere. Always worth popping into just to check if they&apos;ve got something special in.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
If you&apos;re after a bland pair of shoes or trainers that aren&apos;t fashionable in any way and will last a few months then this is the place to go.

No frills and cheap as chips.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A gem of a bar, oddly it seems a bit of a secret despite being smack in the middle of town.

I agree with Marvin, the midweek lunch is great, soup and sandwich deal every time for me!

Good on Friday and Saturday evenings too, djs are more good than bad and its always a nice vibe.
 4 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Good selection of trainers with some stonking exclusives that you cannae get elsewhere.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Good range of decent trainers and shoes. Bit hit and miss sometimes but usually a good bet for a first look if you&apos;re on the hunt for a new pair.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Worth a look if you&apos;re after a cheap suit or need a new shirt or something. Nothing too exciting here.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
If you want to see the cold hard face of Glasgow, go here for Karaoke. Terrible tunes sung by women you wouldn&apos;t bring home to your mother.

Don&apos;t be fooled by either the green plants or bench in the picture. Both have been stolen. The bench ended up in my close. I didn&apos;t steal it though. Promise.
 1 bambam 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I love the fact that they redecorated a few years ago but just replaced the grubby 70s tat with fresh, clean looking 70s tat. I don&apos;t think they give a monkeys about the food or the drink in here, everything is basic and its all about the music. A great place to see local and up and coming bands on the cheap, it also has a pretty good jukebox.
 3 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
There are quite often wee indie nights or bands on in here but it is more of a space than a venue proper. If it is quiet it seems to lack atmosphere and if it is busy you could wait half an hour at the bar. I have had good nights here but that isn&apos;t down to the place itself.
 2 ahc 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree with Charlie. Not a pub to stay in for very long, especially if you are not a local.
 2 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Is very good for people who live / work in the centre of Glasgow. There is not as much variety as the Tesco superstores, however it&apos;s good to nip in and pick up some food for dinner, or a pint of milk and some fags.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Fairly well placed in the centre of the city. Is handy of you work nearby.

Can get very busy during the day, especially around lunchtime.
 3 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a well places supermarket, handy for people who live, work or study locally.

It&apos;s nothing special, but convenient for getting milk, lottery tickets or cigarettes.

Try and avoid the credit card salepeople within the store offering credit as they can be annoying.
 3 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Not so much a B7B but the main drinking establishment in Alness. Most of the local&apos;s old enough(ish) to drink and head down here on a Friday and Saturday night for a few pints.

Last order can be a bit early on a Saturday night tho so watch out.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Some of the most amazing scampi and chips known to man can be acquired at the Shandwick. Lots of other good hearty meals also available.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Lots of information and collections, including rocks and minerals, dinosaur fossils and old coins, as well as scientific instruments from the 17th century.

Is closely connected with a lot of the (Charles Rennie) Mackintosh exhibits in and around Glasgow.

Very educational, and the admission is free, which is always a bonus! (Although I recommend making a donation...)
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great, cheap, hearty meals at the Castle. Friendly staff and a cracking portion of Sausage, Beans and Chips!
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 03/09/2009 Report this place 
If you are a Stirling uni student and it is a Thursday night then Fubar is the place to go! If you want to avoid big queues then buy your tickets in advance. You will see students dotted about the town selling them, at a sometimes cheaper price, so it is worth buying them in advance. But don’t plan on arriving any time before 11 because it doesn’t start getting busy till about then.
 1 Pam14 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a good place for students to go and relax on the comfy leather sofas. Your student discount will get you a large drink for the price of a medium on all hot drinks and the free wi-fi will come in handy if you want to get some studying done.
 1 Pam14 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This café is simple and clean and only has about 10 tables, but the food is good if you are looking for a simple lunch like soup, sandwich or even just a nice coffee and cake! Set in the cobbled streets of the Village, East Kilbride’s original centre, the café is surrounded by a couple of independent shops so is in a good location for lunch and a wander.
 3 Pam14 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a beautiful hotel, set in magnificent grounds. It is the perfect place to go for a relaxing weekend break and re-charge your batteries! The hotel is decorated with class and the rooms were very clean. There are also lots of things to do if you go as a family. There are two swimming pools, a giant outdoor chess board and croquet!
 5 Pam14 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Quite an &quot;old mans&quot; pub, but it is fairly welcoming.

With a regular karaoke (every saturday, I think) and cheap drinks, it is a decent place to spend an evening with friends.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a fairly decent chippy.

They do nice sized portions, which I believe is caught locally.

Prices are ok too!
 3 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Considering Irvine is fairly small, this is a fairly large supermarket.

It is just off a main road, so travelling to it is pretty easy and convenient.

There is a petrol station there as well.
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Always a friendly bunch. The drivers are usually quite chatty.

The fares are cheap as well, which is surprising considering they are a smallish company!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This place offers a good choice of things to do. There is ice skating and swimming, a really big soft play area and loads more!

The downside is that it&apos;s usually populated with kids with far too much time on their hands.

It can be quite expensive too, but worth a look though!
 4 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Please be aware this is NOT actually a hotel, but a homeless shelter for people with drink / drug problems.

Have heard lots of stories about this place, but suffice to say it is certainly NOT a place you want to take the family to stay in!
 1 TheLittlerich 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Handy of you are going to a gig at the SECC or fancy mixing with media lovies from the close by STV and BBC offices. On a warm day, the decking area out back offers magnificent views down the river.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Forget the affordable quirky furniture with strange names. The meatballs are worth the trip alone. Sadly the people who work there have to wear the most horrific uniforms but it doesn&apos;t stop them being friendly and helpful. I love Ikea too!
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
You may spy Duncan in his cycling shorts - worth the membership fee I think! Good equipment and not full of muscles showing off in tiny shorts. A place for all levels to keep fit
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A wooden sweat box with bouncy floors. The perfect place to see your favourite band. The smell of stale beers seeps through the floor boards but it&apos;s worth it. You can smell the history of a good time at the Barrowlands.
 1 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Cute, intimate venue which puts on excellent plays and one of the best panto&apos;s in town. With an excellent bar, this theatre is a hidden gem in Glasgow.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I disagree, the food is more traditional Italian here. Big Brother fan? This is the one for you as Federico Martone of BB fame&apos;s family run this little joint. Try the Qui Quo Qua speciality cooked up by Leonardo - you;re in for a treat.
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Perfect for a sunny day, the outdoor eating area here always proves popular. Celeb spotter? Italian footballers aplenty head to Piazza Italia, and much like Qua, this is another part of Big Brother&apos;s Federico Martone&apos;s family empire. Bello!
 4 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Quite mainstream Italian but seems popular with the punters and the decor is certainly interesting. A very family atmosphere in this restaurant, perfect for a night out with the kids. Mot quite as good as it&apos;s sister restaurant in Bishopbriggs but still worth a visit.
 3 Laura Boyd 03/09/2009 Report this place 
I love this place! I go at least three times a year. It is full of interesting stuff from different periods of Scottish history.
 5 Graham Fraser 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great traditional Scottish Pub - loads of live music on but there early if you want a seat!
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
One of my favourite pubs. Table service with great staff - 2-4-1 pizza and a fantastic beer menu!

And the best things is... your mobile doesn&apos;t work so no one can find you..!
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Not a fan of this place - no music and it&apos;s just a big echo chamber and noisy!
 2 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice pub - friendly staff, good food and you can sit outside on those sunny Glasgow days!
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Love it! Great noodles and agree with Marv - the Chicken Katsu is fab.. can also recommend the yagi soba. Good Japanese beer as well.
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
5 star sandwiches - recently came runner up in a poll for best sandwich bar in the UK.

I defy you to find a better meatball sandwich!
 5 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Don&apos;t be put off by the entrance - this is a fantastic traditional Italian restaurant, just as mamma made. All the classics are here and they do a mean Lasagne.

You gotta try it out - you will love it
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the smallest restaurants I have been in - Great fish restaurant with loads of specials on - really attentive waiting staff. You gotta book though..!
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
One of my favourite Glasgow restaurants, top quality food, all locally sourced. Varied menu with Fish and Meat,

You can&apos;t beat going to here for dinner and wondering around to the Park Bar or the Ben Nevis for a nightcap..
 5 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A great wee Scottish pub - more whiskies than you can shake a stick at.

There is sometimes live music on, many a time there are a bunch of fiddlers in the corner jamming!

If you can&apos;t get a seat in the Park Bar across the road - then wonder over here..
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A Glasgow favourite with loads of different stuff on the menu - the Monkfish is a favourite of mine.

You gotta book as it is a busy restaurant but worth going to.
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A great hidden jem - slightly older crowd but great wee booths with candles on the table.

Really good wine and champagne menu and good people watching!
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
BAR 10 is down a quite wee side lane - nice boozer and funky music.
 3 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Big empty soulless kit pub - not my kind of boozer but OK if you want cheap beer..
 2 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Decent enough pub - good some nice beer on tap and big outside area when the weather is nice!

Good jumping off point to start the night..
 3 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Not the largest of Tesco&apos;s by any means, but well stocked and friendly staff - there queue management is second to none. Though they do have a tendancy to force you down the &apos;self serve&apos; route which I hate.

If too early in morning (as in between 8am-9am) there may be some stock not there - reason being I hear, is that they can&apos;t have the delivery lorry coming before 9am due to residential area.

Plenty parking and recycyling bins (including plastic bags) available, plus cashline and Costa coffee bar.
 3 CaseyJones 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Kit pub with some interesting beers if that&apos;s your kind of thing.

There are plenty of other traditional Scottish pubs nearby that though!
 2 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The dome is a must see at Christmas. The decorations are amazing with a huge tree in the centre of the room that spans right up to the top of the dome. They really make an effort.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
My Local pub - and I walk past 5 other to get here! Great atmosphere, one of the best places to watch Scotland play footie on the telly. Good food and it&apos;s also a micro brewery with a range of their own lagers.

Plenty of real ale on draft and a selection of bottled ales. Thoroughly recommend it.
 4 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the best all round stores in Edinburgh. From kitchen ware, to curtains and kids toys right through to mens and womens clothes. Not necessarily most fashionable for men, but regular quality garments. Great place to visit for christmas presents, just wonder about and seek inspiration. There is an electrical department but it may be a bit more expensive so do shop around.

If going with kids buggy then there is limited lift space to get in and out of the Leith Walk entrance.

If coming by car then car park across the road under Omni Centre is ideal.
 3 CaseyJones 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The foods nothing more than average and the toilets are outside. Add to that the broken lock on the outside loo and you really have an experience.
 2 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Although the fish is excellent in here I opted for the steak and was glad I did. Everyone at the table enjoyed there meal and I would certainly go again.
 5 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice pub and a funky wee beer garden too. Slightly off the beaten track of Princes Street but worth a visit as its good for a drink.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A fantastic venue with amazing acoustics.

This is the main hall for the Scottish National Orchestra - well worth going to see them play - a world class venue and a world class Orchestra.

Also hosts other events like Celtic Connections.
 5 GaryW 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Been taking my car to be served and repaired here for 7 years. Great service, can usually fit you in at very short notice and you don&apos;t get ripped off. If they can&apos;t fix it then they will recommend you to a specialist. Can&apos;t rate them highly enough.
 5 CaseyJones 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Great burgers, well worth a visit. The bean burger is a treat, and quite a bit of eating.
 5 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Lots of interesting things to see and do, and its all free. The kids enjoy it as there some interactive stuff, and some strange exhibitions for them to play with.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
You won&apos;t get ripped off here, far from it. Friendly service and will do their best to fix whatever is needing done. I&apos;ve had minor problems been fixed for no charge here and now will only go to them if I have any tyre, brake, exhaust issues. They will get my business everytime.

Free internet access too, though they could do with updating their flash and browser resolution ...
 4 CaseyJones 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Kids love coming to the transport museum. They may not be interested in cars, buses or trains but they sure will enjoy climbing all over the exhibitions.
 5 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This used to be a decent shop until they decided to half the mens department. Its TOP MAN, so it should be about mens clothes.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
The most greasy food I have even eaten from a chip shop. The prices are very cheap and there is a reason for that, the food is not good.
 1 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
A huge range of designer clothes which you can buy at half the price at the surrounding shops. Good to buy from if your flush.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
There&apos;s something for everyone in here. I like the electrical department downstairs which is like curry&apos;s but a bit cheaper.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Vast range of designer clothes and suits at good prices. The shop is over 3 floors and it can be a bit hard to find clothes as there&apos;s so much to look at but worth the effort.
 4 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
In the heart of Glasgow, Queen Street is the main station for connection between Glasgow and Edinburgh. Its not a big station really, but does the job. Not a lot on offer in terms of bars and places to eat so its best to pop outside if you are looking for a refreshment.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Good place to park the car when visiting the city centre. It not that expensive either and there are loads of spaces.
 1 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a place for the younger generation. I used to enjoy going here when I was younger as its a large club that gets the best DJ&apos;s. Now I just think it smell musky.
 3 Charlie 03/09/2009 Report this place 
Much the same as other Ten Pin Bowling alleys. Good for some cheap stodgy food, a few pints and a laugh. Novelty wears off after about 45 minutes or so once everyone realises that bowling is pretty dull. But there&apos;s plenty of decent arcade machines and a bar to migrate to once that sets in.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Easily the best attraction Glasgow has to offer. On top of all the antiques and paintings there&apos;s loads of dinosaur bones and fossils. Plus theres a nice focus in places on local Glasgow history and even as someone who&apos;s lived here for years, and been to the museum countless times I always discover something new.

There&apos;s usually some sort of novelty exhibition going on aswell - like a display of Kylie&apos;s clothes or Doctor Who memorabilia.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Well it is free.. and its ok for a wander round if the Kelvingrove is too busy, but its not that interesting overall. Unlike the Kelvingrove you&apos;ll probably only visit this place once.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great range of ever changing modern art and paintings. If you can fight your way past the emo kids that congregate on the front steps you&apos;ll be treated to a great way to while away a couple of hours.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s just gone into administration and to be honest its probably just as well. Nobody really ever seemed to know what went on in here. I&apos;m not sure if it was free to get in or what went on. I only went in because they had XBox&apos;s in here one day and to visit the decent restaurant at the top. They also had a shop with overpriced novelty items.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Always having interesting contemporary exhibitions. Worth keeping an eye on whats happening

 http://local.stv.tv/...14371-cca/ 

As something always appears that might tickle your fancy.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great little cinema. Serves beer and is often one of the only places you can catch the latest Ghibli releases with subtitles rather than the overdubbed monstrosities that Disney produce.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Big beast of a cinema that always has plenty of room to show the latest releases. Packed with neds and kids on a Friday and Saturday night - its a more pleasant experience during the week or during the day.

The food in the bar/restaurant is pretty rank.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great place to catch the special editions of big movies in 3D or the spectacular education documentaries that they show. Worth a visit just for the experience.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
No longer a cinema but a venue for gigs. Which it does pretty well.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty decent sports hall where you can partake in loads of activities. They&apos;ve got a climbing wall, indoor 5&apos;s, badminton courts, a gym and a huge indoor arena where they put on indoor athletics events.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 04/09/2009 Report this place 
The crepes are OK - Waaay overpriced for all they are though...
 3 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Just what you need after a night out!! Possibly the best Veg pakora in Glasgow ;-)
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
I love this place! 2-4-1 pizzas all the way! I love the Fiorentina with an egg in the middle (although my freinds think I&apos;m bonkers). They have a great selection of flavoured schnapps which are my fav...for the guys they have a tonne of different beers.
 5 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
I used to go here a lot when I was at uni for an extended liquid lunch ;-) they used to do 2-4-1 cocktails on a Monday...don&apos;t know if they still do or not but the cocktails are delicious anyway!!

Its not been full of posers when I&apos;ve been there.

Food is a bit pricey but you get huge portions so I suppose I shouldn&apos;t complain!
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Oh my goodness - how hot can a club get??!! And who thought it was a good idea to put the cloakroom up 4 flights of stairs??! Not great for stumbling up when you&apos;ve had a bit too much to drink!! Still have a good night though, good cheesy tunes..somethims a couple random ones..what more could you want??!
 3 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Quite posh and swanky...not my type of place for a night out but you can&apos;t knock the surroundings - good if you have something special to celebrate! The food in the restaurant is delicious - I go there when its on the 5pm.co.uk offer £12 for 2 or 3 courses - can&apos;t afford to otherwise!!
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Can feel like you&apos;re in a school canteen sometimes as you are just sitting in rows of tables...its better when its not peak dinner time and you can have a bit of space to yourself...food is superb and service is really quick so great if you&apos;re in a rush!
 5 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
I don&apos;t know if I even want to try and count the times I&apos;ve stumbled in here after a night out!! I have had the food sober too so can recommend!
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
pizza slices can be a bit hit and miss but I still good value at £2! Good if you&apos;re in a rush to see a movie at the cinema and cheaper than their prices!
 3 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Now this place unless you look for it you don&apos;t notice its there - I love it! Food is reasonably priced and very tasty! recommended!
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
I recommend this place too! Very tasty italian restaurant!
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Yum yum! Had a very tasty veg pizza in here! Service fairly quick and staff are friendly.
 4 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Pricey - I&apos;d rather go to pizzahut - you get more for your money. Food is OK so if you get a special offer try it out.
 3 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
This place was recommended to me by a friend and I have recommended it to all my friends! Its a lovely little restaurant, friendly staff, good food and good wine - perfect!
 5 hcan87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Knickers!
 3 Chico-La 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Excellent for a roll&amp;chips after a Jags match!
 4 Chico-La 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great pub - cosy atmosphere with an even cosier restaurant downstairs. Well worth a visit.
 4 Chico-La 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Okay bar - Bring you cheque book - £4.60 for a pint of Peroni on a Thus night - nearly fell of my stool - either I&apos;m getting old or poorer!!
 2 Chico-La 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Does the best coffee and Italian sausage bap has to be tried to be believed.
 5 lizm 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic for everything, if you need it Hugh Rose will have it. Very friendly and helpful staff.
 5 lizm 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Surely one of the loveliest spots in Edinburgh and one of the best Gardens in Scotland. Loved the Power Plant show which was on during the festival
 5 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Sort of closed at the moment (summer 2009) for major refurbishment but a brilliant gallery; all human - well, Scottish - life is here, not just the toffs.
 5 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Just becasue its run by the City doesn&apos;t mean mean it&apos;s not worth visiting, They have some good permanent stuff as well as visitng shows. Nice cafe too if a bit pricey. Handy for the station!
 4 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
If it&apos;s at the Fruitmarket it will be weird but it&apos;s not like that&apos;s a bad thing. Cafe&apos;s a bit right-on for my taste.
 4 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
if you believe photography is an art from (and if you don&apos;t why not) this is the place to visit. Don&apos;t forget Edinburgh is where some of the most important early photography was done.
 4 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
There&apos;s so much in this museum that you need to see and the fact it&apos;s free is great because it doesn&apos;t cost a fortune to have a nice day out.

It&apos;s great for kids, but there&apos;s lots here for adults as well.

I&apos;d agree, the cafe is quite expensive, but it&apos;s nice to stop by for a coffee if you&apos;re in for a while.

Worth a visit.
 4 Gillian Harvey 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Really nice theatre, just five minutes walk from Edinburgh Waverley station, so it&apos;s really central and easy to find.

The theatre puts on a lot of good shows in here throughout the year - I&apos;ve been quite a few times.

Various bars in the theatre too, which means they don&apos;t get ridiculously cramped during interval time!

Nice and spacious, staff seem helpful.
 4 Gillian Harvey 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Undoubtedly one of the spookiest places in what can be a very spooky city. It used to be even more so before the city began to market it as a tourist attraction. Then only a few folk knew about it.
 4 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great for a good day out, there&apos;s lots of animals from lions to monkeys and bears, and a whole load of different areas to explore.

I went last year and loved it, planning to go back before it shuts for the season.

You can drive through a section and see all the animals milling about, and there are also lots of areas where you can go and see the animals up close.

There&apos;s also an island which you can catch a boat over to, to see the chimps, which is worth doing.

Perfect on a nice day - maybe not so good if raining! Quite expensive too, but I&apos;d say it&apos;s worth it.

Good for all ages - I went with my boyfriend, no kids, and we weren&apos;t bored once!
 4 Gillian Harvey 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Like all Scottish presbyterian churches (and let&apos;s not get into how a Presbyterian kirk can have a cathedral), quite austere but impressive inside. A fantastic modern organ.
 4 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Gorgeous hotel, quite old fashioned looking, but that adds to its charm.

It&apos;s a good place to go for a weekend away, it&apos;s perfect for totally relaxing. There are swimming pools and a lovely restaurant as well as ballroom and there is usually some form of entertainment.

Good for kids too - there&apos;s horseriding and a pool with soft play items, and they cater to kids in terms of food too.

It&apos;s only about an hour and a half&apos;s drive from Glasgow too, so perfect for a short break.

Only downside is the price - it&apos;s really quite expensive to stay here and to eat etc.

Some nice little restaurants in the surrounding area (five minutes walk) though - and some lovely little independent shops to browse - as well as the famous Christmas shop, which is open all year!
 4 Gillian Harvey 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Shouldn&apos;t this be in Drumnadrochit or at least somewhere near Loch Ness?
 2 cheekyweeman 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Beautiful hotel, slightly outside the main town.

A good place to go for a luxurious weekend, and not too far from Glasgow etc to get to.

Dunblane itself is quite small, but there are some nice little shops and bars around, and the hotel more than provides in this area too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 04/09/2009 Report this place 
It is a chain but they have a lively team at Waverley. Totally on the ball for customers trying to get away quickly for their train - they really don&apos;t hang around and have a bright cheery attitude. Variety of bagels and wide range of fillings - Marmite and peanut butter, double bacon, smoked salmson and cream cheese ...
 5 Shaba 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great little tucked away pub. Food is Amazing! The service is excellent they have the bad boy pub quiz on Monday nights and all the staff are friendly. Outside seating for sunny nights or the smokers and have been known to have Barbeques. Most important is the reasonably priced drink and excellent selection. Well worth a visit!
 4 Fiona Fee 04/09/2009 Report this place 
The Baked Potato Shop offers oustanding baked potatoes with a wide variety of vegan and vegetarian fillings and salads. Coleslaw is stunning also highly recommend the cheese and vege chilli combo - not forgetting the legendary vegetarian haggis samosas.
 5 Shaba 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Recently reinvented as City Walls it does appeal to an older crowd. Food is reasonably priced although microwaved so not inspiring. Really nice large pub with loads of seating for chatting to friends.
 3 Fiona Fee 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Excellent restaurant serving fresh italian food, good value for money and nice atmosphere. Don&apos;t miss the seafood platter and the schiacciatas, to name just a few. I love the Battlefield Rest!
 5 Maria de la O 04/09/2009 Report this place 
The view from the top is spectacular, rivalled only by the top of the Cineworld a few blocks further up. That said, it&apos;s hidden away and poorly signposted, so it&apos;s little wonder it has got into trouble.
 2 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
I miss TFI Fridays :(. This place was an absolute key element of the experience. Win the quiz, see of the beer box prize, lose a few hours and then head off to Best Kebab.

Students, you haven&apos;t lived if you haven&apos;t tried.
 4 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
As said already, this is owned by Federico, who was on BB once. As for the food, I&apos;ve only been once but both my girlfriend and I thought it was excellent.

The service was friendly and not over-bearing and the price was reasonable. It&apos;s a little cramped, but that&apos;s the only complaint.
 4 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
A bit overpriced, stale decor and not the best boozer in Candleriggs. Still, I end up going back because of the worldwide selection of beers.
 3 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
This hostel offers cheap accommodation and an excellent location in St Andrews and...that&apos;s it really. Luckily I stayed there for just one night: there was no hot water to have a shower in the morning and the rooms were far from clean. A piece of advice: do not go anywhere near the rooms&apos; sofa covers! They must be radioactive by now...
 1 Maria de la O 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Makes up a golden square of bars in the Merchant City together with O&apos;Neills, Red Lizard and Blackfriars.

Home do plenty food and drink deals, even on a Saturday early doors. It&apos;s cosy but spacious and definitely worth visiting. On a Saturday night, it transforms into a hip place to be.
 5 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Located on the main street and overlooking the water, An-Caladh is a nicely decorated and very clean B&amp;B;in the heart of charming Plockton.

Our highlight was probably the breakfast. We were able to choose between full Scottish breakfast and traditional smoked haddock, generous and delicious!

Overall we had a very pleasant stay.
 3 Maria de la O 04/09/2009 Report this place 
A whisky lover&apos;s dream. Best selection of malts in the city centre.
 5 ahc 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Very studenty during the week, no doubt thanks to it&apos;s cheap booze. Great place to watch a game, lots of screens and usually a good atmosphere.
 3 ahc 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Who had the wonderful idea of putting the stage against the front windows? On summer nights you feel like you are at an in-store signing... only there is nothing you would buy and the bands certainly wouldn&apos;t get signed.
 1 ahc 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Great pre-club boozer and the music is always good on Friday and Saturday night - anything from hip-hop to glitch. Oddly for such a trendy place it has a trad jazz band every Saturday afternoon. Billisto&apos;s Big Quiz on a Wednesday is a good laugh, though often quiet. That gives you a better chance oif the often substantial cash prize.
 4 ahc 04/09/2009 Report this place 
An identikit Wetherspoons chain bar set in a shell of a building. This one in particular seems to attract the sort of drinkers you probably don&apos;t want to spend time with.

It&apos;s cheap, but what price a good pub?
 1 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
This is the kind of place you&apos;d probably take one glance at and walk on by. If you&apos;re looking for somewhere to have a pub lunch, next time you walk by, pop your head in.

They do cheap meals that are always overflowing off the plate. The drinks prices are good too.

I can&apos;t speak much for the bar on the left side - it looks like the sort of place you&apos;d think twice about - but for pub grub, don&apos;t miss it.
 4 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
Dark, but a definite place to check out. There are drinks offers during the week that fill the place up and it&apos;s as busy as any other bar on the street at the weekend.

They tried out live bands here for a while, but made a mess of the whole thing with where they positioned the stage.
 4 Grant87 04/09/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s not Starbucks.
 5 Sheena 05/09/2009 Report this place 
Pro lane bowl is your standard ten-bin bowling venue. It has a kid’s soft play area, which the little ones love, and there are several amusement games and pool tables available to pass the time between turns. There is also a snack bar, a bar and a seated area for children&apos;s parties. You can usually find karaoke set up at the weekends but expect to pay higher prices then too. The decor is a little dated but it is the only ten-pin bowling lane in East Kilbride.
 2 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
The last time I got my nails manicured at Nail Zone in East Kilbride, I found the staff very friendly. The prices are about standard but if you have a student card then they offer discounted rates on certain days of the week.
 3 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
Like many theatres, the Kings has managed to restore its period character.

The best shows from the West-End usually come to the Kings more than the other Glasgow theatres so if it is big show-stoppers you are after, keep an eye on the listings!

The best seats can be found in the circle. If you are after a bargain, then head for the galleries. But try and stay to the middle of the row otherwise you may find yourself with restricted viewing.
 4 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
Set on the outskirts of the pretty town of Banchory, this tearoom and restaurant looks out onto the river Feugh. There are windows right along the building, allowing most tables to get a nice view. When I was there, it wasn’t a nice day but had it been a nice summer’s day (if they even exist now) it would have been lovely to sit out on the decking. The smell of home baking made this little restaurant feel so homely and I just thought it captured the essence of the place. The food was fantastic and is definitely a place I would be happy to take people to again. If you visit the falls of Feugh, be sure to watch out for the Salmon that sometimes see jump over the rocks.
 5 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
This is now a bit more than a Simply Food M&amp;S.;Has clothes depts too now. Obivously smaller than Princes Street and Gyle Shopping Centre stores, but good selection and easy parking (why go to Princes St these days!), plus cafe upstairs.

Craigleith is now becoming first option rather than going into town - where you can&apos;t park and only get hassled with George Street being so busy now.
 3 CaseyJones 05/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty large Sainsbury&apos;s with plenty parking, cafe and recycling facilities near by. They&apos;re bakery is good and meat and fish counter staff are really helpful.

They do Pizza Express pizzas too. Couple of negative comments - their cleaning stuff for households is right in the far corner, easy to miss, plus their queue management is not a patch on Tesco. At weekends expect to queue for 10 mins odd.

To end of positive - good quality food, well stocked fruit and veg section and flowers as you go in the door are beautiful.
 3 CaseyJones 05/09/2009 Report this place 
I would highly recommend d this restaurant if looking for a nice meal out in Edinburgh. I was there last weekend and the place was packed out with a good atmosphere.

Food was great and was served at a good pace. I ate off the set menu which was good value for money – two courses for £7.95.

However, there was a wide range of foods at differing prices if you wanted to splash out.
 5 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic restaurant, been there several times and never been disappointed. The set menu is definitely the best option to go for. For £20, you can order as much food as you like.

The Vietnamese food is served in the middle of the table, allowing you to try a bit of everything ordered. This is a very good place for a large party to go, however I would book in advance as it is always busy.

The corn chicken is by far the best starter. A good night out for all.
 5 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
I love Paperchase for their cute cards and snazzy notebooks. If you are looking for value for money, then this is probably not the best place to visit.

However, if you are looking for a nice journal or some unique birthday card or arts and crafts materials then this is the place to go!

I can spend hours in this shop, stumbling across lots of unusual and interesting gifts and I think it is always a nice shop to have a wander around on a rainy day.
 3 Pam14 05/09/2009 Report this place 
The Ceilidh Place is a fantastic Hotel - welcoming, friendly and good value. Also run music events in the hall opposite. Highly recommended.
 5 Sheena 05/09/2009 Report this place 
Excellent venue - and a very good child friendly cafe/bar - at least during the day.
 5 Sheena 05/09/2009 Report this place 
The Cameo is top class - great movies, comfy seats and an amazing bar with good music.
 5 Sheena 05/09/2009 Report this place 
A good venue whether it is for bigger names or up and comers. Sundays are great with Michael Redmond but when it is the lower acts on the bill there doesn&apos;t seem to be a deep pool to draw from. Have heard the same set from one particular comedian several times here. Still, good value for money overall.
 3 ahc 06/09/2009 Report this place 
Handy for drink and bite to eat when around Holyrood area / Dynamic Earth.
 2 CaseyJones 06/09/2009 Report this place 
Beautiful building and like all Pizza Express restaurants it is simple quality italian food. no need to book (in fact not sure if you can book at Pizza Express). Try the salads, large serving and light if want to give the pizza menu a miss.
 3 CaseyJones 06/09/2009 Report this place 
Great just to wander about and take in the beauty. Take a picnic in the summer and go with the family - amazing new Centre just built too. Right next to Inverleith Park and an amazing open green space in the City.
 3 CaseyJones 06/09/2009 Report this place 
Had been to this bar when it was a dark wine bar and was not that fussed with the place, but now has expanded and is now a great place to go, especially after a rugby international, buzzing and while you might have to queue to get in, the wait will be worth while.
 3 CaseyJones 06/09/2009 Report this place 
If you want quality (no tartan tat) then this is the place to go. Down at Leith this unassuming establishment will get you fully kitted out. I splashed out and went for the day lovat jacket, waistcoat, plus kilt. It is handmade and fitted to your size (leaving plenty of room too for when you get on and fill out a bit!).

Great service and while you do pay for the quality - it was an enjoyable experience and I was fully kilted out for my wedding day. They also made a couple of ties out of the kilt tartan off-cuts.
 4 CaseyJones 06/09/2009 Report this place 
A lovely wee bar and always quiet. Good place for a coffee and a read of the papers during the day.
 4 ahc 06/09/2009 Report this place 
Good food, good staff, good prices. What more do you want?
 4 ahc 06/09/2009 Report this place 
A big soulless barn of a place. It is one of life&apos;s great mysteries why this franchise shed is always busy when the likes of Blackfriars and Bar 91 are only a stones throw away.
 1 ahc 06/09/2009 Report this place 
Last time I was in here the music was fantastic, dj playing everything from obscure disco to Balearic beats. The big screen was showing old Betty Boop and Popeye cartoons. The draught lager was excellent and the atmosphere great.

The place looks amazing too. Apparently the design is based on Jeunet&amp;Caro&apos;s film The City of Lost Children. Smart, fun and all the cooler for not taking itself seriously.
 5 ahc 06/09/2009 Report this place 
This is, in my opinion, the best Indian restaurant in Stirling.

Located right in the centre of town, this small but welcoming restaurant has a wide range of menu choice.

The chicken chasni, which is a medium spiced creamy sweet and sour dish, is my favourite dish and one I would recommend.

Price is reasonable, about £8 a meal and then you have your rice and drinks on top of that.
 4 Pam14 07/09/2009 Report this place 
My family stayed here the night of my graduation and we ate from the graduation set menu in their restaurant.

The food was faultless and reasonable compared to other graduation offers around. I had sea bass and crème Brule and all family members enjoyed every course.

Service was quick as well, which was nice after a busy day.

The hotel is decorated in a traditional Scottish style. It had the feeling of an old building but still had modern bathrooms and clean rooms.

The hotel has special graduation deals on around June. Although it was a little expensive, it is a nice place to go on a special occasion.
 4 Pam14 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Great place for a Sunday pub lunch, good local food and pleasant surroundings, nice outside courtyard when the weather&apos;s fit to sit outside. Hmm mmm!
 5 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Great pub for good cocktails, nice surroundings. I&apos;d say more about the barmaids too, but guess this is a family website, still, great place to watch sports in with its plasma screens.
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Used to be good until it became one of those dratted &apos;Scream&apos; pubs - I guess that at least that means the drinks are cheap, but it&apos;s lost a lot of the atmosphere that would bring me to it in the first place.
 2 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Best pub jukebox in Aberdeen, plus some good gigs now and then - one for the rocker.
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Great place for Friday night drinks - good layout and selection of beverages, just what you need when hanging out with a bunch of friends.
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
One of best places for a regular pint or two, spacious interior and great service, highly recommended.
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Worth it just for those cocktails, and for seeing punters&apos; confused faces when they&apos;re unable to find out where the toilets are (I&apos;m not giving anything away). Great gothic exterior and interior, though they should really be playing for spooky organ music than cheesy chart tosh.
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Good city-centre location right at the Castlegate, and loads of space to accommodate friends (just a shame I don&apos;t have any). Handy spot for getting the bus home after too, just in case you&apos;re sensible enough to leave the car at home...
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Not too bad for a chain pub, decent and good for pre-club drinks.
 3 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Can you even call yourself an Aberdeen Uni student if you&apos;ve never been here? And are Robert Gordons students allowed to step foot in the place? (I&apos;d hope not.) A must for those pretending to study psychology while instead downing a jar or two on mummy and daddy&apos;s generous weekly allowance...
 4 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Don&apos;t think even having a lobotomy would explain why you&apos;d want to go to this place. For me this is hell - if I even suddenly find myself trapped in the place I&apos;ll know that second before (in the real world) I must have been hit by a bus or something. Avoid.
 1 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Dino&apos;s doesn&apos;t look appealing from outside, but the food is worth braving an entrance for.

Granted, it&apos;s been a few years since I was here, but I would definitely go back. Reasonable fare at reasonable prices.
 3 Grant87 07/09/2009 Report this place 
A bit pretentious, but you come to expect that in the Merchant City. No complaints about the food though and they do an excellent lunchtime deal for around the £5 mark.
 3 Grant87 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Good place for catching live music, layout certainly helps have a good view of whatever&apos;s going on.
 3 Michael 07/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree with Glasgow Girl! The Christmas showing of It&apos;s a Wonderful Life is brilliant!

The GFT is the best Cinema in town.
 5 bambam 07/09/2009 Report this place 
This is indeed a big beast of a Cinema but it&apos;s dirty and tacky. Being a main stream cinema, it shows everything you would want but it&apos;s not as good as the GFT for a viewing experience.
 4 bambam 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Firewater used to be good 3 years ago. These days it&apos;s jaded and tired.
 3 bambam 07/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a good boozer to watch a Rangers game in. Best to go down in full colours for the best experience.

This place is dark, dingy, damp and dirty... but that&apos;s why it&apos;s good!
 3 bambam 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Good sausage suppers and smarter looking than your average chippy.
 3 topspin 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Busy and basic. Not exactly the best pub in town, but definitely one for the locals.
 3 topspin 07/09/2009 Report this place 
An old classic in Aviemore. A decent pint of beer. The food leaves a lot to be desired, unless you desire unimaginative, stodgy pub grub.

Trades a bit on it&apos;s position but still one of the best.

The Tartan Army meet here and there&apos;s always sport on.
 3 topspin 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Sells all manner of things you need but didn&apos;t think you wanted. Got a good fondue set there.
 3 topspin 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Really nice food and well placed for a night on Ayr&apos;s slightly cracked tiles. Good for a Sunday afternoon.
 3 Toots 07/09/2009 Report this place 
A real old boozer. No airs or graces and i doubt if the decor has changed since Tam himself pulled the first pint. That&apos;s why it&apos;s great.
 4 Toots 07/09/2009 Report this place 
One of Ayr&apos;s nicer bars. Good menu and a decent crowd. A good bit better than a lot of its contemporaries around there.
 3 Toots 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Rough and ready. A real Ayr pub. It&apos;s a long dark drink of bar.
 3 Toots 07/09/2009 Report this place 
I love Greggs. It&apos;s great. Steak bake and a tuna crunch. All your vitamins in one paper wrapped bundle of joy.
 5 Toots 07/09/2009 Report this place 
You buy yer maw underwear?
 1 bambam 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Cheap, nasty and tacky! Head to AP for lingerie, buy your toys online.
 2 bambam 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Great location and much expanded and developed from the old booths and sawdust on the floor days. Haven&apos;t tried the food but looks good.
 4 Shaba 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Absolute joke. The manager can&apos;t even get it together to order enough bread and milk to last the day. They also magically manage to have no staff working at key times - like 8:30am when people are nipping in for breakfast stuff / packed lunches etc.
 1 Shaba 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Four Nations pizza - need I say any more?
 4 Grant87 07/09/2009 Report this place 
Bambam is right on the money.

Firewater was a cracking pub when it first opened. Good booze and good tunes. These days its turned into a lame, tired, dark pit filled with kids with silly hair and tight trousers.

Best avoided.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 07/09/2009 Report this place 
This is not a friendly place. I had been in all day with a friend of mine, then my girlfriend at the time showed up.

The bouncer refused to let her in because there &quot;was a function on&quot;.

I spoke to 3 members of the bar staff who knew nothing about the so-called function.

This place is pretentious and smarmy, and only really a venue to visit if you work in the local area and have NOWHERE else to go.
 2 TheLittlerich 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Not exactly being a vodka connoisseur I wouldn&apos;t have tripped over myself to go to a place offering over 40 different flavours (I think it was that much, the memory gets hazy), but oh my, what oh what was I missing! Loads of fun types, though a couple of recommendations: Irn Bru and Lemon Sherbert. Oh, and for goodness sake stay away from the curry one...
 4 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Great Tapas-style Indian menu, as a vegetarian provides some great options and combinations. Doesn&apos;t have a drinks licence which could be considered unfortunate but is something I actually quite like (keeps out the drunken plebs), plus the Mango Lassi&apos;s more than make up for it... The takeaway part is good too, but I&apos;d recommend sitting in for the full experience.
 5 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
I&apos;d disagree with &apos;fancy shoes at silly prices&apos;. OK, there are choices for the rich and/or fashion brave, but there&apos;s also plenty on offer if you&apos;re looking for some good, trendy shoes or trainers that will last a fair while.
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Seating is limited but it&apos;s a good place to chill out if you&apos;re out during the week. It&apos;s also a top place to watch the Scotland matches when they&apos;re on.
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s definitely all about the music. You have to be one of the crowd to fit in here and it&apos;s not a top choice for an essential Glasgow night out. Jukebox is legendary though and there&apos;s always more often than not some form of live music downstairs at night time.
 3 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Cocktails in buckets! Not that I&apos;m into that kind of thing, of course...
 3 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
This used to look like and feel like an absolute dive. Now it&apos;s been given a smarter look from the exterior, but you can&apos;t change the clientele. Woeful, but cheap.
 1 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
For students - especially those in their first year - this is an absolutely essential venue to try. It&apos;s geared 100% towards students and is open til around 3am almost every night. There&apos;s always some sort of activity going on and it&apos;s never empty.

Being a student venue, the drinks are very cheap, although the quality isn&apos;t up to much. But if you&apos;re a student, who cares? As long as it leaves you feeling merry.

The food ain&apos;t bad for what it is either.
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Appalling place. Sticky carpets, leering old men...and women, I could go on. Yes the drinks are cheap but it&apos;s even more soulless and confused than a Wetherspoons.
 1 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Food snobs beware. But if you&apos;re looking for an affordable lunch, like Chinese and have a big appetite, then why not?
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
This was an Edwards chain bar previously, much like a Wetherspoons but without the acquired droves.

It&apos;s an OK pit stop if you&apos;re making your way along Sauchiehall Street&apos;s bars. You probably won&apos;t find yourself staying for more than one though.
 2 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Wrong, wrong, wrong, wrong, wrong. Perhaps it is just my luck, but every Blue Lagoon I have ever had the misfortune of eating out of has been utterly dreadful.

Goodness knows how it became so popular, but its growth seems to made it rest on its laurels. The chips are soggy, before you&apos;ve added anything to them.

I&apos;d review more of their &apos;delicacies&apos;, but my mind is blocking out the trauma.
 1 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
A basement venue with live music every night of the week. It&apos;s also one of a select few bars up this side of town that&apos;s open into the wee small hours.

They have cheap drinks up until 7-8pm, after which the prices sky rocket. But for live - normally indie - music, it&apos;s a definite must-be.
 3 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Student central in Edinburgh, this is in the Scream chain of bars, which means if you&apos;re a student, you can get discounted food and drink.

The main action can be found downstairs, with plenty comfy seats, a pool table and a basement venue that hosts gigs every now and then.

There&apos;s no mobile phone reception down in the Tron either, so it&apos;s a good hideaway!
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a great lunchtime venue, with good and cheap food. Good drinks selection as well and near Dundee Uni and the shops.
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Lomond just refitted my shower room. They did a fantastic job from start to finish and project managed the whole thing - I just had to select which fittings I liked. Vera in the office looked after us well and, although they didn&apos;t give us the most competitive quote, they weren&apos;t far off.
 5 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
The restaurant here offers a good, reasonably-priced and varied menu to suit all tsates. It gets very busy, so I would suggest you book in advance.

The bar is great, with both proper tables&amp;chairs as well as &apos;comfy&apos; sofa areas. They have pub quizzes and music nights as well as showing football on big screens. Avoid on a Hampden matchday, but otherwise I&apos;d recommend.

The hotel is also very good and is my dad&apos;s hotel of choice when he comes to vist as it&apos;s within walking distance of my house. Rooms are clean and modern and even the single ones are spacious. It&apos;s ideal for anyone visiting the Southside of Glasgow and a 10-15 minute bus ride into the city centre.
 4 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Got to love the Bier Halles, this one has a great vibe, the red drapes and spare lighting giving it a bit of a Twin Peaks vibe (though unfortunately not nearly so freaky). And yep, the two for one pizzas are great when you&apos;re wanting a few drinks but feeling a little peckish...
 4 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
A prefectly nice, if slightly dated, &apos;tartan&apos; hotel with some front rooms with views overlooking the park. Please note that this is not in the city centre. Also, be careful to confirm your booking before arriving - on two occasions I have had family members book rooms here only to be told that the hotel didn&apos;t have their booking/be advised that the hotel would be closed during their stay and they would be moved elsewhere.
 2 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Not too bad, especially for before a gig at the ABC or the Garage, though have to say I&apos;ve always found it a bit too crowded for my liking at the weekends, not one of my favourite locales on Sauchiehall Street...
 2 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the best garden centres in the south Glasgow area. It stocks a large range of plants, garden accessories and pet items. It also has a fab coffee shop/restaurant, easy access&amp;has ample parking and is on the edge of Rouken Glen park so you can explore that after your shop.
 4 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Simple and good value, with friendly and very tolerant (of the numerous kids we had with us) service - and the food was great. We initially didn&apos;t get the &quot;tapas&quot; thing and thought portions were pretty light. In the end we had ordered just the right amount for our two family group. Some of the dishes were exceptional. Drumstick lollies at the end as well.
 4 Shaba 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Open until 11pm for booze - yes please! Saved me on those occasions when I&apos;ve been past 10pm and worried I&apos;ll die from thirst... Oh, and nice selection of beverages too, some very decent Port there!
 4 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Lovely handmade sandwiches, soup, lunches and cakes. Delightful service and even a home/office delivery service. Excellent!
 5 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Definitely not all about the music when £2 White Russians and Sleazy Burgers are around upstairs... Nice selection of beers and ciders as well nowadays, great to have some Addlestones now and then.
 5 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Have been here a few times for decent enough cafe food, but won&apos;t return again after I found that my toasted sandwich had green mould on it.
 1 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Friendly but tiny salon. Very reasonable prices. Just two stylists, so book early. Note, they don&apos;t accept card payments.
 4 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Sadly this is now closed down&amp;has become a dry cleaners!
 1 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Really good, friendly service. Much cheaper than the big brand servicing centres. They&apos;re always happy to help and, even with me being a girl who knows nothing about cars, don&apos;t ever feel they&apos;re trying to rip me off.
 5 garythesnail 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Reputable and high quality servicing and maintenance of our cars over the last few years - excellent customer service e.g. will drop you back at work / lend a car if available.
 4 Shaba 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Definitely looks better since it was refurbished, not too shabby.
 3 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Guess it is good to see live music promoted, just a shame it&apos;s in such a shabby fashion... and the less said about the rest of the place the better.
 2 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
If you&apos;re visiting the city centre during the day, this is the sensible place to park. It&apos;s not very expensive and it beats having to drive around endlessly looking for an on-street space, which you will then pay through the nose for.
 4 Grant87 08/09/2009 Report this place 
no longer there ....!
 1 CaseyJones 08/09/2009 Report this place 
ugh!

Great for young people out on the pull. Bamboo is a bit of a meat market. If you want to go then put on the skimpiest outfit you can and you&apos;ll get past the bouncers.

I worked there once, and the door staff turned me away... on my first night I was working there! ha ha!
 2 TheLittlerich 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Good food, great for lazy Sundays when you can have a meal then wander round Kelvingrove Park after, providing the weather doesn&apos;t make that prospect as appealing as another Pete and Katie Christmas single.
 4 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Decent pub quiz and not too bad all in all - though it still rankles that they&apos;d name a bar after a stoner from a Coen Brothers movie. It&apos;s a bit like naming a leisure centre after one of the characters from Trainspotting.
 4 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Armstrongs is an Edinburgh institution - from classic suits to sporrans, kilts and military jackets etc.
 5 Shaba 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Not exactly the classiest locale in the world but good atmosphere and the odd gem of a live gig now and then...
 3 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Agreed, good place, but make sure you visit near the start of payday, lest you bankrupt yourself for the rest of the month...
 3 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Not the worst place in the world, but with the variety of bars nearby think there&apos;s better places to wander into when the choice comes down to it.
 3 Michael 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Its all about the ingredients … Put great ingredients in, treat it with love and respect and the end product is fantastic and that in a nutshell is what KOOLBA offers … So, if you want GREAT Indian food and you also like grilled meat than Koolba is the place for you … You will not be disappointed … Try the Chicken Chat appetizer with a Makhsoos entrée with rice and Nan bread, that’s my personal favourite … ENJOY!!!!
 5 AJK 08/09/2009 Report this place 
My personal favourite is the upstairs (rather than downstairs) where you can have good food with your drinks in a relaxed and informal environment … If I am not mistaken, they have a weekly wine club, not sure on what day but it looks like fun!!
 4 AJK 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Can it be, I am the first too review this!!! BEST HAMBURGERS IN GLASGOW.. FULL STOP!!! For extra hot, try it with the Chilli … It also goes down very well with a San Miguel pint …
 5 AJK 08/09/2009 Report this place 
You get a great price for the a very nice room especially if you face the clyde ... The only problem is that there is very little to do in the area if you are not going to the SECC or visting STV or the BBC.
 4 AJK 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Very average ... Glasgow has a lot better Indian Food to offer ... If you don&apos;t know better and you are from out of town then India Quay is where you end up if you happen to be in the Lancefield Quay area ... It does the job but you would have missed a golden opportunity to eat GREAT Indian food in Glasgow .. Try Koolba, Balbirs or Mother India to name a few!!!
 2 AJK 08/09/2009 Report this place 
a REAL GEM! The food is excellent and the bar/restaurant is very nice … Unfortunately the location is not great and you will need to either drive their (they do have free parking) or take a taxi … I would not walk there but once you are there it is worth it!!
 4 AJK 08/09/2009 Report this place 
Amazing place - bought my first &apos;black tie&apos; suit from here (back in the days when I went to 21st birthday parties - long ago ...). No matter what time of day you go there is a wide range of customers - some amazing antique costumes on display - almost like visiting the museum.
 3 CaseyJones 09/09/2009 Report this place 
Hidden above a jewlellers shop, this place is a real gem! (no pun intended!)

It is nice and cosy, and feels very relaxed. You can soak up the work of Charles Rennie Mackintosh whilst you are there, and there is even a small exhibition upstairs.

The staff are extremely helpful and friendly, the food is great and the prices are very reasonable!
 5 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
I am still surprised with this place. Seemingly NEVER closed, they take prescriptions and also provide over-the-counter medicines.

They have wheelchair / zimmer frame / mobility scooters on sale (I have never needed any so couldn&apos;t tell you any more), and they seem helpful enough.
 5 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
Me and an ex went with her kids. It cost us a fortune (about £50 for 2 games of bowling for us and 2 kids).

There was a bar available, and quite cheap.

If there is nothing else to do, try here. Otherwise go for a stroll along the beach.
 2 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty much the same as all amusements in all sea-side towns. Flashing lights, noise and the ability to get through cash like there is no tomorrow.

Devoid of any kind of atmosphere. Same as everywhere else.
 2 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
This is about as entertaining as they come when it comes to amusement arcades. A fairly large choice of slots to put your money in, some go beep and some go bing bing.

At least they have some arcade games to play as well. See if you can beat my score on Time Crisis!
 3 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
One word - AMAZING!!! Went with my girlfriend and the kids and we had the best day!

A huge variety of animals to see and places to visit. Oh, and make sure you take a camera! We ended up with over 700 pictures of the day!

Prices are not bad at all, especially considering you can drive through the safari part as many times (and as slow) as you like.

There is plenty of places where the kids can play. A HUGE tree house that is wicked (Yes, I admit I was playing in it as well...)

You can get really up close so some amazing animals. The sea lion show is a MUST (it&apos;s hilarious) and so it the chimpanzee boat tour.

We are going again, and this time we&apos;re going to take stuff for a BBQ (there are grills provided).

If you want to save money take a picnic. Plenty of places you can sit and eat if you don&apos;t fancy paying for the food. (Although the burgers are delicious!)

5 stars is simply not enough! I&apos;d give it 10!
 5 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
This is usually where I go to get my shoes.

It&apos;s simple and fairly inexpensive.
 4 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
This is not a bad place to eat. It&apos;s good if you&apos;re pushed for time and are looking for a gran-n-go lunch.

Try their steak bakes or the chicken pasties.
 3 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
Another greggs-like company that seem to have jumped on the grab-n-go bakery bandwagon.

However, they do make some nice food. I prefer this to Greggs.

Their food is more home-made and quite tasty!
 4 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty basic mini-spuermarket but they sell cheap frozen food. A fairly good variety, and they do have some good offers on most of the time.
 4 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
Pretty basic, but ok if you want a newspaper, bottle of coke or a packet of cigarettes.
 3 TheLittlerich 09/09/2009 Report this place 
@BGT babe... You&apos;ve never been chatted up in yer life! And don&apos;t even pretend that my band aren&apos;t the best band in the world.

Mad fer it.

Oh, this place is rubbish. The only people you will find in here are the rubbish bands, their mates and their mates, mates.
 1 bambam 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Don&apos;t forget you can get Bucky by the glass here.

Mad fer it.
 3 bambam 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Good place to watch the football. Cheap booze, plenty of seats and a decent enough feed when you need something to soak up the beer.

Also hosts the Glasgow Arsenal Supporters Club meetups.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
A handy addition to the Gt Western Rd pub roster. Great pizza&apos;s at 2 for 1 all through the week and a great selection of foreign beers.

As bambam says.. it makes a nice change to be able to go to Bierhalle thats above ground.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Great selection of Whiskys and a nice place to pop into for a quiet pint amidst the madness of a Glasgow city center night out.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the best pubs in the west end. Friendly atmosphere, decent pints and plenty of whiskys.

Can be a wee bit dark inside, but they do let dogs in.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Big, grand place, not sure if its a chain pub but its got that air about it. Food is average. Pints are average. Good for the football or rugby though as its size lends well to packing folk in and creating a good atmosphere.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice place for a pint. Play decent music. The food is fantastic.

Oh and there&apos;s also a great venue upstairs where everyone who&apos;s anyone will have played at the start of their career.
 5 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Decent bar that serves a fine pint of Addleston&apos;s. Not expensive and has a relaxed atmosphere.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
The food is fantastic and if you can get a seat outside on a sunny Sunday afternoon its a great place to while away the hours.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Bring the big bucks cos this place is damned expensive. The interior is fantastic and the beer is great but it&apos;s definitely a payday only haunt.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Bit of a labyrinth inside. Make sure you have your phone on you cos its easy to get lost. Its a bit of a haven for the older crowd heading out at the weekend. Nothing really exciting about it at all and despite its attempts at being a bit different it feels quite soulless.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Feels like you&apos;ve wandered into a pub somewhere in the middle of the Highlands. Dogs lying about, old men singing randomly, someone breaking out a fiddle and a fine selection of whisky make for a great experience.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Serve a great pint of cheap Guinness. Bar staff are friendly and the locals are a barrel of laughs when you get talking to them.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
The Vale is a great no nonsense bar - perfect for a swift pint before heading off east via Queen Street.
 4 Shaba 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Poor mans KFC. The chips are tasteless and the chicken is bland.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Top place for watching action movies with lots of special effects. The huge screen and surround sound make you feel like you are in the movie.
 5 Charlie 10/09/2009 Report this place 
Took our wee boy to see G-Force, and was laughing as he kept ducking as something leapt out of the screen! Brilliant!
 5 TheLittlerich 11/09/2009 Report this place 
I really enjoy visiting this cinema! Although in the centre of town, it still feels like an out of town experience once you walk through the front doors. The queues are fairly quickly cleared, even when it is busy. (oh, and it does get VERY busy in the evenings and at weekends!) The 3D is good and sound is all Dolby Digital surround sound!

Free magazine available in the fayer with details on ALL the films out and coming soon. (This is very handy to help you pick the film you want to see).

The prices are not bad (I found them to be cheaper than the Odeon) although cinema prices are not what they used to be. For the best value for money, use Orange Wednesdays (text FILM to 241 from an Orange mobile phone) to get 2 for 1 on tickets.

The only con is if you haven&apos;t got a head for heights... If you have, avoid the lifts!
 4 TheLittlerich 11/09/2009 Report this place 
It could be so much better than it is...
 2 TheLittlerich 11/09/2009 Report this place 
I just had the worst experience in my rock and roll life ever in Lebowskis.

I opted for the Veggie Burger after it was recommended by the bar staff. 35 minutes later our food arrived. My veggie burger came with a mushroom and an aubergine.

The rest of the burger, the pepper, tomato, onions and goats cheese was on top of my mates beef burger!

I wont be hurrying back here anytime soon.
 1 bambam 11/09/2009 Report this place 
Brilliant Italian restaurant with the choice of a &apos;posh&apos; area downstairs with a massive menu or a more &apos;bistro&apos; feel on the ground floor. Personally, I prefer the more relaxed and informal bistro part. Fab pizzas, including a low-cal version and amazing pasta. I am a regular here&amp;have never had a bad meal. The puddings are also brilliant - if you have any room left as the main courses offer good-sized portions. They also do take-away pizza&amp;pasta. Prices are reasonable for a pizza/pasta restaurant but excellent considering the quality&amp;freshness of the food.
 5 garythesnail 13/09/2009 Report this place 
Fine if you fancy a dance and don&apos;t mind being confused about where you are!
 2 Munchie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice atmosphere and always try the Pride cocktail!
 3 Munchie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
lovely bar, very nice atmosphere.
 4 Munchie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Even though this shop in on the High Street (Royal Mile) it does not fall into the tartan tat trap that other &apos;scottish&apos; shops do further up the street.

This is the best whisky shop I have ever been to, staff are friendly and knowledgeable, even on rum. If you want a rare cask whisky then you can get a quality malt for under £50 easily.
 4 CaseyJones 15/09/2009 Report this place 
I went here and got more than I expected. My burger had my mates toppings in it too, which was great for me but not for him as he ordered a veggie burger and only got a mushroom and aubergine.

I found the service to be very slow, over 40 mins for a burger aint good. Dont go here if you are popping out for a bite to eat at lunch time unless you get long lunches.
 2 Charlie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Cheap stale bread with the wrong filling. Not a good experience at all. Asked for tuna and got chicken, I wont be back
 1 Charlie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
This place is now called Rosco&apos;s and serves traditional Scottish food. Its not too bad, the staff are very friendly and the food is reasonalbe but a bit expensive.
 3 Charlie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Got food poisoning here when I ate the balmoral chicken. Its a shame because I had been a few times in the past and the food was good but I wont be back. The bar downstairs is good though and they server bud on tap.
 2 Charlie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Not the best Sainsbury&apos;s around. Its a bit scabby and I would only go there to get some cheap sweeties before going to the pictures.

I Wouldn&apos;t bother doing the weekly shop here as there&apos;s a better Sainsbury&apos;s in the Kingsgate retail market.
 3 Charlie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Bit of a bipolar place. During the day it&apos;s a nice quiet old mans boozer, but on a Friday and Saturday night (i&apos;m guessing due to its proximity to the Tunnel) it becomes a ned fest - packed with Glasgow&apos;s worst in their shiniest shirts and shortest skirts wailing badly at the karaoke.
 3 MarvinSaysBelieve 15/09/2009 Report this place 
If you do manage to navigate the industrial estate and clydeside express way you may be unlucky enough to find this dump. A feeezing cold shell warmed in one corner by what looks like a jet engine.

Seen my mates band here a couple of times and thats the only reason i&apos;d go again. Truly terrible,
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Littelrich, if you can get your car into the &quot;drive through&quot; without being arrested I would like to see this. This McD&apos;s is in the shopping mall.
 1 Charlie 15/09/2009 Report this place 
My nostalgia tells me that this was a good night out when I was younger but my head says it&apos;s always been a dump.

Packed with students and playing terrible terrible music - this place is best avoided unless you&apos;re under the age of 20 and are so drunk you wont notice the sticky floors and students vomit.
 2 MarvinSaysBelieve 15/09/2009 Report this place 
Gone and hopefully soon forgotten. Glasgow&apos;s finest east end girls squeezed into cow girl costumes. Not a pretty site.
 1 MarvinSaysBelieve 15/09/2009 Report this place 
A nice cosy pub but drinks are quite expensive.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Used to eat&amp;drink here often until the framed spiders etc on the wall started to freak me out!
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
A nice cosy pub where you can get good value food.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
A little hidden gem with a cosy atmosphere. They only seem to serve traditional drinks though&amp;popular spirits.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
You will see a real mix of clientele in this pub! I always enjoy their music&amp;range of drinks.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Good for food&amp;drinks but always seem to have the football on the big screen...which isn&apos;t my thing!
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Good value food&amp;drinks. Went here for the first time recently&amp;will definitely go back.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Went in here recently although it&apos;s changed it&apos;s name. Not half as good as Frankensteins in Edinburgh but still had a good selection of music.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
If you&apos;re not a student, you stand out like a sore thumb in here! Good value food&amp;drinks though.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
The James Bond theme playing in the toilets gets extremely boring! A bit of a mix in here...cheesey tunes downstairs&amp;r n&apos; b upstairs. Usually very busy&amp;entry is free.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
I used to work here when it first opened&amp;it was a novelty, however, it soon became a place to be avoided!
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
I used to often go here but I went in recently (aged 24)&amp;felt like a pensioner! The clientele is very very young!
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Not the classiest joint!
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Very popular bar...good for cocktails.
 4 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Only been here once but not really my scene.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Ok for cheap food&amp;drink.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Good for cheap food&amp;vino!
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Probably most popular with students. Used to go here often.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
More of a man&apos;s pub.
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
I liked the music&amp;atmosphere in this place but they have recently changed the menu (not so good)&amp;I think it is going downhill due to it&apos;s location.
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
A bit of an old man&apos;s pub.
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Good for lunch or for drinks at night. A mix of ages&amp;good music.
 4 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Only been in once but wouldn&apos;t rush back. Ok for a quiet drink.
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Good food&amp;drinks offers. Quite loud music playing at all times which wouldn&apos;t suit everyone if they are out for a meal but it is a very popular place.
 5 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
More suitable for the older crowd!
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
I like the atmosphere in here. A good mix of people, music&amp;plenty of seats!
 5 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Haven&apos;t been in here for a while. Would imagine that it wouldn&apos;t attract the most classy clientele these days.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Went in here for a drink one Saturday afternoon&amp;it was empty.
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
This has now changed to &apos;The Rig&apos;. Still full of quite rough customers! There&apos;s dance music upstairs&amp;pop downstairs usually.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Attracts the very young crowd&amp;is often packed full so you can&apos;t move!
 3 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
I really like it here...a good selection of cocktails.
 5 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
This has now changed to &apos;Prohibition&apos;. Good atmosphere with music, a cocktail menu&amp;a small dance floor.
 4 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
I preferred this place when it was &apos;The Ministry&apos;. Still ok for a dance though!
 4 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
A good selection of cocktails&amp;reasonably priced food.
 4 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
A family orientated pub. Good for food.
 4 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
There&apos;s no music in this pub&amp;therefore, not the best atmosphere.
 2 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
An old man&apos;s pub with no female toilets!
 1 Dolly 16/09/2009 Report this place 
Great place. Good selection of curries, all of which I tried were excellent.

Recommended if you&apos;re lucky enough to find yourself in Peebles.
 4 MarvinSaysBelieve 17/09/2009 Report this place 
I love this place! It&apos;s a must for every trip home...not sure how much non-locals would enjoy it though...
 4 Munchie 17/09/2009 Report this place 
Had really good service from this shop - and at a reasonable price too! From the time of choosing the fabric to the blinds being installed in the conservatory was about a week.
 5 Amelie 18/09/2009 Report this place 
Good place for Sunday lunch at a reasonable price. I prefer to eat in the bar, rather than the dining room because the dining area is quite &apos;stuffy&apos;.

The menu is pretty varied and covers everything from traditional Scots fare to curry.
 4 Amelie 18/09/2009 Report this place 
This end of Dumbarton Road didn&apos;t use to offer decent places to eat, but times are changing! I went here to eat one saturday lunchtime having heard good things about it. Strangely, it doesn&apos;t open till 1 but we got there before and wandered around the empty restaurant with no sign of life anywhere. So we helped ourselves to menus and eventually someone appeared.

At lunchtime there was a choice between a set number of tapas dishes from a limited range or as many as you want from the a la carte. We went for the latter. My favourite of the lot was the calamares - absolutely delicious.

The overall standard of the food and the service was excellent. My one bugbear was the table. The top of it is mosaic-like and seemed to be not the cleanest. In fact, had to ask for the table to be wiped down and as the waitress cleaned she made a comment like the mosaic tops weren&apos;t the easiest to clean.

But I&apos;d certainly go back. Really enjoyed the tapas I had and would like to try more another time.
 4 Amelie 18/09/2009 Report this place 
Love this restaurant - it&apos;s informal yet has great food.

There&apos;s a pre-theatre menu which is really good value, but find I get tempted off on to the a la carte sometimes too which can be a bit more pricey.

But the fish or seafood here is always good.
 4 Amelie 18/09/2009 Report this place 
Love, love their ice cream! Just thinking about it brings memories of summer barbecues, where the ice-cream for the caramelised bananas just had to come from here.
 4 Amelie 18/09/2009 Report this place 
had some really great meals here, in the restaurant downstairs. Altho&apos; it&apos;s effectively underground, the lighting and decor create a really welcoming environment.

The food&apos;s always beautifully presented.
 5 Amelie 18/09/2009 Report this place 
Relaxed,bright atmosphere and friendly staff make this a very good place for lunch or dinner. The menu specialises in seafood and there is a small fish stand for buying a wide range of seafood to take home. Very tasty!
 4 Amelie 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Radio Taxis is a traditional (and busy) stopping point from many a night out in Perth. It&apos;s near some decent pubs like the Twa Tams and the taxis generally don&apos;t take long to arrive even at midnight when it&apos;s packed out.
 4 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
&quot;You can&apos;t get fitter than a Kwik-Fit fitter,&quot; or whatever the slogan was. &quot;They&apos;re the boys to trust.&quot;

How apt - the tyre prices are keen, they&apos;re quick and honest. Only problem is a lack of nearby public transport if you have to leave the car there.
 4 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
These bakers hail from Dundee but don&apos;t let that put you off. Their rolls and cakes are actually pretty good, and a &quot;Goodies Roll&quot; is almost as legendary in some offices as a Murrays Pie (see the other review for more). Better than Greggs at least.
 3 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Support your local newspaper! The PA is the town&apos;s mouthpiece, and even though it&apos;s only got about 3 writers left (and most of the production seems to be done in Hamilton or something) it&apos;s still the top dog in Perth. Gordon Bannerman&apos;s reports on Saints are rightly legendary.
 5 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
A good place to pass a couple of hours with the kids. Always a constant turnover of exhibitions and artefacts, with a particularly keen eye on local history.
 4 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
George&apos;s shop has been on the go for years and hasn&apos;t changed all that much - but then why should it? If you want a copy of the Sun, 20 Silk Cut, a bottle of Tizer and a fine selection of adult magazines, McConnell&apos;s is your place.
 4 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
This place should be classified as an antique - it&apos;s a fine family-run tea shop and restaurant. The bruschetta is superb, and I&apos;m told the bacon rolls would make you greet, they&apos;re so good.
 5 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Went to this shop on the day it opened. Can&apos;t believe it&apos;s still open now; make what you want of that comment.
 3 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Don&apos;t be put off by the name or the location, it&apos;s a good simple cafe with decent prices and excellent service. Ignore where the profits end up and stop there for a cup of tea.
 5 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
It&apos;s not an Indian at all, it&apos;s one of the oldest established Chinese restaurants in Scotland, the hub of the local Chinese community. And a good place too, especially for a quick business lunch.
 4 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
A good Chinese restaurant but I&apos;ve never been lucky enough to eat Chinese food here! Had a steak a few times and it was absolutely superb. Recommended.
 3 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Don&apos;t know where the restaurant name on this site came from, it&apos;s &quot;Cafe Breizh&quot; and always has been. A lovely French restaurant which also specialises in traditional Neapolitan cuisine, with a wood-burning pizza oven.

Sadly my last visit co-incided with not getting a main course delivered to the table (for whatever reason) but the food remains superb - the Haggis Crepe is fantastic.
 4 IBM 19/09/2009 Report this place 
The food&apos;s great but the service is typically French - snooty, aloof and occasionally rude :-)
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
This is a super-pub, with a large &quot;American diner&quot; style restaurant (most of the seats are booths with private TVs, Playstations, etc) and a typical New York style menu. Upstairs is a large nightclub, and it doubles as the town&apos;s first sports bar - football on every screen.

And for all that, it&apos;s not that great to be honest, far too much like the pub equivalent of Tesco.
 2 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
This place is supposed to be great, but I&apos;ll be brutally honest and say that on my first and only visit, I ate about three grains of horrible rice and sent the rest back. Wouldn&apos;t be in a hurry to re-visit.
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
The Grill closed as a restaurant in 1992 as I recall. It&apos;s now a pub called &quot;The Retreat&quot;. And not a very good one.
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Patrick&apos;s hasn&apos;t been around for some time. It&apos;s now a pub called Rocablu, with an accompanying restaurant called The Thai.
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Not sure if this place is open these days, but it used to be quite good. Posh food served in a fairly laid-back, down-to-earth setting, with live mood music played on a Saturday night.
 3 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Had a meal here once and ended up getting the bill torn in half, it was that bad. To be fair it was in 1998 and it hadn&apos;t long opened, but it&apos;s safe to say I&apos;ve not been back, even though my mate was the chef in there for a while!
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
This is actually a fish and chip shop, and a damn good one. The fish is always cooked to order and of course there&apos;s a retail park (with a huge car park) over the road, where you can dump the motor while you wait. They even do fish in breadcrumbs, which is a rare one these days.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
A farm shop which specialises in good whole food (not sure if it&apos;s organic or not) and a wee bit pretentious if I&apos;m honest. If you want a baked tattie dressed with 101 things when you asked for cheese and beans - and fancy a rural setting while you eat it, this place will do you fine. Their ginger loaf is magnificent too.
 3 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
One of my favourite watering holes in Scotland. It&apos;s a very friendly local pub, serving both chain-pub beer and decent ales, set in the grounds of Linlithgow Station. Watch out for the wee toy train going back and forth in the eaves above the pub!
 5 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
A lovely boozer and almost worth a stop-off in Linlithgow on the way somewhere else. Good selection of beer and a convivial atmosphere.
 5 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
If you&apos;ve got a boot fetish then you&apos;ll be in heaven here. It&apos;s a posh shoe shop for those who want a bit more than Clarks can offer, never mind &quot;Shoe Zone&quot;.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Closed some time ago, but when it was open, Actionwear straddled two camps - ski-ing and outdoor equipment (where its prices couldn&apos;t really compete with Milletts etc) and cutting edge fashion, especially shoes - which people didn&apos;t fancy in amongst hillwalking gear.
 2 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
A very old, family-run shoe shop. Being the wrong gender for the fayre on offer, it&apos;s not really my thing; but many an old dear has told me that they wouldn&apos;t get their baffies anywhere else.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
This isn&apos;t &quot;St Johnstone FC&quot; as such, it&apos;s a spin-off social club for supporters. A decent club with the usual bars, stage, and bags of room for a wee knees-up. Enjoy if someone will sign you in.
 3 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
I was refused entry here some time ago - they asked if I was 21. I was 22. The sign on the door said I had to be 18. They refused, I walked away, they lost a fortune. I got jaked somewhere else that night, so hell mend them.
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
A fine wee pub on the way to the train station - in fact other than the station bar itself, it&apos;s the last stop before your train home (obviously you don&apos;t want to live in Dundee).
 3 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Great pub in the town centre. It&apos;s large, with good service, a good choice of drink and plenty room to get a seat. Get in early at the weekend though.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice big pub with a good atmosphere, not entirely full of students and with bags of room to get a seat, or stand around admiring the abundant talent - whatever gender you&apos;re looking for.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Traditionally somewhere you&apos;d find footballers and associated riff-raff on a Saturday night, but it&apos;s a good pub all the same. Does some very good food too, and there&apos;s a huge garden out the back, available for functions and outdoor barbecues. Good place.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
The name isn&apos;t a guarantee of satisfaction by any means, and possibly a breach of trades descriptions. Best avoided, IMHO.
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
There are many things it&apos;s not. Worthy of 5 stars is certainly one such epithet that isn&apos;t warranted.
 1 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
The kind of place you&apos;ll find multiple stag and hen nights in the summer. As I found out whilst on a stag night. Not a bad pub but full of ne&apos;er-do&apos;wells.
 3 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Yet another good pub in Linlithgow - bit of a walk from the station if you&apos;re passing through, but still worth a look. It gets busy of a Friday night but it&apos;s got a good selection of booze, friendly service and plenty room. Good food too.
 4 Bob Flaps 19/09/2009 Report this place 
Three of us ate here one saturday night. It was really busy, all the tables full. Obviously a popular place for diners of all ages.

But even with a packed restaurant the service was quick and efficient.

The food itself was very good, altho one of the dishes wasn&apos;t as hot (temp-wise) as it might have been - perhaps it had been sitting out for too long. But everything else was great. We started with the Royal Thai platter of starters, a good choice as there were at least five different ones on the plate. For main courses we chose a lamb curry, a mixed seafood and a chilli chicken dish. All three were delicious, but our favourite was the lamb curry which had a wonderful creamy, fruity sauce.

One irritation was the potplants which are at each table - one of us kept getting jabbed by rather sharp leaves.

The other irritation was the ladies loo - only two available, and one was broken. So there was a bit of a long queue!

That said, the Royal Thai is a great choice for a reasonable, family celebration.
 4 Amelie 20/09/2009 Report this place 
havn&apos;t actually bought a dress from here....afterall i only intend on getting married once and bought my dress elsewhere....however the dresses in the window are always stunning. Upstairs their shoe and bag collection is suppposed to be great and i know many a person who has found something to finish off their wedding outfit here.
 4 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
funky and cool....if you&apos;re into brand names get yourself down here. May be overlooked due to its location but, well worth a look in... just down from the side door of Boots Chemist (up from the main entrance of the Bon Accord Centre.
 4 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
everyone knows this place...its the one with the tiger in the window. good food and atmosphere.....if ye like indian get on down..most of aberdeen have tried it so, why dont you
 4 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
i&apos;ll give them 5 stars for their meringues alone.. good crunch with a chewy bit in the middle....perfect.

i love meringues.....especially kelly of cults ones..perfect to top off those strawberries
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
if ye love a chicken pie ye love ross&apos;s..top notch.....awe is it wrong to drool.

oh, open well into the morning too...or at least it was........lovely
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
big selection of fresh cakes....do ye like a cream one, one with a hole, iced, fruit or a plain old scone....something for everyone.

simple favourites like macaroni cheese etc available to if your needing a quick lunch fix
 4 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
i prefer this holland and barrett to the larger one in Trinity (The Mall) centre. situated out the side door of Marks and Spencers it stokes everything your average health freak needs....It has options for the wheat/gluten/dairy free of us aswell and the staff are top notch.....love it
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
jennifer is fab.. have had my hair cut by her since i was little. She recently did my hair for my wedding and i loved it. She knew exactly what i wanted and even made it better than i had imagined..brilliant
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
sexy and hot....you&apos;ll love it here, especially if your young and flirty...great collection of gear for hen do&apos;s and fancy dress.

the shoes are so naughty their nice and the outfits are so hot their smoking.

love this shop....its wicked
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
your man...or woman (depending on your oreintation) will love you all the more for shopping here
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
so pleased we finally got an office franchise.....if its good enough for ferne cotton its good enough for me. great shoes and now its on our high street We no longer need to travel south or pay for delivery.

YEEEESSSS!
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
i like this bar alot and if you liked odonoghues you&apos;ll like it too.....enter form the side street down from the douglas hotel....enjoy the craic!!
 4 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
do not worry people........it says its closed for refurb but budz next door also said this and they never reopened.

chicago rock down the stairs was always good for a bit of cheese but this took it a tad far
 1 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
i liked it here and i&apos;m 25 but as i&apos;ve siad on chicagos reveiw i believe it wont reopen (it states at the mo closed for refurb but think thats it for chicago and jumpin jacks)
 3 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
this has been colsed for ages statin refurb but think we can all breath a sigh of relief and say its gone..

loved this place when it first opened but by the end it was rubbish..it made me feel old and i aint (possible underager prob) and definate ned magnet
 1 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
this aint been open since i was too young to drink there so at least 7years
 1 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
fun fun fun....the arcades are great (make sure you take lots of money tho) the bar upstairs is fab and for the kids the foam factory is a blast. their is also trampolines and a few other bits to keep the children entertained.
 5 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
where to start..there is rambo&apos;s for the kids (including the under 3&apos;s in a seperate area)- beware tho that there is no coffee shop inside it so bring magazines/papers/juice and nibbles to occupy yourself as the kids have their fun.

there is an indoor crazy golf which is fun and an outdoor pirate golf that is great when it aint in the minuses. theres the amusements, bowling a bar and rides outside..the rides aint the greatest and some have been there forever but the kids dont mind, they&apos;ll still have a blast
 4 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
oh its also one of the rare places you&apos;ll find a wimpy.. gosh, i love wimpy.....prices are crazy tho so hope you&apos;re feeling flush....if not head to burger king along the front or to skippers (perfect for the kids and a reasonable priced, yummy place to eat
 3 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
closed
 1 rufiovstinkerbel 20/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic fish and chips! You can use either the take-away or the restaurant. Queues for the take-away can be out the door, but they&apos;ve a good system for paying, ordering etc which seems to help things move quickly.

It&apos;s not just fish and chips either - you can get various pies and even salad!

The restaurant side is very popular with pensioners who are attracted by a great-value tea-time menu .
 4 Amelie 20/09/2009 Report this place 
Yes. Cadenhead&apos;s Whisky Shop sells the best value whisky in Edinburgh. Cask strength bottlings and staff who actually drink the stuff and make recommendations based on quality and value. Also do regular &quot;tastings&quot; in the Canon&apos;s Gait ( http://local.stv.tv/...nons-gait/ ) along the road.
 5 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Comfortable stop off point on the Canongate. Decent quality lunches.
 3 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Black Bo&apos;s is a small, friendly and relaxed bar (and restaurant) just off the High Street in the old town with a great selection of draught and bottled beers. Fine music via DJs in the corner and also has a small (very small) beer garden.
 5 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Convenient for the local attractions such as the parliament, Dynamic Earth and Holyrood Palace / Park. But have a bizarre no kids license - at least last time I was there. Also tends to be frequented by the rapidly diminishing ranks of Scotsman staff from across the road and various, politicians and their hangers on seeking an alternaive from the parliament.
 3 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Kebab Mahal is not really the place for a romantic dinner for two but specialises in no-nonsense curry and kebabs served to a broad range of customers fom all backgrounds. Very tasty and great value - simple formica tables, soft drinks from fridge and amazing freshly made bread - expect to queue day or night but moves quickly.
 5 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Taken over by James Thomson, owner of the capital’s celebrated Witchery, Prestonfield House is a five start hotel and restaurant (Rubarb) in a stunning location below Arthur&apos;s Seat near Duddingston Loch. Accolades include Scotland’s Most Romantic Hotel in the Hotel of the Year Awards.
 5 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Decent course, lovely views of the surrounding area - beware of driving your ball over the railway line on the fourth though!
 4 Michael 21/09/2009 Report this place 
This is on the High Street of nearby Conon Bridge, not Dingwall! But it&apos;s not too bad since its makeover, looking forward to the poker nights...
 3 Michael 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Best pub in Dingwall, bar none (won&apos;t be so cruel as to say there&apos;s little competition for the honour). Can be a bit busy at the weekends, but that in itself is good for catching up with old friends - especially on Christmas Eve, when the whole town seems to crowd in there!
 5 Michael 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Many folk reckon it lost it&apos;s heart and soul following acquisition by House of Fraser. For example, the amazing basement toy store was taken over by Hamleys. Only good point recently has been the hook up with Valvona&amp;Crolla for the food hall and coffee shop - amazing coffee and great views across to Princes Street Gardens esp during Winter Wonderland - also get to moan about tram works in the street below.
 4 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
The Commercial Bar isn&apos;t too bad for pre-match drinks on Saturday before catching the Stagees, not somewhere I&apos;d haunt on a regular basis though...
 3 Michael 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Bought a Mac from here recently. The salesguy answered all my questions without making me feel stupid. He also managed to show me the range of functionality without it feeling like a heavy sales pitch.

I also liked the fact that they run workshops in the store so that you can learn more about how to get best use of the programmes. Tho&apos; having said that, I&apos;m unlikely to go to any of these classes and would rather have the info online.
 4 Amelie 21/09/2009 Report this place 
The Clachaig Inn is a great place with stunning views over Glencoe. The Boots Bar at the back of the Inn is always busy and has a really good atmosphere. The food served is excellent quality, using local produce and at very reasonable prices. The staff are from all over the world and are very friendly. With live music every Fri, Sat&amp;Sun night and a mixture of real ales on tap, this place is the perfect stop off after a long day on the hills.
 5 Southsider 21/09/2009 Report this place 
The Country Park, covering over 200 acres, boasts beautiful woodland walks, adventure playground, pets corner, visitor centre, tearoom, shop and a fantastic 14th century castle housing world class collections including historic weapons, armour and musical instruments - info at http://www.deancastle.com/ 
 4 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
The Park Hotel is a functional and comfortable hotel offering excellent value for money right next to Rugby Park.
 4 Sheena 21/09/2009 Report this place 
This is the place to go to try some good hot chocolate! This small, fairly new shop on the high street has a delight of home made chocolates and a couple of tables to sit and relax. The hot chocolate comes with two melted squares of chocolate placed on top which slowly melt into your drink – so if you have a sweet tooth like me, it is the perfect choice for a wintery morning!
 4 Pam14 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Situated on the waterfront the Museum has a wealth of things to see for all ages. Took my 3 yr old boy and he loved playing with the boat and fishing toys that are available for the public. Could spend a whole day moving through the displays covering fishing, world wars and ancient settlers and inhabitants.

Also, if you get the chance, eat in the Cafe, but book if over lunch. Great local food on offer and the view from the Cafe is beautiful across the bay to Bressay.
 4 CaseyJones 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Great swimming pool with slides. It does rain in Shetland (yes is does sometimes) and great to know that there is a good pool on offer for a family outing. Toddlers pool is small but good and there is always a lifeguard monitoring it.

Also small (very) soft play area for toddlers, but contained and safe and it gets them tired out ....
 4 CaseyJones 21/09/2009 Report this place 
For a small place like Prestwick this place is fairly happening. Good food and then turns into one of the main nightclubs too - so you don&apos;t need to venture far.
 3 CaseyJones 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Great historical club - if you know a member then well worth trying to get a game organised and then lunch too. Lunch is fantastic.

Course is testing in terms of club selection, ball placement, etc. Steady and on the fairway wins most of the time, too many blink shots and undulating joing fairways to try and blast it with your long game.

Great views across to Arran. As it is a links course too it can be played all the year round.
 4 CaseyJones 21/09/2009 Report this place 
Lovely little restaurant, very homely. Worth a visit if you&apos;re up here.
 3 Gillian Harvey 23/09/2009 Report this place 
Very nice Italian. Authentic food, good service, very warm and friendly. I go here quite a lot and if you like classic as well as more modern dishes then it&apos;s worth stopping by.
 3 Gillian Harvey 23/09/2009 Report this place 
This has been renovated beyond recognition over the past 12 months and it&apos;s been a vast improvement.

It&apos;s a chip shop first and foremost and it does the job. They also offer pizzas and other takeaway fare at reasonable prices.
 3 Grant87 24/09/2009 Report this place 
A Chinese takeaway that has got away for a long time with being the only in the immediate area. Because of that, the standard has gone way downhill and the prices are a bit high.

There&apos;s competition just up the road now though, so maybe they&apos;ll get their act together.

One saving grace is their &apos;Ping Peng&apos;, which is a box of mixed starters for around £3.
 1 Grant87 24/09/2009 Report this place 
I stayed here for a wedding and thoroughly enjoyed my stay. The room - in the newer part of the hotel - was clean and spacious. Breakfast was good and hearty. Location was great - in the centre of the village and close to the beach, pubs and attractions. Staff were friendly.
 4 garythesnail 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Really nice pub/bar with great food.
 3 garythesnail 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic delicatessen shop selling a wide range of cheeses, traditionally cured hams, salamis, olives, hand made preserves, etc...Provender Brown is not the cheapest option, but once in the shop it&apos;s difficult to resist...everything looks delicious! My favourites are virgin olive oil breadsticks and their tasty Italian mortadella (very finely sliced) mmmm!
 4 Maria de la O 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Fantastic bead and jewellery making shop. Beautiful displays and original stock, I could spend hours browsing in this small shop!
 5 Maria de la O 25/09/2009 Report this place 
I stayed here about a year ago. It was during the seafood festival, so they were very busy and service could have been better - reception is the bar&amp;priority was given to the drinkers rather than the guests. Room was adequate but small and there was a lot of noise at night from the bar/restaurant downstairs. Althought it wasn&apos;t too bad, I would probably try somewhere else next time.
 2 garythesnail 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Paco&apos;s central location, spacious premises and extensive menu makes it a great a choice, especially for group dining. I particularly enjoy the burgers: tasty and reasonably priced!
 4 Maria de la O 25/09/2009 Report this place 
A good old-fashioned pub where Robert Burns used to go. A traditional drinking area out the front with a smarter dining area at the back. Food was really nice traditional meals and good value for money. Friendly staff.
 4 garythesnail 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Paco&apos;s central location, spacious premises and extensive menu makes it a great a choice, especially for group dining. I&apos;d particularly recommend the burgers: tasty and reasonably priced!
 4 Maria de la O 25/09/2009 Report this place 
A really nice place to stay - traditional rooms, some with loch views. And a great place to eat whether you want a formal meal or just a lunch or even a cream tea (scones&amp;tea are brilliant). In summer there are some great views and in winter it&apos;s cosy with lovely log fires.
 4 garythesnail 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Really good value for money guest house. Clean with good sized rooms. Within easy walking distance of city centre with private parking. Owners were helpful and friendly. Would definitely stay here again.
 4 garythesnail 25/09/2009 Report this place 
A classic function club right in the heart of Dingwall. The Ross Shire club is a bit of an unknown quantity during normal opening hours, but if you&apos;re planning on throwing a party the large function room is ideal for almost any occasion.
 3 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
A charming restaurant and bar snuggled away in the corner of Mayburgh. About five minutes drive from Dingwall, the Cottage bar&amp;Restaurant offers traditional food in a traditional setting, perfect for a family night out.
 4 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Oscar&apos;s is a popular Dingwall haunt, tucked away in the west end of the town. With a small, friendly bar in the front and a large function room for hire through the back, Oscar&apos;s offers a place to grab a drink or to catch some of the local and not-so-local musical acts and club nights.
 3 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree, well worth a visit. It&apos;s not too artsy either like the last person said, it&apos;s really interesting and you don&apos;t need to be an expert to appreciate what&apos;s in there!
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
I don&apos;t drink whisky, but during a visit to Edinburgh I made sure to go in here. It&apos;s a lovely quaint little shop and I got a nice present for my dad - who does like a little dram!
 5 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
I&apos;m quite interested in herbal medicine, vitamins etc, and this lovely old fashioned little shop caters perfectly for this. Good advice off the staff too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Yes, it&apos;s gorgeous in here. Go for a special night out. Quite pricey, but worth it!
 5 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Great if you like seafood, obviously! A nice, slightly hidden away restaurant. Good choice of wine, and really fresh fish served. Went on a Saturday night and there was a good, lively atmosphere.
 5 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Perched atop the picturesque town of Castlebay, the Castlebay hotel offers stunning views of the town and the castle. Joined to the side of the hotel is the traditional Castlebay bar, the venue for many of the island&apos;s top gigs and a perfect place to grab a pint and watch the ferry come in and out of this beautiful location.
 5 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Situated in the picturesque town of Castlebay, the Craigard Hotel is a beautiful place to stay during your visit to Barra. Featuring some of the best food the island has to offer, the Craigard is perfect for enjoying a meal while surrounded by stunning views of the sea.
 4 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Love this little place! Only been once but the cakes and pastries are delicious. It&apos;s like a little corner of Italy!
 5 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice little boutique. I&apos;ve found some good items hidden away in here. If you&apos;re in the area, it&apos;s worth stopping by.
 3 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Quite homely. A nice attractive pub from the outside and in.
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice fairly small hotel. Good staff and comfy rooms.
 3 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
I agree with the past review. It&apos;s a Hilton so the standard is always going to be quite good but it wasn&apos;t too dear. Good spacious room which are nice and attractive. Had a lovely meal too. I&apos;d return.
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Very helpful staff who really want you to enjoy your trip. I was very pleased with their service when I stayed in Dundee a few months ago.
 5 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Perched right at the top of the town, the Tulloch Castle Hotel is probably the best hotel Dingwall has to offer. Situated in the beautiful grounds of Tulloch Castle, the hotel offers a great place to stay and its function rooms are second-to-none in the area for any occasion.
 5 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Without a doubt Scotland&apos;s premier snowsport attraction, the Caringrom mountains are an absolute must for anyone with a penchant for skiing or snowboarding. The train will take you up to the highest pistes, and the resort features some of the longest runs in the UK for winter sports. And if you are not into hurtling down the hill on planks of wood, fear not - this mountain destination is also a favoured spot for hikers and hill-walkers alike.
 5 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Oban&apos;s premier seafood restaurant, The Waterfront Restaurant is a must if you enjoy the taste of a fresh catch. During the day you can sample the delights of that morning&apos;s catch sitting by the water and watching the boats come in and out, and in the evening you can visit the restaurant above for a fine dining experience. Be sure to check availability, especially in the summer months, as this restaurant can be extremely popular.
 5 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Beautiful old fashioned-style hotel. Perfect for a romantic weekend away.

Surrounding amenities good too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Had a delicious meal in here. Was busy when I went in - it seems like quite a popular haunt for the locals. Good mix of dishes too and not too expensive.
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Good big cinema, nice and spacious! Staff are quite good too.
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Great boutique. You could pass by and walk right past though, so you really need to know it&apos;s here. Doesn&apos;t look like much from outside, but go inside and it&apos;s like Aladdin&apos;s cave!
 4 Gillian Harvey 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Knowing its reputation for great fish and chips I went here expecting good things. People were queuing out the door, so great is the reputation of this place. So I had high hopes.

The fish was absolutely great - melt in the mouth stuff! The chips were OK too. But only negative comment was that it was a freezing cold day when were there and we had been seated by the exit door. Everytime it opened (it was also the entrance to the adjacent shop) we got blasted with the cold from outside - so it did rather take away frm the overall enjoyment of eating in what&apos;s meant to be such a leading establishment in fish and chips.
 4 Amelie 25/09/2009 Report this place 
The Solid Rock Cafe&apos;s younger sibling. The usual collection of rockers, emos and goths. Decent food and decent pints. If you&apos;re a rocker but don&apos;t like the requisite leathers of the Solid Rock Cafe down the street, then this is for you.
 3 Pemulis 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Walked past it this past weekend but it seems to have closed down. Shame.
 1 Amelie 25/09/2009 Report this place 
Probably one of Aberdeen&apos;s most expensive restaurants, so a place to go to for special occasions. The setting is brilliant, right by the harbour mouth, so you can watch all the sea traffic coming in and going out to sea as you eat.

As you&apos;d expect this restaurant specialises in fish.
 4 Amelie 25/09/2009 Report this place 
nice spacious pub with attractive timber panelled decor, giving it a warn and homely feel. good space downstairs for private functions too.
 4 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
Amazing burgers! Huge selection plus great hot chocolates. Quite a dark interior which isn&apos;t huge but this makes it warm, cozy and inviting when you&apos;re battling through the Dundee wind. Good seating in the windows if people-watching is your thing.
 4 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
As mentioned, good location right between the Uni and the town centre. The food is good and pretty cheap, available either in the large bar area or in the seperate more formal dining room next door. A good mix of locals and students with a great big space infront of the bar.
 3 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
Nice lively pub with a good student food menu. Interesting decor and a favourite stop for student pub crawls.
 3 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
Great pub. Recently renovated giving it a bit more class. Very good food but a little pricier than the average student can manage on a regular basis. Good location just down from the students union and near the art school. Students flock to its great beer garden in the summer months.
 4 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
We love the art bar. Good range of more interesting beers, ciders etc with a small and intimate feel. Low lighting and good music make this one of the more interesting bars in Dundee.
 5 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
Traditional feeling pub with dark timber interiors. Good live music though in its downstairs space which is available for private use.
 3 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
Newly refurbished with a much more cosmopolitain feel. Nice modern furnishings with a bar running the length of the building. I think there is a small garden area out the back also? Good atmosphere and close to the students union.
 4 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
A student bar through and through. Good drinks prices and a lively atmosphere. Many students stop of here for one of its many cocktails before heading off to either the union or a club in town. Only real downside is the small bar in relation to the size of the place - fighting your way in to order a drink can be hard work.
 3 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
A good live music venue with a big open indoor space plus a few garden tables and chairs to mull slowly over your pint on, on a sunny day. Also hosts unusual events occasionally such as salsa lessons.
 3 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
One of the most recent additions to Dundee&apos;s club scene. A good venue with a large round dance floor. Unlike other clubs in Dundee, it only has one space emcompassing 2 bars, some seating and the dance floor. A VIP area is located one floor up with views down onto the masses. Good drinks promotions and cheap entry deals.
 4 bakes 26/09/2009 Report this place 
 
To write a review sign in 
 
 About FAQs T&amp;Cs; Privacy Contact Us 
 Copyright©20072012 STV. All rights reserved. 
 
 
 Sign in Sign up Sign in 
 Email Password Remember me? Sign in 
 Forgot it? 
 
 
Or...
 

 News Sport Entertainment Local Player On TV Explore 
 
LATEST:  Lanarkshire athletes are Korea bound for International Children&apos;s Games
 
LATEST:  The price of food is a real concern for Lanarkshire pensioners
 
LATEST:  Ones to watch in the East Kilbride Pirates squad - part one
 
LATEST:  East Kilbride man gives the gift of sight to thousands of African children
 
LATEST:  What&apos;s on guide for Thursday
 
LATEST:  Facing the issue of youth unemployment in South Lanarkshire
 
LATEST:  Man repeatedly raped mother and child over period of five years
 
LATEST:  Murray carried the weight of the nation&apos;s expectation on his shoulders
 
LATEST:  Three Lanarkshire health centres to be rebuilt
 
LATEST:  Find a home for Cracker the greyhound
	</body>
</document>
