<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005608" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20081123200302AArYSCg" time="2012-07-12-22:10" support="1" score="0.0005581979969428312" bingtitle="What is the Average pay rate in the U.S? - Yahoo!7 Answers" webtitle="What is the Average pay rate in the U.S? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>You find some of the fast food restaurant workers, assembly ... it&apos;s nearly impossible to live, i.e., pay bills and ... Would I be able to finance this car on my own ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Personal Finance &gt; Resolved Question 
 Woody Member since: 09 April 2008 Total points: 960 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What is the Average pay rate in the U.S?
 I have been told that pay rates are really bad for the average worker, what are the hourly rates? What do you do? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Isolde Member since: 26 June 2008 Total points: 1,132 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 An average worker doing what job? The amount of pay someone receives for a job depends on the individual&apos;s level of experience doing the assigned work, what type of work is being done, and how much education the individual has. Higher levels in any of these areas will result in higher pay.

The minimum wage in the U.S. is $6.55 per hour, which will go up to $7.25 per hour on July 24, 2009. This just means that an employer cannot pay an individual on hourly wage, rather than salary, less than this amount for any work performed. Minimum wage jobs usually require less education, less experience, and less responsibility to do the work for that particular position. You find some of the fast food restaurant workers, assembly line workers, and general laborers making minimum wage...basically, young workers (high school age) and individuals just entering the workforce are usually employed in minimum wage jobs. In actuality, it&apos;s nearly impossible to live, i.e., pay bills and eat, making only minimum wage. The cost of living in the U.S. is too high. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 3 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (0)
 
No other answers.
 
Discover Questions in Personal Finance 

 Should I get a savings account? The lady i babysit for isnt paying me..? Should I file a chapteter 7 or 13 bankruptcy? Bank offered me lower mortgage than i actually need.. Can i now get a personal loan to top it up? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Advertising&amp;Marketing Careers&amp;Employment Corporations Credit Insurance Investing Other - Business&amp;Finance Personal Finance Renting&amp;Real Estate Small Business Taxes 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
