<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005997" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/278927-reasons-not-to-eat-fast-foods/" time="2012-07-12-22:40" support="1" score="0.005354383905631667" bingtitle="Reasons Not To Eat Fast Foods | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Reasons Not To Eat Fast Foods | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>For example, a patron may enter a fast food restaurant intending to purchase one hamburger and a side salad only to feel swayed by bargain prices and the visual appeal of ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Diet&amp;Nutrition Food&amp;Health Not Eating Healthy Reasons Not to Eat Fast Foods 
 
 Reasons Not to Eat Fast Foods 
 Oct 13, 2010 | By August McLaughlin Photo Credit tasty burger image by Alexey Klementiev from Fotolia.com 
Though eating fast food on occasion is unlikely to pose harm, frequent intake is linked with health risks. For optimum wellness, the American Dietetic Association recommends a diet based upon nutritious, whole foods, such as fruits, vegetables, whole grains, lean protein sources and healthy fats. Cooking healthy foods can save money and heighten appreciation for basic foods. There are many reasons not to eat fast food.
 
Trans Fats

Trans fats are fats produced through a process in which hydrogen is added to vegetable oil to create a longer-lasting, solid form fat source. Trans fats can harm your health in several negative ways, according to the American Heart Association. In addition to increasing your LDL, or &quot;bad&quot; cholesterol, trans fats may reduce your HDL, or &quot;good&quot; cholesterol. Fast food restaurant items are major sources of trans fats. Since fast food restaurants are not required to list trans fat content on menus, it is possible to consume excessive amounts of unhealthy fats without realizing it. Fast food items particularly high in trans fats include french fries, fried fish filet sandwiches, fried chicken, fruit-filled pies and pastries, cookies, crackers, tortilla chips, refried beans, hard taco shells and potato chips.
 
Overeating

Fast food increases the risk of eating excessive calories, fat, cholesterol and overall food portions. According to &quot;Fat Land,&quot; by journalist Greg Critser, people tend to consume more food when excessive portions are available. The fast food trend of &quot;super sizing&quot; french fries or soft drinks for a low monetary price can instill a false sense of hunger and cause consumers to &quot;feast,&quot; according to Critser. For example, a patron may enter a fast food restaurant intending to purchase one hamburger and a side salad only to feel swayed by bargain prices and the visual appeal of large, reasonably price portions of less healthy foods. The more often a person overeats fast food, the more likely he is to repeat the behavior and experience cravings for less healthy fare.
 
Reduced Nutrient Intake

Eating fast food is associated with reduced nutrient intake and heightened risk for numerous medical conditions. According to research involving 1,033 Minnesota residents, published in the &quot;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&quot; in 2006, people who eat fast food regularly tend to consume fewer vegetables and more fat than people who do not. Fast food partakers also tend to exercise less. A low-nutrient, high-fat diet and low physical activity are associated with increased risk for high cholesterol, high blood pressure, heart attack, stroke, certain forms of cancer and heart disease. Fast food restaurants scarcely provide vegetables, other than iceberg lettuce, tomatoes and potatoes --- which are usually deep-fried. Consuming few antioxidants in the form of colorful fruits and vegetables can lead to poor immune system function and more frequent colds, bouts with the flu and numerous other infections and diseases.
 
References

 American Heart Association: Know Your Fats &quot;Fat Land: How Americans Became the Fattest People in the World&quot;; Greg Critser; 2004 &quot;International Journal of Behavioral Nutrition and Physical Activity&quot;; Robert W Jeffery et al.; 2006 American Dietetic Association: Heart Health and Diet 
 
Article reviewed by Libby Swope Wiersema Last updated on: Oct 13, 2010
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Reasons Fast Food Is Bad for Kids 
 
 The Reasons Why Fast Food Is Bad for Your Health 
 
 Reasons Why We Should Stop Eating Fast Food 
 
 Why Fast Food Is Not Healthy 
 
 Risks of Fast Foods 
 
 Hydrogenated Oil in Fast Foods 
 
 Why Is Fast Food Not Good for Health? 
 
 Why Are Fast Foods Bad for the Body? 
 
 List of Foods Containing Fructose Corn Syrup 
 
 Will Not Eating Fast Food Make Me Lose Weight? 
 
 Why Should People Stop Eating Fast Foods? 
 
 Effects of Fast Food on People 
 
 Why Fast Foods Are Bad for You 
 
 Why Avoid Eating Fast Foods? 
 
 Is Eating Fast Food Bad for Your Health? 
 
 Can Eating Fast Foods Increase the Risk of Heart Disease? 
 
 Fast Food You Can Eat on a Heart-Healthy Diet 
 
 Tips for Eating Fast Food 
 
 Foods That Trigger Overeating 
 
 What Not to Eat While Dieting 
 more Heart Disease And Fast Food advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 What Is Detrimental to Healthy Eating? 
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Detrimental Effects of Eating Raw Eggs 
 
 Low Carb Fast Food Ideas 
 
 How to Use Cake&amp;Pastry Flour to Make Flaky Pastry 
 
 Reasons Why a Person Who Is Eating Right&amp;Exercising May Not Be Losing Weight 
 
 The Price Difference Between Healthy Food&amp;Fast Food 
 
 Healthy Ways to Eat Fast Food 
 
 Not Eating Fast Food for 6 Months 
 
 Detrimental Effects of Sugar on the Body 
 
 Researched Reasons to Eat Breakfast 
 
 Fast Food Low Carb Options 
 
 Why Do People Eat Fast Foods? 
 
 What Are the Different Kinds of Detrimental Inherited Traits? 
 
 Reasons for Stomach Pain After Eating 
 
 Low Carb Fast Food Choices 
 
 Health Risks Associated With Eating Fast Food 
 
 The Advantages of Not Eating Fast Foods 
 
 Detrimental Effects of Alcoholism 
 
 10 Reasons to Eat Healthy 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
