<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005303" url="http://cruiseforums.cruisecritic.com/showthread.php?t=1362019" time="2012-07-12-21:50" support="9" score="0.013624368980027533" bingtitle="Self-Service Beverage Stations: Are they becoming a thing of the ..." webtitle="Self-Service Beverage Stations: Are they becoming a thing of the past on RCI??? - Cruise Critic Message Boards">
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="001496" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000242" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000459" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>... ice cream &quot;parlor&quot; (counter) where you could get ... the fountain with the drink of choice and ice if you want it, as with any conventional land buffet, fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Cruise Reviews, Cruise Deals and Cruises |
 
 
 
 
   SEARCH 
 
 
 Home 
 
 Cruise Deals 
 Cruise Deals Last Minute Cruises New Ship Cruise Deals Southampton Cruise Deals 
 
 
 Cruise Reviews 
 Cruise Reviews Member Reviews 
 
 
 Features 
 
 Find a Cruise 
 
 Luxury 
 
 News 
 
 Planning 
 Cruise Basics First-Time Cruisers 
 
 
 Ports 
 Ports Main Africa Alaska Asia Australia&amp;New Zealand Bahamas Bermuda Canada&amp;New England Canary Islands Caribbean    Caribbean - Eastern    Caribbean - Southern    Caribbean - Western Europe Cruises    Baltic&amp;Northern Europe    British Isles&amp;Western Europe    Mediterranean Cruises          Mediterranean - Eastern          Mediterranean - Western Hawaii Mexican Riviera Middle East Nile River Panama Canal South America South Pacific Transatlantic USA World Cruises 
 
 
 Styles 
 Cruise Styles Main Cruise Food Disabled Expedition Cruises Family Fitness&amp;Recreation Gay&amp;Lesbian Group&amp;Theme Cruises Holiday Luxury River&amp;Canal Romance Senior Single Spring Break 
 
 
 Subscribe 
 
 
   Cruise Critic Message Boards &gt; Cruise Lines &quot;P - Z&quot; &gt; Royal Caribbean International Self-Service Beverage Stations: Are they becoming a thing of the past on RCI??? 
 
 User Name Password Remember Me?   Register here! Forgot Your Password? 
 
 
 Register FAQ Guidelines Photo Gallery FREE E-Letter Members List Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
   
 Notices Find out who is sailing with you on your cruise -- make new friends, share shore excursions (and save money!!), learn from your fellow cruisers! 

 Hi there! Why haven&apos;t you registered yet?? You are missing out on our FAMOUS Roll Call forums, where you can meet other cruisers sailing with you and share a tour or shore excursion and SAVE MONEY! Register Now! 

 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 

   Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
  # 1   February 18th, 2011, 01:53 AM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Self-Service Beverage Stations: Are they becoming a thing of the past on RCI??? After doing a 10-day ultimate Caribbean cruise on Celebrity Equinox followed by a 5-day on RCI Navigator of the Seas, I noticed some specific areas with the most apparent contrasts. I have posted my list of prime differences under both the Celebrity and RCI cruise line forums today if you care to read them.

However, something surprised me on RCI vs Celebrity. On Equinox there are multiple full-featured and self-service beverage stations opened 24 hours. You can even refill your own water bottles and thermoses to take back to your cabin. On Navigator, all beverage stations were off limits to guests and you had to request drinks or choose what had been poured and sitting out already in cups. And worst of all, unlike Equinox, Navigator did not have 24-hour beverages, just food (I&apos;m talking cold, thirst-quenching beverages other than water and coffee or hot tea). I was often so thirsty late-nights/early mornings and longed for something besides water or hot drinks. Is that a more recent cutback? Last time I cruised RCI (way back in 2002 on Vision of the Seas) they not only had 24-hour beverage stations but it was self-service. I think all drinks other than soda&amp;alcohol should be that way, as they still are on Celebrity. Are they that way on other lines like Norwegian, Carnival and Princess

Similarly (and conversely) there are no self-serve soft-serve ice cream machines on Celebrity as with many ships, but instead they did have a free ice cream&quot;parlor&quot;(counter) where you could get delicious and varying multi-flavored hard scoop ice cream (and soft-serve too), albeit only during business hours. __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 2   February 18th, 2011, 02:33 PM 
 Jimnbigd Blue Ribbon Cruiser   Join Date: Nov 2009 Location: Dallas, Texas Posts: 3,080 
 It might be a sanitary issue for RCCL, though I don&apos;t know why they would then allow it on Celebrity. People refill glasses they already drank from, contaminating the&quot;push lever&quot;on the machine. (Machines that use a button are better for this reason.) But I&apos;ve never had a problem with a waiter filling my drink. And RCCL Cafe Promenade has self-serve coffee (with a push button). I&apos;ve often wondered about people refilling their drinks at fast-food restaurants because of this same sanitary reason. __________________
 SS Norway Sep 1997 
 Norwegian Sea Jan 1999 
 Norwegian Sea Apr 2000 
 Carnival Jubilee Oct 2002 
 Norwegian Star May 2003 (Hawaii) 
 Carnival Jubilee Sep 2003 
 Carnival Conquest Nov 2003 
 Rhapsody of the Seas Jan 2004 
 Carnival Ecstasy Dec 2004 
 Carnival Elation Nov 2005 
 Splendour of the Seas Jan 2006 
 Rhapsody of the Seas May 2006 
 Carnival Ecstasy Dec 2006 (New Year&apos;s Eve) 
 Splendour of the Seas Feb 2007 
 Voyager of the Seas Mar 2008 
 Carnival Ecstasy Jan 2009 
 Voyager of the Seas Mar 2009 
 Carnival Ecstasy Jan 2010 
 Voyager of the Seas Mar 2010 
 Voyager of the Seas Dec 2010 
 Voyager of the Seas Mar 2011
Carnival Conquest - May 2011
 Mariner of the Seas - Dec 2011 
 Mariner of the Seas - Mar 2012 
 
 

 Last edited by Jimnbigd; February 18th, 2011 at 02:34 PM . 
 
 Jimnbigd View Public Profile Find all posts by Jimnbigd 
 
 
  # 3   February 18th, 2011, 03:44 PM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Jimnbigd It might be a sanitary issue for RCCL, though I don&apos;t know why they would then allow it on Celebrity. People refill glasses they already drank from, contaminating the&quot;push lever&quot;on the machine. (Machines that use a button are better for this reason.) But I&apos;ve never had a problem with a waiter filling my drink. And RCCL Cafe Promenade has self-serve coffee (with a push button). I&apos;ve often wondered about people refilling their drinks at fast-food restaurants because of this same sanitary reason. 
 I don&apos;t buy that because 1) Their fountains do use buttons, not levers 2) My drink bottle never touches the spout, it just&quot;sits&quot;there 3) They allow it on their sister cruise line 4) They don&apos;t even allow self-serve via their own provided cups 5) Coffee is not a cold, thirst-quenching beverage 6) It is more unsanitary to have filled cups just sitting there in the open air, not to mention ice melting and watering the drinks 7) That still doesn&apos;t address why cold drinks are not 24 hours anymore, just hot ones __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 4   February 18th, 2011, 04:55 PM 
 COMBOY Cool Cruiser   Join Date: May 2000 Location: LOS ANGELES, CA, US Posts: 891 
 I never remember free sodas or self service beverage machines in the Windjammer. Maybe way in the past. Whatever the case...it&apos;s all about $$$ with RCCL. I can only assume that on Celebrity it&apos;s consider more upscale (higher fares) and older passenger base that just doesn&apos;t drink all that much soda to justify NOT have the self serve drink fountain for those that want it. Celebrity doesn&apos;t have tons of kids drinking soda. RCCL wants them to buy those soda cards and get refills from the bars. I don&apos;t think it has anything to do the health issues. Just my thought. 
 
 COMBOY View Public Profile Find all posts by COMBOY 
 
 
  # 5   February 18th, 2011, 05:32 PM 
 cruisenfever 30,000+ Club   Join Date: Oct 2004 Location: NE Ohio ~~ Where it&apos;s always&quot;Next Year&quot;!! Posts: 32,907 
 You can not compare RCI against Celebrity Equinox. They are in no way the same. You are comparing apples to oranges.

RCI does not provide and has never provided free self-service soda machines. They do, however, offer soda packages.

On our recent Enchantment cruise, there were two self-service drink stations located inside the WJ where you could get hot/cold water, ice tea, lemonade and 4 different flavored waters.

Radiance does have drink stations inside the WJ, but the drinks are already poured and are on trays.

On Radiance and Vision class ships, there is a self-service drink station outside of the WJ. There you can get hot and cold water plus usually iced tea/lemonade.

I&apos;m really surprised to hear that you can not get anything to drink 24/7 on Navigator. I thought that Cafe Promenade was opened 24/7.

From the RCI website............

 Cafe Promenade - Navigator of the Seas 
 
Serving 
Breakfast, Lunch, Dinner and Late-Night Snacks: 24 hours a day

 Costs 
All meals (including regular coffee, tea, water, iced tea or lemonade) at the Caf Promenade are included in the price of your cruise. Specialty coffee drinks, beer, wine and soda are offered at current bar menu prices. __________________
 Patti (&amp;Jim) 
 
 
 (478 nights at sea ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ ~ 422 RCI nights&amp;657 cruise points) 
 
The secret of happiness is not in doing what one likes, but in liking what one does..... Anonymous Last edited by cruisenfever; February 18th, 2011 at 05:34 PM . 
 
 cruisenfever View Public Profile Find all posts by cruisenfever 
 
 
  # 6   February 20th, 2011, 03:36 AM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by COMBOY I never remember free sodas or self service beverage machines in the Windjammer. Maybe way in the past. Whatever the case...it&apos;s all about $$$ with RCCL. I can only assume that on Celebrity it&apos;s consider more upscale (higher fares) and older passenger base that just doesn&apos;t drink all that much soda to justify NOT have the self serve drink fountain for those that want it. Celebrity doesn&apos;t have tons of kids drinking soda. RCCL wants them to buy those soda cards and get refills from the bars. I don&apos;t think it has anything to do the health issues. Just my thought. 
 Wait, what did I miss? Who said anything about soda?? Not me. 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by cruisenfever On our recent Enchantment cruise, there were two self-service drink stations located inside the WJ where you could get hot/cold water, ice tea, lemonade and 4 different flavored waters.

Radiance does have drink stations inside the WJ, but the drinks are already poured and are on trays. 
 Yes, which is exactly what I explained above and don&apos;t like (seems more unsanitary sitting out in open air, not to mention wasteful and allowing ice to melt). 

 Quote: 
 On Radiance and Vision class ships, there is a self-service drink station outside of the WJ. There you can get hot and cold water plus usually iced tea/lemonade. I&apos;m really surprised that you can&apos;t get on a huge ship like Navigator/Voyager Class what you can get, even 10 years ago, on the smaller and older Vision Class ships. 
 Yes, my last RCI cruise before Navigator was Vision of the Seas with a little 24-hour beverage station at Windjammer. 

 Quote: 
 I&apos;m really surprised to hear that you can not get anything to drink 24/7 on Navigator. I thought that Cafe Promenade was opened 24/7.

From the RCI website............

 Cafe Promenade - Navigator of the Seas 
 
Serving 
Breakfast, Lunch, Dinner and Late-Night Snacks: 24 hours a day

 Costs 
All meals (including regular coffee, tea, water, iced tea or lemonade) at the Caf Promenade are included in the price of your cruise. Specialty coffee drinks, beer, wine and soda are offered at current bar menu prices. 
 I was just there. I saw no self-service (or even sitting-out) cold drinks at the Cafe Promenade: No lemonade, no iced tea -- only cold water from your sink, unless you ask I guess. As far as coffee and hot tea go, I have specified thirst-quenching (not hot) , drinks many times already. The Promenade gives you all sorts of heavy food 24 hours, but nothing to wash it down with while eating, unless you want to slowly sip a hot drink which is obviously not the same.

I will sail Radiance Class or Celebrity or other cruise lines which many have indicated still allow for 24-hour and self-service beverages, as do most $10 all-you-can eat low-end buffet or fast food restaurants on land. __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) Last edited by SWLinPHX; February 20th, 2011 at 03:43 AM . 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 7   February 20th, 2011, 07:23 AM 
 twiggers Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Nov 2009 Location: DFW Posts: 2,142 
 There are self-service stations on the Majesty. I believe this was something they were testing out and may implement on other ships. This was just soda though.

As for juice...we could go down to the Promenade Cafe and get ice tea/juice/water at any time (on Liberty).

Rome service is also available 24/7. __________________
 
 

 

 

 

 Previous Cruises (45 nights at sea) 
Grandeur of the Seas - 3/18/12 (Panama/ABC)
Voyager of the Seas - 12/31/11 (Western)
Navigator of the Seas - 5/22/11 (E. Med)
Adventure of the Seas - 12/19/10 (Southern)
Majesty of the Seas - 11/19/10 (Bahamas)
Liberty of the Seas - 4/11/10 (Western)
NCL Jewel - 12/13/09 (Western) 
 
 twiggers View Public Profile Find all posts by twiggers 
 
 
  # 8   February 20th, 2011, 07:27 AM 
 satxdiver Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Nov 2006 Location: San Antonio spaceship earth Posts: 2,807 
 When I first cruised on RCI the WJ was open 24 hours although not always the food line. I could get my sport bottle filled with ice and water or tea anytime doing it myself. Now the WJ is open only specific times and they will not allow pax to touch the ice, water or tea dispensers. One time I went to where the glasses were setting out filled and poured two of them in my sport bottle only to be yelled out by the staff. You have to be sitting at a table and given the drinks by a waiter! I still go get my own drinks despite their complaining.

If you want ice and water, you have to get it at a bar. The IC offers ice water out of a container so just water and no ice. I always insist my stateroom attendant keep two ice buckets full for me. For some this may not be a problem but for those of us from the south, ice is required.

I agree with you on this and do not understand why RCI does it this way. This is one of the main reasons I prefer Princess since the HC is open 24 hours and you can serve yourself ice and free drinks (water and tea, lemonade at lunch, juice at breakfast). Princess also allows you to bring onboard your own wine. I took a case of wine on my last Princess voyage. __________________
 
 RCCL: Rhapsody, 2003; Voyageur, 2008, 2009; Adventure, 2008 , Mariner 2010, 2011
 Holland America: Veendam, 2006 
 Princess: Grand 2005, 2006 ; Ruby 2010, Island 2011, Emerald 2012, Golden 2012, Crown 2013 
 Carnival: Elation 2005 

 May 2012 Diving trip to Cozumel
 
 
 
 
 satxdiver View Public Profile Find all posts by satxdiver 
 
 
  # 9   February 20th, 2011, 07:30 AM 
 GMoney 5,000+ Club   Join Date: Dec 2004 Location: South Park Posts: 6,560 
 So this topic somehow now warrants 2 threads, and then argumentative sniping from the OP with those who try to answer? Wow... __________________
 Patrick 
 About 425 Days at Sea since 1998. Gave Up Cruising for Swimming, Biking and Running... 
March &apos;11: Tobacco Road Marathon (4:30) 
May &apos;11: Avenue of the Giants Marathon (4:30) 
Nov &apos;11: City of Oaks Marathon (4:29) 
Nov &apos;11: Philly Marathon (4:23) 
March &apos;12: Tobacco Road Marathon (4:43) 
 
 GMoney View Public Profile Find all posts by GMoney 
 
 
  # 10   February 20th, 2011, 08:36 AM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by twiggers There are self-service stations on the Majesty. I believe this was something they were testing out and may implement on other ships. This was just soda though.

As for juice...we could go down to the Promenade Cafe and get ice tea/juice/water at any time (on Liberty).

Rome service is also available 24/7. 
 We had only hot coffee, hot tea and water at the Promenade Cafe on Navigator; I remember after sampling their sandwiches and pizza I was looking all around for something to wash it down with and that&apos;s when I realized there was only hot drinks (I eventually found some water). And yes, the older RCI ships like Majesty (Monarch, Vision and Radiance classes) have self service, which is one reason I was surprised all their new mega-ships do not. Also, room service with RCI (unlike Celebrity) costs money after midnight, and it is nighttime I am talking about when I am thirsty. I doubt anyone would pay a $3.50 surcharge or whatever it is every time they want a drink at night. I need refills (and my sports bottle)! On Equinox we could get not only coffee, hot teas, hot cocoa, etc. at a self-service fountain, but also 3 different punches and lemonade. It make sense when their buffets all keep a station open for pizza and 24-hour snacks that they allow you to drink something, if nothing else so that you don&apos;t choke. __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) Last edited by SWLinPHX; February 20th, 2011 at 08:43 AM . 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 11   February 20th, 2011, 08:43 AM 
 GXmanDC Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jan 2008 Location: Washington, DC Posts: 1,394 
 Allure has self-serve machines with lemonade, iced tea and a few other options in the Park Cafe and Solarium Bistro. Not sure about Windjammer, I never went there. __________________
 Steve 
 Washington, DC 

 Allure of the Seas 01/29/2012 (Ft. Lauderdale-Labadee-Costa Maya-Cozumel-Ft. Lauderdale) 
 Allure of the Seas 02/06/2011 (Ft. Lauderdale-Nassau-St. Thomas-St. Maarten-Ft. Lauderdale) 
 Liberty of the Seas 01/17/2010 (Miami-Labadee-Grand Cayman-Cozumel-Miami) 
 Freedom of the Seas 01/25/2009 (Miami-Labadee-San Juan-St. Maarten-Miami) 
 Explorer of the Seas 08/09/2008 (NJ-Bermuda-NJ) 
 Liberty of the Seas 01/19/2008 (Miami-Grand Turk-St. Thomas-Labadee-Miami) 

 Next Up: Independence of the Seas Feb 2013 Last edited by GXmanDC; February 20th, 2011 at 08:55 AM . 
 
 GXmanDC View Public Profile Find all posts by GXmanDC 
 
 
  # 12   February 20th, 2011, 08:44 AM 
 goouchjac Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Oct 2002 Location: Palm Harbor, Fl. Posts: 2,603 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by cruisenfever You can not compare RCI against Celebrity Equinox. They are in no way the same. You are comparing apples to oranges.

RCI does not provide and has never provided free self-service soda machines. They do, however, offer soda packages.

On our recent Enchantment cruise, there were two self-service drink stations located inside the WJ where you could get hot/cold water, ice tea, lemonade and 4 different flavored waters.

Radiance does have drink stations inside the WJ, but the drinks are already poured and are on trays.

On Radiance and Vision class ships, there is a self-service drink station outside of the WJ. There you can get hot and cold water plus usually iced tea/lemonade.

I&apos;m really surprised to hear that you can not get anything to drink 24/7 on Navigator. I thought that Cafe Promenade was opened 24/7.

From the RCI website............

 Cafe Promenade - Navigator of the Seas 
 
Serving 
Breakfast, Lunch, Dinner and Late-Night Snacks: 24 hours a day

 Costs 
All meals (including regular coffee, tea, water, iced tea or lemonade) at the Caf Promenade are included in the price of your cruise. Specialty coffee drinks, beer, wine and soda are offered at current bar menu prices. 
 Yes, the promenade cafe is open 24hrs..no problem getting water,,coffee,etc... 
 
 goouchjac View Public Profile Find all posts by goouchjac 
 
 
  # 13   February 20th, 2011, 08:49 AM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by goouchjac Yes, the promenade cafe is open 24hrs..no problem getting water,,coffee,etc... 
 Man, I feel like a broken record... I never said you couldn&apos;t get coffee . People keep quoting some text they read from somewhere as if that changes how it actually was just a week ago when I was onboard and what I was also told by the staff. And yes, you can probably order lemonade or something from a waiter during meal time as it stated. Notice it said nothing about 24-hour drinks in your quote, and definitely not self-service, the two things I was referring to when I started the thread. The whole thing about having to take what has been sitting out even during meal times and their attitude about it really rubbed me the wrong way; being treated kind of like kids in a school cafeteria. I can see satxdiver had the same experience. 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by satxdiver When I first cruised on RCI the WJ was open 24 hours although not always the food line. I could get my sport bottle filled with ice and water or tea anytime doing it myself. Now the WJ is open only specific times and they will not allow pax to touch the ice, water or tea dispensers. One time I went to where the glasses were setting out filled and poured two of them in my sport bottle only to be yelled out by the staff. You have to be sitting at a table and given the drinks by a waiter! I still go get my own drinks despite their complaining.

If you want ice and water, you have to get it at a bar. The IC offers ice water out of a container so just water and no ice. I always insist my stateroom attendant keep two ice buckets full for me. For some this may not be a problem but for those of us from the south, ice is required.

I agree with you on this and do not understand why RCI does it this way. This is one of the main reasons I prefer Princess since the HC is open 24 hours and you can serve yourself ice and free drinks (water and tea, lemonade at lunch, juice at breakfast). Princess also allows you to bring onboard your own wine. I took a case of wine on my last Princess voyage. 
 I couldn&apos;t agree with you more! __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) Last edited by SWLinPHX; February 20th, 2011 at 09:03 AM . 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 14   February 20th, 2011, 09:11 AM 
 foxesden1 Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Oct 2007 Location: Westcoast USA Posts: 2,829 
 Okay so I have to ask this one more time, because I am even more mixed up!


I am on LOS sailing in 41 days (YAAA) TA to Spain, I have a five year old daughter, who other then a sip of soda has never in her life had her own glass of soda. Not to keen on starting now.. two weeks? Forget it, she will be a coke monster within days..

I was going to bring a sippy cup with a lid, and refill it with juice/water mix during the day (room service, WJ)

But now I am reading you may not be able to? I have never been on ANY cruiseline that did not have a self serve drinks station (hot/cold) on the pool deck. 

T 
 
 foxesden1 View Public Profile Find all posts by foxesden1 
 
 
  # 15   February 20th, 2011, 09:46 AM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by foxesden1 Okay so I have to ask this one more time, because I am even more mixed up!

I was going to bring a sippy cup with a lid, and refill it with juice/water mix during the day (room service, WJ)

But now I am reading you may not be able to? I have never been on ANY cruiseline that did not have a self serve drinks station (hot/cold) on the pool deck. 
 From what I&apos;ve gathered, the Monarch, Vision and Radiance classes do have 24-hour, self-service beverage stations, but the Voyager, Freedom and Oasis classes do not. That is probably not a steadfast gauge as they are always changing things on their older ships to match current policies and features. You will have no trouble getting juice or other non-soda/non-alcoholic drinks during the day, but you&apos;ll either have to ask someone or take the glasses that are sitting out pre-filled in the open air and fill it from there. They are apparently much more restrictive and less trusting in certain areas than their sister line Celebrity such as with beverages, towel check-outs, room-service fees, etc. I guess they are used to dealing with too many kids and families so they have started to run things where guests are more supervised and rules are enforced. That reminds me of being at grade school, so as a paying guest I won&apos;t be sailing certain ships again. __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 16   February 20th, 2011, 09:57 AM 
 GXmanDC Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jan 2008 Location: Washington, DC Posts: 1,394 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by SWLinPHX From what I&apos;ve gathered, the Monarch, Vision and Radiance classes do have 24-hour, self-service beverage stations, but the Voyager, Freedom and Oasis classes do not. That is probably not a steadfast gauge as they are always changing things on their older ships to match current policies and features. You will have no trouble getting juice or other non-soda/non-alcoholic drinks during the day, but you&apos;ll either have to ask someone or take the glasses that are sitting out pre-filled in the open air and fill it from there. They are apparently much more restrictive and less trusting in certain areas than their sister line Celebrity such as with beverages, towel check-outs, room-service fees, etc. I guess they are used to dealing with too many kids and families so they have started to run things where guests are more supervised and rules are enforced. That reminds me of being at grade school, so as a paying guest I won&apos;t be sailing certain ships again. 
 Allure (Oasis Class) does have self-serve, non-soda beverage stations in the Park Cafe and Solarium. Maybe Windjammer, not sure.

I&apos;ve seen the glasses of tea, juice, lemonade on Freedom class. I don&apos;t see what the big deal is, just grab one. They are not unsanitary, unless someone is putting their fingers in the cups or spitting. One difference is that you don&apos;t have to wait for anyone, just grab a glass. __________________
 Steve 
 Washington, DC 

 Allure of the Seas 01/29/2012 (Ft. Lauderdale-Labadee-Costa Maya-Cozumel-Ft. Lauderdale) 
 Allure of the Seas 02/06/2011 (Ft. Lauderdale-Nassau-St. Thomas-St. Maarten-Ft. Lauderdale) 
 Liberty of the Seas 01/17/2010 (Miami-Labadee-Grand Cayman-Cozumel-Miami) 
 Freedom of the Seas 01/25/2009 (Miami-Labadee-San Juan-St. Maarten-Miami) 
 Explorer of the Seas 08/09/2008 (NJ-Bermuda-NJ) 
 Liberty of the Seas 01/19/2008 (Miami-Grand Turk-St. Thomas-Labadee-Miami) 

 Next Up: Independence of the Seas Feb 2013 
 
 GXmanDC View Public Profile Find all posts by GXmanDC 
 
 
  # 17   February 20th, 2011, 10:09 PM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by GXmanDC Allure (Oasis Class) does have self-serve, non-soda beverage stations in the Park Cafe and Solarium. Maybe Windjammer, not sure.

I&apos;ve seen the glasses of tea, juice, lemonade on Freedom class. I don&apos;t see what the big deal is, just grab one. They are not unsanitary, unless someone is putting their fingers in the cups or spitting. One difference is that you don&apos;t have to wait for anyone, just grab a glass. 
 To clarify, I am defining&quot;self-service&quot;as being able to fill your cup or water bottle at the fountain with the drink of choice and ice if you want it, as with any conventional land buffet, fast-food restaurant or convenience store. This last cruise on RCI was the first time that was no longer available. The week before this was all readily available on our Celebrity ship.

You can pick a pre-filled cup off the tray yourself or sometimes with a crew member manning the station, but my point is sitting out in open air is not less unsanitary than filling up your own cup at a push-button fountain, if that is their reasoning. Also, beverages sitting out may or may not have ice and if they do are often watered down if sitting too long. Finally, I think it would be a waste for their crew to pre-fill dozens of cups without knowing which drinks people want or how much they need. I just think it is a lousy system all together, and this is the first cruise of 5 where this is the new protocol. __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) Last edited by SWLinPHX; February 20th, 2011 at 10:12 PM . 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 18   February 20th, 2011, 10:21 PM 
 Merion_Mom 30,000+ Club   Join Date: Oct 2003 Location: Merion, Pennsylvania Posts: 32,312 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by SWLinPHX To clarify, I am defining&quot;self-service&quot;as being able to fill your cup or water bottle at the fountain with the drink of choice and ice if you want it, as with any conventional land buffet, fast-food restaurant or convenience store. This last cruise on RCI was the first time that was no longer available. The week before this was all readily available on our Celebrity ship.

You can pick a pre-filled cup off the tray yourself or sometimes with a crew member manning the station, but my point is sitting out in open air is not less unsanitary than filling up your own cup at a push-button fountain, if that is their reasoning. Also, beverages sitting out may or may not have ice and if they do are often watered down if sitting too long. Finally, I think it would be a waste for their crew to pre-fill dozens of cups without knowing which drinks people want or how much they need. I just think it is a lousy system all together, and this is the first cruise of 5 where this is the new protocol. 
 Walk up to the drink counter.

Say to the worker (and there is ALWAYS at least one there):

&quot;Excuse me, may I please have a fresh glass of iced tea/lemonade with/without ice?&quot;

You will have one immediately.

WHY you need to be the one to pull the lever on the dispenser is something that utterly eludes me.

 

By the way, RC has now extended that hours that room service does NOT have a fee. I believe that it now begins at 2 a.m. 
 
 Merion_Mom View Public Profile Find all posts by Merion_Mom 
 
 
  # 19   February 20th, 2011, 10:37 PM 
 SWLinPHX Cool Cruiser   Join Date: Jul 2002 Location: Phoenix, AZ U.S.A. Posts: 251 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Merion_Mom Walk up to the drink counter.

Say to the worker (and there is ALWAYS at least one there):

&quot;Excuse me, may I please have a fresh glass of iced tea/lemonade with/without ice?&quot;

You will have one immediately. 
 Although I have provided many reasons I will address your comment directly: First, there isn&apos;t always someone standing there. Second, that doesn&apos;t mean you have drinks available in the non-meal times or overnight or 24 hours. Third, you can&apos;t fill your own water bottle or thermos as we did on all our shore excursions, something that really comes in handy. Finally, some people like getting their own food and drink at a buffet, just like they do with the food anyway. ...enough reasons? 

 Quote: 
 WHY you need to be the one to pull the lever on the dispenser is something that utterly eludes me.

 
 See reasons above in this post or in the many previous posts. Don&apos;t strain your eyes rolling them though, LOL. 

 Quote: 
 By the way, RC has now extended that hours that room service does NOT have a fee. I believe that it now begins at 2 a.m. 
 Nope. Just came off RCI. Time was midnight or 12:30, can&apos;t remember which. We had room service late night as we watched movies in our cabin on Celebrity... no limit, no charge and awesome ordering system via the interactive room TV. __________________
 Facebook Roll Call - Celebrity Equinox: 1/28/11 Facebook Roll Call - RCI Navigator of the Seas: 2/7/11 
 Cruise Critic&amp;Facebook Group Name Tags 
 RCI Navigator of the Seas -2/7/11 (5 nts. W. Caribbean) Celebrity Equinox -1/28/11 (10 nts. Ult. Caribbean) Celebrity Millennium -8/27/04 (10 nts. E. Mediterranean) Carnival Pride -10/19/03 (8 nts. Mexican Riviera) RCI Vision of the Seas -9/15/02 (11 nts. Vancouver to Hawaii) 
 
 SWLinPHX View Public Profile Visit SWLinPHX&apos;s homepage! Find all posts by SWLinPHX 
 
 
  # 20   February 20th, 2011, 10:49 PM 
 DanJ 5,000+ Club   Join Date: Mar 2001 Location: London, Canada Posts: 6,350 
 I was recently on the Navigator and noticed the drink station thing at breakfast, since we are used to filling our own glasses of juice on Carnival and Princess. I actually preferred walking up and grabbing a glass already out for me. It&apos;s not like it&apos;s been sitting there more than a minute or 2 getting all diluted, as they don&apos;t have hundreds of glasses out at once. I assume they do it this way because they probably go through less juice and lemonade. I can see some people being bothered by it being this way, but there are also people who would rather not have to fill up their glass like they are at a 10 dollar buffet or McDonalds when they are on a cruise either LOL.

As for Cafe Promenade at night, I spent a little time sitting there each night after midnight, and although I had a soda card, other people had no issue asking the bartender for something else. They do make mixed drinks, so orange juice is available, and of course, ice water is no problem to get there either. __________________
Dan 

&quot;I&apos;d Rather Be On A Ship With A Drink On The Rocks, Than In The Drink With A Ship On The Rocks.&quot;

Fond Memories Of

Navigator Of The Seas - Western Caribbean - Jan 2011
Carnival Pride - Grand Turk and Bahamas - Twins First Cruise - Aug 2009
Caribbean Princess - Eastern Caribbean - Jan 2008
Sapphire Princess - Mexican Riviera - Jan 2006
Carnival Victory - Canada/New England - Sept 2001
Carnival Tropicale - Panama Canal - Jan 2001
Grand Princess - Eastern Caribbean - Nov 1999
Westerdam - Honeymoon -Eastern Caribbean - Nov 1995 
 
 DanJ View Public Profile Find all posts by DanJ 
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 


 Bookmarks 
 Facebook Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 

 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Jump 
 User Control Panel Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Community Guidelines and Message Board Help   Need Help Using The Boards? Ask Here!   TEST FORUM   What Are Message Boards; What are Forums   How To Post   How To Find Your Own Posts New Cruisers   Ask a Cruise Question   Cabin Selection Tips   First Time Cruisers Cruise Lines&quot;A - O&quot;   AIDA Cruises   American Queen Steamboat Company   Azamara Club Cruises   Carnival Cruise Lines   Celebration Cruise Line   Celebrity Cruises   Clipper Cruises   Costa Cruises   Crystal Cruises   Cunard Line   Disney Cruise Line   Fred. Olsen Cruise Line   Hebridean International Cruises   Holland America Line   Hurtigruten   Imperial Majesty Cruise Line   Island Cruises   Lindblad Expeditions/National Geographic   Majestic America Line   MSC Cruises   Norwegian Cruise Line   Ocean Village   Oceania Cruises   Orient Lines   Other Cruise Lines Cruise Lines&quot;P - Z&quot;   Other Cruise Lines   Paul Gauguin Cruises   Peter Deilmann Cruises   P&amp;O Cruises ( Australia )   P&amp;O Cruises ( UK )   Princess Cruises   Regent Seven Seas Cruises   Royal Caribbean International   Seabourn Cruise Line   SeaDream Yacht Club   Silversea Cruise Line   Star Clippers   Thomson Cruises   Windstar Cruises   World of ResidenSea ROLL CALLS   All Other Cruise Lines Roll Calls   All River Cruise Roll Calls   AIDA Roll Calls   Azamara Roll Calls   Carnival Roll Calls   Celebrity&quot;Connections&quot;Roll Calls   Costa Cruises Roll Calls   Crystal Cruises Roll Calls   Cunard Roll Calls   Disney Roll Calls   Fred Olsen Roll Calls   Holland America Roll Calls   Norwegian Cruise Line Roll Calls   MSC Roll Calls   Oceania Roll Calls   P&amp;O Cruise Lines Roll Calls - UK and Australia   Paul Gauguin Roll Calls   Princess Roll Calls   Regent Seven Seas Roll Calls   Royal Caribbean&quot;Meet&amp;Mingle&quot;Roll Calls   Seabourn Roll Calls     Seabourn Legend Roll Calls     Seabourn Odyssey Roll Calls     Seabourn Pride Roll Calls     Seabourn Sojourn Roll Calls     Seabourn Spirit Roll Calls     Seabourn Quest Roll Calls   Thomson Roll Calls   Windstar Roll Calls Photo Gallery   Cabin Photos   Cruise Videos   Carnival Photos   Celebrity Photos   Holland America Photos   Norwegian Photos   Royal Caribbean Photos   Princess Photos   Photo&amp;Camera Discussions River Cruising Member Cruise Reviews   Cruise Reviews of the Week Special Interest Cruising   Disabled Cruise Travel   Eco Cruising   Family Cruises   Fitness, Spa&amp;Sports Cruises   Freighter and Other Non-Traditional Cruise Travel   Gay&amp;Lesbian Cruisers     G&amp;L Roll Calls   Honeymoon&amp;Wedding Cruises   55+ Cruisers   Luxury Cruising   River Cruises   Singles Cruises   Solo Cruisers   Theme Cruises Cruise Discussion Topics   First Time Cruisers   Ask a Cruise Question   Cabin Selection Tips   Cruise Air   Cruise Fashions&amp;Beauty   Cruise Memorabilia   Cruise News   Cruise/Travel Insurance   Hotels - Pre&amp;Post-Cruise   Hurricane Zone 2012   Saving Money on Your Cruise - Tips&amp;Advice   Scuba and Snorkeling   What Ever Happened To........??? UK Cruising   UK Cruisers   The Pub Australia and New Zealand Cruising   Australia&amp;New Zealand Cruisers North American Homeports   Gulf Coast Departures   East Coast Departures     Florida Departures   Florida Departures   West Coast Departures Ports of Call   Africa&amp;Middle East   Alaska   Antarctica   Asia   Australia&amp;New Zealand   Bahamas   Bermuda   Britain   Canada   California Coastal / Pacific Northwest   Caribbean     Antigua     Aruba     Barbados     Belize     Bonaire     Cancun     Caribbean - Other     Cayman Islands     Costa Maya     Costa Rica     Cozumel     Curacao     Dominica     Dominican Republic     Grand Turk     Grenada     Jamaica     Martinique     Playa Del Carmen/Calica     Private Islands     Progreso/Merida (Mexico)     Roatan     San Juan, PR     St. Barts     St. Croix     St. Kitts&amp;Nevis     St. Lucia     St. Martin     St. Thomas/St. John     Tortola     Trinidad&amp;Tobago   Colombia   Europe     British Isles/Western Europe     Mediterranean - Eastern&amp;Western       France Ports       Greece Ports       Italy Ports       Spain Ports       Other Mediterranean Ports     Northern Europe&amp;Baltics   Guatemala   Hawaii   Key West   Mexican Riviera   New England   New Orleans   Pacific Islands, All   Panama Canal   Private Islands   South America   United States Cruise Critic Member Cruises   Carnival Spirit - 04/13/12   Carnival Freedom - 04/21/12   Carnival Spirit - 07/24/12   Carnival Conquest - 09/30/12   NCL Sun - 11/04/12   Carnival Breeze - 11/24/12   Carnival Magic - 08/26/12   Carnival Breeze B2B- 12/02/12&amp;12/08/12   Carnival Breeze 01/05/13   Carnival Dream B2B 02/02/13&amp;02/09/13   Carnival Miracle 10/19/13   Carnival Sunshine 01/05/14   Carnival Freedom 02/02/14&amp;02/08/14 B2B Cruises   Carnival Breeze 02/15/14 Cruise Conversations   Cruise Blogs&amp;Websites   Cruise Casinos   Cruise Foodies   Cruise Rituals   Floataway Lounge   Lose Before You Cruise   Member Cruise Reviews Friends of Cruise Critic   International Critters Corner   Curt Jerome Wild&quot;Off Topic&quot;Friends   Diamonds/Diamonds Plus RCCL Cruise Chats   Cruisers From California   M&amp;M&apos;s Cruise Clubhouse   CRUISE OVER? FEEL BLUE? TALK HERE, WE LISTEN 10/2 Sapphire BUT ALL WELCOME.   New and Improved Florida Folks   The One&amp;Only International Mixed Nutz   ARIZONA CRUISERS: NEVER ENDING CIRCLE OF FRIENDS!   Looking for Mariner 10/30/05 Cruisers   Mustard of the Seas   Capt. Bills World Cruise   Friends Who Sailed Caribbean Princess on May 13 2006!   Military Cruisers   Looter Rebels   Maryland Cruise Addicts   Sogno 101509 Friends   &quot;IOS GANG&quot;of the EXPLORER   Crazy Cruzers   WATPOPWUA Chat   Miracle Maniacs and Friends   Big Apple to Big Easy 10/21/12   Las Vegas, NV Cruisers   Martin Family Cruisers   Bucket Brigade Land&amp;Sea Cruisers   Captain Tony&apos;s Cabin   The STARS   NCL cruise nuts with Steve (Paradise Sailor) and Margaret (Got Tequila?)   IT&apos;S GRANDER ON THE GRANDEUR! April 30, 2005   Let the Games Begin Again   Brilliance 12/21/07 Cruisers (Carib and Panama Canal)   Captain Bills World Cruise   Friends of Explorer Of The Seas 3-15-2009, 12night   Ruby Princess 10/19/2011 all plans made   Woo Moo Foo - OHANA   BUCKEYE CRUZERS!!!! Where are ya, Ohio!?!?!   September 18th, 2004 - Friends of Hurricane Jean   Radiance 2007 ARRG Gang!   HORNBLOWERS OF THE AMERICAS: Mariner of the Seas 1/4/2009 Around the Horn   Fabulous February 2011 NCL Spirit Cruisers   Carnival Liberty April 18, 2009   Emerald Princess 10/03/2008 Trans-Atlantic   Coral Princess 1/23/2006   DAWN PRINCESS April 9, 2005!   Anyone going on the Miracle aug.15,07   Valor - 09/07/08 Eastern Caribbean Here We Come !!!!   Summiteers 04/30/2004 Western Caribbean Where Are You?   Radiance 2007 ARRG GANG   Connie Sparklers   Menopause Sisters   The Voyagers Living La Vida On The Victory   Friends who sailed Emerald S Caribbean Oct 21, 2008   Friends who sailed Glory Eastern 11/25/06   Friend who sailed Explorer 7/20/07   Friends who sailed The LEGEND - 1/6/05   Friends who sailed Radiance of the Seas Dec 2, 2010   Friends who sailed Mariner August 17 2008   Cruising Freemasons   Pink Boa Society Friends   Red Hot Rubies   The Pirates of Paradise   South Pacific Odyssey Friends ~&quot;October 22, 2011 LA to Tahiti to LA&quot;   It&apos;s a Kinda Magic Friends - October 16th,2011   Central Connecticut Cruisers 2012   The Third Cruise   CruiseAholics   Friends of Century Christmas/New Year 2011   Cruisin&apos; With Pom Poms   Primate Posse -- The Legend Lives On   Wild Turkeys   East Ghost Explorers   Sunshine Sailors   All Things NOLA   Cruising Square Dancers   The Bead Brigade   Friends of the Cupids   Macadamia Cruise Nuts   &apos;Friends of TommyCruiser and BettyCruiser&apos;   Friends who sailed Inaugural Cruise! June 3rd 2012! BREEZE ROLL CALL   Learn How Your Group of Friends Can Have a Forum Here Private Area   Archive - large threads 
 


 All times are GMT -4. The time now is 03:50 PM .
	</body>
</document>
