<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005468" url="http://caloriecount.about.com/fast-food-exercise-challenge-gt9-1494" time="2012-07-12-22:01" support="4" score="0.005435023910129355" bingtitle="Calorie Count :: FAST FOOD/EXERCISE CHALLENGE! (Six Weeks)" webtitle="Calorie Count :: FAST FOOD/EXERCISE CHALLENGE! (Six Weeks)">
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001440" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>... off eating out entirely with the sheer number of ... I edited the main post to change &quot;No fast food/restaurant&quot; to EDIT: Set a ... Join Calorie Count - it&apos;s easy and free!</description>
	<body>
		-- Calorie Camp Logging Community Foods Exercise Tools Advice Blog 
 FOODS ACTIVITIES RECIPES FORUMS ASK MARY GROUPS GROUPS   
 Overview Forums Groups Journals Profile Supporting Mailbox 
 Existing users: Log in 
 Want to Lose More Than 100 lbs Groups &gt; Want to Lose More Than 100 lbs &gt; Goals, Weigh-ins, Checking-In ... &gt;FAST FOOD/EXERCISE CHALLENGE! (Six Weeks) 
 Report Violation | Hotkeys 
 
 Search 
 
 This Group&apos;s forums: Select a Forum Rants, Raves, and General Chit Been There Done That!!! Discus Forum Ideas Goals, Weigh-ins, Checking-In Introduce Yourself Weight Issues (clothes, exerci 
 
 
Search this group&apos;s forums: 
 
FAST FOOD/EXERCISE CHALLENGE! (Six Weeks)
 Indi Martin indiwarrior 
 Apr 28 2010 02:21 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 
 Quote  |  Reply 
Hello! I got several awesome and thought-provoking responses to my Fast Food Victory post in Rants, and Sarah came up with an idea for a challenge - I thought it would be fun to see how many of us we can get on this!

RULES:

 Until the week of June 8 (six weeks from now) - no fast food, no restaurants . EDIT: Set a food-related goal - maybe no fast food, or no vending machines, or hitting your nutrition, or something reachable but positive! It&apos;s a great challenge for your pocketbooks as well as your health, and it only takes six weeks to break a habit/build a new one. Join me!  For each week, specify an exercise goal (anything!!) in addition to the no fastfood/restaurant foods to hit. That keeps us on track on a few non-scale victories! 

I&apos;ll start:

Last Week: Goals (hit/miss): None, because this is just starting! -2.4 pounds!

Current Week: No fast food or restaurants! Exercise goal: Bike at least 25 miles and three weight-lifting sessions.

Goal: Feel great after six weeks, with the added bonus of some weight lost! :)
 47 Replies ( last ) «previous 1 2 3 next» 67alecto Getting on the path to a healthier lifestyle 67alecto 
 Apr 28 2010 02:51 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #1   
 Quote  |  Reply 
Just keep in mind that this is pretty restrictive, which can lead to frustration.

With this challenge, you are automatically excluding yourself from:

 Meals with co-workers/friends on special occasions (or perhaps you have a regular lunch you share out). Being able to eat if you have to travel. Any sort of food day at work with catered (healthy) food. The social aspect of being &quot;out&quot; with friends and family. 

 Good luck to everyone, and more power to you if you can do this.

 
 Sunni sunnim 
 Apr 28 2010 03:07 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #2   
 Quote  |  Reply 
Indi - I am in on the fast food part of it, but it is not reasonable for me to cut out all restaurant meals. As Alecto said this takes out too many of the social things I do.

That having been said here goes:

This week&apos;s goals: No fast food (including Subway), no fancy coffee (ie Starbucks). Exercise goal: 4 - 5 nights of Walk Away the Pounds (at least all the way through once)&amp;2 nights of square dancing.

The coffee is a bigger challenge for me than the fast food.

Blessings,

Sunni
 Evy rain0rshine2 
 Apr 28 2010 03:14 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #3   
 Quote  |  Reply 
I am totally down for the no fast food part of the challenge, it&apos;s not that big of a deal to me anyways as I find myself feeling sick every time I eat it, but I can&apos;t swear off eating out entirely with the sheer number of family events and friend&apos;s birthdays and so forth I have coming up. I can say I will limit myself to eating out no more than once a week unless I&apos;m traveling or have absolutely no other option. =)

This week&apos;s goals: No fast food. No vending machine junk at school. 

Exercise goal: Wii Fit at least three times this week, excluding my Glee and 30 minute Free Step date on Tuesday night. Also, I&apos;d love to start arriving earlier and parking further away from my class buildings on my school&apos;s campus so I can get in more walking. =)
 Indi Martin indiwarrior 
 Apr 28 2010 04:04 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #4   
 Quote  |  Reply 
That&apos;s great! @Alecto, no, I totally understand that part may be too restrictive. Feel free to do whatever part of it, or set your own food related goal that you want to hit in six weeks. Diversity is great. :)

@sunni - Thanks for joining us! That&apos;s a great exercise goal too, lots of movement. :D

@rainorshine - No vending machines is a cool idea!! Welcome aboard! I&apos;ve heard great things about Wii Fit - best of luck!
 Indi Martin indiwarrior 
 Apr 28 2010 04:12 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #5   
 Quote  |  Reply 
I edited the main post to change &quot;No fast food/restaurant&quot; to EDIT: Set a food-related goal - maybe no fast food, or no vending machines, or hitting your nutrition, or something reachable but positive!, as it did seem kind of restrictive. I hope that helps! I think having goals/challenges based on victories we have 100% control over is really positive - I know sometimes my body will do whatever it will do on the scale, science be damned! :D But I can DEFINITELY control how many miles I bike or what I put in my mouth. At least, I hope so! 
 
 missjennas missjennas 
 Apr 28 2010 04:55 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #6   
 Quote  |  Reply 
I&apos;ll join!

Food Goal: No fast food, or buying food on campus. Also limit myself to only eating out at restaurants once a week.

Exercise Goal: Go swimming for at least an hour a week and do 30 minutes of workout tapes 3 days a week

 
 Sarah Determined to change my life. sarah_ann_artist 
 Apr 28 2010 13:42 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #7   
 Quote  |  Reply 
YES!  Great Idea!

This Week&apos;s Food Goal: I will not eat out at fast food, or any restaurants. 

I think it is great that you added exercise goals, too. I have been uber busy the last couple weeks, and will continue to be the next week and a half. I have my MFA Exhibition on May 8, which has been keeping me very busy. I graduate a week later on May 14, but will be basically free to go nuts on the workouts after May 10, like I was when I started this lifestyle change. 

Pre May 10th Exercise Goal: 30 min using Wii Fit Plus (either 30 min step aerobics, or 30 min yoga/strength routine) at least 3 days/week. 

I&apos;ll determine a new more ambitious goal or goals after that date. I&apos;ll have so much free time for a while after that to really focus on getting healthy, woo hoo!

AWESOME! It feels really great to carve this in stone. I am glad I shared my bad day yesterday. It has started a great idea!

Sarah
 feffers feffers 
 Apr 28 2010 16:50 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #8   
 Quote  |  Reply 
I&apos;m in too! 6 weeks...so many possibilities!

This Week&apos;s Food Goal: 

Get back into my very very strict fulfilling of all the nutrient values of my CC analysis. I&apos;ve become more lax - which is still working - but I want to become more stringent with it again. I was doing SO well, and it was like a game. It&apos;s the beginning of Week 4 (or 5?), so it&apos;s a good time for a refresher.

This Week&apos;s Exercise Goal:

Wii Fit (we finally got one!) for 30 minutes a day at the end of all the other house work I need to do.

This Week&apos;s Life Goal:

Finish up at least 2 odds and ends of MY life per day. 

(I added the last one because my parents are being really great and have helped me to get a newer used car after my beloved 17-year old Camry got its death certificate. Thus, to pay them back for their generosity, I&apos;m helping out like mad around their house. I need to remember to focus on myself too.)
 slwpresent on the D&amp;E weightloss plan. slwpresent 
 Apr 28 2010 19:30 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #9   
 Quote  |  Reply 
What a great way to start (I just joined here today). I&apos;m in!

This week&apos;s food goal: Prepare&amp;eat healthy dinners at the table. Not at my desk, not on the couch. Not not eating one.

This week&apos;s exercise goal: 2.5km walked minimum 4x week and *stretching* after each walk.
 Indi Martin indiwarrior 
 Apr 28 2010 20:26 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #10   
 Quote  |  Reply 
These are all great! @slwpresent - welcome to the group, love to have you. :)

Biked 6.4 miles today to the library - makes my total 15 so far for the week, so I really believe I&apos;ll hit my week&apos;s goal. Maybe next week I&apos;ll up the mileage! ^__^
 Melina sourmena 
 Apr 28 2010 22:14 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #11   
 Quote  |  Reply 
I&apos;ll join in! Goals

- No sugary drinks, ie no sugary coffee drinks from Starbucks. I&apos;m always over my sugar limit on CC, so I&apos;m going to to limit that. No fast food or vending machine junk for sure. 

- My exercise goal is to hit at least 600 calories burned when I work out three days a week, and 700 burned at least once a week. On weekends, when I don&apos;t exercise at the gym, I&apos;ll walk or hike for at least an hour each day. 
 Jennifer newjenn73 
 Apr 29 2010 01:16 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #12   
 Quote  |  Reply 
LOVE this challenge! Is it too late for me to get in on it??

Just let me know and i&apos;ll post up my stuff or wait for the next challenge!!

Thanks :) JeNN
 Indi Martin indiwarrior 
 Apr 29 2010 01:18 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #13   
 Quote  |  Reply 
No way is it too late! Post a goal! :)
 Jennifer newjenn73 
 Apr 29 2010 12:07 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #14   
 Quote  |  Reply 
AWESOME!! 

GOALS----

Food: NO fast food such as McD&apos;s, Arby&apos;s...junk like that. Cutting out sugar too.

Exercise: 30 minutes a day/6x a week. *Now I know that I will PROBABLY do more than 30min. a day...but my goal is AT LEAST 30min. a day.

TOTAL GOAL: By June 8th I hope to be at least 10lbs down and more than that....FEEL FABULOUS!! This is my 1st full week on plan and although I do miss certain things that I have let go of, the way I feel now out weighs the stuff I gave up.

I AM SUPER EXCITED ABOUT THIS CHALLENGE!! 

 

 

 
 emerald222 
 Apr 29 2010 12:44 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #15   
 Quote  |  Reply 
Sounds like a good way to get started!!! My daughter has come up with a slogan for me &quot;50 by 50&quot;. For you Moms - don&apos;t let your beautiful 19 year old daughter know that turning 50 this year bother you.   But I do like the challenge.

Current Week: Goals (hit/miss): Just getting started.

Next Week: No fast food! Bring my lunch every day. Exercise goal: start water exercise program and 3 hours walking.

Goal: More than 50 by 50!
 Indi Martin indiwarrior 
 May 03 2010 11:27 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #16   
 Quote  |  Reply 
Week One! Biked 27.4 miles (Goal was 25), and no fast food - hit my target! I don&apos;t weigh in until tomorrow, so hopefully all that hard work is reflected on the scale. :)

Week Two: Food Goal - Hit my calorie target every day (1400-1600). I&apos;ve been up and down on that this week. :/ Exercise Goal - Bike 30 miles!

How&apos;s everyone doing?
 Jennifer newjenn73 
 May 03 2010 11:40 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #17   
 Quote  |  Reply 
My week 1 was good up until Thursday night, then went all to hell! I am back on track this morning and looking forward to a goal hitting week!!! 

goals for wk2: NO fast food!! NO alcohol!! .....and 40 minutes of exercise daily :)

 
 Jennifer newjenn73 
 May 03 2010 11:42 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #18   
 Quote  |  Reply 
reply to #15... Emerald222.. My slogan is 40&amp;FABULOUS!! I told hubby that for my 40th birthday...I wanted to run a marathon!! I have 3 yrs to meet goal and i know i am gonna do it!!!
 Sarah Determined to change my life. sarah_ann_artist 
 May 03 2010 13:09 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #19   
 Quote  |  Reply 
Had an excellent first week!!!

Week 1: No fast food OR restaurants, 3 -30 min workouts: Done!

Week 2: I have family&amp; friends coming to town this week for my MFA show starting on Saturday, so it might be hard for me to avoid restaurants this weekend, so just NO FAST FOOD this week. If and when I eat at restaurants I will choose as wisely as I can. 

I am going to try to get in 3 - 30 min workouts, but I am going to be so incredibly busy this week I will not make it a rule. I will be getting lots of added activity with all I have to do before Saturday, so I will not be missing out totally. Cannot wait til this week is over. Next weeks exercise goal will be much more ambitious!

 This on top of cutting out over-processed foods makes me happy! I feel so good!

Sarah

 
 Cloudhaacker ?I don&apos;t know-Hope to loose a bunch! cloudhaacker 
 May 03 2010 15:34 
 Member posts 
 Send message 
 #20   
 Quote  |  Reply 
I&apos;m going to join in this, even though I&apos;m a little late! I can&apos;t do the no fast food because we&apos;re going on vacation next week and we&apos;re going to Mall of America, so I&apos;ll have to eat out. So my goal is to eat half of what I would normally eat. so here goes!

Week 1: Eat half of what I normally would, exercise enough that I meet 3,500 calories burned (that is 1 lb, right?)

Here we go!!

EDIT: I think I&apos;m going to modify this to say I want to exercise enough that my calorie deficit for the week will meet 3,500 calories. I don&apos;t know that I could exercise enough to meet that! Does this sound more realistic?
 47 6 47 Replies ( last ) «previous 1 2 3 next» Join Calorie Count - it&apos;s easy and free!
 Advertisement 
 Advertisement 
 Eat for Better Health 
 Watch What You Eat with RA Can You Eat to Beat Psoriasis? Diet Do&apos;s and Don&apos;ts with Neutropenia Chronic Headaches Linked to Caffeine 
 
 

 Recent Activity 
 sharmyworld101 supported heavyb68 heavyb68 supported mbeaudoin05 heavyb68 supported kstock219 heavyb68 supported neniiita heavyb68 supported Sammylou0183 
 Advertisement Free Coupons 
 $2.00 off any 2 Playtex OrthoPro or Binky Pacifier
 Claim Coupon 
 
 
 home | about us | press | help | mobile | bookmark | contact | advertise | tell a friend 

 ©2012 About, Inc., A part of The New York Times Company . All Rights Reserved. 

 Subscribe to our feeds: RSS | Twitter | Facebook User Agreement | Privacy Policy | Your Ad Choices | Mobile Privacy Policy&amp;Terms 

 
 
 Dashboard Calcamp Home Customize Goals Dietitian Support 
 
 Food Log Activity Log Weight Log Analysis Tagged Items Account Settings 
 
 Overview Forums Groups Journals Profile Supporting Mailbox 
 
 Overview Food Browser Recipe Browser New Recipe My Recipes Unit Converter Suggest Food Coupons 
 
 Overview Activity Browser Exercise Plan Workout Center Beginner&apos;s Corner 
 
 Overview Diet Profile BMI Tool Burn Meter Calorie Target Go Mobile Toolbar Challenge 
 
 Ask Mary Experts Members Videos Q&amp;A Books 
 
 Blog Home Tips&amp;Updates Dieting&amp;You Success Stories Recipes Healthy Eating Site Highlights
	</body>
</document>
