<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005691" url="http://www.livestrong.com/calories-in-fast-food/" time="2012-07-12-22:16" support="1" score="0.009661904012795706" bingtitle="Calories in Fast Food | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Calories in Fast Food | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>... restaurants have different recipes -- and different calorie counts -- there are commona... Fast Foods ... In the United States, there is one fast food restaurant for every 1,200 ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Calories in Food Brands Calories in Fast Food 
 
 Calories in Fast Food 
   
 Calories in Czech Kolaches 

Czech kolaches are an ancestor of the fast-food cheese or apricot Danish. Kolaches are tender rolls made of sweet dough, flattened and filled in the center with apricot, prune, poppy seed jam or a sweetened cheese filling.
 
 All About Calories in Fast Food 
 
 Fast Foods With 250 Calories 

Also, you may find yourself in a situation where fast food is the only option such as on a long road trip. If you are trying to find healthy or simply lower calorie options in fast food establishments, a good place to start is ...
 
 300 Calorie Fast Food Meals 

 Fast food may be cheap and convenient, but a lot of your options are also high in calories , fat and sodium. To help save calories and prevent weight gain, read the nutrition information at your favorite fast food restaurants to...
 
 300 Calorie Fast Food 

When eating out, fast food may be your cheapest option, but it may not always be the healthiest. Some fast food meals contain a day&apos;s worth of calories , fat and sodium. But as an informed consumer, you may be able to make healt...
 
 Fast Food Calories and Nutrition 

 Fast food -- burgers and fries, pizza, fried chicken, egg rolls and more -- is readily available, cheap and satisfying. When you&apos;re feeling hungry and pressed for time, fast food is a tempting and easy option. But before you gr...
 
 Nutrition Booklet Guide for Fast Food Calories 

Consumption of fast food is a staple of American living. According to the National Restaurant Association, sales topped $163 billion in 2009. There has been a distinct trend in how Americans view fast food , with the desire for ...
 
 How Many Calories Are in Long John Silver&apos;s Food? 

Although much of its food is preserved with artificial ingredients and fried in partially hydrogenated soybean oil, Long John Silver&apos;s does offer a few lower calorie options. If you eat at Long John Silver&apos;s, limit your calorie ...
 
 Diet&amp;Gender 

Diet and gender are linked, from the differing nutritional needs of men and women to the role diet plays in factors affecting weight in adulthood. These effects show that men and women differ in physiological and psychological...
 
 A List of Calories of Common Fast Foods 

Studying American nutrition without examining fast food would be like analyzing American cinema without considering action movies. Although restaurants have different recipes -- and different calorie counts -- there are commona...
 
 Fast Foods That Have the Worst Calories 

Some sandwiches and entrees that you choose to satisfy your hunger and nutritional needs cross the line between acceptable and harmful dietary contributions. Whether you choose fatty dishes or super-size beyond healthy limits, ...
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food 

Watching your calorie intake while eating at a fast - food restaurant can be tricky. Though fast food is often quick and relatively inexpensive, the American Heart Association says that it is best reserved for an occasional meal....
 
 Calorie Guide for Fast Food 

In an effort to respond to government and consumer requests for healthier fare, many fast food restaurants are replacing trans fatty oils with healthier options and bulking up their menus with low-fat, low- calories food s.
 
 Lowest Calorie Fast Foods 

Americans use fast food as a way to balance the fast track lives that they lead. This is contributing to an epidemic of obesity. Fast food chains are not oblivious to the bad press they receive regarding their menus. Some of ...
 
 Highest Calorie Fast Food Meals 

According to the USDA Nutrient Database, a 16 oz. chocolate milk shake has 423 calorie s , a large French fries, 539, and 32-oz. cola, 411. Some serving sizes take an even larger bite out of the daily 2,000 calorie average recomm...
 
 Calories in Fast Foods 

In the United States, there is one fast food restaurant for every 1,200 people. Each day, about a quarter of Americans eat fast food . With numbers like these, there is little doubt that fast food restaurants have a significant...
 
 What are the Lowest Calorie Fast Food Items? 

In today&apos;s on-the-go society, many people have trouble avoiding fast food for some of their meals. Many restaurants cater to people who are more health-conscious, offering low- calorie food options on menus. Choose low- calorie f...
 
 Highest Calorie Fast Foods 

Each day, one out of every four Americans eats fast food . At fast food restaurants, the average calorie consumption for a meal ranges from 800 to 1,200 calorie s , according to a 2009 study published in &quot;Obesity.&quot; This statistic ...
 
 Fat&amp;Calorie Content of Fast Foods 

 Fast foods typically contain high quantities of calorie s and fat, including unhealthy trans fats and saturated fats. Learning more about the fat and calorie content of your favorite fast foods might help you to understand the i...
 
 Low-Calorie Foods at Fast Food Restaurants 

Every day, 1 in 4 Americans is eating fast food , according to the website HelpGuide.org. One fast food meal can easily meet a day&apos;s worth of calories , but it doesn&apos;t have to. With careful planning and knowledge of healthful eat...
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food Ideas 

More fast food restaurants are including healthier selections on their menus, allowing you to stick to a lower calorie diet while hitting the drive through occasionally. Stay less than 500 calorie s with these fast food meal ide...
 
 Low Calorie Fast Food Options 

While a typical fast - food meal provides protein, iron and essential vitamins, fast food is notoriously high in calories and fat, according to the University of California at Los Angeles. However, smart consumers can make low-ca...
 
 High Calorie Fast Foods 

Unfortunately, fast food often sacrifices health for convenience and price. Many fast food products are high in calories , as well as other unhealthy substances like fat and cholesterol. Thankfully, many fast food stores now pro...
 
 Calorie Counter for Fast Foods 

 Fast food has a well-deserved reputation of being high in calorie s and fat, but many chains are now offering healthier options. By enjoying high- calorie items in moderation and navigating menus carefully for lower- calorie items...
 
 Fast Foods With the Highest Calorie Content 

It&apos;s not easy to make the right choice, but if you do a little research, you can safely eat at a fast food restaurant without worrying about too many calories .
 
 Fast Food Calorie Facts 

Eating at a fast food restaurant does not mean that you have to sacrifice your daily caloric goals. Calories vary widely among food s and establishments. Don&apos;t assume that a burger at McDonald&apos;s has the same number of calories a...
 advertisement 
 More in Calories in Food Brands 
 
 Calories in Taco Bell 
 
 Calories in Applebees 
 
 Calories in Red Lobster&apos;s Food 
 
 Calories in Subway 
 
 Calories in Fast Food 
 
 Calories in McDonalds 
 
 Calories in Papa John&apos;s Pizza 
 
 Calories in Arby&apos;s 
 
 Calories in Green Giant Foods 
 
 Calories in Burger King 
 
 Calories in Starbucks 
 
 Calories in Sonic Drive-in Food 
 
 Calories in Chipotle 
 
 Calories in Lean Pockets 
 
 Calories in Pizza Hut 
 
 Calories in Tim Horton&apos;s 
 
 Calories in Del Taco 
 
 Calories in Happy Meals 
 
 Calories in KFC 
 
 Calories in Little Caesar&apos;s Pizza 
 Follow Us Facebook Twitter YouTube RSS Google + Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
