<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005594" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g60982-d433902-r47906242-Fatty_s_Chinese_Fast_Food-Honolulu_Oahu_Hawaii.html" time="2012-07-12-22:09" support="16" score="0.048153623142308484" bingtitle="The Only Place for Cheap, Authentic Chinese Food in Waikiki ..." webtitle="The Only Place for Cheap, Authentic Chinese Food in Waikiki - Review of Fattys Chinese Fast Food, Honolulu, HI - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food: Restaurant Reviews ... is a hole in the wall type place with good Chinese food. They have a few counter seats and ...</description>
	<body>
		Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food reviews
 
 Home Honolulu 
 Honolulu Tourism Honolulu Hotels Honolulu Vacation Rentals Flights to Honolulu Honolulu Restaurants Things to Do in Honolulu Honolulu Travel Forum Honolulu Photos Honolulu Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Hawaii (HI) &gt; Oahu &gt; Honolulu &gt; Honolulu Restaurants &gt; Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food 
 
 Back to Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food 
Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food: Restaurant Reviews
 2345 Kuhio Ave , Honolulu , Oahu, HI 96815-2995 808-922-9600 7 visitor photos Ranked #126 of 1,276 restaurants in Honolulu 57 Reviews Cuisines: Chinese More restaurant details Restaurant details Good for: Dining on a budget Dining options: Lunch, Lunch, Dinner, Takeout, Takeout, Late Night, Late Night Neighborhood: Waikiki Update restaurant details Write a Review 
57 reviews from our community
 80% Recommend 
 Excellent 22 Very good 24 Average 8 Poor 1 Terrible 2 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 57 reviews sorted by Date Rating doc2th Ottawa, Ontario Senior Contributor 37 reviews Reviews in 15 cities 28 helpful votes “The Only Place for Cheap, Authentic Chinese Food in Waikiki” Reviewed October 27, 2009 2 people found this review helpful 
We&apos;ve been to Hawaii more than ten times and always go here. This hole in the wall beside the Miramar and back of the International Marketplace is the best authentic Hong Kong style food you can get in Waikiki. Cheap too! It is very small - maybe ten stools around an L shaped counter, behind which are the servers and cooks. The cooking is a show in itself - watch the fast paced movements, ingredients being flipped out from the containers with practised ease, and flames shooting up from the giant woks. Dishes are mostly noodles, dumplings, etc. and substantial enough. Don&apos;t expect gracious service (although the ladies are amiable enough) or an elegant atmosphere, but it&apos;s great food for those in the know and good value for the money. On the other end of the restaurant you can take out&quot;plates&quot;- two scoops of rice with stuff to go with it. This restaurant is usually full, there are some chairs outside for waiting.
 
 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by doc2th for Honolulu Ask doc2th about Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. OshkoshTraveler1 Oshkosh, Wisconsin Senior Contributor 33 reviews Reviews in 18 cities 17 helpful votes “Tasty Chinese Food, watch it cooked” Reviewed March 1, 2009 
Fatty&apos;s is a hole in the wall type place with good Chinese food. They have a few counter seats and carry out. We ordered and ate sitting on a planter outside the door. I had the pork chop on rice and my wife had the chicken fried rice. I enjoyed watching the very experienced cook master the wok a few feet away. The food was tasty and quick.
 
 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 7 more reviews by OshkoshTraveler1 for Honolulu Ask OshkoshTraveler1 about Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. DonLynski Winnipeg Senior Contributor 29 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 10 helpful votes “Fatty&apos;s Chinese Kitchen” Reviewed December 7, 2008 1 person found this review helpful 
When we travel to Waikiki, Fatty&apos;s is the first on our lists of restaurants to visit, we enjoy the atmosphere and the food is great!! You get in, place your order, it is prepared right in front of you, you eat , pay and leave. There is usually a line-up, waiting for a seat or pick up order, the turn over is very quick. It&apos;s worth the wait!!!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask DonLynski about Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. A TripAdvisor reviewer on Facebook “The cheapest Chinese food at Waikiki.” Reviewed November 23, 2008 1 person found this review helpful 
The cheapest Chinese food at Waikiki.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? This review is the subjective opinion of an individual contributor and not of TripAdvisor LLC. A TripAdvisor reviewer on Facebook 56 helpful votes “Beef Chow Fun and Ginger...” Reviewed March 16, 2008 
Beef Chow Fun and Ginger Chicken are the best dishes...used to get take-out and feast on the beach...
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? This review is the subjective opinion of an individual contributor and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 45-49 of 57 reviews « 1 ... 9 10 11 12 » 
Travelers who viewed Fatty&apos;s Chinese Fast Food also viewed
	</body>
</document>
