<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005131" url="http://www.a2magic.com/Party-Tips.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="1" score="0.0016630297647953019" bingtitle="Michigan Kids Birthday Party Ideas by Michigan&apos;s Birthday Party ..." webtitle="Michigan Kids Birthday Party Ideas by Michigan&apos;s Birthday Party Magician">
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="208"/>
	<description>... Center, Craft Store, Family or Fast Food Restaurant ... stamps, directions to location, thank you notes, napkins, plates, table ...</description>
	<body>
		Party 
 Tips for Great Kids&apos; Birthday Parties Javascript 
 DHTML Drop Down Menu Powered by dhtml-menu-builder.com 
 
 Looking 
 for a great Michigan magician to make your child&apos;s birthday 
 memorable and fun? 
 Click on the link for the &quot;A2 
 Magic Kids&apos; Birthday&quot; page. 
 
The A2 Magic Guide to Planning
Successful Children&apos;s Birthday Parties 

 Birthday 
 parties are a huge event in a childs life! A great party will 
 provide your child with the gift of cherished memories for years 
 to come. Jeff Wawrzaszek has delighted thousands of childrens 
 audiences with his Birthday Party Magic Show. Here, youll 
 find a treasury of valuable tips and suggestions that he has 
 gathered over the years to help ensure the success of your childs 
 special day! 

Planning a birthday party can be lots of fun, especially if 
 you get your child involved. There are plenty of things kids 
 can help with. Choosing a theme, making a guest list, putting 
 stickers on invitations, helping to choose party supplies and 
 making the goody bags are just a few suggestions. If your child 
 is 4 or older, getting them involved in the planning and decision 
 making is a great way to make them feel important, build self-esteem 
 and create excitement for the big event.

Below are several steps and considerations for planning your 
 childs birthday party. Taking a few minutes to read them may 
 not only give you ideas as to how you may get your child more 
 involved in the planning, but will also keep things running 
 smoothly every step of the way. 

 Setting 
 the Party Date 

 First 
 things first...consider the possible dates and times, as well 
 as the location and the number of guests youd like to invite. 
 Once you have a couple of dates in mind, make sure there are 
 no conflicts with family schedules, sports or other commitments. 
 If your child has a best friend or two that just have to be 
 there, check with their parents to see if they would be able 
 to make it. Finally, if you are considering hiring a magician, 
 clown or other childrens entertainer, call for available dates 
 and details first. 

 Setting the Time 

 Once 
 youve nailed a date down, decide on the time. Birthday parties 
 usually run between 1 - 3 hours, with most averaging 2 hours 
 in length. Choose a time of day when your child is normally 
 at their best. If you dont want to provide lunch or dinner, 
 consider a time when cake and ice cream will suffice. 

 Choosing 
 a Party Location 

 While 
 the vast majority of birthday parties are held at home, there 
 are other great places to hold a kids party. If you have limited 
 space or dont like the idea of having to clean up after the 
 big event, or if youre just looking for other activities to 
 do, a remote location may be the answer. Here are some suggestions 
 for great places and activities to consider for your childs 
 party: 
 
 Arcade, 
 Dance Studio, Bowling Alley, Child Care Center, Classroom, 
 Play Arena, Childrens Theater, Community Center, Craft Store, 
 Family or Fast Food Restaurant, Farm, Firehouse, Gym, Miniature 
 Golf, Nature Center, Swimming Pool, Park, Petting Zoo, Pizza 
 Parlor, Playground, Pottery Studio, Recreation Center, Skating 
 Rink. 
 
 If 
 you have a monthly community magazine that publishes a calendar 
 of local events, check to see if there are any special activities 
 that you can take advantage of on the day of your childs party. 

 Number 
 of Guests 

 Keep 
 the group to a manageable size. Ive entertained at thousands 
 of birthday parties, and most tend to include 8-15 kids. If 
 you are inviting the whole class or a larger group, enlist the 
 help of a couple of teens or adults to keep things running smoothly. 
 Below are suggested guidelines for additional help. 
 
 3-4 
 year olds, 1 helper for every 3-4 kids
5-8 year olds, 1 helper for every 5-6 kids
9-12 year olds, 1 helper for every 8 kids 
 
 Choosing 
 a Party Theme 

 If 
 your child is 4 or over, let them help you choose a party theme. 
 Limiting ideas to a single theme helps put the focus on many 
 other aspects of the party as well. Consider their interests: 
 What do they love? Who are their favorite characters or heroes? 
 What games do they like? What kind of party do they want to 
 have? A trip to your local party or dollar store will give you 
 plenty of ideas of what is available in the way of invitations, 
 decorations and table supplies. 

 Planning 
 the Party 

 Once 
 the invitations have been mailed or delivered, its time to 
 plan the party. The A2 Magic Checklist for Planning Successful 
 Childrens Birthday Parties is a handy page that will help 
 you keep track of what needs to be done. A copy of the checklist 
 is included further down on this page. 

 Ice 
 Breakers, Games and Party Activities 

 Have 
 some ice breakers ready to get the party started. Kids generally 
 dont all arrive on time. Usually there is a 10-15 minute frame 
 of time when theyll be arriving. A craft or an activity that 
 they can easily join in on is a great way to get things going.

Select several party games and activities that are age appropriate 
 and geared to the skill levels of your invited guests. You can 
 find plenty of game ideas online or at your local library. Plan 
 more activities than you think youll need. Some may run faster 
 than expected, and others may not be of interest to the kids.

Generally, the best types of games for birthday parties are 
 non-competitive games or games where everybody wins. If you 
 are playing team games, stay away from having captains who choose 
 team members. This may help to eliminate any hurt feelings for 
 the last ones picked. If you are handing out prizes, its usually 
 best to have a prize for everyone. 

 Piatas 

 Piatas 
 can be lots of fun but may be the cause of some potential accidents. 
 Watch just about any episode of Americas Funniest Videos and 
 youll see people getting hurt, ceilings crashing down, something 
 getting broken or nobody being able to break open the piata. 
 If you are using a standard piata, exercise a little caution.

There are some special piatas that will eliminate all the above 
 problems. They have several ribbons attached to the bottom. 
 One is attached to a trap door that will open the piata and 
 let the prizes drop out. Kids take turns pulling ribbons. The 
 ribbon will either be pulled out or, if theyve selected the 
 correct one, will open the piata. 

 If 
 Youve Booked Entertainment 

 Good, 
 professional entertainment is always a great highlight to any 
 kid&apos;s birthday party. If youve hired a magician, clown or some 
 other childrens entertainer, here are some suggestions that 
 will help to guarantee great results: 

 
 Limit 
 the entertainment to 30-45 minutes. This seems to be the 
 ideal amount of time for most kids birthday parties. 
 Scheduling 
 the entertainment for the first half of the party helps 
 to keep the attention focused on the birthday child. Singing 
 Happy Birthday and opening gifts is usually best saved for 
 the last half of the party and after the entertainment. 
 Save 
 the goody bags and balloons for the end of the party. Party 
 blowers and noise makers can become a real distraction for 
 the kids who are trying to enjoy the show. 
 Exercise 
 equipment, musical instruments and lots of toys can be very 
 tempting to the youngest guests. Having the entertainment 
 in an area where there are fewer distractions will help 
 guarantee a great show. 

 Food 

 If 
 you are planning to do more than cake and ice cream, its best 
 to keep the menu simple. Pizza seems to be the popular choice 
 at most kids parties. If you are going to get a little fancier, 
 strawberries and nuts may be best left off the menu, as some 
 kids have allergies to them. Its always a good idea to ask 
 parents when they RSVP about any food allergies their kids may 
 have. If necessary, you can have an alternative food available 
 for any guests with special needs. 

 Opening 
 Gifts 

 For 
 most kids, the highlight of the birthday party is opening gifts. 
 Kids love to open gifts, and their friends love to watch the 
 reaction the birthday child has to the gift theyve given. Half 
 the fun of giving a gift is knowing that its going to be enjoyed 
 by the person who receives it.

Before the party, take a little time to talk with your child 
 about the proper way to say thank you and what to say if they 
 receive duplicate gifts or something they may already have. 
 Make sure you have a teen or another adult helper keeping a 
 record of what your child receives and who gave it. This will 
 come in very handy when its time to write thank you notes. 

 Winding 
 Down 

 Its 
 always a good idea to give the kids a chance to settle down 
 before going home. All high-energy games and activities should 
 stop about 10 minutes before the party comes to a close. This 
 is a great time to get the kids together to pass out the goody 
 bags and say thank you for coming. 

 Goody 
 Bags 

 Save 
 the goody bags for the end of the party. Not only is it a great 
 way to resign your guests to the idea of going home, it also 
 insures that nobody misplaces their little treasures during 
 the course of the party. Goody bags dont have to be extravagant. 
 A small favor or gift for each child to take home is a great 
 way to say thank you for coming. You can find great ideas for 
 the goody bags at your local dollar or party store. Make sure 
 you keep everything the same for each child. Customizing gifts 
 may cause disappointment for some. 

 Handling 
 the Unexpected and Special Touches That Make a Difference 

 If 
 youre planning an outside party, have a back-up plan in case 
 of rain.

Have a few extra games and activities in mind in case you need 
 to fill some time.

Have extras of almost everything...favors, balloons, prizes, 
 food and drinks. Sometimes an extra child or two will arrive, 
 or something will break or get lost. Its always best to be 
 prepared.

Be sure to have a party bag for the birthday child as well.

Kids love to see their names in print. Putting their names on 
 badges, name tags and table cards makes them feel important 
 and helps you keep track of who&apos;s who at the party. 
 
 The A2 Magic Checklist for Planning
Successful Children&apos;s Birthday Parties 

 Here 
 is a timeline countdown for planning a great childrens birthday 
 party. While the suggested time frames are the ideal, great 
 parties can still be planned by combining and condensing the 
 time frames on the checklist below to fit the amount of time 
 that you have available. 

 3-4 
 Weeks Before the Party: 

 ❏ Consider 
 possible dates, times, locations, number of guests and budget. 
 ❏ If 
 you are considering hiring a magician or entertainer call for 
 details and availability first. 
 ❏ If 
 your child has friends that just have to be there, call the 
 parents and check their availability as well. 
 ❏ Set 
 the date and time. 
 ❏ Choose 
 a theme. 
 ❏ Make 
 or buy invitations and thank you notes designed around your 
 theme. 
 ❏ Fill 
 out invitations, including RSVP date and maps, if necessary. 

 2-3 
 Weeks Before the Party: 

 ❏ Mail 
 or deliver the invitations. 
 ❏ Plan 
 activities, games and party starters. 
 ❏ Plan 
 your menu. 
 ❏ Make 
 a shopping list of groceries and party supplies. 
 ❏ Pre-order 
 balloon bouquets or any special supplies. 
 ❏ Start 
 making or buying decorations. 
 ❏ Shop 
 for goody bags, prizes, candles, paper and table supplies. 

 1 
 Week Before the Party: 

 ❏ Order 
 the cake. 
 ❏ Follow 
 up with guests who have not responded. 
 ❏ Enlist 
 the help of adults or teens to lend a hand on the day of the 
 party. 

 2-3 
 Days Before the Party: 

 ❏ Check 
 to make sure you have film and/or videotape ready. 
 ❏ Purchase 
 food, beverages and any other final supplies. 

 
 1 Day Before the Party: 

 ❏ Bake 
 or buy the cake. 
 ❏ Prepare 
 any food that can be made ahead of time. 
 ❏ Prepare 
 goody bags (make a couple extras, just in case). 
 ❏ Make 
 extra ice. 
 ❏ Child 
 proof party area. 
 ❏ Prepare 
 and organize games and activities. 
 ❏ Decorate 
 the house. 

 The 
 Day of the Party: 

 ❏ Pick 
 up balloons. 
 ❏ Mark 
 the party location with balloons or yard signs. 
 ❏ Prepare 
 food that couldnt be prepared earlier. 
 ❏ Chill 
 extra beverages .
 ❏ Have 
 Fun! 

 1 
 Day to 1 Week After the Party: 

 ❏ Write 
 and send Thank You notes. 

 Here is a list of supplies that you may 
 need to pick up or gather: 

 Invitations, 
 stamps, directions to location, thank you notes, napkins, plates, 
 table covers, table skirting, plastic tableware, cups, serving 
 trays or bowls, place cards, name tags, straws, centerpieces, 
 balloons, candles, piata, yard sign, favors, party hats, favor 
 bags, candy, pencils, stickers, toys, games. 

 See 
 how A2 Magic can make your child&apos;s birthday party amazingly 
 successful, memorable and fun! 

 Contact Jeff Wawrzaszek to book your Birthday 
 Party Magic Show 

 

 

 Link 
 

 Home | Services&amp;Prices | About A2 Magic | Kids 
 Birthdays | Libraries&amp;Schools | Cub Scout Banquets | A2 Magic Workshop | Reviews | Contact | FAQ | Party Tips | Free 
 Magic Tricks 

 ©Copyright 
 2009 - A2 Magic  
 
 

 
  Michigan magician - a2magic.com
	</body>
</document>
