<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005487" url="http://groups.yahoo.com/group/LifeSafety/messages/107?xm=1&amp;m=e&amp;l=1" time="2012-07-12-22:03" support="1" score="0.0015022028948078845" bingtitle="LifeSafety : Messages : 107-136 of 184 - Yahoo! Groups - Join or ..." webtitle="LifeSafety : Messages : 107-136 of 184">
			<query id="000066" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>It&apos;s actually been around for several years, previously known as &quot;Soda Pop&apos;s ... was working, was a booth dispensing free coffee. So I stole a bit from Mr. Bean:</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Groups 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 LifeSafety ·Life Safety 
 
 Home Messages Attachments 
 
 Members Only Files Photos Links Database Polls Members Calendar Promote 
 
 Info Settings 
 
Group Information

 Members: 316 Category: Issues Founded: Oct 14, 1999 Language: English 
 Already a member? Sign in to Yahoo! 
Yahoo! Groups Tips

Did you know...
 Message search is now enhanced, find messages faster. Take it for a spin. 
 
Messages
   Messages Help 
 
 Message # Search: Advanced 

 Messages 107 - 136 of 184  Oldest  |  &lt; Older  |  Newer &gt;  |  Newest 
 
 Messages: Show Message Summaries  ( Group by Topic ) Sort by Date   #107 From: &quot;sparkydmfd&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Aug 27, 2003 7:36 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #54 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Greetings!

I am in the process of trying to put together a long overdue
newsletter! Please send me any questions, submissions, etc. to Sparky@... and I&apos;ll work on that in the next week. For
now I wanted to pass along an article I wrote that you can find in
the Calliope magazine this month. The Calliope is a publication
published 6 times per year by Clowns of America International
(COAI).

What plans do you have for Fire Prevention Week?
Have you started booking school shows for this year?
What behaviors are you covering?
Do you have a set theme for your programs?
Are you doing anything with NFPA&apos;s theme with your characterization
program?

Just some food for thought. I&apos;d love to hear from you!

Be safe!
Pam&quot;Sparky&quot;Moody
www.lafsforlife.org
=============================

Educational Clowning For Safety Sake!
By: Pam&quot;Sparky&quot;Moody, copywrite 2003

So, you have a great clown character developed. Let&apos;s take a step
back and see what kinds of things you are doing with it. Have you
ever thought about using that character to save and change lives?

My character was originally born into clown ministry several years
ago. As a firefighter character clown, it didn&apos;t take long to
realize that I could use this character to promote vital safety and
self esteem messages to all ages. I now have a nonprofit
organization that works in partnership with the Des Moines Fire
Department, doing just that. I&apos;m hoping to inspire some of you to
seek out the use of your characters in a similar manner.

Professional Partnerships
Honor the professions of others doing their jobs. By this, I mean
seek the advice of educators and safety professionals before stepping
in front of a gym of 400 kids to do a show. Study the methodologies
of learning. Contact your local police / fire department and find
out what the true problem areas are for your region. Do they have
any slogan-type campaigns you should tie into? Gain the respect of
school leaders and safety professionals in your community before
going further.

Schools also have set policy on how much safety education they must
teach each year, etc. Find out what your school requirements are,
then try to meet them all in one show. Not only can you offer to
meet their safety requirements, but you may also meet a need of
exposure to the&quot;arts&quot;as well.

Retention
Delivering messages through the art of clowning, magic, comedy, etc.
allows you to repeat your messages in a variety of formats. This
serves to enhance the retention of these messages 2-fold. Let me
explain.

For every message that I cover in a program, I present that message
at least 3 different times. I may bring it to light first in a skit,
following up with some magic and finally recapped at the end. This
allows the child to learn from a variety of mediums. First, the
child hears the message as I speak it. He then sees the message as I
act it out. Sometimes I hold up signs and they can read the
messages. Whenever possible, have the children repeat the messages
allowing them to verbalize. Adding some comedy and magic gives me
that every so important REPETITION. Each child learns in their own
way. Some are more audio learners and some visual. My programs are
written to teach everyone at any level.

At the end of each program I always recap everything I&apos;ve covered
that day. An easy way to do this is with silks and a change bag,
although there are several different types of things you could do.

Slogans
Whenever possible, use slogans with your presentations. These can be
common ones, such as Stop, Drop and Roll or create your own.
Advertising has proven the effectiveness of using a rhyme or slogans
to remember messages. Other examples are: Don&apos;t be a fool in a
swimming pool; Never point a gun, not even in fun; If you see a gun
it&apos;s time to run; Don&apos;t trust luck - BUCKLE UP, etc.

Demonstrate GOOD Behavior
This is often hard to do as a clown, since we are often known as
buffoons, but when working in schools I try to only
demonstrate&quot;good&quot;behaviors. When dealing with safety issues, I
want to make absolutely certain a child doesn&apos;t learn the wrong way.
A young child will&quot;mimic&quot;your behavior so be careful what you model
for them.

Mirror Existing School Programs
Does the school have a program in place that you can tie into? I
have one program I do on choices that is easily adapted to several
types of prewritten curriculum such as the&quot;Character Counts&quot;or
the&quot;Tools for Success&quot;program. Schools will love you if you can
expand on programs they already have in place.

Be Cool
Know everything that is cool in a kid&apos;s eyes. What video games are
they playing? What are their favorite cartoons? Characters? Tie
into current events or happenings whenever possible.

Volunteers
Treat your volunteers with respect and honor. It&apos;s difficult for
elementary age children to get up in front of their peers. Be
careful not to embarrass or make fun of them. Whenever possible,
make them the hero!

Rules
At the beginning of each assembly, I introduce myself and immediately
share the RULES of the assembly. I do this for a couple of reasons.
The first being that my assemblies are fun and full of interaction.
Early into this, I found this sometimes difficult because kids are
grilled ahead of time by their teachers on their definition
of&quot;proper assembly behavior.&quot;I simply share that this is going to
require interaction and if you see something you LIKE, please clap!
If I ask you a question, it&apos;s ok to SHOUT out the answer. HOWEVER,
ahead of time, find out what the universal sign for QUIET is for that
school. In our area it&apos;s one hand extended in the air with two
fingers pointed like a peace sign. I will finally say to the
audience that we are going to cover a lot of important messages today
and if I think we&apos;re getting a little too noisy and missing some of
the messages, you all know what this means? (extend my fingers in
the air) QUIET, they will all yell in unison. That&apos;s right, it
means we need to quiet down for just a minute so we don&apos;t miss
anything important!

Financially Speaking.....
Everyone has opinions on this, but personally, there is not a lot of
income to be made in schools. There is however outside funding
sources you can look to.

 PTA/PTO - Parent organizations will often pay for this type
of assembly
 Local Clubs and Civic Organization - Such as Optiminist
Clubs, Lions, Kiwanas, etc.
 Arts Related - Grant funding is often available through local
Arts Councils.

From a broader standpoint, I can assure you if you present a quality
program to a school when birthday party time comes around, who do you
think the number one clown they will want to do their party will be?
You guessed it! YOU, the clown that was the STAR at their school
assembly.

Keeping Records
Keep accurate records as to where you go and how many children are in
attendance. Many grants require you show some unit of measurement.
In getting others to&quot;buy-into&quot;your program, they will most
definitely want to know how many lives you will touch, etc.

Handouts
Handouts are a wonderful way to send them home with a reminder of the
program they had that day. Of course, this adds more expense to your
program, but you can often get handouts donated for safety related
programs from companies such as State Farm or Allied Insurance
Companies.

I have found trading cards to be a great handout. The kids hang onto
them because they have color pictures of the performers on the
front. On the back is a recap of each safety message we covered.
You can often get cards such as this sponsored by offering to place
the sponsor logo on the back of the card as well. This also makes a
good conversation tool for the supper table which insures the child
WILL be sharing those messages with mom and dad over dinner.

I hope this has stimulated you in some way to consider using your
characters for safety sake! The greatest resource I&apos;ve found is the
S.M.I.L.E. Organization. SMILE is an acronym for Safety Magic In Law
Enforcement and they publish a fabulous quarterly newsletter complete
with skits and routines for clowns, puppets, ventriloquists and
magicians. For more information visit the website:
www.smileclowns.org.
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1)   #108 From: SparkyDMFD@...
 Date: Wed Sep 10, 2003 2:28 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #55 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Happy Wednesday!

Well, I may be just a &quot;tidge&quot; later with this than I mentioned when I last wrote, but at least it&apos;s not MONTHS! I hope this finds you all well and keeping busy with plans for the upcoming Fire Prevention Week Activities.

This year, in addition to our annual Open House, we&apos;re going to try something new. We host a huge open house at our main firestation in downtown Des Moines bringing in all apparatus and equipment for display. We move all in-service rigs to the pad out front and fill the inside of the station with things to see and do. This will be our 4th year of giving out FREE smoke detectors compliments of State Farm Insurance. They also bring in a crew offering FREE kids ID badges which are always a hit with families. Interstate Battery sets up a booth giving out FREE 9-volt batteries for the smoke detectors. We have FREE drink, popcorn and Ice Cream (compliments of Wells Blue Bunny). The American Red Cross usually sets up a display....but each year I try to come up with something EDUCATIONAL for families to do while there. This year we are going to have a &quot;build a puppet&quot; station where kids can go and have assistance making a puppet from athletic socks. Once their puppets are complete, we will have a curtain set up from our puppet stage and they will receive personal instruction on how to make the puppet come to life and a few simple puppet movements. We will be using One Way Street&apos;s new safety CD for the puppets to sing to. In the past this event has drawn several thousand down to spend a Saturday afternoon at the firehouse!

I heard from Mike Billingsley this week that a group in the area of TEXAS (big area) recently got together to show and tell their programs for this school year. What a WONDERFUL idea. I&apos;m envious that there aren&apos;t yet enough of us in our neck of the woods to do this. If any of y&apos;all do it again, please share it because it just might be worth a drive for some to attend!

You&apos;ll notice a routine posted further down in the newsletter. I would really like to see more sharing of this type in this newsletter. Skits, magic.....props you&apos;ve made that works for you.....this newsletter is only as good as the members make it! Please share your ideas with me!!!

Have a SAFE week!
Sparky

INDEX
1 )  Fire Prevention Week PSA&apos;s
2 ) Clown Camp
3 ) SMILE Conference
4 ) AFBEA Characterization Conference
5 ) Cool a Burn Routine
6 ) Clown Call For Help!
7 ) The END

( 1 )=========&gt;Public Service Announcements&lt;=========
From: Sender911
(thanks for sharing!)

Looking for a new way to reach out to your community with a message of fire safety? The Idea Bank has created a series of 30-second public service announcements you may use free of charge. Please let your radio stations know about this free service. They will be able to download these broadcast quality PSAs directly from this Web page and air them. 

 You can actually e-mail the information to your local press from the website:  National Fire Prevention Week 


( 2 )===============&gt; CLOWN CAMP&lt;=============

This is the news we&apos;ve been waiting for!!!!! The official &quot;Clown Camp&quot; held annually at the University of Wisconsin at LaCrosse will be holding an entire week-long track next summer for &quot;Community Safety Education!&quot; 

If you&apos;ve never been to clown camp before it&apos;s the experience of a lifetime and you have plenty of time to get this worked into those budgets and start nudging for the time off. The week is set for June 12 - 18, 2004.

Camp will officially start Saturday night, June 12th and will complete Friday morning, June 18th. It will be the most informative and hands-on training you can get to enhance your clowning and will have several classes each day dedicated to safety education! The costs have not been set for next year, but you can plan on spending around $600 (cheaper if you share your room) but this is ALL INCLUSIVE. You will live in the dormitories and eat 3 buffet style meals a day. There are also scholarships you can apply for. The first year I went to camp, I went on a 1/2 scholarship and was grateful for the opportunity.

You will learn from some of the best instructors in the world! I emphasize WORLD as there will be plenty of people there from other countries and you&apos;ll soon see why clowning is a &quot;universal&quot; language as well (ha). Each day starts early and ends late....even later if you want to attend an evening jam session or visit the neighborhood &quot;pub&quot; next to the campus. 

They also have an &quot;Open Mic&quot; each night which is a fabulous opportunity to share your routines and/or practice with an audience. 

The camp store in unbelievable with more merchandise for sale that you ever could want (or afford!). 

I&apos;m confident that this class will fill up quickly as word gets out. You&apos;ll want to keep an eye on the camp website:   Homepage   Dr. Richard Snowberg shared that it will be updated to reflect this within the next 2 weeks. 

( 3 ) ============&gt;SMILE CONFERENCE&lt;=============

S.M.I.L.E. (Safety Magic In Law Enforcement)
The 5th Annual SMILE Conference is coming up this November, in Phoenix, with a tremendous instructor lineup include Dave &quot;Mr. Magish&quot; Mitchell as the lead instructor. Full details can be found at the weblink below. 
 Events 
 Dates: November 21-23, 2003 
Location: Phoenix, AZ
e-mail: billyclub@... or PattyM123@...

( 4 )==========&gt;AFBEA Characterization Conference&lt;===========

 17th Annual Educational Characterization Through Clowning and Puppetry Camp
 Sponsored by AFBEA (Arizona Fire and Burn Education Assn)
Date:  February 3-6, 2004
Location:  Bullhead City, Arizona
e-mail: afbea@...
 Conference 


( 5 )============&gt; ROUTINE&lt;===============
COOL A BURN

Message:
Cool a burn with cool, cool water for a long, long time

Material needed:
Dove or chick pan (single load)
Lota Bowl, vase or Foo Can
Foam French Fries (instructions at end)
D&apos;lite thumb tip or oversized thumb
Something to catch the water, ie: bucket, trash can, etc

Routine:
Enter with the comments that you are very, very hungry. Let&apos;s make something to eat. HHHmmm, what should I make. I know, FRENCH FRIES are my nearly favorite food! Pick up the empty bottom of the dove/chick pan. Ponder for a moment on ingredients you need. I use only a silk flower because Sparky doesn&apos;t know much about cooking…but she does know her mamma uses FLOUR in about everything. Then ask the kids for help. They catch on quickly and those within reach toss in anything imaginary from &quot;potato seeds&quot; to pickles. Then I need to put the lid on the pan. I do this because it will keep the grease from splattering and making a really BIG mess. Plus, mamma always told me things cook quicker and hotter with a lid. 

As soon as I press the lid on the pan, it SNAPS into place, releasing the preloaded section with French fries. I quickly lift off they lid in excitement and anticipation of sampling my fries. Anxiously I dive in with my hand to grab one, quickly pulling back with a loud, &quot;OUCH!&quot; Activate the d&apos;lite thumb tip appearing to have severely burned my thumb on the hot fries! I begin shaking it and blowing on it in obvious pain.

If you work alone, you will need to quickly regain composure as you remember that you must &quot;COOL THE BURN&quot; using cool, cool water for a long, long time. With the other hand pick up the lota vase and begin pouring the cool water in front of the thumb tip. Each time the vase empties itself….exclaim that it&apos;s still burning…you need MORE water, and pour again, again, and again a seemingly unlimited source of water. Each time verbalize your message that you need plenty of cool, cool water for a long, long time. Eventually release the light on the thumb tip so the red goes away and you appear to be healed. 

Recap your message making sure you point out:
· ABC&apos;s of safety, Always Be Calm
· Cool a burn with cool water for a long time

This routine can be done alone or with an assistant. I have also done it without the d&apos;lite thumb tip and used an oversized &quot;thumb&quot; which I keep nestled inside of the load of fries so I can pick it up easily.

RECIPE FOR FOAM FRENCH FRIES
Find some foam ¾ to 1 inch thick. Cut into strips resembling French fries. The height needed will vary depending on if you use a dove or chick pan. Make sure they are plenty tall enough that they spring up high when you release them in the pan, making them very visible to the audience. You will want plenty of them so they fit snugly into the pan. Foam usually comes in cream or white color. After cutting into fries, spray paint yellow, then go over them lightly with brown, giving them a golden look. Don&apos;t load them with lid on until just prior to the show so they will keep their shape better. In other words, don&apos;t store them smashed inside of your dove/chick pan. 

( 6 )==========&gt; Call for HELP&lt;============
 CLOWNS.... Please Help by J.T. &quot;Bubba&quot; Sikes 
 
The XP society needs YOUR Help.  Most people have never heard of XP, so let me give you a quick overview. Xeroderma Pigmentosum (XP) is a rare genetic disorder affecting over a thousand children worldwide.  Exposure to sunlight for only
3 - 5 minutes can result in 3rd degree burns to their bodies.  These children can NEVER go outside during the daylight hours and play. They can NEVER have a normal life of playing with friends like other children do.  Most of the world looks at them as being different.  The only time these children get to play with others is at Camp Sundown.  This organization gets very help from Corporate America. The reason....there just isn&apos;t enough reported cases for them to get the publicity they need for their donation.  Please take time to visit www.XPS.org to learn about XP and the programs offered.

It takes about $300,000 each year to keep the Retreat Center, Summer Camp, Public Awareness and Research Programs going.  Without this money, these XP kids have nothing to look forward to each year.  We also need to raise money to build a Patio/Multipurpose Room onto the center.

 So.... Here&apos;s what you could do to help 

 • We are asking you or your Clown Alley to do ONE (1) Fund Raising              event this coming year and donate the proceeds to the XP         Society.  You could do Face painting, Balloons, Magic Show,  Clown Program or whatever.
• or, Put out a Tip Jar at one of your events and mark it for XP
• or, Donate the profits from One (1) Birthday Party. 

Listen, any gift is more than they have now and will be appreciated. We really need your help and I can&apos;t think of a better group of people, the clowns, to make these kids dreams come true .  Camp Sundown is their only chance to feel, act and be normal in the eyes of their peers. Please, truly consider the XP Society for your Clown Alleys Charity Donations this year and for years to come.  I can tell you from first hand experience after volunteering my clown services at camp in July 2003, this organization puts your donations to work to benefit anyone in the world with XP.  Everything they have has come form caring people that donate their time, money and talents. These people do it because they want to make a difference for the XP Kids.  The XP Society has NO highly paid officers running the society.  They have a board of directors that are Volunteers, just like many of us. Your Money WILL NOT go to pay Big Salaries and Administrative cost .  It goes to Camp Sundown, publicity to make people aware of this disorder and for research.  Even this flyer is donated so money is not taken from needed funds to operate camp.  This is an 501 &quot;c&quot; 3 organization.

You can now designate the XP Society for the Combined Federal Campaign.  Please tell your coworkers about this worthy organization.

Workplace Contribution Campaign Information:
1. Combined Federal Campaign (CFC) for Federal Government Employees:         Check with  your  administrating agency (often United Way).
2. Also, United Way workplace campaigns: The XP Society is assigned         number by  COUNTRY.  Please contact caren@... if you need a         number to designate the XP Society for your contributions.

Make checks Payable to: XP Society, Inc. 
 Mail checks to : XP Society, Inc., 437 Snydertown Road, Craryville, N.Y. 12521

**Note** Please forward this request for help to all your clown friends.  With your help, we CAN make a difference for these kids. 

( 7 ) ============&gt; THE END&lt;===========

What plans do you have for fire prevention week?
Need help with something? Looking for a skit or routine?

Drop me a line and I&apos;ll post it here where over 200 professionals can possibly help you out! Sparky@....

Have a safe week!

Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody
www.lafsforlife.org


 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #109 From: SparkyDMFD@...
 Date: Wed Oct 15, 2003 10:53 am
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #56 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Good morning!

Did y&apos;all survive Fire Prevention Week? Everyone resting up? However, it seems that here it lasts the entire month of October.

We had a great week. Our &quot;Build a Puppet&quot; station at our Open House was a complete success. Most of the children present were familiar with our puppet/clown program and found it to be &quot;pretty special&quot; to be able to actually make their own and learn how to use it behind the puppet curtain. We made basic sock puppets and had lots of little extras that could be added to them. It was fun to see some of the creations that came from some of the kids.

We&apos;re off to a &quot;struggling&quot; beginning of the school year as our major grant funding through our county was NOT renewed last May. This has had a profound effect on our characterization budget, which we continue to work on. 

We are hopeful to move into our new home sometime within the next week and when that happens I&apos;ll be dropping my AOL account completely and returning to cable. Make sure you have my e-mail address down as: Sparky@... and mail will always get to me wherever I&apos;m at.

There are a couple of requests for scripts here. If you have them, please consider sharing them with the group! We would all be interesting in your sharing! 

Have a safe week!

INDEX
( 1 )  Survivor Script Request
( 2 )  Cowboy Script Request
( 3 )  S.M.I.L.E. Conference
( 4 ) A.F.B.E.A. Conference
( 5 )  Dallas Area Training
( 6 )  Clown Camp
( 7 )  Watches
( 8 )   Inspiration
( 9 )  Humor

( 1 ) =======&gt;Survivor Script Request&lt;=========
Subj: Survivor program 
From: SWALKER@... 

Hey, guys, 

 Do you know who I can contact to see if they have a script for the &quot;Survivor&quot; fire safety program? THANKS!

( 2 ) =======&gt;Cowboy Skit Request&lt;========

 From: MLafon@... 


PAM THIS IS MARK (SQUIRT) FROM TEXAS. IF THERE IS ANY ONE WITH A COWBOY CLOWN SKIT WE ARE LOOKING. THANKS FOR YOUR TIME AND DEDICATION. HOPE EVERYTHING IS GOING  OKAY. GUESS MY RED RAIDERS WILL KICK THE CYCLONES
THIS WEEKEND.


( 3 ) ========&gt; SMILE CONFERENCE&lt;=========
Hosted in downtown Phoenix, AZ!
 November 21-23, 2003 
 S.M.I.L.E. Members………... $175
Non Members………………. $225
 Pay at the door …………….... $250 

 Please make checks for the conference payable to: S.M.I.L.E. And send them to:
 S.M.I.L.E.
PO Box 13971
Scottsdale, AZ.  85267-3971 

Great instructor lineup! Read all about it at the following website:
 Conference 

( 4 ) =======&gt; AFBEA Conference Update&lt;=========

From:  afbea@... 

We have updated the Characterization Camp Brochure and it is now online at
http://www.afbea.org/events.htm

Remember to get your registration forms in before December 19th. If you have
any questions regarding the camp you can contact us at afbea@... or call
Beverly at 480-858-7240.

( 5 ) =======&gt;Dallas Area Conference&lt;=========== 
 Dear Joey&apos;s: 

 It took a little longer than I anticipated, but it&apos;s done! My hour-by-hour (literally) journal from Mooseburger Camp is now posted at www.topper.us Trust me --------- it&apos;s long.........BUT! It tells the WHOLE story of Moosecamp! I imagine there are things in my journal that may have never been revealed before!! Plan to spend more than 2 minutes reading it! It&apos;s one of those stories that once you put down, you just can&apos;t pick it up again!  :)
 
 Now, some BIG news!! 

Many of you already know this and many others have already figured it out. And you&apos;ll ALL know it when you go to www.topper.us 

 I&apos;m bringing a 
 VERY SPECIAL EDITION 
 of Mooseburger Camp 
 to the Dallas/Ft. Worth area 
 March 18-21, 2004. 
 
 The website is almost complete and it will be accessible through www.topper.us very soon. 
 
 Here is what I can tell you about the
 SPECIAL EDITION CAMP! 
 
 It will be TREMENDOUS!!! 

 I am bringing in the best of the best of the best instructors, classes, merchandise and activities for this event! The camp will be held in Arlington, near Six Flags. 

 For scheduling purposes you should know that the FUN&amp;GAMES will start on THURSDAY AFTERNOON!! And once they start, they don&apos;t stop until Sunday afternoon about 4pm! 
 
 Classes, fun, learning and EXCITEMENT will run: 
 
 Thursday from about 4pm until Midnight! 
 Friday from about 6:30 a.m. until MIDNIGHT! 
 Saturday from about 6:30 a.m. until MIDNIGHT! 
 
 Sunday from about 6:30 a.m. until about 4:00 p.m. 
 
 OH YEAH!!! We&apos;re going to have a BLAST!!! 
 
 Arlington, Texas is billed as &quot;FUN CENTRAL&quot; 
 The hotel and the visitors bureau are 
 VERY excited about this Camp 
 and have bent over backwards to help make this happen! 

 How much more fun can you have, than 150 clowns in one room!? 

 The registration fee is ridiculously low! PLUS it will include 6 meals! Details soon! 
 
 We&apos;ll do a show on Sunday afternoon for a local Children&apos;s Charity as well! Details soon! 

 Each night we&apos;ll descend on a local restaurant, as a group, to entertain ourselves and them! They&apos;ll know we are there!!! And they&apos;ll never forget it! And neither will you! Bring your balloons! Bring your walk-around gags! Bring your walk-around magic tricks! Bring a fun attitude because we&apos;re going to have FUN! 

 After dinner, each night, we have a SUPERB event, too! No need to go back to the room and sleep! 
 With only a weekend to work with, my attitude is this - 
 SLEEP WHEN YOU GET HOME! HAVE FUN AND LEARN WHILE YOU ARE AT CAMP! 
 
 You will have an opportunity to meet and learn from some of the best of the best!! 
 
 Lunches will be working lunches. We&apos;ll have great info to absorb as we recharge our batteries each day! 

 Even though we have long, FUN, days, I&apos;ve worked plenty of breaks into the schedule at regular intervals. We all know that the brain can only absorb what your rear-end can withstand! So there will be plenty of breaks, time in the dealer room, snacks, etc...

The Vendors will be THE BEST! We&apos;ve got the best of the best, PLUS I&apos;ll have a few UNIQUE vendors that you&apos;ve never seen before! And it won&apos;t be &quot;the same old stuff&quot; on the shelves either! Yes, we&apos;ll have the staples of clowning, but we&apos;re going to have the new, interesting, unique, &quot;GOTTA HAVE IT STUFF&quot; that you want, too! 
 
 We&apos;ll have a &quot;TALENT SHOW&quot; one night for you to strut your stuff for camp-mates! 
 We&apos;ll have a balloon tying contest too! Bring your own balloons and pumps! 
 We&apos;ll have lot&apos;s of FUN and ENTERTAINING activities, information and classes! 

 This camp is for YOU!! If you have NEVER been a clown, this is the PERFECT place to start! If you have been a clown for 40 years, this is the PERFECT place to recharge your batteries and put on a fresh new look! 
 
 The age range is 13 - 113. This is a FUN camp, but a lot of serious learning will take place. It will overwhelm small kids. 

 There will be an early registration discount!!! GET READY! 
 
 Also, there is a limit on the number of campers we can accept . There are definite limits on the number of people we can put in the rooms we&apos;ve booked so my best advice to you is to REGISTER EARLY! The number of folks already knocking at my door, just from word of mouth, is quite shocking! I already know of 2 groups planning to attend with 6-12 people per group! There REALLY IS a limit on the number of registrants, by design. Don&apos;t miss out! Register early!

That&apos;s it for now! Stay tuned for more info!

Best Wishes,
Carl E Jones
Topper the Magic Clown
 www.topper.us 
 Dallas, Texas 
 
 ( 6 ) ==========&gt;Clown Camp 2004&lt;=======

Information is being updated on the Clown Camp website for the Community Safety Education track June 12-18, 2004.   Daily class schedules are not yet posted, but fees, etc, are updated for budget requests! If you&apos;ve never been, you won&apos;t want to miss this fabulous educational week! 
 
 Courses for 2004 

 ( 7 )===========&gt;Watches&lt;============

These are so cool.....Sparky has one and it&apos;s quite a conversation piece! I wear it on top of my shirt so I can see it easily and so can the kids! It&apos;s all miniature &quot;fire stuff&quot; and personalized with &quot;Sparky!&quot;  

 WhimsicalWatches.com 

Greetings from Whimsical Watches,

Hope you had a nice summer.  We recently moved our studio to a larger sunny
location in Atlanta.  The move did not stop our creative minds, we have many
new watch styles.    Do visit our site www.WhimsicalWatches.com.

Before the rush of the holiday season, we are offering:
FREE Shipping on orders of two or more watches.
Order 4 watches take 10% off,  Plus Free Shipping
Mention this email when ordering.

We look forward to hearing from you.

Marilyn, Dee and Mary
800 320 1014
Whimsical Watches(tm) - Home of the original watch with miniatures.
www.whimsicalwatches.com

Marilyn Hume
marilyn@...
800-320-1014

 ( 8 )  =========&gt;Inspiration&lt;==============
 ALL USED UP

A well-known surgeon was attending a dinner party and watched the host
adroitly carve and slice the large turkey for his guests.

When he finished slicing, the host asked, &quot;How did I do, Doc?  I think
I&apos;d make a pretty good surgeon, don&apos;t you?&quot;

&quot;Perhaps,&quot; said the physician. &quot;But anyone can take them apart. Now
let&apos;s see you put it back together again.&quot;

Like surgery, some tasks require special talent, skill or training.
Not everyone can be a surgeon. Many do not have the aptitude to teach
a class or repair an automobile, nor can most of us cook a gourmet
meal, play the piano expertly, or solve a complex mathematical
problem. But we can each contribute.

Spanish cellist Pablo Casals said, &quot;Don&apos;t be vain because you happen
to have talent. You are not responsible for that; it was not of your
doing. What you do with your talent is what matters.&quot;

On the other hand, don&apos;t be discouraged because you believe you have
no ability. Each of us has much to offer. What you do with the ability
you have is what matters.

Erma Bombeck was known for her humorous journalism. But she frequently
seasoned her humor with pinches of wisdom. At the end of a newspaper
column on March 10, 1987, Erma wrote these words:

&quot;I always had a dream that when I am asked to give an accounting of my
life to a higher court, it will go like this: &apos;So, empty your pockets.
What have you got left of your life? Any dreams that were unfulfilled?

Any unused talent that we gave you when you were born that you still
have left? Any unsaid compliments or bits of love that you haven&apos;t
spread around?

&quot;And I will answer, &apos;I&apos;ve nothing to return. I spent everything you
gave me. I&apos;m as naked as the day I was born.&apos;&quot; She would agree that
what we do with the talent we&apos;re given is all that matters.

Do you still have some encouragement that you haven&apos;t spread around?
Do you have ability you have not used up? Do you still have some bits
of love to share?

If you were asked to empty your pockets today, will you find them
half-full? Or will you discover that you have joyously spent
everything you were given?

Get Books By Steve Goodier Here: (877) 344-0989
 http://lifesupportsystem.com/books.html 
 
 ( 9 ) ========&gt; Humor&lt;============= 

 Due to a power outage at the time, only one paramedic responded to the call.

The house was very, very dark, so the paramedic asked Katelyn, a 3-year-old girl, to hold a flashlight high over her mommy so he could see while he helped deliver the baby. Very diligently, Katelyn did as she was asked.

Her Mommy pushed and pushed, and after a little while Connor was born.

The paramedic lifted him by his little feet and spanked him on his bottom.
Connor then began to cry.

The paramedic thanked Katelyn for her help and asked the wide-eyed 3-year old what she thought about what she had just witnessed.

Katelyn quickly responded, &quot;He shouldn&apos;t have crawled in there in the first place. Smack him again.&quot;


========&gt; The End&lt;=========

Please continue to send me material to share, questions, skits, magic and resources! Have a great FALL! (enjoying the color show of leaves here in the Midwest!)

Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody
www.lafsforlife.org
















 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #110 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Oct 30, 2003 1:05 am
 Subject: LifeSafety special newsletter sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 I&apos;m forwarding on to you a FREE internet clowning newsletter that is available and a wonderful resource. It&apos;s actually been around for several years, previously known as &quot;Soda Pop&apos;s Newsletter.&quot; It recently changed hands and has even gotten better. Subscription information is contained within if you&apos;re interested in receiving it biweekly.   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org   ----- Original Message ----- From: Clown Education Online To: Sparky@... Sent: Wednesday, October 29, 2003 5:21 PM Subject: The Clown Newsletter: Issue 326 
 
 
 Published with: 

 
 Formerly Soda Pop&apos;s Newsletter Issue 326 

  
 
 Newsletter Response Menu 
 
 Submit a New Article 
 
 Reply to an Article 
 
 Answer Weekly Question 
 
 Suggest Weekly Question 
 
 Submit Weekly Gag/Joke 
 
 Unsubscribe 
 
  Subscribe 
   
 Post Text Link Ad for $5!   
 
 Garage Sale Item for $5! 
 
 Advertise on Top Banner 
 
 Advertise on SideBar Badge 
     
 
   
 
 
 Good day Pam! 
 In This Issue: 
 From Duffer&apos;s Desk 
 S.M.I.L.E. Conference Ad 
 Non-smoking Ideas 
 Mermaid calling out for caring clowns! 
 All I want for Christmas is my 2 buck teeth! 
 Lions Club Clown Alley... 
 Please help!!! 
 Requesting Gospel Clown Info 
 The Great Clown Adventure Ad 
 Re: Face Painting 
 Re: Toby KID&apos;s Brain Twisters! 
 Party Hats... 
 How far have I gone? 
 From Jackie LeClaire 
 Dear Jackie... 
 About Poppi... 
 Where in the world have I been? 
 Do you smell Fowl Humor? 
 Re: Coffee Gag/givaway ideas 
 Lost N Found? 
 Breakfast @ McDonald&apos;s 
 School Shows 
 Letters to the Editor 
 What&apos;s For Sale 
 Weekly Question Answers 
 Weekly Question 326 
 Weekly Gag 
 This Week&apos;s Sponsors 
 
 From Duffer&apos;s Desk 
 Hi everyone,
The bi-weekly schedule has started, and I felt was a very good success. I only received 250 or so returned emails. This might not sound good, but in fact it is, dealing with this newsletter. You may notice that we have our top banner sponsors back, for those that receive the html version. Please visit their web sites by clicking on the banners&amp;text ad links. they help keep the newsletter alive.
Last time, I think I accidentally left out some articles I meant to place in the newsletter. So I am including them in this issue. As you can see yet another very large newsletter this week! in fact, some of you wrote in last minute and I&apos;ll have to keep those posts for next newsletter. I&apos;m trying to find a way to organize all of my email boxes, forms and links, they are getting very messy, its like trying to find a specific paper on an extremely cluttered desk. Many different ideas going here there and everywhere. So I&apos;ll be cleaning them up and removing some forms of communication. It is all a matter of testing what works and what doesn&apos;t.
I need to ask you all to do some things for me. When you are replying to an article, please state in the message what article you are referring to. If you quote it, this will help me out a lot! Also, if you would like to get a private reply, please include your email address at the end of your message.
Trick or Treat! Smell my big clown feet! Hope you all have a great Halloween Friday! Where I live, we don&apos;t get any trick or treaters, so I&apos;m brain storming ideas for when I move into my new place where I&apos;m expecting some! I&apos;ll be able to flex my creative Halloween ideas.
I&apos;ve run into some roadblocks and detours, but I&apos;m trying to straighten them out, I&apos;ll spare you all the details. But I have some great plans, whether they pan out, I don&apos;t know yet. I&apos;ll keep ya posted!
Duffer 
 

     Back to Top 
 Click here to submit or reply to an article. 
   
 
 
 www.smileclowns.org/Conference.htm 
 SMILE Conference 2003, November 21-23 in
Phoenix, Arizona. Safety Magic In Law Enforcement!
Lead Instructors: Dave Mitchell and Terry Ricketts
 
 
 Back to Top 
 
 
 Non-smoking Ideas 
 Thanks so much for all the ideas for non-smoking routines. I appreciate the
time all of you took to help. Several of the ideas have given me a good
place to start.
Karl Koch
&quot;Cookie&quot;
-----------------------------
I&apos;m responding to KKOCH&apos;s article because I&apos;m also looking for material to use in an anti smoking performance, and would like to know if he would be willing to share any info gathered from the newsletter. Skits, magic or whatever. Thank you for your help. Also to Duffer, I, like many others, appreciate you stepping up to take over the newsletter. Thanks for your time and effort, God bless. Dan Knight
merrygoclowns@... 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Mermaid calling out for caring clowns! 
 Hello Duffer 1 thanks for keeping this alive.
My name is Doodlesz and the question I have is ...2 part.
1.
My dad lives with my sister and brother-in-law in Tallahassee FL and he has a light case of Parkinson disease... I was wondering if there are any clowns out there (who live in Tally of course!:)) who would pay him a clown visit ???
2.
does anyone out there live in Wildwood Fl???
I use to work at Weeki Wachee Springs as a mermaid and one of my good friends is there helping with the retired Mermaids and her father also has Parkinson disease . Her Mom is taking care of him and I thought it might be nice if she received a clown visit to lift her spirits !!!???
Contact me personally at: scrabbleladyz@...

Doodlesz D Clown 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 All I want for Christmas is my 2 buck teeth! 
 Hi everyone. I am so glad to be getting the newsletter again. Couldn&apos;t
get it for a long time before. Webtv just took way to long to load.
Anyway I need some info.
Does anyone have an address or info for anyone that has the &quot;false buck
teeth&quot; ? Not the Billy-bob teeth. Ones that they had made by a dentist ?
I have e-mailed a few clowns that sport these teeth but they have not
replied to me.
I have gone to my dentist for them. The problem is that he can&apos;t find
teeth that &quot;LONG&quot;. I was hoping if someone else has had them done they
could give me the dentist name or any info that will help.
Keep up the good work on the newsletter.
Thank you
Jackie Killeen
Dolly-Doo the Clown
Nassau, New York 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Lions Club Clown Alley... 
 My Lions club has formed a clowns club and we would like to know how to put together a charter and by-laws/rules. Is there a recommended format and guidelines? Please let me know how you set up the structure for your club. Thanks.

kathyjim@... 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Please help!!! 
 I have been asked to do educational sessions, i.e.. inservices on
Teamwork, Alzheimer&apos;s disease, the Aging process for a health care
facility. They wanted it done in clown to get a message across. I
have no idea on how to do this and where to obtain resources. Any
ideas? I would like to implement clowning and education in some way as
a goal for our clowns. Please help!!!
Gerrie &quot;Blossom&quot; Healy
mth@... 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Requesting Gospel Clown Info 
 hey there
I am also a new clown within the last year or so, and as a Christian I have
a few skits that fit the gospel bill but any information on this topic would
be greatly appreciated, thank you
patches d&apos; clown
________________
I, too would like Gospel Clown information. I would like to attend a
short training session and also write to people and share ideas.
Belinda &quot;Binty&quot; Sims, bsims4@...
 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 
 Unique Competitions - Affordable&amp;Fun
February 22 - 26, 2004 in Las Vegas!
www.greatclownadventure.com 
 
 Back to Top 
 
 
 Re: Face Painting 
 to a post from Twinkie Dee regarding face painting.
I didn&apos;t realize until last night I could just reply to a post right
through the newsletter, so if not too late, can you pass this on to
Twinkie for me.
She mentioned Jim Howle paints and paint brushes, where do you buy
these? I&apos;ve tried searching the internet, might not be putting in the
right words because I&apos;m not having any luck.
I&apos;m a young clown who would love to do cheek art for my grandkids
birthday parties, but don&apos;t intend to start a business. Could Twinkie
recommend any good books for the simple drawings such as rainbows,
balloons, cars, what ever might appeal to little kids.
Any suggestions at all would be appreciated. I do have artistic talent,
but am nervous about trying to paint something on &quot;skin&quot;, especially if
there is a wiggly child in the skin.
Thank you.
Twinkie can reply directly to my home email: snickers1019@...
Donna (Snickers) Hanzal
132 East Demont Avenue
Little Canada, MN 55117
651 483-2891
 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Re: Toby KID&apos;s Brain Twisters! 
 When does one cross from craftsmen to artist?=20
Answer- I think a craftsmen is someone who excels in their craft, =
whatever craft it may be but they might have a little tunnel vision. An =
artist is someone who might take that craft a step further, color =
outside the lines .=20
What is the age group you target your clowning too?=20
Answer- I entertain mostly at children&apos;s birthday parties or children&apos;s =
events, so I cater to children, but I find the adults are just as =
entertained by what I do for the children as the children are.=20
Are you as funny when your not clowning as when you are?=20
I am a mother, moms are always being make fun of, the brunt of the =
jokes, laughed at etc. So I guess the answer to this question is YES.
If you have a day job, has your day job and clowning ever crossed? For=20
good? For bad?=20
I am a stay at home mom, if there is such at thing, see above.
When clowning in a hospital do you visit adults as well as children? Do=20
you do anything special for the nurses and other staffers?
I have not clowned in a hospital in a many years. I tried to do special =
balloons for the staff and hand out stickers to them, even sand them =
songs. I bet they are glad I stopped going!!!!
2tfruity@... 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Party Hats... 
 Hi Duffer and gang,
I like that you went back to the &apos;old&apos; way the newsletter was printed and
sent. I&apos;m not hooked up to the Internet, so I missed most of what was
sent. Thanks!! Any hoodle... I&apos;ve been shopping again and I found some out
of this world party hats. I went to Clown Camp in May and while I was
there Don and Dee Burda did a birthday party routine on stage one night.
Of course it was wonderful. But... they had on these hats that EVERYONE
went crazy over. But when they had bought them they were in the clearance
section. Well I found them!!!!!
Here in Arizona we have TARGET stores. They now are carrying them in the
party section. And they&apos;re only $9.99. I&apos;ll describe them for you. There
are 2 different styles but they come in lots of colors. One is a cone
shaped hat that has a face on it. It has a big colored nose, huge eyes, a
smile with a tongue sticking out, and eyebrows. There&apos;s a tassel on top.
Lots of big and small circles, squares and such. there&apos;s a puffy brim
that matches the nose. This hat is made of a chenille type material
that&apos;s extremely soft.
The other style is shaped like a birthday cake. It too has big eyes, a
smile with a tongue sticking out. Material candles on top. Decorations
out of material and colored ropes. And it to has a puffy brim.
Now if you don&apos;t have a Target store and you want to see what these look
like, email me and I&apos;ll send you an attachment of a photo of them. Or the
tag on the inside reads: &quot;My Favorite Company, Inc. Commonwealth Toy&amp;
Novelty Co., Inc. New York, NY, Bunde, The Netherlands. Style 89659. -
053-03-0210. /deotm /ck Uten.
OK? OK!
Keep up the great work.
Julie &quot;Lovely Buttons&quot; Varholdt
julievarholdt@...
Duffer Note: The &quot;Old Way&quot;? You mean all text? You must have something set in your email client that makes it a text email, cause I&apos;m still using graphics and you are not signed up as text in the mailing list. Its probably because I&apos;m using lower res graphics. This is probably why many of you especially the WebTV crowd are able to read the newsletter again. With the program Rick used and gave me, it produces a text and html version simultaneously as I compile it. there are many pros and cons to both versions. I obviously concentrate on the html version. I may cover more about this in a later issue. 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 How far have I gone? 
 What was the furthest that I did a gig?
During 1994 while attending Clown Camp in La Crosse, WI, Richard
Snowberg asked me if I wouldn&apos;t want to help him with a performance &quot;out
of town&quot;. I was more than happy to do. I must be honest, I can&apos;t
remember now what the name of the town or state was, but I do remember
that it was at the Black Hawk College.
Richard decided to show me some of the country site and we took a scenic
drive next to the Mississippi for a very long time. I am speaking under
correction, but I think that it was close to a 3 hours (or perhaps even
longer) drive from La Crosse. Do I hear some of you say, &quot;3 hours,
that&apos;s nothing&quot;.
Oh, sorry, it is my mistake, I forgot to mention that it takes a total
of plus minus 35 hours to travel from Pretoria, South Africa to La
Crosse, Wisconsin. So, that would make it a total of close to 38 hours
of traveling time to the gig that have seen the furthest away from
my home.
PS Richard, if you read this, won&apos;t you please refresh my memory about
the name of the town and state where we performed that year, and also
how far it is from La Crosse?
Best wishes
Piet Nortje. 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 From Jackie LeClaire 
 Most of the routines I learned and did with my father were circus
oriented. At the time we worked together, we were not in the clown
world that you are in today.
I work today in the Circus Sarasota&apos;s Laughter Unlimited program and one
of my partners is Barry DeChant, also known as &quot;Bonzo&quot; the clown.
He has written a book &quot;Complete Book Of Skits&quot;. It is excellent, and
things are explained that with some practice, the average clown can
perform them. I recommend it highly to you.
I have included, his email address above and will repeat it again. I
am sure if you contact him, he may still have some for sale. I also
understand that he has written other books, and at least working on, or
already in print, one on Clown Ministry. We do some of these routines
with the Laughter Unlimited Clowns.
Barry DuChant. &quot;Bonzo&quot; Bonzkari@...
Good Laughluck to you, Jackie LeClaire
http://community.webtv.net/JACKIELECLAIRE/JACKIELECLAIREClown
http://community.webtv.net/JACKIELECLAIRE/ClownPhotosJackie
 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Dear Jackie... 
 Dear Jackie,
I am happy to see that you are contributing your insights and opinions to an online newsletter for clowns. I am glad to see that you are still active and getting around in the clowning field. Waldo and I have always been very fond of you, and would have liked to have seen you at Clownfest held in CHerry Hill, NJ this year.
Bump a nose,
Tulip
 waldo@... 
 
 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 About Poppi... 
 I have been a Clown all my life. The only problem was he didn&apos;t come out
right away.
But about 9 years ago, with the help of my Wife and a Clown I met at a
street fair They got me started as Poppi&quot;T&quot;Clown. Who found another Clown hiding
inside him. and that started Dr Chick N Pox on his tour of Hospital Clowning.
between the 3 of us I&apos;m having the time of my life. I have met so many
wonderful people and learned some many ways to make a frown turn into a smile. Thank
you to all that have crossed our path (POPPI ,DR CHICK. AND ME Jack)
A Clown&apos;s Smile And Mind is A Shame To Waste
Bump A Nose
Poppi&quot;T&quot;Clown


 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Where in the world have I been? 
 Hi Duffer just back in the country after being away so I thought that I
should answer the last question about the furtherest away to being a
klown. I live in New Zealand and I have been both to Finland and the UK to
klown. I am not sure of miles/km but it involves over 27 hours worth of
flying time from Heathrow to my home and about 29 to Helsinki!!
As a side issue I want to state in public a HUGE thanks to Toto who I
visited while in the States. There was nothing that was a problem. We went
to Wisconsin and saw the Clown World Museum, Greg and Karen Di Santo in
action, (still smiling about that), and a whole lot more. He is a great
guy and I want to say thanks a heap mate!!
Cheers Dave/Mischief McKlown


 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Do you smell Fowl Humor? 
 Because I lost my most favorite juggling bunnies, I went out and found myself some new juggling friends, Beanie baby: duck, goose&amp;turkey. I can think of a few one-liners and gags for them, but possibly you can help me out in a longer list?
Thanks,
Duffer 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Re: Coffee Gag/givaway ideas 
 I like to make up small plastic bags of cheerios, usually 6 in a bag, and
staple it shut. Pass them out as doughnut seeds. Adults love these.
Bobbie Belle
---------------------------
Coffee
I did this at a trade show. &quot;up stream&quot; from the booth I
was working, was a booth dispensing free coffee. So I stole
a bit from Mr. Bean:
The next day I arrived at the trade show with a small baby
bottle filled with milk! Kept it chilled in my pocket with
a pack of Blue Ice. When I spotted someone carrying a cup
of coffee, I would hold out my baby bottle of milk, and ask
them if they wanted some!
Quite a few accepted! Went over big, except for a couple
that seemed to think it might be human breast milk!
Walking tall and stretching imaginations!
Bill &quot;Stretch&quot; Coleman
http://www.stiltwalker.com/
--------------------------------
Flutter-Bee
last year you gave out a free B how about a Brown E to go with your coffee?
Sounds like fun!
MertsPub@...
--------------------------
Hi Duffer!
Re. ideas for walk-arounds/giveaways...here is a cute one that I enjoy and so do the people I approach...walk up to someone and ask them if they have ever received a kiss from a clown, 99% of the people will say no, ask them to pucker up and when they do you hand them a Hershey&apos;s candy kiss. Very simple and very inexpensive but really sweet!!! Piperoni the clown with the Happy Clowns of Hemet, CA
--- Albert Piper
--- aspiper@...
------------------------


 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Lost N Found? 
 Hello, I recently misplaced one of my all time favorite magic tricks of almost 11 years. I think I originally got it at the WRCA convention in Laughlin. It was made by Ickle Pickle who informs me that it has been almost 2 years since it has been around. I&apos;m very confident that if I look and ask around enough someone will find this trick collecting dust somewhere. Please let me know if you have any clues as to where I can purchase the following trick.
One two three color wilting flower - A lazer tube houses a white feather flower that can be turned into three (pink,yellow and red) feather flowers. The middle flower can wilt or bow and at the end all three can bow. It is listed on the Daytona Magic website as part number FF010 but unfortunately it is no longer available. I would really appreciate someone finding this trick as it has brought sooooooo much enjoyment over the years.
Klinko the klown - Klinko @ cox.net&lt;:O)


 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Breakfast @ McDonald&apos;s 
 I think this is something that we can all learn from and should be included in the next newsletter. Thanks, TNT
tntclown@...

This is a good story and is true .
I am a mother of three (ages 14, 12, 3) and have recently completed my
college degree.
The last class I had to take was Sociology.
The teacher was absolutely inspiring with the qualities that I wish every
human being had been graced with.
Her last project of the term was called &quot;Smile.&quot;
The class was asked to go out and smile at three people and document their
reactions.
I am a very friendly person and always smile at everyone and say hello
anyway, so, I thought this would be a piece of cake, literally.
Soon after we were assigned the project, my husband, youngest son, and I
went out to McDonald&apos;s one crisp March morning.
It was just our way of sharing special playtime with our son.
We were standing in line, waiting to be served, when all of a
sudden, everyone
around us began to back away, and then even my husband did.
I did not move an inch... an overwhelming feeling of panic welled up
inside
of me as I turned to see why they had moved.
As I turned around I smelled a horrible &quot;dirty body&quot; smell, and there
standing behind me were two poor homeless men.
As I looked down at the short gentleman, close to me, he was &quot;smiling&quot;.
His beautiful sky blue eyes were full of God&apos;s Light as he searched for
acceptance.
He said, &quot;Good day&quot; as he counted the few coins he had been clutching.
The second man fumbled with his hands as he stood behind his friend. I
realized the second man was mentally challenged and the blue-eyed
gentleman
was his salvation.
I held my tears as I stood there with them.
The young lady at the counter asked him what they wanted.
He said, &quot;Coffee is all Miss&quot; because that was all they could afford. (If
they wanted to sit in the restaurant and warm up, they had to buy
something.
He just wanted to be warm).
Then I really felt it - the compulsion was so great I almost reached out
and
embraced the little man with the blue eyes.
That is when I noticed all eyes in the restaurant were set on me, judging
my
every action.
I smiled and asked the young lady behind the counter to give me two more
breakfast meals on a separate tray.
I then walked around the corner to the table that the men had chosen as a
resting spot. I put the tray on the table and laid my hand on the
blue-eyed
gentleman&apos;s cold hand.
He looked up at me, with tears in his eyes, and said, &quot;Thank you.&quot;
I leaned over, began to pat his hand and said, &quot;I did not do this for you.
God is here working through me to give you hope.&quot;
I started to cry as I walked away to join my husband and son. When I sat
down my husband smiled at me and said, &quot;That is why God gave you to me,
Honey, to give me hope.&quot;
We held hands for a moment and at that time, we knew that only because of
the Grace that we had been given were we able to give.
We are not church goers, but we are believers.
That day showed me the pure Light of God&apos;s sweet love.
I returned to college, on the last evening of class, with this story in
hand...
I turned in &quot;my project&quot; and the instructor read it.
Then she looked up at me and said, &quot;Can I share this?&quot;
I slowly nodded as she got the attention of the class.
She began to read and that is when I knew that we as human beings and
being
part of God share this need to heal people and to be healed.
In my own way I had touched the people at McDonald&apos;s, my husband, son,
instructor, and every soul that shared the classroom on the last night I
spent as a college student.
I graduated with one of the biggest lessons I would ever learn:
UNCONDITIONAL ACCEPTANCE.
Much love and compassion is sent to each and every person who may read
this
and learn how to LOVE PEOPLE AND USE THINGS - NOT LOVE THINGS AND USE
PEOPLE...
If you think this story has touched you in any way, please send this to
everyone you know.
There is an Angel sent to watch over you.
In order for her to work, you must pass this on to the people you want
watched over.
An Angel wrote:
Many people will walk in and out of your life, but only true friends will
leave footprints in your heart.
To handle yourself, use your head.
To handle others, use your heart.
God Gives every bird it&apos;s food, but He does not throw it into its nest. 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 School Shows 
 Hi everybody,
This is Piet &quot;Bubbels&quot; Nortje from Pretoria, South =
Africa. I must say that I like the (3-in-1) question of the week =
concerning school shows.
Some years ago I started to realize that (sadly) there wasn&apos;t really a =
demand for clowns at schools anymore and I did some research on the =
possible reasons for this.
I came to the conclusion that there were a couple of reasons for this. =
Most of the schools was of the opinion that most of the clowns that they =
have been using in the past didn&apos;t have an &quot;age appropriate&quot; kind of show =
to offer and this had the result that school most kids in the 6th and =
7th grade just wasn&apos;t interested to come and watch a clown show.
Secondly it was quite true that a lot of the clowns and magicians over =
here simply just haven&apos;t invest the required time to adapt to the fact =
that we have to be able to &quot;compete&quot; against other types of =
entertainment such as Playstation games and computers. Kid&apos;s are much =
wiser at an earlier age these days and we need to really know what to do =
and how to do it to really entertain and impress them if we want to do =
school shows.
(In South Africa children start their school &quot;career&quot; at the age of 6 =
years in Grade 0 and they continue their &quot;primary school&quot; career up =
until the 7th grade). High school is from 8th to 12th grade.)
So, about 8 years ago I had the opportunity to do a specific kind of =
school show that was aimed at a specific age (and target) group. This =
was a show that was aimed at kids that was going to school for the first =
time at the beginning of the next year. The school year in South Africa =
is (more or less) from mid January to begin December.

Each year our schools have an &quot;open&quot; day and this is basically nothing =
less than a marketing effort to get parents to sign their kid&apos;s up to a =
specific school for the following year and it is mainly aimed at the =
Grade 0 and Grade 1 children. ( 6, 7 8 year age group.) These open days =
are spread out from August to November.
That first year I did two of this type of shows, but to be honest, I =
wouldn&apos;t really say that it was a &quot;proper&quot; theme show for that occasion, =
but I did get the feeling of what could be done and also how to go about =
to &quot;formulate&quot; a show that can and will work.
I talked to the teachers in charge of the &quot;open day&quot; project and at =
first I also realized that they didn&apos;t really had an idea what exactly =
they would expect from a clown at such a venue. They just wanted to =
&quot;kill some time&quot;.
So, I put on my &quot;thinking cap&quot; and I did some more research on this =
matter. This eventually lead me to put together a show that is =
specifically aimed, targeted, marketed and performed at Primary School&apos;s =
open day&apos;s. I mainly deals with that little bit of fear and uncertainty =
which most of the kid&apos;s are experiencing (in our country) when they are =
&quot;going-to-the-big-school&quot;.(That is &quot;kid talk&quot; for going to a &quot;formal&quot; =
school.)
Eight years down the road and my &quot;BUBBELS-is-going-to-the-big-school&quot; =
show is a big hit not only at schools in and around my town, but also in =
neighboring towns.
The first year I did only 2 schools, the following year it was 5 schools =
and it has grown to 45 schools so far for this year, and I am still =
getting inquiries on a almost daily basis.
This year I have taken the time and effort to prepare a nice flyer in =
which I state exactly what my program is all about and I have faxed it =
to all the primary schools in Pretoria. It has kind of snowballed from =
there to the schools in other towns and I am glad about this.
My presentation contains some visual magic, funny-bits, silly clown =
stuff ,sight gags and basic 3 ball juggling. All the story lines =
(patter) are about Bubbles&apos; &quot;fear&quot; when he had to go to the big school.
I think one of the most valuable &quot;tools&quot; that I have introduced (this =
year) to my show is my &quot;Bubbels School Rapport Card&quot;. I printed a letter =
in which I explained to the teacher/s in charge of the open day that I =
invite their advice, suggestions and critique on my show and it&apos;s =
content. I have also made a &quot;Rapport Card&quot; that they have to fill out =
and mail back to me. I also provide a stamped self addressed envelope. =
These rapport cards gives me a very good indication of how to (if =
needed) change or adapt my show to make it even more successful.
About two years ago, one of the original first two teachers that has =
booked this show of mine, came to me with the request of a possible =
&quot;circus theme&quot; show for the kids in the 2 and 3 rd grades as the circus =
is part of the school curriculum. I followed the same procedure and now =
I normally are busy with a circus theme show at local schools during =
February and March of each year.
My advice for possible schools shows; be age appropriate in whatever you =
are going to do at schools. Try to identify a &quot;theme&quot; or target group, =
get a working show together for that group and hit the market with it.
Best wishes
Piet Nortje
partyfun@... 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 Letters to the Editor 
 Thanks for continuing the great work of the &quot;Soda Pop Newsletter!&quot; The new format is good. Keep up the good work. -Steve Bissell (not Kissell) A/K/A Bubee B. Bulbenik
--------------------------
Bless you, Rick and all of the staff that work on the newsletter. It is so helpful to so many. Thanks and I will look forward to the next one.
Penny
-----------------------
I am a volunteer/caring clown. As a volunteer clown or any other type =
&quot;volunteer&quot;, my philosophy has always been family and health first!! =
Enjoyment in what I am doing comes next. When any one of these was put =
into jeopardy, I knew it was time to pull back. I am very grateful to =
you for this letter, so please continue with the great information, =
education and entertainment, but do it, so that you get the same rewards =
without causing any problems in your life. No one is sitting at the =
computer doing the work but you----that makes you the =
CEO!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! Do it your way!!
Gratefully,
Reeneea &quot;Star&quot; Schraeder 
 
 Click here to reply to article. 
 

 Back to Top 
 
 
 
 For Sale: Great for parades and food fairs, etc.
 One large chicken suit which looks like you are riding the chicken . Your
legs are actually the chicken legs and you have fake legs that looks like
you are riding....this is a great costume, asking $500.00 plus shipping.
Check out my web page and you can look at me riding it. sunshine@... 
Web site: http://www.nnex.net/~sunshine 
 
 
 Click here To Submit an Item for Sale 
 
 Back to Top  
 
 
 
 
 
 What do you write in your Thank You notes? 
 
 
 Carmen Tellez 
 Hello again __________________,

Thank you so much again for inviting Charm and Happy to your son (or daughter) ____________ party. You
know he&apos;ll always remember his _______th (or st) birthday. Especially when he saw grandpa wearing that
silly apron frying Charms big goofy looking fish during games time.

Seems like you and dad couldn&apos;t stop laughing when Charm asked the kids who&apos;s daddy knows how to
make funny noises like a clown. Well I don&apos;t think either one of us expected little __________&apos;s answer
and description.

Please keep us in mind for future family events. We really had a fun time.

Carmen Tellez
CharmandHappy.com
562-948-5342 tel.
============== end======
I try to make the note personalized and help them remember specific fun highlights of the party.
carmen@... 
 

     Back to Top 
 Click here to submit or reply to an article. 
   
 
 &quot;Toto&quot; Johnson 
 My &quot;thank you&quot; notes are quite simple...just a &quot;thank you for having
Colossal Clowns International at your event&quot; type note...but I write them on cards
with a photo of a painting of me on the front.
&quot;Toto&quot; Johnson
P.S. In response to Toby Kid&apos;s comments from the last newsletter...
Hahahahaha...I HAVE been to Maine and Alaska, but you still have me beat as
I have only been to 46 states. I still have North Dakota, South Dakota,
Montana, and Hawaii to go. So far the countries visited/performed in (or a
combination of both) are Canada, Mexico, Bahamas, England, Scotland, Denmark,
Sweden, Norway, Russia, Portugal, Finland, and Japan. I also spent a 1/2 hour at
the airport in Frankfurt, Germany but that really doesn&apos;t count.


 
 

     Back to Top 
 Click here to submit or reply to an article. 
   
 
 Buttons the Clown 
 Hi,
I address the handmade postcard to The (Jones) Family. I start out by
thanking them for asking me to be a part of (Sally&apos;s) (6th) birthday
celebration. I compliment the birthday child for being such a good
helper. I tell (Sally) I hope she will think of me whenever she plays
with the gift I gave her. Sometimes I compliment the birthday child&apos;s
friends. If I have been given a tip, I note how much I appreciated the
bonus given. I ask them to please refer me to their friends who might
need a clown. When someone does recommend me to someone who does book
me, I send a card to that person thanking them for doing
so. Buttons the Clown

 
 

     Back to Top 
 Click here to submit or reply to an article. 
   
 

 
 What is the best way to market your services to restaurants&amp;their owners/managers for a weekly or monthly appearance for a &quot;Kids Night&quot;?
suggested by: Glynis 
 

 
 
 Click here to submit an Answer 
 Click here to submit a Question! 
 Back to Top 
 
 
 
 Old Polaroid cameras make great sticker dispensers. Open up the
back and feed the stickers through the slot where film comes out. Take a
picture of you subject, then give them their photo. I like the ones
with smiley faces on them with different sunglasses on each sticker. I
comment on how handsome or cute they are in their photo. You could also
use animal stickers, etc. This can be a walk around that last along
time, and adds humor to the passing out sticker walkaround clowns.
Happy Smiles!
Linda Hartin
Colors da Clown
lhartin@... 
 Click here to submit a gag 
 
 This Week&apos;s Sponsors 


 http://chucklesheart.com/wst_page2.php
http://greatclownadventure.com/
http://www.flashyfootwearco.com/
http://www.smileclowns.org/Conference.htm 

 Back to top 



 
 Copyright Oct 30, 2003 CEO . All rights reserved. 
 Contact Us 
 &quot;When you&apos;re green you grow; When you&apos;re ripe you rot.&quot; 
 Unsubscribe 
 
 
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #111 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Jan 9, 2004 10:02 pm
 Subject: Community Safety Education Camp sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 
 This is hot of the desk of Dr. Richard Snowberg. This is from the original &quot;Clown Camp&quot; that I&apos;ve been telling you about previously. Dr. Snowberg put this flyer together at the request of a couple of fire departments so they could have something to submit to their finance departments with &quot;less&quot; emphasis on clown and more on the safety education. Now is the time to be planning and trying to get funding for this &quot;once in a lifetime&quot; opportunity! It&apos;s an unbelievable experience and this should be truly wonderful with a one week dedicated track for Community Safety Education! There are also applications for scholarships to apply for on the camp website:  http://perth.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/  or if you would like a full registration packet, or color version (complete with graphics) of the below flyer, please e-mail Richard Snowberg: 
 snowberg.rich@...   Hope to see you there! ~Sparky~  Sparky@... 
  

 The University of Wisconsin-La Crosse 

 Community Safety 

   Education Camp 

 The Educational Studies Department at the University of Wisconsin-La Crosse is offering a summer week long program for community safety educators June 12-18, 2004. Police officers, fire/safety officers, and EMTs will benefit by attending this program which goal is to help community officials develop or improve safety education programs.   This program will   assist personnel in learning how to improve communication skills-particularly with children, through the development and/or use of a variety of means.   In attempting to reach both youngsters, and senior citizens you must first focus their attention.   Valuable, often life saving information, may fall on deaf ears, if you cant entertain the attention of your audience. (The definition of entertain is to focus attention.) This week long program will teach you techniques and help you develop strategies for entertaining your audiences. 

   

 This program, directed by emeriti Educational Studies associate professor, Dr. Richard Snowberg, will bring a diverse professional staff together to provide classes, demonstrations, and workshops dealing with: 

 How to assemble a school show 

 How to obtain funding for local safety programs 

 How to write scripts that hold attention and are educationally sound 

 How to utilize diverse performance skills to carry your message: including magic, juggling, puppetry, ventriloquism, clowning, and storytelling. 

   

 The program will also provide a hands on opportunity to participate in a local La Crosse area childrens safety education fair. At a nearby city park, a variety of demonstrations, performances, games, and other safety activities will be provided during a fun filled afternoon. 

   

 It is a tradition that all short term, mostly week long summer special offerings, are called camps. While you wont be living in a tent, you will be enjoying an invigorating and renewing educational experience. 

   

 More Details 

 This program, held on the campus of the University of Wisconsin-La Crosse, will use campus facilities for all aspects of the program. Participants will attend classes in air-conditioned classroom buildings, eat in a common food service facility, and be housed in a traditional campus residence hall. The schedule is as follows: 

 Saturday, June 12 

 10:00am-Midnight 

        Can start moving into residence hall(s) 

 2:30pm -7pm 

       On-site registration-Whitney Center 

       Camp Store opens-Whitney Center 

 4:00pm 

       Orientation meeting-Whitney Center 

 7:00pm 

       First General Session 

 Thursday, June 17 

 10:00pm-closing general session 

 Friday, June 18 

 7:00-8:00am last meal 

 8:00-noon check out of residence hall 

       (no classes on Friday) 

   

 Registration Includes: 

 Double room university residence hall accommodations, unless you elect the extra cost single room 

 All meals while on campus (Saturday dinner through Friday breakfast) 

 Evening snacks and beverages 

 100+ page instructional notebook and a spiral notebook for note taking 

 Personal name badge and badge holder 

 Attendance at any camp classes or courses of your choice 

 Opportunity to learn from the finest performance arts instructors available 

 Individual and group color photographs 

 A CD-ROM of over 500 pictures taken during the program 

 Certificate of completion at programs end 

 Opportunity to perform at evening open mike sessions 

 All pre March 1 registrants receive a free camp t-shirt 

   

 2004 Program Fees: 

 Double Occupancy:                                 $599.00 

 Single Occupancy:                 $675.00 

 w/o room/board                        $399.00 

 Late registrations, received after April 30 will be assessed an additional $30.00 fee. 

   

 What will you do during your week-long program? 

 During the week, participants will attend a common course. The Community Safety Education course, meeting mornings will assist community service personnel and others in: 

 seeking and obtaining necessary funding for a community safety program 

 locating existing resources (human resources, existing programs, skits, etc.) 

 developing (writing and assembling) entertaining programs, skits, and patter 

 identifying themes and messages for safety educational programs 

 convincing their fire or police departments that an educational program is needed or can be improved 

   

 Beyond the scope of the general course will be at least a dozen classes which will deal with various issues and/or skills which participants will find helpful. You will be able to pick and chose those offerings that meet your specific needs. Classes will include: 

 Selling Your Community Safety Program 

 Community Safety Messages 

 Creating Safety Shows for your Community 

 Safety Shows for Seniors 

 Costuming Your Performance 

 Proper use of sound systems to carry your message 

 Safety Magic 

 Safety Show Props 

 Safety Skits 

 School Assemblies 

 Sponsorship for Funding Program Needs 

 Working with a Partner   

   

 Performance Workshops will also be available dealing with: 

 Comedy Magic 

 Ventriloquism 

 Puppetry 

 Clowning 

 Balloon Sculpturing 

 Physical Comedy 

 Juggling 

 Storytelling 

   

   

 All participants in this program will meet daily to discuss ideas, common problems, special issues, etc. Good networking with other like professionals will take place in these sessions. 

   

 Program Faculty 

 Bob Neil-Illinois 

 34 year veteran police officer in Des Plaines Illinois-Developed community relations program-First Officer Friendly in city-Employee of the year in 1992-Oprah Winfry Show appearance as expert on missing and exploited children-Talented magician and multiple award winning clown-Enjoys school shows, trade shows, parades and charity events 

   

 John Sheffield-Texas 

 Professional firefighter, arson investigator, and a lieutenant-Core member of Firehouse Clowns that is responsible for teaching fire safety-As Mr. B , a happy hobo clown, he enjoys teaching children about fire safety-Has traveled abroad and clowned with Innovative Missions Opportunities 

   

 Pam Moody-Iowa 

 Sparky is a professional clown who developed L.A.F.S for Life (Life and Fire Safety for Life)-Is a partner with Des Moines Fire Dept. teaching vital safety and self esteem messages-Presents 200-300 shows each year-Has given professional presentations at the National Fire School (1999, 2001, 2002) and programs in Illinois, Wisconsin, Iowa,&amp;Louisiana 

   

 A dozen other staff members with performance skills training experience will also be on hand to provide a wealth of diverse classroom experiences. These educators include: Kenny and Brenda Ahern, Paula Biggio, Don and Dee Burda, Betty Cash, Greg&amp;Karen DeSanto, Gigi, 

 Jim and Maybel Howle, Pat Jannell,   Kathy McGlaughlin,. Dave Mitchell, Lee Mullally, Rone, Phyllis Sheffield, Mary Lou Staskiek, and Sam Tee. 

   

   

   

 Attendees are all eligible to earn CEU credits (Continuing Education Units) through their attendance and participation in this program. 

   

   

   

   

   

   

  
 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #112 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Jan 9, 2004 10:37 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #57 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Dear friends,   WOW, where has the time went! I can&apos;t believe the New Year is now in full swing.   What&apos;s everyone doing for their programs this year? We&apos;re doing an &quot;All American Safety&quot; program that is completely patriotic! I even found a fabulous patriotic safety song. I&apos;m already thinking about next fall and would love to hear from everyone as to what they&apos;ve done in the past and future. So many creative minds out there........remember, this newsletter is all about sharing and helping one another.    How many are waiting on pins and needles to see if they got their FEMA Grants?    This is a short issue, but I had some items to pass along, especially a plea for help from a new safety clown in Georgia.    Please send me ANYTHING you have to share to Sparky@... .   ~Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org   ================================== INDEX (1) SMILE News (2) New Puppet/Clown Needs Help (3) Resources (4) Starting Fundraising (5) Inspiration THE END!   ( 1 ) ===========&gt;S.M.I.L.E. News&lt;=============   I wanted to let you know that NOW is the time to join SMILE if you&apos;re not already a member!    S.M.I.L.E. is an acronym for Safety Magic In Law Enforcement but don&apos;t let the name fool you. Membership is actually a little heavier on the fire side of the safety arena.   SMILE produces a fabulous quarterly newsletter that is packed with skits, routines, resources and information for puppets, clowns, magicians and/or ventriloquists. A worthy investment for annual dues of $25.    All information can be found at their website:  http://www.smileclowns.org/   ( 2 ) =======&gt;NEW Puppet/Clown Needs Help!&lt;=========   Hello Everyone,    I am a paramedic with a rural ambulance service in southeast Georgia. I am working on starting a Clown and Puppet team. I am hoping that someone out there has some info to help me out. I need any guidelines, programs or skits that you may have to share. I appreciate any and all suggestions.                                                                      Thank you,                                                                                      Dr. Esophagus dresophagus@...   ( 3 )  =============&gt; Resources&lt;=============   
 Printed Publications 

   
 
 The Funny Paper 
 
 www.funnypapermag.com 
 
 $25 per year, 6 issues 
 
 mail (with payment) to:    Chris Van Krieken, Suite 807, 80 Inverlochy Blvd., Thornhill, Ontario, Canada L3T 4P3 
 
   
 
 Clowning Around 
 
 www.worldclownassociation.com 
 
 $27 per year,   6 issue 
 
 Magazine that comes with membership to World Clown Association (WCA) 
 
 P.O. BOX 77236
CORONA, CA 92877-0107

 
 
 Face Painting International       Magazine 
 
 1 year (4 issues)   $30 
 
 (LOTS of color pictures) 
 
 2117 Hollywood Blvd, Hollywood, FL   33020 
 
 www.sillyfarm.com/fpi.html 
 
   
 
 One Way Street News 
 
 www.onewaystreet.com 
 
 $15 per year, monthly 
 
 Magazine geared for puppet and clown ministries 

 Call #800-569-4537, ext. 3 or mail payment to: 
 
 One Way Street, Inc. 
 
 P.O. Box 5077 
 
 Englewood, CO   80155-5077 
 
   
 
 The Christian Conjurer 
 
 www.fcm.org 
 
 This magazine comes with a $25 annual membership to the Fellowship of Christian Magicians.   Mail to: 
 
 FCM Mail Center
7739 Everett Court North
Maple Grove, MN 55311-1815 

 
 The Cross and the Clown          Non-denominational Christian Clown Educational Publication www.clowning4christ.com/News.htm   $25/year6 issues                      Check payable to Clowning for Christ, PO Box 8, Madison, GA   30650       Phone:   #800-442-6432 
 
 FREE INTERNET NEWSLETTERS 

 Life Safety 

 Send blank e-mail to:   LifeSafety-subscribe@yahoogroups.com 

   www.yahoogroups.com/community/lifesafety   
 
 The Clown Newsletter (formerly Soda Pops Newsletter)   This is a tremendous FREE bi-weekly resource that you receive via e-mail. 
 
 To subscribe e-mail:   theclownnewsletter@... , put add me in the subject line. 
 
 Clown Thought For The Week     
 
 e-mailed weekly from Bruce Charlie Johnson.   To subscribe, e-mail:   Bruce@... 
 
   

   
 ( 4 ) ===========&gt;Starting Fundraising&lt;=============   Starting a Fundraising Program
By: Robert DeMartinis 
Where is the Money?
 
As a fundraising consultant, I am often asked how to start a fundraising project. Most organizations know what they need funds for but do not know from where the funds will come. Whether it is a first fundraising project or a new initiative in an established fundraising program, they all start in the same way - you start asking those closest to your organization for support. For a visual aid in the fundraising strategy, picture a dart board. At the center is your board of directors. In separate concentric circles moving away from the center are staff and volunteers, vendors, community businesses and individuals, and finally foundations.   Not all organizations will have all the circles and some may even have more. New nonprofits may start with fundraising from family and friends of those who started the organization. Whoever they are, always start with those who are closest. That is the point. They are the most likely donors and they are critical to building additional support. The more you move away from those closest to your organization, the more time and convincing each fundraising prospect will take.   If you approach someone who is unfamiliar with your organization, one of the first questions they will ask is what other sources of funding do you have? They will look to see if those with a stake in the organization have come forward with support. If the board does not support the project, why should anyone else? As for staff, the goal is not to raise a great deal of funds but rather to build a high percentage of participation at any level. This show of support can go a long way in convincing other prospects about the dedication of the organization and its people.
 
Vendors of an organization, those with whom you do business, should be asked to participate in a fundraising project. Some have policies against giving to organizations with whom they do business but you will never get less than zero which is worth the ask since you probably are already getting nothing. Sometimes you will be surprised to find that contacting a vendor may lead to a gift from a larger corporate foundation. Other times it may lead to a reduction in price for the services or products you are already receiving from the vendor but either way, more funds will be available for your organization&apos;s mission.   Now that your entire organization and those with a direct connection have been solicited for support, hopefully you have garnered a high level of participation. Reaching out into the community for fundraising, the ability to show that you have done all you can from your own people will add great credibility in seeking sources of funding from the outside.   Local business and community leaders have the next closest stake in your work and should be contacted next. Present the value of your work in the community and be prepared to discuss ways that you can help publicize the generosity of local businesses. While philanthropy is a primary motivation, businesses, and politicians, are also pleased to have opportunities for good public relations.   Finally, foundations should be approached with grant proposals. Start with local foundations first before moving on to national foundations. I have my own way of approaching foundations for clients and you should develop your own through trial an error. Pay attention to guidelines and deadlines, provide what is requested, make personal contact whenever possible, look for relationships that can tip a funding decision in your favor and write with conviction from your heart. Some people may not agree with my strategy, but I have found that it works for me and believe substance, commitment and conviction outweigh a professionally polished proposal.   No matter the fundraising project, I believe it is smart to always be prepared to prove that you have done all you can with the local resources you have before seeking additional support from afar. As you work your way through each circle, don&apos;t forget to ask those who make gifts to also become fundraisers by recommending others who may offer support and even making contacts to open doors for you.   ( 5 ) =========&gt; Inspiration&lt;========== 
AND THEN SOME
 By: Steve Goodier 
           How wonderful it would be if there were a simple formula
for success! &quot;Follow these steps and you will be successful in
business, as a parent, as a student, in your vocation or in any
endeavor you attempt.&quot;

           I think of the man who was honored as &quot;Businessperson of
the Year.&quot; At the presentation dinner, a newspaper reporter asked him,
&quot;To what do you owe your great success and prosperity?&quot;

           &quot;Five things contributed to my success,&quot; said the man.
&quot;First, I always treated people fairly. Sec­ond, I always offered a
fair price. Third, I was al­ways honest. Fourth, I was always generous
to my employees. And fifth, my Aunt Edna died a few years back and
left me two and a half million dol­lars.&quot;

           Certainly, the top four items on his list are well worth
following, though they are no guarantee of success. For a variety of
reasons, some of which are outside our control (like Aunt Edna), our
lives are filled with successes and failures, all of which contribute
to our growth. But some of the sagest advice I&apos;ve heard on the subject
of success comes from Professor Richard Weaver, who taught at Bowling
Green State University, Ohio. He says that what often sets a
successful person apart from oth­ers are three simple words: &quot;and then
some.&quot;

           Those people who tend to achieve what they want from life
do what is expected of them -- and then some. They are thoughtful to
others; they are considerate and kind -- and then some. They meet
their obligations and responsibilities fairly -- and then some. They
are good friends to their friends -- and then some. They can be
counted on in an emer­gency -- and then some.

           By going beyond the expectations of others, they
demonstrate every day their desire to do their best and to be their
best. They, too, fail and blunder, but in the end, they can be counted
on to pick up the pieces and move forward.

           Those are three words worth remembering. Count on them to
help build a quality life -- and then some.

To subscribe (free)  LifeSupport-subscribe@yahoogroups.com 
 ===================================================   THE END! 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #113 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Feb 20, 2004 8:20 pm
 Subject: Life Safety Issue #58 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
   Greetings friends!   I had a few special things to pass along to you.   First of all several of you had responded to the last issue stating that you had applications in for the special fire prevention grant with FEMA. Just this morning, Murry &quot;Bubba&quot; Joy from Maine passed this link along to me. It looks like we&apos;re all still waiting in limbo....which is good news! Don&apos;t give up hope yet. Here&apos;s the link:   AFGP Fire Prevention and Safety Grants (2003 Special Fire Prevention and Safety Grants) http://www.usfa.fema.gov/fire-service/grants/safetygrant/sg_awards/2003awards/03-prev-grantsaward.shtm     ===========&lt;Clown Camp&lt;============   A reminder for everyone headed for the special Community Safety Education Week at Clown Camp at the University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse, classes are quickly filling up! I believe also, if you get your registration in by March 1 you receive a FREE Camp t-shirt. You only need to send $100 to register and hold your spot. The balance is due by April 15.   Special Community Safety Education flyers are available if you want a hard copy, e-mail:  snowberg.rich@... 
 Otherwise you can see all of the information online at:   Community Safety Education Week link: http://www.uwlax.edu/communitysafetyeducation/   Clown Camp main website link: http://perth.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/   I know several of you have already registered and I look forward to seeing you the week of June 12 - 18 ! If you get the opportunity to come in a day ahead, it&apos;s a fun trip to drive about 90 miles over to see the Great Circus Museum in Baraboo, WI.    Camp is a fabulous experience always but will be exceptionally fabulous this summer with the addition of this special week with emphasis on Safety Education. If you have any questions that I can answer for you, please drop me an e-mail:  Sparky@...   =====&gt; JFS Conference / Breckenridg, CO&lt;======   Juvenile Firesetter Conference April 26 - 27 Breckenridge, CO   Save $25 if you register by March 5 !!!!! www.firesafetyeducators.org questions: E-mail:  KWOOLLEY@...     I&apos;ll try to attach the flyer to this e-mail but in case yahoogroups won&apos;t send it through, you can also find it at the following website:  www.yahoogroups.com/community/lifesafety . Sign-in and select &quot;FILES&quot; from the menu on the left. You&apos;ll find it under JFS Flyer.   ==========&gt; Program Update&lt;==========   So what&apos;s going on in everyone&apos;s programs this year?   We&apos;re doing &quot;Safer America&quot; a patriotic program. We began working on this last year when one of our firefighter/puppeteers were stationed in Iraq flying Blackhawk Helicopters. He&apos;s home now and honored with our patriotic production this year.   The messages we&apos;re covering include:  Don&apos;t smoke or take drugs Home Alone Safety Fire - Exit Drills   I&apos;m using 2 songs from the new &quot;Safety Rock&quot; CD available through www.onewaystreet.com . The program opens this year with Sparky actually singing a safety version of &quot;Born in the USA&quot; which actually goes over all of the messages to be covered in the show. Now, Sparky is NOT a singer, but can pull it off in her clown voice with some Karaoke music. At the end of the song I produce a HUGE American Flag that literally appears from nowhere! The kids go crazy! If you would like a copy of Sparky&apos;s Born in the USA lyrics, drop me an e-mail:  Sparky@...   Last year I found a fabulous song on the internet at the following website: http://www.safetyape.com/           Look for Safer America and you can listen to the entire song online. It&apos;s not even available for purchase, but the artist sent me a CD with that song and the rights to perform it. It&apos;s a GREAT ending to our program, which we also conclude with red, white and blue confetti canons. The kids and teachers love it!   It&apos;s the easiest show we&apos;ve done yet, and everyone is telling us, it&apos;s our BEST!    What&apos;s up with your programs? Drop me a note and share.....we&apos;re always looking for fresh ideas!   ========&gt; Our SAVE!&lt;============   Well, it&apos;s taken us YEARS but we FINALLY have our first known &quot;Documented Save&quot; from our program. An 8 year old girl reacted to a kitchen grease fire exactly how she should have, immediately removing her younger sister from the home and gave FULL credit to our program that she sees each year at her school. We were blessed to receive some good media coverage from this...which can never hurt when in need of funding!   ++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++   I&apos;ve been very busy this spring with programs and appearances. I&apos;ve been invited back to the Wisconsin State Fire Inspectors Conference in Osh Kosh the end of March. I hope to see several of you again, there!    I&apos;ve also been working a lot with a couple of different ministry clown troupes. I&apos;ll be taking one of the troupes to a One Way Street Competition in Omaha when I leave Osh Kosh! This is my youngest troupe of 5 kids...they&apos;re AWESOME! I started working with this troupe from a local church last August at their request. My church clown troupe recently added 5 new clowns...bringing our total this year to 8! This weekend will be their first appearances and we&apos;ll be doing 3 church services, a family fun night AND making a visit to a brain injury rehabilitation center in the next 2 days! I think this weekend could be called &quot;Baptism By FIRE!&quot; (grin)   Next week I&apos;m headed back to the Show Me Clowns Conference held in Lake of the Ozarks each February. I&apos;ve also ran into a couple of people from this group there before...which I wasn&apos;t expecting as this is a gospel clown conference. This is probably the BEST overall conference I attend each year, with over 500 other gospel clowns. The instructors are always unbelievable and the best in the business. We all stay in a Baptist Bible Camp located right on the Lake of the Ozarks. It&apos;s pretty wild spending your every waking minute with over 500 clowns in the same camp! ( www.showmeclownsforjesus.org ) ( www.windermereusa.org ) I go with my 2 ministry partners and we make it a &quot;girls weekend!&quot; Tons of fun.   So....my spring schedule is filling up fast with lots of fun things!    Drop me a note and let me know what you&apos;re up to!   Be safe!   Love&amp;laughter,   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org         

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #114 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Sat Jan 5, 1980 8:17 pm
 Subject: Upcoming training sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Passing along some educational opportunities here from Breckenridge, CO; LaCrosse, WI and Arlinton, TX. If you have any others you feel are important to share, please let me know!   Be safe!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody   ===========&gt;Safety&amp;Prevention / Colorado&lt;==========     Hello Pam,   Could you also add or send out to the group the following web site for our Safety&amp;Prevention conference also in Breckenridge, CO following the JFS pre-conference. This will be April 28-30 and is for injury/ems, law enforcement and fire. Lots of valuable sessions and a great time!   www.safetyandpreventionconference.org   =========&gt; Community Safety Education Camp&lt;============   A reminder for everyone headed for the special Community Safety Education Week at Clown Camp at the University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse, classes are quickly filling up! I believe also, if you get your registration in by March 1 you receive a FREE Camp t-shirt. You only need to send $100 to register and hold your spot. The balance is due by April 15.   Special Community Safety Education flyers are available if you want a hard copy, e-mail:  snowberg.rich@... 
 Otherwise you can see all of the information online at:   Community Safety Education Week link: http://www.uwlax.edu/communitysafetyeducation/   Clown Camp main website link: http://perth.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/   I know several of you have already registered and I look forward to seeing you the week of June 12 - 18 ! If you get the opportunity to come in a day ahead, it&apos;s a fun trip to drive about 90 miles over to see the Great Circus Museum in Baraboo, WI.    Camp is a fabulous experience always but will be exceptionally fabulous this summer with the addition of this special week with emphasis on Safety Education. If you have any questions that I can answer for you, please drop me an e-mail:  Sparky@...   ==========&gt; Clown Training / Texas&lt;============   Dear Clown Friends and Friends of Clowns:                        In the past several days, quite a few people have asked if they can invite friends to the BIG CLOWN SHOW at the end of Mooseburger Clown Training Camp on Sunday, March 21 at the La Quinta Inn Conference Center in Arlington. The answer is yes!!!!   However, with about 500 kids planning to attend that show (thanks to Love for Kids Charity) my best advice to you is to arrive about 1:30 p.m. We will seat all of the kids FIRST . La Quinta Inn has graciously donated 500 hot dogs to the kids and we want to try and have them all situated in the same general area.   There is a STRONG probability that this show will be STANDING ROOM ONLY for adults! The registrations are coming in &quot;hot &apos;n heavy&quot; and we fully expect to max out on registrants very soon . We are FAR ahead of the curve for the normal number of registrants this far in advance of Camp. As such, Pricilla and I are already trying to figure out how to squeeze more clowns into Camp than we originally planned on! (Kind of like putting clowns in a clown car!)   It&apos;s my BEST advice to you that you REGISTER RIGHT NOW if you want to attend.  We are FAST approaching the number of clowns that we can accommodate.   FULL details about Camp can be found at www.topper.us   Or, t o go directly to the registration site, click here:
 http://mooseburger.com/ushop/index.cgi?ID=ADU6VO&amp;task=show&amp;cat=Moose+Camp+Caravan   The list of instructors (including Frosty Little, the only remaining MASTER CLOWN in the world!)  is phenomenal! Pricilla Mooseburger, Frosty Little , Chuck Sidlow, Mark Renfro , Dale Bothun , Karen Bell, Joe Barney, Wayne and Marty Scott&amp;MORE!!   And the vendors will be there will clown supplies from A TO Z! You do NOT have to bring anything to camp if you don&apos;t want too! You can TOTALLY outfit 110% of your clowning needs&amp;supplies at Camp! PLUS, we have vendors that have NEVER been at ANY other Clown event!   Each morning, you&apos;ll have a chance to hear from Frosty Little and Chuck Sidlow the REAL scoop on being a clown for Ringling Brothers and Barnum&amp;Bailey Circus! Frosty was the BOSS OF THE CLOWN BOSSES and Chucko was a Boss Clown! They have seen things and experienced life as clowns that many people can only dream of. Their stories (and antics!) are &quot;not to be missed!&quot; events at Camp! Absolutely, positively a once-in-a-lifetime chance for many of you to hear things you&apos;ll never get the chance to hear again! For example;   There is NO BETTER WAY to improve as a clown than to attend Mooseburger Clown Training Camp, SPECIAL EDITION - March 18-21, 2004 in Arlington, Texas at the La Quinta Inn Conference Center .    Carl E Jones Topper the Magic Clown www.topper.us www.carlejones.com 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #115 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Mar 11, 2004 2:25 pm
 Subject: Unusual Request sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Howdy!   I&apos;m on a mission of &quot;fun&quot; today and wanted to solicit your help! I&apos;ve entered &quot;Sparky&quot; in a contest to be on the label of &quot;Jones Soda.&quot;   I&apos;m asking for you to go to the following website and vote for my &quot;mug&quot; shot! Naturally.....a &quot;10&quot; rating would be appreciated, but you have to be hones (grin)!   http://www.jonessoda.com/gallery/view.php?ID=0000200380   Thanks and have a SAFE day!   Lovel&amp;laughter,   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #116 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Mar 18, 2004 2:46 pm
 Subject: &quot;Safety Clowns In the News!&quot; sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 
 How exciting! It&apos;s not even Fire Prevention week and safety clowns are making the news! Earlier this week, I cam across a GREAT article (below) from The Post - Searchlight from Bainbridge, GA. Article is very nicely done showcasing obviously a great training event for dedicated safety clowns! I know we have some Georgian&apos;s in this group but not sure if you&apos;re part of this same organization.    The second article below is from the Des Moines Register about our local group, L.A.F.S. For Life. Unfortunately on the web they don&apos;t post the pics that accompany the article but there were TWO large color photos within the article which continued over 2 pages. Also were some boxes printed in highlight telling statistical information about our group and directing people how to donate.    Spring is here and I&apos;m ready to spread my wings and hit the road (or air) for awhile! Next week I&apos;ll be at a state fire conference in Osh Kosh, WI presenting a one day workshop. I&apos;ll go from there to a conference in Omaha, NE on Friday. I just received an invitation to return to the Louisiana State EMS clowning conference in May. June I&apos;ll be at Clown Camp in LaCrosse, WI (I know at least a couple of you who are registered to attend and can&apos;t wait to see you!). Next October I&apos;ve been invited to present a one day workshop at the Kentucky Clown Derby on educational clowning for safety!!!!   So what&apos;s going on in your neighborhoods! Please share.......   Love&amp;laughter,   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org   ===========================================   http://www.zwire.com/site/news.cfm?BRD=2068&amp;dept_id=387472&amp;newsid=11131674&amp;PAG=461&amp;rfi=9     Clowning around for a cause 
 
 

 By MARY FRANCES DONALSON, News Writer March 16, 2004 

 
 

 
 MAKEUP PRACTICE: Tonya Griffin carefully paints her lips as she adds finishing touches to her clown face. 
 
 

 The Southwest Georgia Life Safety Educators will be clowning around Willis Park Saturday as part of the Artsfest celebrations.

But this group not only clowns aroundwhich includes costumes, make up, puppets and skitsthe group is dedicated to promoting life safety education to people of all ages through their performances.

The group is comprised at present of nine volunteers from Decatur Countys emergency agencies and one from Seminole County. The first four persons to become involved in this safety program were Lance Robinson of Decatur County Fire and Rescue Service, Nadine Brown of Emergency Medical Service, Tonya Griffin and Naise Gordon, both of 911.

Using grant money from the Georgia Burn Foundation and funds from their department budgets, the four received 40 hours of training in alternative teaching methods for fire and life safety education using clowns, puppets and other materials. During their classes they learned to put on clown makeup, develop individualized costumes and prepare skits with the puppets that were purchased.

We plan to go into the elementary schools with our program teaching such life safety topics as Stop, Drop and Roll, fire prevention, Saying Nope to Dope, learning to use 911, Stranger Danger, respect for authority and bicycle safety, said Griffin. We will also be entertaining at public events such as Artsfest and offering safety tips to the public. If we can save even one life, or teach one child safe habits, all our efforts will be worthwhile.

So enthusiastic were the initial members of the educator group that others became interested and joined the organization. These are David Ingram and Sam Hughes of the Recovery Volunteer Fire Department, Patrick Cofty of the Brinson Volunteer Fire Department, Rebecca Robinson (wife of Fire and Rescue Service member Lance Robinson), Casey Alday of 911, and Michael Smith of the Donalsonville Fire Department.

The group meets every Monday night in a training classroom at the Industrial Air Park to practice putting on their clown makeup, which requires time and patience, and work on their educational skits. Each individual is responsible for his or her own makeup kit and costume, and the final outfit may cost several hundred dollars, Griffin said.

According to the 911 director, there are three basic types of clowns: Whiteface, Auguste (buffoon) and the tramp character. The Life Safety Educators practice all three types of makeup, then choose their favorite and decide how they want to develop their own character.
For example, Griffin has chosen the clown name of Starkles, and her makeup and costume feature stars. Her clown shoes decorated with stars cost approximately $250, which, like the rest of her working equipment, will be paid out of her own pocket.

These are the most dedicated people Ive ever seen, says Lowell Takles, a professional clown who performs at various events as Ono. Experienced in this work, Takles meets with the class on Monday nights, serving as technical adviser and assisting them with makeup techniques and other guidelines for this program.

The safety education program is strictly voluntary and anyone wishing more information or desiring to participate may contact Griffin at 248-3860.
 
 The Post-Searchlight 2004 
     ===============================================================================   http://desmoinesregister.com/news/stories/c4780927/23794788.html     
 

   Search: 
 
 Search tips     Make us your home page 
    Subscribe to the Register 
    Careers at the Register 
    Advertise with us 
    Contact us 
 
   Home : News 


 News 
 7-day indexes 
   Crime/Courts 
   Education 
   Environment 
   Fire&amp;Rescue 
   Local Govt. 
   Nation/World 
   People/Places 
   Politics 
   State Govt. 
   War 
   Web Extras 
   Obituaries 
   Forums 
   Sports 
   Communities 
   Business 
   Opinion 
   Life 
   Entertainment 
   Marketplace 
   Help 

 
   Education 

L.A.F.S. not just clowning around


 By KRISTIN DANLEY-GREINER 
Register Correspondent
 03/18/2004 At least once a week during the school year, Des Moines elementary school students are treated to a special performance by Sparky the clown and her troupe of puppeteers. The group not only entertains students, but it also stresses fire safety and many life lessons at the same time.


Because of dwindling finances and aging equipment, the number of performances may be cut unless the group can find more money.

Sparky, aka Pam Moody of Des Moines, leads the assemblies, which are typically presented to students in kindergarten through fifth grade in the Des Moines school district under the program L.A.F.S. for Life. L.A.F.S., or Life and Fire Safety, is affiliated with the Des Moines Fire Department. Sparky also performs for events at her church, community gatherings and other area schools.

None of the Des Moines elementary schools pay for the performances put on by L.A.F.S. for Life. Rick Miller, guidance counselor at Cattell Elementary on Des Moines&quot; east side who booked the show for his school, said the students enjoyed it so much that he would encourage anyone who is able to support the group financially.
&quot;I thought the performance had a lot of energy and vitality. The songs involved the children as well, and made them really excited about it,&quot; Miller said. &quot;The variety of ways they approached their lessons with different methods made it a much more upbeat presentation. The props really helped, too. I feel it was one of the better assemblies we&apos;ve had this school year.

&quot;The program reinforced messages that some are taught at home. I was excited to see that they really got the kids talking and involved,&quot; Miller added. &quot;Anyone who can support them should.&quot;


Moody explained that this year&apos;s patriotic-themed show, &quot;Safer America,&quot; is the biggest show she does, and the troupe books only one show per week. It costs roughly $500 to put on. Sometimes, the group has to hold two shows at bigger elementary schools in order to accommodate the number of students, and the second show costs about $100.
&quot;You have the time factor for setting up, plus costuming and makeup,&quot; Moody said. &quot;Our puppets are starting to show signs of wear and tear, and we&apos;re using the original sound equipment. We store everything in a trailer that&apos;s kept outside and it&apos;s taken a beating from being hauled around and set up and taken down.&quot;


L.A.F.S. is facing financial problems because the nonprofit organization did not receive a community betterment grant from Polk County this year.

The troupe says it costs less to put on comedy and magic shows featuring Sparky. The troupe visits all of the elementary schools in the Des Moines district at least once every two years.
&quot;They are very popular with the school district,&quot; said Rick Moody, assistant fire chief for the Des Moines Fire Department and Pam Moody&apos;s husband. &quot;Teachers and other administrators have sent us letters praising the performance. In fact, most of the schools want to have us out more often than what we have the time and money for.&quot;


Rick Moody used to help his wife put on the shows, but with his duties at the fire department, he has not been able to help lately. The puppeteers are fire inspectors with the Des Moines Fire Department&apos;s fire inspection bureau.
&quot;All the kids want their autographs,&quot; Rick Moody said. &quot;I used to help as a puppeteer because I decided I couldn&apos;t ask the macho fire inspectors to do it if I wasn&apos;t already doing it myself.&quot;


Within the past couple of years, L.A.F.S. for Life has expanded its audience base to include senior citizen groups. Because of the lack of money, the troupe has also cut back on those presentations.
&quot;It takes quite a bit of money to do this. We just don&apos;t want to cut back on the performances at the schools, because we feel that is so important,&quot; Rick Moody said.


For educators, a price tag cannot be placed on something they consider valuable for their students. Howe Elementary&apos;s second-grade teacher, Carol Meier, said she was able to incorporate the L.A.F.S. for Life performance into her classroom work and held a lively discussion after the performance.
&quot;They did a wonderful job, and the students absolutely loved it. They used catchy safety messages in familiar songs they&apos;d rewritten that caught the students&quot; attention and really got their messages across,&quot; Meier said. &quot;The kids enjoyed the music and the messages, and the performers really connected with them.&quot;


Moore Elementary School Principal Udell Cason Jr. said his students were entertained and educated simultaneously.
&quot;It certainly grabbed the attention of the youngsters, while at the same time put forth a message in respect to fire safety and the do&apos;s and don&apos;ts when faced with imminent situations,&quot; Cason said. &quot;It was an excellent opportunity for the kids.&quot; 
 
Want to help?


 
Send donations to:
 
L.A.F.S. for Life

P.O. Box 158

Altoona, IA 50009-0158 
 
For more information, call 283-4775 or visit sparky@... and www.lafsforlife.org.
 
   E-mail this story 
   Send a letter to the editor 
   Subscribe now 
 

 
 
       Make us your home page 
    Advertise with us 
    Subscribe to the Register 
 
 

 News | Sports | Business | Opinion | Life | Entertainment | Forums | Help 
 Cars | Jobs | Homes | Apartments | The RAGBRAI Store | Classifieds | Subscribe 
 Copyright 2004, The Des Moines Register.
Use of this site signifies your agreement to the Terms of Service (updated 1/3/2003). 

 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #117 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Mar 19, 2004 3:19 am
 Subject: LifeSafety sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Wow.....I think y&apos;all are starting to wake-up a bit. This is GREAT......response to my e-mail this morning. This is exactly how this is supposed to work. Share something about your self, your character, your department, your troupe....you never know who may be reading this!    When I first started this group several years ago it was because I was the one and only safety clown in the state of Iowa! (actually even some surrounding states). I was starved for information and resources. There are over 220 people on this list from all over the world. You never know who may benefit or be inspired as a result.   Keep sending me your messages and I&apos;ll share what you&apos;d like!   Have a GREAT weekend!   Sparky Sparky@... ====================================== Received the following note from Jay Clifton ( mclifton@... )   Georgia is full of clowns and we don&apos;t need a reason or special event to clown around.   http://fireclowns.tripod.com/   http://www.geocities.com/gpsea2001/   http://www.gfbf.org/   ======================================== Hello Sparky:

Coolade is the name clowning is the game. I read the article you set out and enjoyed it greatly. Those clowns from Decatur County Georgia just went through the Alternative Teaching Methods Class at the GPSTC (Georgia Public Safety Center) in Forsyth Georgia last year. We teach two classes a year at the Fire Academy on clowning puppets and robotics. This class has been taught since 1991 when two dedicated public service employees went to the Fire Academy in Florida and took a clowning class there. They brought the class back and it has been taught ever since. We have taught over 300 firefighters, police and emt&apos;s as well as 911 dispatchers from all over the state of Georgia, North Carolina and Maryland. Plus teaching one class in South Carolina at the fire training grounds there. We have had some great clowns come out of these classes who are dedicated to saving lives in there communities. The next class will be March 22-March 26, 2004. I hope to have another good class. Keep up the good work and keep them smiling.

Love in Christ

Coolade
aka Vann Baxter ( tvannbaxter@... )   Sparky&apos;s note: Please share with us about your classes in advance in the future. I know there are many on this list from the SE and perhaps someone would like to take advantage of a good training event!
 =========================================   Debbie Weaver ( debbie.weaver@... ) sends along an invitation to their upcoming conference:   &quot;The AMAZING Safety Race&quot; Overland Park, Kansas June 10 - 12, 2004   Visit the website: http://ksffa.com/FEAK/feak.htm   Download the brochure...... http://ksffa.com/FEAK/2004%20MVAFC%20Pub.%20Ed.%20Conference%20Registration%20Packet.pdf   

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (2) #118 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Mar 24, 2004 1:11 am
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #59 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Howdy again already!   Great to hear from everyone. I&apos;m just passing it along as it comes my way. I&apos;ve added a couple of other tidbits to the bottom. How about websites? Does anyone have any website&apos;s they&apos;d like to share with the group? A department website or a clown/entertainer website? Favorite resources?   For those of you out East.....be sure and check out this website:  http://www.magicalwizard.com/kentucky_clown_derby.htm  The Kentucky Clown Derby has included a one day intensive safety education training prior to the main conference on Friday, October 8th in Louisville!    I&apos;m off to Wisconsin in the morning for the State Fire Inspector&apos;s conference so I won&apos;t be answering any e-mails for a few days. Thanks for the input....keep it coming!   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org ________________________________________________________________________ 
From:  spannergcfsc@... 

Hello everyone, I am a little slow on the response. My name is Shelly D, aka Spanner, and along with my husband, Hooligan, we are fellow Iowa fire safety clowns. We make up the Grundy County Fire Safety Clowns. (Always looking for new recruits but some just won&apos;t let what little hair down they have.) With the help of Sparky and JetSiphonM we have been clowning since winter fire school 2003. Always looking to network some new ideas, especially skits. Looking forward to parades this summer and keeping in touch with fellow clowns. Spanner

 
 From:  cubbie@...   I got my start in clowning at Georgia State Fire Academy in 1998. They get together now twice a year for a week for what we call a Fire Safety Blitz. Fire Safety Clowns and Fire Safety Educators from all over the State of Georgia travel to individual counties teaching fire safety to entire school systems and their communities. They work with a local hosting fire department to strengthen or establish their own education program to build on the foundation work laid by the fire safety blitz. This is one of the most successfully programs anywhere in the United States.
If your looking for a safety program to model Georgia Firefighters have it.
  Coolaide good to hear from you again.

Jim &quot;Cubbie&quot; Caton
Past Vice President
Gator Clowns of Jacksonville FL
WCA alley #002 
   Sparky&apos;s note: Cubbie, I LOVE the idea of the Fire Safety Blitz! Do you have a central meeting place or does your meetingi place move each time? How can you get two weeks per year to do this? Who organizes it and decides where everyone goes? Just curious....I love the idea! I know you guys have a very tight-knit organization there, but how do you keep in contact with everyone? Newsletter? E-mail? We&apos;d love to hear more information!   ===========&gt; Laughter&lt;============= 
 A HEALTHY DOSE OF LAUGHTER

I read that a child laughs 400 times a day on the average, while an
adult laughs only 15 times each day. Which is puzzling since laughter
feels so good and is so good for us!

You may know the benefits of laughter on the mind and spirit, but are
you aware of how much a good laugh can help you physically? Nor­man
Cousins used to say that laughter is so bene­ficial for your body that
it is like &quot;inner jog­ging.&quot;

Mayo Clinic (Mayo Clinic Health Letter, March 1993) reports that
laughter aids breathing by disrupting your normal respiration pattern
and in­creasing your breathing rate. It can even help clear mucus from
your lungs.

Laughter is also good for your heart. It in­creases circulation and
improves the delivery of oxygen and nutrients to tissues throughout
your body.

A good laugh helps your immune system fight off colds, flu and sinus
problems by increas­ing the concentration of immunoglobulin A in your
sa­liva. And it may help control pain by rais­ing the levels of
certain brain chemicals (endorphins).

Furthermore, it is a natural stress reliever. Have you ever laughed so
hard that you doubled over, fell off your chair, spit out your food or
wet your pants? You cannot maintain muscle tension when you are
laughing!

The good news is that you are allowed more than 15 laughs a day! Go
ahead and double the dose and make it 30 times today. (You may begin
to no­tice immediate improvement in your relationships!) Then double
it again! You are bound to feel better, you will cope with problems
more effectively and people will enjoy being around you.

Laughter: it&apos;s just good medicine!
__________

This reading can be found in Steve Goodier&apos;s book:
   RICHES OF THE HEART
       Sixty-Second Readings that Make a Difference

Now On Sale! Call (877) 344-0989 or click:
&lt;a href=&quot; http://lifesupportsystem.com/books.html &quot;&gt;
 http://lifesupportsystem.com/books.html &lt;/a&gt; 

 ==========&gt; More News&lt;============   This article appeared in the Dallas Fort Worth Star Telegram. It quotes a firefighter in attendance, but isn&apos;t specifically about safety clowning: 
 &quot;You don&apos;t just put on a costume and become a clown,&quot; said Buckets, a Lewisville firefighter who teaches fire safety through clowning. &quot;Here, we learned about what&apos;s inside us and how to bring that out with excellence and integrity.&quot; 
 The entire article below: 
 Posted on Mon, Mar. 22, 2004 http://www.dfw.com/mld/dfw/news/8247056.htm 
 
 
 
 
 
 SPECIAL TO THE STAR-TELEGRAM/BRIAN LAWDERMILK 
Greenie, a clown played by Linda Greene of Midland, blows bubbles Sunday afternoon at the Mooseburger Clown Arts Camp, which is based in Minnesota and takes its program on the road once a year.
 
 
 SPECIAL TO THE STAR-TELEGRAM/BRIAN LAWDERMILK 
Snickers, played by Sherri Omo, clowns around with Lexi Sturgeon, 4, of Garland at the Mooseburger camp Sunday.
 
 
 
Topper the Magic Clown, played by Carl Jones, gets the crowd involved during a skit at the Mooseburger camp, held at the La Quinta Inn Conference Center in Arlington.
 
 
 
 
 

Serious Fun
 
 125 clowns gather at a camp in Arlington to work on their craft and entertain underprivileged children 
 
 By Brian Builta 
 
 Special to the Star-Telegram 
 
 
The juggling clowns and magic performances were entertaining.

But it was God Bless America played by a 36-clown kazoo band that brought out the goose bumps Sunday afternoon at Arlington&apos;s first Mooseburger Clown Arts Camp.

The La Quinta Inn Conference Center on Watson Road was awash in large shoes, baggy pants, bright fluffy hair and 125 adults wearing way too much makeup, all gathered for the purpose of clowning around, improving performance skills, networking and making underprivileged and at-risk children laugh.

Mooseburger, a Minnesota-based clown education group, takes its program to other states once a year. Carl Jones, aka Topper the Magic Clown, was the driving force behind bringing Mooseburger to Arlington.

&quot;A lot of clowns never have the opportunity for professional training,&quot; said Jones, who attended Mooseburger in Minnesota in the fall. &quot;By bringing them here, more clowns in this area will have the opportunity to be better clowns.&quot;

After four days of classes such as face painting, costuming, magic, comedy, prop building, and hospital and gospel clowning, the clowns gathered Sunday to entertain 300 children with Love for Kids, a Dallas-based organization that helps foster a better environment for underprivileged children.

Although the success of the weekend camp might not make the Metroplex a funnier place to live, many clowns said they are better for the experience.

&quot;You don&apos;t just put on a costume and become a clown,&quot; said Buckets, a Lewisville firefighter who teaches fire safety through clowning. &quot;Here, we learned about what&apos;s inside us and how to bring that out with excellence and integrity.&quot;

Dizzye Dee, a clown from Oklahoma City, said clowning has revealed her true self.

&quot;The makeup just allows it to come out,&quot; Dizzye said. &quot;Just because you grow up doesn&apos;t mean you have to stop riding in shopping carts. It&apos;s important not to lose the inner clown.&quot;
 ONLINE: Mooseburger Clown Arts Camp, www.mooseburger.com 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #119 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Apr 29, 2004 3:21 am
 Subject: Firefighter clown injured in Iraq! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 CALLING ALL Safety Education Characterization comrads!   A fellow educational safety clown serving in Iraq has been seriously injured (article below). Please join me in sending him letters/photos, etc. of well wishes and encouragement to:   Mason Poe c/o Dunn Fire Dept Station #1
102 N Powell Ave Dunn, NC 28334-4500   Wouldn&apos;t it be awesome to receive cards and photos from all over the world from other safety professionals showing concern? Let&apos;s show Mason Poe that we&apos;re not just &quot;clowning around&quot; about this.....we sincerely care and are grateful for his service!   Love&amp;laughter,   Sparky &lt;:o) www.lafsforlife.org   
     

 
 Wednesday, April 28, 2004 CLEAR
58 
 

 
 


 


 
 

 
 Print story Mail story 

Published on: 2004-04-24

 
 Marine from Dunn injured in Fallujah, Iraq 
 By Amneris Solano
Staff writer 


 Poe 

DUNN - Sgt. Mason Poe joined the Marines not just to follow in his father&apos;s and older brother&apos;s footsteps, but because he wanted to support his country, family members said Friday. That same desire to serve led him to work as a firefighter in Dunn.

&quot;He did not join (the Marines) because he wanted to pay for school,&quot; said Joe Poe, his father. &quot;He did not join because he wanted to get away from home. He did not join because someone talked him into it. He joined to be a Marine.&quot;

Sgt. Poe was seriously injured Tuesday.

He was in a group of about six Marines west of Fallujah, Iraq, his father said. The Marines were traveling in a Humvee hit by a roadside bomb. &quot;They were ambushed,&quot; Joe Poe said.

Sgt. Poe suffered skull, neck, back and leg fractures and a collapsed lung. He was taken to the 31st Combat Support Hospital in Baghdad and will be transferred to Germany as soon as the swelling in his brain goes down, his family has been told.

Poe&apos;s mother, Marilyn, said the Marine Corps has kept the family informed about his injuries. She said they wait by the phone for updates.

&quot;There isn&apos;t too many people that Mason hasn&apos;t touched,&quot; she said.

Sgt. Poe, a member of the 2nd Marine Division from Camp Lejeune, had been deployed to Iraq for about a month.

He graduated from Triton High School in 1999, where he was a long-distance runner. He served four years as an active-duty Marine, then got out last year and returned to Dunn to work as a firefighter. He was recalled to active duty this year.

&quot;He is very dedicated and takes his job seriously,&quot; said Dunn Fire Chief Austin Tew. Before he went overseas, Poe had planned to do a fire safety project involving children in kindergarten through third grade. He would dress as a clown and teach the children about fire safety, Tew said.

He has been a member of the Fire Department since was 16. He joined the department full time June 16.

 Kept in prayers 


The marquee in front of the Dunn Fire Department on North Powell Avenue asks passersby to keep Poe in their prayers. Tew said the sign will stay up until Poe comes home.

Joe Poe said the military and firefighting are two of his son&apos;s passions. His older brother, Joseph Poe, is a gunnery sergeant in the Marines.

Joe Poe, a veteran of the 1991 Gulf War, retired after 20 years in the Army. He suffers from Gulf War illness - an unexplained syndrome affecting thousands of combatants in that conflict - and spends much of his time in a wheelchair.

&quot;Both of my sons believe in this country,&quot; Joe Poe said. &quot;They believe in fighting for the freedom of others.&quot;

Sgt. Poe is the youngest of the couple&apos;s four children. He traveled to Asia and the Middle East during his four years in the Marines. He was a member of the U.S. Marine Corps Fleet Anti-Terrorism Security Team that provided security during the investigation of the terrorist attack on the USS Cole.

&quot;He&apos;s a hell of a man,&quot; Joe Poe said. &quot;He&apos;s a rock.&quot;

Staff writer Amneris Solano can be reached at solanoa@... or 486-3521.
 
 
 &gt;&gt;&gt;ONLINE AUCTION DOGWOOD FESTIVAL DAILY ADS COUPONS BUY A HOME FIND A RENTAL FIND A JOB FIND A CAR ONLINE MARKETPLACE BUY LOCAL PHOTOS PLACE AN AD 


 
 
 ADVERTISEMENTS 
 
 
 
 
 

 Copyright 2004 The Fayetteville (N.C.) Observer
 Contact Us 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #120 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Mon Jun 21, 2004 10:34 pm
 Subject: Clown Camp Report sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Howdy from Iowa!   Just returned from a week at the first-ever &quot;Community Safety Education&quot; track at the official &quot;CLOWN CAMP&quot; which was held at the University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse.   This year camp hosted just over 100 campers. 35 of these were enrolled in the special one week track for Community Safety Education (photo attached). In addition to the traditional host of FABULOUS clown camp staff were 3 professionals from the safety arena. This included myself (Sparky); John &quot;Mr. B&quot; Sheffield who is a member of the Firehouse Clowns and is a lieutenant on his south Texas fire department; and Bob &quot;Kiwi&quot; O&apos;Neil who is a retired police officer from Des Plaines, IL.   I had the opportunity to meet a couple of you from this group there!    Of the 35 enrolled in the safety track, I would guess 1/2 were safety professionals and the other half were professional clowns wanting to add safety to their messages.   The days were LONG and we all worked very hard. We began on Saturday night and concluded on Friday morning. There were 2+ intensive classes each day on safety application, etc. The rest of the day you were free to pick from any variety of arts classes you were interested in. These included comedy, magic, movement, balloons, juggling, face painting....of all levels! This week there were participants from China, Malaysia, India, Canada and of course, the USA.   From the moment we arrived we split our our group of 35 into two....to begin working on a stage presentation for Wednesday in the park. The City of LaCrosse hosted a safety day in the park which consisted of 5 different safety stations. 2 of the 5 stations were stages that the clowns presented 3 - 20 minute safety shows. It became a class project to build the program using all of the participants from the beginning. This initiated the process of deciding on the messages to cover right down to the performance itself. It was wonderful to see them perform their skits after such short preparation time and for never having worked together. I know they sent me home with many great ideas I hope to implement!!!!! The finale to our day was Mr. B wiping out on his WIFE&apos;S GIGANTIC clown tricycle. The ambulance arrived and clown medics jumped out ....loaded him on a &quot;clown-like&quot; stretcher which of course left without the patient. The real medics then came in, made a quick assessment and quickly transported the clown patient off to a roaring applause. Just as the ambulance left the scene, the remaining 40+ clowns came running out of the smoke house with smoke licking at their wigs and smoke alarms roaring. We ran toward the audience of 250 +, stopping just short of them at our special meeting place! It was the perfect ending to a well planned day.    I&apos;ve included 2 articles from the event in this mailing.    It&apos;s too early to know for sure, but I&apos;m fairly confident the University of Wisconsin will look to continue this safety education camp in the future, probably skipping next year. If you&apos;ve never had the opportunity to attend &quot;Clown Camp&quot; in LaCrosse, I encourage you to try to go sometime in your life. Next year will be their 25th anniversary and there will be some really BIG name clowns in attendance. They are also only hosting one week in the states next year as the second week will be hosted in Japan! Bookmark their website and watch for the dates and information to appear for next year.  http://perth.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/   I also go the &quot;heads up&quot; from John Sheffield that a fabulous Fire Safety Conference will be hosted later this year in the Houston, TX area starring the famous Leon &quot;Buttons&quot; McBryde! I&apos;ll pass along details as I receive them since I know we have a whole lot of Texan&apos;s receiving this newsletter!    That&apos;s all for now. I&apos;m back to recuperating from Camp!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org   CAMP NEWS ARTICLES........... Published - Friday, June 18, 2004 
Clown camp debuts community safety program

By PAUL SLOTH/Staff writer
 Educating children about safety shouldn&apos;t be boring. The information is too important. 
   
That&apos;s why Onalaska&apos;s Assistant Fire Chief Troy Gudie spent the past week at the University of Wisconsin-La Crosse&apos;s annual Clown Camp.

The Onalaska Fire Department is looking for ways to get its message across and sometimes it helps to clown around; seriously.

&quot;There&apos;s a lot more to it than people expect,&quot; Gudie said.

Participants spent all day in workshops learning the art of clowning. In the evening, they honed their skills by practicing their routines in front of the other campers.

Gudie was joined by former volunteer firefighter Jeff Hoch, a youth minister at First Evangelical Free Church in Onalaska.

This is the first year the camp offered a special program designed for community safety professionals.

Gudie said he plans to incorporate some of the things he&apos;s learned at camp into the safety education program.
 
 Onalaskas Assistant Fire Chief Troy Gudie performs as Flash the Clown Wednesday during a safety fair at Myrick Park in La Crosse. The University of Wisconsin-La Crosses Clown Camp organized the event.
Photo by Paul Sloth 
 
&quot;I would like to do a spring and a fall event,&quot; Gudie said. &quot;I think the kids really enjoy it.&quot;

The clown camp has been around for 24 years. It is the oldest and longest running clown training program in the country.

Richard Snowberg started the camp to teach people not to amuse, but to entertain.

&quot;The word &apos;entertain&apos; means to focus attention and were using clown arts to do that,&quot; Snowberg said.

This year&apos;s community safety program is aimed at safety professionals who might know a lot about their specific field, but might need some help getting their message across.

&quot;A lot of times they know the content but they don&apos;t have effective ways to communicate that to their audience,&quot; Snowberg said.

This is the third year that Gudie has attended the camp.

The clown campers offered a safety education fair Wednesday at Myrick Park in La Crosse.

It was an opportunity for participants to practice what they learned at camp.

The event was held in conjunction with the La Crosse Fire Department, the La Crosse Police Department, Tri-State Ambulance and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.

Gudie, who is known as Flash in the clown world, said he is trying to encourage more agencies in the area to use clowning in their safety education programs.

&quot;I can&apos;t get La Crosse to put makeup on yet,&quot; Gudie said. &quot;The time will come, I&apos;ll keep working on them.&quot;

The clown camp attracts people from around the world. This year, the staff included clowns from Japan and Malaysia.

Next year the clown camp staff will offer a weeklong program in Nagoya, Japan.

&quot;What we&apos;re doing in a global sense is showing them ways to communicate with their audience     ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~ 
 Posted on Sun, Jun. 20, 2004 
 
 
   
 
 
 

They&apos;re not just clowning around
 
 Clown Camp helps cops, firefighters get messages across to children 
 
 BY ANASTASIA MERCER 
 
 La Crosse Tribune 
 
 
ONALASKA, Wis. The Onalaska Fire Department once sent firefighters into its city schools to conduct safety education programs.

Now, it sends in the clowns.

&quot;I come in with the puppets and clowns and magic, and for a half-hour we have their total attention,&quot; said Jeff Hoch, who is contracted to provide Onalaska&apos;s safety programs as a clown named Lt. Higbee.

Hoch, who also is pastor at First Evangelical Free Church in Onalaska, was learning more about clown techniques as part of the 24th annual Clown Camp at the University of Wisconsin-La Crosse on Monday.

&quot;This is a great place to learn,&quot; Hoch said. &quot;It&apos;s a great opportunity to see what other departments are doing. Then we can work together to make our communities safe.&quot;

Clown Camp director Richard Snowberg said this is the first year the camp has offered specific classes for police and fire department officials who provide safety education programs. About 35 people at the camp, which started Saturday and ran through Friday, were in the classes, he said.

&quot;We&apos;ve done similar types of programs with teachers and hospital workers,&quot; Snowberg said. &quot;It was a request we&apos;ve been receiving.&quot;

In all, about 225 people attended Clown Camp this year, Snowberg said, some from as far away as Japan, India and Canada. It is the largest and oldest camp of its kind, Snowberg said. &quot;We&apos;ve gained quite a bit of notoriety,&quot; Snowberg said.

Bob Neil, a retired Des Plaines, Ill., police officer who continues to provide safety education in Illinois schools, spent part of Monday morning revealing the secrets behind his magic tricks and stunts.

He showed the group a raccoon puppet named Albert who teaches students how to dial 911 on a giant telephone. He also demonstrated a sleight-of-hand trick using three wallets, two $1 bills and a fake $1 bill. The lesson: making good choices.

&quot;It costs you $2, but it&apos;s a pretty good one,&quot; Neil said of the trick. &quot;The (two) kids walk away with a buck, and they are real thrilled.&quot;

Neil told attendants that humor is a &quot;great, great educator.&quot; If you make students laugh, he said, they won&apos;t forget the lesson. &quot;Not only will they remember it, they will share it with somebody else,&quot; Neil added. &quot;You&apos;re expanding the message you want them to get.&quot;

Karen Baxter, known in Alberta, Canada, as the clown Rootin&apos; Tootin&apos; Newton, said although she isn&apos;t a police or fire official, she had a good reason for attending the class.

&quot;I&apos;m a teacher in a junior high school, and I started a Kids as Clowns group four years ago,&quot; she said. &quot;I wanted to be educated in safety so I can share it with the kid clowns, so they can share it with the elementary kids in our district.&quot;
 
 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #121 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Mon Sep 20, 2004 5:53 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #60 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Happy Fall!   Where has the summer gone? Like always, time just seems to fly by. I&apos;m sure many of you are making final preparations for Fire Prevention Week. I&apos;ve noticed around here, departments are starting earlier. I&apos;ve had more requests for Open Houses (in the suburbs) that are being held in September.    September/October here in Iowa are always busy months. Everyone is trying to squeeze everything into the last of the nice &quot;outdoor&quot; weather and making preparations to hibernate for the winter. For me, this means parades, town festivals, etc. every weekend.    This year for Fire Prevention Week, I&apos;m doing the UNTHINKABLE! I&apos;m LEAVING TOWN for the entire week!!!! (I can&apos;t believe it either) I was asked last spring to serve on staff at the Kentucky Clown Derby ( www.kentuckyclownderby.com ) in Louisville. After 3 minutes of careful consideration.......I said YES! This will be a weekend conference that has optional &quot;intensive&quot; workshops on Friday during the day. I will be hosting one of those preconference workshops on educational safety clowning. Rick has decided to take off and we&apos;re going to make a mini-vacation out of it since we&apos;ve never really spent much time out East. He&apos;s looking forward to hooking up a Chief in Louisville who has attended 3 years of EFO classes with him at the National Fire Academy.   Clown camp was my first experience of instructing to both safety professionals and citizens (who are already professional clowns). What a fabulous concept to get others to jump on our &quot;bandwagon&quot; and help us with our prevention efforts! It was awesome to see both sides of the profession sharing and learning from each other.   Next February I&apos;ll be repeating this same type of workshop in Richmond, VA at the Circus Magic Conference. ( www.circusmagic.com )   Most of my month of August was spent again at the Iowa State Fair . This is a tremendous opportunity for me to reach the maximum number of people from all over the world! This year I presented 44 shows on 4 different stages throughout the fairgrounds, spending a total of 100 hours on the fairground in costume during the 11 days of the fair. If you have access to local fairs and festivals, they&apos;re tremendous opportunities to share your messages to an ultimate number of people. It is also likely that you may find a commercial &quot;sponsor&quot; to cover your time there. Mine for the last 3 years has been Wells Blue Bunny Dairy. I know Keith Ramsey from Washington State has a sponsor for his local fair for safety programs as well. It&apos;s worth looking into!   Since school has recently resumed I&apos;m also &quot;reminding&quot; you to check with your local public television stations and ask to do a show on their ICN Network . This is another great way to reach children across your state without the hassles and time of travel. It&apos;s a bit &quot;different&quot; doing a show in a studio without a live audience sitting in front of you, but you will have the opportunity to talk specifically to each classroom signed &quot;into&quot; your session. There are cameras on them as well and depending on how many are included in the session, I take 1-2 questions from each class at the end to sort of &quot;personalize&quot; their experience. This setup is also not conducive to using a full puppet-stage setup.    The annual S.M.I.L.E. Conference is coming up in Phoenix, AZ. November 19 - 21. They have a GREAT lineup of instructors, including Earl &quot;Mr. Clown&quot; Chaney, among many others. I&apos;m planning on presenting some classes as well.  I&apos;m attaching a flyer to this e-mail.    I&apos;ve been having some SERIOUS computer problems the past couple of months the result of some pesky little worm virus. This has caused me MANY hours on the phone to Dell and I&apos;ve been forced to strip off most of my hardrive and start from scratch. Due to this little &quot;snafu&quot; I&apos;ve lost a lot of information and e-mail addresses that I once had (grin). FRUSTRATING is an understatement! I also want to bring your attention to my change in internet providers. I recently went on DSL so e-mail you receive from me you may notice comes from:  SparkyDMFD@... . The best address to keep on file for me is:  Sparky@... . This address will never change but I know some people keep controls on their e-mails so I wanted to let you know what the &quot;sending&quot; address will be.   I&apos;m extremely fortunate to report that our local organization, L.A.F.S. For Life, received word the end of July that we received our FEMA Grant!!!!!!! This has been pending since last November and was a welcome relief! One of the things included in this grant is a partnership we&apos;ve formed with another local organization (Proteus, Inc.) who works with the non-english speaking Latino population. We have committed a certain amount of hours to be spent educating this group of people. ( so far I&apos;ve learned &quot;no hable espanol!&quot;)  In exchange, Proteus will furnish us with interpreters and Spanish handouts. This is a growing population here in Iowa with all of the packing plants, etc. This grant fully funds us for one year, ending July, 2004. This is AWESOME news. I know several others on this list that had grants pending. I&apos;ve only heard one confirmation that they did not receive it. Anybody else receive theirs? I noticed the stats are out for the next year&apos;s grants. Get those applications in!   It&apos;s been so long since I&apos;ve sent anything out ot the group and we have so many new members as the result of some of my travels. WELCOME and a reminder that this group is a FREE resource to share ideas and network. I merely moderate it to insure your e-mail boxes don&apos;t become filled with spam, jokes and junk. Please send me anything you would like to share or ask and I&apos;ll try to get it passed on in a timely fashion!   Well, enough rambling. I do have a couple of things to share below.    Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org   ====================================   Mike Leemstra from the Bowling Green (OH) Fire Department sent some GREAT photos of a new game their department has created. I&apos;ve posted the photos along with the text below in the files section of the LifeSafety website: http://groups.yahoo.com/group/LifeSafety/files/   Mike&apos;s note: Hi Pam, 
 Mike here from BG fire. Remember me from Clown Camp. You may when you see the attached pictures. Any way, I thought of a new game this year. I don&apos;t know if anyone has done it that you know of, but I did a trial with a third grade class and it went over GREAT!!! The kids had a really fun time. 
 The game is called memory or concentration. After a match was made I talked about that safety topic. If you don&apos;t know how it is played email me back and I will explain. 

 We have a couple of good artists here on the department and I had them draw pictures of 9 safety rules. We blew them up after scanning them onto the computer and put them on foam core board. The front has our BG Fire patch and a number. If anyone is interested in more details let me know. 

 I have more pictures but the files are kind of big. If you want more let me know.   mleestma@... 

 (if you can&apos;t view them at the website, let me know and I&apos;ll e-mail them directly to you: Sparky@...) 

 =========================================== 

 National Night Out - Clowns at the Carousel 

 For the second consecutive year, our local clown alley has hosted &quot;Clowns at the Carousel.&quot;  

 It all began as an idea on how we could celebrate &quot;International Clown Week&quot; which falls the first week of August each year. All clowns are encouraged to do charitable things that week and bring attention to the art of clowning.  

 We chose Union Park in Des Moines because it is home to a beautiful real Carousel! If you visit their website: ( www.heritagecarousel.org ) you can even view photos from this year&apos;s event.   

 Well our first year (2003) we teamed up with Des Moines Parks and Recreation. They had some inflatable rides leftover from a previous event that was cancelled due to rain. They offered those to us and we sponsored the Carousel for a couple of hours of rides. They also bring out the &quot;Showmotion Stage.&quot; We were completely unprepared for a crowd of over 3,000 that came (not to mention the traffic snafus from DMPD&apos;s perspective) 

 For 2004 we planned all year with a committee of people including Des Moines Police, Parks and Rec, local sponsors. Our 2004 event we planned on &quot;National Night Out&quot; which is always the first Tuesday night in August.  This brought even more sponsors on board!! It became the premier event for National Night Out.  We had the mounted police present, large police presence plus the DMPD Explorer&apos;s post as well as the Sheriff&apos;s Explorer post who helped with traffic control and miscellaneous other jobs.  This year our goal was to diversify even more to keep the lines down from what they were last year. We increased the total event to 4 hours (from 2). During those 4 hours we offered: 

 Continuous stage entertainment Free face painting Free balloons Siltwalkers&amp;Walkarounds FREE Carousel Rides FREE Inflatable rides FREE ice cream (Wells Blue Bunny) FREE Milk (Roberts Dairy) 
 I have a new clown trained from the Department of EMS who brought out the Safe Kids Van and presented safety demonstrations.   I offered numerous safety presentations throughout the evening on stage.   It was a successful evening providing a perfect environment to form coalitions to share public safety messages. We&apos;ve already met to begin planning for next year&apos;s event.    This might be something you may want to work on for next summer!    ==================================   This is all I have for now! Please send me information to share. New routine or idea? Plans for fire prevention week? Please share!!!   Love&amp;laughter,   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #122 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Sep 21, 2004 4:11 am
 Subject: Seatbelt Safety Help Needed! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Deb &quot;Clickette&quot; Cooper is a clown character that is all about &quot;seatbelt safety.&quot; She is fairly new to clowning and works for the Department of EMS for the State of Iowa. She also serves with me on Safe Kids Coalition.   Clickette has a booth this Saturday at a &quot;Toddler Fest.&quot; She&apos;s looking for ANY ideas or help you can offer her as to something interactive she can do with the kids.   Any suggestions? Either e-mail me or e-mail Deb Directly at:  dcooper@...   Thanks, Sparky Sparky@... 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #123 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Mon Nov 8, 2004 8:27 pm
 Subject: Outstanding Texas Training For Safety Clowns! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Well, how was everyone&apos;s fire prevention week? Always a busy time for any fire professional, especially clowns with numerous open houses, etc. I did what every good fire clown does for Fire Prevention Week.....I LEFT TOWN! (grin). Indeed, my name is now officially &quot;mud&quot; but I had the opportunity to present a one day intensive pre-conference workshop at the Kentucky Clown Derby! It was fabulous and I had the opportunity to work with 28 students. The vast majority of them were in fire service from Indiana, Kentucky and Ohio.  A couple were entertainers desiring to include safety messages in their programs.    Rick took off that week and we made a mini-vacation out of this experience. How beautiful it was driving with the fall colors in full beauty! Rick has a buddy there from his EFO classes at the fire academy and we enjoyed touring his department, new training facility and also shared in some of the local night life. We had a GREAT visit but I&apos;ve already sworn that I will never leave town again during this BIG week!    =========&gt;ARIZONA Conference&lt;===============   This Saturday I&apos;ll be headed to Phoenix for the 2004 S.M.I.L.E. Conference. The conference isn&apos;t actually until the following weekend, but I plan to visit friends and relatives in advance.    This is another tremendous training opportunity in the metro Phoenix area.   Dates: November 19 - 21 Where: APS Building, 2nd Floor, 400 N. 5th Street, Downtown Phoenix Registration: $125 (SMILE Members)                   $150 (non members)   Fabulous instructors including:  Earl &quot;Mr. Clown&quot; Chaney (former Ringling Clown and original Ronald McDonald) Dave DeDera (retired Ringling Clown, currently head clown at Circus Circus, Las Vegas) Terry &quot;Malcomb&quot; Ricketts - Long time clown and lecturer   Numerous SMILE Instructors   Visit the following link for complete details, including hotel information.    http://www.smileclowns.org/SMILEConference2004a.pdf   Hope to see you in sunny Arizona next week!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org     =====&gt; TEXAS Conference&lt;=======   Missouri City Fire and Rescue Services, together with Stafford Fire Department present:   Effective Fire Education Programs Utilizing Humor Seminar   When:  December 6 - 8, 2004   Where: Stafford Convention Center             10505 Cash Road             Stafford, TX 77477   Registration Cost: $150 per person   For more information, contact: Judy Rodgers #281-261-4388   Featuring Leon &quot;Buttons&quot; McBryde&quot;, a legendary circus clown among other well qualified instructors.   Please download the attached brochure or visit the following website and download the information there:   http://www.ci.mocity.tx.us/news/2004/2004_graphics/Clown.pdf   ==========&gt;Arizona/Nevada Conference&lt;=========   18th Annual Educational Characterization through Clowning and Puppetry Camp.   Date: January 31 - February 3,2005        Location: Bullhead City, Arizona Description: The 18th Annual Characterization Through Clowning and Puppetry Camp continues to be one of the most rewarding and challenging experiences of your career. It will provide new and creative techniques and approaches using educational puppetry, clowning and characterization, which will enhance your ability in developing creative fire and life safety educational programs   Cost: $255 (non members of AFBEA)          $230 (AFBEA members only)   http://www.afbea.org/Docs/Camp%20Brochure.pdf   Very affordable housing at Harrah&apos;s in Laughlin. Complete details on brochure at the above link.   Registrations only accepted prior to December 17th - so get them in early!   If I don&apos;t see you in Arizona next week, I hope to see you in Bullhead City in February!   =========&gt;VIRGINIA Conference&lt;=============   Safety Education Clown Training Heads EAST!   When: February 25 - 27, 2005 Where: Williamsburg, VA What: Circus Magic   http://www.circusmagic.com/RunScript.asp?page=16&amp;Poll_ID=13&amp;p=ASP\Pg16.asp   This will be similar to my class last month at the Kentucky Clown Derby. I will be hosting a one day pre-conference one day intensive workshop on Educational Clowning for Safety Sake. This will be an awesome conference with a premier lineup of top-notch instructors! ~Sparky~     
 Exciting Activities Fantastic Workshops 
 
 Over 50 Classes! 33 Instructors Competition Advanced Classes Gala Performance Exhibitor Show Great Friends! Preconvention Workshops 
 
 Leon McBryde   Bubba Sikes Tom King Jinny Cagne Andy Anderson   Sue Kleinwachter Tony Jones Dana Abendschein   Dave Risley Bonnie Bradshaw   Dave Hill 
 
 Terry Davolt Steve Varro Kitty Kuhr Danny Taylor Karen Bell Pam Moody Prince Puppets Bob Gretton and Teresa Gretton Lou&amp;Charlene Page Steve Kissell 
   Register for this Year&apos;s Convention 
 
     =============================================== Hopefully you&apos;ll be able to attend one of the above specialized safety-clown trainings! If you need more information or have questions, please don&apos;t hesistate to give me a holler!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org       

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #124 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Dec 23, 2004 4:36 am
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #61 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Greeting and wishes for a blessed holiday season!   I can&apos;t believe Christmas is in 2 days! Where did the year go???? I thought now was as good of time as any to get some things cleaned out of my e-mail bin. I&apos;ve held some things for quite awhile!   The photos attached, I hope you can open from your e-mail accounts. They&apos;re from &quot;Nozzle&quot; who has been serving overseas (still clowning) for some time and recently returned to the states and is a firefighter on a base in Missouri. He&apos;s really sold his new chief on educational safety clowning in a BIG way! His first year program here was a tremendous success and he shares photos and articles in the attachments. I&apos;ve ran them both and they are clean of any viruses, I guaranty you! Thanks for sharing Nozzle and CONGRATULATIONS on your success.    Steve shared the following note with me accompanying his photos: Pam,   Here are a couple pics from the firs day of FP week. Unfortunately, my new partner, Chief, retired the following week&lt;sob!&gt; He is a Shrine Clown, so at least I will be able to still see him at the circus in Kansas City.  We had a blast that week...and Chief really supports my program. Even bought me the Puppets...I have 8 young guys that work the puppet show with me and have become completely addicted :) Even the Chief loves them....we even do the CSFD teams &quot;Puppets in Black&quot; song with them...always a big hit. I will try to get some pics of that for ya.   Steve   ==========&gt;Memory Game Update&lt;=======   Mike Leemstra of Bowling Green, Ohio shares a follow-up from his posting in the previous newsletter regarding the &quot;Memory Game&quot; he created. (Note: you can find photos from this game with instructions uploaded in the files section of the LifeSafety Website:  www.yahoogroups.com/community/lifesafety ) 
 Pam, 
 I sent you some pictures of the game that I made. I just thought I would let you know how it went. GREAT!!! 
 The kids had a great time playing the game. It got REALLY LOUD!!! Some of the kids that sent thank you pictures back even mentioned it. The teachers had no complaints about being too noisy though. All of the comments I heard thought the kids learned a lot while having a lot of fun. One student even compared the yelling for which card to turn over to The Price is Right TV show. 

 Have a happy/safe trip. 
 Mike BG Fire. 
   ==========&gt; SMILE Conference Recap&lt;=========   I again attended the SMILE Conference in Phoenix late November, which was a tremendous success! Attendance was up this year and there was a great blend of individuals with a wide range of skills. Key instructors were legendary clowns, Earl Chaney, Jim Howle and Dave DeDera. The conference was great, but the evening at the hotel were even greater as we heard circus stories from the gentlemen above. I laughed so hard I hurt everywhere! I returned to Iowa completely EXHAUSTED!! I still have to admit one of my most favorite instructors is always Terry Ricketts. His level of energy and enthusiasm just makes his presentation. He also teaches you so many practical things that you can make very economically without having to spend hundreds on props and tricks.    There were several &quot;friends&quot; from Clown Camp last summer, where we hosted a Community Safety Education Camp. It was like a reunion from all parts of North America! It was also inspiring to meet some brand new safety clowns and get caught up in their fresh outlook and ideas.   You can read about the SMILE Conference 2004, and see photos at their website:  www.smileclowns.org   It&apos;s also membership renewal time for S.M.I.L.E. Members....or if you ever thought about joining this great organization, NOW would be the perfect time! Their calendar year runs from Jan - December. Dues are $25 per year and you get a fabulous quarterly newsletter filled with skits, routines, etc. They offer a nice potpourri of educational articles. You can also find membership information and forms on the website or if you have questions about the organization, feel free to e-mail me:  Sparky@... .   =========&gt; AFBEA Characterization Conference DEADLINE&lt;======   *****FINAL Deadline for Registrations has now been extended to December 31******** Don&apos;t delay.....get those registrations in NOW! You can also register online through the website found below!   18th Annual Educational Characterization through Clowning and Puppetry Camp.   Date: January 31 - February 3,2005        Location: Bullhead City, Arizona Description: The 18th Annual Characterization Through Clowning and Puppetry Camp continues to be one of the most rewarding and challenging experiences of your career. It will provide new and creative techniques and approaches using educational puppetry, clowning and characterization, which will enhance your ability in developing creative fire and life safety educational programs   Cost: $255 (non members of AFBEA)           $230 (AFBEA members only)   http://www.afbea.org/Docs/Camp%20Brochure.pdf   Very affordable housing at Harrah&apos;s in Laughlin. Complete details on brochure at the above link.   I&apos;ll be going this year so look me up!   ======================================   We&apos;re in the process of starting a new show in &quot;mid-year&quot; which is rare for us. This show will be a spoof of a newscast and is entitled &quot;DMFD TV-9 News.&quot; I think it may be one of our better ones. We&apos;re using a lot of the rap/hip-hop music (or whatever you call it) from the Colorado Springs CD (I just LOVE this CD). One song is from the Yellow-Dyno CD. I&apos;m hanging up my Sparky helmet for this program and playing an ANCHORWOMAN in a character roll. I&apos;m really looking forward to trying a new character. The puppets will be doing the commercial breaks and we have a BIG SCREEN TV (made in my craft room) where we will be doing live &quot;on-the-scene&quot; reports. We&apos;ve been adding little bits of humor, etc. of all local news stations. We don&apos;t perform our first program for 2 more weeks, but I&apos;m really excited about it. I&apos;ll continue to do all of my other shows as Sparky.   The next couple of months will be challenging for me as I&apos;m on the road nearly every weekend. I&apos;ll be at the AFBEA Conference in Bullhead City the end of January/first of February, go from there to the Show Me Clowns Conference in the Ozarks, then presenting a weekend class at  Winter Fire School at Iowa State University , then on to Circus Magic in Williamsburg, VA. Then starts March. So far I have only one state fire conference booked in Wisconsin in March. Will any of my Wisconsin friends be there?    I&apos;ve been encouraged by the thought that entertainers conferences have been adding one day &quot;pre-conference&quot; intensive workshops on educational safety. This was the set-up at the Kentucky Clown Derby. We had 28 registered for my class. Most were professional safety personnel but it was really very economical for them to attend a 2 1/2 day workshop. They spent the first day with me learning all about safety application, presenting school shows, etc. Then they had the remainder of the weekend to concentrate on the skills to back up their safety plan. It&apos;s a great concept and I hope it continues to grow. If you know anyone out East, pass the word along. Next Stop:  www.circusmagic.com February 25 - 27 in Williamsburg, VA.    ========&gt; New Year&lt;========   As always, this time of year is always good for setting resolutions, or goals for the upcoming year. Take time to reflect upon where you&apos;re at and where you would like to be headed. Are you doing enough for prevention.....or could you even consider &quot;cutting back&quot; some? Can you &quot;stretch&quot; your character to a new level? Could you concentrate on learning a new skill? Do you plan on attending at least one quality &quot;training&quot; event this year?    =========&gt; The End&lt;=========   Please keep sending me your thoughts, skits, illusions, stories, photos, etc. I&apos;ll try to get them out when I can!   That&apos;s all for now! May you each have a truly blessed Holiday Season and a prosperous New Year!   Love&amp;laughter,   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody   

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #125 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Mar 25, 2005 11:24 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #62 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Greetings from the Midwest!   It has been a LONG time since I&apos;ve sent out anything to this group. My travels in recent months has brought several new members to this group. WELCOME!   The last 6 months I&apos;ve spent a great deal of time &quot;on the road&quot; and &quot;in the air!&quot; This has enabled me to meet many new friends and touch base with some old ones as well. I presented a full day intensive workshop at the Kentucky Clown Derby in Louisville last October and at Circus Magic a couple of weeks ago in Williamsburg, VA. November took me to the annual S.M.I.L.E. Conference in Phoenix followed by the AFBEA Characterization Conference in Bullhead City, AZ the end of January. Then on to the Show Me CLowns Conference in the Ozarks and I just returned from a State Fire Inspector&apos;s Conference in Manitowoc, WI.    I&apos;ve enjoyed finding the balance in working with safety professionals who are working to better their characterization programs for prevention and working with professional entertainers who are wanting to use their existing talent&apos;s to present positive safety and self esteem messages.    I&apos;ve been having fun with our &quot;big school program&quot; this year. It&apos;s been really different for us........I even have a new character just for this program (photo attached), which is a FIRST for me! Our inspectors who do the BIG school programs with me are loving it, too! It&apos;s probably the most fun program we, as a cast, have ever done. The entire program is a newscast from DMFD-TV 9 &quot;Good News&quot; station. I serve as an anchorwoman who is half-clown and give the news from my anchor desk out front of the set.  We have a big-screen TV that we do LIVE-on-the-scene reports from. There are lots of commercial breaks which include the puppets with great messages. We&apos;re using a lot of music from the Colorado Springs Fire Dept CD and one song from the Yellow Dyno CD that we have actual light-bulb puppets sing.  The song is about listening to the &quot;light in your heart&quot; and doing the right thing. It&apos;s a great program!   We&apos;ve captured some mannerisms and quirks from each of the 4 local news stations in Des Moines which has captured the eyes of the media who have been loving the humor we&apos;ve found in them!  Another cool thing that we&apos;re trying with this program and it&apos;s working very well is I sit with my laptop in front of me at my anchor and actually have it plugged into the sound system which is located just behind the curtain I&apos;m in front of. Therefore, I am actually able to run all of the sound and sound effects right from the anchor which give us more manpower for other backstage duties.    When I first began working on a safety program in 1997, I thought it had to be something BIG. My husband had the puppeteer background from our church puppet troupe and I had the clown character from working in clown ministry. We shot for the stars right from the beginning which was FABULOUS but we quickly found out that with a paid department and 50+ elementary schools in our city, there was no possible way we could do all of the shows we would need to do each year. Over the years I&apos;ve developed a number of other shows on a variety of subjects that can be played well to audiences of all sizes. My character also grew stronger and I conquered doing shows alone. I&apos;m my own set-up person, sound person, clean up person.......everything. By downsizing, I&apos;ve been able to share many more different types of messages in different environments. When I work alone, I traditionally do mostly comedy/magic but sometimes will do some ventriloquism if I want to work with a partner.    Schools in our area know that we can only present our BIG program to one school each week. This means every school won&apos;t get that program in a school year.....and the program will change the following year. It&apos;s not unusual for us to have a waiting list to get a big program. That means Sparky is free the other 4 school days each week to do lots of other programs. Personally, I choose not to work much at a preschool level. I just don&apos;t feel that&apos;s where my &quot;gift&quot; lies with children. Not that I don&apos;t do them on occasion, but usually as a favor to someone.   A note to our new members.....this group is for networking!  I started it back in October, 1999.....wow, it doesn&apos;t seem like that long ago! You can go to the website at:  www.yahoogroups.com/community/lifesafety and signin to view all past posts and newsletters. There is also a photo section to upload photos of your characters/groups and a link section.     This is a place to post questions, give answers, share scripts, brainstorm ideas, etc. I moderate it to insure everything remains &quot;on topic&quot; and your mailbox isn&apos;t filled with spam. Since the majority of those on this list receive this at their work, I don&apos;t want you bombarded with e-mails. I&apos;ve toyed with the idea of opening it up, but my experience with other egroups has been WAY TOO MUCH mail!    Enough small talk........on with the little bit of news I have to share...........   Sparky &lt;:o) www.lafsforlife.org   ==========&gt; Sound Effects Software&lt;======== Hi,   My name is Matt Benson and I&apos;m a firefighter at Hudson Bend Fire Dept down near Austin Texas. I am wondering if you use a sound effects software or know anyone who might use one for there show? If you or anyone you know uses such software for there pub-ed shows I would greatly appreciate your help and advice.      Thanks a bunch,   Matt Benson HBFD   (Sparky&apos;s note: I heard about great software while in Bullhead, but I must have written the name down incorrectly because I haven&apos;t been able to locate it! Can you help Matt? E-mail me your response:  Sparky@... )   =========&gt;Safety Music Question&lt;========   Hi I am Mark Spillman &apos;Fireplug&apos; .   I am involved in the programs at Richland Hills Tx .We have a good program BUT we are not very creative .WE BORROW a lot . We need any music that we can get our hands on. We like to use music in our shows but we cannot seem to get any that is on disk or in mpeg form. We dont play instruments. We would appriciate any help .   my e-mail cowboymedc@... address 1404 oates rd, Bridgeport,Tx 76246   --------------------- Sparky&apos;s note : I feel your pain since I&apos;m not musically gifted either! Being in Bullhead this year was a reminder of just how many musically gifted people are involved in these types of programs....and I&apos;m not one of them! I have some personal favorite for recorded music that I use a LOT. My favorites include:   Safety Rock - purchase online at www.onewaystreet.com   Yello Dyno - purchase online at http://www.yellodyno.com/   Safety Hop - Contact Colorado Springs Fire Department   Music With Mar - She has 4 safety CD&apos;s out geared for different ages. You can get a safety package of all for for $39 (the cost of 3) purchase online at http://musicwithmar.com/   Please send me any great music ideas/resources you have and we&apos;ll create a complete &quot;updated&quot; list of safety music. Send them to me at Sparky@... .   =======&gt;S.M.I.L.E. News&lt;=======   The brochure will soon be out for an outstanding educational experience coming up the third weekend in November. Plan now to attend the SMILE Conference in beautiful Scottsdale, AZ. We Iowans LOVE going to Arizona in November! We have secured JT &quot;Bubba&quot; Sikes as our lead instructor. Complete plans will be out soon   The SMILE Newsletter just came out this week and is tremendous! There were a couple of great routines on anti-bullying that caught my attention along with others. This newsletter is a fabulous resource for anyone wanting to teach positive messages using variety arts such as puppetry, clowning, ventriloquism, magic, etc. For more information or to join, just visit the website:  www.smileclowns.org   =======&gt;Cool Website&lt;======   My buddy, Murray Joy in Maine just completely overhauled his website. There&apos;s a lot of cool things out there including newsclips, photos, etc. of many years worth of prevention programs. Stop out and be sure and sign his guest book so he&apos;ll know you&apos;ve been there!   http://mysite.verizon.net/vzep8b0a/   ======&gt;Submissions&gt;=======   Please send me your articles, questions, comments, resources to share here! This is YOUR space! Networking only makes our jobs easier. Send any submissions to me at Sparky@...   ======&gt; The End&lt;========   That&apos;s all for now. Looking forward to hearing from you!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org           

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #126 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Apr 14, 2005 4:21 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety - Safety Music sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Thanks to Cheryl &quot;Kawshun&quot; Evans for passing this along! You can find this story on CBS&apos;s Good Morning America website. A perfect example of the power of music in education! Personally, I love this CD and highly recommend it!   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org   With Safety CD, Girl Saves Mom 

 COLORADO SPRINGS, Co., April 6, 2005 
 
 
 
 
 
 CD Helps Save Mom&apos;s Life 

 
  (Photo: CBS/The Early Show) 

 
 
 (CBS)  Before you tell your kids to turn down that music, you might want to pay attention to the story of a little girl in Colorado Springs who learned a potentially life saving lesson from a CD.

As The Early Show correspondent Melinda Murphy found out in this week&apos;s &quot;Wonderful Person,&quot; you don&apos;t have to be Wonder Woman or Bat Girl to be a hero.

Five-year-old Jasmine was playing in her room when her mom suddenly got very sick and nobody else was home.

&quot;I was listening to my CD,&quot; Jasmine says. &quot;And then I saw my mom on the floor and then I called 911 because she was having a seizure.&quot;

Jasmine&apos;s mom, Madeline, has epilepsy, and has suffered through many seizures. Usually her husband or oldest daughter is around to help. But not this time.

&quot;She fell right here,&quot; Jasmine shows Murphy.

This time, Jasmine had to come to the rescue all by herself

&quot;I went 911,&quot; Jasmine explains.

The following is an excerpt of the call: 

 Jasmine: Hello

 Operator: This is Colorado Springs 911. Do you have an emergency?

 Jasmine: My mom is having a seizure. 

Tim DeLeon and John Bajza were among the firefighters who responded.

DeLeon says, &quot;On our first contact, she said, &apos;I knew what to do because I had a CD.&apos; After we started stabilizing mom, she ran to her room and proceeded to play it for us as loud as she could.&quot;

That CD is called &quot;The Safety Hop,&quot; and it teaches safety through songs. Coincidentally, it&apos;s the very CD Jasmine had been listening to when her mom was having the seizure.

The song goes, &quot;Call 911 whenever there is trouble.&quot;

Recorded by the Colorado Springs Fire Department, the music is intentionally fun . With titles like &quot;Under The Bad Smoke,&quot; &quot;Buckled-Up,&quot; and one of Jasmine&apos;s favorites: &quot;Call 911,&quot; sung to the tune of &quot;My Boyfriend&apos;s Back.&quot;

Jasmine agrees the songs are very usuful.

&quot;Yea,&quot; she says, &quot;Because they help me take care of my family.&quot;

Jasmine got the CD at school, part of a safety program developed by the local fire department.

Orlen Weaver runs the program, taking a special trailer from school to school to teach kids about safety.

How important is it to teach 911 to a child?

&quot;I think it&apos;s really important,&quot; Weaver says. &quot;Most kids from 5 and up know it. I talked to a group of 4-year-olds today, and one or two, had heard that and had an idea.&quot;

Weaver ends each session by handing out the CDs. He was the one who gave Jasmine her copy.

&quot;When I heard that,&quot; he says. &quot;I was thrilled to death because I had just seen her five days before her mother needed her help. And it was the firefighters who contacted me to tell me. And this tells me that what I&apos;m doing is worthwhile. It&apos;s making a difference. Needless to say, it was pretty exciting.&quot;

The Oteros agree.

&quot;I was so proud of her,&quot; Madeline Otero says. &quot;I was happy that she did that because that shows right there that she will take care of mommy.&quot;

Jasmine loves the CD for its music. In fact, even before all this happened, it was one of her favorite toys - a toy with a valuable lesson.

To other 5-year-olds, she says, &quot;Whenever you have trouble or your mom&apos;s having a seizure, you just need to call this number, 911.&quot;

The Colorado Springs fire department estimates that it has handed out more than 25,000 &quot;Safety Hop&quot; CDs.

For more information about Weaver&apos;s Smoke Trailer please call (719)385-7366. The message is ready to be sent with the following file or link attachments:
Shortcut to: http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2005/04/06/earlyshow/contributors/melindamurphy/main685877.shtml 

Note: To protect against computer viruses, e-mail programs may prevent sending or receiving certain types of file attachments. Check your e-mail security settings to determine how attachments are handled. 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #127 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Mon Apr 18, 2005 8:33 pm
 Subject: Life Safety - Music update sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Greetings again!   Someone mentioned they weren&apos;t able to see the photo in the last e-mail about the CBS Report on the Colorado Springs &quot;Safety Hop&quot; CD. If your e-mail prevents you from seeing it, just go to the website below:   http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2005/04/06/earlyshow/contributors/melindamurphy/main685877.shtml   Now, I&apos;m going to tell you just how BLONDE I really am! I just realized you can watch the entire video report at the website above. It&apos;s great! You can actually hear a clip of the music the little girl learned her lesson from. Lots more informative if you watch the video report!   &quot;Kudos&quot; to Colorado Springs Fire for creating such a FABULOUS resource! Hopefully they&apos;ll consider a &quot;sequel?&quot; 4 of the 5 songs we&apos;re using in this year&apos;s program is from their CD. GREAT resource!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #128 From: Sparky&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Jun 9, 2005 7:00 pm
 Subject: End of School Year! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 
 
 
 

 

 DMFD TV-9 
 
 

 
 Check out my photos 

 sparkydmfd has invited you to view a photo album on Yahoo! Photos 
 Today were presented our last program of the school year.  Des Moines&apos;schools finish tomorrow for the summer.  This year our&quot;themed&quot;program was a newscast.  I stepped into the roll of an anchorwoman.  All in all it was a GREAT year for DMFD TV-9.  The&quot;Good News&quot;station! 

 
 
 View DMFD TV-9 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 

 

 

 Try Yahoo! Photos for yourself Got digital pictures of your own? Upload them to Yahoo! Photos - then share them with friends and even get 35mm-quality prints. Find out more . Get 10 FREE Prints 
 Order Prints of sparkydmfd&apos;s photos for yourself - your first 10 are FREE! Just click &quot;Order Prints&quot; while viewing photos to get started. 

 

 
 
 

 If you can&apos;t see the button above, copy and paste this web address into your browser&apos;s web address bar: http://pg.photos.yahoo.com/ph/sparkydmfd/album?.dir=/eb50.src=ph.tok=phYjzHDBvR1y5IBo 

 Copyright©2005 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy - Terms of Service 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #129 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Jun 29, 2005 5:41 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety Issue #63 sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Greetings safety clowns&amp;professionals!   Just sharing that my youngest GRADUATED from high school last month!!!! This is truly GOOD NEWS in the Moody household!!!!!!!!!!!   Summer is well upon us and I&apos;m sure we&apos;re all grateful to be done with our school shows and moving onto other things. For the most part, our schools in Des Moines run from late August until the first of June. This year, due to &quot;snow days&quot; (we have plenty of those in Iowa) Des Moines Schools went through MID JUNE!!!!!! Unbelievable for us! Of course, the teachers aren&apos;t any happier about school dragging on like this than the rest of us are. Therefore, what do you think they wanted the most the last 2 weeks of school?????? YEPPERS! Lot&apos;s of assemblies......especially ones with puppets, clowns and magic! This combined with the fact that our weather turned extremely HOT very quickly made for one miserable clown. Temperatures the past 2 weeks in Iowa have averaged 95 by day with 75 - 95% humidity! You would think Sparky would be a &quot;tiny&quot; little thing wasting away under all those petticoats, but for some reason the heat doesn&apos;t seem to have that effect on me (grin)!    Once school completes the market completely changes for me. The summer &quot;camp&quot; programs start for all of the kids too old to go to the babysitter but too scary to leave home alone. I&apos;ve also filled numerous requests for &quot;Literacy Festivals&quot; so far this summer. Libraries are also requesting programs. When you&apos;re a safety clown, you don&apos;t have to look too hard for a group to share your messages with!   I just finished writing our new program for fall and we are busy building sets and making props. Traditionally I resume school programs the 2nd or 3rd week of September. Our schools usually resume the 3rd week of August, but they&apos;re busy working on bringing the kids back up to where they were at when school let out, and not yet ready for assemblies.    Today, I&apos;m sitting on the 24th floor of the Hyatt Regency in New Orleans catching up on work! I&apos;m here for a week with my hubby who is the &quot;working one&quot; this week! He&apos;s doing promotional assessments for the New Orleans Fire Department and I&apos;m enjoying some much needed R&amp;R. This is my first visit to this beautiful city and we&apos;re seriously enjoying it! Rick works from 8 - 5 each day and then we head down to the French Quarter, Bourbon Street or the Riverwalk for some good food and sightseeing! If you&apos;re contemplating brushing up on your clown skills, makeup or costume and want to visit this fair city.....keep in mind that Clowns of America International ( www.coai.org ) is hosting their national conference here next spring. You can find details on the website furnished.   When I return from New Orleans I will spend a week at our &quot;Burn Camp&quot; which is held in far NW Iowa, followed by our annual family vacation in the Ozarks. I&apos;ll return to jump right into the Iowa State Fair. This will be my 4th year at the State Fair (I think). The Iowa State Fair is one of biggest fair&apos;s in the world and a great opportunity to educate thousands of people! Last year I broke all records presenting 44 shows during the 11 days at the fair on 4 different stages. I spend about 9 hrs each day at the fair performing and meeting people.    I recently returned from another week at Clown Camp hosted annually at the University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse. This was the 25th anniversary of the Camp so we played with 350 clowns from all over the WORLD for one week. I was surprised to run into Keith Tanner (TX) there and Tanya (AZ) in addition to &quot;Guy&quot; (Appleton, WI) and a few other fire clowns that I can&apos;t remember their names (blonde moment). As always, it was a fabulous week of learning (and playing!) The last morning, the director Dr. Richard Snowberg, announced they will be repeating the Community Safety Education track during next summer&apos;s camping experience! I&apos;ll keep you posted with more details become available. It&apos;s an experience you don&apos;t want to miss and I know it&apos;s helpful to have this in your BUDGET as soon as possible. Let me say that &quot;Clown Camp&quot; is really one of the most affordable educational experiences available. You attend for an entire week so the registration of around $700 is ALL INCLUSIVE, meaning it includes dormitory housing and 3 meals at the cafeteria daily. They also many $250 scholarships available. CEU&apos;s are also available for this camp. More details should be available by early fall.   The next few months, I&apos;ll be traveling to New York, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Arizona and hopefully Hawaii! All but the Hawaii stop will be for educational safety clowning. In December Rick and I will celebrate 30 years of marital bliss and we&apos;re hoping to do that on Maui (grin). Sparky will NOT be going on the Hawaii trip however, we do plan to spend some time with my old buddy &quot;CoCo Nut&quot; who resides on Maui. I know you must be saying to yourself......&quot;Sparky can&apos;t be old enough to be married 30 years&quot;.....you&apos;re right....I believe I was 9 when we married (ha!)   Well, enough rambling. Lots of things I&apos;ve been saving up for you to share here. Please continue to send me our articles, ideas, etc. This is all about &quot;sharing!&quot;  Enjoy!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org   INDEX 1)  Sparky&apos;s Photos 2) Tenessee Fire Clown School 3) Fire Prevention Week 4) Murray Joy from Maine 5) Kentucky unveils new fire clown 6) McAllen, TX Fire Clown in the News 7) More Texas Fire Clowns in the News 8) Greensboro North Carolina Fire Clown 9) Bullhead City Fire Clowns in the News 10) Wisconsin State Firefighter Memorial 11) S.M.I.L.E. Conference 12) AFBEA Characterization Conference 13) Sparky&apos;s Unofficial Fan Club 14) The End   1)=========&gt;Sparky&apos;s Photos&lt;==========   I&apos;ve uploaded some photos to yahoo of our last school show of the season. This particular program utilized my new &quot;anchorwoman character,&quot; Annette Bugler. We did a live newscast entitled &quot;DMFD TV-9 Good News.&quot;   http://pg.photos.yahoo.com/ph/sparkydmfd/album?.dir=eb50&amp;.src=ph&amp;store=&amp;prodid=&amp;.done=http%3a//photos.yahoo.com/ph//my_photos   Clown Camp - University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse (the first of these photos are a field trip to the World Circus Museum at Baraboo, WI)   http://pg.photos.yahoo.com/ph/sparkydmfd/album?.dir=3e87&amp;.src=ph&amp;store=&amp;prodid=&amp;.done=http%3a//photos.yahoo.com/ph//my_photos   2) =========&gt; Tenessee Fire Clown School&lt;==========   My buddy Tom &quot;Huffy&quot; Hufford from Tulsa Fire will be hosting a weeklong Fire Clown School in Franklin, TN in the near future. For more information e-mail Huffy at huffytheclown@... .    Also CONGRATULATIONS to Huffy for his recent promotion to Assistant Fire Marshal of Tulsa Fire! KUDOS Huffy!   Stop by the Tulsa Fire Department Clowns website at: www.tfdclowns.com   (Sparky&apos;s note: Huffy was my inspiration and mentor when I first began educational safety clowning. I will be forever indebted to him for his giving heart and inspirations!)    3) ==========&gt;Fire Prevention Week&lt;=========   NFPA National Theme - &quot;Use Candles With Care&quot; &quot;When you go out - Blow out!&quot;   NFPA recently released the theme for the upcoming Fire Prevention Week, October 9 - 15, 2005.    Candles in homes are used for a variety of reasons and becoming more and more popular. Also, candles are in homes, churches and synagogues for a variety of rituals. For those of you who aren&apos;t familiar with NFPA, you can find a wealth of information at their website:  www.nfpa.org including statistical data that can be useful in your prevention efforts and grant justifications.   I have ordered a couple of candle puppets from One Way Street ( www.onewaystreet.com ) to be used in my school program for the upcoming year. They are &quot;Flicker&quot; and &quot;Shimmer.&quot;    Another idea I thought of from an &quot;illusionist&quot; view. Have you ever seen the &quot;appearing straw&quot; or &quot;appearing ladder?&quot; Well, Terry Ricketts shared at last year&apos;s SMILE Conference something similar that can be made out of those GIANT &quot;pixi sticks&quot; that come with the flavored sugar powder inside. They&apos;re plastic and probably about 2 ft long. You purchase several of those (very cheap), dump the candy powder out of them. Carefully cut them down one side so you can roll them up into a little wad. Secure with a rubber band and you can produce this from your pocket or even just your bare hand. This could be a measuring stick for how far kids should stay away from burning candles. (sort of like the 10 ft rule with a pool) Just thinking outloud.....please do share your ideas. Children are in complete &quot;awe&quot; that you could produce this 2 ft. straw from your bare hand.......and when you impress them this much, they&apos;ll remember the message. Another thought is to actually leave them with the produced straw and you&apos;ve also just given them their &quot;first magic trick.&quot; They will go on and share the same messages with their family and friends!    4) =========&gt;Murray Joy from Maine&lt;==========   Check out the following website of photos of a couple of safety clowns from the far Northeast (Maine). The school they presented at posted these photos on a website...go check them out!    Please note when looking at the photos, the little &quot;blue house&quot; they are using. Murray (aka Bubba) built this as a miniature &quot;smoke house&quot; that he can use with small groups to simulate a fire and crawling low under smoke. I believe their large foam props come from Peachey Keene ( http://www.peacheykeene.com/ )   Photos:  http://www.springhillweb.com/clowning/   Murray has also recently reworked his website. You&apos;ll want to visit his site below. Make sure you sign the guest book so he&apos;ll know you were there!   http://mysite.verizon.net/vzep8b0a/   5) =========&gt;Kentucky unveils New Fire Clown&lt;===========   Hello Pam,

I did a small birthday party at the firehouse. I attempted to use a
CLOWN VOICE, it lasted about 2 minutes. I&apos;ve got to work on that. I
ripped the crotch out of my suite, and a kid ripped my pocket almost
completely off. Other than that it went great.

Thanks for all your help,
Rob (Dwyer) aka &quot;Beeper&quot;   (I&apos;ve attached photos provided by Beeper) 
 6) =======&gt;McAllen Texas Fire Clown In the News&lt;========   Firefighter Robert Hernandez, aka &quot;Flash&quot; the fire safety clown from McAllen Texas in the news. Click on the link below to read the complete article:   http://www.themonitor.com/SiteProcessor.cfm?Template=/GlobalTemplates/Details.cfm&amp;StoryID=7081&amp;Section=Valley   7) =====&gt;More Texas Fire Clowns in the News&lt;========   Boots from Alamogordo appears at an EMS Safety Day. Find the article at the link below:   http://www.alamogordonews.com/cgi-bin/artman/exec/view.cgi?archive=523&amp;num=7843   8) ========&gt;Greensboro, North Carolina Clown in the News&lt;=====   Flame the safety clown and her performing dog, Ember are mentioned in the article found at the link below. I had the opportunity of meeting Flame at our conference in Des Moines back in 2003. She uses her dog in her performances and is actually a prevention employee of the Greensboro Fire Department.   http://www.yesweekly.com/main.asp?SectionID=18&amp;SubSectionID=44&amp;ArticleID=177&amp;TM=69933.55   9) ======&gt;Bullhead City, AZ clowns in the News&lt;=========   This article cam from the Mohave Daily in early May.............. 
Fire department clowns, talking bus share safety message at schools
 

By DANIEL McKILLOP
 
 Tuesday, May 10, 2005 7:55 PM PDT 

 

BULLHEAD CITY - Students at Diamondback Elementary School listened attentively as clowns and animated figures lectured them about safety tips during the &quot;Summer Safety&quot; show.

During the characterization program, Diamondback second-grader Jeremy Medile won a bicycle for choosing the name &quot;Mr. Safe &apos;T&apos; Bus&quot; for the Bullhead City Fire Department&apos;s remote-control, miniature school safety bus - which is used as a tool to lecture local elementary school students about bus safety in conjunction with Wal-mart two months ago.

Medile said he was &quot;happy&quot; when he won the bike.

&quot;My mom helped me,&quot; Medile said about how he came up with the name for the bus.

 

Bullhead City Fire Department public information officer Larry Tunforss said the bus was once known as &quot;Brains&quot; because it was a bus safety know-it-all.

Tunforss said Bullhead City public education specialist Barbie Barrett made fun of the bus during the demonstration and stated that Brains needed a new name.

After Brains&apos; name was ridiculed, the students from elementary schools throughout Bullhead City were given a handout and were invited to change the bus&apos; name.

In addition to Monday&apos;s bike giveaway, the show instructed students to wear helmets while on bikes, skateboards, roller skates and scooters, Tunforss said. The students also learned about water safety &quot;with all of the drownings we have in Arizona, we&apos;d like not to have any in Bullhead City.&quot;

He said water safety tips such as feet-first, first-time before jumping into the water, and swimming with a friend and wearing floatation devices were part of the presentation. The students were also instructed on how to call 911.

Bullhead City Fire Department Captain Marvin &quot;Rookie&quot; McCabe and firefighter Jeff &quot;Buzz Saw&quot; Jackson were garbed in clown attire and makeup while they presented the students with tips on summer safety issues.

Barrett was the ventriloquist for the puppet called &quot;Chimp&quot;, which was located on the stage to the right of the students. Bullhead City Fire Department Fire Marshal Jim Dykens was the ventriloquist for the puppet named &quot;Doctor Moopy&quot; off to the left.

Bullhead City school resource officers Brandon Grasse and Vincent Jaime also participated in the characterization program.

&quot;Summer Safety&quot; stopped at Mountain View Elementary School Tuesday and will continue to Desert Valley Elementary School on Friday. Sunrise Elementary School is slated for next week.
 10) ====&gt;Wisconsin State Firefighter Memorial&lt;======   In mid March I was presenting classes for the Wisconsin State Fire Inspector&apos;s Conference and learned of their fundraising efforts for a firefighter&apos;s memorial. They&apos;re hosting a GREAT &quot;raffle&quot; with some unbelievable prizes. Actually, there are hundreds of prizes, with the grand prize being a beautiful RED HUMMER! There are numerous other cars, boats and wonderful prizes available, but I can actually provide you with a testimony to the wonderful riding RED HUMMER, which they escorted me to dinner in one evening. I believe I will WIN this! (grin) (Sparky would look good in it!) Anyway, if you&apos;re interested in helping them out with their project and odds are very good that you&apos;ll win something, you&apos;ll want to visit the following website SOON! I think the raffle ends in August sometime. Tickets ar $20 each and your gift is &quot;tax deductible!&quot; All information can be accessed at the following website:   http://wsfmraffle.com/   11) =======&gt; S.M.I.L.E. Conference&lt;=========   If you&apos;ve never attended a SMILE Conference before, this is one you won&apos;t want to miss! JT &quot;Bubba&quot; Sikes will be the headliner instructor along with a host of great lineup of safety clown instructors (including me!). From a Midwestern standpoint, you just can&apos;t beat Scottsdale, AZ in late November! Mark your calendar now for November 17 - 19, 2005 and plan to join us for a fabulous 3 day learning event. (flyer is attached)   You can also find details on the SMILE website:  www.smileclowns.org   If you have questions, please e-mail me!  Sparky@...     12) =======&gt; AFBEA Conference&lt;===========   Mark your calendars for the dates below for the next &quot;Characterization Conference&quot; hosted annually by AFBEA in Bullhead City, AZ. Keep a watchful eye on the following website for complete details as they become available:  www.afbea.org (under EVENTS) Date: January 31st - February 2, 2006   13) ==========&gt;Sparky&apos;s Unofficial Fan Club&lt;==============   Last year at clown camp, I had the opportunity of meeting &quot;Giggles&amp;Harley&quot; a couple of great Shrine Clowns from Georgia. They teased me all week and became dear friends. They started their own &quot;Sparky Fan Club&quot; and Giggles just redid the website. If you&apos;ve got a minute, stop by the website below and click on &quot;Sparky&quot; at the top of the page. Be sure and sign the guestbook so Giggles will know you were there! (Thanks boys.....you truly flatter me!)   http://www.gigglesplacecom/giggles.html   14) ============&gt; The End&lt;=================   Wow, I&apos;ve been saving more than I realized! Please send me your contributions. Inquiring minds want to know!   Sparky Sparky@... www.lafsforlife.org 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #130 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Tue Jul 5, 2005 1:05 pm
 Subject: LifeSafety-Handouts Help sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 I&apos;m looking for Fire Safety handouts in SPANISH that I can order.  I need to use up this portion of my FEMA Grant in the next couple of weeks and I&apos;m having trouble locating Spanish materials to purchase.    Any help or advice of companies you order through, would be greatly appreciated! Please drop me an e-mail at Sparky@... or give me a call #515-299-3473.   *********CLOWN CAMP 2006 ANNOUNCED ***************   The dates have been set for &quot;Community Safety Education Camp&quot; at Clown Camp 2006. They will be June 4 - 10, 2006. This is held at the University of Wisconsin - La Crosse and CEU&apos;s are available through this University Program. Start planning NOW to attend this fabulous training opportunity.          Thanks for your help with the handouts!!!!   Gracias&apos;   Sparky 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #131 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Jul 15, 2005 1:24 pm
 Subject: Texas Summer Showcase sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Forwarding this along for Keith! I know MANY in this group are within driving distance of this event.   Sparky www.lafsforlife.org     ----- Original Message ----- From: Keith Tanner To: Sparky@... Sent: Monday, July 11, 2005 9:24 AM Subject: Texas Summer Showcase 
 
 HOWDY from Texas , Sparky! 

  

 I thought Id pass this along to you and the rest of the group. Were VERY excited to announce the THIRD Annual Texas Summer Showcase. This event, hosted by our wonderful friends up in Denton , is an event where departments can come together, conduct their Fall Life and Fire Safety Program in front of their peers, get a constructive critique and have time to do some fine tuning before hitting the road during October. This is also a wonderful networking opportunity where you can see different approaches to set construction, use of props, message delivery, sound systems and many other facets of Educational Characterization!!! Were trying very hard to grow this event into at least two days of nothing but programs! Who knows how big this could get!!! 

  

 Let me know if you have any questions and have a blessed and safe day!!! 

  

 &lt;[:o) 

  

 Keith Tanner, Fire Marshal/EMC 

 Round Rock Fire Department 

 203 Commerce 

 Round Rock , TX   78664 

 (512)218-6632 

  
 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #132 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Thu Sep 1, 2005 1:31 am
 Subject: Help needed for Lousiana! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Calling all who are trained in EMS, Paramedic, Nurses and/or Doctors!   I just received a call from Debbie Huffman, who works for the State Department of Health, EMS Division in Baton Rouge, LA. They are welcoming anyone who can volunteer to assist them in their efforts during this horrific event.   As they bring the dead and wounded from New Orleans, they come through a Triage Center which is located in the basketball coliseum in Baton Rouge. The ones who are not bad enough to be hospitalized are kept there and cared for at that location, leaving troom for the most critical in the hospitals.    They are in need of volunteers who meet this criteria. The people they have are tiring. This will NOT be a glamorous job as you would curl up in any corner you could find to sleep, etc.   If you would like to volunteer , or would like more information, please call Deb on her Nextel cellphone: #225-268-1512 . You would need to provide your own transportation as well.   The cellphone service is intermitted and often interrupted, so if you don&apos;t get her, keep trying or leave a message.    Prayers are welcome any time day or night!   Thanks, Pam 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #133 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Mon Oct 3, 2005 9:12 pm
 Subject: Technical Help needed! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Greetings!   I&apos;m in need of &quot;sound advice&quot; (no-pun intended).   I&apos;m needed to record bits of songs onto one CD. Can anyone tell me what the easiest way to do this is? Naturally, I need this like YESTERDAY (grin).   If you can help either respond to me at Sparky@... or give me a call at #515-299-3473.   Thanks in advance!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #134 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Oct 5, 2005 3:14 am
 Subject: update - thanks! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 Thanks to all of you who responded to me personally with technical advice for my &quot;technical&quot; dilemma!   When I get time, I&apos;ll share some of the great feedback and ideas with you. To those of you who have called and left messages, THANK YOU!   I wanted to let you know that my mother died unexpedly during the night last night so I&apos;ll be spending the remainder of the week in Southern Iowa at my parents home. She had battled Alzheimer&apos;s for the past couple of years and she was truly &quot;blessed&quot; with a massive stroke last night when at the hospital having her wrist set from a fall.    My program is temporarily &quot;on hold&quot; until this all passes.   Please keep our family in your prayers as we celebrate her life and mourn her passing. She was one fabulous person. She&apos;s survived by my father, who was a dedicated Captain on the Des Moines Fire Department for decades before retiring in 1984. He&apos;s been a tremendous husband and caretaker in recent years.    If you still have input on the &quot;technical&quot; sound issue, please continue to send them along. I&apos;ve been learning LOTS and great ideas for software programs.   Blessings to you all on your fire prevention efforts during this busy time of year!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #135 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Wed Nov 16, 2005 3:08 am
 Subject: LifeSafety Educational Clowns in the News! sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
 
Greetings and welcome to a &quot;NEWSY&quot; issue of the LifeSafety! I&apos;ve been collecting articles of &quot;fire clowns&quot; in the news for some time now and apologize for the delay in getting this out. It may not come to you all in one e-mail.......so don&apos;t be surprised if you get more than one. We have a great assortment of news from all over the country! Happy reading! ~Sparky~

1) Bullhead City, AZ

2) Plumas County, CA

3) Albany, GA

4) Pittzburg, PA

5) Avondale, AZ

6) Rockmart, GA

7) Pierce County, WA

8) Croton, CT

9) Gainesville, TX

10) Onalaska, WI

11) Greensboro, NC

12)  Fort Oglethorpe, GA

13) Camden, SC

14) Alton, IL

15) McKinney, TX

 1)=====&gt;Bullhead City in the News&lt;======== 

http://www.mohavedailynews.com/articles/2005/07/03/news/local/local%202.txt

 Higher education: College for Kids grads play to a packed house 
By DANIEL McKILLOP
 
 Saturday, July 2, 2005 9:11 PM PDT 

 

BULLHEAD CITY - Mohave Community College held its College for Kids closing ceremony to a packed house Thursday.

Graduates entertained the audience with music, song and dance. The students adorned the room with tie-die and silkscreen T-shirts, drawings, paintings, pottery and architecture - in the form of Egyptian pyramids.

Pam Campbell, who has been College for Kids coordinator for five years, said the program has been in existence for 24 years.

She said there were 45 graduates from Primary Fine Arts and 44 from College for Kids.

 

Campbell said Primary graduates range from kindergarten-third grade, and those from the College for Kids start at fourth grade.

&quot;We like to do a lot of fine-arts training because that is something that is not being done elsewhere in the community,&quot; Campbell said. &quot;We try to do a great number of arts programs such as paintings, drawings and ceramics.

&quot;This year, we added T-shirt designing, which is a pretty exciting class.&quot;

Campbell said the difference between this year&apos;s graduates from those of the past is their interest in computers.

&quot;Next year, we&apos;ll be offering more computer classes,&quot; she said. &quot;Computers were winning over a lot of other classes. There was a big interest in honing computer skills.&quot;

Caleb Herrell, who helped Phil Gobel instruct ceramics and T-shirt design, and will start his sophomore year at Mohave High School, said it was rewarding for himself and the graduates. &quot;A lot of these kids remind me of when I was little,&quot; he said.

Dan Hargrove, MCC governing board member, said he wished all of the graduates good luck and thanked all of those in attendance, &quot;When I look at these kids, hopefully, possibly, (they will be) future MCC graduates. Oh, that would be great.&quot;

Mike Kearns, MCC campus dean, took the podium next, and he said the program will continue next year.

The graduates then went into their entertainment mode. Forty-four Primary graduates marched onto the stage and performed the Fine Arts Parade of Nations. They sang &quot;I&apos;m a Little Teapot&quot; to represent England; they used shakers, guiros, go-go bells, and cowbells to depict the music of Jamaica; they danced with ribbons to exhibit China&apos;s artistic dance; they danced the German polka, and they sang &quot;America the Beautiful&quot; in recognition of the United States.

The Bullhead City Fire Department, &quot;American Heroes,&quot; arrived with the clown named &quot;Buzzman&quot; and the larger-than-life &quot;Captain Safety.&quot; The two animated figures&apos; charismatically captivated the graduates and the audience.

The graduates also depicted their experiences from Desert Survival Class.

The College for Kids Dancers performed to the song &quot;Let&apos;s Get It Started.&quot;

Some of the graduates sang American songs ranging from Jazz from deep in the Mississippi to &quot;When the Saints Come Marching In.&quot; They wrapped it up with &quot;I&apos;m Proud To Be An American&quot; and &quot;God Bless America.&quot;

&quot;It was an incredible program, and I&apos;m really glad my son (Tyler Long) got to take part in it,&quot; Alexandra Oswald said. &quot;He loved every moment of it.&quot;

Long, 13, said he enjoyed the music because &quot;he loves singing.&quot; The Egyptian studies, and the &quot;American Heroes&quot; were his most enjoyable parts of the program.

&quot;I want to be a police officer when I grow up,&quot; he said. &quot;I got to learn about the K-9 unit, forensics and stuff like that.&quot;

 2)=======&gt;Plumas County, CA&lt;======== 


 Forest Service to host fall festival 
 
 The Forest Service turned 100 years old July 2. The Plumas National Forest will celebrate this historic event Saturday, Oct. 8 at the second Annual Fall Fest at the Mt. Hough Ranger Station.



The theme for this year&apos;s festival will be Celebrating A Century of Service. Through activities, exhibits and presentations, participants can help salute the past and embrace the future of the forest.

The event will begin at 11 a.m. with an opening ceremony and a proclamation read by an actor impersonating Teddy Roosevelt, who established the Forest Service in 1905. The first chief of the Forest Service, Gifford Pinchot, played by another actor, will also make an appearance.

Highlighting the Fall Fest will be three living history presentations. Jim Armstead will portray mountain man and explorer Jim Beckwourth, and Fred Rutledge will portray Roosevelt.

Back by popular demand will be Frank Helling, who will present A Visit with John Muir. There will be only one performance by each of these individuals. The schedule is as follows: Jim Beckwourth at 11:45 a.m., Teddy Roosevelt at 1:15 p.m. and John Muir at 3 p.m.

Puppeteer and clown Tammy Jakl will entertain children and adults alike, while she teaches good land stewardship. Queenie, the Fire Clown, will also be at the festival to teach and encourage fire safety.
 
Children can learn about Remarkable Raptors as they examine skulls and owl pellets. Younger children will enjoy Goin&apos; on a Bear Hunt, a short walk in search of Smokey Bear. Other interactive games and activities will encourage children to learn more about the forest they live in or visit.

Richard Burrill will be returning to demonstrate Native American archery techniques. Also returning will be Ray and Gloria Gipson, who will demonstrate how plants were once used to dye cloth and wool, and how to extract the dyes. Visitors may want to bring chairs to enjoy the program. Sack lunches will be available for purchase, or pack a picnic lunch and plan to stay all day.

In honor of the centennial, Plumas National Forest invites retirees to staff a special booth, entitled &quot;The Way It Used to Be,&quot; and share stories and tales of their experiences while working for the service.

For more information, contact Judy Abrams at the Mt. Hough Ranger District at 530-283-7618; Michele Jimenez-Holtz at the Supervisor&apos;s Office at 283-7744; or visit the Plumas National Forest Web site at fs.fed.us/r5/plumas.   3)=========&gt; Albany, GA&lt;=========   Firefighters write new safety show for kids
 
 September 9, 2005 

 Albany -- Firefighters with the Albany Fire Department are going all out, to teach children to stay safe. 

  Firefighters are putting together an all new show for their 11th Annual Kids Fire Safety Day, to be held at the Albany Civic Center October 11th. 

 The firefighters from Albany and Lee County are writing their own new songs, music, and skits to teach kids fire safety. 

 They put on clown suits and make up to get the children&apos;s attention, and then teach them how to stay alive in case of a fire. Battalion Chief David Eddins said &quot;Not to play with matches, to be careful with candles and around stoves, if we instill that in their mind early on, then hopefully we can prevent property loss, and most importantly is unnecessary deaths.&quot; 

 Use Candles with Care is the theme for this year&apos;s Kids Fire Safety Day program. Kindergarten through second grade school classes are invited to attend the program at the Albany Civic Center October 11th, starting at 9:30. 

 Last year over five thousand children attended the fire safety program. 

 Firefighters use clown suits to teach safety
 
 
 October 11, 2005 

 Albany-- This is Fire Prevention Week. Albany firefighters put on clown suits and sang and danced for more than 4,000 students Tuesday, to teach them Fire Safety. 

  Firefighters go all out to grab the students&apos; attention, and teach them a life-saving lesson. Firefighter Bernadette Wilson said &quot;Little kids catch on better when someone is dressed up as a clown.&quot; 

 Talking matches and dancing smoke alarms grab the kids attention. Firefighter Whitney Williams said &quot;When you go out to talk to kids sometimes, it&apos;s better to interact with them, so they get the big picture.&quot; 

  This is the Albany firefighters&apos; 11th Annual Kids Fire Safety Day. Students, 4 to 7 years old from six Southwest Georgia counties, packed the Civic Center. 

 The firefighters wrote the songs and show themselves this year. Wilson said &quot;I&apos;m very proud of it. This is our first time doing this on our own, without using anyone else&apos;s skits.&quot; 

 The theme of this year&apos;s fire safety show is use candles with care. Williams said &quot;When you go out, blow it out. So that&apos;s what we&apos;re teaching them, and they seem to be a good job with listening.&quot; 

 Stop, drop, and roll, and the 911 emergency number were also important lessons from the firefighters. This show could save the life of one of these students, and that makes all the clowning around worth it. Wilson said &quot;I&apos;m thinking this year is going to have a better impact than any other year.&quot; 

 These firefighters enjoy making the children laugh, but they hope their message keeps them safe in case of fire. 

  Georgia Fire Safety Commissioner John Oxendine was one of the guests at the Albany Firefighters Kids Safety Day. 

 4)=======&gt;Pittsburg, PA&lt;========== 
 

 
Couple clowns around for fun

   
 
 
 By Mary Pickels 
TRIBUNE-REVIEW
 Friday, September 23, 2005 

 When spending time with Julz and Bunkers, one may feel a bit caught in a comedic tennis match.
Swivel your head one way as Julz pulls trinkets from a bag.
Waving a small plastic duck in the air, she says, &quot;Put it on my bill.&quot;
Holding a little condiment bottle, she jokes, &quot;Gotta &apos;ketchup&apos; with me.&apos;&quot;
Plopping a tiny stuffed gray bunny on her head, she says, &quot;Oops, a gray hare.&quot;
Palming a toy egg beater, she declares, &quot;I&apos;m whipped.&quot;
Swivel the other way and you are likely to see Bunkers constructing a balloon hat, his eyes growing wide with effort, as wide as the eyes of the child eagerly awaiting the prize.
In between breaths come the jokes, like why he doesn&apos;t sing as part of his act.
&quot;People tell me I&apos;m a tenor -- then they tell me 10 or 12 miles down the road,&quot; he says, deadpan.
He may pull out a huge plastic needle, and announce that he&apos;s there to administer flu shots.
Julz, aka Julie Thompson, 48, and Bunkers, aka Carl Mowers, 45, live in a prop-filled home in Westmoreland City. They perform as We2Clowns. And although they have day jobs, the two spend most weekends taking their clown act on the road, entertaining everywhere from children&apos;s birthday parties to church programs to nursing homes.
Thompson, who works as a customer service representative for Trans Care Ambulance in Monroeville, used to work for Hills department store. When a clown was needed for a baby fair, she agreed to don the costume.
&quot;I&apos;ve been a clown for about seven years,&quot; she said, &quot;but people who know me say I&apos;ve been a clown my whole life.&quot;
Thompson, president of Tri-Rivers Clown Alley in Pittsburgh, has attended various seminars and workshops to hone her craft.
But being a clown, she said, &quot;has to be in your heart. We&apos;ve gone the circuit. ... It&apos;s not an act. I don&apos;t change my voice. I just say it enhances who I am.
&quot;You have to look at things in a different manner,&quot; she said.
Thompson credits her father, John Voich, 85, for creation of many of her props, including a hat topped by a swing on which a stuffed parrot is perched. Thompson dons the hat and answers a question in the affirmative, the parrot swinging back and forth.
&quot;Whatever it takes to get the smiles,&quot; she said.
Mowers got his start in New York state, where he was a captain in a fire department involved with fire safety programs. His first year performing in front of school children was in 1992. He still recalls his knees knocking.
He attended a few seminars and learned about character development. Then, his fire department acquired &quot;Pluggy.&quot; The remote-control robot became his sidekick, giving him someone to &quot;talk&quot; with while performing.
&quot;It just started clicking,&quot; he said.
He moved to Westmoreland County in 2000, where he met Thompson. He was employed as a machinist at Kennemetal until it recently closed its drill division. He&apos;s mulling over the idea of returning to school to start a new career.
The two usually work together, but Mowers readily admits Thompson is more comfortable performing for very young children than he is. She acknowledges his superior talent as a crafter of balloon animals.
Thompson includes comedy, puppets and audience participation in her act.
Mowers finds the groans of an adult audience as gratifying as the giggles of children. He wears his humor on his suspenders, sporting pins proclaiming, &quot;Skinny clowns can&apos;t be trusted&quot; and &quot;Eat a prune, start a movement.&quot;
Mowers, who also performs magic, is more of a perfectionist with his appearance, Thompson said.
While it can take him an hour-plus to apply his makeup, using tiny brushes to get each line in place, Thompson takes a more basic approach.
&quot;These are my brushes,&quot; she said, holding out her hands.
&quot;Together, we complement each other,&quot; Mowers said.
Barbara Flynn, children&apos;s librarian at the Norwin Public Library, scheduled We2Clowns for a recent afternoon appearance.
&quot;They were very, very fun,&quot; Flynn said, &quot;I think as much so for the parents as for the kids.&quot;
As part of her act, Thompson read one of her favorite stories, &quot;There Was an Old Lady Who Swallowed a Fly,&quot; while using an animal puppet.
&quot;That helped to reinforce the reading aspect,&quot; Flynn said, while simultaneously entertaining the patrons.
The two were &quot;quirky,&quot; she said, and involved the children by using audience participation.
We2Clowns have encountered some unusual situations while performing. For instance, some people have severe clown phobias.
Once, Mowers said, he placed an order at a fast-food restaurant while still in clown face. When he drove around to the window to pay, the teenage cashier refused to take his money, staring at him in fear and asking her supervisor to handle his order.
They have been denied entrance to convenience stores while in makeup and costume, as workers were suspicious they were robbers attempting to conceal their appearance.
They endure children&apos;s demands to step on their shoes -- Thompson&apos;s cost $375 a pair -- or &quot;honk&quot; their noses.
They pretend it&apos;s the first time they&apos;ve heard an old joke, like, &quot;Why won&apos;t a cannibal eat clowns? Because they taste funny.&quot;
And they work to preserve the anonymity of a clown.
Although Thompson does not change her voice during a performance, she also does not reveal the person beneath the costume.
&quot;I can&apos;t tell you how many buffets I&apos;ve passed up,&quot; Thompson said. &quot;You don&apos;t want a kid to see a clown eating birthday cake. It takes away the mystique.&quot;
 5) ========&gt;Avondale, AZ&lt;========= 
 
Open house to teach kids, adults fire safety


 AVONDALE - To mark Fire Prevention Week, the Fire Department will host an open house to teach kids and adults the importance of incorporating fire safety at home.

Visitors can climb aboard a firetruck; children can meet Splash the Clown; and lunch will be served.

The open house will be held from 9 a.m. to 1 p.m. Saturday at Station 172, 1825 N. 107th Ave.
 6) ==========&gt;Rockmart, GA&lt;========   
 Puppets help teach fire safety message 09/28/05 
 Agnes Hagin 
 
 Funds from the Polk County Community Foundation and the Burn Foundation will be used to enhance the fire education program of the Rockmart Fire Department.
The money, totaling $1,000 from each foundation, will be used to purchase eight puppets and materials for building a stage that can be set up for shows to children, ages 3 to 5.
These youngsters will see an entertaining, 20-minute fire safety show that is designed to hold their attention. The focus of the program will be to convey safety messages: fire is a tool, not a toy, dont play with matches, if clothes catch on fire, stop, drop and roll. Kids are also informed that firefighters are friends and not to run and hide from them in event of an emergency and are shown the importance of a fire drill.
Fire Chief Todd Queen hopes the first presentation will be made during October, which is Fire Safety Month.
We start building a fire education foundation during the Pre-K and kindergarten years, Queen explained. It is reinforced annually as we revisit schools to update information presented. By the time students end elementary school, we feel they have a good foundation for fire safety education.

A fire safety program usually takes fire or six individuals. If there is a fire safety blitz (traditionally held in October), then everyone at the department is involved.
The decision to purchase puppets came after firefighters noticed the traditional fire programs for young children were not working.
We discovered we were scaring some of the little children, Chief Queen explained.
Thereafter, Queen said a different approach was view-ed to get the message across to younger children. Mem-bers of our staff learned in clown school that a puppet program can be used, he said. The puppets can be adopted to specific needs.
Typically, he said kids are not afraid of puppets. They see many in Sesame Street and other programs designed for young children.
We can adopt our own program or purchase pre-packaged programs, Chief Queen added.
Clowns are used in programs for children in first through fifth grade, which was described as a fun, interactive way to deliver the fire education message.
Fire prevention is the primary goal of the local department, which has a mission statement that includes prevention, protect life and property and extinguish all unwanted fire. If we can prevent a fire, two and three dont exist, Queen added.
In addition, he emphasized that fire safety education can save the life of a child.
We are fortunate that we have not had many fire fatalities in Polk, but there have been some in Georgia. Many of these are children.
Although children, five and under, make up about 7 percent of the countrys population, they accounted for 12 percent of the home fire deaths, assigning them a risk almost twice the national average, according to the National Fire Protection Association.
 7) ========&gt; Pierce County, WA&lt;======== 
 

 County groups unite in promise for youth 
 

 DEBBY ABE; The News Tribune 
Published: September 28th, 2005 12:01 AM 
 Investing in prevention today saves heartache and dollars down the road. 
Thats the common-sense premise behind the national Americas Promise movement that now includes nearly three dozen jurisdictions and organizations in Pierce County that have made a commitment to help todays youth.

Founded by retired Gen. Colin Powell, Americas Promise is an alliance of communities, individuals, companies and organizations that promotes five promises that every child should benefit from: a caring adult, safe places with structured activities, a healthy start and healthy future, an effective education and an opportunity to give back to communities.

On Thursday, the Alliance for Youth of Pierce County will honor the 24 newest affiliates that have vowed to promote the five promises.

The new affiliates range from the City of Tacoma and Tacoma School District to Kawshun D Safety Clown and Pierce County Juvenile Court.

Agreeing to promote the promises focuses attention on youth and gets everyone to talk in the same language, said Helen Myrick, chairwoman of the Pierce County of Promise Committee.

It also opens up grant possibilities.

The Greater Pierce County Community Network, which disburses about $100,000 in grants annually, requires applicants to address the five promises. Pierce County, the first county of promise in the state, makes a similar requirement of applicants to its youth violence allocation program, which disburses $1.3 million annually.

 8) =========&gt;Croton, CT&lt;======== 
 Come to kickoff Saturday

 
   
The members of Naval Submarine Base New London&apos;s Fire Department would like to invite everyone to the annual open house to kick off Fire Prevention Week this Saturday at SUBASE Station 2 on the corner of Lafayette Drive and Route 12. There will be free truck rides, a bouncing moonwalk for children, a static display of the Life Star helicopter, numerous fire prevention activities to help kids learn about fire safety, as well as other exhibits that will help adults get a refresher on things we can do to help our children stay safe throughout the year. Hot Rod the 911 Clown , Sparky the firedog, and Siren the interactive fire truck, will be there too. Jim Reed from WKNL KOOL 101 will broadcast live during the day and play some great music to keep us all entertained.
Last year&apos;s event was well attended and everyone had a good time. In addition to riding on the fire truck, children will also experience shooting water out of a fire hose. The fire safety house will be also be fired up so that children can see how smoke reacts in a house fire, and how to get out safely.
The event runs from 10 a.m. to 3 p.m. at the fire station in front of the Polaris Park housing area on Route 12. We hope everyone will come and have a great time.
If you have questions or want more information, call 694-3466 or 694-4487.

 9) =======&gt;Gainesville, TX&lt;========== 


 Sales help fire prevention efforts 

 By JENNIFER SICKING, Register Staff Writer 

In addition to getting out and staying out, National Fire Prevention Week allows firefighters the opportunity to teach young and old about fire safety.

It&apos;s just an opportunity for people to have an awareness and to make the public contact, especially with younger children, and teach them about fire safety, Mike Murphree, public education division chief of the Gainesville Fire Department, said.

This week Gainesville firefighters plan to visit Saint Mary&apos;s Catholic School, Robert E. Lee Intermediate School, W.E. Chalmers Elementary School and Edison Elementary School to talk to students about fire safety. Presentations at Saint Mary&apos;s, Lee and Chalmers will include presentations by the department&apos;s clown troupe, the Flame Outs.

With the kids we try to teach them to prevent fires, but also what to do if they have an emergency, Murphree said.

For adults, it comes down to being aware.

For years one of the most common was cook-related fires, especially in the early evenings, Murphree said.

Other types of fires, firefighters commonly see are from smoking or heating early in the fall season.

Heating, especially early in the year, when you haven&apos;t given them a good check up or forgot to move the combustibles (can cause fires), Murphree said. Unfortunately, human beings are pretty lackadaisical.

According to the to the National Fire Protection Association:

Only one-fifth to one-fourth of households in the United States have actually developed and practiced a home fire escape plan to ensure they could escape quickly and safely.

Home candle fires rose 15 percent from 2000 to 2001 to hit their 22-year peak in 2001, the latest year for which data is available.

During 2001, an estimated 18,000 home fires started by candles were reported to public fire departments. These fires resulted in an estimated 190 civilian deaths, 1,450 civilian injuries, and an estimated direct property loss of $265 million.

One-third of home candle fires occurred after candles were left unattended, abandoned or inadequately controlled. Twenty-six percent occurred when some form of combustible material was left or came too close to the candle. Six percent were started by people (generally children) playing with the candle.

There were an estimated 32,000 home structure fires per year associated with electrical distribution equipment fires between the years 1999-2002. These fires resulted in 220 civilian deaths, 950 civilian injuries and $674 million in direct property damage per year.

In 2002, children playing with fire started an estimated 13,900 structure fires that were reported to U.S. fire departments, causing an estimated 210 civilian deaths, 1,250 civilian injuries, and $339 million in direct property damage.

One-third of American households who made an estimate thought they would have at least 6 minutes before a fire in their home would become life-threatening. The time available is often less. Eight percent said their first thought on hearing a smoke alarm would be to get out.

 =======&gt;More from Gainesville, TX&lt;========== 
 
 Clowning around for fire safety 

 By JENNIFER SICKING, Register Staff Writer 

Through a take on Fear Factor, firefighters sought to teach fire safety through laughter Tuesday morning.

The Flame Outs - Gainesville Fire Department&apos;s clown troupe - visited Saint Mary&apos;s School with their fire safety message, and also touched on other emergency situations. Each year during National Fire Prevention Week, students visit the schools with their fire prevention message. Snakes, fire, burns and bicycle safety all played a part in the firefighters&apos; humorous skit called Fire Factor this year.

Firefighter Brad Thompson told the students the clowns faced challenges to see what they know about safety. The contestants were: Outback Jack, Wipe Out, Truckie and Buckets.

Buckets informed the audience he wasn&apos;t scared of anything.

I&apos;ve buffed up, he said.

After having a bucket of snakes dumped into their sleeping bag, Wipe Out had a snake attach itself to his leg. As he jumped around the gym, Thompson asked the other clowns who they should call.

Ghostbusters, Truckie offered as an option.

Buckets instead offered another suggestion. Nine, he started to say before the students yelled𔄣-1.

With that Buckets, took an early lead in the safety contest, and really never faced any serious competition from the other clowns.

Buckets lifted the plate to his face to dig in as three of the clowns bailed out of the eating contest. Thompson told Wipe Out, Truckie and Outback Jack they had to choose a replacement from the audience. Foregoing the numerous hands raised by the children, they selected teachers to sit at the table and face the maggots and lizard eyes.

However, they only had to eat one bite if they answered a review question about fire safety correctly.

Darlene Linder, one of the teachers who faced taking a bite, described the clown&apos;s performance and its message as wonderful.

It gets the kids very excited and draws attention to things they need to do to be safe, she said. Then they get home and tell their parents, which is a good reminder.

Chandler Herr said she learned an important lesson of not playing with fire, but her favorite part of the show was when they had to eat the maggots.

Juan Salinas said enjoyed the part where the clowns were riding bicycles and planned to jump trash cans.

They&apos;re really fun and they teach a lot of things about fire, Salinas said.

 10) ===========&gt;Onalaska, WI&lt;========== 

 Published - Friday, October 14, 2005 

 National Fire Prevention week recognized by area open houses 

By RANDY ERICKSON/Editor

 If Troy Gudie and Jeff Hoch are breaking out the clown paint, chances are pretty good it&apos;s the second week of October and National Fire Prevention Week again.
   
Gudie, Onalaska&apos;s assistant fire chief, and Hoch, an Onalaska minister and reserve member of the Onalaska Fire Department, put on the greasepaint each fall to help spread the message of fire safety to Onalaska schoolchildren in kindergarten through third grade.

The challenge for them is to keep their act fresh, because for those third graders it might be the fourth time they&apos;ve come to the Onalaska Fire Station for their lesson in fire safety.

No matter how they might change their routine, though, the messages stay the same

If your clothes are on fire, stop, drop and roll.

Crawl low in smoke.

Pre-plan a safe exit from the house in case of a fire, and have a predetermined meeting place.

Feel the door for heat before opening it if there is a fire.
 
 
 
Keep smoke detector batteries fresh.

When it comes to candles, if you go out, blow it out.

People can learn even more about fire safety and other safety issues at Fire Prevention Week open houses planned for Saturday at Onalaska and Holmen fire departments.

Onalaska&apos;s open house will run from 10 a.m. to noon Saturday and offers a chance for people to get an up-close look at the department&apos;s equipment as well as La Crosse County&apos;s emergency management mobile command post and mass casualty trailer, and ambulance and the MedLink Air helicopter, which is scheduled to arrive at 10:30 a.m.

The Onalaska event also will feature frequent door prize giveaways, refreshments and other health and safety displays. One of the door prizes is a chance to have lunch at the fire station with Onalaska&apos;s full-time firefighters.

The Holmen Area Fire Department will hold it&apos;s annual Fire Prevention Week open house from 11 a.m. to 1 p.m. Saturday at the fire station on Main Street, with tours of the fire station and fire safety information handouts.

 11)==========&gt;Greensboro, NC&lt;=========== 
 Fire safety: Learning a lesson for life 
 
 By Eric J.S. Townsend 
Staff Writer 

GREENSBORO - They laughed and they danced. They hollered and sang along to music.


And those were just the puppets.

Young students from several local schools had an even better time Friday morning as Flame the clown and her dog, Ember , taught them fire safety, getting a little help from some furry fabric friends.

Now if only the lessons stick.

Similar puppet presentations have taken place each day this week at the Greensboro Fire Department&apos;s training facility on North Church Street. Organizers say about 2,000 children attended the programs.

Entertainment was only part of the mission. Firefighters also hope the kids learned fire prevention, and perhaps an ounce or two of safety, especially with today wrapping up national Fire Prevention Week.

Although the year&apos;s theme was &quot;Use Candles With Care,&quot; lit wicks didn&apos;t get as much play from &quot;Reuben,&quot; &quot;Charles&quot; the monkey, &quot;Pepper&quot; the dragon and &quot;Jeremiah&quot; the -- what else? -- bullfrog.

Organizers instead stressed the danger of hot stoves, keeping smoke detectors in working order, and the stop-drop-roll maneuver for extinguishing clothing fires.

&quot;These kids are so young you almost don&apos;t want to plant the idea ofcandles,&quot; said Flame, known to colleagues as Mitzi Rice, the department&apos;s fire and life safety educator. &quot;At this level, (kids) see mom and dad with matches and lighters, and they&apos;re curious how it works.&quot;

That&apos;s not to downplay candle safety. An August report by the National Fire Protection Association reported that the nationwide number of residential fires ignited by candles each year tripled between 1990 and 2002.

With the holidays approaching, coupled with an expected hike in energy prices, local fire fighters anticipate candles contributing to an above-average number of blazes this winter.

Officials say this is the time to teach fire safety -- before such accidents take place.

&quot;The big thing is to get the kids to go home and talk about it with their parents,&quot; said Battalion Chief Bill Lentz. &quot;If parents sit down with their kids, they can draw a map of the house to show them how to get out in a fire.&quot;

 12) ======&gt;Fort Oglethorpe, GA&lt;====== 


 Fun fills Catoosa schools during Fire Safety Week 
 Santa and Fort Oglethorpe Fire&amp;Rescue Clown Battalion out and about town 10/17/05 
 Randall Franks 
 

 Santa and his friends play it up for fire prevention week. (Catoosa News/Terry Pennington) 
 The kids are all gathered snug on the floor; they anxiously await what comes through the door; the puppet Spike and his friends set the mood with a song; Peaches and Bubbles come out and sing along; the adorable clowns deck the halls with lights; they tuck themselves in for the night; Santa arrives and sees an unsafe sight; he tells Peaches and Bubbles what theyve done wrong; and fire safety lessons are learned by the murmuring, laughing and fun-loving throng.
With Fire Safety Week underway members of the Fort Oglethorpe Fire&amp;Rescue Clown Battalion are out in full force sharing its message with students in schools and at Constitution Hall.
Capt. Doug Flury, Fort Oglethorpe Fire Department public information officer, said the department has conducted the fire safety programs for children since the 1960s. In the mid 1990s the program added eye-catching robotics, performing puppets, and colorful clowns to get the message across, he said.
Flury said the Clown Battalion
 Students at Boynton Elementary School learn about fire prevention and safety during a skit presented by Fort Oglethorpe Fire&amp;Rescue. (Catoosa News/Terry Pennington) 
reworks the program each year to keep it fresh and appealing for the children.
Leisa Kibble, fire safety educator and public relations officer, enjoys being a part of the educational programs that touch thousands of Catoosa children.
Kibble said in just a few days this week the troupe gave 16 performances at Boynton Elementary School, Battlefield Primary and Elementary schools, Cloud Springs Elementary School and West Side Elementary School. The Clown Battalion also shared many of its programs at Constitution Hall with children from kindergartens and pre-schools that made field trips to learn about fire safety by visiting the fire station and seeing the program.
I expected the kids to just get coloring books and crayons and maybe get to sit in a truck and talk to a fireman, said Misty Martin-Chastain after attending a field trip with her son Austin to Constitution Hall with First Baptist Church of Ringgold pre-school. I was floored to see how much information my son was able to learn in such a short amount of time on fire safety. The entire program was so educational and well put together. Our family has a real fire plan now.
The group adjusts its program for the various ages of children it informs.
We completely write our own shows, Kibble said. This year was a take off around Scrooge (The Christmas Carol by Charles Dickens). It was probably the best show we have ever done and the kids went nuts when Santa Claus walked through the door.

Ebenezer Scrooge is a miserly character whose life is filled with wrongs he committed towards his fellow man and three ghosts take him back to see parts of his history. He has a chance to change his future by what he learns.
During the skit, Santa, with his elf Jingles at hand, informs Peaches and Bubbles they are on the naughty list for all they have done wrong.
Peaches and Bubbles have a fire burning in the fireplace; their shoes are near the fire; candles are flickering by their bed; their Christmas tree is loaded with lights and a turkey is cooking in the oven overnight.
In a Scrooge-type flash back, Peaches and Bubbles travel to holidays throughout the year and see their fire safety mistakes from the Fourth of July to Halloween.
Angie McDonald, fire prevention educator, said the group is always nervous when it is preparing a new show for the children.
After we were finished we had people coming up telling this was our best show, she said. That sets our mind at ease.
We try to be creative when we do it, she said We are sent out to teach fire prevention but weve covered way more than that this year.
Deputy Chief Merv McDonald said the programs concentrate on four or five subjects such as EDITH (Exit Drills In The Home). The program teaches children about safety plans to get families out of the house in the event of fire.
When students see these programs for five to seven years, hopefully its something theyll remember for a lifetime, he said.
Teaching children not to play with matches or fireworks; sharing home safety relating to the kitchen, fireplaces and candles; learning home addresses and how to call 911 were all in this years program, he said.
A key reminder is for families to change their smoke detector batteries when they change their clocks back this fall, he said.
These programs provide tools to grow up and become adults and be safe, he said. Just as math gives them tools. Its just another tool in their toolbox.
McDonald said providing the programs in the school system is a perfect situation.
The schools bend over backwards to accommodate us, he said. Its the only way we can target that many individuals at any one time. We encourage the students to take that information back to their parent s. We even send a survey out to parents to get them to find out what (their kids) learned about.

 13) =======&gt;Camden, SC&lt;======= 


 CFD&apos;s smoke detector safety program earns Energizer award 
 

 By MARTIN CAHN, C-I assistant editor October 31, 2005 

 

       
 

 The Camden Fire Department has received one of five National 2005 Energizer Keep Going Awards for Fire Safety.
 
 

 

 
  
According to the Energizer Battery company, the CFD received the award for ``going the distance in encouraging the Camden community to adapt the lifesaving `Change Your Clock, Change Your Battery` message.``

The Camden Fire Department will receive $1,000, as well as a battery donation of 2,000 Energizer Max 9-volt batteries, to further aid in its fire safety efforts.

Camden Mayor Mary Y. Clark noted the honor at Tuesday morning`s city council meeting and asked CFD Chief John Bowers to explain the award.

Bowers said that before 1986, there were about 160 fire deaths in South Carolina each year. Now, it`s less than 100.

``That`s still 100 too many, but it was an almost overnight change, and those numbers have stayed there,`` said Bowers.

The big push to install smoke detectors in targeted communities around the state came in 1986, he said.

``We believe this is a fundamental part of what we do,`` said Bowers.

He said because Energizer is donating so many batteries, the CFD will likely share them with the Lugoff Fire Department and Kershaw County Fire Service.

``We feel they would go bad before we could use them all,`` Bowers explained.

The fire chief said the $1,000 grant will go toward the department`s program of installing smoke detectors for anyone who asks.

``Our goal is to make sure your head doesn`t hit the pillow tonight without working smoke detectors,`` he said. ``In fact, we`ll install them for you. We want to keep you off the ladders.``

Bowers said his department installs smoke detectors in about 10 to 12 homes each week.

According to Energizer information, the Change Your Battery program encourages Americans to change the batteries in their smoke alarms when they change their clocks back to Standard Time, which takes place Sunday.

``The Camden Fire Department was selected for the countless hours spent on preparation of its fire safety clown and puppet show,`` said Energizer Vice President of Marketing Jeff Ziminski. ``Each year this group takes its puppet show on the road to schools, day cares, churches and adult day cares. This creative program and their free-of-charge replacement initiative underscore the department`s commitment to fire safety education.``

Ziminski said public education about smoke alarm maintenance is vital in reducing the number of home fire fatalities each year.

``The Energizer Keep Going Awards are a small way we can honor and recognize the hard work and dedication of fire departments nationwide that tirelessly put themselves on the line to promote this lifesaving message throughout their communities,`` said Ziminski.

He said the CFD is one of the 5,800 fire departments across the United States spending time canvassing neighborhoods to change smoke alarm batteries, holding educational fire safety events and creating awareness about the importance of working smoke alarms in preventing home fire fatalities.

Energizer and the International Association of Fire Chiefs have worked together on spreading the word to change smoke alarm batteries when resetting their clocks for daylight-saving time for 18 years, company officials said. 
 


 14) ========&gt;Alton, IL&lt;=============== 
 
 
  
 Fire captain turns clown Skits teach children safety
 
 
 
 REUBEN MEYER, For The Telegraph 10/19/2005 
 
 
 
 
       
 

 
 The Telegraph/JOHN BADMAN Capt. Dave Owens of the Hartford Fire Department performs a fire safety skit last week for pre-schoolers at South Roxana Elementary School. Owens, who teaches the children as Senders the Clown. 
 HARTFORD -- For Capt. Dave Owens of the Hartford Fire Department, teaching fire safety to children is all about clowning around. 

 Owens, the alter ego of Senders the Clown, performed his skits at Roxana and Hartford grade schools last week to promote fire safety during National Fire Prevention Week.

On Thursday, Owens and other members of the Fire Department presented their fire safety message to an enthusiastic group of first- through third-graders at Hartford Elementary School. Owens said he hopes his message of fire safety sinks in with the children.

&quot;We want to make the skits as lifelike as possible so the children will be able to react as normally as possible in the event of a fire,&quot; Owens said.

For Owens, donning the clown make-up is a fresh approach to teaching children about fire prevention and safety. Owens was exposed to the idea of using clowning while training in Texas.


 Advertisement 
   
 &quot;I saw video of a clown teaching fire prevention to a group of children. It was awesome. There was a lot of interaction between the clown and the children.&quot;

When Owens returned from training in Texas, he presented the clown idea to Fire Chief Ron Cobine and the villages Board of Trustees, who were skeptical at first.

&quot;Yeah. Right. Whatever. Thats the response I received,&quot; Owens said.

Owens said he thought his clown idea would be more effective than the &quot;smoke house,&quot; which the Fire Department had used previously. The smoke house is a two-story building the department would fill with smoke to teach children how to react to a fire. Owens found the smokehouse wasnt always an effective aid.

&quot;The older kids loved the smokehouse, but it scared a lot of the little kids.&quot;

Once he received the departments blessing in February, Owens was off to Arizona to learn the clown trade and how to incorporate it into teaching fire safety. He spent a week at the Arizona Fire and Burn Education Association Clowning and Puppetry Camp, where he learned new and creative techniques using clowning and characterization. The techniques allowed Owens to enhance his abilities to develop his fire and life safety program.

&quot;I learned clown etiquette and techniques that make our fire safety program more exciting for the kids,&quot; Owens said.

Any apprehension Owens had about the success of the program quickly vanished with the reception received at the pilot presentation.

&quot;We had 20 kids up at the firehouse. It was a big hit. The kids loved it,&quot; Owens said.

Members of the Fire Department support Owenss skit. Each plays a positive role in making the skit a success. Owenss brother, Bill, plays the role of the drill sergeant in the skit.

&quot;In the skit, my brother points out everything Im doing wrong and makes me do it over the right way. Its more powerful than just standing and lecturing the kids,&quot; Owens said

The fact that Owens is the father of two gives added weight to the message hes presenting.

&quot;If being a clown helps send the message that fire safety is important, then Im doing my job. Theres no price tag on a childs life,&quot; Owens said.   15) ==========&gt; McKinney, TX&lt;============== 
 Firefighters teach students not to clown around in crisis 

 By TRICIA SCRUGGS McKinney Courier-Gazette 

Last month 10,194 elementary school students in McKinney learned how to respond to emergency situations.

A group of skilled McKinney firefighters also trained to be clown characters, known as the McTown Klownz, wrapped up a month-long program Tuesday, teaching children about fire and life safety.

As far as public education is concerned our theme is fighting fire with fire education, said Keri Price, the department&apos;s public education coordinator.

She said since 1970 the number of injuries and fires has dropped as awareness of how to handle emergencies and how to prevent fires rose.

Advances in technology have had something to do with that, but I think a lot of it is education, Price said. I know that people 20 years ago fought a whole lot more fires than I ever will see.

Characters Boots, Flash, Hoser, Siren and Rescue began preparing the program months in advance by writing their own scripts, rhymes and building sets like the movie theater backdrop displayed at McNeil Elementary School Oct. 28.

The clown troupe accompanied by D.J. Nitpick who helped usher students into the cafeteria and played crowd pumping songs like Let&apos;s Get it Started, Who Let the Dogs Out, and Y.M.C.A., performed skits showing how to handle choking, fire, hand gun, stranger danger&apos; and seat belt situations.

When you panic in an emergency, you can&apos;t remember what you&apos;re supposed to do, Siren told Boots and the students as the duo rapped the first rule in any emergency, ABC or Always Be Calm.

Other lessons included stop, drop, cover your face and roll during a fire and don&apos;t touch, get an adult when it comes to hand guns.

Assistant Fire Chief Frank Roma said the clown program started with one employee who wanted to educate the public about safety. He said while visiting a school where the troupe had performed the prior week he quizzed a kindergarten class about what they learned.

They knew it down pat, Roma said. They&apos;re really learning something and that shows the value of this program. We&apos;re proud of the work our folks put into it and it gets bigger and better every year.

The McTown Klownz also travel to smaller districts in Collin County like Anna, Melissa and Van Alstyne where fire departments don&apos;t already have a clown education program.

Each clown completed a four-day beginner&apos;s class where they learned how to apply make-up, clown etiquette and costuming. Some continued learning additional techniques like making balloon animals and performing magic tricks. Next month the clowns will perform at the National Clown School in California showcasing their popular program, which also generates visitors from local fire departments.

We want people to know that these are firefighters who volunteer to participate in this program to help educate the community, Price said. Children will take the message back home to their parents, so we&apos;re not just reaching the kids, we&apos;re reaching the whole family.

 
 
 
     

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) #136 From: &quot;Sparky&quot;&lt;SparkyDMFD@...&gt;
 Date: Fri Nov 18, 2005 6:36 am
 Subject: LifeSafety Educational Opportunities sparkydmfd 
 Offline 
 Send Email   
   ----- Original Message ----- From: Sparky To: lifesafety@yahoogroups.com Sent: Friday, November 18, 2005 12:21 AM Subject: LifeSafety Educational Opportunities 
   ----- Original Message ----- From: Sparky To: LifeSafety@yahoogroups.com Sent: Tuesday, November 15, 2005 10:35 PM Subject: LifeSafety Educational Opportunities 
 Tonight I&apos;m enjoying some quiet time in Prescott Valley, AZ and obviously catching up on cleaning out my e-mail folder! Sorry if I appear to be bombarding you with e-mails this evening, but these are all things I&apos;ve been wanting to pass along, but just haven&apos;t had the chance.   I&apos;m enjoying being in AZ much more than some of you can appreciate as I know that we&apos;re getting our first BIG snow in Iowa tonight! So glad I&apos;m not there to shovel it!   Wednesday I&apos;ll be headed to Phoenix to attend the annual S.M.I.L.E. Conference.  If you live in the area, there&apos;s still time to register for this premier educational safety clown/puppeteer conference! You can find a brochure at the following website:   http://www.smileclowns.org/PDF/SMILEConference2005.pdf  . I&apos;ll be returning to Iowa on Sunday......only to leave again on Wednesday for beautiful MAUI, HI. Perhaps if I play my cards right, I can dodge &quot;winter&quot; in the Midwest for this year! (grin)   =========&gt;2006 AFBEA Characterization Conference&lt;======= (yippppeeee! another reason to leave Iowa in the Winter!)   19th Annual Educational Characterization Through Clowning and Puppetry Camp     We Are Now Taking Registrations Date: January 30th - February 2, 2006        Location: Bullhead City, Arizona Cost: $230 AFBEA Members    $255 Non-Members        Hotel: Ramada       Rates: $18 and $42 Description: The 18th Annual Characterization Through Clowning and Puppetry Camp continues to be one of the most rewarding and challenging experiences of your career. It will provide new and creative techniques and approaches using educational puppetry, clowning and characterization, which will enhance your ability in developing creative fire and life safety educational programs I&apos;ve attached a flyer to this e-mail, but you can also find all of the details at the following link: http://www.afbea.org/Events.htm   =========&gt; University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse / Clown Camp&lt;========   Community Safety Education Week will be repeated at the original and official &quot;CLOWN CAMP&quot; held at the University of Wisconsin-LaCrosse! This will be the 26th year for Clown Camp on this campus and the second time they have hosted a community safety education week. The first time (2004) was a tremendous success and they will build upon that program for the 2006 week! Another track being held simultaneously is &quot;Humor and Clowning For Educators&quot; and I&apos;m sure these two tracks together will only compliment the overall program!    http://www.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/htm/courses.htm#Comsafety   Clown Camp home page:  http://www.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/   Numerous scholarships are available for Clown Camp. You can get them through the actual Camp at their website. There are also scholarships available to members of COAI and WCA. Check out this link:  http://www.uwlax.edu/clowncamp/htm/schchaaut.htm#scholarships   Camp runs from June 4 - 9. One of the greatest things about camp is the registration is ALL INCLUSIVE! You&apos;ll be housed in the dormitories on campus and receive 3 meals per day in the campus cafeteria. The shows alone are worth the registration cost. It&apos;s an unbelievable educational experience, not to mention just plain FUN!    You can receive additional information and a full color brochure by contacting the camp office at: snowberg.jani@...   I&apos;ll be on staff again this year and hope to see many old friends return and meet many new!    (If you&apos;ve never visited this area before and plan to come to camp....plan to add a day to your trip and see the World Circus Museum at Baraboo, WI! You&apos;ll be glad you did!  http://www.circusworldmuseum.com/ )   ==========&gt;Condolences&lt;=========   Our deepest sympathies are extended to safety clown &quot; Debbie Huffman &quot; from Baton Rouge, LA on the recent death of her son, David. David was murdered when a stray bullet entered their home while he played video games in front of his television. He was a junior in high school. Debbie works for the Lousiana Department of Public Safety and coordinates their state safety clown program. If you&apos;d like to send a card, mail to Jeff&amp;Debbie Huffman, 3041 Toulon Dr., Baton Rouge, LA 70816-2155.   ============&gt;Sparky Updates&lt;=========   First of all I want to thank you to so many of you who sent responses to my request for &quot;sound advice!&quot; My problem was resolved, but not by any of my doings! I&apos;m just as &quot;green&quot; in this field as I was before. We have a new Captain in our troupe that comes with this knowledge and also has served extensively in his church puppet troupe. He&apos;s added so much to our program this year! I WILL be present in Bullhead City this year at the annual Characterization Camp, and I obviously need to spend some time taking some of the &quot;sound classes&quot; there! I&apos;ll be the one looking for a &quot;Tudor&quot; so seek me out! (grin)   I was off to a slow-start to Fire Prevention Week/month with the unexpected death of my mom on October 4. Thanks to all of you for your notes of encouragements and kind words. They were much appreciated. I took two weeks off and wondered if and when I could once again done my red nose....but time does heal and the one thing my mamma was proud of was her daughter, the safety clown!    The middle of October took me back to the Wisconsin State Fire Inspector&apos;s Conference in Wausau but this time, I went strictly as the banquet entertainment! This was my fourth conference with this group but the first time strictly as an entertainer and not an educator. What a great group of people they are! I had a great time and spent 2 nights and 3 days with them. My dad accompanied me which was good for both of us. He is a retired fire captain from Des Moines and found himself right at home with the Wisconsin Fire Professionals.    I must share a somewhat humorous experience that I won&apos;t soon forget. The night of the banquet, it was nearly midnight by the time I broke down my set and had my van packed. A quick shower and returned to the lounge for some chat and a nightcap took us to bed plenty late! About 4 AM we were awoken by the smoke detector in our room. Dad woke up first and was up &quot;whiffing&quot; around the room, obviously smelling something burning...and looking for the cause. I stumbled to the door to see if there was smoke in the hallway. It ended up to be the heater in our room, we unplugged it and the smoke detector quit beeping. I called the desk to alert them to our dilemma just in case anyone else in the hotel was experiencing smoke and fire alarms in their rooms, I thought they should know. The hotel operator&apos;s response to me was, &quot;Oh, it&apos;s probably just the heater in your room. This happens every year about this time when the dust burns off. I&apos;d suggest if you want to get a quiet night sleep....you just take the BATTERIES out of your SMOKE DETECTOR !&quot; Now remember, we&apos;re attending the Wisconsin State Fire Conference and they have 250 firefighters staying in this hotel! This will certainly be &quot;show material&quot; for future safety professionals! Just in case you&apos;re wondering......NO we didn&apos;t take the batteries out of the smoke detector and we didn&apos;t really get much sleep the rest of the night! It was a long drive home the next day! Now for the big question.....did Sparky practice what she preached? Let&apos;s just say....I need to have a few more drills. Did we &quot;roll out of bed...staying close to the floor.....NO! Did I crawl to the door and FEEL it with the back of my hand before opening.....NO! I flung it wide open and jumped into the hallway! BAD, BAD Sparky! Guess that&apos;s why those drills are sooooooo important!    Now, I&apos;ve drug dad along with me to Arizona for the SMILE Conference! He&apos;s visiting family here while I attend the conference. We flew in on Sunday which was an experience since it was dads first time FLYING! We&apos;ve been having a great time traveling together. It gives me someone to travel with and it&apos;s keeping him busy....and he, too....is missing out on all the snow at home! I haven&apos;t yet convinced him to go to Laughlin with me the end of January....but don&apos;t be surprised if I talk him into it! Chief Rickey (my better half) will be attending the National Fire Academy and will have to miss the Bullhead Conference for the first time, but I do think there may be another couple from our puppet troupe tagging along as well. I believe my 22 yr old daughter, may be coming along as well, just for a little vacation.    I&apos;ve been wearing Sparky and our troupe ragged trying to play &quot;catch-up&quot; on all shows that had to be cancelled in early October. I needed to get everything caught up before coming to the SMILE Conference because of my pending trip next week to Hawaii! By Thursday of last week I was at my throat specialist with acute laryngitis, which I get frequently. Our show this year has met with AWESOME comments! We got the idea from another troupe that performed last year in Bullhead City. Sorry, I can&apos;t remember the name of the group, but it&apos;s a spoof of the movie, Ladder 49. We call it &quot;Firestation 49.&quot; We changed the script greatly from theirs and some of the behaviors to meet the concerns of our area, but the concept remains theirs. You can see some photos from our production this year at the following elementary school webpage  http://www.pleasanthillpto.org/dsm_fire.htm   Please send me information about your group/programs to share! Since I&apos;m slow at getting these out to you, I send warmest wishes for a joyous holiday season your way in advance!   Pam &quot;Sparky&quot; Moody www.lafsforlife.org   

 

 Reply | Messages in this Topic (1) 
 
 Messages 107 - 136 of 184  Oldest  |  &lt; Older  |  Newer &gt;  |  Newest 

 
      What&apos;s This? Actions Start Topic 
Just address an email to LifeSafety@yahoogroups.com

 Jump to a particular message Message # Search Messages Advanced 
SPONSOR RESULTS
 
 Home Fire Sprinklers HomeFireSprinkler. org - Home Fire Sprinklers Save Lives - Free Info 
 

 Safety&amp;First Aid SafetyEquipment. CPR-Savers. com/ - Wholesale Safety Equipment: $AVE on OSHA/ANSI safety kits&amp;First Aid. 
 

 Environmental Issue Local.com - Looking For Environmental Issue? Find It Nearby With Local.com! 
 
 
 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
