<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005899" url="http://community.jennycraig.com/index.php/topic/75678-cheating-a-bit-and-losing-still/" time="2012-07-12-22:34" support="4" score="0.00780673664708404" bingtitle="Cheating a Bit and Losing Still - Jenny Craig" webtitle="Cheating a Bit and Losing Still - Jenny Craig">
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="156"/>
	<description>... sandwich with frosties to drink ... items if you go out to a fast food restaurant. I know when I started Jenny, I had to get an ... of &quot;cheating&quot; I actually got my order ...</description>
	<body>
		Jump to content 
 
 Jenny 
 
 
 
 
 how it works 
 
 
 overview details program options location options consultant advantage 
 
How it works

Oh, it works, alright. Find out what&apos;s in our secret sauce. You&apos;ll learn the details about all our programs, including the one that works for you. Find out where you can meet with your consultant, why she makes all the difference in the world, and how Jenny will rock yours.
 
 
 cuisine 
 
 
 overview breakfast lunch dinner snack/dessert 
 
Cuisine

Real cuisine for real people. Let&apos;s just say deprivation isn&apos;t on the menu. Find out what is, including all the craveable options for breakfast, lunch, dinner, snacks, and that all-important menu item—dessert. Plenty of choices for your taste and mood.
 
 
 real stories 
 
 
 overview Mariah Carey 
 
Real Stories

Read about people who&apos;ve walked a mile in your pant size. You&apos;ll read stories from people from all walks of life who are living Jenny every day. If they can do it anyone can. Yes, that means you. Get inspired today!
 
 
 tools 
 
 
 overview 
 
Tools

One of the many advantages of Jenny is access to useful tools that make things easier. Unlike other programs, many Jenny tools are free for you right now. So have at &apos;em.
 
 
 community 
 
 
 overview forums blogs 
 
Community

Get in on the conversation! Celebrate reaching milestones. Get support for the moments when the donut is calling you. Connect with real people who get where you&apos;re coming from and believe in where you&apos;re headed.
 
 
 Log in Free consultation? Call us! 
 
      Sign In     Create Account 
 Search Advanced 
 Search section: This topic This forum Forums Members Help Files Calendar Blogs Pages 
 
   View New Content Forums Members Calendar Blogs Chat More 
 
 Jenny Craig → Welcome → New Members 
 
 3 
Cheating a Bit and Losing Still
 Started by BlueEyedAngel , Mar 03 2012 02:09 PM Losing Cheating Snacking 
 
 
 You cannot reply to this topic Go to first unread post 
 9 replies to this topic 
 #1 BlueEyedAngel 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 430 posts 


 
Posted 03 March 2012 - 02:09 PM 
 Alright, I have been doing great on Jenny!After three full weeks I had little temptation for other foods. I have been eating yogurt if there was snack I wasnt too thrilled about. Yesterday I cheat twice!I want to tell everyone that even though I dont recomend it, I found it a good experience for me. When I weighed myself yesterday morning I was at 331.8 pounds. I weighed in at 333.0 the day before I thought it was a fluke. I doubted I had dropped a 1.2 pounds in a day. Anyways..my day went on. Work has been hectic and I go into work at 4:00 am. So I had my brocoli potato around 9:00 (anytime bar and apple at around 6 am). We live thirty miles out of town, so when my husband got off of work at 11:00 we went to wal mart and I asked if he was hungry. He said yes, but knew I didnt have anything. So, I said: I am hungry too. I forgot to grab a snack from the store so where you go I will decide if I can have something. He chose Wendys.

At wendys we have always ordered their spicy chicken sandwich with frosties to drink (both larges). I was rather proud of myself that he ordered his usual and I ordered a small jr. hamburger (no cheese) with a diet coke. I am not a big fry person so I had about three of those and my hamburger and was full.

I had my usual afternoon snack (veggie bruschetta chips, yum!). But I didnt have any cottage cheese, so I ate an apple. Last night we went to the movies and after the movies he asked if I wanted to go to dinner, or grab a snack and go home. After deliberation he decided he wanted a snack and we could go home. He picked dairy queen.

Now, I didnt have my nifty eating out guide from JC so I was on my own. I got a small blizzard (Which I should have gotten something with less calories). But I thought, If I gain a little bit its okay cause I cheated today. But I&apos;ve had a hankering for ice cream!So, problem solved.

This morning, you can imagine my suprise when my scale read: 329.8!Which could once more be a fluke, but when I was prepared to have not lost any I still have!Amazing!So, needless to say, I dont commend my cheating, but am rather proud that I downsized my order from wendys and my order from dairy queen!(I usually order a large blizzard). Jenny is teaching me to curve my appetite, and that in a world where they offer to&quot;supersize&quot;everything, I dont have to:)
 
 ~* Hannah *~ 

 Joined the Jenny Family February 9th, 2012 

 


 JULY JIGGLES CHALLENGE: 

 
 
 Back to top 
 
 #2 Blessed4Life2 
 

(:Forum Optimistologist:)
 Members 10,832 posts 


 
Posted 03 March 2012 - 02:38 PM 
 Awesome! 

 Keep in mind it takes a couple of days for the scale to show a cheat sometimes.....but hopefully yours wont! 

 Hope ur having a GREAT weekend!!!! 
 ♥ *´¨) 
 ¸.•´¸.•*´¨)¸.•*¨)
(¸.•´(¸.•` MeLissa~ 

 

 &quot;reached my goal (-64 lbs) and now ROCKIN&apos;maintenance....WooHoooooo&quot; 

 
 Back to top 
 
 #3 vfish 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 187 posts 


 
Posted 03 March 2012 - 06:38 PM 
 It&apos;s so good that you are downsizing. Soon you may be able to avoid those frosty&apos;s and fried foods all together. It&apos;s SO much healthier to eat at home, it does take&quot;retraining of the brain&quot;Just choose the healthy items if you go out to a fast food restaurant. I know when I started Jenny, I had to get an entirely new approach. I used to take my kids to Wendy&apos;s, Taco Bell, wherever. Now I NEVER eat that stuff and my kids hardly ever do. At Wendy&apos;s I think a small Chili and a baked potato are good choices.
 Start Date: 11.29.11






 
 Back to top 
 
 #4 happineff 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 643 posts 


 
Posted 03 March 2012 - 09:18 PM 
 Great job Hannah!Those are some non-scale victories for sure--AND scale victories!!! Once you harness the knowledge that YOU have the power to control your food options and make healthy decisions, you WIN!!!And it&apos;s okay that you cheated a little (and I think it was pretty little), because we&apos;ve all been there. After all, we&apos;re not going to be on Jenny FOREVER, so someday we&apos;ll be face with these exact same situations; you&apos;re already practicing moderation and not feeling guilty about it afterward. It feels great, don&apos;t it?! 
 
 ~ happineff ~♥~ Hannah ~ 


 ‎&quot;Victory is won not in miles but in inches. Win a little now, hold your ground, and later win a little more.&quot; 

 

 ♥ ¸¸.• *&quot;♪♫ •*¨*•. ¸¸♥ ¸¸.•* ¨*•♫ ♪&quot;♪♫ •*¨*• .¸¸♥ ¸¸.•*¨ *•♫ ♪&quot;♪♫• *¨*• .¸¸♥ 

 



 THE FINAL STRETCH!!!!Can I reach GOAL by August 17th? 


 
 
 Back to top 
 
 #5 BlueEyedAngel 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 430 posts 


 
Posted 04 March 2012 - 12:48 PM 
 Melissa, thanks for the encouragement!And I might have gained one pound from the cheat two days ago but I think that I was down to 329.8 was a fluke in itself. This morning I weighed in at 331.8. I find though that I also weigh more after I sleep in...rather odd. 

vfish, I feel its a bit harder for me to eat at home because I live thirty miles away from where I work. We live out in the boonies!Hence the cheating, even though I feel good about it, wouldn&apos;t have been necessary if I had brought a snack with me. The blizzard on the other hand, I knew was going to be a cheat that was going to happen. Date night for my hubby and I only happens about once a month. So I know once a month I will have to choose my dinner and/or snack. But, something I can plan on:)

Hannah, it does feel great!I feel like I am in so much more control of myself already:) And I agree that it was pretty little cheat that I dont plan on making a habit out of:)
 
 ~* Hannah *~ 

 Joined the Jenny Family February 9th, 2012 

 


 JULY JIGGLES CHALLENGE: 

 
 
 Back to top 
 
 #6 Luana6805 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 50 posts 


 
Posted 04 March 2012 - 07:41 PM 
 I am so inspired by this, thank you for sharing your&quot;cheats!&quot;I was going to McDonalds 3-4 times a week (I may be underestimating) for TWO meals a day and my family still visits the drive-through regularly, but I&apos;ve been ordering a diet coke-- not even because I really want one, but just to feel like I get to order something, too. I&apos;m scared to actually order any food items, but what you did was perfect!In fact, I&apos;m pretty sure this exact kind of meal is in the Jenny guide for eating out, so way to go!And you used to get a bigger size blizzard before, so that&apos;s huge progress, too. Giving into a&quot;hankering for ice cream&quot;with a smaller amount than usual means you&apos;re in control. You should be so proud of yourself!Like I said, this really inspired me because I know the time will come when I need to try to make a good choice at a fast food restaurant, and it&apos;s great to hear what others have done under pressure.

&quot;in a world where they offer to&quot;supersize&quot;everything, I dont have to&quot;-- yeah!Now that&apos;s a quotable quote.
 
 Back to top 
 
 #7 I Called Jenny 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 5,336 posts 


 
Posted 05 March 2012 - 05:28 AM 
 All things considered, Hannah, you did pretty good in the&quot;cheating&quot;department. It could have been a WHOLE lot worse so you&apos;ve made progress and that&apos;s fabulous. You are already learning moderation, as Hannah, pointed out, so you took a giant step forward.

As for the scale, well that&apos;s always going to be a little tough to register what happens when you&apos;re naked on your scale and then hours later, clothed, on the JC scale.

But it&apos;s Monday and you&apos;re back on JC, so keep moving onward while your scale moves downward. 
 Phyllis 

 Height: 5&apos;2
SW - 177.6
Goal!- 132
Returning Weight - 143
CW - GOAL AGAIN!!! 



 

 Before JC with hubby and nephews in 2006/After JC (2nd time) in 2011 


 
 After JC 10/11 
 Back to top 
 
 #8 BlueEyedAngel 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 430 posts 


 
Posted 05 March 2012 - 04:41 PM 
 Luana - I am glad that I could inspire you so much!I thought about being really down on myself and being mad cause I ate fast food. But then I thought, I am in control. I can get a small hamburger instead of a spicy chicken sandwich (which runs about 600 calories before fries/drink). Same thing with the blizzard. I have a major sweet tooth and thought OH gosh...ice cream sounds so so so good. A small blizzard and the hankering was gone. I told myself if I didnt lose it was okay. I knew what I had eaten and knew the decisions I was making:)

Phyllis, I am an at home client, so my scale is my JC scale . But I weigh myself early in the morning before i jump in the shower for work. So clothes count for something Im sure, but I dont wear any. LoL. And it being Monday I am moving forward and keeping the cheating next to nil. I am close to my 20 lbs mark!Only around 2.2 pounds away and am not cheating!Want to hit the 20lbs down more than I want to cheat;)
 
 ~* Hannah *~ 

 Joined the Jenny Family February 9th, 2012 

 


 JULY JIGGLES CHALLENGE: 

 
 
 Back to top 
 
 #9 Jen.M 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 552 posts 


 
Posted 06 March 2012 - 07:31 AM 
 Awesome job, Hannah!Sounds like you&apos;re starting to learn to make the right choices that you&apos;ll have to stick with once you reach your goal weight. That&apos;s fantastic!I think that&apos;s really one of the keys - once you have to start making food choices on your own, and you&apos;re confident in making the RIGHT choices, you&apos;re on your way. Congrats! 
 
 
March, 2011......................August, 2011...................November, 2011.......................March, 2012
 

 

2007. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 2012

 
 
 Back to top 
 
 #10 BlueEyedAngel 
 

Advanced Member
 Members 430 posts 


 
Posted 09 March 2012 - 04:48 PM 
 Thanks for the support, Jen!

As an update to this kind of&quot;cheating&quot;I actually got my order in too late (missed my phone call with my JCC last week due to work issues). Hence, I am going to be going from today through next tuesday on my own choices, my own food; until my jc food gets here. Should be interesting!Very excited, and a tad nervous, to see how I do. 
 
 ~* Hannah *~ 

 Joined the Jenny Family February 9th, 2012 

 


 JULY JIGGLES CHALLENGE: 

 
 
 Back to top 
 Back to New Members · Next Unread Topic→ 
 
 
 
 
1 user(s) are reading this topic

0 members, 1 guests, 0 anonymous users
 Reply to quoted posts       Clear     
 Jenny Craig → Welcome → New Members 
 
 Mark Community Read 
 Forums Blogs Pages Mark all as read 
 Help 

 Community Forum Software by IP.Board
	</body>
</document>
