<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005539" url="http://www.lizmichael.com/hitman.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:05" support="5" score="0.0077436721100333054" bingtitle="Hit Man On Line - LizMichael.com - Political Activism for the ..." webtitle="Hit Man On Line">
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001059" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>He jogs back to the motel, stopping at the fast food restaurant ... the early part of the day checking out the places ... Then make your exit, usually through the front ...</description>
	<body>
		Home * Political Links * News * Soap Box * Cartridge
Box * Jury Box * Humor * Boycott * Biography * Contact Liz 
 Liz Michael for United States
Senate 

 

 HIT MAN ON-LINE
 A Technical Manual for
Independent Contractors 
Originally published by Paladin Press 
Written by Rex Feral 

 This book was downloaded
~2500 times between May 23, 1999 and March 31, 2000 

 In 1993, a triple murder was committed in
Montgomery County by a man who was alleged to have used this
book, Hit Man, as his guide. He was caught and convicted and
sentenced to death. Wanting to profit from their loved one&apos;s
murder, and realizing that the murderer himself was too poor to
be worth suing, the family of those killed by the hit man sued Paladin Press , the publisher of the book Hit Man, saying Paladin Press &quot;aided and abetted&quot;the murder. 

 May 21, 1999, Paladin Press settled the case, giving the families of those killed
by the hit man several million dollars, agreeing to destroy the
remaining 700 copies of the book in their possession, and
surrendering any rights they have to publish and reproduce the
work. While the families were successful in profiting from their
loved one&apos;s death, they have not been successful in stifling the
book. With the surrender of the publishing rights by Paladin Press , the book has entered the public domain, and is being
published on the Internet here at Overthrow.com in its entirety
this weekend, May 22-23, 1999. 

 The book was initially published in 1983.
13,000 copies of the book are now in existence. There has only
ever been one case where the book was associated with a crime, in
that case the criminal had recently finished a lengthy prison
sentence and had a history of prior violent crime. It is our
opinion this book has never incited a murder, that the settlement
of the Paladin Press case was wrong
and forced by the insurance company, and that this book, and no
book, should be banned. We invite the public to judge for
themselves. 

 That said, here is Hit Man ... 

 WARNING 

IT IS AGAINST THE LAW TO manufacture a silencer without an
appropriate license from the federal government. There are state
and local laws prohibiting the possession of weapons and their
accessories in many areas. Severe penalties are prescribed for
violations of these laws. Neither the author nor the publisher
assumes responsibility for the use or misuse of information
contained in this book. For informational purposes only! 
 
 CONTENTS 

 Preface :
ix

 Prologue :
1

 Chapter
One 
THE BEGINNING
Mental and Physical Preparations: 9

 Chapter
Two 
EQUIPMENT
Selection and Purpose: 13

 Chapter
Three 
THE DISPOSABLE SILENCER
A Poor Man&apos;s Access To A Rich Man&apos;s Toy: 21

 Chapter
Four 
MORE THAN ONE WAY TO KILL A RABBIT
The Direct Hit Is Not Your Only Alternative: 53

 Chapter
Five 
HOMEWORK AND SURVEILLANCE
Mapping a Plan And Checking It For Accuracy: 71

 Chapter
Six 
OPPORTUNITY KNOCKS
Finding Employment, What To Charge, Who To Avoid: 87

 Chapter
Seven 
GETTING THE JOB DONE RIGHT
Why The Described Hit Went Down The Way It Did: 95

 Chapter
Eight 
DANGER! EGO, WOMEN AND PARTNERS
Controlling Your Situation: 111

 Chapter
Nine 
LEGALLY ILLEGAL
Enjoying the Fruits: 121
 
 PREFACE 

A WOMAN RECENTLY ASKED HOW I could, in good conscience, write
an instruction book on murder.

&quot;How can you live with yourself if someone uses what you
write to go out and take a human life?&quot;she whined.

I am afraid she was quite offended by my answer.

It is my opinion that the professional hit man fills a need in
society and is, at times, the only alternative for&quot;personal&quot;justice. Moreover, if my advice and the
proven methods in this book are followed, certainly no one will
ever know.

Some people would argue that in taking the life of another
after premeditation, you act as God -- judging and issuing a
death sentence. But it is the employer, the man who pays for the
service, whatever his reason might be, who acts as judge. The hit
man is merely the executioner, an enforcer who carries out the
sentence.

There are many, many instances when atrocities are committed
that the law cannot or will not pursue. and other times when the
law does its part but the American legal system is so poor that
real justice is not served. In those cases, as in cases of
personal revenge and retribution, a man must step outside the law
and take matters into his own hands.

Since most men are capable of carrying out their threats and
wishes only in their heads, it becomes necessary for a man of
action to step in and do what is required: a special man for whom
life holds no real meaning and death holds no fear ... A man who
faces death as a challenge and feels the victory every time he
walks away the winner.

Some men could not kill under any circumstances. Other could
kill only in self-defense or to protect what they hold dear. One
man learns to kill in times of war and spends the rest of his lie
trying to forget the horror, while his brother may consider all
his wartime efforts a justifiable part of his past having no
effect on his present.

How many times have you shared a few beers with a group of
macho buddies who eventually turned the subject of conversation
form women and sports to that of guns, ammunition, wars, and the
killing?

It seems that almost every man harbors a fantasy of living the
life of Mack Bolan or some other fictional hero who kills for fun
and profit. They dream of living by their reflexes, of doing
whatever is necessary without regard to moral or legal
restrictions. But few have the courage or knowledge to make that
dream a reality.

When the bragging and boasting starts, I just sit back and
smile as one after the other talks of what he would do, and how
he would be., if it weren&apos;t for family obligations, mortgages and
corporate jobs.

You might be like my friends -- interested but unsure,
standing on the sidelines afraid to play the game because you
don&apos;t know the rules. Within the pages of this book you will
learn one of the most successful methods of operation used by an
independent contractor. You will follow the procedures of a man
who works alone, without backing of organized crime or on a
personal vendetta. Step by step you will be taken from research
to equipment selection to job preparation to successful job
completion. You will learn where to find employment, how much to
charge, and what you can, and cannot, do with the money you earn.

But deny your urge to skip about, looking for the&quot;good&quot;parts. Start where any amateur who is serious
about turning profession will start -- at the beginning.
 
 PROLOGUE 

HE SLEEPS WHILE THE PLANE IS in flight, having learned long
ago that few people will try to make conversation with a sleeping
man. At 1:35 PM the stewardess awakens him. They are about to
land.

He enters the terminal and casually strolls past the embracing
couples and reunited families, heading directly for the men&apos;s
room. He is just another of the hundreds of businessmen who
arrive at and depart from a major city airport on any given day.

Safe inside the toilet stall, he locks the doors and slips out
of the business suit he chose to wear on the trip. From his
duffel bag he pulls faded jeans, sweatshirt and tennis shoes.
Hurriedly, he pulls on the clothing. Then, balancing a small
mirror on the back of the toilet, he slips a stocking cap over
his hair to flatten and hide it before pulling on a shoulder
length wig. His neatly folded suit, shirt and tie fir snugly on
top. From a zippered side pocket he takes a pair of tinted,
wire-rimmed glasses and a nondescript hat. In less than ten
minutes, he leaves the men&apos;s room a different man.

At the row of car rental booths in the airport lobby, a tall
hippie in a sweatshirt waits in line to rent a car. He does not
seem to be inconvenienced by the long lines that are so
irritating to the other customers. When the girl behind the
counter finally gets around to him, he responds affirmatively to
her offer to help.

&quot;Yeah, I wanna rent a small car for a few days.&quot;

She take sin his appearance. She has seen his type many times
before and immediately interprets his use of the word small to
mean cheap. She suggests an economy car that is terrific on gas
and comes with unlimited mileage.

He explains that he intends to pay cash for the use of the
car. She tells him that he may do so when he brings the car back,
but a valid driver&apos;s license and major credit card are required
identification for security purposes. From an ordinary looking
wallet, he pulls the necessary identification: a valid North
Carolina driver&apos;s license and a major credit card, both in the
name of Alfred Johnson.

With key in hand, he leaves the car rental booth and goes to
claim his baggage. Then he wanders to the airport news stand to
purchase a city map and some reading materials.

Seated in the lobby, he checks the map for an address he
memorized weeks earlier. Folding the map so he can follow it
while driving, he exits to pick up his waiting car.

Afternoon traffic is moderately heavy on the interstate.
Exits, side streets and intersections are unfamiliar. He drives
carefully and obeys all traffic rules. He does not want to become
involved in any accidents or pick up any traffic tickets.

Finally, he arrives in the section of town where he will find
the memorized address. he drives slowly down the street until he
has located the apartment complex, then drives on past so his
interest will not be observed.

He continues to scout the neighborhood, checking streets and
consulting the city map he carries for possible escape routes. He
notes that the neighborhood is upper middle class; neatly kept
lawns and sidewalks, with a population consisting of mostly
singles and young families.

Three blocks west of the apartment complex there is a park
which has a small pond. One block east he finds a large shopping
center which has a movie theater and an adult book store that is
open all night.

About a mile away, at the point where he exited the interstate
highway, there are several chain motels and fast food
restaurants. he heads back in that direction and pulls into a
motel parking lot. He jots down the California license tag number
of a car parked near the restaurant entrance. It is 4:15 PM.

The motel clerk is disinterested and mechanical in registering
him. He fills out the required form in the name of Sam Wilcox,
gives a fictitious address in Los Angeles and uses the California
tag number from the car parked at the restaurant. The clerk does
not ask for further identification.

&quot;I&apos;m a late sleeper. I&apos;d like a room on the back side --
away from the pool, if you have it,&quot;he requests.

&quot;Will that be cash or charge?&quot;the clerk asks
without looking up.

He lays down enough small bills on the counter to cover two
days lodging,&quot;Cash,&quot;he answers.

He drives the car around back, locates his room and takes in
his baggage. By 4:45 he is seated on the bed studying the
contents of a large manila envelope taken from his locked
suitcase. Using the information from the envelope and the
telephone directory, he begins to chart routes on the city map.
Afterwards, he carefully studies an assortment of photographs
taken from the envelope. Satisfied, he returns everything to the
envelope and locks it away in the suitcase again.

Wearing a jogging outfit and still in his hippie disguise, he
drives to the shopping center and locks his car. On foot, he
begins a slow jog through the neighborhood. He circles the block
and carefully scrutinizes the area before cutting into the
apartment complex parking lot. The sun is just beginning to set.

The apartments are all identical. Patios on the rear are
enclosed with privacy walls. On the front, each apartment is
separated from the other by an ornamental cedar fence. Two
parking spaces are reserved at the front of each apartment for
the residents&apos; use. Guest parking is clearly marked in the center
of the parking lot, surrounding a small island landscaped with a
few scrawny trees and thick bushes.

He jogs over to the guest parking island and sits down on the
curb. Removing his shoes and socks, he begins to rub his tired
feet. It is 6:47. If his information is correct, the mark should
be arriving home from work any time now.

At 6:53 a green Mustang pulls into the parking space in front
of the apartment he has under surveillance. The car matches the
description of the vehicle belonging to the mark. A heavyset man
emerges slowly from the small car. He is puffing on a large
cigar. Judging by his physical characteristics and the cigar,
this man appears to be the mark. He glances up uninterested, as a
jogger trots out of the parking lot.

He jogs back to the motel, stopping at the fast food
restaurant for dinner. The clerk shortchanges him by five dollars
and the hamburger he orders is not prepared to his liking but he
does not complain. without drawing any attention, he heads back
to his motel where he reads and watches television until 11:00.

It is after 11:30 when he swings his car into the apartment
complex parking lot. The mark&apos;s lights are on and his car is
still parked in its allotted space. The mark is said to spend
most of his free time alone at home, staying up late watching
television and sleeping in until an hour or so before his
scheduled time to report for work at a used car lot; it appears
that this information is correct.

He circles the guest parking island and drives back to the
motel.

Early the next morning he is waiting in his parked car with a
pair of binoculars and a newspaper when the mark leaves the
apartment. In the bright morning sunlight he clearly makes
positive identification. This is his man!

Using his premarked map, he spends the early part of the day
checking out the places the mark is known to frequent. Around
noon, he drives to the main post office to pick up a parcel he
mailed to himself the day before. as he drives, he contemplates
the various places he has checked out. Because of the layout of
the apartment complex in relation to the private patios and
sectioned courtyards, he decides that the best place to make the
hit is in the mark&apos;s own home.

Back at the motel, he opens the heavily taped parcel which was
addressed to Mark Donaldson. There had been no problem in picking
up the package, stamped&quot;Fragile -- Precision Machined
Parts.&quot;Today the postal clerk had not even asked for
identification.

Inside the first box is a second box. And inside the second
box is a special set of clothing, several pairs of rubber gloves,
a clean pair of tennis shoes, a new disguise, ammunition, a
disassembled weapon and a disposable silencer.

Lovingly he begins to assemble his weapon. With gloved hands,
he wipes every part, inside and out, for fingerprints. As he
loads the clip, he wipes down each of the bullets. he is a man
with a job to do. He has the tools, he has done his homework, he
knows he has the right target and he has determined how he will
accomplish the job.

After putting the tools away, he leaves the motel to fill the
gas tank on the car. While he is out, he steals and out-of-state
tag from a parked automobile and replaces the rental tag on his
car with a stolen tag.

Back in his room, he dials the airport and gets flight
information. Space is available on a flight departing at 11:55
PM.

At 7:00 PM the alarm sounds, waking him from a four hour nap.
It is time to get ready for work.

He dresses in the clothing that came in his parcel. He puts on
the clean tennis shoes and a new disguise. He puts the hippie
disguise, clothing and shows into the duffel bag, along with the
tools he will be using. When he is all dressed and packed to go,
he has a very few important details to complete.

First, he removes the manila envelope from the suitcase and
goes over to the bathroom to burn all the items it contains over
the toilet. One by one, he burns the information sheets,
photographs, maps and other physical evidence that may prove
conspiracy to commit a crime and flushes away the incriminating
remains.

He pulls out a fresh pair of rubber gloves and begins tot wipe
down the room for fingerprints. He knows the room will probably
be rented against by tomorrow, but he takes the precaution
anyway. he puts all the trash, newspapers and magazines
accumulated during his stay into a plastic garbage bag, along
with the room&apos;s telephone directory and places it beside his
luggage. He will dispose of these items on the way to the
jobsite. Still wearing the rubber gloves, he loads his luggage
and equipment into the car, locking it in the trunk, and heads
for the mark&apos;s neighborhood. He will not be returning to the
motel again.

At the shopping center one block from where the mark lives, he
parks the car in the crowded theatre parking lot and gets out to
continue on foot.

No one is out and about as he walks into the apartment complex
parking lot. Protected by the cedar privacy fence, he peeks
through a crack in the drapes and sees the mark puffing on a
cigar while he watches TV from a recliner chair. The volume is so
loud that he can hear the program plainly from his position
outside.

He goes to the front door where he quietly and efficiently
picks the lock. The mark is startled by the intrusion of his
entry but is unable to respond quickly enough. he is helpless
against the professional.

The muffled sound of three shots fired in rapid succession
goes undetected by the neighborhood. The professional has neatly
carried out his assignment. Quickly but carefully, he checks the
body to make sure there is no pule and drags the body to a place
in the apartment where it will not be easily detected. At the
scene of the shooting, he drops a newspaper over the blood that
has seeped into the carpet. He pockets the three empty cartridges
that were ejected from the gun. Then, after a quick check of the
apartment to make sure he leaves behind no incriminating
evidence, he exits, locking the front door behind him.

Resisting the urge to run, he strolls nonchalantly back to the
theater parking lot and his waiting car. Safe inside, he
immediately runs a rat-tail file down the barrel of the gun to
change the ballistic markings. Then he changes back into his
hippie clothing and disguise, unobserved while the other car
owners are inside viewing the movie.

he checks the work clothes carefully for bloodstains. Finding
none, he drops them into the charity collection box at the
shopping center entrance, keeping the shoes he wore for disposal
later.

He drives cautiously and carefully to another shopping center
several blocks away. He feels no panic. It will be days before
the crime is detected, days before anyone investigates the mark&apos;s
failure to report for work or answer his door. In the crowded
parking lot, he disassembles the weapon and removes the stolen
tag. Now his only remaining task is to dispose of the weapon.

He gets back onto the interstate highway and heads out of
town. Traffic becomes sparse as the city is left behind; now he
begins to toss out the small gun parts at irregular intervals,
aiming for water filled and overgrown drainage ditches. He also
tosses out the tennis shoes.

At a rest area, he walks through the woods and buries the
barrel of the gun. He crushes the plastic silencer and disposes
of the bits and pieces as he drives back to town.

Just before he reaches the airport, he pulls over to the side
of the road and wipes the car for fingerprints. He removes and
discards the stolen tag, replacing it with the rental tag. He
disposes of the rubber work gloves and replaces them with a pair
of leather driving gloves. Then he returns the&quot;clean&quot;rental car to the agency and heads directly for the airport men&apos;s
room.

A short time later, a businessman emerges from the men&apos;s room
and approaches the ticket counter for information. His flight
leaves in forty five minutes.

he checks his baggage, a suitcase and small duffel bag, and
goes to the coffee shop to wait for the flight to be called.

On the plane he dozes, having learned long ago that few people
will try to make conversation with a sleeping man. Too all
appearances, he is just another businessman suffering from an
exhausting schedule; no one interrupts his rest.
 
 1. THE BEGINNING 

AS A FIRST CLASS MECHANIC, you will become and expert at your
profession. Becoming an expert entails research -- reading,
observing, and asking questions -- as well as development of a
wide range of physical abilities and weapons expertise.

The preparations outlined in this chapter should be considered
essential prior to any acceptance of actual employment. Your keen
mental and physical fitness will serve as your edge between life
and death.

 PERIODICIALS 

Read and reread pertinent articles relating to weapons and
techniques that interest you in magazines such as Soldier of
Fortune, New Breed and Gung-Ho. Stay abreast of new trends and
developments as well as new gadgets and inventions as they become
available. As well as the valuable articles, study advertisements
and classified sections for a wealth of information and sources
for supplies and books.

Check our military newsletters like Military Exchange. Your
local library can inform you of what is available in this
category.

 BOOKS 

Books on subjects related to the professional hit man are hard
to find. But there are a few publishers out there who have the
backbone to provide those of us who take life seriously with the
necessary educational materials. Paladin Press advertises in
almost every issue of Soldier of Fortune and other publishers
offer relevant reading material, available by mail order. Check
advertisements and classified sections.

And let&apos;s not forget reading for entertainment. With the right
attitude and an open mind, almost any good mystery or murder
story can provide some ingenious new methods of terrorizing,
victimizing, or exterminating. Sometimes a new poison will be
introduced, or perhaps a new method for induction. Sometimes the
warped imagination of a fiction writer will point out an obvious
but somehow never before realized method of pacification or body
disposal. So don&apos;t bypass these fictional characters. Chuckle
through the trenchcoats and warped personalities but test out any
new theories you come across.

 DAILY PUBLICATIONS 

A subscription to your local newspaper may be the wisest
investment, with the highest return, that you will ever make.
Each morning as you sip your coffee and scan the local section,
you will be met with a variety of up-to-date employment
opportunities. So study your local paper carefully to see who in
your area might be your next employer ... or victim.

 Headlines -- Follow closely any news stories about
people who have been apprehended for contract hits. These stories
sell papers, and readers thrive on the sensationalism they
create. Study details made available for law enforcement
techniques, mistakes that led to the arrest, and methods the law
used to obtain incriminating information. Learn from the other
man&apos;s mistakes. And if he is lucky enough to be acquitted, make a
note of the attorney&apos;s name in case you ever find yourself in the
position of needing a good one.

 Drug Arrests -- If the reported suspect posts a heavy
bond, he is probably dealing in a big way. As soon as he gets
back on the streets, chances are he will be dealing again to
raise money for his defense. His name and address are right there
in the paper. Is he worth a drug rip-off, or would it be more
profitable to contact him discreetly about eliminating that
certain witness.

 Political Corruption -- Keep up with gossip. All
politicians are expected to be corrupt, but who among them is
desperate or despicable enough to be willing to pay to eliminate
the competition? Tried and true methods are accidental death,
assassination, or worse yet, political death brought on by
scandal.

 Divorce -- Follow closely news or rumors of
particularly nasty divorce proceedings involving any wealthy or
socially prominent couple. Chances are, one could use your
discreet professional services. Or perhaps some not so wealthy
acquaintance who prefers not to become entangled in messy divorce
proceedings may find it a proper time to collect on that old life
insurance policy.

 Adjustments -- Thefts, cases reported where the law did
not render justice, bogus operations that swindle ordinary people
out of their hard earned money -- all these are potential
opportunities for employment. Work for a flat rate or for a
percentage of recovery, plus expenses.

 Classified Sections -- You can place an ad under the
guise of collector and solicit any particular weapons you might
want. Or scan these ads when you are in the market for new toys
and pick them up from private owners to avoid registering your
weapons.

Classified sections also announce gun shows, which are an
ideal source for all types of equipment at competitive prices.

 REFERENCE MATERIALS 

 Local City Directory -- If at all possible, get one of
these to keep at home. Otherwise, they are available in the
reference of information section of the public library.

If you have partial information on a mark, you can usually
gather the rest without leaving the comfort of your easy chair..
These directories are broken down into three categories:

Alphabetical by Name: Lists name, wife&apos;s name, occupation and
employers, street address, telephone number and other living in
the home.

Street Address: Lists alphabetically by street and then
numerically by house number. If you know the mark&apos;s address you
can also know who lives next door, the type of neighborhood,
vacant lots, business and so on, all according to the information
that was available when the directory was compiled.

Phone Numbers: If all you have is a phone number, look it up
in the numerical listing. Then go to the Alphabetical listing and
Address sections to gather the rest of the information.

 Auto Tag Department, County Courthouse -- Often the
books are left out for public use. Look up the mark by last name
or tag number for address.

 Telephone Directories -- For obvious reasons, it will
sometimes be to your advantage to know the mark&apos;s telephone
number.

But don&apos;t overlook the wealth of supply sources available in
the Yellow Pages and become familiar with suppliers and readily
available merchandise. If you live in a small town, get
directories for any large cities in a 200-mile radius. Their
Yellow Pages will be extremely valuable if you don&apos;t want to
obtain supplies locally.

 Maps -- A local city map is a must for planning routes
if you are not familiar with the road systems. And of course a
city map for any out-of-town job is in order.

A large atlas showing the national road system network is
handy not only for planning travel, but also for finding nearby
large cities and alternative routs to the job.

Just remember that once you use a map, if you have marked it
in any way, it should be destroyed immediately.

 Travel Arrangements -- Start inquiring now about the
various modes of transportation available for out of town jobs.
Find out necessary identifications, advance scheduling
requirements, and time factors involved. File this information
away for future use.

Stop by and ask what your local travel agent can do for you.
You will be surprised at the variety of services they offer. When
you are ready, call and make the necessary arrangements by
telephone, using a fictitious name. They do all the work in
making the arrangements to your specifications, and the airline
pays their fee.

 Shipping and Routing -- You can take a plane under an
assumed identity and arrive at your destination in a matter of a
few short hours. But how will you get your weapons to the
jobsite? better start now checking into alternative methods for
shipping your tools separately.

The US Postal Service offers Express Mail to most major
cities, and the main post office is generally located very near
the airport. By disassembling your weapons and double packing as
a precautionary measure, you can send your tools to yourself
under an assumed name (post office to post office) and have them
waiting for pick up the next morning. Airport mail is not
x-rayed.

If time is not a factor, check into bus line, common carrier
or UPS rates and delivery schedules.

 Locating the mark -- An obliging postal clerk will
inform you of the several ways of tracking down the last known
address of anyone you choose to locate as a function of the
Freedom of Information Act.

One way is to send one dollar and a written request addressed
to the postmaster of the mark&apos;s last known location. A Freedom of
Information Act form will be returned to you within a matter of
days giving the Postal Service&apos;s most recent update.

Or, you can address an empty envelope to the mark&apos;s last known
address with your return address in the upper left hand corner.
Under your address should appear this notation in bold letters:

DO NOT FORWARD
ADDRESS CORRECTION REQUESTED

Within a few days your envelope will be returned with the
updated information. The fee is twenty five cents.

 LAW 

The Law Enforcement Handbook for your state should be
available through any college bookstore where law enforcement
classes are taught. If not, STEAL ONE! If such courses are
available in your area, you may want to audit a few.

How can you successfully evade the law if you have no
knowledge of how it operates? By all means, learn everything you
can about the law and how it works and how it applies to you.
Learn what constitutes a good arrest and what abuses or mistakes
can make an otherwise good arrest null and void.

I hope you will never have to fall back on the information and
knowledge you acquire, but it will be worth its weight in gold if
you ever have to rely on it. And you will have the added
advantage of using you knowledge of how your opponents think and
operate as you plan successful jobs.

 MISCELLANEOUS 

Check every source available to you for potential information.
Even those cheap tabloid newspapers sold at the grocery store
counter have classifieds that offer fake ID&apos;s, interesting
gadgets, nontraceable mailing addresses, and so on.

Your public library more than likely has the local newspaper
on microfilm, and the information section has employees eager to
help you find books and materials on the subjects you are
researching.

Chambers of commerce will mail out information and maps of
their cities upon request.

And bookstores and libraries have reference books that show
all the books still in print and available on any given subject.

Keep an open mind, and sources of information will open up to
you, sometimes in the least likely places and when you least
expect it!

 FITNESS 

Your body should be as fit as your mind. You should be capable
of running, jumping, climbing, swimming, pushing, pulling or
meeting the demands of any other physical requirement encountered
in your job. This means not only careful attention to exercise
and diet, but moderation if you are going to partake of tobacco
products and alcohol, and complete abstinence from any
involvement with drugs.

A man who smokes two packs of cigarettes a day will certainly
not be capable of running long and hard for any length of time.
And his endurance in hand to hand combat situations will be
severely limited. By the same token, a man who overindulges in
alcohol may be taking his own life in his hands. The use of
cigarettes and alcohol in moderation is acceptable, although
undesirable, but use of any kinds of drugs is suicide.

Drugs dull the senses and the reflexes, yet the user feels
sharp and alert. His confidence in his abilities swells out of
proportion. His ego takes over. He sees himself as
indestructible, incomparable. That image of himself may be the
last thing he ever sees.

I, as a professional, never use drugs, although I will steal
them for financial gain, or to use as bait or even as an
induction agent for some chemical that I know will do an
effective job. I don&apos;t need an unreal&quot;high&quot;that can
mar my judgement. There is no margin for error in this business.
A single mistake can cost you your life, either literally or by
providing the evidence to take away your freedom. Either way you
are just as dead. A professional needs a clear head and
unhampered reflexes to be able to react properly in any
situation. This is equally true whether he is performing the job
itself or conducting prejob research. If you have to depend on an
artificial sense of courage in order to carry out your
assignment, then this job is not for you.

 COMBAT TRAINING 

If you are afraid of taking a punch, again, this job is not
right for you. No matter how careful you are, no matter how
thorough your research, at some time you will probably have to
prove or defend yourself physically. Any skills you can acquire
are to your advantage.

You can get expert training in hand to hand combat is you can
find someone qualified to teach you. Preferably, this will be
someone with Special Forces training or the equivalent.

You will need to know kill techniques as well as survival
self-defense, and you won&apos;t learn these skills at the corner
karate school that includes women and children in its classes.
Sport karate can get you killed in the street.

You should become so familiar with skills like breaking holds,
throws, effective punches to vital areas and crippling moves that
will come when needed as a reflex action. You should be aware of
the best barroom fighting techniques. You should be able to fight
two men at the same time. You should know the best way to disarm
an opponent. And more.

But such skills require real practice with a sparring partner
who cant take, as well as give, a good punch. In order to teach
these methods in the proper way, your instructor will have to
take his fighting as seriously as you do.

Veterans with wartime experience and the ability to kill are
first choice instructors. Their contact with real life and death
situations has made them a bit unconventional. Some never again
conform to the rules of society, and quite a few rigorously keep
in top physical shape while stockpiling M-60s and hand grenades
under the bed in preparation for the next war.

The same man who can train you in the very best methods of
self-defense and combat fighting might also be one of your best
sources for accessory merchandise. his contact with other
veterans will give you access to a chain able to locate almost
any weapon you might request.

The veteran with guerilla warfare training will be a walking
textbook on silent movement, torture, revenge, ammunitions,
escape, silent weapons, and a host of ways to kill. And if, by
chance, you accept a contract where a partner is in order, he may
the first man you&apos;d choose to cover your back.

The time needed to acquire the skills of this degree will
vary, depending on your physical condition at the time you begin
training, your aptitude for following directions and your
eagerness to learn. I have seen an eager student, one who is
willing to put in the hard hours of practice and full contact
sparing sessions, progress very rapidly to the point of
capability in less than six months.

 MERCENARY SCHOOLS 

Once your fighting ability has been established, you may want
to test your news skills at one of the mercenary of survival
school advertised in the various military magazines. Look for a
school that can teach you more than you already know, and be
prepared for one hell of a workout while you build your endurance
and skills. An added benefit in attending one of these schools is
that the people you meet there, like you, take the game of life
seriously. Be prepared to meet people who have the same interests
in weapons, explosives and effective kill techniques as you do.
Some of them may prove to be very good resources or even future
employers.

 AWARENESS TRAINING 

It is estimated that if ten people witnessed the same crime
and then were separated before they could compare what had taken
place, ten different descriptions would be given. People rarely
pay attention to what is going on around them unless, or until,
it becomes of importance to them personally. This book stresses
the importance of using disguise and false identification to foil
positive identification. But just as important to your success
are your own observation skills.

Start now developing and exercising your observation powers.
Make a habit of studying your surroundings. listen when others
talk. A man can reveal a great deal about himself through his
conversation and opinions. make a note of features or habits that
make one man different from another. Think of the people you know
intimately. Can you tell whether they are right or left handed?
What color are their eyes?

Sharpen your observation skills.

 FIRST CLASS MECHANIC REQUIREMENTS 

 Expert marksmanship Thorough knowledge and respect for all weapons Knowledge through reading, expert advice and
 experimentation on accessories such as explosives, poison
 and diversions Knowledge and ability of hand to hand combat Top mental and physical condition Common sense 
 
 EQUIPMENT 

A HIT MAN WITHOUT A GUN is like a carpenter without a hammer.
Not very effective. What kinds of gun does he use and where does
he obtain them? Unless he has a proper false identification, he
certainly cannot make his purchase from the local gun shop and
fill out the federal registration forms linking the weapon to
himself.

What other basic equipment will the beginner need as essential
tools of the trade. What equipment should be added to his
inventory later?

 BASIC EQUIPMENT CHECKLIST 

 WEAPONS 
 AR-7 Rifle (or any breakdown type) 3-6 Powered Scope Disposable Rifle Silencer Two Extra 15 or 30 Shot Rifle Clips 22 Ruger Mark I or Mark II Pistol (or any fixed
 barrel type) Disposable Pistol Silencer Shoulder Holster Extra Pistol Clip 
 AMMUNITIONS 
 Hollow Point Bullets Liquid Poison Wax 
 ACCESSORIES 
 Double Edged Knife With Six-Inch Blade (Like the
 Gerber Mark II) Disposable Rubber or Surgical Gloves (Flesh Tone
 Preferred) Handcuffs Ski Mask or Stocking Mask Duffle Bag with Lock 
 

 THE WEAPONS 

The AR-7 Rifle is recommended because it is both inexpensive
and accurate. The barrel breaks down for storage inside the stick
with the clip. It is lightweight and easy to carry or conceal
when disassembled.

The rifle has a ridge on top that will easily accept a scope,
even though it is not cut for one. Put the scope in place,
tighten it down, then sight it in. After sighting it in, scratch
a mark behind each scope clamp to allow remounting of the scope
without resighting each time.

A three to six powered scope is recommended to insure accuracy
at up to sixty-five yards. When braced, right to fifteen shots
should cover a four inch pattern area with no difficulty.

Get two extra fifteen or thirty shot clips from your local gun
dealer or order through one of the gun magazines. But never load
these clips to full capacity, as they tend to jam when fully
loaded. When loading the clip before job assignment, be sure to
wipe each bullet to remove fingerprints, or spray with WD-40 or
some other oil.

The AR=7 has a serial number stamped on the case, just above
the clip port. This number should be completely drilled out. The
hole left will be unsightly but will not interfere with the
working mechanism of the gun or the clip feed. The serial number
can remain on the gun until you prepare it for use on the job.
After the job assignment is completed, you will be disposing of
the gun; therefore you do not want any serial number available
if, perhaps, some of the discarded gun parts are discovered.

If the serial number is on the barrel of the gun, grinding
deeply enough to remove it may weaken the barrel to the point
that the gun could explode in your face when fired. To make these
numbers untraceable, use a hammer and chisel or a numbering set
purchased from the hardware store to stamp them out or make them
illegible. make sure your blows go as deep as or a little deeper
than the existing numbers. Then grind the serial number off
slightly. This method will keep the true serial number from being
raised in any acid tests if the part is found.

The recommended handgun is the fixed barrel Ruger Mark I or
Mark II, again because it is inexpensive and reliable. This gun
has a ten shot clip that seldom jams if kept clean. The gun can
be easily broken down in the field, which helps when disposing of
it after use.

Extra clips are a must for both the rifle and pistol and
should be carried as a precautionary measure. Hollow-point
bullets are recommended because they deform on impact, making
them nontraceable. As an added precaution, you can fill the
hollows with liquid poison to insure the success of your
operation.

Using a handheld one eighth inch drill, enlarge the hollow
point openings. Fill the hollows with the liquid poison of your
choice, then seal with a drop of melted wax.

TO test your guns and ammunition, set up a sheet of quarter
inch plywood at distances of two to seven years maximum for your
pistol, and twenty to sixty yards maximum for your rifle. Check
for penetration of bullets at each range. Quarter inch plywood is
only a little stronger than the human skull. Find the maximum
range for both your rifle and your pistol. Also, test your
weapons under various weather conditions and determine how wind,
rain and snow affect your range and accuracy.

Close kills are by far preferred to shots fired over a long
distance. You will need to know beyond any doubt that the desired
result has been achieved.

When using a small caliber weapon like the 22, it is best to
shoot from a distance of three to six feet. You will not want to
be at point blank range to avoid having the victim&apos;s blood
splatter you or your clothing. At least three shots should be
fired to ensure quick and sure death.

You can judge when death has occurred by observing the wound.
When blood ceases to flow, the heart has stopped working. Check
for pulse at both the wrist and throat as an added precaution.

If you must do your shooting from a distance, use a rifle with
a good scope and silencer and aim for the head -- preferably the
eye sockets if you are a sharpshooter. Many people have been shot
repeatedly, even in the head, and survived to tell about it.
Close kills enable you to determine right away if you have
successfully fulfilled your part of the contract; distance shots
may mean waiting around to read the morning papers.

In either case, as soon as possible, run a rat-tail file or
wire cleaning brush down the ore of the gun to change the
ballistic markings. Do this even though you intend to discard the
crime weapon, And make sure you carry away and discard all shells
that were ejected as the shots were fired.

If, for some reason, you just can&apos;t bear to part with your
weapons, there are five parts that will require immediate
alteration, and this alteration can only be made once in the life
of the gun:

Using a rat tailfile, alter the gun barrel, the shell chamber,
the loading ramp, the firing pin and the ejector pin.

Each one of these items leaves its own definite mark and
impression on the shell casing which, if any shells happened to
be left behind, can be matched up to the gun under a microscope
in the police laboratory.

When using the file, make sure that you scrape the part on
each listed item where it makes contact with the shell.

Personally, I feel that any weapon used to commit a crime is
disposable. If you consider the value of a gun to be higher than
that of your personal freedom, you&apos;d better leave that gun at
home.

A subject of primary importance is where to purchase the
weapons you use on job assignments. As suggested in Chapter 1,
you can often pick up throwaways from people who advertise in the
classified section of the newspaper. Just be sure that any weapon
you use on a job cannot be traced back to you by the person you
purchase it from. Gun shows offer a wide variety of tools and
weapons useful in this line of work. Usually no registration is
required. At most, they may ask to see your driver&apos;s license. And
with so many dealers present vying for your business, prices may
be competitive. Flea Markets, private gun collectors, veterans
who hoard and stash a variety of interesting toys, and bargain
hunter magazines are other possible sources.

If you must obtain a weapon through legal channels (signing
registration and the like), it might be wise to pay some beggar
or wino ten or twenty dollars to present his driver&apos;s license and
do the signing before you disappear with the gun.

 AN IMPORTANT WORD ABOUT REVOLVERS 

Although revolvers are often depicted as being a favorite tool
among hit men, they are not recommended by this pro. Revolvers
cannot be effectively silenced. The open cylinder allows gases to
escape, thus making some noise. When fired, gas is forced around
the cylinder in a 360 degree circle, thereby throwing powder all
over the person who fired the gun.

An automatic, on the other hand, is tightly sealed so that
when it is fired almost all the powder residue is forced into the
silencer, where it is trapped. This prevents the powder from
escaping and covering the person who fired the shot. Some residue
will come out from the automatic&apos;s ejection port, but only a very
small amount. If a shell catcher is used, the powder residue will
become trapped inside the catch bag.

Remember that a silencer will affect the range and accuracy of
your gun. Once the silencer is in place you will have to resight
to maintain accuracy.

 BASIC ACCESSORIES 

A duffel bag or some other method of inconspicuously
transporting your tools to the jobsite will be needed.
Preferably, it will have a lock. It should be large enough to
hold your pistol, disassembled rifle and several small accessory
items. These items should be kept assembled in the bad in a safe
hiding place, wiped clean of fingerprints and ready for use.

Inside the bag should be several (at least dour or five pairs)
of flesh-tone, tight-fitting surgical gloves. If these are not
available, rubber gloves can be purchased at a reasonable price
in the prescription department of most drug stores in boxes of
100. You will wear the gloves when you assemble and disassemble
your weapons as well as on the actual job. Because the metal gun
parts cause the rubber to wear so quickly, it is a good practice
to change and dispose of worn gloves several times during each
operation. A small tear in the thin, worn rubber can lead to a
hole, leaving behind a partial, identifiable fingerprint at the
most inopportune time. Never dispose of the gloves worn on an
assignment in the vicinity of the job. Although your fingerprints
may have been covered while you worked, they are clearly and
distinctly obtainable by turning the found gloves inside out. I
know a fellow or two who learned this lesson the hard way.

LEather gloves are not to be considered as a job tool. The
leather has the same, individual, distinct characteristics of the
human fingerprint. If you have to use leather gloves, destroy
them immediately after the job. If found in your possession, they
can convict you as quickly as a set of your own fingerprints.

Your bag should contain a few pairs of cheap handcuffs,
usually available at pawn shops or army surplus stores. These,
two, are throwaways, and may be needed to restrain the mark while
you gather information that has been requested by the employer
before you pull the trigger.

The knife you carry should have a six inch blade with a
serrated section for making efficient, quiet kills. Your physical
training and combat techniques, outlines in Chapter 1, should
have taught you where to strike.

The knife should have a double edged blade. This double edge,
combined with the serrated section and six-inch length, will
insure a deep, ragged tear, and the wound will be difficult, if
not impossible, to close without prompt medical attention.

Make the thrusts to a vital organ and twist the knife before
you withdraw it. If you hit bone, you will have to file the blade
to remove the marks left on the metal when it struck the victim&apos;s
bone.

A rolled up ski-mask can be worn inconspicuously as a knit cap
until the time to intrude on your victim. Then, pull it down to
cover your features. A stocking mask may also be used, but may
prove a bit awkward. And the distorted features created tend to
shock people, whereas the ski mask is not so monstrous.

You will want to complete your bag with a few minor
accessories like an inexpensive pen-light from the drug store
flashlight department. This will be of extreme value as you pick
locks or search darkened rooms. Remember to hold your hand over
the beam of light as you direct it.

Throw in an ice pick, a large screwdriver and a flat-bladed
knife like a putty or hook knife for gaining entry through locked
doors, windows, or sliding glass doors.

You may not need all these items on any one job, but it will
be to your advantage to have them in case they are called for.

 EXTRAS 

After the basic equipment has been assembled, the following
items can be added to your inventory as they are called for or as
you can afford them.

If you are seen by some observant witness, it will be to your
advantage if the description he gives the authorities is
completely inaccurate. Using your imagination, you can totally
change your appearance by using wigs, false beards, wash-in hair
color and other disguises. Get books on theatrical make-up from
magic shops or then public library and start to experiment with
the many ways professionals completely change their looks. Learn
to use wigs, false tattoos, scars, black eyes and the like to
fool your observers. If a man has an unsightly wart on the end of
his nose, that is what everyone will remember about him, not the
color of his eyes.

A mark in hiding who expects to become a target may not open
his door to you, but he very likely would respond to a request
for help from a woman or old person who came calling. Along the
same lines, props like repairman, medic and police officer
uniforms may get deadbolts unbolted and guards let down.

Some people will argue that a professional will not stoop so
low as to play games with disguises. It may be great fun to fool
people about who you really are, but it is certainly no game. By
using disguises and changing them regularly, a professional has
added freedom of movement. If the disguise is easily changeable
-- that is if he can get out of it and into another quickly --
then he is time and money ahead.

A man who calls himself a professional and would walk up
barefaced and blow someone away with witnesses lurking about is
only fooling himself. If you are going to take such great care in
the selection and preparation of your tools, why risk being
clearly identifiable? Indeed, the use of disguise and props while
you carry out your assignment is highly advisable.

 CLOTHING 

Dress, as well as disguises, should be coordinated according
to the job setting. A hippie would be totally out of place in an
office complex among men in three piece suits. A clean-shaven,
well dressed young man would be out of his natural element among
a group of bikers. A feeble old man with a walking cane and a bag
of groceries, on the other hand, might fit in almost anywhere.
Dress to blend inconspicuously with your surroundings.

You might start with a basic pair of dark coveralls. Except in
certain circumstances, camouflage is out. Black, dark brown or
olive green clothes do not stand out and will probably appear at
first glance to be a mechanic or delivery driver&apos;s uniform. The
many large pockets provided will enable you to easily conceal
rubber gloves, extra clips and other tools. The bulkiness will
even allow for concealment of your weapon. And underneath, you
can wear your street clothes for a quick change after the job is
completed.

Recon of night work, where you do not intend to have your
movements detected, call for camouflage or night suits. Be sure
to fit this apparel to terrain and weather conditions. You
wouldn&apos;t dress in black like a ninja to move about on a moonlit
night or on a snowy white background. Neither would you wear
light clothes to move about in dark alleys or against dark
backgrounds. and if you are the only one running around in
camouflage garb, you are more than likely to draw attention to
yourself.

 UNINVITED ENTRY 

Following is a template for lock picks which will allow you to
make a completely adequate set of picks out of ordinary hacksaw
blades ground to shape on your workshop grinder:

 THE STANDARD PICKS 

Notice that one has slightly less angle at the tip. These two
are the most commonly used.

[insert graphics]

 THE TORSION BAR 

Notice the small site-down at the tip to allow for different
sized key slots. A large, thick hair pin makes a good torsion
bar.

[insert graphics]

 LOCK PICK DIRECTIONS 

1. Insert the pick all the way into the lock, facing up.

2. Place the torsion bar in the bottom of the lock, facing
down. Exert a slight amount of pressure on the torsion bar in the
direction the knob turns to open the door. (on the doors, if the
knob is on the right, it turns to the right. If one the left, it
turns to the left.)

3. Use only one finger to exert pressure on the torsion bar
while you jiggle pick up and down (no more than an eighth of an
inch at the most) and work the pick all the way back out of the
lock. If you exert too much pressure or try to force the lock,
you may freeze it or break the pick. The tumblers inside the lock
must be bounced into place.

4. Each time you remove the pick, you must release the
pressure on the torsion bar and begin again.

In a short time you should become an expert at opening common
door locks. Padlocks will hardly take any time at all to master.
Deadbolts may take a little longer, but they are well worth the
time and effort.

You can also use ordinary channel lock pliers to open most
deadbolts. By twisting the lock and breaking the retaining bolts,
you can use a knife point or pick to turn the bolt and gain
entry.

Auto part stores also carry a handy little gadget called the
Slim Jim that will enable you to get into almost any locked
automobile in a manner of seconds. These are inexpensive and come
with an instruction booklet depicting the methods for entering
different makes and models.

 SURVEILLANCE 

The walkie-talkie, or two way radio, if it is a really good
one, can be an indispensable tool when working with a partner. A
good set is expensive, but has the range and ability for
communicating through walls and over long distances -- up to two
miles at least. It will also have a volume control as well as a
code&quot;beeping&quot;device.

The vast array of available surveillance equipment and the
rapid advances in technology in this field are mind boggling. The
old microphones and reel-to-reel tape recorders that had to be
stored nearby are a thing of the past. Now you can plant a bug
less than the size of a quarter and sit in you car two miles away
while you listen to the action on your car radio. If you are
interested in these James Bond tactics, start collecting catalogs
and prices now for future use.

One fellow gave a girl who lived with his mark a pretty
barrette he found on the floor in a bar. The girl took the
barrette home and left it on the dresser. Unfortunately for the
mark, who eventually met his demise, the&quot;found&quot;barrette concealed a micro-transmitter. The hit man was able to
collect enough information on their activities to plan a
successful hit.

Bugs offer some fascinating alternatives to the old standby
method of sit-and-watch. Check into them as well as the
electronic bug detectors, which are now easily accessible. Think
of the kinds of information you could assemble with just a
micro-bug and a voice-activated micro-cassette recorder, and
think how hard it would be for someone without proper detection
equipment to discover.

Of course, no surveillance equipment would be complete with a
good pair of binoculars. The best have a rating of 10 x 50 or
higher for night vision, range and clarity.

Even a small micro-cassette recorder can come in handy while
you are doing your prejob research and will take the place of
pen, paper, and fumbling in the dark.

 MISCELLANEOUS 

An air gun (one with pump, not spring, action), will come in
handy on a number of occasions. You can use pellets to knock out
lights or to create diversions. Or, you can make your own darts
to carry a fast-acting poison to the mark or to his noisy
watchdog.

From time to time you may need a method for climbing to or
from high places. Twenty feet of knotted rope (measure after
knots are tied) can come in handy for climbing to second floor
balconies or coming down from a roof. Tie one end in a high
branch of a large tree and practice until you can scale it
easily.

Of course, the tools you use will vary from job to job. Some
you will find yourself using again and again, while other
suggested items will never be called for. Stock your inventory
according to personal preference and need.

 LUXURY ITEMS 

As you move up the ladder of professionalism and become
accustomed to success, you may want to increase you inventory
with several toys that will make James Bond envious. Among these
may be cleverly designed attach cases with concealed weapons
activated by a button on the handle, fancy cameras, Star-Light
scopes, Laser bugging equipment, electronic gadgets and the like.

Of course, your selection of weapons will grow and you may
even have a secret vault in your home to conceal your collection
of fully automatic toys like the Mac-11, M-16, tranquilizer guns,
hand grenades and sophisticated exploding devices.

You will be able to afford the best in false identifications
and obtain real uniforms and badges for various state and federal
law enforcement agencies to aid in the performance of your
contracts.

Throwaway cars and boats may even become common and you even
own your very own plane, through legal methods explained later.

Money talks, and for every need you have, there is a man out
there who is willing to fill it for you for a price. That&apos;s how
you got started, remember? But money buys a lot more than
material things. Money can buy smart attorneys, judges, alibis,
and even time, if necessary. The possibilities are endless for
the smart man who plans his moves carefully, is mentally and
physically prepared and doesn&apos;t leave any trails as he performs
his highly paid services.
 
 THE DISPOSABLE SILENCER 

IN THE COURSE OF PUTTING this book together, while disguising
myself as a writer I chanced to interview a former law
enforcement officer with twenty seven years experience for his
opinion of how a perfect hit would go down. It was the opinion of
this officer of the peace that the perfect hit would start with
the purchase of a nondescript automobile, then driving, with
tools in tow, to the jobsite.

Once there, he would follow the mark until a routine was
established and probably waste the man in a public place with a
blast from a double barreled sawed-off shotgun. Then he would
throw the gun down and drive away while the bystanders were in a
state of mass hysteria.

Even if he got caught with the shotgun in his hands, he
argued, they would not be able to prove that the blast from that
shotgun was the murder weapon since shotguns are untraceable.
Obviously he has not kept in touch with new investigative
procedures and techniques, for it is now known that each shotgun
makes an individual and distinct spread pattern and the gun most
certainly can be matched as the murder weapon.

&quot;Why not hit the mark in his own home?&quot;I inquired
innocently.

&quot;Oh, I&apos;d never hit a guy in his own house,&quot;he
answered,&quot;Too many witnesses .. you know, family ... nosy
neighbors and the like.&quot;

What about a small caliber handgun with an attached
silencer?&quot;I asked.

&quot;Well,&quot;he answered,&quot;You would have to carry
the handgun concealed, and that&apos;s against the law. But the
shotgun, if it were a legal sized shotgun, you could carry that
right in the window of your pickup truck on your gun rack. And
I&apos;d never touch a silencer. Boy! They&apos;d burn you if you got
caught with a thing like that!&quot;

I concluded the interview pretending to be in awe of his
wisdom, while inside I was amazed by the ignorance behind his
reasoning. Why on earth, I thought, would a man worry about
breaking gun restrictions when he was en route to commit a
murder.?

Yet, I felt comforted by his viewpoint. For his opinion
probably represents the way a goodly portion of law enforcement
officers think.

There have been many times when an amateur has just walked up
to his mark on the street, blown him away in the midst of a
crowd, ditched the gun in a garbage can and gotten away with it.
But the whole procedure lacks professionalism and the risks are
much too high.

The professional is on call to kill. He not only provides the
employer with his gun, but with his expert knowledge, discretion
and ability to carry the assignment off without needlessly
endangering anyone but the mark.

The silencer is one of the most important tools a professional
will ever have. The silenced weapon, when fired, will not draw
attention. Lack of attention means more time. Time means getting
the job done right. The panic, the pressure, is absent. There are
many books available on the subject of making your own silencers.
Most of the methods used require machine shop tools and the
ability to use them with precision accuracy. This fact alone has
put a lot of would-be professionals out of the game, or at least
back into the ranks of amateurs.

On the following pages, you will learn how to make, without
the need of special engineering ability or expensive machine shop
tools, a silencer of the highest quality and effectiveness. The
finished product attached to your 22 will be no louder than the
noise made by a pellet gun. Because it is so inexpensive (mine
cost less than 20 dollars to make), you can easily dispose of it
after job use without any great loss. Future silencers will cost
even less to make, since many of the materials will not be used
up in the first application.

Your first silencer will require possibly two days total to
assemble (including drying time) as you carefully follow the
directions step by step. After you make a couple, it will become
so easy, so routine, that you can whip one up in just a few
hours.

When it&apos;s done, no need to take it out in the woods to try it
out. Just stack some magazines or newspapers in a box and shoot
to your hearts content in the garage. Believe me, it&apos;s that good.

Just remember, as I mentioned before, to resight your gun
after the silencer is in place. And when you do go out in the
woods, experiment to test how your range is affected. You will
lose some distance, and this must be taken into consideration
later, when planning a hit.

 DISPOSABLE SILENCER DIRECTIONS 

The directions and photographs that follow show in explicit
detail how to construct a silencer for a Ruger 10/22 rifle. The
same directions can be followed successfully to construct a
silencer for any weapon, with only the size of the drill rod used
for alignment changed to fit inside the dimension of the barrel.

The following items should be assembled before you begin:

 Drill rod, 7/32 inch (order from a machine shop if not
 obtained locally) One foot of 1/4 inch brake line from auto parts One quart of fiberglass resin with hardener One foot of 1-1/2 inch (inside diameter) PVC piping and
 two end caps One yard thin fiberglass mat One roll of masking tape One 1/8 inch drill bit One 3/16 inch drill bit Handful of rubber bands Three or four single inch razor blades One sheet 80 grit sandpaper Six small wood screws One box steel wool 

Cut a 10-inch section from the brake line. See figure 1. Drill
a set of 1/8 inch holes down the length of the tube going in one
side and out the other. The holes go all the way through. Notice
in the photograph that the holes begin 1-1/2 inches from the end
of the tube that fill on the gun.

Next, take a 3/16 inch drill bit and enlarge the holes. See
figure 2.

Using masking tape and keeping the tape as free of wrinkles as
possible, mask off about six inches of the gun barrel and the end
of the barrel. Use only masking tape. Duct tape is too thick and
would make for an improper fit. See figure 3.

Then place the drill rod down the barrel to keep the brake
tube aligned. This perfect alignment is extremely important.

If the drill rod you purchase is a little too large, as
sometimes happens, put it in a drill and using a file and
sandpaper (80 grit), turn down the first six inches until it will
fit inside the gun barrel. I operate the drill from the floor
with my foot, letting the rod spin between my knees as I reduce
the size. Check regularly until you achieve a perfect fit. If you
grind the rod too small, cut it off and start over. Fit must be
tight with no play. See figure 4.

Wrap glass mat around the gun and tube three times. Secure it
with string or rubber bands every half inch to keep it tight and
in place. The glass should be wrapped about two inches behind the
sight and up to the first hold on the tube. See figure 5.

Now mix the resin. About a shot glassful will do. Mix it two
or three times hotter than the package directions.

Brace the gun in an upright position and dab the resin into
the glass cloth with a stubby brush. Keep dabbling until the
cloth is no longer white but has become transparent from
absorption of the resin. See figure 6.

As soon as the glass is tacky to touch without sticking (times
differs according to weather conditions and humidity), it is time
to remove the piece from the barrel. Move fast!

First, take a razor blade and cut a notch behind the sight so
the piece can be removed. Then push on the glass to slide it off.
Do not pull on the tube. See figure 7.

After removing the gun barrel, peel out the tape and allow it
to finish hardening. You must work quickly. If you let the glass
harden too much on the gun, you will have to cut it off and begin
again.

USe a grinder and 80 grit sandpaper to smooth the hardening
rough surface.

NEzt, grind the sides down about halfway, but do not grind
past the point where the front of the sight makes contact. See
figure 8. Cut it down until the barrel fits easily and snugly.

Stand the glassed inner tube upright in a vise.

Mix a small amount of resin and use an eyedropper to fill in
any interior holes or air bubbles until the solid fiberglass is
level with the steel tube end. This will give the junction of the
steel inner tube and glass coupling added strength. See figure 9.

Clean the eyedropper with acetone.

Cut the PVC tube to desired length. This one is eight inches.
See figure 10.

Drill a large hole in the center of one cap, making it large
enough to fit on the glass end to the point where the sight makes
contact.

Then drill small holes all around the cap at the bottom, as
shown, with a 3/16 bit. See figure 11.

Wrap masking tape around the cap to cover the holes. See
figure 12.

Stand the cap with the inside tube inserted into a vise. Get
the cap level and straight with the tube.

Cut a lot of 1/2 inch square pieces of fiberglass matting and
fill the cap with it up past the level of the small holes.

Mix resin and pour it over the cut glass to a point about 1/4
inch above the holes and allow it to dry before removing the cap
from the vise. Don&apos;t worry about any resin that leaks out around
the base hole. Resin fills the small holes, making the tube
strong enough to take the blast when you fire the gun.

When the inside is hardened, turn the assembly over and add
glass around the backside of the cap for added strength as shown.
Avoid getting resin in the opening where the barrel fits. See
figure 13.

Place the finished cap and inner tube on one end of the PVC
tubing that has already been cut to size. Center the inner tube
as you look in the open end of the PVC.

Now drill a 1/8 inch hole in three place around the tube about
1/4 inch from the lip of the cap.

Take the inner tube out and enlarge the holes in the cap to
3/16 inch. See figure 14.

Replace the inner tube and tighten it down with three small
wood screws.

Trim the inside tube down until it extends about 1/2 inch
beyond the outside PVC tube.

Sharpen one end of the drill rod to a point and use as a
punch. Stand the tube up with the solid cap down. Then drop the
drill rod down the inner tube to get a true center mark. See
figure 15.

Find a drill bit a little larger than the outside diameter of
the inner tube. Remove the cap and drill the hole.

Replace the cap on the open end of the PVC and drill three 1/8
inch holes around the cap as before for wood screw.

Grind off any inner tube that sticks out. make it flush with
the face of the cap. See figure 16.

Unfold the sections of steel wool and roll between palms to
make strands as shown.

Feed the strands into the silencer tube in a circular motion,
packing the wool tight with a stick. Do this until the tube is
completely full. See figure 17.

Replace the end cap with the three screws. See figure 18.

Paint the finished silencer black and attach it to your
weapons. You may want to ensure proper alignment by wrapping tape
or placing a hose clamp around the extension behind the sight.
See figure 19.

 THE FINISHED PRODUCT 

Your finished product is whisper-quiet, the way a silencer is
supposed to be! It is inexpensive, effective and reusable for
over four hundred rounds before you will need to repack.

This little tool is so easy to make that you will feel no pain
when you crush it to bits and throw it away.
 
 TO
KILL A RABBIT 

IT WOULD TAKE VOLUMES and volumes to list the many ways men
have devised to exterminate one another, and I am sure you have
already started to accumulate quite an extensive list of your own
personal favorites.

Some very good books are available on this subject and even
television, movies and fictional stories are out to teach you a
new trick or two! but be careful. Some of the methods depicted
are only theories of an imaginative writer and do not work in
reality. so be sure that any method you choose is a proven
effective one.

In Chapter 2, much detail was given concerning the effective
use of the pistol and the rifle in making a kill. Although
several shots fired in succession offer a quick and relatively
humane death to the victim, there are instances when other
methods of extermination are called for. The employer may want
you to gather certain information from the mark before you do
away with him. At other times, the assignment may call for
torture or disfigurement as a&quot;lesson&quot;for the
survivors. Your assignment could call for suicide or accidental
death may be the order. It may, or may not, be important that the
body disappear. There are ways to put off discovery of the body
and ways to make it disappear completely.

Books that deal with these subjects are available for your
information, but the following techniques are personal favorites.

 EXPLOSIVES 

I will be rare to get a request for someone to be taken out
with a bigger boom than that created by your 22. If you get such
a request and don&apos;t know how to handle explosives properly, you&apos;d
be better off passing up the job.

Here, again, much data is available on making homemade
explosives, but these directions should be pretested before
actual use. Quite of the few directions I have found product
nothing but an unsatisfactory fizzle.

Also, beware of the ability of the authorities to trace
explosives. Sources for these supplies are limited, so make sure
the components you have are untraceable.

The only time I can think of that explosives might be in order
is when several marks will be together in one place at one time,
and you might be able to get them all with one shot. Notice that
I stress the word might. Shrapnel doesn&apos;t always kill. So in the
aftermath, it will be your responsibility to enter the area and
make sure that the desired result was accomplished. Survivors are
not good for business. And since explosives tend to attract
immediate attention, you will have to work fast and take extreme
added risk.

Personally, I prefer discreet one-one-one contact and tend to
avoid anything that draws attention. If explosives are the only
alternative I military C-4 plastics or a military issue hand
grenade (baseballs; the pineapple kind is obsolete). A hand
grenade, properly placed, can give the desired results in a
one-on-one situation. For instance, a grenade placed beneath the
mark&apos;s car directly under the driver&apos;s seat with a wire leading
from the pin to the drive shaft will work wonderfully. Just make
sue the mark is the only one who drives the car or you may blow
up some innocent victim. Messy mistakes of this type are not only
a professional embarrassment to you and your employer but they
tend to alert the mark of your intentions and bring the
authorities out in full force.

I once witnessed the destruction of a small stone house by
means of a simple fertilizer bomb. The readily available
components of it make it untraceable and it worked so well that
all that was left was part of the foundation and a large, gaping
hole where the bomb had been.

To make a fertilizer bomb, purchase a fifty pound bag of
fertilizer from your garden center. Get the kind with the highest
nitrate content you can find. Next, buy one pound of black powder
from a gun shop that sells reload supplies. Then, get 10-20 feet
of waterproof fuse from a hobby shop that sells model rockets.

Place the gunpowder inside a jar which comes with a screw-on
lid. Drill a hole in the lid and slip one end of the fuse through
tying a knot in the fuse to keep it from slipping out of the jar.
Screw the lid on the powder filled jar.

Under the bag of fertilizer place the powder filled jar cap
side down. Extend the fuse and light or use a cigarette as a
delayed igniter. RUN LIKE HELL~

Dynamite is nice and can be picked up from many building sites
or roads under construction. But during storage the sticks have
to be turned over regularly to prevent settling of the nitro. And
the blasting caps necessary to make it go off are so tricky that
just by walking across the carpet enough static electricity could
be created to blow you away.

As I said in the beginning, unless you know what you are
doing, stay away from requests for this kind of extermination, or
the life you take may be your own.

 ARSON 

Arson is a good method for covering a kill or creating an&quot;accident.&quot;When properly set, the fire will appear to
have started from natural causes and arson will not be suspected.

Fire investigation has become a science in recent years, and
authorities and professional fire fighters can learn a great deal
about the fire and its origin by a study of the scene.

Before you try to fake a fire, know how to do it properly. For
instance, lots of the new carpeting on the market is now fire
retardant, as there are many other sympathetic materials. So
rather than start a fire in the middle of the room, start it
under an electrical appliance or from a stove burner that has&quot;carelessly&quot;been left on, or some other likely spot.

Don&apos;t ever use gasoline or other traceable materials to start
your fire. Woodgrain alcohol is you best starter because it burns
away all traces.

One good fire in an area that will create a lot of smoke from
burning materials is preferred. Fire investigators can trace the
origin of the fire, and two flames started simultaneously will
immediately arouse suspicion.

It is not the flame that kills most victims of a fire, but the
inhalation of smoke. A fire victim will have smoke present in his
lungs. Therefore, if this is your choice of extermination, your
mark should be unconscious, but breathing, when the fire is set.
Make sure that no scratches or bruises point to foul play. And
remove the batteries from all smoke detectors with gloved hands
before you set the fire.

Never hang around to watch the fire you set. Police have been
known to photograph the crowd; that&apos;s how a lot of pyromaniacs
get caught. Don&apos;t let your curiosity get the better of you!

 BARE HAND KILLS, KNIVES, AND SILENT WEAPONS 

All of these are primarily self defense methods or tools. Who
wants to take a chance with his bare hands or a knife in a
one-on-one confrontation when a gun is so much quicker, cleaner
and more effective and gives you so much more leverage? A mark
may risk a chance at defending himself against your personal
onslaught, but that cold steel with the silencer attached shows
right away that you mean business and gets instant respect.

However, skillful knowledge and use of these abilities is
desirable and recommend. There may come a time when you need a
silent method for eliminating a mark in a crowded area, or a way
to quiet a bodyguard as noiselessly as possible in order to get
the mark.

As in all kill methods, be sure of your proficiency before
your life depend son it. Stay in top physical condition, practice
regularly until the moves become automatic and study pressure
points so you will know where to strike and how much force to use
for desired results.

an ice pick hidden against your arm as you casually stroll
past an unsuspecting victim in a crowded place can e used to
strike him a powerful kidney blow without interrupting the
natural swing of your arms as you pass.

Movies and fictitious stories like to show the cutting of the
victim&apos;s throat as a slice from ear to ear. However, this is not
the best, or preferred, method.

Using your six-inch, serrated blade knife, stab deeply into
the side of the victim&apos;s neck and push the knife forward in a
forceful movement. This method will half decapitate the victim,
cutting both his main arteries and wind pipe, ensuring immediate
death.

As described earlier, the proper way to make a kill with the
recommended knife is to twist the blade before withdrawing it
from a vital area. The serrated edge will make an open, gaping
wound that cannot be closed to stop the bleeding.

You combat instructor should be able to teach you a wide
variety of skills with silent weapons, when to use them and where
to strike. You will develop your own personal preferences and
style.

There will hardly be a time when you will kill with your bare
hands unless you use your ability for self-defense. A knife may
be called for on occasion, and should be carried with you on all
your assignments in case it is required. Silent weapons are
specialty measures which require skill an talent for effective
use.

In any case, the object is to get to the mark, complete your
assignment, and get out, as cleanly and as quickly as possible
without drawing any unnecessary attention.

 POISONS 

Poisons are sweet, silent and effective, and some leave no
traces. Poison is one of the hit man&apos;s best friends.

If you know your mark&apos;s habits well enough, the desired result
can be achieved while you are sitting miles away. If you make
personal contact for their introduction, poisons will give
prompt, guaranteed results.

Because there is so much government regulation, effective
poisons are getting harder and harder to come by. The recent
Extra Strength Tylenol scare didn&apos;t help matters. Yet, there are
sources still available for your use.

At the local library, a very helpful assistant led me to a
reference section, where I copied down the name and addresses of
several large chemical suppliers (You don&apos;t want&quot;industrial&quot;chemicals: they are janitorial supplies.)
I obtained phone numbers from information and called the numbers
systematically until I found the one that carried the products I
wanted. Under the guide of HM Research and Development, I ordered
the minimum amounts required and sent along a money order for
faster processing.

Later, I went so far as to have a company letterhead made and
sent inquires on certain chemicals, minimum ordering requirements
and costs to the suppliers on my list. The letter went something
like this:

Dear Sirs:
Our firm is interested in obtaining small quantities of the
following chemicals for research purposes only. Please send a
quote on minimum purchase requirements, costs and delivery.

Sincerely,

Jow Blough
President
	</body>
</document>
