<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005383" url="http://www.scrapbook.com/forums/showtopic.php?tid/1394285/" time="2012-07-12-21:56" support="1" score="0.0015327044240112547" bingtitle="Altered Paint Cans - Scrapbook.com - Powered by Scrapbook.com" webtitle="Altered Paint Cans - Scrapbook.com - Powered by Scrapbook.com">
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="120"/>
	<description>If you have an ACE True Value store, they are often cheaper there. My Home Depot and Lowe&apos;s run near 5 bucks a can ... If they do, I leave it shut. That was one thing ...</description>
	<body>
		Save 15% on ALL Girl-Themed Products Login  •  Sign Up  •  Help  •  My Account  •  My Reviews  •  Wish List  •  View Cart    
 
 Scrap by Color Brands Product Types Themes NEW Arrivals Clearance Rack Coupons&amp;Specials Product Reviews Quick Search! Customer Service My Shopping Account: View My Cart My Wishlist My Product Reviews Track My Order 
 
 Summary (Featured) Layouts Digital Layouts Cards Scraprooms Other Projects Photos Search My Gallery: My Images My Albums Add Images My Favorites/Votes 
 
 General Scrapbooking Beginning Scrapbooking Cardmaking&amp;Stamping Non-ScrapBook Related Interactive Fun More Forums... My Forum Stuff: Control Panel My Favorite Topics Private Messages 
 
 Articles Blogs Tips Quotes Titles Poems Free Newsletters More Resources... My Resources: My Contributions My Favorites Resources Submit Resources 
 
 Beginner Intermediate Advanced All Classes&amp;Tools 
 
 All Videos Product Demos Projects Techniques Site Tips For Fun My Videos 
 
 My Profile Order History Wish List My Reviews My Gallery Activity Stream My Forum Stuff My Friends Public Comments My Favorites More... 
   
 
 
 Forums Help SIGN UP 
 My Cookies Frequently Asked Questions Forum Rules 
 

 
 
 Location:   Summary Index » Forum Index » Scrapbooking Forums » General Scrapbooking »Altered Paint Cans 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
   Previous   Bottom   Next 
 
  Page 1 of 2  ALL 1 2 
 

 
 Username Post: Altered Paint Cans       (Topic#1394285) lakestatescrapper  
 Pro
 Posts: 1846
 
Joined: 09-23-06

 lakestatescrapper&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 06:43 PM - Post# 3041593    

All this talk about paint cans gets me wondering.

what do you guys put into them once your done???

and where do you get the plain new cans at??

thanks...i def. want to alter a paint can, but only if i can find a good use for it or for someone i give it to.
 Julie 
PUHLLEESE check out my blog. It&apos;s not scrap related, but if you have a sense of humor then I think you&apos;ll love it!
 Pegleg Starfish 

Mom to Hurley 
Mom to Master Chief 
Girlfriend to Tyler 
Slave to 

WOW! I haven&apos;t scrapped in SO long. I need to carve some time to get back into it. Maybe I should use my free time to scrap instead of surfing this addicting site! 


 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 janet28rn  
 Governor
 Posts: 24773
 
Joined: 05-18-06

 janet28rn&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 06:47 PM - Post# 3041621    
     In response to lakestatescrapper 

home depot... lowe&apos;s... paint and supply stores.... are a few ideas of great places to look for paint cans of various sizes and at a cheaper rate 

You can fill them with ANYTHING. I like the idea of picking a theme (school days, baby, holidays, spa, etc...) and decorating and filling to coordinate.

Hope this helps! This makes a great and creative gift idea (especially with the holidays coming soon!)
 ~ Janet ~ 

 &quot;You can have it all... you just can&apos;t have it all at once.&quot; ~ Oprah Winfrey

 2012 Volume Scrapping Challenge
53/100 layouts - 53% 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 luv2scrap1968  
 Veteran
 Posts: 388
 
Joined: 01-28-06

 luv2scrap1968&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 06:50 PM - Post# 3041647    
     In response to lakestatescrapper 

well, I am using my as Christmas gifts/ wrapping..... I made each can to match the colors of each person&apos;s home.... and then I put their Christmas gift in it. They can use it to hold whatever they like, and can hide *junk* in it, in plain view, since the cans are cute, and can be set out as an *interior* decoration.

I get my cans at Sherwin Williams, they cost me about $3.00 or so. You can cover them with SB papers, or do like me, and when I went in to get the paint cns, I also got 12 or 13 wallpaper sample books, and that is what I have used for most of mine!!

Rachel
 Be who you are and say what
you feel, because those who mind don&apos;t
matter, and those who matter don&apos;t mind
 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 HappyStamping  
 Mayor
 Posts: 11546
 
Joined: 12-31-05

 HappyStamping&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 06:51 PM - Post# 3041649    
     In response to janet28rn 

They are great for giving presents! Themes work well! Dog, cat, Disney, Winter, Christmas, birthday, love......etc...
 Sue

 Member of the P.O.G. 
 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 lakestatescrapper  
 Pro
 Posts: 1846
 
Joined: 09-23-06

 lakestatescrapper&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 06:54 PM - Post# 3041675    
     In response to HappyStamping 

Thanks ladies. I will have to pick a few up next time im at HOme Depot! Great gifting idea!
 Julie 
PUHLLEESE check out my blog. It&apos;s not scrap related, but if you have a sense of humor then I think you&apos;ll love it!
 Pegleg Starfish 

Mom to Hurley 
Mom to Master Chief 
Girlfriend to Tyler 
Slave to 

WOW! I haven&apos;t scrapped in SO long. I need to carve some time to get back into it. Maybe I should use my free time to scrap instead of surfing this addicting site! 


 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 MomTo4CrazyKids  
 Governor
 Posts: 16859
 
Joined: 12-14-05

 MomTo4CrazyKids&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 07:10 PM - Post# 3041785    
     In response to lakestatescrapper 

If you have an ACE True Value store, they are often cheaper there. My Home Depot and Lowe&apos;s run near 5 bucks a can, even the small ones are 3 bucks. At ACE, the gallon sized ones are 1.44. Not too shabby!

Melinda
 ~*Melinda*~ 
 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Nancy Keslin  
 Queen
 Posts: 38658
 
Joined: 03-30-06

 Nancy Keslin&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 07:11 PM - Post# 3041791    
     In response to MomTo4CrazyKids 

I gave lots of them last year for Christmas presents. We filled them with cookie mix and hot cocoa mix.
 Nancy 
 Zutter Zister-Bind it All Design Team 
 Homescool in My Little Corner 
Design Team Member The Sampler 
 Contributing Artist for Ideas for Scrapbookers 
Design Team Member Your Memories Here 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 JustMeinIN  
 Diva
 Posts: 5358
 
Joined: 07-27-06

 JustMeinIN&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 07:50 PM - Post# 3042127    
     In response to lakestatescrapper 

I&apos;m making snowman kits with mine this year.

Handful of painted rocks (look like coal)
hat
scarf
plastic carrot

 Do Not Click 

*June*
Stampin Up Demo

Challenges:

Swaps:

Hosting:

 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 lakestatescrapper  
 Pro
 Posts: 1846
 
Joined: 09-23-06

 lakestatescrapper&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 08:02 PM - Post# 3042239    
     In response to JustMeinIN 

June, that is the cutest idea ever!!!!!!

 Julie 
PUHLLEESE check out my blog. It&apos;s not scrap related, but if you have a sense of humor then I think you&apos;ll love it!
 Pegleg Starfish 

Mom to Hurley 
Mom to Master Chief 
Girlfriend to Tyler 
Slave to 

WOW! I haven&apos;t scrapped in SO long. I need to carve some time to get back into it. Maybe I should use my free time to scrap instead of surfing this addicting site! 


 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Smitten_Scrapper  
 Resident
 Posts: 222
 
Joined: 11-15-06

 Smitten_Scrapper&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 08:02 PM - Post# 3042241    
     In response to lakestatescrapper 

Here is one I did

 Paint Tin 

I actually got this at a thrift store for 35 cents but I heard that sometimes if you go to your local hard ware store and ask for an empty one, they give it to you. I decorate it and it takes about an hour or tow, and than I just put some little things like a wallet, lip gloss, nail polish, etc and its an insta-gift!
 ~*~Sara~*~
Wife to Earl 
Mom to: Adrienne Rose (6) Tyler Mason (2) 

 Please check out My Blog regarding my daughters epilepsy and what I am doing about it!! 
 I&apos;m in love with a bug! 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 ilovenick  
 Diva
 Posts: 6695
 
Joined: 05-29-06

 ilovenick&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 08:40 PM - Post# 3042477    
     In response to Smitten_Scrapper 

I get them on that auction site eb*y
 Mayoress of Nickville! 

 I Nick Lachey!!!
 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Debra K  
 Veteran
 Posts: 580
 
Joined: 10-25-06

 Debra K&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 09:11 PM - Post# 3042705    
     In response to ilovenick 

After reading this tread it sparked and idea in me. Thanks everyone 
 Laugh, Love, and Live 
 
Mom of two boys 
 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Momma2Bryn  
 Veteran
 Posts: 378
 
Joined: 08-04-06

 Momma2Bryn&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 09:15 PM - Post# 3042737    
     In response to Debra K 

Wow! I adore the snowman idea!! Christmas present ideas!!

   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Momma2Bryn  
 Veteran
 Posts: 378
 
Joined: 08-04-06

 Momma2Bryn&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 09:17 PM - Post# 3042751    
     In response to Momma2Bryn 

JustMeinIN - do you have a picture of one of your snowman tins?

I&apos;m going to google them too for ideas. I&apos;ve never seen altered paintcans until today. You guys are so crafty!!


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Jennifer Priest  
 Governor
 Posts: 20477
 
Joined: 06-22-06

 Jennifer Priest&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 09:49 PM - Post# 3042973    
     In response to Momma2Bryn 

There are a couple of places to get them for a good price. Best price Ihave seen is at Dunn Edwwards paint store for $1.83 per can. Online I have seen them for $1.99 but then you have to pay shipping. OSH has the really tiny ones that are the perfect size for gift cards.

I have lots of pics in my gallery (Altered stuff album) of cans I have done.

Stuff you can put in them:

Anything you would put in a basket
crayons/art supplies for a kid
toy car or army men for kid
bath goodies
cookies (I did this last year for like 15 people)
did one for easter for easter eggs
my dd has one with her stickers in it

etc....

HTH
 Check out my Blog Here 

 Happy To Be: 
Fiskateer #2074
CHA Designer Member 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Jennifer Priest  
 Governor
 Posts: 20477
 
Joined: 06-22-06

 Jennifer Priest&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 09:52 PM - Post# 3042997    
     In response to Jennifer Priest 

I did a Disney one for Katie&apos;s teacher last year cuz she is a serious Disney fan--fill it with candy....put gardening supplies in it (like stakes for plant labels, a pair of gloves, a little shovel, a couple packs of seeds)..fill it with tea making supplies like a diffuser, some tea filled tins, a sppon and cup....really there are so many possibilities.
 Check out my Blog Here 

 Happy To Be: 
Fiskateer #2074
CHA Designer Member 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Danielle_K  
 Veteran
 Posts: 294
 
Joined: 03-26-05

 Danielle_K&apos;s Gallery 12-13-06 10:04 PM - Post# 3043081    
     In response to Jennifer Priest 

I&apos;ve altered a big one that I use as a trashcan on my scrap table.
 You use 60 muscles to look angry, only 20 to smile....so what&apos;s the problem? 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 ilovenick  
 Diva
 Posts: 6695
 
Joined: 05-29-06

 ilovenick&apos;s Gallery 12-14-06 04:39 AM - Post# 3043817    
     In response to Danielle_K 


 Dadie Said: 
 I&apos;ve altered a big one that I use as a trashcan on my scrap table.
 

Ohh- what a good idea!! Thanks!
 Mayoress of Nickville! 

 I Nick Lachey!!!
 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Scraps4Two  
 Expert
 Posts: 1404
 
Joined: 01-23-06

 Scraps4Two&apos;s Gallery 12-15-06 09:52 AM - Post# 3053621    
     In response to ilovenick 

The snowman kit idea is fabulous! I&apos;m am so going to make one like that! how fun!
 ~Jen
 

Scrap Faster!!

&quot;I believe that if life gives you lemons you should make lemonade, then try find someone whose life has given them vodka...and have a party!&quot; Ron White

Blessed are the flexible, for they shall not get bent out of shape. 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 Jessica Guthrie  
 Veteran
 Posts: 311
 
Joined: 10-03-06

 Jessica Guthrie&apos;s Gallery 12-15-06 01:14 PM - Post# 3054989    
     In response to Scraps4Two 

What I have done for wedding gifts is decorate the can with papers and embellishments that coordinate with the bride&apos;s wedding colors. I then label it &quot;Our Wedding Cards&quot; and just set it on the gift table. If they don&apos;t have a wishing well or something to put cards in, I open it. If they do, I leave it shut. That was one thing when I got married - I had all these nice cards and nowhere to put them fater the wedding craziness was over! The same thing can work for baby showers, birthdays, retirement parties, etc.
 Scrappin&apos; since &apos;98! 
My Blog: www.jessicaguthrie.blogspot.com 
 Kits2Remember Go here for acrylic, metal and chipboard panels! 


   
 
   Email   Report 
 
 
 

 
 

 
 
   Previous   Index   Next 
 
  Page 1 of 2  ALL 1 2 
 

 
 Icon Legend Permissions Topic Options 
   Report 
 Report Post 


 Quote Post 


 Quick Reply 
 
   Print 
 Print Topic 


 Email Topic 
4709 Views 
 
 
 
 Online Now 383 registered users and 356 anonymous users are online now. 
 

 
 Recent Hot Topics 
 July VLB Challenge -- Gonna be aa Blast   (310) July Photo Fun   (279) July Monthy Sketch Challenge-Open-Please Join Us!   (213) July Scraplift the Person Before You ~ Closed and Scrapping   (189) ##July Ugly Paper Challenge: Mailing Papers ##   (182) 
 
 

 
 Recent Topics 
 Woohoo! Doh! July Challenge At Berry71bleu Hoarding it&apos;s an issue!!(: die hard cardstock June 2012 Round 4 Poll Pls jog my memory June 2012 Roun3 Poll site blogs - some very iffy indeed! 
 
 
 

 
 Location:   Summary Index » Forum Index » Scrapbooking Forums » General Scrapbooking »Altered Paint Cans 
 
 
 Weekly Deals&amp;Projects Daily Deals Store Specials Clearance New Products Dollar Store Jill&apos;s Deals Daily Deals Top Rated Scrap by Color The Gallery Featured Layouts Cards Digital Layouts Scraprooms Other Projects Search Images Resources&amp;More Articles Learn to Scrap Poems Title Ideas News Videos Classes Customer Service Contact Us FAQs Shipping Info Returns Security About Scrapbook.com Meet the Founder My Place My Profile Order History Wish List My Reviews My Gallery Activity Stream More...       ©2012 Scrapbook.com
	</body>
</document>
