<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005466" url="http://www.chineseop.com/generalcooking/Which-has-more-acid--tea-or-coffee-.html" time="2012-07-12-22:01" support="1" score="0.0013294757326871175" bingtitle="Which has more acid, tea or coffee?-About Food &amp; Health" webtitle="Which has more acid, tea or coffee?-About Food&amp;Health">
			<query id="001132" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>... discomfort, while that fourth of fifth cup ... vegetarian items would you want at a fast food restaurant? ... Favorite thing from chinese take out? What condiments do you eat ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Sitemap | RSS Feed | Bookmak Us Catalogue Home Cooking Recipes Dining Out Entertaining Cuisine Non-Alcoholic Drinks Health Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Beer wine Others 
 

 Related Resources 
 You are: Home &gt; General Cooking &gt; 

Which has more acid, tea or coffee?
 Views:    Font: [ Large Medium Small ] 
 Here are some friends with simlar question as we.And I have this question for many days,anyone help us?
Kitty said: Yes. Which has more acid, tea or coffee? -I try seach this on internet but no results found.Maybe this is a stupid question.
Mike said: oh,no,you are wrong.I have found as below for this question( Which has more acid, tea or coffee? ),it will help you,my kids.
 
Which has more acid, tea or coffee?
which has more acid?
 Answers: I Think Tea...That&apos;s what my Stomach tells me. Tanic Acid I believe. FYI:

Tea - research shows that green tea may prevent cancer, restrict blood cholesterol, control high blood pressure, lower blood sugar, suppress aging, deter food poisoning prevent and treat skin disease, stop cavities and fight viruses

while:

Coffee- no research was found to suggest that coffee may enhance health. Upon reviewing the characteristics of coffee the presence of carbohydrates, minerals, and phenolic acid suggest the possibility of potential health benefits but apparently not substantial enough to be noteworthy

No reference to acid in the tea so I&apos;d say from the above information that coffee has more acid. tea contains tannic acid. if one is a heavy tea drinker, they should avoid eating ice cream--it reacts with the acid&amp;causes gall stones or kidney stones or summthin like that---read about it a long time ago Both coffee and tea are categories of beverages. Each type of coffe can be brewed to different strengths and each type of tea can be steeped to different strengths. So, there is no categorical answer. I did extensive research on this very topic early in college. My findings are as follows:

One can drink several pots of tea with no discomfort, while that fourth of fifth cup of coffee can bring a grown man to his knees faster than Darth Vader&apos;s force choke.

Definitely coffee. vinegar!! coffee! 


 
 Read this: All the information of cooking and health post by website user,chineseop.com not guarantee
correctness,It&apos;s Non-profit and only for informational purposes. 
PRE: When did we first start drinking cocoa in the UK?  NEXT: Bigelow tea? 

Related Question about Food and Health
 Bottled water addendum? 
Bottled water addendum? further to my question about bottled water has anyone no...
 WHAT ARE the BENEFITS OF EATING JACKET POTATOES FOR BREAKFAST AND LUNCH? 
WHAT ARE the BENEFITS OF EATING JACKET POTATOES FOR BREAKFAST AND LUNCH? extra c...
 What&apos;s your Weirdest Food Combination? 
Ive had some really weird ones. Anyone ever try French Toast stix with ketchup o...
 Whats good to each for lunch at work? 
Whats good to each for lunch at work? i need somethin to eat that wont give me g...
 Why is it okay to eat fish during lent, but not meat? 
Why is it okay to eat fish during lent, but not meat? Answers: Fish is meat and ...
 What vegetarian items would you want at a fast food restaurant? 
What vegetarian items would you want at a fast food restaurant? To start off wit...
 Has anyone got any ideas for recipes etc for me to use in my new juicer? 
I like a nice juice cocktail made with spinach, swiss chard, carrots, celery, gr...
 In home canning, what is the reason (scientific?) for advice to not can mixed ve 
In home canning, what is the reason (scientific?) for advice to not can mixed ve...
 

Popular Question about Food and Health
 I&apos;ve heard that people make coffee out of Chicory, is this true? My passion fruit vine is loaded with fruit. How can I make use of them (Essex , What the hell should i eat? What do you think of cruise vacations? Would you get into a giant tub of? Favorite thing from chinese take out? What condiments do you eat on your canned beans? What is a foolproof way to season a cast-iron skillet? 
 
 About | Contact | Sitemap | Top 
©2007 - 2008 chineseop.com Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
