<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005141" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/25917690/Frommer-s-National-Parks-of-the-American-West" time="2012-07-12-21:40" support="3" score="0.001576049027513612" bingtitle="Frommer&apos;s National Parks of the American West" webtitle="Frommer&apos;s National Parks of the American West">
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>A 2 Exploring the Park by Car You can see many of the park’s most famous rock formations through your car windows. After leaving the visitor center. and several easy ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Buy Now You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 16 to 63 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 79 to 213 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 229 to 336 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 352 to 507 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 523 to 530 are not shown in this preview. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Frommer&apos;s National Parks of the American West
 More than 65 million people visit the national parks annually-and overcrowding has become a serious problem. So we sent our authors out to hit the trails and campsites to figure... ( More ) More than 65 million people visit the national parks annually-and overcrowding has become a serious problem. So we sent our authors out to hit the trails and campsites to figure out how to beat the crowds and enjoy an unspoiled experience of nature. Our authors take you to the most spectacular landscapes in the western U.S. and provide advice for every kind of park visitor, from the day-tripper who wants to see the highlights quickly to the back-country camper to the families traveling with kids. This incredibly detailed, complete guide covers every kind of activity available in each park, from hiking to bird watching, with a range of sports for visitors of all ages and skill levels. Completely updated, this new edition ofFrommer&apos;s National Parks of the American West also includes reviews of park lodges, camping, and nearby accommodations to help you plan all aspects of your trip. Exact prices are listed for every establishment and activity. No other guide offers such detailed, candid reviews...or such honest advice. Complete with maps of every park, including detailed maps of hiking trails in the major parks.List of Maps. 1 Planning Your Trip to the National Parks of the American West. 2 Arches National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 3 Badlands National Park (Jack Olson). 4 Big Bend National Park (Eric Peterson). 5 Black Canyon of the Gunnison National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 6 The Black Hills: Mount Rushmore National Memorial, Wind Cave National Park, Jewel Cave National Monument&amp;Custer State Park (Jack Olson). 7 Bryce Canyon National Park&amp;Grand Staircase– Escalante National Monument (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 8 Canyonlands National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 9 Capitol Reef National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 10 Carlsbad Caverns National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 11 Channel Islands National Park (Eric Peterson). 12 Crater Lake National Park (Eric Peterson). 13 Death Valley National Park&amp;Mojave National Preserve (Eric Peterson). 14 Devils Tower National Monument (Eric Peterson). 15 Glacier National Park&amp;Waterton Lakes National Park (Eric Peterson). 16 Grand Canyon National Park (Shane Christensen). 17 Grand Teton National Park (Eric Peterson). 18 Great Basin National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 19 Great Sand Dunes National Park&amp;Preserve (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 20 Guadalupe Mountains National Park (Eric Peterson). 21 Joshua Tree National Park (Eric Peterson). 22 Lassen Volcanic National Park (Eric Peterson). 23 Mesa Verde, Hovenweep, Chaco&amp;Other Archaeological Sites of the Four Corners Region (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 24 Mount Rainier National Park (Eric Peterson). 25 North Cascades National Park (Jack Olson). 26 Olympic National Park (Eric Peterson). 27 Petrified Forest National Park (Eric Peterson). 28 Point Reyes National Seashore (Eric Peterson). 29 Redwood National&amp;State Parks (Eric Peterson). 30 Rocky Mountain National Park (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). 31 Saguaro National Park (Eric Peterson). 32 Sequoia&amp;Kings Canyon National Parks (Eric Peterson). 33 Theodore Roosevelt National Park (Jack Olson). 34 Yellowstone National Park&amp;Little Bighorn Battlefield National Monument (Eric Peterson). 35 Yosemite National Park (Eric Peterson). 36 Zion National Park&amp;Cedar Breaks National Monument (Don&amp;Barbara Laine). Appendix A: A Field Guide. Appendix B: Useful Toll-Free Numbers&amp;Websites.  Index.Residents of northern New Mexico since 1970,Don and Barbara Laine have traveled extensively throughout the Rocky Mountains and the Southwest, spending as much time as possible in the outdoors. They have written Frommer’s guides to Utah, Colorado, and Zion and Bryce Canyon national parks. The Laines have also authoredLittle-Known Southwest andBest Short Hikes in Arizona for The Mountaineers; andThe New Mexico Guide for Fulcrum Publishing. A Denver-based freelance writer,Eric Peterson has contributed to numerous Frommer’s guides covering the American West, and written ( Less ) 2,107 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 01/27/2010 Copyright: Traditional Copyright: All rights reserved Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Read book online. Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
