<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005249" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g30620-d543894-Reviews-Zaxby_s-Huntsville_Alabama.html" time="2012-07-12-21:47" support="2" score="0.002592643712143761" bingtitle="Zaxby&apos;s, Huntsville - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor" webtitle="Zaxbys, Huntsville - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>... fast food restuarant. they brought my food to me ... I visited this fast food restaurant with my children, husband ... are indeed a good value - about $5.40 drink ...</description>
	<body>
		Zaxby&apos;s, Huntsville
 
 Home Huntsville 
 Huntsville Tourism Huntsville Hotels Flights to Huntsville Huntsville Restaurants Things to Do in Huntsville Huntsville Travel Forum Huntsville Photos Huntsville Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Alabama (AL) &gt; Huntsville &gt; Huntsville Restaurants &gt; Zaxby&apos;s 
 
 All 184 Huntsville Restaurants» 
Zaxby&apos;s
 1025 N Memorial Pkwy , Huntsville , AL 35810 256 551 0122 Menu 1 visitor photo Ranked #61 of 184 restaurants in Huntsville 18 Reviews Cuisines: American Most recent review “Upscale Fastfood” - Jul 5, 2012 Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
18 reviews from our community
 61% Recommend 
 Excellent 5 Very good 6 Average 4 Poor 2 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 18 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any Katie A Huntsville, Alabama Reviewer 5 reviews 1 helpful vote “Upscale Fastfood” Reviewed July 5, 2012 
It was satisfying. My first experience was a employee lunch, they forgot something in our order but they made up for it with fresh ingredients.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? b b Meridianville, Alabama Senior Contributor 41 reviews 6 helpful votes “Good chicken” Reviewed June 28, 2012 
Everyone is nice and friendly. Food is good for the money you pay.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Coe35 Madison, Alabama Top Contributor 51 reviews 21 helpful votes “Good service, good food.” Reviewed May 30, 2012 
For fast food, this is a cut above...service was excellent during our visit and atmosphere was good. If you&apos;re looking for something better than McDonalds or Burger King, here it is...
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? YvonneB_71 Huntsville, Alabama Contributor 16 reviews 17 helpful votes “Good if you like chicken” Reviewed May 14, 2012 
I LOVE the big Zax snack! Their Zax sauce is so yummy.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Lovegooddining Huntsville, Alabama Senior Contributor 28 reviews 6 helpful votes “Consistant value and chicken” Reviewed April 4, 2012 
Always like the chicken fingers. Best chicken fingers for fast food.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? VJohnson2 Fort Washington, Maryland Reviewer 4 reviews 1 helpful vote “wonderful service” Reviewed February 15, 2012 
not your ordinary fast food restuarant. they brought my food to me on real dishes. awesome!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? butchAlabama Alabama Senior Contributor 46 reviews 8 helpful votes “Really, Chicken Fingers?” Reviewed February 7, 2012 
Lacks anything to distinguish it from a school cafeteria
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Bob95FXDL Clarksville, Tennessee Contributor 15 reviews 36 helpful votes “Great for a Quick Lunch” Reviewed December 15, 2011 
Zaxby&apos;s is second only to Chik Fil-A. Portions are good-sized and taste is excellent. Like Chik Fil-A, the counter personnel actually listen to what you ask for without interrupting to ask about sizes sides, and drinks (unlike McD, BK, etc.).
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? KCBandBAB Annapolis, Maryland Contributor 16 reviews 10 helpful votes “What&apos;s not to like?” Reviewed December 8, 2011 
Zaxby&apos;s is amazing. The Nibblerz meal is phenomenal, but pretty high up there in WW points values!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? jenmc8 Senior Reviewer 8 reviews “This place is incredible!!!” Reviewed August 4, 2011 
I visited this fast food restaurant with my children, husband and in-laws. As soon as I walked in I was greeted by very friendly and courteous staff. I had never been to a Zaxby&apos;s before and the person taking my order suggested different menu items he thought I might like. He was very helpful in suggesting what the children would... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? 1-10 of 18 reviews « 1 2 » 
Travelers who viewed Zaxby&apos;s also viewed
 Ruth&apos;s Chris Steak House 48 Reviews Huntsville, AL
	</body>
</document>
