<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005128" url="http://couponbycategory.info/restaurant/how-to-deal-with-a-customer-thats-yells-at-you-at-fast-food-restaurant-job/" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="18" score="0.040194123885040775" bingtitle="how to deal with a customer that’s yells at you at fast food ..." webtitle="how to deal with a customer thats yells at you at fast food restaurant job?">
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001169" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="109"/>
	<description>... that’s yells at you at fast food restaurant job? sometimes we mess about an order or ... say am sorry ill get u a new order then tell ... They’re trash. Let them yell and ...</description>
	<body>
		The Best Coupons By Category 
 
how to deal with a customer that’s yells at you at fast food restaurant job?
 by admin on Wednesday, January 11th, 2012 | 30 Comments 
by tcp909 
 Question by dani : how to deal with a customer that’s yells at you at fast food restaurant job? 
sometimes we mess about an order or things just go wrong and some people freak out and yell at me/other employees and i don’t know how to handle it.

 Best answer: 

 Answer by ♥Maya♥ 
y would they yell at u?? there RuDe!! omg u should say am sorry ill get u a new order then tell them not to yell at u! best answer????

 Know better? Leave your own answer in the comments! 

Some cool fast food deals images:
 Posted in Restaurant Tags: Customer , deal , Fast , Food , Restaurant , that&apos;s , yells 
 
 SOFA 2009 (Sculptural Objects and Functional Art) » « La Jolla Shores Hotel | 8110 Camino Del Oro La Jolla California 
30 Responses to“how to deal with a customer that’s yells at you at fast food restaurant job?”
 
 ldyblucpl says: at 3:14 pm 
Sometimes people are just jerks, sometimes people are just really tired of poor service, and this makes them snap. Apologize, fix it, maybe give them something free. If the still rant, just look them in the eye and try not to respond. Most people just vent and want to say what they got to say. When they stop yelling say something like,“Again, I really apologize for our mistake, we have done our best to fix the situation. Thank You”and then walk away, if possible.
 REB says: at 4:11 pm 
I know it isn’t right for them to yell at you, what I have learned is to stay calm and keep a low soft toned voice b/c if you yell back, they will yell more, but a soft answer turns away wrath and usually calm them down to the tone you are in. I worked for WalMart and the rule was“The customer is always right”, so you try to satisfy the customer and don’t take it personal because it really is not. Some people are hot tempered and you just have to do your best to calm them down like I said by being calm yourself and if that doesn’t work, simply say sir or ma’am, I can see your upset let me get my manager for you and get them to handle it if you are not able, that is what they are there for. Hope this helps some, I have been in customer service for years and can honestly say as long as I remained calm and pleasant, the customer calmed down also and often apologized for their behavior, their are always that small percentage that no matter what you do it doesn’t matter b/c it is just they way they are and you just have to listen and if you can’t help them call a manager or someone higher in authority than yourself.
 peace&amp;love;&lt;3 says: at 4:32 pm 
just try to be pleasant with them and apologize as much as you can. if you messed up, you can’t really blame them for being upset.
 baudkarma says: at 5:17 pm 
That’s something your manager should handle. The minute he or she hears someone raising their voice, they should be there to find out what’s going on. It’s bad for morale if employees feel like they have to put up with a customers abuse just because they made a mistake.

Next time a customer yells, ask them once, very nicely, to please lower their voice. If they refuse, go get the manager and let them handle it.
 barracuda says: at 6:12 pm 
Make them look like the fools. Just explain everything calmly to them, smile, and get the manager if you can. Some people are coming in to start a fight, or they’re divas. They’re trash. Let them yell and scream.
 Gixaw says: at 6:59 pm 
Some people are just idiotic about simple matters. So what if you or someone else made a mistake. Let them rant on and let off some steam. Then offer them something free, if they still continue then let them go. If they have some decency they will realize that they are making a scene that is most likely annoying the other people in the restaurant. But try not to get irritated with them, because that rarely solves a problem.
 Heather says: at 7:26 pm 
Kick them out!!!!!!
 Autumn Storm says: at 7:49 pm 
Talk really loudly and maybe the jackasses will take a hint!
 Anne says: at 8:09 pm 
when people do stupid things like that it is not a reflection on you and your Performance, it is a reflection on them and how childish they can be.

my best advice is to remain polite, apologize for the mistake and offer to correct the order. if they get too rude, it may be best that your manager handle the situation.
 Carl says: at 8:43 pm 
Tell them very politely that a mistake was made and that yelling at people who are preparing food that they are going to eat may not be the most intelligent thing to do. (hint ! hint!) unless they like Lugie burgers.
 Kroptonik says: at 8:55 pm 
go get your manager! its not your job to deal with that shit
 bectasy2004 says: at 9:07 pm 
Apologize to them, fix the mistake and ask if there is anything else you can do for them..If they do not calm down, tell them you will let them speak to your manager. Let your manager handle it from there. That is what the manager is for. It is not up to you to handle situations after you have corrected the mistake. It turns over to the manager then.
Always remain calm though when dealing with this type of customers.
 supbasket says: at 9:43 pm 
well i would probubly just yell back or get the manager…
 kandyland says: at 10:02 pm 
It was your mistake, not theirs. Don’t let it get over you. It is not a big deal. All you have to do is to say sorry and get the right order for them. That is how customers are sometime. They are not as friendly as you expect them to be.
 Eich says: at 10:42 pm 
If a person has a complaint, ask them what’s wrong then let them know you will do your best to fix their problem. Keep your cool. If the situation gets out of control, get your manager or shift leader to handle the problem.

Remember, always remain calm. You will be fine.
 Bert says: at 10:46 pm 
yell back at them and spit in thier food.
 driytchie says: at 11:15 pm 
Step a side, and get a Manager. That is what they get pd., for.
 Nita says: at 11:22 pm 
some people are just jerks! Just take the heat and try and fix their order
 Fat Tay says: at 11:46 pm 
Okay, this is a little complicated but I know someone who did it. When the customer leaves, follow them out and write down their license plate number. Hire a private detective to gather information on the person (it’s not really too expensive). My friend did this and found out the guy who yelled at him was a convicted pedophile. He also found out he worked as a mechanic for the county. So my friend shows up where this idiot works and starts screaming at him. He started yelled about how child molestors shouldn’t be working for the county. He got escorted away but the the guy ended up getting fired for lying on his job application.
 girl87 says: at 12:40 am 
i work as a waitress for a long long time. from my past experiences, (especially on a busy night) when i ordered the wrong food, and the customer was mad and almost wreck the place, the first thing i did was, i apologized, then i explained to the person that you will do something about it right away (replacing it). if the person is still yelling at you and be rude to you, please say softly but firmly, we can solve the problem if you can just coorperate with me. this is what i did and the person seemed to give in and stop yelling because i addressed her and she understood that she would get a new course without any charge. if that person is still yelling at you and do not keep his or her cool? you can talk to your manager. sometimes, customers like that, i feel like i just want to let them go.
 RandomMacaroons says: at 1:37 am 
two ways to handle:

1. if you want to keep your job:
Apologise for messing things up and say that you’d fix it up immediately. Just make sure you don’t look so pitiful. Be confident when you say sorry, tell the guy you’re sorry. but you ain’t sucking up to him.

2. if you don’t want your job anymore:
ask the customer to get a life for being so impatient with you.
 Karamazov says: at 2:25 am 
TAlk to your manager
or threaten to call the poloice if he keeps it up ( or her)
 Elle Ann says: at 2:30 am 
oh i’ve dealt with these kind of A$ $ holes just tell them you’ll get another one as quickly as possible but in the sweetest voice possible and no matter how much they yell you keep that tone…its no fun for them if you’re not yelling back
 Partyplanner21 says: at 3:10 am 
Some people have such pitiful, pathetic lives that the only way they can feel better about themselves is by taking out their frustration and anger on someone in a position they view as “servitude,” or less than them. Ask management what their policy is on customers who are abusive. Do they condone the abuse of their employees? If so, this is not a place you want to work. Once you know that management’s on YOUR side, you can put these people in their place by apologizing once, but adding that management’s policy does not condone the behavior of customers who insult employees and they will be asked to leave the restaurant if they can’t act in a civil manner.”

You don’t have to take workplace harassment – that’s abuse, and it’s against the law. But, also, ask yourself if you’re at your best on the job. Can handle the work or are you messing up out of pure laziness? If you’re messing up orders, or if you’re being rude to customers and they are reacting, then you should reconsider the fast food industry as a vocation and consider going into something with less customer interaction.

But if someone is harassing you for no reason, you certainly don’t have to take that.
 Oneida says: at 3:35 am 
Very directly.
Apologize 1 time and correct the order.
The rudeness of persons can not be anticipated.
Stand up. If it continues do not tolerate it. If your manager does not step up for you then find another that will.
No you do not need to be a victim ot rudeness.
What ever the reason is.
 Stephen E says: at 3:50 am 
tell them f off and get fired
 scott b says: at 4:13 am 
Sometimes people have other things going on in their lives that cause them to take out their anger and frustrations on undeserving people.So when they place an order and it is wrong it opens a door to get pissed and take out their frustrations for all of their anger on the closest person for the the stupidest of reasons.

So I would think when I the next time you get a rude customer that over reacts is that maybe they are being rude because their life sucks and it is giving them a perverted pleasure to make your life,if even for a brief moment,as miserable as their life is.Smile,apologize,appear sympathetic and relate to them on their level.”yes,sir/ma’am I know your frustration,it drives me nuts when it happens to me.”Kill them with kindness and show them their attitude/anger doesn’t bother you. Throw in an apple pie or a dessert with their replaced order,things like that often help to calm them down and see that you really are sorry for their inconvenience.Mind you it is an inconvenience to the customer that they have to come back to get the order corrected.Getting angry right back at them or letting them see that they are making you angry only feeds into their negative energy and could create a bigger problem. Tell yourself ,”it’s just burgers and fries it isn’t a matter of life and death.”Then, think about all of the pleasant customers you have helped.Or think of something positive to get you past that rude person that took your head off because the people in the back accidentally put onions on a burger when the ticket said no onions.Big deal,it’s just burgers and fries……….mistakes happen.it won’t be the first mistake and most importantly will not be the last.Don’t let the jerks of the world get you down
 Cutie Pie says: at 4:31 am 
wow thats awful. ive worked a lot of fast food to pay for univ. and ive only been yelled at once, but ibe been reprimanded by customers, and they can be condescending and rude in any customer service position. you need to take it with a grain of salt. also check the food before you served it make sure its even serveable and double check to make sure everything is there. if there is still a problem and the customer is upset just take it with a grain of salt and grab your manager. They are there to deal with bitchy customers, thats not your job, its theirs. Just apologize for the inconvinience and grab your manager and all will be fine.
 kewlkitty82_2000 says: at 5:21 am 
Just don’t let it get to you. There are a lot of people who probably just have bad attitudes. I had one lady a couple of weeks ago scream at me and my manager, and called both of us wenches. I just had to keep my cool, because she was probably having a bad night. If it gets even more serious, where they come by all the time, and is constantly acting the same way, your company has the right to refuse their service. just politely let them know that they cant treat you guys that way, and tell them that they will have to go to a different location.
 Parkwoodman says: at 5:28 am 
I’ve experienced that same scenario, when I worked at McDonald’s. The customer felt he was justified to rail on me for a mistake. I excused myself from the customer and searched for the Assistant and/or Manager and had the customer yell and scream at them. They are more experienced in handling hot heads and I stand back to see how they do it.
 
 
 
Categories

 Automobile Books Department Stores Food&amp;Wine Home&amp;Garden Jewelry Luggage Music Online Pet Supplies Pinterest Pizza Printable Restaurant Shoes Sports Toys 
 
Tags
 2011 anyone BEST Black book Cool Coupon Coupons deal deals find Food Free friday from Garden good Great HELP home images Latest Luggage Men&apos;s Music News Nice Online Part photos Pizza Printable Review Reviews shoe Shoes Size Sports store this Tool toys Video Watch Women&apos;s 

 
 
 

 

 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 
 
 

 

 

 
 
Powered by Yahoo! Answers
	</body>
</document>
