<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005214" url="http://www.franchisegator.com/Mexican-Food-Franchises/" time="2012-07-12-21:45" support="2" score="0.00264875791017967" bingtitle="Mexican food franchise opportunities - Mexican fast food business ..." webtitle="Mexican food franchise opportunities -  Mexican fast food business for sale">
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000044" bing-rank="162"/>
	<description>You’re not going to find our recipes in a cookbook – we use the same recipes that America’s ... I would like to receive the Franchise Gator newsletter</description>
	<body>
		Franchise Opportunities 
 Mexican Food Franchise Opportunities Connecting people with franchise and business opportunities since 2002 
 Home Franchise Industries Mexican Food Franchise Opportunities 
 Bookmark 
Franchise Selector

Search over 300 Franchises.
 Select Industry Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Canadian Cheap Children&apos;s Cleaning&amp;Maintenance Computer&amp;Internet Education Food Franchise Services Health&amp;Fitness Healthcare&amp;Senior Care High Capital Home Based Business Home Services Low Cost Mobile Multi Unit and Area Developer Personnel&amp;Staffing Pet Retail SBA Approved Small Business Sports&amp;Recreation Travel, Cruise&amp;Hotel Veteran&apos;s Women&apos;s Select Location Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Puerto Rico Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virgin Islands, U.S. Virginia Washington Washington, D.C. West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Select Capital $10,000 $20,000 $30,000 $40,000 $50,000 $60,000 $70,000 $80,000 $90,000 $100,000 $150,000 $200,000 $250,000 $300,000 $350,000 $400,000 $450,000 $500,000 $550,000 $600,000 $650,000 $700,000 $750,000 $1,000,000 + 
 
Franchise Newsletter

Free insider information.
 
 Food Franchises 
 
 Bagel Bakery Bar-Grill-Pub Barbeque Burger Cafe Candy Vending Catering Coffee/Espresso Commercial Coffee/Espresso Machines Cookie and Candy Business Deli Fast Food Food - Canadian Fried Chicken Frozen Yogurt Gourmet Ice Cream Italian Restaurant Juice Mexican Food Nutrition Pizza Prepared Meals Quick Casual Restaurant Smoothie Sub Sandwich Taco Take N Bake Vending Machine Distributorship Wing 
 
Top Industries

 Business Opportunities Cheap Franchises Food Franchises Home Based Franchises Children&apos;s Franchises 
 
 All Industries 
 
Franchise Links

 A-Z Franchise List Franchise Newsletter 
 
Franchise Services

 Franchise Consultant To Buy A Business Franchise Financing Franchise Merchant and Consulting Services Franchise Your Business 
 
Franchise Articles

 Starting a Franchise Business Buying a Franchise Franchise CEO Interviews All Franchising Articles Franchise Press 
 
Franchise Favorites

 Franchising FAQ&apos;s Business Tools Franchise Events 
 
Mexican Food Franchise Opportunities
 Welcome to Franchise Mexican Food Franchise Directory. Entrepreneurs interested in Mexican fast food franchise opportunities can find in-depth details on owning a variety of restaurants focusing on cuisine featuring Burritos, Tacos, Queso and more! Read below to learn more about Mexican and other food Franchise Opportunities and restaurant Business for sale listings!

Didnt find what you were looking for? Check out the rest of the franchises we have available.

 
 
Franchises
 America&apos;s Taco Shop® At Americas Taco Shop, we offer a dining experience unlike that of your typical quick-service restaurant. To put it simply, were passionate about good food. Youre not going to find our recipes in a cookbook we use the same recipes that Americas family has perfected in their kitchens for generations. 
 Liquid Capital Required :
 $90,000
 Carl&apos;s Jr. With a delicious menu and instant brand recognition, its easy to see why Carls Jr. is known as Americas premier burger chain. We are looking for experienced operators to join our team. By providing world-class training and support, this turn-key opportunity has been designed with your success in mind. Contact us today to learn more! 
 Liquid Capital Required :
 $500,000
 Taco John&apos;s Do you dream of owning the hottest restaurant in town? Then Taco Johns is the perfect franchise opportunity! Our extensive training and marketing programs, successful business model and popular menu are second to none! Contact us today and see why were the BOLDEST franchise opportunity around! 
 Liquid Capital Required :
 $200,000
   
Articles Related To Mexican Food Franchises:
 
 Moe&apos;s Southwest Grill Serves Turkey? 
March 17, 2011
Not that kind of Turkey, silly. They now have their first restaurant open in Istanbul, Turkey. Master licensee and president and CEO of DOTS Food David Ergisi just opened the new Moe&apos;s in popular tourist destination, the Sapphire Towers. The second Turkey location will open in late spring at the Marmara Forum Mall. These are only 2 of the 21 planned locations over the next 5 years.  Read more 
 
 Kids eat free at hundreds of California restaurants Tuesday 
September 28, 2010
Families across California are invited to take part in Family Day celebrations, including dining out in one of the hundreds of participating restaurants throughout the state offering free kids meals on Tuesday during the hours of 4 to 8 p.m. Nearly 1,000 restaurants will offer a free kids meals with the purchase of an adult entre (limited to two per table) during the statewide celebration.  Read more 
 
 Margaritas Mexican Restaurant Named Tops in New England 
September 15, 2010
Margaritas Mexican Restaurant Named Tops in New England  Read more 
 
Request More Info
 Selected Companies: 0 All Fields Required Select Liquid Capital $10,000 $20,000 $30,000 $40,000 $50,000 $60,000 $70,000 $80,000 $90,000 $100,000 $150,000 $200,000 $250,000 $300,000 $350,000 $400,000 $450,000 $500,000 $550,000 $600,000 $650,000 $700,000 $750,000 $1,000,000 + Select Timeframe 1-3 months 3-6 months 6+ months Select Franchise Location International Location Canadian Location Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District Of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Puerto Rico Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Alberta British Columbia Manitoba New Brunswick Newfoundland Northwest Territories Nova Scotia Nunavut Ontario Prince Edward Island Quebec Saskatchewan Yukon 
 Add Comments 
 I would like to receive the
Franchise Gator newsletter 
Franchise Gator is a highly trusted leader in the franchise industry. Since 2002, we have helped our visitors gather quality franchise information. Your information will only be shared with the franchises you have selected. We NEVER share or sell your information to anyone other than the specific businesses you have requested. 

 Please view our privacy policy .


 


 
 
 
 Copyright©2001 - 2012 Franchise Gator. All Rights Reserved. 
 Advertiser Info Privacy Statement Terms of Use Sitemap Press 
 Follow us: 
 
 Directory Search By Industry 
 Automotive Franchises 
 Business Opportunities 
 Business Services 
 Cheap Franchises 
 Children&apos;s Franchises 
 Cleaning&amp;Maintenance Franchises 
 Computer&amp;Internet Franchises 
 Education Franchises 
 Food Franchises Health&amp;Fitness Franchises 
 Healthcare&amp;Senior Care Franchises 
 High Capital Franchises 
 Home Based Business Franchises 
 Home Services Franchises 
 Low Cost Franchises 
 Multi Unit&amp;Area Developer Franchises 
 Mobile Franchises 
 Personnel&amp;Staffing Franchises 
 Pet Franchises 
 Retail Franchises 
 SBA Approved Franchises 
 Small Business Franchises 
 Sports&amp;Recreation Franchises 
 Top Franchise Lists 
 Travel, Cruise&amp;Hotel Franchises 
 Veteran&apos;s Franchises 
 Women&apos;s Franchises 
 Search By State Search By Investment Franchise Videos Blog 
 Tweet 
 About Franchise Gator Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
