<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005505" url="http://english-finance.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:04" support="2" score="0.0011703108392865905" bingtitle="Plain English Auto Financial Tips for the Lay Man" webtitle="Plain English Auto Financial Tips for the Lay Man">
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>You cannot afford not to have a car, but the cost ... If you were to buy something for dinner from a fast food restaurant ... And meals cooked fresh to order are always better.</description>
	<body>
		Plain English Auto Financial Tips for the Lay Man 
 Wealth of information relating to Car Leasing and Finance 
Recent Posts

 How to Pay Less per Month on Your Next Car The enjoyment of a car. The Independents–America’s Last Holdout Auto Manufacturers Look for Unique Ways to Save Money on Car Insurance Buy the premium gas! 
 
Archives

 June 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 
 
 How to Pay Less per Month on Your Next Car 
 Author: June 30, 2010 
You cannot afford not to have a car, but the cost of owning a car can almost drive anyone insane. There are several different ways to go about saving money on owning a car. I’m going to attempt to go into each one briefly.

The easiest way to save money on your car is to shop around. Oftentimes you can find a vehicle that meets your specifications at a better deal. You may find a brand new vehicle of a model that you are looking for but it’s last years model. You can save thousands off the sticker price this way.

It’s also advisable to not buy a new car. Experts say that new vehicle can depreciate as much as twenty percent within the first year of ownership. Most vehicles are designed to hold up well nowadays and you can always save money by buying well maintained vehicles that are only a couple of model years old.

There are times when it can be advisable to refinance your car. Lower interest rates equate to less money paid over the course of you loan. This is especially true if you are able to keep your payoff date the same. If you simply need to have lower monthly payments, you can refinance for a longer period which will lower your monthly payment.

It is also very advisable to do your homework when it comes to insurance. You can save up to thirty percent of your monthly insurance payments by shopping around, and there is a plethora of companies that will give you quotes over the internet in a matter of a few minutes. You can also save alot of money by increasing your deductable. Changing your deductible from five hundred to one thousand dollars can save you as much as four hundred dollar per year.

Anyone looking to save money on a vehicle needs to make sure to buy a vehicle with good gas mileage. You can save almost a thousand dollars a year if you trade your twenty mile per gallon car in for one that gets thirty miles per gallon. You can also increase your miles per gallon in your current vehicle by accelerating smoothly, and braking in moderation. Using your cruise control to maintain vehicle speed improves your gas mileage and paying attention to speed limits allow you to reap the benifits of higher miles per gallon.


 read comments (0) 
 The enjoyment of a car. 
 Author: April 5, 2010 
Having an automobile is a luxury some people don’t have the pleasure of enjoying. The ease and convenience of being able to jump in the car and go can be somewhat empowering. No line at the bus stop or having to plan your movements around somebody’s schedule. The independence you feel behind the wheel of your own car is one of the greatest joys. When you have the ability to keep your life moving in a timely fashion it means more time to get out there and indulge in the simple things that help keep you in the best frame of mind and can contribute to a more fulfilling personal experience.

Nothing can beat having access to a car when you are planning that outing to visit friends and family that may be just around the corner or halfway across the country. Loading up you vehicle with all your personal favorites and hitting the highway just to get away from it all is a treat to many families. Obvious other means of transportation are available to get you to your desired destination, but choosing to go in a car is the absolute best way if you want to be in total control of your journey. Being able to travel through different states and regions, taking your time to enjoy the scenery or stop off at your favorite eatery adds more fun in you travels. Weather you enjoy those winding mountain roads or scenic beach drives, traveling in a car gives you the ability to control your experiences and create your own wonderful memories. Just driving along the route which you’ve chosen, wind blowing in your hair, is enough to make most motorist truly enjoy their cars and the freedom it gives.

Minus a few negative aspect of car ownership, like gas prices and maintenance, owning a car is quite fulfilling. It is not just a mode of transportation it can be a hobby. The pride one takes in their car is relevant by the appearance as well as the performance. Beautiful custom paint jobs, big shiny rims, plush interiors, and audio visual systems that most would love to have in their homes, so just how much fun you can have pampering your vehicle. Owning a car and being able to express yourself by it appearance and the control you have over you own movements may just throw cars up there as necessity rather than just luxury.


 read comments (0) 
 The Independents–America’s Last Holdout Auto Manufacturers 
 Author: March 7, 2010 
Until the 1950s and 1960s the United States had several car manufacturers that were called the independents. These were truly the orphaned brands that continued to manufacture cars and trucks even though the big three had taken over the majority of vehicle production. Although Ford, General Motors and Chrysler manufactured the majority of cars in the United States several small manufacturers held on through the late 1950s and 60s. The stories of these independents are all but forgotten today and the cars are long past into salvage yards and museum collections.

Studebaker

Once a major car manufacturer the Studebaker Company survived long past its expected funeral. The company produced its last American cars in 1963 but held on in Canada to produce cars through 1967. Many Studebakers were designed by American iconic designer Raymond Loewy. His designs for Studebaker included the Avanti that debuted in 1963 and actually continued in production three decades after Studebaker had shuttered its U.S. plants. Studebaker was known for its reliability and quality throughout most of its history. Financial difficulties in the late fifties led to a merger with Packard and the resulting influx of cash allowed the company to survive a few more years. Between 1957 and 1963 Studebaker provided the sales channels for most Mercedes automobiles in the United States.

International Harvester

A manufacturer of tractors and farm equipment the International harvester Corporation also produced trucks and utility vehicles into the mid seventies. The Travelall, Scout and Travelette were all road going vehicles produced by IH during its passenger vehicle heyday from the late 1950s through the 1970s. International harvester also employed the design talents of Raymond Loewy for assistance with its vehicles. International also built a line of light and medium duty pickup trucks up until the mid 1970s. These trucks were known for their ability to get through tough terrain however poor work quality and porous metals with rapid rusting tendencies doomed the company. With the gasoline crisis of the seventies looming the large and uneconomical utility vehicles built by International Harvester caused production to end. The tractor division continued on however.

American Motors

Still surviving today as a subsidiary of Chrysler/Fiat, Jeep is the last American Motors brand to survive. The company that was formed as the merger of Hudson and Nash took place in 1954. Jeep was acquired from Kaiser –Jeep in 1970 expanding the product lineup. The resulting company produced cars in the United States through the late eighties when Chrysler bought out the share of Renault, the French automaker and brought AMC, Jeep and Eagle into the Chrysler fold.

With the purchase of AMC by Chrysler in 1987 the big three of American auto manufacturers consolidated their holdings through the economic reshuffling of 2009.


 read comments (0) 
 Look for Unique Ways to Save Money on Car Insurance 
 Author: February 21, 2010 
Since fuel cost today is more likely to increase than decrease, people are searching unique ways to save money on car insurance. One major factor car owners are starting to review is the amount of money they are spending on car insurance. If you want to decrease the amount you are spending on insurance premiums each year, you might want to consider your insurance policy and your credit score. Also, you may want to look at other details that might cause your insurance premium to increase. You might want to consider a car that does not come with too many specifications because these normally contribute to increased insurance premiums.

If you are thinking about purchasing a vehicle that is known for its speed, insurance companies are going to automatically think you are the type of person that likes to drive fast. Vehicles likes this in an insurance adjuster’s eyes will demand more coverage than the average vehicle. You may also want to reconsider buying cars with extremely high theft rates that will more than likely demand a higher insurance premium. In addition, if you are able to provide a security system for your vehicle or provide secured parking, you can actually lower your premium.

When it comes to acquiring car insurance, you should always make sure you have a decent credit score . This will play a major role in determining whether you will be paying a higher insurance premium. If you have a really low score, you might want to start paying off some of your bills to increase your credit score. By just dedicating a little time to restructuring your credit score can save you hundreds on your car insurance. Insurance adjusters are going to use your credit score when they write up your policy, so it is best to increase it if you can. If you are currently covered and would like to renew your policy after it ends, your credit history will be reevaluated to determine your new car insurance premium.

The best thing to do when searching for car insurance is to look around until you find a policy that fits the rates you are looking for. You should make sure that you keep a copy of all insurance quotes so you can compare them later. Once you have found the right insurance coverage for your car, you should contact the insurance company to verify they are licensed to conduct business in your state. Also, you may want to review past complaints filed against the insurance company to guarantee the company is not defrauding its customers.


 read comments (0) 
 Buy the premium gas! 
 Author: February 2, 2010 
There are tons of different ways to save money on cars. The trick is following through on all these things. In this article we will go over three things you can do to save yourself as much money as possible on you vehicle. And lets face it, this article is really for everyone, because everyone could use saving a little money on their cars. So lets get you more informed.

The first tip is to read and follow you owners manual. Yeah, it’s that thing that has been in the glove box and used to kill spiders, prop things on and even use to fan yourself. But have you ever thought of actually reading it? This is the first step! This owners manual will go through a number of different things that your particular car needs on a regular basis to keep it running in the best possible working order.

The next things is to get regular oil changes and tune ups. These are easy things to let slip your mind and put off another couple hundred miles, but the reality of the situation is that if you’d like less problems with your car and a longer life then this is very important. Keeping it in fresh oil and a proper tune up just helps the car to run smoother and running smoother mean you burn less gas.

Speaking of gas, that is where out third tip comes in. Go ahead and splurge, buy the premium gas at the gas station. I know it cost more and you’re wondering why I am telling you to spend more to save more, but there is sense of this. If you were to buy something for dinner from a fast food restaurant, it’s most likely not going to be healthy for your body and might possibly taste bad. If you choose to instead buy your dinner from a price restaurant, you could ask that the chef cater toward making you meal healthy. And meals cooked fresh to order are always better. This is true for gas as well. If you invest now, in premium gas, the life of your vehicle will last much longer.

I hope these things helped you become more informed in lower the cost of owning a vehicle. There are many other things that can be done if you’re still trying to get the price lower than it currently is.


 read comments (0) 
 4-Wheel Drive vs. 2-Wheel Drive 
 Author: January 30, 2010 
This could be touchy subject matter when comparing the options for the drive-train of an auto. You see, those guys that think they are accomplishing something in buying that huge, 4-wheel drive truck that sits above all the cars on the highway like an semi-tractor have a problem that Freud would like to analyze. Anyway, the subject is cost comparison, not something else.

The traditional 2-wheel drive auto has served humankind for many model-year events, as where the 4-wheel drive became popular about the time that Bubba took your daughter to the Monster Truck Pull that summer. With the hype behind the superior performance of a 4-wheel drive vehicle apparently has not driven one a a solid sheet of ice during a Memphis winter storm. Believe me, that will separate the men from the boys when trying to maintain control of a Ford F-150 Super-cab 4WD along Elvis Presley Boulevard without sliding into a group of excited, and cold Elvis fanatics.

4WD, good for off-road situations, like taking Betty-Lou muddin’after the all-you-can-eat catfish fry at the Jaycee Banquet. 2WD, good for casual driving, not muddin’. There are money saving features of the 2WD opposed to the 4WD as well; the price of tires. Have you shopped for a set of Goodyear for a 4WD lately? Especially those with the tread that makes a sound like a Sherman tank coming down the street. So, that example shows the savings in one area of the two distinctions.

The last area of savings comparisons belongs to the that of auto insurance. Yep, the insurance companies rate the 4WD vehicles as a higher risk than 2WD, due in part for knowing that Bubba and Mary-Lou will be participating in the events aforementioned. So, shop and compare, do the math, and you will see the overall savings by investing in a 2WD vehicle. But, don’t take my word for it, read the literature available by browsing the Internet, or by contacting your tire store, insurance agent, and local car wash; for the removal of debris from the weekend spent muddin’with Bubba and Mary-Lou.


 read comments (0) Plain English Auto Financial Tips for the Lay Man
	</body>
</document>
