<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005247" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/01/30/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565.html?ref=food&amp;ncid=edlinkusaolp00000008" time="2012-07-12-21:46" support="1" score="0.0009178256698071405" bingtitle="Glendale-Fast Food Dispute: Southern California City Tries To Make ..." webtitle="Glendale-Fast Food Dispute: Southern California City Tries To Make Restaurant Signs Smaller">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>Glendale Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon. Glendale goes after oversized fast-food restaurant signs ... Support the Fit Kids Bill ... Oil Spill: Residents To Receive ...</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 Fast Food E. Coli Food Food Informants 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 42k Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k GOP Votes To Repeal Obamacare Again 21k Romney Campaign Releases New Ad Accusing Obama Of Spreading Lies 7k When Did Romney Leave Bain? 11k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Entertainment 
 Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 1k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 47 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 16 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 Business 
 WATCH: Evidence Ex-Wall Street Trader May Have Taken Cyanide 2k Here Are The 16 Banks Under Investigation Over The Libor Scandal 371 Paul Krugman Slams Times Colleague, CNBC 3k America&apos;s Best States to Live In 250 Evander Holyfield&apos;s Unable To Avoid Foreclosure On $14 Million Mansion 697 
 Like 34k   Go to Business More in Business 
 Small Business Money 
 You might also like 
 World Tech Media Culture Sports Weird News Crime 
 Media 
 Katie Couric Speaks Out About Ann Curry&apos;s &apos;Today&apos; Ouster 412 Gallup: Confidence In TV News At New Low 4k Anderson Cooper&apos;s Coming Out Was Planned For Months 264 WATCH: Greg Gutfeld Freaks Out 2k Katie Couric&apos;s Photo Shows Up In Unexpected Place 21 
 Like 46k   Go to Media More in Media 
 Eat The Press Calderone: The Backstory 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment TV Comedy Arts Books Religion Moviefone 
 Kitchen Daily 
 Beat The Heat With 15 No-Cook Meals 12 Ways To Turn Your Ugly Pie Into A Showstopper 43 Kitchen Trick: Preserve Fresh Herbs In Frozen Olive Oil 11 Rise And Shine: 10 Mouth-Watering Eggs Benedicts Food Debate: Does Ketchup Belong On Hot Dogs? 227 
 Like 37k   Go to Kitchen Daily More in Kitchen Daily 
 Recipes Baking Breakfast Chefs and Experts Entertaining Healthy Eating Dinner Tonight Easter Kitchen Daily Videos 
 You might also like 
 Food 
 Travel 
 PHOTOS: Guess Who Has The Worst Traffic? 459 Concordia Captain Makes Shocking Revelations 947 Boo: Now The World&apos;s Cutest Airline Spokesman 61 70-Year-Old Minister Takes 7000th Coaster Ride 53 Theme Park Sued For Barring Amputees From Coaster 79 
 Like 24k   Go to Travel More in Travel 
 Travel Video Destinations Themed Guides TSA Airlines 
 You might also like 
 Food Culture World GPS for the Soul Kitchen Daily 
 Green 
 PHOTOS: Adorable Baby Elephant Saved By Mother 361 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 245 A &apos;Snow Monster&apos; In Mount Rainier Creek 370 Young Man Mysteriously Found Dead Inside Tiger Den 80 Waldo Canyon Fire Fully Contained 98 
 Like 104k   Go to Green More in Green 
 Energy Climate Change Animals Green Tech Green Holiday 
 You might also like 
 Politics Food World Science Healthy Living 
 Tech 
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately 900 Is The U.S. Government Planning To Secret Super-Scanners? 525 The Mildly Fabulous Story Of The First Photo Posted To The Internet 209 WATCH: Conservative Group Calls For Boycott Of Google 1k Facebook Fires Yoga Teacher For Banning Smartphones In Class 527 
 Like 54k   Go to Tech More in Tech 
 Best of TED Social Media 
 You might also like 
 Small Business Green Science New York San Francisco TechCrunch Engadget Joystiq 
 Comedy 
 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh 896 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 16 15 Dogs Receiving The Best News Ever 46 WATCH: Awesome Slip &apos;N Slide Jump 
 Like 105k   Go to Comedy More in Comedy 
 Funny Videos Comedy Club Political Humor Original Videos Crossing The Line 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment Weird News College Arts Culture 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 Food 
 Recipes Chefs Restaurants Desserts Cocktails Wine Beer 
 
 
Glendale-Fast Food Dispute: Southern California City Tries To Make Restaurant Signs Smaller
 
 The Huffington Post     Joe Satran   
 First Posted: 01/30/2012 6:13 pm   Updated: 01/30/2012 9:43 pm 
 Follow   Fast Food ,   Video , Fast Food Advertising , Fast Food Billboards , Fast Food Glendale , Fast Food Industry , Fast Food Signs , Glendale , Glendale Fast Food , Glendale Fast Food Signs , Food News 
share this story
 Get Food Alerts Sign Up Submit this story digg reddit stumble 
A full 38 pages of Title 30 of the Municipal Code in Glendale, Calif., in Los Angeles county, are dedicated to the regulation of signs. The rules dictate the portion of a sign&apos;s height that is allowed to rise &quot;above any parapet or eave line&quot; (half), the body responsible for OKing murals (&quot;the design review board&quot;) and the required vertical plane angle on marquee signs (&quot;less than twenty (20) degrees&quot;).

But even Hammurabi&apos;s Code is useless if it&apos;s not enforced. And so it is with Title 30 of Glendale&apos;s Municipal Code. Since its 1995 adoption, restaurants in the San Fernando Valley city of 190,000 have openly flouted the size restrictions set forth in the law. There are now 60 pole-mounted restaurant signs in Glendale that are bigger than they&apos;re allowed to be -- most of them advertising major fast food chains.

Glendale&apos;s City Council, or at least a highly vocal contingent thereof, wants that to change.

&quot;It&apos;s a matter of aesthetics,&quot; Councilman Ara Najarian told the Glendale News-Press . &quot;These signs are something you see in East L.A.,&quot; referring to the downtrodden, largely Hispanic neighborhood 14 miles to Glendale&apos;s southeast.

The Council has actually been trying to get the restaurants to change their signs for years, but it&apos;s proven to be a complicated process than you would expect. In the past week, councilmembers have written a resolution that would take a harder stance. It&apos;s told restaurants that they have to make signs compliant with city code within the next two years.

But one aspect of the decision is ruffling feathers. The L.A. Times explains that businesses that do not plan to change their signage within the foreseeable future -- many of them large fast food chains with established graphic design strategies -- are exempt from the terms of the crackdown until March of 2014.

So a California town tries to fight the fast food with a high-profile municipal law and instead falls flat on its face. Sound familiar ?

 
Also on HuffPost:
 FOLLOW 
 HUFFPOST FOOD ON Facebook: Like 17k Twitter:   Get Alerts CONTRIBUTE TO THIS STORY 
 Send Corrections Send us a Link Contact us 

 Send a Tip Send Photos/Videos Comment 
 
 
 Fast Food Video 
 A full 38 pages of Title 30 of the Municipal Code in Glendale, Calif., in Los Angeles county, are dedicated to the regulation of signs. The rules dictate the portion of a sign&apos;s height that is allowed... A full 38 pages of Title 30 of the Municipal Code in Glendale, Calif., in Los Angeles county, are dedicated to the regulation of signs. The rules dictate the portion of a sign&apos;s height that is allowed... 
 Fast Food Video 
 A full 38 pages of Title 30 of the Municipal Code in Glendale, Calif., in Los Angeles county, are dedicated to the regulation of signs. The rules dictate the portion of a sign&apos;s height that is allowed... A full 38 pages of Title 30 of the Municipal Code in Glendale, Calif., in Los Angeles county, are dedicated to the regulation of signs. The rules dictate the portion of a sign&apos;s height that is allowed...   Loading... TOP LINKS ON THIS TOPIC 1 of 3 
 glendale Glendale-Fast Food Dispute: Southern California City Tries To Make Restaurant ... 
 
 Glendale Seeks to Shrink Signage at Fast Food Restaurants -- Grub Street Los Angeles 
 
 Glendale-Fast Food Dispute: Southern California City Tries To Make ...: A full 38 pages of Title 30 of the Munic... 
 
 Mediterranean Fast Food Restaurant Business Opportunity For Sale, Glendale, California, CA | BizBen 
 
 Foodista | City of Glendale, CA Fights Back Against Fast Food Signs 
 
 Glendale Seeks to Shrink Signage at Fast Food Restaurants: McDonald&apos;s: The Merrill Lynch of fa... via 
 
 Glendale Seeks to Shrink Signage at Fast... 
 
 Glendale City Councilman Ara Najarian apologizes to East L.A. community for sign comment - Glendale News Press 
 Around the Web: 

 Oversized Signs: Glendale to Go After Oversized Fast-Food Signs ... 

 VIDEO Oversized Sign Ban in Glendale watch Lynette Romero s ... 

 Glendale goes after oversized fast-food restaurant signs - latimes.com 

 Glendale Fast Food Places | Urbanspoon 

 Glendale goes after oversized fast-food restaurant signs 

 Report Corrections 
 More in Food... 

 Obesity in Asia: American Fast Food Changing... Marion Cunningham Dead: Home Cooking Guru, Dies... Coca-Cola Addiction: UK Teen Zoe Cross Hospitalized... Deep-Fried Samoa Girl Scout Cookies Ready For...     
 Comments 91 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 
Previewing Your Comment.
This comment has not yet been posted You have exceeded your word limit by   words. Please click the &quot;Edit&quot; button and shorten your comment.

 Post Comment Edit Cancel 

You can post to us this information Contact us Click here to leave a comment.

HuffPost High School welcomes a lively, thoughtful debate in the comment section. Keep in mind that the articles here are penned by young authors, so please keep criticism respectful, and help us to keep this a safe and supportive place for writers of all ages to contribute. Post Comment Preview Comment To reply to a Comment: Click &quot;Reply&quot; at the bottom of the comment; after being approved your comment will appear directly underneath the comment you replied to. Post Comment Preview Comment To reply to a Comment: Click &quot;Reply&quot; at the bottom of the comment; after being approved your comment will appear directly underneath the comment you replied to. 
 Share your Comment: 
 Post to Facebook. Post to Blogger. Post to Twitter. Post to WordPress. Post to TypePad. Post to Tumblr. Post to Yahoo! 
 Blogger login: Blogger password: Select blog:   refresh list Remember me: 
 
 Wordpress host: Wordpress login: Wordpress password: Remember me: 
 
 TypePad host: TypePad login: TypePad password: Select blog:   refresh list Remember me: 
 
 Tumblr login: Tumblr password: Remember me: 
 Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Recency  |  Popularity Page:  1   2   3   Next ›   Last »  (3 total) Ghandii 30 Fans 05:14 PM on 02/01/2012 Oh...and same to you Joe Satran...East LA is a good Community.... so why don&apos;t you find another town to portray with your &apos;downtrodden&apos; attitude.... Ghandii: Oh...and same to you Joe Satran...East LA is a good http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Ghandii/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132357576.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER Thaag Tidestalker Axial Tilt: the Reason for the Season! 275 Fans 07:49 AM on 02/01/2012 They should do how they do it in Honolulu. There ARE no signs on poles. Thaag_Tidestalker: They should do how they do it in Honolulu. There http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Thaag_Tidestalker/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132238791.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 joeshop8 150 Fans 02:34 AM on 02/01/2012 I never eat fast food.............that being said I think if a Person wants to eat it thats great. I just wish the Cities that want signage changed to just remember those same Fast Food places generate a lot of tax revenue and entry level jobs. The Govt. Trolls are driving business out of Ca. at a fast pace, and this is one more example of why They are leaving. You issued the permit during planning and construction, dont change the rules mid-stream. joeshop8: I never eat fast food.............that being said I think if http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/joeshop8/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132222099.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER greggrwag 49 Fans   01:20 AM on 02/01/2012 BTW why regulate signs, should&apos;t the Glendale goons be regulating dust from a construction pit somewhere else? greggrwag: BTW why regulate signs, should&apos;t the Glendale goons be regulating http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/greggrwag/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132216308.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER greggrwag 49 Fans   01:16 AM on 02/01/2012 Maybe we should start telling the government employees what to do on how they eat or drink and raise their kids for a change they wouldn&apos;t like that too much would they, oh no don&apos;t take away their 6-7oz coffees MacDs breakfeast that they so love every morning and take out the soda machines in the hallways that they cram quarters into every afternoon. Whats good for the goose is good for the gander. greggrwag: Maybe we should start telling the government employees what to http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/greggrwag/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132215995.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Bruins 1 Fans 01:11 AM on 02/01/2012 I hope each and everyone of them sure the City. Bruins: I hope each and everyone of them sure the City. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Bruins/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132215533.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER fymayawf 61 Fans 12:37 AM on 02/01/2012 Boneheads. Stop patronizing them and they will go away along with their signs. fymayawf: Boneheads. Stop patronizing them and they will go away along http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/fymayawf/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132212002.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER FLmarebob 19 Fans 11:41 PM on 01/31/2012 These signs have been up for years, now all of a sudden they&apos;re too big? Seems to me that Glendale is just trying to raise some money. FLmarebob: These signs have been up for years, now all of http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/FLmarebob/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132205506.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER Catherine Girod 76 Fans 11:25 PM on 01/31/2012 I&apos;m pretty sure that photo isn&apos;t real, or at least it isn&apos;t Glendale. A) there is no Grinder in Glendale (I think there might have been at one time, or maybe it was something else). B) the only Taco Bell in Glendale with that particular signage is on Central Ave, with no other fast food around it. C) the McDonald&apos;s on Central has extremely modest (as far as McDonald&apos;s goes) signage. The other McDonald&apos;s restaurants in Glendale are also lacking the giant golden arches. D) it looks like a Panda Express sign behind the McDonald&apos;s sign. The only Panda Express in Glendale is inside the Glendale Galleria, with no signage on the outside of the mall.

I&apos;m just saying you can&apos;t always believe what you see, especially in the era of Photoshop. Catherine_Girod: I&apos;m pretty sure that photo isn&apos;t real, or at least http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Catherine_Girod/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132203211.html History  | Permalink  | Share it GOODDOC1 &quot;civil war&quot; is an oxymoron 615 Fans 11:33 PM on 01/31/2012 It&apos;s probably just a stock photo. HP uses them a lot. GOODDOC1: It&apos;s probably just a stock photo. HP uses them a http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/GOODDOC1/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132204307.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER Catherine Girod 76 Fans 11:37 PM on 01/31/2012 Perhaps, but it is still a misrepresentation. I drive through Glendale frequently and have never seen an area that looks that bad. Catherine_Girod: Perhaps, but it is still a misrepresentation. I drive through http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Catherine_Girod/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132204848.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Cal Gal 3 4 Fans 10:42 PM on 01/31/2012 Good for the Council. It&apos;s not just aesthetics. Those signs encourage people to ignore &quot;Mom and Pop&quot; eating establishments that probably serve heathier food in favor of &quot;junk food chains&quot; that contribute to this country&apos;s epidemic of obseity and diabetes. I hope the &quot;big guys&quot; (in more ways than one) don&apos;t use their money and &quot;heft&quot; to win this one from the little guy. Stick with it! Go after them! Cal_Gal_3: Good for the Council. It&apos;s not just aesthetics. Those signs http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Cal_Gal_3/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132196718.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER FLmarebob 19 Fans 11:45 PM on 01/31/2012 This applies to all businesses, not just fast-food. If you don&apos;t like it, don&apos;t eat it, but please quit telling others what to do. FLmarebob: This applies to all businesses, not just fast-food. If you http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/FLmarebob/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132205994.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER harolddundee 150 Fans 10:25 PM on 01/31/2012 Just another case of government trying to tell people how to live. harolddundee: Just another case of government trying to tell people how http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/harolddundee/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132193917.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 f1nesse101 freedom with peace and prosperity 99 Fans   09:51 PM on 01/31/2012 Glendale&apos;s City Council is an elected post. When elections roll around big business will root out the members who try to enforce the regulations. Glendale city council chambers must be a really lonely place, with not much to do. f1nesse101: Glendale&apos;s City Council is an elected post. When elections roll http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/f1nesse101/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132188305.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 zelda777 transcend the B. S. 360 Fans 09:44 PM on 01/31/2012 Bravo! Any fight against junk food is good. Wherever it is common - in most of the USA and more and more in other parts of the world, people become obese and unhealthy. That&apos;s considered normal nowadays. zelda777: Bravo! Any fight against junk food is good. Wherever it http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/zelda777/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132187148.html History  | Permalink  | Share it GOODDOC1 &quot;civil war&quot; is an oxymoron 615 Fans 11:35 PM on 01/31/2012 You really think this bill will make a dent in the obesity rates, or improve anyone&apos;s health? Maybe you should move to Glendale and run for office. GOODDOC1: You really think this bill will make a dent in http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/GOODDOC1/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132204593.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 lovaevry1 13 Fans 09:33 PM on 01/31/2012 If they want something done, they should not buy food from there. I mean, they were openly mocking a nearby neighborhood, if they are that uppity they shouldn&apos;t eat fast food. It&apos;s not healthy. lovaevry1: If they want something done, they should not buy food http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/lovaevry1/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132185270.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 jwyola 122 Fans 09:07 PM on 01/31/2012 Councilman Ara Najarian told the Glendale News-Press. &quot;These signs are something you see in East L.A.,&quot; referring to the downtrodden, largely Hispanic neighborhood 14 miles to Glendale&apos;s southeast. Is this not Racial HATE SPEECH? jwyola: Councilman Ara Najarian told the Glendale News-Press.&quot;These signs are http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/jwyola/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132180707.html History  | Permalink  | Share it mrpell 253 Fans 10:14 PM on 01/31/2012 Only to an ignorant liberal with a chip on their shoulder. mrpell: Only to an ignorant liberal with a chip on their http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/mrpell/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132192191.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER Catherine Girod 76 Fans 10:41 PM on 01/31/2012 If you are familiar with the ethnic makeup of both Glendale and East L.A., you&apos;ll understand. I&apos;m not an ignorant liberal with a chip on my shoulder but I found it to be rather offensive. Catherine_Girod: If you are familiar with the ethnic makeup of both http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Catherine_Girod/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132196496.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Cal Gal 3 4 Fans 10:55 PM on 01/31/2012 No it&apos;s not &quot;hate speech&quot;. The Councilman was just pointing out the obvious that &quot;fast food chains&quot; are allowed by corrupt governments to take advantage of people who live in poverty. The poor are &quot;plucked&quot; by big business &quot;vultures&quot; for every last dime. The poor&apos;s desperate needs and desires are ignored in order to make a few rich men even richer. It&apos;s too bad that no one will stand up for these children, especially, and get the junk food out of these helpless communities . Cal_Gal_3: No it&apos;s not&quot;hate speech&quot;. The Councilman was just pointing http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Cal_Gal_3/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132198744.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Ghandii 30 Fans 05:18 PM on 02/01/2012 He IS the Corporate Enabler...he just wants the signs shorter... Ghandii: He IS the Corporate Enabler...he just wants the signs shorter... http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Ghandii/glendale-fast-food_n_1242565_132358412.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
     Page:  1   2   3   Next ›   Last »  (3 total) new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost i8Qz06fBrewXsgD0nMcHeMPq0DAczTLLiOgvxgvdY44UGIi%2FD2woeCOTEcma0adn%2BgEYvrF1Ts4fObbEVDpPEkFSUJ3LDEWB %2BbjOXcDk4YT8Q7qzY54AWfbN9Zz0nkIwmYowPqxJ%2ByZd8wNt0ZxosGQphgUUnVmGmKCWt7A5Ah48MpPBtu4B2JqBHunJVvyN 1 of 2 Excedrin Recall: When Is The Migraine Medicine Coming Back? 
 Like 171 The Unlikely Celeb Katie Holmes Turned To For Divorce Advice? 
 Like 10 WATCH: Cookie Monster Sings &apos;Share It Maybe&apos; 
 Like 5k Is Sex Better Without An Orgasm? 
 Like 147 Will Vera Wang&apos;s Brand Survive Her Split? 
 Like 12 18 Signs You&apos;re About To Cheat 
 Like 95 This Charlie&apos;s Angel Turns 61 Today 
 Like 47 Teen Hospitalized For Addiction To Coke -- No, The Other Kind 
 Like 156 Can Oral Sex Cure Morning Sickness? 
 Like 130 Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of HuffPost Food Group 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
