<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005853" url="http://www.recipesource.com/fgv/potato-salads/french-fried-potato1.html" time="2012-07-12-22:31" support="2" score="0.006883877859551607" bingtitle="RecipeSource: French Fried Potato Salad" webtitle="RecipeSource: French Fried Potato Salad">
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>Gift Ideas; Hints; Kids; Medieval; Microwave; Mixes ... Servings 3 Double order of french fries -from your favorite fast -food restaurant 1 ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to RecipeSource!
 RecipeSource is the new home of
SOAR: The Searchable Online Archive of Recipes
and your source for recipes on the Internet.     RecipeSource : Fruits, Grains,&amp;Vegetables : Potato Salad Recipes : French Fried Potato Salad 
 
 Search for Recipes: 
 Search entire site 
 Search just this area 
 Advanced Search Browse by region: 
 Africa&amp;Middle East 
 Armenian Egyptian Ethiopian Lebanese Moroccan Persian Turkish Other African Other Middle Eastern   
 Asia&amp;Pacific Ocean 
 Australian Burmese Chinese Filipino Hawaiian Indian &amp; Pakistani Indonesian Japanese Korean New Zealand Singaporean Tahitian Thai Tibetan Vietnamese 
 Europe 
 Austrian Basque Belgian British Croatian Czech Danish Dutch Finnish French German Greek Hungarian Icelandic Irish Italian Norwegian Polish Portuguese Rumanian Russian Scandinavian Scottish Serbian Spanish Swedish Swiss Ukrainian Welsh   
 North&amp;South America 
 Argentinian Brazilian Cajun Canadian Caribbean Colombian Eskimo Mexican Native American Peruvian Venezuelan   
 Non-regional 
 Jewish 
 
 Browse by type: 
 Main Dishes 
 Breakfast Dishes Burgers Casseroles Crockpot Cooking Dinner Pies Eggs Fish &amp; Seafood Meat Pasta Pizza Poultry Sandwiches 
 Soups&amp;Stuff 
 Chili Soups Stews Stocks 
 Baked Goods 
 Bagels Biscuits Breads Buns Desserts&amp;Sweets Muffins Pastries Rolls Scones   
 Fruits, Grains&amp;Vegetables 
 Bean Salads Beans &amp; Grains Fruits Fruit Salads Pasta Salads Pickles Pilafs Polenta Potato Salads Rice Salads Stuffed Vegetables Stuffing Vegetables   
 On the Side 
 Beverages Butter Cheese Chutneys Condiments Dressings Jams &amp; Jellies Marinades Oils Pesto Preserves Puddings Relishes Rubs Salsas Sauces Spices Vinegar 
 Sweets&amp;Desserts 
 Brownies Cakes Candy Cheesecakes Chocolate Cobblers Cookies Frozen Yogurts Mousses Pies Sherbets Sorbets Tarts Trifles Frostings Frozen Desserts Other Baked Desserts Other Desserts 
 Snacks&amp;Appetizers 
 Appetizers Dips &amp; Spreads Snacks 
 Holiday Foods 
 Easter Halloween Thanksgiving Christmas Other Holidays 
 Restricted&amp;Special Diets 
 Baby Food Diabetic Gluten Free Vegetarian 
 Miscellaneous&amp;Other 
 Beauty Products Bizzare Camping Canning/Preserving Copycat Crafts Dutch Ovens Food Humor Gift Ideas Hints Kids Medieval Microwave Mixes Pet Food/Treats 
 
 Other info: 
 About Us Frequently Asked Questions Privacy Policy Site Map Site News Submit a Recipe 
 
 
 
 MMMMM----- Recipe via Meal-Master (tm) v8.03
 
 Title: FRENCH FRIED POTATO SALAD
 Categories: Salads
 Yield: 6 Servings
 
 3 Double order of french fries
 -from your favorite fast
 -food restaurant
 1/4 c Onion; finely chopped
 3 tb Parsley; chopped
 1 md Clove garlic; mashed
 1 tb White wine vinegar
 1/2 c Mayonnaise
 Pepper to taste
 
 Place french fries in a large bowl immediately, to prevent them from
 becoming limp. Set aside. In another large bowl, combine onion,
 parsley and garlic. Add vinegar. Add pepper, if desired. Mix
 thoroughly. Let stand for at least 1 hour, stirring occasionally.
 When ready to serve, add mayonnaise to onion mixture. Mix well. Add
 french fries. Serve immediately.
 
 Source:“The Unique Potato Salad Cookbook”by Vera Klein
 
 MMMMM 
 Plain Text Version of This Recipe for Printing or Saving 

   
Copyright©1995-2000 SOAR.©2001-2011 RecipeSource.
 All Rights Reserved.
All trademarks are the property of their respective owners.
	</body>
</document>
