<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005900" url="http://www.iabar.net/Industrial%20Commissioner.nsf/9a275c73f72409f4862564bb00563305/a15652062fdfdef08625737600528e06?OpenDocument" time="2012-07-12-22:34" support="2" score="0.002401728383336414" bingtitle="www.iabar.net" webtitle="">
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>... of factory work, bus boy, cashier, assistant manager in a Wal-Mart garden center and fast food restaurant ... he see a neurosurgeon to confirm ... ORDER</description>
	<body>
		This decision is presented AS IS. There is possibility of introduction of error in the posting process. Reliance on this decision should be tempered by sound legal advice from licensed counsel. 
 
 Case Title: DRISKILL V. TMC TRANSPORTATION Date: 10/02/2007 
 File Number: 5019284 

 Claimant Employer/Defendant Insurance Carrier DAVID DRISKILL TMC TRANSPORTATION SELF-INSURED 
 Summary 
 
 Decision: 
 
 STATEMENT OF THE CASE 
 Claimant, David Driskill, has filed petition in arbitration and seeks workers’compensation benefits from TMC Transportation, employer self-insured, defendant. 
 This matter was heard by deputy workers’compensation commissioner, Ron Pohlman in Des Moines, Iowa on July 10, 2007. The record in the case consists of claimant’s exhibits A-Z; defendant exhibits 1-11 as well as the testimony of the claimant, Gina Boomershine, L.P.T. and Martha Grice. 
 This matter was stayed by the workers’compensation commissioner by order filed August 3, 2007 because the defendant had filed a petition in mandamus in the Polk County District Court regarding a ruling on motion to compel issued by the undersigned on July 3, 2007. The petition in mandamus was dismissed and the commissioner lifted his stay order on September 28, 2007. The ruling on motion to compel has been appealed to the commissioner. 
 ISSUES 
 The parties submitted the following issues for determination: 
 Whether the work injury of June 20, 2005 was the cause of any permanent disability; 
 The extent of claimant’s entitlement to permanent partial disability pursuant to Iowa Code section 85.34(2)(u); 
 The commencement date for payment of permanent partial disability; and 
 Whether the claimant is entitled to payment of medical expenses pursuant to Iowa Code section 85.27. 
 FINDINGS OF FACT 
 The undersigned having considered all the testimony and evidence in the record finds: 
 Claimant at the time of the hearing was 41 years old. He has a GED. He lives in rural Kentucky. His prior work history consists of factory work, bus boy, cashier, assistant manager in a Wal-Mart garden center and fast food restaurant management. In the factory, the claimant was required to lift bags weighing up to 50 pounds. He was a working manager in the fast food restaurant and at times was required to lift up to 100 pounds. He was required to perform all tasks in the restaurant as a fill in. He was also responsible for management duties such as scheduling. As an assistant manager he was responsible for receiving which involved unloading heavy materials including lawn mowers and trees. 
 He sustained a low back injury in a motor vehicle accident in 1996. He had surgery consisting of a partial laminectomy and obtained a good result. The claimant underwent a lumbar MRI on August 2, 2000 which revealed a significant scar at L5-S1 but no herniations at other levels of the lumbar spine. The claimant had an injection at L5 on December 7, 2000. 
 The claimant went to truck driving school and obtained a commercial driver’s license. He was hired by TMC Transportation to be a driver in August 2002. He went to orientation in Des Moines, Iowa and underwent a physical. He discussed his prior back surgery with the company physician and he was cleared to work without restriction. He also had to pass physical testing required by the company. He had to be able to carry a tarp weighing 140 pounds up a 13 foot ladder on the truck, carry 10 chains and complete a driving test. He passed all of these tests. The claimant estimates that before the injury he could lift up to 200 pounds. He had no problems walking. 
 The claimant considered this to be the best job he has ever had. He drove 5000 miles per week across the country. Each day he was required to climb up onto a load and apply the tarp. On June 30, 2004, the claimant passed the required department of transportation physical. 
 On June 20, 2005, the claimant had an accident with his truck and trailer. The accident photographs in the record show that the roof of the claimant’s truck was completely torn off and the driver’s seat is bent backwards. The claimant was taken by ambulance to the hospital. The ambulance notes indicate that the accident was a rollover; that claimant had multiple abrasions, and lacerations to the top of the head and left elbow; that claimant complained of pain to the right shoulder; that the claimant remembered his head sliding on the pavement. At the hearing the claimant could not recall being in the ambulance. He testified that his next memory after the accident was being at home with his wife. 
 At the hospital the claimant was sutured as needed and x-rays as well as CT scans were completed of the cervical spine, left elbow and right shoulder. The radiographs were normal. The claimant was released from the hospital with a restriction of no work for 7 days. 
 The claimant was referred by the employer to Occunet an occupational health facility in Paducah, Kentucky by the employer. He was first seen there on June 24, 2005. The claimant was provided conservative care consisting of medication and physical therapy but he obtained no pain relief. He was complaining of lower back pain. On July 19, 2005 the physician there recommended an MRI of the lumbar spine. 
 The MRI revealed herniated disks at L4-5 and T12-L1. A referral was made to a spine specialist. The claimant then saw Eugene Gulish, M.D., an orthopedic surgeon who has since been the claimant’s primary treating physician. Dr. Gulish saw claimant first on August 2, 2005. At that time Dr. Gulish ordered an MRI of the right shoulder to rule out a rotator cuff tear. The MRI of the right shoulder demonstrated some changes in the rotator cuff though it appeared to be intact. Dr. Gulish also reviewed the lumbar spine MRI which he read as revealing mild bulges at L3-4, L4-5 and significant deformity at L5 which he identified as the site of the prior surgery. 
 The claimant was sent to the Pain Management Center of Paducah by Dr. Gulish where the claimant’s primary treating physician was Laximaiah Manchikanti, M.D. Claimant began treating there September 21, 2005. Dr. Manchikanti has treated the claimant with two injections (1 in 2005 and 1 in 2006); medication and physical therapy. On June 8, 2007 Dr. Manchikanti opined: 
 With regards with the narcotic dosage I agree that he is on mild, at most moderate doses and not heavy doses. 
 I agree that his activity could be improved slowly to improve his physical function. 
 I have not deemed medical necessity to send him to neuropsychological work up, however, he can have a psychological evaluation. That would be helpful. 
 I have performed injections in 2005 and early 2006. I have stopped these since the insurer has not approved and patient had no way of paying for this. Patient stated that it has helped him substantially and we tried to resume these injections on multiple occasions. 
 (Ex. N, p. 41) 
 On June 12, 2007, Dr. Manchikanti opined that the claimant was not capable of working in any capacity based upon his examination of April 25, 2007 and that his restrictions were: 5 pounds lifting to waist; 5 pounds waist to chest; 0 pounds overhead lifting; 5 pounds pushing/pulling; no walking more than one block; 10 minutes sitting; 5 minutes standing; 10 minutes driving and no bending or stooping. 
 Dr. Gulish wanted the claimant to continue conservative treatment and to lose weight. Eventually, however the decision was made to have the claimant undergo an arthroscopic surgery on the right shoulder. This surgery was performed by Dr. Gulish on January 6, 2006. Dr. Gulish’s notes reflect a phone call on January 25, 2006 where claimant was complaining that he was losing control of his legs and falling for the past three months. Further he complained that this was occurring with more frequency recently. 
 On January 27, 2006, Dr. Gulish recommended an EMG and nerve conduction study of the lower extremities to determine the cause of the claimant’s falling down. 
 The claimant saw Mark L. Crawford, M.D., a spine surgeon, on February 6, 2006. Dr. Crawford’s assessment was neck pain and herniated disk at L1-2 and L5-S1. He did not believe the claimant was a surgical candidate but did recommend an MRI of the cervical spine. 
 The claimant saw Salman Saeed, M.D., a neurologist on March 30, 2006 for an EMG study which was normal. Apparently, the claimant was dissatisfied with this test because it was not on the left lower extremity which was giving the claimant the greatest difficulty. Dr. Gulish agreed that the claimant should have an EMG of the left lower extremity. 
 The claimant underwent an EMG on August 18, 2006 at Dr. Gulish’s request for the left lower limb. The EMG was normal. 
 On October 2, 2006 the claimant was offered light-duty work by the employer to be performed in Indianapolis, Indiana. The claimant initially asked this be delayed as his wife was having surgery. Later, the claimant was advised not to travel by Dr. Manchikanti. 
 The claimant underwent an MRI of the cervical spine on December 7, 2006 which revealed no definite focal cervical pathology. 
 The claimant saw Michael Chalfee, M.D., for an independent medical evaluation on September 5, 2006 to determine whether the claimant was able to return to work. Dr. Chalfee opined: 
 Discussion: I’ve reviewed his records. He’s had a long course of conservative treatment including epidural steroids and pain management. Regarding his back, I do not think this patient is a surgical candidate, but I would recommend he see a neurosurgeon to confirm this. In the meantime, I do think he is able to participate in sedentary type work. Physically getting to DeMoine, [sic] Iowa will be a challenge for this patient, but I do think the patient could participate in the alternate work program. I believe this would reacclimate him into the work force. As far as his shoulder goes, he definitely has glenohumeral arthritis. Juding [sic] from the amount of OA that he has, I do not think his OA was was [sic] a direct result of his accident. I don’t think he should have any current work restrictions related to his shouler [sic]. I think his sedentary duty is related to his back injury. Again, I do feel he should be evaluated by a neurosurgeon who does back surgery on a recurrent basis. I have nothing else to offer this patient from an orthopedic standpoint. 
 (Ex. J, pp. 2-3) 
 The claimant saw Theodore Davies, M.D., for a neurosurgical consultation at Dr. Gulish’s request on January 30, 2007. Dr. Davies ordered another lumbar spine MRI and a carotid duplex scan which was normal. Dr. Davies recommended referral to a neurologist for the claimant’s falling episodes and prescribed a walker for safety. Dr. Davies recommended further evaluation by a neuropsychologist or neurologist. 
 On May 7, 2007, the claimant underwent an independent medical evaluation with Robert Milas, M.D., at claimant’s attorney’s request. Dr. Milas opines that the claimant has sustained a traumatic brain injury with short term memory loss; that the claimant has a central cervical disk protrusion at C6-7 evident on an MRI scan of the cervical spine (there is no indication as to whether Dr. Milas had access to the cervical MRI performed in Kentucky or whether he obtained any new MRI of the cervical spine) and lumbar disk protrusion at L4-5 level evident on an MRI of the lumbar spine. Dr. Milas opines that the claimant has a 100 percent disability rating under the AMA Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment , Fifth Edition. Dr. Milas does not believe the claimant is employable in any occupation. 
 The claimant underwent an independent medical evaluation at defendant’s request on May 9, 2007 with John Prevo, D.O. Dr. Prevo reviewed the functional capacity evaluation performed by Ms. Boomershine. Claimant appeared for the independent medical evaluation in a wheelchair and Dr. Prevo and his nurse tried to get the claimant onto the examination table but were unsuccessful. Dr. Prevo felt this was because the claimant gave a submaximal effort. Dr. Prevo then proceeded to examine claimant while he remained in the wheelchair. Dr. Prevo concludes that the claimant’s limitations are personal in nature and self-limiting. 
 On May 10, 2007, the claimant went to the emergency room at Iowa Lutheran Hospital in Des Moines, Iowa complaining of chronic back pain made worse by the drive from Kentucky to Iowa. The claimant was treated with an injection of Demerol. 
 The claimant’s family physician is Ken Cook, M.D. Dr. Cook on June 5, 2007 opined: 
 Mr. Driskill received treatment for lumbar disc problems in 1995 and subsequently had a lumbar laminectomy in 1996 in a Memphis area hospital. He did well from 1996 until 2005, at which time he was in a semitrailer truck accident and received injuries including cervical disc problems, as well as lumbar degenerative disc problems. The patient had no problems with his right shoulder prior to this accident, as well. He does have difficulty walking; in fact he uses a walker for ambulation. The motor vehicle accident in June 2005 was the cause of his diagnosis, which is now cervical and lumbar disc disease, status post rotator cuff problems of the right shoulder. Mr. Driskill has a permanent impairment for low back, mid back, right shoulder, neck and head. All of these impairments were caused by the auto accident in June 2005. His restrictions in a work setting now are that he has to use a walker for ambulation, which prohibits him from being gainfully employed. He cannot drive a semi. He cannot do any light duty at this time. He requires a walker on a permanent basis. I do not feel he is exaggerating or malingering his injuries. 
 (Ex. Q, p. 15) 
 The claimant underwent a vocational economic assessment by Kent Jayne on June 3, 2007. Mr. Jayne concludes that the claimant is unlikely to be employable in any feasible vocational rehabilitation plan given his current level of function. Mr. Jayne also opines that the claimant is in need of further psychological or neuropsychological evaluation as well as further pain management. 
 Gina Boomershine is a licensed physical therapist at Accelerated Rehabilitation Center in Des Moines, Iowa. She was hired by defendant to perform a functional capacity evaluation on the claimant which took place in Des Moines, Iowa on May 9, 2007. She testified that a functional capacity evaluation takes four hours. She concluded that the claimant gave a submaximal effort because he failed 12 out of 15 criteria. She noted that the claimant had no tightness in the back that she would attribute to muscle spasm. She noted that the walker the claimant uses does not have wheels and that the claimant uses a reciprocal gait with one foot in front of the other so in her opinion he should be able to balance without the walker. She noted a positive Waddell’s and positive cog wheeling. She concluded that the claimant had extraneous pain that was not anatomical. The claimant refused to attempt a number of the tests she requested because he was fearful of falling. Ms. Boomershine weighs 140 pounds and the claimant weighs 350 pounds. 
 Ms. Boomershine testified that she would have done her best to keep the claimant from falling. Ms. Boomershine acknowledges that she is not an expert in fear, that she does not know what effect severe depression would have on a person’s behavior in the functional capacity evaluation; and that inactivity would decrease strength, endurance and range of motion. 
 The claimant was referred for a psychological evaluation on June 14, 2007. The evaluation was conducted by Leslie Strategier, PhD, licensed clinical psychologist and E.C. Hurley, M.A, clinical intern. They had the claimant take an MMPI-2. The pattern of claimant’s responses indicated that the claimant was a person in significant distress which invalidated the MMPI-2. The conclusions were that the testing required a significant amount of time, responses invalidated the test and that the claimant was significantly depressed which may influence the claimant’s tendency to over report his pathology. 
 The claimant saw Dr. Gulish on June 21, 2007 for evaluation. Based upon his evaluation Dr. Gulish recommends as follows: 
 Recommendation: This certainly has been a difficult patient to treat and is a difficult patient for me to rate. He has been extensively worked up and has had a plethora of consultations, including two neurosurgery consultations, two EMG and nerve conduction studies, MRI studies of the head, neck and lumbosacral spine, as well as plane films of these areas. I have watched the patient progressively deteriorate in my time of treating him, from being able to walk under his own power until this last visit when he could barely walk across the room using the walker and assistance from his wife, and could almost not get up on the examination table, even with maximum assistance. His studies tend to complicate the issue. The patient indicates that he has incontinence of the bowel and bladder, that he has difficulty achieving an erection, all signs of cauda equine syndrome and yet when we look at the MRI study of his lumbosacral spine, there is not a disc protrusion of the magnitude that could cause this. One is left to wonder why this happening in the face of the studies which we have. He has been reported by at least two examiners to be dragging his left foot and yet his EMG and nerve conduction studies on two occasions are negative. Why would he therefore have an impending foot drop, while at the same time having a normal electrical study? The MRI study of the head is negative and yet, over the course of time, this patient’s cognition has continually deteriorated from a point where he was alert and oriented on his first visit, to a point on his last visit where he could not answer questions and could not remember facts, even surrounding the accident which was the genesis of this two year downhill course. To further cloud the issue, the patient had a laminectomy done in 1996 at the same level where the most significant disc protrusion exists today. One wonders what is the relationship of this to his present condition and why has his shoulder not improved more. He has some osteoarthritis of the shoulder which certainly precedes his motor vehicle accident but at arthroscopy he had an intact rotator cuff. He had subacromial scarring and impingement syndrome but this usually responds quickly to surgical treatment and generally results in a normal functioning shoulder. But in this man, his range of motion has remained restricted and he continues to complain of shoulder pain. He is obviously depressed and I think in the future this must be addressed. His mentation is of great concern to me. He had a recent extensive workup by Work Life Resources, INC., which indicated that the patient was severely mentally involved. 
 I will confine my impairment rating to that which I am an expert, ie; orthopaedic surgical/musculoskeletal problems, in accordance with the AMA’s Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment, Fifth Edition, and go by those guidelines. I think that to evaluate his axial skeleton in any way other than a DRE model would not be accurate. Therefore, I have used this model to determine his MMI rating for his neck and his lumbosacral spine. In accordance with AMA’s Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment, Fifth Edition, the cervical spine would be rated in accordance with Table 15.5, Page 392, as a DRE cervical Category II with an 8% whole person impairment. His lumbosacral spine would be rated as a DRE Category III with a 13% whole person impairment. This is found on Table 15.3, Page 384. His shoulder would best be rated with a range of motion model. He has an abduction range today of 90%. This, according to Table 16.48, Page 477, results in an upper extremity of 4% which equals a whole person impairment of 2%. His flexion range is 60 degrees which equals an 8% upper extremity impairment, resulting in a whole person impairment of 5%. This is found in Table 16.40, Page 476. External rotation is found in Table 16.46, Page 479 and results in an 8% upper extremity impairment, which correlates to a 5% whole person impairment. Internal rotation of 20 degrees results in a 4% upper extremity impairment correlating to a 2% whole person impairment. Going then to the Combined Values chart, Page 604, in the Guides, we combine these values and are left with a 31% whole person impairment for his musculoskeletal system. I have not made an attempt to include his depression in this rating. I have not made an effort to include whatever head injury may have occurred in this rating. If you have further questions, please feel free to call on me. 
 (Ex. H, pp. 30-31) 
 In his deposition Dr. Gulish indicated that the shoulder surgery revealed that the rotator cuff was intact but that the claimant had impingement and acute findings which indicated that the impingement was due to recent trauma. 
 The claimant is currently taking several medications including Loracet, Valium, Topamax, Ambien, and Protonix. He does not leave the house and no longer engages in activity with his family. 
 REASONING AND CONCLUSIONS OF LAW 
 The first issue is whether the work injury of June 20, 2005 was the cause of any permanent disability. 
 The claimant has the burden of proving by a preponderance of the evidence that the injury is a proximate cause of the disability on which the claim is based. A cause is proximate if it is a substantial factor in bringing about the result; it need not be the only cause. A preponderance of the evidence exists when the causal connection is probable rather than merely possible. George A. Hormel&amp;Co. v. Jordan , 569 N.W.2d 148 (Iowa 1997); Frye v. Smith-Doyle Contractors , 569 N.W.2d 154 (Iowa App. 1997); Sanchez v. Blue Bird Midwest , 554 N.W.2d 283 (Iowa App. 1996). 
 The question of causal connection is essentially within the domain of expert testimony. The expert medical evidence must be considered with all other evidence introduced bearing on the causal connection between the injury and the disability. Supportive lay testimony may be used to buttress the expert testimony and, therefore, is also relevant and material to the causation question. The weight to be given to an expert opinion is determined by the finder of fact and may be affected by the accuracy of the facts the expert relied upon as well as other surrounding circumstances. The expert opinion may be accepted or rejected, in whole or in part. St. Luke’s Hosp. v. Gray , 604 N.W.2d 646 (Iowa 2000); IBP, Inc. v. Harpole , 621 N.W.2d 410 (Iowa 2001); Dunlavey v. Economy Fire and Cas. Co. , 526 N.W.2d 845 (Iowa 1995). Miller v. Lauridsen Foods, Inc. , 525 N.W.2d 417 (Iowa 1994). Unrebutted expert medical testimony cannot be summarily rejected. Poula v. Siouxland Wall&amp;Ceiling, Inc. , 516 N.W.2d 910 (Iowa App. 1994). 
 The claimant, before this accident, was able to engage in substantial physical activity as demonstrated by his ability to successfully complete a rigorous physical test to obtain employment at TMC and as evidence by his successful service in this employment for three years. He did not have a disc herniation in 2000 when he underwent an MRI. 
 His primary treating physicians have opined that he has permanent physical impairment and severely limiting physical restrictions. Dr. Gulish believes that the claimant has depression or issues related to his pain medication. The depression has not been treated. The functional capacity evaluation and examination with Dr. Prevo present a picture of the claimant as self limiting but Ms. Boomershine acknowledged that she is not aware of the impact of severe depression on effort in a functional capacity evaluation. 
 Dr. Gulish has observed a dramatic deterioration in the claimant’s condition and cognitive ability over the course of his treatment of the claimant. Such deterioration is directly traceable to the work injury. The chain of events leading to the claimant’s current conditions starts with the work injury. It appears based upon an examination of the record as a whole that the claimant has developed depression secondary to the injury and that this may explain the claimant’s over reporting of his pathology. This is confirmed by the recent psychological testing. When after a compensable accident, a claimant’s disability is increased or prolonged by a trauma connected neurosis or hysterical paralysis, all disability, including the effects of the nervous disorder is compensable. Gosek v. Garmer and Stiles Company , 158 N.W.2d 731 (Iowa 1968). The claimant has established that his current permanent disability is causally related to the work injury. 
 The next issue is the extent of claimant’s entitlement to permanent partial disability pursuant to Iowa Code section 85.34(2)(u). 
 Permanent partial disability that is not limited to a scheduled member is compensated industrially under Iowa Code section 85.34(2)(u). Industrial disability compensates loss of earning capacity as determined by an evaluation of the injured employee’s functional impairment, age, intelligence, education, qualifications, experience, and ability to engage in employment for which the employee is suited. Second Injury Fund of Iowa v. Shank , 516 N.W.2d 808, 813 (Iowa 1994), Guyton v. Irving Jensen Co. , 373 N.W.2d 101, 104 (Iowa 1985), Diederich v. Tri-City R. Co. , 219 Iowa 587, 258 N.W. 899 (1935). The concept is quite similar to the element of tort damage known as loss of future earning capacity even though the outcome in tort is expressed in dollars rather than as a percentage of loss. The focus is on the ability of the worker to be gainfully employed and rests on comparison of what the injured worker could earn before the injury with what the same person can earn after the injury. Second Injury Fund of Iowa v. Nelson , 544 N.W.2d 258, 266 (Iowa 1995), Anthes v. Anthes , 258 Iowa 260, 270, 139 N.W.2d 201, 208 (1965). Impairment of physical capacity creates an inference of lessened earning capacity. Changes in actual earnings are a factor to be considered but actual earnings are not synonymous with earning capacity. Bergquist v. MacKay Engines, Inc. , 538 N.W.2d 655, 659 (Iowa App. 1995), Holmquist v. Volkswagen of America, Inc. , 261 N.W.2d 516, 525, (Iowa App. 1977), 4-81 Larson’s Workers’Compensation Law , 81.01[1] and 81.04[1]. The loss is not measured in a vacuum. The worker’s personal characteristics which affect the worker’s employability are considered. Ehlinger v. State , 237 N.W.2d 784, 792 (Iowa 1976). Earning capacity is measured by the employee&apos;s own ability to compete in the labor market. An award is not to be reduced as a result of the employer’s largess or accommodations. U.S. West v. Overholser , 566 N.W.2d 873, 876 (Iowa 1997), Thilges, 528 N.W.2d 614, 617. 
 Total disability does not mean a state of absolute helplessness. Permanent total disability occurs where the injury wholly disables the employee from performing work that the employee&apos;s experience, training, education, intelligence and physical capacities would otherwise permit the employee to perform. See McSpadden v. Big Ben Coal Co. , 288 N.W.2d 181 (Iowa 1980); Diederich v. Tri-City R. Co. , 219 Iowa 587, 258 N.W. 899 (1935). 
 A finding that claimant could perform some work despite claimant&apos;s physical and educational limitations does not foreclose a finding of permanent total disability, however. See Chamberlin v. Ralston Purina , File No. 661698 (App. October 29, 1987); Eastman v. Westway Trading Corp. , II Iowa Industrial Commissioner Report 134 (App. May 19, 1982). 
 Claimant is not able to function in his current condition at a level that would enable him to perform work of any kind. The claimant is permanently and totally disabled. This is supported by the restrictions of Dr. Manchikanti. The claimant is taking multiple medications that interfere with his cognitive functioning. He has significant permanent impairment as set out by Dr. Gulish. He has been prescribed the use of a walker as a result of neurological consultation and continues to use this through the date of the hearing. 
 There is no evidence that vocational rehabilitation would be of any benefit for the claimant and no evidence that there is any work that the claimant could perform in his current condition. 
 The last issue is whether the claimant is entitled to payment of medical expenses pursuant to Iowa Code section 85.27. 
 The employer shall furnish reasonable surgical, medical, dental, osteopathic, chiropractic, podiatric, physical rehabilitation, nursing, ambulance and hospital services and supplies for all conditions compensable under the workers&apos; compensation law. The employer shall also allow reasonable and necessary transportation expenses incurred for those services. The employer has the right to choose the provider of care, except where the employer has denied liability for the injury. Section 85.27. Holbert v. Townsend Engineering Co. , Thirty-second Biennial Report of the Industrial Commissioner 78 (Review-Reopening October 16, 1975). 
 The medical expense in question is the bill for emergency room treatment at Iowa Lutheran Hospital. This treatment was not authorized. The travel to Iowa was not recommended by the claimant’s primary treating physicians and given the distance it should not be unexpected that the claimant would experience increased pain and require additional treatment. 
 The claimant was given an injection and obtained some pain relief. As such, he is entitled to payment for this care as he has shown it was reasonable, necessary and beneficial in treatment of his injury. 
 ORDER 
 Therefore it is ordered : 
 The defendant shall pay claimant benefits for permanent total disability at the weekly rate of six hundred twenty-seven and 36/100 dollars ($627.36) commencing June 20, 2005 for as long as the claimant remains permanently and totally disabled. 
 The defendants shall receive credit for benefits previously paid. 
 Accrued benefits shall be paid in lump sum together with interest pursuant to Iowa Code section 85.30 with subsequent reports of injury pursuant to rule 876 IAC 3.1. 
 The defendant is responsible for payment of the claimant’s medical expenses pursuant to Iowa Code section 85.27 and shall reimburse the claimant for any medically expenses that claimant has directly paid. 
 Defendant shall pay the costs of this action pursuant to rule 876 IAC 4.33. 
 Signed and filed this ___ 2 nd ____ day of October, 2007. 

 
 

 Copies To: 

 Mr. James M. Hood 
 Attorney at Law 
 220 Emerson Pl. Ste. 100 
 Davenport, IA 52801-1628 

 Mr. David E. Schrock 
 Attorney at Law 
 PO Box 36 
 Cedar Rapids, IA 52406-0036 

 Mr. Peter M. Sand 
 Attorney at Law 
 225 2 nd St., SE, Ste. 200 
 Cedar Rapids, IA 52401-1400
	</body>
</document>
