<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005279" url="http://www.planetfeedback.com/taco+bell/drive-thru+service/sauce+shortages+at+taco+bell/296090" time="2012-07-12-21:49" support="12" score="0.027962966583757253" bingtitle="Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? | Taco Bell Drive-thru Service ..." webtitle="Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? | Taco Bell Drive-thru Service | PlanetFeedback">
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000010" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000597" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001478" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000912" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001351" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000129" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>And we shouldn&apos;t have to re-confirm ... In order to provide these services and condiments, there has to be a ... I know the fast food restaurant (not taco bell) that ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME SHARED LETTERS RATINGS MY PLANET COMMUNITIES MISSION SIGN UP! 
 Shared Letters 
Join and browse our exclusive open discussion forums and talk about whatever you like.
 
 
 
 Channels » The Suggestion Box 
 » Company Responses 
 » PFB Feedback Line 
 » Consumer Podcasts 
 » Mommy Talk&amp;Daddy Dialogue™ 
 » Shared Letters 



 Newsletter 
Sign up for PlanetFeedback&apos;s &quot;Consumer Café&quot; email newsletter!
 
 



 


 
 
 

 Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell?

Posted Sat February 3, 2007 12:00 pm, by Lori N. written to Taco Bell

 Write a Letter to this Company   |   Rate this Company 

 
My family enjoys Taco Bell food, however our last 2 drive-thru visits have been very disappointing.

During our previous visit, we were asked the routine question at the order-box &quot;what sauce would you like?&quot;...to which I replied with the usual &quot;lots of hot&amp;fire sauce, please&quot;. I neglected to check my bags at the window after they were handed to me to make sure there were plenty of hot sauce packets&amp;realized when we got home that we were given just 2 hot&amp;2 fire sauces for 9 items. We ended up using Pace from our fridge.

Tonight&apos;s visit was equally disappointing. I responded with the same &quot;lots of hot&amp;fire sauce, please&quot; when asked at the order-box. Our order was large, 4 bags/4 people to feed. I asked the person who handed me my order if there was lots of sauce in one of the bags...I was assured that there was. I made the mistake of not checking for myself. When we got our food home, we found that there were 2 packets of mild, 2 packets of hot&amp;1 fire. We got out the Pace again.

Taco Bell tasts best with the original flavor of Taco Bell sauces that are offered as condiments. Taco Bell just isn&apos;t the same with Pace. We shouldn&apos;t have to beg for enough sauce to be enjoyed with the number of items ordered...especially when we&apos;re asked about our sauce preferences during each visit. And we shouldn&apos;t have to re-confirm that our original request was granted.

 Reply 




 Log In/Create an account | 14 comments 
        del.icio.us       Digg this    
 PlanetFeedback Comments are subject to strict terms and conditions. We reserve the right to deny site membership privileges to any individuals acting inappropriately. 
 
 
 
 I had the same problem by robinbird Posted Mon February 5, 2007 @ 1:50 PM 
 
I had the same problem.I just started going in to place my order so I
could help myself to all the sauce I needed. The bins are always
overflowing so I don&apos;t feel like I&apos;m taking too much.

Oh and the Taco Bell sauce that you can buy at the grocery store
tastes nothing like the stuff in the packets. I wonder why?

 Reply 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? by Richard S. Posted Mon February 5, 2007 @ 11:13 AM 
 
Instead of asking for lots of hot sauce, it would be better to say I
want 7 packages of the hot sauce. Your idea of &quot;lots&quot; maybe different
than mine.



 Reply 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? by tater30 Posted Sun February 4, 2007 @ 6:45 PM 
 
psssttt..... instead of buying Pace... you could buy the Taco Bell
brand of hot sauce or whatever you use. they sell it in the grocery
store...

just saying...

 Reply 
 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? by Derek Fitzpatrick Posted Sun February 4, 2007 @ 2:34 AM 
 
I can kind of relate to Taco Bell on this one.

I work in a pizza parlor, and I give out peppers, cheese, napkins, and
plates...

Those items aren&apos;t free for us! In fact, it can get very pricy for us
if we do not monitor or have some kind of system when we give them
out.

If a customer asks for peppers and cheese, I will puposely hand them
more peppers than cheese because of the cost difference. It may seem
petty when you look on it at a 1-on-1 level, but imagine how many
transactions a Taco Bell does a week. I know for pizza we are doing
about 1300 or so. It adds up!

In order to provide these services and condiments, there has to be a
system. Otherwise, places are just going to cut it...




 Reply 
 
 
 
 
 I think you have a good point, but... by Sarah H Sun February 4, 2007 @ 3:56 PM 
 
 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? by Gino Posted Sun February 4, 2007 @ 2:06 AM 
 
I usually check before I leave and even then things get mixed up.Maybe
they&apos;re trying to cut corners

I don&apos;t know if it&apos;s a regional thing. I&apos;m on the east coast and
recently have been buying a lot of fast food. I have a bowlful of
extra sauces and condiments. Taco Bell put a handfull or more packs
and I ordered for two people. Same with Burger King. I know I&apos;ll use
them but I can imagine a lot of people just tossing them out.

 Reply 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages at Taco Bell? by &quot;The One and Only&quot; MA Loper Posted Sun February 4, 2007 @ 1:27 AM 
 
That&apos;s ironic that you posted this today. My husband just made a late
night border run to our local store because we were craving nachos.
THEY WERE OUT OF NACHO CHEESE sauce!

How can Taco Bell be out of Nacho Cheese. That&apos;s like being out of
tortilla shells, y&apos;know?

Maybe they are having supplier issues this week.

 Reply 
 
 
 
 
 Haha... by Sarah H Sun February 4, 2007 @ 3:57 PM 
 
 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages? by mrstonecold Posted Sat February 3, 2007 @ 11:51 AM 
 
While this complaint is very valid, i just have to ask one question
.and lets take the 4bags/4people: How many actual tacos did you order?
because most fast food restaurants don&apos;t just hand out dozen sauces
out the window unless you are specific as it cost money! And if you
only ordered 5 tacos..then you got lots of sauce as isnt it 1 sauce
per taco? or something like that! I know the fast food restaurant (not
taco bell) that i work in, we only give 2 ketchup/1 salt for each fry
unless otherwise specified..and as someone else said, lots to one
person may mean something totally different to another! i.e. a few to
me means 3, handful to me means 4 or 5, a couple means 2, lots means
maybe 5 or 6....and when people ask for a dozen ketchup, half the time
it goes into there fridge and we arent a grocery store...we are a
restaurant and when people start doing that, then we start charging
for extra condiments as its not free!

 Reply 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages? by mary jo Posted Sat February 3, 2007 @ 11:22 AM 
 
Just because you ask for &quot;lots&quot; doesnt mean you will get them. They
are probably told there is a limit to how many they can give out.
Although, isnt that stuff in bowls inside for people to get how many
they want? Cant you just go in and take a handful like most greedy
people do?

Taco Bell food does NOT taste best with their sauce in MY opinion. In
MY opinion it tastes best with NO sauce.

 Reply 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages? by Jeffrey Posted Sat February 3, 2007 @ 6:44 AM 
 
While 1 is clear not &quot;lots,&quot; it&apos;s a non-specific term. You need to
ask for what you want. They, on the other hand, have the right to
turn you down. In my opinion, 1 sauce per item ordered is fair.
1.5-2 per item would be nice.

Here&apos;s the thing: you had the Pace at home. Why not use it? Or buy
other kinds of sauce. There are some excellent hot ones out there.
You can even buy Taco Bell sauce in the grocery.

That way, you can avoid this issue.

 Reply 
 
 
 
 buying taco bell sauce in stores by dahbird Tue March 13, 2007 @ 5:05 PM 
 
 
 
 
 
 Re: Sauce Shortages? by Peregrina Posted Sat February 3, 2007 @ 1:35 AM 
 
Next time be specific. Say &apos;five each&apos; or &apos;half dozen&apos; or something
like that. One person&apos;s lots and lots is another&apos;s &apos;two&apos;.

 Reply 
 
 
 
 I don&apos;t mind paying by C B Sun February 4, 2007 @ 10:18 PM 
 
 
 


 


 
 
 

 
 Home | Shared Letters | Ratings | Login | Communities | Categories | RSS | Contact Us | Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Policy | FAQ Copyright 2012©All Rights Reserved PlanetFeedback.com | Web by Cicada
	</body>
</document>
