<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005193" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/302019-free-tote-bag-w-Food-Network-mag-subscription" time="2012-07-12-21:43" support="4" score="0.011537487529716436" bingtitle="free tote bag w/Food Network mag subscription" webtitle="free tote bag w/Food Network mag subscription">
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>... the mail; instead I will receive a clearly marked reminder notice with the then current rate at least 45 days before my credit card ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals free tote bag w/Food Network mag subscription 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Results 1 to 1 of 1 
Thread: free tote bag w/Food Network mag subscription 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 02-13-2012,  11:41 AM #1 katland 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2006 Posts 16,928 
free tote bag w/Food Network mag subscription
 www.tote.foodnetworkmag.com 

free tote bag with paid order, while supplies last

Each term includes the features of the Continuous Service Program*
1 year for just $15 SAVE 62%!
2 years for just $25 SAVE 69% Best Deal!

*Continuous Service Program: I understand that unless I tell you otherwise I will receive uninterrupted service and delivery of Food Network Magazine, and my subscription will be automatically renewed at the end of each subscription term, at the rate then in effect and I authorize Food Network Magazine to charge the credit/debit card I have provided. I won&apos;t be bothered with any renewal notices in the mail; instead I will receive a clearly marked reminder notice with the then current rate at least 45 days before my credit card is charged. I may opt out of the automatic renewal at any time by contacting customer service. Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
