<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005085" url="http://www.antiqueimmo.com/2011/05/09/watch-the-monaco-grand-prix-2011-qualifying-from-a-balcony-overlooking-the-startfinish-line/" time="2012-07-12-21:36" support="1" score="0.0023188907078843554" bingtitle="Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 Qualifying from a Balcony ..." webtitle="Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 Qualifying from a Balcony overlooking the Start/Finish Line! | Antique Immo Real Estate">
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>... the departure line, Saint Devote corner and hill, tunnel exit ... For Sale: Fast Food restaurant – Nice Centre Ville; For Sale: Rights to Lease – Nice Port / Place ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Businesses 
 All Businesses 
 Businesses in Nice Riviera Businesses 
 List Your Business 
 Villas&amp;Apartments 
 All Villas 
 Villas in Nice Riviera Villas 
 All Apartments 
 Apartments in Nice Riviera Apartments 
 Land List Your Property 
 Advice 
 Advice for Buyers Advice for Sellers 
 List Your Property 
 Glossary of Real Estate Terms 
 Blog Finance Partners Contact SELL NOW! 
 FOR SALE: Wonderful, Must-See F2 Apartment–Cap d’Antibes Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 from a Panoramic view of the track! 
Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 Qualifying from a Balcony overlooking the Start/Finish Line!
 
 With this exclusive package, guests will have the opportunity to view the 28th May Qualifying race from a private terrace situated on the 3rd Floor of Heracles Block B , one of the principal buildings on the Port front. 

 
 

 With this location, you and your guests will be situated directly over the grid&amp;Start/Finish line, and will have superb views of the departure line, Saint Devote corner and hill, tunnel exit, port and pool area, and the pit lane exit. You will be in the middle of the buzz, over the Prince’s lodge, in the heart of the action. 

 

 

Included in this fantastic price is an open bar for all of your guests!

 28th May–200€ per person. 

 
 
Related Articles:

 29th May 2011–Charity Music and Dance Show at Nice’s Theatre de Verdure! Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 from a Prime View of the track–with open Champagne Bar! Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 from a Panoramic view of the track! Electric Cars come to Nice! 
 Like what you see? For more information please e-mail antiqueimmorealestate@hotmail.fr or contact us via our easy online Contact Form. Please don’t forget to include the property reference in your mail.

Whilst we make every effort to ensure all information given is accurate, please note that all the information above is non-contractual.
 Tagged with: 2011 • apartment • balcony • cheap • end • finish line • grand • grand prix • luxury • monaco • monte-carlo • overlooking • panoramic • port • prix • start • starting line • view • VIP 
  
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
 
Sign up for our newsletter!
 Email Address : 
Recent Posts…

 For Sale–F2-Type Apartment in Nice–Promenade des Anglais–Sea View! For Sale: F1-Type Apartment in Nice Commercial Property in Beaulieu-sur-Mer For Sale For Sale: F1-Type Apartment–Nice Gambetta Right to Lease for Sale in Nice’s Prestigious Carré D’Or! Business Activity For Sale: Fast Food restaurant–Nice Centre Ville For Sale: Rights to Lease–Nice Port / Place Garibaldi–Open to all business types! 29th May 2011–Charity Music and Dance Show at Nice’s Theatre de Verdure! Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 from a Prime View of the track–with open Champagne Bar! Watch the Monaco Grand Prix 2011 from a Panoramic view of the track! 
 
 
Recent Posts

 For Sale–F2-Type Apartment in Nice–Promenade des Anglais–Sea View! For Sale: F1-Type Apartment in Nice Commercial Property in Beaulieu-sur-Mer For Sale For Sale: F1-Type Apartment–Nice Gambetta Right to Lease for Sale in Nice’s Prestigious Carré D’Or! Business Activity For Sale: Fast Food restaurant–Nice Centre Ville For Sale: Rights to Lease–Nice Port / Place Garibaldi–Open to all business types! 
 
 Translate 
 
 Select Language Afrikaans Albanian Arabic Armenian Azerbaijani Basque Belarusian Bulgarian Catalan Chinese (Simplified) Chinese (Traditional) Croatian Czech Danish Dutch English Estonian Filipino Finnish French Galician Georgian German Greek Haitian Creole Hebrew Hindi Hungarian Icelandic Indonesian Irish Italian Japanese Korean Latvian Lithuanian Macedonian Malay Maltese Norwegian Persian Polish Portuguese Romanian Russian Serbian Slovak Slovenian Spanish Swahili Swedish Thai Turkish Ukrainian Urdu Vietnamese Welsh Yiddish Javascript is required to use this website translator , site translator , automatic translation , machine translation
	</body>
</document>
