<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005570" url="http://www.gainesville.com/article/20110807/articles/110809712" time="2012-07-12-22:07" support="1" score="0.000447069923035091" bingtitle="Tough job market for high school students | Gainesville.com" webtitle="Tough job market for high school students | Gainesville.com">
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>Fast-food restaurant Chick-fil-A hires employees as young as 16. Steve Carroll, owner of the ... Postal Worker Rally In Support HR 1351 Bill</description>
	<body>
		Gainesville.com GatorSports.com Gainesville Magazine Scene Moms Guardian Pets Mugshots 
 Register | Log in   
 News Web Search by YAHOO! 
 Web Search
by YAHOO! | Home Delivery | eSUN | Print Ads | Mobile | Place Ad 
 Home News 
 Local News Campus State Nation Business Crime Elections Data Center Videos Weather Mugshots Gainesville Guardian In Education Archive 
 

 Sports 
 Prep Sports Gatorsports.com NFL MLB NBA NHL Golf Auto Racing Tickets 
 

 Entertainment 
 Dining Movies Arts Music Events Videos Games TV Listings Tickets 
 

 Living 
 Health Crossword Sudoku Coupons 
 

 Opinion 
 Send a Letter to the Editor Virtual Town Hall 
 

 Blogs Obituaries 
 Submit an Obituary Funeral Home Directory Send Flowers&amp;Gifts 
 Classifieds 
 Merchandise Boats Motorcycles Yard Sales Pets Roommates Services Announcements Personals Print Ads Place an Ad Enhance Your Ad 
 

 Real Estate 
 For Sale Find an Agent Moving Here Open Houses 
 Jobs Cars 
 Home Article Repository 
 Comments Share 
 Digg Reddit LinkedIn Mixx Technorati Myspace 

 FARK FURL 
 Email Print 
 WITH PHOTO NO PHOTO 
 Reprints Enlarge Text 
 Tweet 
 Teens try to compete for limited jobs in the retail sector and fast-food industry 
 
Rashad Harding, right, stands at the entrance to Abercrombie&amp;Fitch in the Oaks Mall on Wednesday, July 13.
 Jenny Wilkinson/Correspondent By Larry Truong
Correspondent
 
Published: Sunday, August 7, 2011 at 6:01 a.m.

Last Modified: Friday, August 5, 2011 at 5:18 p.m.
 
In a town full of college students, high schoolers often have a hard time competing for summer jobs with older and more qualified applicants. But what they lack in age and experience, high schoolers can make up for in preparation, dedication and enthusiasm.
 
Rashad Harding, 18, who graduated from P.K. Yonge Developmental Research School in May, not only has a summer job, he has three. He is working at two apparel stores at the Oaks Mall—Abercrombie&amp;Fitch and American Eagle Outfitters—and also at Vector Marketing as a kitchen cutlery salesperson.

He has worked for Abercrombie&amp;Fitch, which was his first job, since last summer, and started at American Eagle and Vector this summer.

&quot;It was actually really easy because I always come really prepared,&quot; Harding said about securing his summer jobs. &quot;A lot of people don&apos;t expect an 18-year-old to have a resume and cover letter.&quot;

Harding said he also did research on each of the companies before he went in for the interview to find out more about each company&apos;s expectations. He said that doing this type of preparation, along with dressing the part for each job during the interview, helped him get hired.

&quot;You have to apply early, not whenever you feel like it,&quot; he said.

Nationally, the teen unemployment rate stands at 24.5 percent, almost three times the national unemployment rate, according to the Employment Policies Institute, a nonprofit research organization dedicated to studying public policy issues surrounding employment growth. Teens classified as &quot;unemployed&quot; are those who are actively seeking a job but can&apos;t get one.

Florida&apos;s unemployment rate for 16- to 19-year-olds is 29.4 percent, the ninth highest in the nation. The state with the highest teenage unemployment rate is California at 34.6 percent.

Despite the discouraging numbers, teenage workers typically turn to the retail sector, including fast-food restaurants and retail clothing stores, to seek work. Another attractive—albeit competitive—option for teenagers is working at the neighborhood pool.

Jeff Moffitt, aquatics supervisor of Gainesville&apos;s three community pools, said there are currently five high school students working as lifeguards or pool attendants this summer. He said that although he does hire teenagers, they have to have CPR and lifeguard certifications and keep those certifications up-to-date.

Fast-food restaurant Chick-fil-A hires employees as young as 16. Steve Carroll, owner of the Chick-fil-A at the Oaks Mall for 33 years, said that nearly 40 percent of his current employees are teenagers.

He said that when he&apos;s looking to hire any employee, the first impression he or she makes is the most important.

&quot;Are they pleasant? Can they smile? Can they communicate?&quot; said Carroll about what he looks for during the interview. &quot;But first of all, they need to be themselves. If they don&apos;t have those traits, it&apos;ll wear off real quick.&quot;

Allyson Livingston, 17, started working at Carroll&apos;s store at the start of summer.

A rising senior at Cornerstone Christian Academy, Livingston said she was well prepared for her job interview after getting plenty of practice in her high school speech and debate class.

&quot;My teacher knew we were at the age to get jobs, so we went over interviewing techniques,&quot; she said. &quot;We practiced not being shy and being ourselves.&quot;

Livingston advises other high school students applying for jobs to relax.

&quot;Don&apos;t sweat it,&quot; she said. &quot;They&apos;re not there to attack you. They just want to ask you questions to get to know you.&quot;
 Teens try to compete for limited jobs in the retail sector and fast-food industry By Larry Truong Rashad Harding, right, stands at the entrance to Abercrombie&amp;Fitch in the Oaks Mall on Wednesday, July 13. Gainesville.com August 5, 2011 5:18 PM &lt;p&gt;In a town full of college students, high schoolers often have a hard time competing for summer jobs with older and more qualified applicants. But what they lack in age and experience, high schoolers can make up for in preparation, dedication and enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rashad Harding, 18, who graduated from P.K. Yonge Developmental Research School in May, not only has a summer job, he has three. He is working at two apparel stores at the Oaks Mall—Abercrombie&amp;Fitch and American Eagle Outfitters—and also at Vector Marketing as a kitchen cutlery salesperson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He has worked for Abercrombie&amp;Fitch, which was his first job, since last summer, and started at American Eagle and Vector this summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;It was actually really easy because I always come really prepared,&quot;Harding said about securing his summer jobs.&quot;A lot of people don&apos;t expect an 18-year-old to have a resume and cover letter.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harding said he also did research on each of the companies before he went in for the interview to find out more about each company&apos;s expectations. He said that doing this type of preparation, along with dressing the part for each job during the interview, helped him get hired.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;You have to apply early, not whenever you feel like it,&quot;he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nationally, the teen unemployment rate stands at 24.5 percent, almost three times the national unemployment rate, according to the Employment Policies Institute, a nonprofit research organization dedicated to studying public policy issues surrounding employment growth. Teens classified as&quot;unemployed&quot;are those who are actively seeking a job but can&apos;t get one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Florida&apos;s unemployment rate for 16- to 19-year-olds is 29.4 percent, the ninth highest in the nation. The state with the highest teenage unemployment rate is California at 34.6 percent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the discouraging numbers, teenage workers typically turn to the retail sector, including fast-food restaurants and retail clothing stores, to seek work. Another attractive—albeit competitive—option for teenagers is working at the neighborhood pool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeff Moffitt, aquatics supervisor of Gainesville&apos;s three community pools, said there are currently five high school students working as lifeguards or pool attendants this summer. He said that although he does hire teenagers, they have to have CPR and lifeguard certifications and keep those certifications up-to-date.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fast-food restaurant Chick-fil-A hires employees as young as 16. Steve Carroll, owner of the Chick-fil-A at the Oaks Mall for 33 years, said that nearly 40 percent of his current employees are teenagers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said that when he&apos;s looking to hire any employee, the first impression he or she makes is the most important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Are they pleasant? Can they smile? Can they communicate?&quot;said Carroll about what he looks for during the interview.&quot;But first of all, they need to be themselves. If they don&apos;t have those traits, it&apos;ll wear off real quick.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allyson Livingston, 17, started working at Carroll&apos;s store at the start of summer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rising senior at Cornerstone Christian Academy, Livingston said she was well prepared for her job interview after getting plenty of practice in her high school speech and debate class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;My teacher knew we were at the age to get jobs, so we went over interviewing techniques,&quot;she said.&quot;We practiced not being shy and being ourselves.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Livingston advises other high school students applying for jobs to relax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Don&apos;t sweat it,&quot;she said.&quot;They&apos;re not there to attack you. They just want to ask you questions to get to know you.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; Copyright 2012 Gainesville.com - All rights reserved. Restricted use only. 
All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published 
 without permission. Links are encouraged.
 ▲Return to Top 
 Most Read Most Emailed Most Recent 
 
 Zook taking break from huddle Tebow gets ESPY nod for Best Moment City spraying in earnest after Debby&apos;s deluge sends mosquitoes swarming UF student injured in June hit-and-run dies overnight Review: Latest &apos;Ice Age&apos; will delight the little ones 
 
 Zook taking break from huddle City spraying in earnest after Debby&apos;s deluge sends mosquitoes swarming Recovery center ready to open in old Residence Inn UF student injured in June hit-and-run dies overnight Cats, dogs adopted out for $5 each on Saturday 
 
 Jack Otero: Getting the regulations right PASSAGES program easing girls into middle school More documents released in Trayvon Martin case Deputies: Man raped 3-year-old while mom was away Biden tells NAACP Obama stands by his convictions 
 
 Photos 

 
 Ron Zook at Brantley Quarterback Camp 
 
 Passages Workshop 
 
 Photos of the day 
 
 UF&amp;Shands;Florida Recovery Center Opens 
 
 Live Oak Flood Residents Revisited 
 
 Local Weather 
 
 
Events Calendar More Events Submit Event 

 12 Thu 13 Fri 14 Sat 15 Sun 16 Mon 
 
 Find Local Businesses 
 
 Keyword(s): Location: Popular Searches Apartments in Gainesville 
 Attorneys in Gainesville 
 Auto Dealers in Gainesville 
 Auto Parts in Gainesville 
 Auto Repair in Gainesville 
 Beauty Salons in Gainesville 
 Car Rental in Gainesville 
 Dentists in Gainesville 
 Doctors in Gainesville 
 Flowers in Gainesville 
 Hotels in Gainesville 
 Insurance in Gainesville 
 Loans in Gainesville 
 Mortgages in Gainesville 
 Movers in Gainesville 
 Pizza in Gainesville 
 Realtors in Gainesville 
 Restaurants in Gainesville 
 Storage in Gainesville 
 Tax Preparation in Gainesville 
 Travel in Gainesville 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com 
 
 News 

 Photo Galleries World Local News Campus State Nation/World Business Videos Weather News Archive 
 
 Multimedia 

 Photos Blogs 
 
 Sports 

 Prep Sports Professional Sports Photos Gatorsports.com Tickets 
 
 Entertainment 

 Dining Movies Arts Music Events Videos TV Listings Tickets 
 
 Living 

 Travel&amp;Style Crossword Sudoku Horoscope Photos Coupons In Education 
 
 Real Estate 

 For Sale Find an Agent Open Houses Moving Here Gainesville Apartments 
 
 Classifieds 

 Services Legal Rentals Autos Place an Ad Enhance Your Ad Local Businesses 
 
 Contact Us About Us Advertising Subscribe Work for Us Help Privacy Policy About Our Ads Corrections RSS Terms of Service Photo Reprints Site Map 
 Copyright©2012 Gainesville.com—All rights reserved. Restricted use only.
	</body>
</document>
