<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005866" url="http://www.activediner.com/restaurant/homepage.cfm?CID=211920&amp;WRID=101&amp;CBID=" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="1" score="0.007866537985968142" bingtitle="Ponchos Mexican Restaurant Overview, Special 50% Off Offers, 2319 ..." webtitle="Ponchos Mexican Restaurant Overview, 2319 Gratiot, Marysville, MI, 48040, (810) 364-3663 - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>... times we&apos;ve had to ask for the manager just to get the order ... American, Burger, Fast Food It&apos;s a fast food restaurant...what&apos;da expect, eh?</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Chinese 
 Mexican 
 Burger 
 Chicken 
 
 more... 
 American Breakfast Burger Business Lunch Casual/Family Catering Chicken Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Deli/Sandwich/Subs Diner Dinner Fast Food Fine Dining Kids Friendly Lunch Mexican Pizzeria Scenic View Wheelchair Access 
 
 


Nearby Cities
 Detroit 
 Warren 
 Sterling Heights 
 Southfield 
 Dearborn 
 
 more... 
 Auburn Hills Birmingham Canton Dearborn Heights Eastpointe Farmington Hills Ferndale Lincoln Park Madison Heights Monroe Mount Clemens New Baltimore Novi Plymouth Pontiac Port Huron Redford Rochester Rochester Hills Romulus Roseville Royal Oak Saint Clair Shores Southgate Taylor Trenton Utica West Bloomfield Westland Wyandotte 
 
 



 
Dining Specials
 24grille 
 - American, Continental, Sports Bar and Grill, Banquet/Party Room Restaurant in
Detroit 
 
5.0|Fantastic restaurant! I will go back frequently. Great food with very unique menu. All American Deli - Waterford 
 - American, Casual/Family, Catering, Children&apos;s Menu Restaurant in
Waterford 
 
5.0|Fresh and Friendly 
 
 


 
 United States &gt; Michigan &gt; Marysville Restaurant Guide (1 ratings) 
Ponchos Mexican Restaurant
 (810) 364-3663 
 2319 Gratiot, Marysville, MI 48040 | MAP 
   | Share | Features 
 American , Mexican , Casual/Family , Catering , Children&apos;s Menu , Kids Friendly , Wheelchair Access , Dinner , Lunch ( Mexican Food&amp;Culture History )



 
 Overview 
   
 Reviews (1) 
   
 Map 
   
 



 UPDATE THIS LISTING 
 
Recent Ponchos Mexican Restaurant Reviews
 gave an overall rating of on October 24, 2001 @ 11:41 PM

  Good &quot;Mexican&quot; food at a fair price. The waitress was delightful...just a kid but so eager to be of service. 
 American Polish Cultural Center 
 
 American, Comfort Food/Home Cooking, Polish, Alcohol Restaurant in
Troy 
 Hoops 
 
 American, Sports Bar and Grill, Bar, Billiard/Pool Tables Restaurant in
Auburn Hills 
 McRaes Big River Grille 
 
 American, Bistro, Banquet/Party Room, Bar Restaurant in
Algonac 
   »   See All Marysville Restaurant Coupons &amp; Deals 
 
 advertisements 




 
Reviews of Similar Restaurants
 Burger King   
 American, Burger, Fast Food 
  We did not like the place! Micky D is much better. Play land etc. Burger King   
 American, Burger, Fast Food 
  It&apos;s a fast food restaurant...what&apos;da expect, eh?
They serve a filling, decent breakfast...almost as good as Micky D&apos;s. KFC   
 American, Burger, Fast Food 
  Why is it, we come in and get the newest member of the serving staff...purely ignorant! The past two times we&apos;ve had to ask for the manager just to get the order straighened out! 

   »  Read More:   Marysville Restaurant Reviews 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
