<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005353" url="http://www.couriermail.com.au/news/breaking-news/mcdonalds-cashier-rayan-mcintosh-sacked-after-fracturing-womans-skull-with-metal-rod/story-e6freonf-1226168015417" time="2012-07-12-21:54" support="2" score="0.003644330234309794" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s cashier Rayan McIntosh sacked after fracturing woman&apos;s ..." webtitle="McDonalds cashier Rayan McIntosh sacked after fracturing womans skull with metal rod |
			The Courier-Mail">
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="180"/>
	<description>Food+Drink; Homes+Property; Out+About; Families; QWeekend ... A NEW York City McDonald&apos;s cashier savagely beat two ... cuts from the early Thursday brawl at the fast food restaurant on ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to: Main Content Site Navigation Site Footer Site Search Site Map Network Navigation (other sites) news.com.au Fox Sports CareerOne Carsguide RealEstate News Network The Courier-Mail 
 
 News Sport 
 NRL SuperCoach AFL Olympics Rugby Gold Racing Cricket Soccer Motor Golf Tennis Local Sport All sports 
 Life 
 What&apos;s On Food+Drink Homes+Property Out+About Families QWeekend Weekend Getaways 
 Business 
 Breaking News QLD commercial property Markets Dollar Worklife Boardroom Radio Property News 
 Entertainment 
 Celebrity Movies Television Music Books Crossword Horoscopes Competitions 
 Money 
 Banking Property Money Matters Superannuation Investing Interest Rates Guides&amp;Tools Blogs 
 Travel 
 Travel News Australia World Holiday Ideas Holiday Deals Travel Advice Galleries 
 Opinion 
 Letter to the Editor Our Staff Blogs 
 Video CLASSIFIEDS 
 Sell your car Deaths, funerals Real Estate Business Directory Shopping Wego Travel Deals Search Listings Place an Ad Weekend Shopper 
 Tributes National 
 The Australian news.com.au The Punch FOXSPORTS SportingPulse Business Spectator Eureka Report 
 State and Territory 
 The Telegraph Courier Mail Herald Sun AdelaideNow Perth Now NT News The Mercury 
 Regional and Community 
 Townsville Bulletin Cairns.com.au Goldcoast.com.au Geelong Advertiser Weekly Times Now Community Newspapers 
 Classifieds 
 Classifieds Place my ad CareerOne Carsguide Realestate.com.au TrueLocal 
 Lifestyle 
 Vogue Taste Kidspot body+soul homelife 
 Marketplace 
 Moshtix Foxtix Getprice Shopferret OurDeal WeGo Travel Learning Seat 
 
 
 Breaking Local Queensland National World Technology Weird Galleries body+soul Pride of Australia 
 
 Last updated: July 13, 2012 Search for: 
 Weather: Brisbane 17 °C -
 22 °C .
 A few showers.
 
Julia Gillard
 
 The PM on G20 
 
Why summit will be a winner for Brisbane
 Read More 
Mongrel mystery
 
 Doggy DNA 
 
It&apos;s crazy to peer into your pooches&apos; past
 Read More 
Des Houghton
 
 Asylum concerns 
 
Is ASIO struggling to protect our borders?
 Read More 
 Breaking News 
 
McDonald&apos;s cashier Rayan McIntosh sacked after fracturing woman&apos;s skull with metal rod
 
 by: From correspondents in New York From: NewsCore October 16, 2011 9:29PM 
 
 Increase Text Size Decrease Text Size Print Email Share 
 Add to Digg Add to del.icio.us Add to Facebook Add to Kwoff Add to Myspace Add to Newsvine What are these? 
 
 
 A NEW York City McDonald&apos;s cashier savagely beat two women customers with a metal rod after they jumped the counter - a disturbing bashing caught on camera and posted to YouTube. 
 
&quot;Stop it! Stop! Stop! Oh, my God!&quot;one woman is heard screaming in the video, which has been viewed more than 700,000 times.&quot;Someone call police!&quot;

One woman was left with a fractured skull and broken arm, and the other suffered cuts from the early Thursday brawl at the fast food restaurant on West Third Street near Sixth Avenue in Manhattan, the New York Post reported.

Rayon McIntosh, 31, of The Bronx - who in 2000 was convicted of manslaughter - was charged with assault and criminal possession of a weapon.

Customers Denise Darbeau, 24, of Queens, and Rachel Edwards, 24, of Brooklyn, were charged with menacing, according to WPIX-TV.

The restaurant&apos;s owner, Carmen Paulino, told NBC New York she was&quot;extremely disturbed&quot;by the events.
 
&quot;The actions of this individual are unacceptable and not characteristic of my employees,&quot;she said.&quot;This individual no longer works for my organisation.&quot;

But while some people have been outraged by the actions of McIntosh, others are calling him a hero.

The Rayon McIntosh Defense Fund has been set up on Facebook and is just one of several cyber-support pages.

The 31-year-old worker&apos;s dad is also solidly in his son&apos;s corner.

&quot;You can&apos;t go into a person&apos;s workplace and attack them,&quot;Rayon McIntosh Sr., 54, told the Post .&quot;Let&apos;s be real now - this was self-defence.&quot;

The fight began when the women swore at McIntosh after he questioned a $50 note they passed him.

Darbeau slapped him and jumped over the counter as her friend jumped into the fray.
 
 Increase Text Size Decrease Text Size Print Email Share 
 Add to Digg Add to del.icio.us Add to Facebook Add to Kwoff Add to Myspace Add to Newsvine What are these? 
 
 
 Back to top of page 
 
lifestyle
 
 Best Bastille Day Recipe Ideas 
 
Why not have a French feast to celebrate?
 Read More 
 How to make crepes DIY onion soup Taste 
 
 Celebrity Post Labour Cravings 
 
What did Kourtney Kardashian covet?
 Read More 
 Pink&apos;s cute daughter Yummy mummies Kidspot 
 
 Health Style Food Home Beauty Parenting 
 
 MOST POPULAR BREAKING NEWS 
 
Most Read
 
 Teary dad fears for missing couple &apos;Boob photo&apos; cop wins appeal Motorists brace for Riverside closure Katie&apos;s secret phone calls to Nicole Kidman How much has your suburb changed? Missing in a land of ghosts and gold Mark takes aim at officials Welcome to the new Australian alps New G20 public holiday comes at a cost Jobseekers start to give up hope 
 
 5:43AM Pressure on Assad as envoy defects 5:38AM Opel CEO resigns in middle of turnaround 5:22AM Israeli jailed over US cash-for-kidneys 5:17AM Indians have low eco impact, but feel guiltiest 5:14AM Boeing unveils United mega-deal 4:46AM US targets Iran entities with sanctions 4:39AM Town designates tricky parking&apos;men only&apos; 4:31AM Xstrata merger vote on September 7 4:31AM Chenoweth recovering after Good Wife hit 4:19AM Peugeot slashes 8000 jobs in France 
 
 More Breaking News 
 
Website feedback 
 
Report issues or suggestions for our website and iPad app. Or use this form to alert us to something we&apos;ve got wrong. We value your feedback.
 Your Name * Your email address * Your feedback * Write your feedback here and if your comment relates specifically to this story, please copy and paste its web link. Submit 
Also in Couriermail.com.au
 
 Top Stories 
 
 Missing in a land of ghosts and gold 
 
 Peter Michael POLICE are investigating reports of gunshots in the remote Palmer River goldfields on Cape York, where a prospector has vanished.
 
 Score: New G20 public holiday comes at a cost Mess: Unpaid fines flying towards $1 billion Fail: Jobseekers start to give up hope 
 
 SPORT 
 
 Cadel can still win: van Garderen 
 
 5:39AM Leo Schlink AMERICAN Tejay van Garderen is backing Cadel Evans to make a Lazarus-like recovery and successfully defend the Tour de France title.
 
 Controversy: Froome defied team orders: boss Stoush: Mark takes aim at officials Shifty behaviour: Games produce rings of liars 
 
 LIFE 
 
 Best coffee south of the river 
 
 4:12PM Find out where to get the best brew south of the Brisbane river. It&apos;s about celebrating the places that get the magic mix of great coffee, spot-on service and a setting that inspires us or lets us quietly escape whatever it is we might need to run away from for a while.
 
 Best brunches on Brisbane&apos;s northside Around the world in 10 Brisbane restaurants Best breakfasts on Brisbane&apos;s southside 
 
 Business 
 
 Mine output slumps as exports fall 
 
 10:30PM John McCarthy QUEENSLAND mining is hitting a wall, losing production worth $3 billion in the March quarter as coal prices go into a tailspin. 
 
 Employment woes: Dollar dips on jobless rise Top con: &apos;Clever fraud&apos; looted public servants Sell-off: Mitsui buys $100m slice of National 
 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 
 Katie &apos;Sherlock&apos; Holmes went under radar 
 
KATIE Holmes reportedly used a disposable mobile phone to keep in touch with lawyers as she plotted her divorce from Tom Cruise.
 
 Unforgettable: Do you remember when that was on TV? The Rolling Stones: 7 reasons we love the veteran rockers ESPY: Forget Wimbledon: Maria&apos;s a winner on red carpet 
 
 Weird 
 
 &apos;A shark! It&apos;s a big-ass shark!&apos; 
 
 9:50AM GIRL accidentally hooks a shark. 
 
 Dandenong: Man jumps on bonnet in road attack Video : &apos;I&apos;m either getting struck by lightning or I&apos;m breaking a leg&apos; Tokyo: Fishy experience: Tokyo&apos;s colourful frozen tuna auctions 
 
 Mobile RSS Feeds Newsletters Send Stories Send Your Photos 
 
 About Us Contact Us Get your Newspaper Delivered Advertise with us Sponsorship Journalism Program Job Opportunities Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy Accessibility Sitemap 

©2012 News Queensland. All times AEST (GMT +10:00).
	</body>
</document>
