<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005069" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Hopewell/Hardees_670" time="2012-07-12-21:35" support="1" score="0.0006603481115714161" bingtitle="Hardees - Fast Food Restaurant Hopewell, VA" webtitle="Hardees - Fast Food Restaurant  Hopewell, VA">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="165"/>
	<description>Hardees is a Fast Food restaurant located at 2915 Oaklawn ... For those who like a quiet meal I suggest eating in the non ... Trash for a cause</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Hardees
 
Average User Rating
 
8
 
Great

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(804) 458-0360

 http://www.hardees.com/ 
 VA &gt; Hopewell &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Hardees listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Hardees to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Hardees
 Hardees is a Fast Food restaurant located at 2915 Oaklawn Blvd in Hopewell, VA . Hardees has been described as an Great Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 8 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Burgers, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Hardees
 
 
 
All Reviews for Hardees

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
8
 
Decor
 
8
 
Service
 
8
 
The food here is great! The service is very good. The waiters are very friendly. For those who like a quiet meal I suggest eating in the non smoking section, there aren&apos;t too many people in there. Overall, the food is good old home cooking!
 
Overall Rating
 
8
 
&quot;Great&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Hardees:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
Hardees News
 Who finances the Occupy movement? According to the Overview on the New York Times’ Times Topic site dedicated to collecting ... Fritz, Davenport A: Papa Bear’s Family Restaurant, which opened in April 2009 in a former Hardee’s restaurant at 2202 Rockingham Road, is indeed closed ... Opinion column: D.C. rules strangling job creators Recently, the chief executive officer of CKE Restaurants, which operates the Carl’s Jr. and Hardee’s chains, said his company would ... Both cited the cumulative effect of new regulations. The list could go on and on for nearly every sector ... Hall remembers those lost in 2011 In the 1960s, Clown was living in New York City and had ... Turk owned several businesses, mostly restaurants, during his lifetime, including Burger Chef on Green Street and Atlanta Highway, and several Hardees eateries throughout the area. Trash for a cause The Buffalinos lived in New ... restaurants, we are a one-stop shop,&quot; Kelly said. &quot;We can take their garbage, take their recycling, and can pump their grease traps through Inman Septic.&quot; Right now, Coastal Ladies does grease traps at a Hardee&apos;s ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Hardee’s® Freshly prepared, premium, all-white meat chicken hand-dipped in buttermilk, lightly breaded and fried to a golden brown then smothered in Frank&apos;s® Red Hot® Buffalo ... Hardees Restaurant - American Restaurant Columbia, SC There&apos;s a new diners&apos; guide ... even among restaurants that meet some of ROC United&apos;s criteria. Is it better to buy lunch at In-N-Out Burger, where employees receive ... Hardee&apos;s Locations - Hardee&apos;s Restaurant Locator If you&apos;re looking for a burger chain featuring Southern styled comfort foods, you&apos;ll find it at Hardee&apos;s. Use our Hardee&apos;s restaurant locator list to find the ... Hardee&apos;s - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Hardee&apos;s is a restaurant chain, located mostly in the Southeast and Midwestern regions of the United States. It has evolved through several corporate ownerships since ... Hardee&apos;s Restaurant - Swainsboro, GA (478) 237-9277 · 501 S Main St · &quot;Sausage biscuits are always good, try with extra butter on top! Cinnamon biscuits are also a favorite of mine. Staff is OK, but ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Address
 
Hardees

2915 Oaklawn Blvd

Hopewell, VA 
 

 
Telephone
 (804) 458-0360 
Hardees
 
 Rating :  8 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Hardees Photos
 
 Fast Food Burgers American 
 
 Local Places
 
 Hardees 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hardees 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hardee&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food KFC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Huddle House 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Artistacuba 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Gallery 14 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries St Dennis Chapel Museum 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Frame Shop 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Amboy National Bank 
Cuisine: ATMs 
 

See all Hopewell Art Museums Galleries 
See all Hopewell ATMs 
See all Hopewell Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Hardees Coupons 

 Hardees Hopewell 

 Hardees Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Hopewell Restaurants 
 B | C | D | E | F | H | K | L M | N | P | S | T | V 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
