<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005379" url="http://www.gklife.com/2009/12/10/top-10-drinks-make-you-fat/" time="2012-07-12-21:55" support="1" score="0.0009047754722724774" bingtitle="Top 10 Drinks That Make You Fat | GK Life" webtitle="Top 10 Drinks That Make You Fat | GK Life">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="41"/>
	<description>10 drinks you should ... 500 calories a glass. 7)A smaller size does not always include a smaller calorie count. A small chocolate shake at a fast food restaurant like ...</description>
	<body>
		WOMEN MEN LIFE HEALTH BUSINESS TECHNOLOGY 
 Loading 
 Arts and Culture Food and Drink Home and Garden Travel 
 
Top 10 Drinks That Make You Fat
 Dec 10, 2009 
Dec 10, 2009

 | Posted by in Featured , Food and Drink | 0 Comments 
 



Ten Drinks over 300 Calories


While people become more and more aware of what is in their food, the calorie content of what we drink can often be overlooked. Dieters struggle and watch what they eat when really they may need to watch what they drink. You can pour on ten pounds in a single year, just by drinking one soda per day! Over a few years, this can really add up. If you are a habitual drinker of sugary drinks, and you’re having trouble losing weight, cutting out these empty calories may be the best way to drop a few pounds quickly.





Don’t let the hidden calories in your beverages sabotage your weight loss! Here are ten drinks with 300 or more calories that you should be aware of.


1) A Starbucks 24-oz Caramel Frappuccino Blended Coffee has 380 calories, and that’s without the whipped cream. Whipped cream would make the same drink 500 calories. (24-oz is the Venti size). That morning coffee has as many calories as a slice of apple pie.


2) Starbucks has many coffee drinks, but the blended drinks lead the pack in terms of calories. A 16-oz Vanilla Bean Frappuccino Blended Crème (16-oz is a Grande) has 470 calories.


3) But don’t let brand names influence what you drink. Just a tall mocha containing whole milk and whipped cream has 360 calories. That’s universal wherever you buy a cup of coffee.


4)Beware of drinks that seem healthy, for they can be hiding many calories, too. A 26 oz. Jamba Juice Pennya Cowlada has almost 700 calories! Just for the record, the calorie count information is based on a 2000 calorie a day diet. This one juice drink would consume 35\% of those calories.


5)As smoothies become more and more popular, they are added to many fast food menus. A smoothie, like a juice drink, connotes health. But all of the 24-oz, large-size smoothies on the Jack in the Box menu have over 400 calories.


6)Alcohol is generally not calorie intensive, with wine and beer coming in under 200 calories a glass, but mixed drinks, like daiquiris, may have over 500 calories a glass.


7)A smaller size does not always include a smaller calorie count. A small chocolate shake at a fast food restaurant like McDonalds has 440 calories.


8)Sodas may not seem like such a bad option but most cans and bottles give the caloric information in 8-ounce servings. Most Americans drink far more than 8 ounces. Most large fast food sodas are 32 ounces, which is around 400 calories.


9)A 7-Eleven 44-oz Super Big Gulp of most sugary sodas on tap will have over 500 calories.


10)Kids’ drinks can be laden with calories. A Nesquik 16-oz bottle of chocolate milk has 400 calories.



If you need some great alternatives to sugary drinks, try these:



 Iced tea, or fruit flavored teas 

 Flavored packets of sugar free mixes for water 

 Diet Soda (It may be calorie free, but you should still watch out for acidity). If you need to cut back slowly, try mixing your regular soda half and half with a diet version. You’ll slowly get used to the taste of the artificial sweeteners. 


For more great tips about food and drinks check out our food and drink section.

 
 
 Share this: Share 
 
 
 
YOU MIGHT ALSO LIKE
 What Are the Most Artistic Cities in the USA? Top Recording Artists 2009 Top Budget Friendly Family Vacations 
 Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 


 nine× = 72

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 
 

 

 
Recent Posts

 Chocolate Paradise in Venezuela MasterCard 3Q profit up 38 pct as card use rises Healthy Lunch Snack Ideas Why Parents Have a Midlife Crisis Where’s the Customer Retention? 
 

 

 

 

 
©2012 GenieKnows Inc | All Rights Reserved | Contact | Privacy 
 Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
