<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005658" url="http://www.mynewplace.com/city/nashville-apartments-for-rent-tennessee" time="2012-07-12-22:14" support="6" score="0.002713560386823163" bingtitle="Nashville Apartments for Rent - Nashville, TN on MyNewPlace" webtitle="Nashville Apartments for Rent - Nashville, TN on MyNewPlace">
			<query id="000728" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000291" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000854" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000665" bing-rank="20"/>
	<description>The relatively moderate climate of Nashville allows residents to take advantage ... agility course, benches for the human patrons, and provided trash bags and receptacles.</description>
	<body>
		Register/Sign in | Favorites | Moving 
Nashville Apartments for Rent
 Photo Credit 
Search Apartments in Nashville
 Enter City or Zip Code Search         
&quot;NICE! This is a really simple way to find an apartment. I love it!&quot; - Nashville , TN 
 
Popular Nashville Apartments
 
 Crestview Apartments 

Nashville, Tennessee, 37217

 Studio/1 Bedroom $375 - $480

 2 Bedrooms $635

 Video Tour 
 

 
 Rolling Mill Hill 

Nashville, Tennessee, 37219

 Studio/1 Bedroom Up to $1,145

 2 Bedrooms $1,735 - $2,350

 3 Bedrooms $2,350
 

 
 Twin Oaks 

Nashville, Tennessee, 37211

 Studio/1 Bedroom $617 - $795

 2 Bedrooms $750 - $1,039

 3 Bedrooms $910 - $1,485
 

 
 Post Ridge Apartments 

Nashville, Tennessee, 37221

 2 Bedrooms $827 - $1,391

 3 Bedrooms $990 - $1,509

 Video Tour 
 

 More Apartments in Nashville, TN» 
MyNewPlace Apartment Finder Features

 Floor Plans Photos Interactive Maps Videos 
                 
Nashville Apartments Info
 
Find Apartments in Nashville, Tennessee

Nashville apartments are ingeniously laid out near city parks and appealing during all four seasons - among Nashville&apos;s excellent and sprawling neighborhoods you will find the perfect apartment for you and your family.

Want the inside scoop on Nashville? Check out our Nashville Local Talk for local tips and information about Nashville. You can also get answers to your Nashville questions from our local experts by using the &quot;Ask a Question&quot; feature.

 Search Homes for Rent in Nashville 
 
Nashville, Tennessee

An important river town and a critical city during the Civil War, Nashville always had a strong economy. But, it was not until 1925 when the Grand Ole Opry radio showed first aired that Nashville became nationally and internationally known. Still airing today, the Grand Ole Opry provided the city with its nickname &apos;Music City USA.&apos;

While music and music production is still an important part of the city, it is no longer the primary economic factor. The health care industry takes that honor. The Dell Corporation headquarters in Nashville as well as companies in finance, religious publishing and insurance add heavily to the economy.

Choosing A Neighborhood

Your new Nashville apartment needs to be selected for not only its comfort and fit with your lifestyle but for proximity to work or to school. Hillsborough Village near Vanderbilt University is an excellent area for rentals and has the energy one usually finds near large campuses. The Pike/Main Street area to the Cumberland River is a favorite of musicians and artists and is a bit more bohemian. The downtown area is seeing conversions and newly built high rises. It is becoming very popular with young professionals for its proximity to both work and nightlife.

Things to Do Besides Music

Once settled, you&apos;ll want to explore your new city and there&apos;s plenty to do. There are several good museums, and in Midtown you&apos;ll find great galleries and shops. You can take afternoon trips on a paddlewheel boat, visit a real plantation out at Belle Meade or hit the local brewery which is called Yazoo. Since Nashville has 113 parks, you&apos;ll be able to workout, play golf and pursue almost any outdoor sport that interests you.

The NFL Tennessee Titans and the NHL Predators supply alot of sports action along with several of the local university teams. Since the city has over a dozen colleges and universities, there is much in the way of theater, culture and musical events centered around them. Once in your new Nashville apartment, it won&apos;t take long to get the lay of the land and all it has to offer.

Good Southern Cooking

Eating out options in Nashville are as diverse as is the city. From small Southern food places like Arnold&apos;s downtown to upscale spots like F. Scott&apos;s where you need to dress up, there&apos;s plenty of diversity in this Southern town.

All of the Music

Once you start to venture out from your new Nashville apartment, there&apos;s obviously plenty of nightlife in this entertainment city. For the real deal, go out to Green Hills to the Bluebird Cafe, where both local and visiting songwriters hangout and play. The same writers might be visiting Douglas Corner Cafe or Springwater, where the touring bands stop in and play. Downtown you&apos;ll find Printers Alley with several clubs. If you love music, you&apos;ll love Nashville.
 
Average Apartment Rent in Nashville, Tennessee

 # Bedrooms Jun May Apr 3 Month % change Studio $499 $452 $647 -22.9% 1 Bed $839 $797 $826 1.6% 2 Bed $999 $1,025 $1,034 -3.4% 3 Bed $1,278 $1,275 $1,265 1% 

 See how Home Rentals compare in Nashville 

Nashville Apartment Rental Trends
Apartments in Nashville have competitive rents so be sure to use our apartment finder to get the best deal. In April the average rent for a 1 Bedroom Nashville apartment cost $826. If you need a roommate, try finding a 2 bedroom apartment rental. An average 2 bedroom Nashville apartment was $1,034 in April. The average apartment rent for a 3 bedroom apartment in April was $1,265. Start your apartment search by checking out some of the Nashville rentals listed below. 
Popular Nashville Apartments Searches

Check out our most popular searches for apartments for rent in Nashville, TN

 Furnished Nashville Apartments Pet-friendly Nashville Apartments Studio Nashville Apartments One Bedroom Nashville Apartments Two Bedroom Nashville Apartments Three Bedroom Nashville Apartments Nashville Apartments Under $500 Nashville Apartments Under $600 Nashville Apartments Under $700 Nashville Apartments Under $800 Nashville Apartments Under $900 Nashville Apartments Under $1000 Nashville Apartments Under $1200 Nashville Apartments Under $1500 Nashville Apartments Under $2000 Nashville Apartments Under $2500 Nashville Apartments with Laundry Nashville Apartments with Short Term Lease 

Rent Apartments Near Nashville, Tennessee

Check out these great communities and cities near Nashville for apartments for rent:

 Antioch Apartments Brentwood Apartments Clarksville Apartments Franklin Apartments Hendersonville Apartments Hopkinsville Apartments Lebanon Apartments Madison Apartments Murfreesboro Apartments Smyrna Apartments 

Search Apartment Rentals in Nashville, TN Neighborhoods

Each neighborhood in Nashville is different. Search apartments by neighborhood to find where your Nashville apartments should be:

 Boscobel Heights Apartments Buena Vista Apartments Cleveland Park Apartments Cumberland Gardens Apartments Elizabeth Park Apartments Fisk / Meharry Apartments New Omohundro Apartments Osage / North Fisk Apartments Radnor Apartments Rolling Mill Apartments 

Find Nashville, Tennessee Apartments by Zip Code

You can also search for apartments in Nashville for rent by zip code:

 37230 Apartments 37202 Apartments 37203 Apartments 37201 Apartments 37240 Apartments 37212 Apartments 37232 Apartments 37208 Apartments 37204 Apartments 37206 Apartments 

Other

 Nashville Motels Nashville Real Estate Nashville Commercial Real Estate Nashville cheap hotels 
 
 Apartments for Rent Tennessee Apartments for Rent Apartments in Nashville 
 
Map&amp;Local Information
 
See Nearby...

 Schools Grocery Stores Restaurants Places of Worship Banks Retail Locations Places for Pets Coffee Shops 
 Search for Places of Interest Search 
Local Talk

Get answers about Nashville from local experts or tell us what you love about it.
 
 What neighborhoods in Nashville are good for eating out? 
The Gulch is Nashville&apos;s newest and hippest neighborhood and has quickly become...

The Gulch is Nashville&apos;s newest and hippest neighborhood and has quickly become a favorite dining destination amongst the local food buffs. With a countless array of cafes, bakeries, bistros and upscale dining locales to choose from, as well as several outdoor patios, rooftop terraces, and frequent live music performances, The Gulch is always bustling with excitement. Make sure to stop by Provence Breads in the morning to grab one of their warm and tasty croissants. Historic Hillsboro Village, located just three miles southwest of downtown Nashville, also boasts some of the best restaurants in town. The scrumptious sweet potato pancakes at the renowned Pancake Pantry, a local favorite of almost 50 years, are an absolute must-try.
 What are the most fun neighborhoods in Nashville? 
In addition to the scores of superb restaurants located in The Gulch, this...

In addition to the scores of superb restaurants located in The Gulch, this neighborhood also boasts a booming nightlife, various locally owned shops and boutiques, and a neighborhood art gallery. Also noteworthy, The Gulch is the first LEED certified neighborhood in the South. A downright vivacious locale, visitors and residents of the Gulch enjoy a contemporary lifestyle that is distinctively Nashville. Five Points, located in Nashville&apos;s East End, is another popular hangout spot with a diverse mix of eateries, nightspots, art galleries, and music venues. 3 Crow Bar, situated in Five Points, is a local favorite with a kitschy-decor, extensive drink menu, dart boards, and more than two dozen beers on tap.
 I want to lease a home in Bellevue for three month. What price I&apos;m looking 
Search our site by using 37221 as a zip code to display the apartments in the...

Search our site by using 37221 as a zip code to display the apartments in the Bellevue area. After you see the listing page, select the “Rental homes only” in property type and click search again you will see the list of properties that meet your needs. 
Or go to this link: Rentals near Bellevue Prices range from $800 to over $2000 per month, depending on the apartment’s features.
 What&apos;s the weather like in Nashville? 
The climate in Nashville is humid-subtropical. Summers are warm with average...

The climate in Nashville is humid-subtropical. Summers are warm with average temperatures in the 70s and winters are cool with low temperatures in the 30s. Average annual rainfall is around 48&quot;, mostly occurring during the city&apos;s long spring and autumn seasons. Nashville does see some light snowfall, about 10&quot; a year on average. The relatively moderate climate of Nashville allows residents to take advantage of the hiking and horseback trails at the expansive 2,700-acre Warner Park nearly year round.
 What neighborhoods in Nashville are considered safe? Is Buena Vista a decent place to find an apartment? 
Nashville’s Buena Vista neighborhood is located closer to downtown and though it...

Nashville’s Buena Vista neighborhood is located closer to downtown and though it is a lively place to find an apartment, it is not unsafe. Some notoriously unsafe areas include Nolensville Road, which is south of the city, Antioch, and the Madison area. The safer parts of Nashville are in Green Hills or Belle Meade, though both of those areas are rather expensive in terms of rents in Nashville. Bellevue and Sylvan Park are other options to consider finding an apartment, though they are located outside Interstate 440.
 I&apos;ve got dogs. What are the best places in Nashville for being outdoors with pets? 
Heritage Bark Park, located on Peachers Mill Road in nearby Clarksville, is a...

Heritage Bark Park, located on Peachers Mill Road in nearby Clarksville, is a great dog park with separate, fenced-in areas for large and small dogs, an agility course, benches for the human patrons, and provided trash bags and receptacles. Sevier Park is located right in Nashville on Granny White Pike and offers rolling hills covered in green grass, athletic fields, and a paved pathway winding throughout the park. Leashed dogs are welcome, so grab a gourmet popsicle at Las Paletas (located at the entrance to the park) and enjoy a day in the sun with your favorite pooch at this cozy Nashville gem. Fannie Mae Dees Park, located in the Hillsboro/West End neighborhood is another great spot for dogs with tons of open space, trees, and shaded picnic areas. This park is nicknamed &quot;Dragon Park&quot; by the locals for the massive, brightly colored dragon sculpture in its center.
 What would an ideal weekend be like in Nashville? 
Start out your weekend soaking in the sun at Nashville&apos;s Centennial Park. After...

Start out your weekend soaking in the sun at Nashville&apos;s Centennial Park. After some hiking or boating and a family picnic, get a taste of Nashville&apos;s history at the Tennessee State Museum and the Country Music Hall of Fame. Next, sign up for an evening show and meal on the locally famous General Jackson Showboat. After dinner be sure to check out a concert at Memphis&apos; world class Ryman Auditorium.
 How far is the airport from downtown Nashville and can I get there easily and cheaply? 
The nearest major airport to Nashville, Tennessee is Nashville International...

The nearest major airport to Nashville, Tennessee is Nashville International Airport (BNA). This airport is about five miles from the city center. The cheapest way to travel to and from the Nashville International Airport and downtown Nashville is to ride the Nashville MTA&apos;s Route 18 Airport/Elm Hill bus, which leaves every hour every day of the week, from about 7 am to about 10 pm. Schedules can be found at the Welcome Center at the airport.
 Is the cost of living in Nashville higher relative to surrounding areas or other cities? 
The cost of living in Nashville compared to the rest of the country is 18...

The cost of living in Nashville compared to the rest of the country is 18 percent lower than the whole nation average. Hendersonville to the north is 11 percent more expensive than Nashville. To the northeast, Lakewood is 9 percent more expensive than Nashville, Green Hill is 17 percent more expensive than Nashville, and Mount Juliet is 20 percent more expensive than Nashville. Brentwood to the south is a full 57 percent more expensive than Nashville, while Asland City is only 6 percent more expensive than Nashville.
 Hi What neighborhoods surround Belmont University 
Belmont University in Nashville is surrounded by Belmont/Hillsboro to the south,...

Belmont University in Nashville is surrounded by Belmont/Hillsboro to the south, Hillsboro West End to the west, Edgehill to the north and Historic Waverly to the east. Acklen Westgrove is also very close to Belmont, just to the northeast.
 
 
 See all questions and answers 
 Ask a Question or Comment Ask 
 MyNewPlace 
 Home About Us Blog Feedback Help Affiliates 
 For Renters 
 Free Tools Apartment Directory Rental Property Directory Renters Guide Homes for Rent Cheap Apartments Pet Friendly Apartments 
 For Managers 
 List Your Property Manager Login 
 Legal 
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Equal Housing Opportunity Broker Licenses 
 Social 
 
 

© RealPage , Inc. ©2012 MyNewPlace. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
