<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005210" url="http://www.startupbizhub.com/how-to-start-home-based-greeting-card-business.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:44" support="1" score="0.007312909765725873" bingtitle="How to Start Home Based Greeting Card Business" webtitle="How to Start Home Based Greeting Card Business">
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>It is easy to start your own greeting card business. ... In order to get the business rolling you need to ... Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant; Starting a Hostel Business</description>
	<body>
		News   Franchise 
 1   
How to Start Home Based Greeting Card Business


 It is easy to start your own greeting card business. Below are some of the ideas that you need to know on how to start home based greeting card business. 

This business can bring out your talent and skills in writing and drawing.

 

You might be interested on creating unique and colourful greeting card . If this is the case then you can consider having your own greeting cards home business. It is a business with income potential and incredible growth. You can also have several options in the business itself. Below are some ideas if you want to learn more on how to start home based greeting card business.

The only needed skill in this type of business is your talent in writing and drawing. With the same business you can be selling cards or e-cards sold in stores. It would also allow purchasing a territory from a bigger card distributor.

The first step in starting a greeting card business is to decide on the part of the greeting card business that you need to focus on. If you are a freelance greeting card artist, your main focus would be on designing cards for other companies. In this case you need to purchase a graphic art software and a computer if don’t have these items yet.

If you choose to be a freelancer card writer, your home based greeting card business will focus on writing phrases to be used on cards. If this is the case all you need is a computer for faster turn around time.

You can also become both an artist and writer. In order to get the business rolling you need to find companies that hires freelancer. It usually pays from $50 per assignment to several hundreds per assignment. You are required to submit a portfolio of samples, and sometimes you need to compete with others by presenting a unique and the best option for your client.

One more option is to buy a vending route from a bigger greeting card company. This can become your first step in the business. You need to maintain present clients stocked in cards, change the old cards with new ones and have new clients to build your money. You need to have a start up costs that can run from hundred to thousand dollars in inventory. But if you forward the card the cards to the clients, you will get your payments instantly.

You need to focus on the different aspects of greeting card business if you want to start your own line of cards. You write and design each greeting card inside and out. You can bring out your creativeness and no one can stop you from doing what you think would make the card unique. You have the freedom to decide on things and it can clearly say that this is your greeting cards business.

To market your business, the best tool that you can use is the internet. There is no need for you to compete with larger greeting card companies. All you need to do is to create a special niche for the cards you are promoting on the web and in small local stores.



 &lt;&lt; Getting Insurance for your Home-Based Business     Payroll Work from Home  &gt;&gt; 

1 Respons to &quot;How to Start Home Based Greeting Card Business&quot;.
 1. Rajan Verma on 5/12/2010 3:52:06 AM Hi, I am interested in starting my own Greeting Card Printing Business at home. I have a big hall at home of around 20 by 20 ft. Please guide me regarding what machinery to buy, capital investment required, raw material needed, etc. asap. I live in Chandigarh(India). 
 Name: 
 Email: 
 Comment: 
 Write your business location to help you better. Exp: City, State, Country 
 ( All the above fields are required. ) 
 

 Sign up for Newsletter 
Restaurant Business

 How to Start an Indian Restaurant Business Juice and Smoothie Bar Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant Starting a Hostel Business Startup Sushi Restaurant 

Mobile Business Ideas

 How to Start Mobile Catering How to Start Your Own Charter Fishing Business How to Start a Mobile Spa Business Mobile Detailing Business Startup Kit How to Start Mobile Notary Business 

Farming Business Ideas

 How to Start a Poultry Farm Starting Chicken Farm Business Starting a Dairy Farm Business How to Start a Fish Farming Business Start a Rabbit Farm 

Service Business Ideas

 Starting a Recruitment Agency How to Start a Courier Business Starting Your Own Money Lending Business Starting Your Own Guest House Business Starting Your Own Computer Training Center 
 
 Advice for Small Business Business Insurance Information Business Marketing and Advertising Entrepreneur Business Idea Farming Business Ideas Financing a Small Business Free Business Ideas Home Based Business Opportunity 
 Work at Home Business Ideas 
 Ideas for Small Business Instructor Guides Internet Business Ideas Professional Career Opportunities Repair Business Opportunity Restaurant Business Opportunities Retail Store Ideas Rural Business Opportunities Service Business Ideas Shop Business Ideas Small Business Articles Small Business Opportunities Small Manufacturing Business Starting Rental Business Startup Company Ideas Store Business Opportunities Tips for Buying and Selling Unique Business Opportunities Wholesale Business Opportunities 

Small Business Ideas

 How to Start a Towing Business How to Start a Trucking Business Starting a Taxi Business How to Start a Movie Theater How to Start a Shoe Business 

Small Business Articles

 How to Start a Gas Station How Much Does it Cost to Charter a Private Jet Starting a Night Club How Do You Calculate The Mark Up Price 

Home Based Business

 Starting a Home Health Agency How to Start a Home Baking Business Starting a Funeral Home Business Ideas for Home Based Business Starting a Woodworking Business 

Shop Business Ideas

 Starting a Pawn Shop Business How to Start a Meat Shop How to Start a Donut Shop How to Open a Sandwich Shop How to Start Auto Body Shop 

Store Business Opportunities

 Starting a Grocery Store Business Starting a Fashion Clothing Store How to Open a Liquor Store How to Start a Beauty Supply Store How to Start a Drug Store Business 

Startup Company Ideas

 How to Start a Tour Company How to Start a Security Company Start a Cosmetics Company How to Start a Skateboard Company Starting Your Own Repossession Company 
 Copyright©2007 - 2012 StartupBizHub.com. All Rights Reserved.
 About Us | Privacy | Contact Us 
 Site Map
	</body>
</document>
