<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005726" url="http://www.watfordobserver.co.uk/news/9462187.Second_break_in_at_fast_food_restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-22:21" support="1" score="0.000565897279659284" bingtitle="Second break-in at fast food restaurant (From Watford Observer)" webtitle="Second break-in at fast food restaurantFrom Watford Observer)">
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>Second break-in at fast food restaurant (From Watford Observer) ... Interactive worship at synagogue; Car badly damaged as bin fire gets out of ...</description>
	<body>
		Jump to main content News Sport Weather forecast 
 


 Mobile site News feed E-Newsletters 

 Site map Register Log in 
 
 Second break-in at fast food restaurant(From Watford Observer) 
 
 Get involved: send your pictures, video, news and views by texting WO to 80360, or email us 
 Search: 
 News Sport Leisure Info Pictures Your Say Community Family Advertise Buy&amp;Sell Click2find Dating Cars Homes Jobs 

 Leveson Live Budget 2012 London Marathon London News Twitter Links National Video Blogs Email Bulletins Business 
 
 
 Watford Observer » News » 

News RSS Feed Send your news, pictures&amp;videos 
 
 
Break-in at Boston Chicken in South Oxhey

 12:16pm Tuesday 10th January 2012 in News 

A fast food shop in South Oxhey has been broken into for the second time in a month.

Police were alerted to a burglar alarm in Boston Chicken, Prestwick Road, at 3.14am this morning.

When they got there they found a fruit machine had been broken into.

The shutter at the back of the building was half open but the door was not damaged, police are unsure how the intruders got in.

On Monday, December 12, burglars broke into the fast food shop, forced open the fruit machine and stole an unspecified amount of cash between 4.21am and 5.07am.
 
 Email Print this page Comment(0) 
 
Comments are closed on this article.
 
 Email Print this page Comment(0) 
 
click2find
 Food and drink 
 Search» 
 
Most popular
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Jobs 
 
Find a job in Watford and all around Hertfordshire.
 Search Now» 
   
 Dating 
 
Make a date in Watford and find friendship
 Search Now» 
 
 Homes 
 
Find properties in Watford and Hertfordshire
 Search Now» 
 
 Cars 
 
Find cars for sale in Watford and Hertfordshire.
 Search Now» 
   
 
 News Sport Leisure Info Pictures Your Say Community Family Advertise Buy&amp;Sell Click2find Dating Cars Homes Jobs 


 Cookie Policy Contact Us Subscribe Photo Sales Advertise AdChoices Archive Topics Announcements Site Map Buy&amp;Sell 


 Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy ©Copyright 2001-2012 
 

 This site is part of Newsquest&apos;s audited local newspaper network A Gannett Company 
 


Newsquest (London) Ltd, 58 Church Street, Weybridge, Surrey. KT13 8DP |3105111| Registered in England&amp;Wales
 
About cookies

We want you to enjoy your visit to our website. That&apos;s why we use cookies to enhance your experience. By staying on our website you agree to our use of cookies. Find out more about the cookies we use .
 I agree
	</body>
</document>
