<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005394" url="http://www.querycat.com/question/ff324498249ede98cff1fb9770b462c7" time="2012-07-12-21:56" support="3" score="0.007008135411269103" bingtitle="Can a participating restaurant allow a mixed transaction (EBT Food ..." webtitle="Can a participating restaurant allow a mixed transaction (EBT Food Stamp and EBT Cash combined)?">
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>... eligible for the program, informs the cashier that meal payment is EBT Food ... amount of Food Stamp benefits you may receive ... Why isn&apos;t my favorite fast food restaurant on ...</description>
	<body>
		Search 5,000,000+ questions and answers. 
 
 
 
Frequently Asked Questions
 
 Can a participating restaurant allow a mixed transaction (EBT Food Stamp and EBT Cash combined)? 
 Restaurant Meal Program FAQs Yes, you may process a mixed transaction when EBT cardholder, eligible for the program, informs the cashier that meal payment is EBT Food Stamp and EBT Cash combined. 
 What do I do if my EBT Food Stamp transaction is denied by a participating restaurant? 
 Restaurant Meal Program FAQs You must call your Food Stamp Eligibility Worker or call the EBT Customer Service Center number (1-877-328-9677 or the TTY at 1-800-735-2929). For more information about the Restaurant Meals Program, call your Food Stamp Eligibility Worker or you may call Central Help Line at (1-877-481-1044) 
 How can the eligible food stamp households know that our restaurant is participating in the program? 
 Restaurant Meal Program FAQs Your restaurant name and address will be placed on a list of participating restaurants, which we provide to eligible participants through our local district offices, community organizations, community partners and advocates. The list of participating restaurants can also be accessed through the Food Stamp Restaurant Meals Web Page. 
 How do I get a permit for my restaurant or other food establishment? 
 Environmental Management Department (EMD) FAQs application and fee must be submitted to the Environmental Management Department (EMD) office prior to opening. If the food establishment is new or undergoing remodeling, contact the Plan Review Office at 916-874-6010 before the application is submitted. The Environmental Health Specialist has many things to do when conducting an inspection. Primarily, we inspect the food facility to determine if it complies with the requirements of the California Health and Safety Code (CHSC). 
 I&apos;m a retailer that does not sell food, but would like to add EBT cash. How do I do that? 
 Frequently Asked Questions The State does not provide equipment for EBT cash only transactions. However, you can add EBT cash to your existing debit/credit equipment as long as your equipment has a PIN pad. Just call your third party processor and ask them to add the California EBT BIN. We also recommend that you add the BINs for the other states as the cardholders tend to be very mobile. If you do not have debit/credit equipment, you can call the J.P. 
 Why shouldn&apos;t food stamp recipients receive their benefits in cash? 
 Untitled Document Food Stamp cashout provides no guarantee that benefits will actually be used for food. Recipients would be able to spend the money on other household needs, including housing and medical costs. While these are also important needs, they are not nutritional benefits. Furthermore, recipients of cashed-out food stamp benefits might actually have less money available for food purchases; they are often subject to check-cashing fees to access their benefits, and increases in rent by landlords. 
 What is a Stamp? 
 Handipoints - Help and Frequently Asked Questions Your child will collect Stamps, which are pictures and pieces of trivia, randomly when they check off Tasks. If they check off Happy Tasks, they get Happy stamps, and so on. To get a good mix of stamps, your child has to do a lot of Tasks in each category: Happy, Healthy and Smart. Handipoints.com releases new Stamps regularly to keep the game exciting. Stamp collections have anywhere from 4 to 16 stamps. 
 Who can help me with food stamps or cash assistance? 
 Arizona Attorney General Terry Goddard If you suspect that a resident may be the victim of a criminal act, report it immediately to local police by dialing 911. 
 What is the Food Stamp Program? 
 The Food Stamp Program is a nutrition assistance program in which eligible low-income households purchase food with the use of coupons that can be used like cash at participating grocery stores. 
 When will my food stamp benefits go into my account? 
 FAQs Your benefits will be available after 6:00 a.m. on the same day each month according to the last digit of the head of household&apos;s Social Security Number, even if that day is on a weekend or a holiday. 
 How is the amount of my Food Stamp benefits determined? 
 FAQs The amount of Food Stamp benefits you may receive are determined by the number of people in the household, the amount of income received by the people in the household, the household&apos;s shelter expenses and the amount of medical expenses you have to pay that are not reimbursed (persons 60 or older or disabled). 
 What if I disagree with my food stamp allotment? 
 The Department of Social Services The first course of action would be to call your worker to discuss why you are receiving the specified amount of food stamps. If you still disagree, you have the right to request a Fair Hearing by calling 1-800-342-3334. 
 Why isn&apos;t my favorite fast food restaurant on your restaurant list? 
 NutritionData&apos;s Frequently Asked Questions–Nutrition... Not all restaurants are willing to provide nutritional data on their foods, and, in some cases, the data that&apos;s currently available is not complete enough to meet ND&apos;s standards. Please be patient, though. We are continuously evaluating new additions to our database. More restaurants will be added in the future. 
 How do I find out if a restaurant is participating in the program? 
 Restaurant Meal Program FAQs A restaurant is participating in the program if the Restaurant Meals Program sign or logo is displayed on its door or window. You may also click here for the list of participating restaurants or ask your Eligibility Worker for a list. 
 Are you a food critic /restaurant reviewer? 
 Pacific Palate with Don Genova &gt; About Me &gt; F.A.Q.s Not really. Although I have reviewed restaurants in the past and will be doing one review a month on my Pacific Palate program, I consider myself much more a journalist than a reviewer. Most of the stories I produce are about passionate people in the food and beverage industry who have interesting stories to tell. 
 a cash-only EBT retailer, can I charge a fee? 
 Frequently Asked Questions Surcharges are allowed for EBT cash. If you choose to surcharge, you should treat your EBT customers the same as your debit customers. However, many retailers choose not to surcharge EBT customers. 
 What is the maximum cash withdrawal for every transaction? 
 FAQ Maximum cash withdrawal per transaction is P4,000 while minimum cash withdrawal per transaction is P100. There are no limit for Intrabank Fund Transfer while the maximum third party fund transfer per day is P20,000 
 Can I get my cash back after the transaction has been completed? 
 PreCash - Consumer - Bill Pay - FAQ That depends on the policy determined by your provider. Check with your service provider for details. [back to top] 
 Q What do I do if I get food poisoning from a restaurant, bar, supermarket or mobile food truck? 
 FAQ: Environmental Health and Hazardous Materials - Contra C... Report the illness to Environmental Health within 24 hours by calling 925-692-2500. If you wait longer, there may be no way to determine if the food facility is at fault. Environmental Health can determine if there are other factors or concerns that could contribute to others being ill and take corrective measures. 
 Do farmers&apos; markets accept EBT cards/food stamps? 
 Main FAQ A number of markets in Los Angeles accept EBT cards. Click here for a list of Certified Farmers&apos; Markets using Scrip and a Central POS device to accept EBT cards. You can also see our market list to find a market in your area. If your regular market does not accept EBT cards, ask the market manager if they plan to accept the card in the future. For more information on EBT cards and enrolling in the Food Stamp Program, please call (800) 221-5689 or visit this website: www.ladpss.org More Questions &gt;&gt; 
 
©Copyright 2007-2012 QueryCAT 
 About • Webmasters • Contact
	</body>
</document>
