<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005404" url="http://www.fdis-state.com/possoftware.html" time="2012-07-12-21:57" support="1" score="0.001680620071416719" bingtitle="fdis - My title" webtitle="fdis">
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>... website shopping cart, credit card service, credit card ... Fast Food Restaurant, Basic Dine in restaurant, Bars. ... great in applications that do not require table ...</description>
	<body>
		google-site-verification: google0f4853583193d643.html 
 Contact us | Customer Care Home | Terminals | POS System | Sign Up Now The FIRST DATA name, trademark and logo are owned by First Data Corporation. All other trademarks, service marks and trade names referenced in this material are the property of their respective owners. The First Data Independent Sales Agent Program is operated by Cardservice International, LLC. Cardservice International, doing business as First Data Independent Sales (FDIS), is a registered ISO/MSP of Wells Fargo Bank, N.A., Walnut Creek, CA. American Express requires separate approval. FDIS Agent #111181 is an independent agent for Cardservice International . 
 
 
 Software&amp;Program 
 Retail, Restaurant, Nail&amp;Spa 
 software features 
 Easy Navigation
 Fast Lookups by Barcode, Name
 Built in Help System
 Bar Code Ready
 Fast Processing
 Salesperson Tracking
 Scale Interface
 Works with Portable POS
 Equipment Rentals
 Microsoft Access Compatible
 Time Clock
 Detailed Rental History
 Detailed Customer History
 Quickbooks Compatible
 Invoices on Hold
 Credit Card Processing
 Sets Rental Due Dates
 Built in Backup
 Handles Multiple Clerks
 Handles Multiple Cash Drawers
 Family Memberships
 Coupon Plans
 Gift Certificates
 Handles Customer Account
 Friendly Printer setup
 Freebies and Specials
 Customer Quick Search
 Flexible Pricing
 Prints Mailing Labels
 Flexible Taxing
 Password Protection
 Detailed Inventory Reports
 Movie Reports
 Late, Rented Products, Rental Items in Store
 Management Reports
 Promotions for Preferred Customers
 Financial Summaries
 
 POS Pro 
 Great Idea for All Retail Sale Stores, Liquor Store, 99 Cent Store.
 Fast Food Restaurant, Basic Dine in restaurant, Bars.
 Adelo Restaurant POS 
 Aldelo Restaurant Software - LITE
 Aldelo - NextPOS For Restaurants Lite Version software is for restaurant owners looking to replace their cash registers. Aldelo NextPOS Lite works great in applications that do not require table service.
 Aldelo Restaurant Software - PRO 1st License
 Aldelo For Restaurants PRO software is an affordable, easy to use, feature rich, and 100% multi-lingual restaurant point of sale and store management solution.
 Adelo is Great for all size restaurants, From Small size, Pizza Store,
 Take Out Restaurant o Large Dine In Restaurants
 Contact FDIS Today 
 888-381-7888 
 We specialize on software developing 
 Retail, Ware House,Travel Agent
 Whole Sale, Hotel, Nail,Wedding...etc
	</body>
</document>
