<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005869" url="http://backgroundchecks411.typepad.com/my_weblog/2011/03/grocery-jobs.html" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="1" score="0.0014045697117303743" bingtitle="HR Articles: Grocery Jobs Created by New King Soopers Marketplace" webtitle="HR Articles: Grocery Jobs Created by New King Soopers Marketplace">
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>Cashier; Clearwater; Colorado; Construction; Dallas; Denver ... So far, a dentist office, fast food restaurant, and disabled ... There are a selection connected with retail ...</description>
	<body>
		HR Articles 

Blog on the background check and employment space.
 
 Archives 
 
 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 

 More... 
 
Pages
 
 Job Search 
 
 Categories 
 
 Air ambulance Applicant tracking system Arizona Atlanta Austin Background check Baltimore Bar Blogging Cashier Clearwater Colorado Construction Dallas Denver Durham Education Engineering Family counselors Finance Food and Drink Fort Worth Ft Lauderdale Glendale Government Grocery Healthcare Hotel Houston Insurance IT Job Search Jobs for veterans Las Vegas Lazyboyjobs Los Angeles Manager Manufacturing Medical Miami Military Nashville Nevada Non profit Nursing Oregon Orlando Outplacement Paramedic Phoenix jobs Portland Pre employment test PT Radiology Recruitment process outsourcing Registered nursing Resume builder Sales San Antonio San Diego Sarasota Seattle St Louis Tech Tempe Texas Travel Tucson Waukesha Web/Tech 
 
 About 
 Blog powered by TypePad 
Member since 02/2005 
Recent Posts
 
 Jobs in Tempe Benefit from Minority Funding Fort Lauderdale Sales Jobs Options Family Therapist Jobs More Effective Treating Eating Disorders Grocery Jobs Supported by Customer Loyalty Programs Houston Tech Jobs Supported by Innovation Funding Sales Rep Jobs Phoenix Top Retail Industry Pediatric PT Jobs Phoenix Joining Together Fort Lauderdale Sales Jobs Created by Patriot National Nursing Jobs in Arizona Saved by AHCCCS Plan Registered Nursing Jobs Arizona a Good Option 
 
 Categories 
 
 Air ambulance Applicant tracking system Arizona Atlanta Austin Background check Baltimore Bar Blogging Cashier Clearwater Colorado Construction Dallas Denver Durham Education Engineering Family counselors Finance Food and Drink Fort Worth Ft Lauderdale Glendale Government Grocery Healthcare Hotel Houston Insurance IT Job Search Jobs for veterans Las Vegas Lazyboyjobs Los Angeles Manager Manufacturing Medical Miami Military Nashville Nevada Non profit Nursing Oregon Orlando Outplacement Paramedic Phoenix jobs Portland Pre employment test PT Radiology Recruitment process outsourcing Registered nursing Resume builder Sales San Antonio San Diego Sarasota Seattle St Louis Tech Tempe Texas Travel Tucson Waukesha Web/Tech 
 
 «Non Profit Jobs in Houston Created by College Forward | Main | Registered Nursing Jobs Arizona a Good Option» 

March 11, 2011
 
Grocery Jobs Created by New King Soopers Marketplace
 
A local company is creating hundreds of new grocery jobs .

Last month, King Soopers opened a new store that will anchor Northgate Village, a shopping center located in Greeley, Colo. The King Soopers Marketplace is larger than the company&apos;s other stores, measuring about 123,000 square feet.

According to an article by the Greeley Tribune , the new store is expected to bring in $30 million of revenue each year and create 200 to 250 jobs, most of which will be full-time positions . And while most of the positions have already been filled, there is a chance that more jobs will be created soon.

In addition to creating jobs directly, King Soopers also is drawing other companies to the area, which will in turn create more positions. So far, a dentist office, fast food restaurant, and disabled housing facility are planning to locate at Northgate Village.

The King Soopers Marketplace itself will include a Starbucks, sushi bar, olive and antipasto bar, burrito bar, lobster tank, and grilling station. There also will be a jewelry store, pharmacy, home decor, bed and bath, kitchenware, toys, baby items, fuel center, and bank.

&quot;It&apos;s really a cool store,&quot;King Soopers Spokeswoman Kelli McGannon said.&quot;Our average store size is around 65,000 (square feet). I think the size is a response to customers looking for added convenience at their grocery store. It&apos;s our response to making our store more relevant to them — make sure they get the variety and products ... in one place. How can I get what I want in a one-stop shop.&quot;

King Soopers is planning to open other Marketplaces throughout Colorado in the near future, including stores a store in Fort Collins, which is scheduled to open by June 1st. There are currently three King Soopers in Greeley and 144 King Soopers and City Markets throughout the state.
 
 Posted at 12:19 PM in Grocery , Job Search | Permalink 
 
TrackBack
 
TrackBack URL for this entry:
 http://www.typepad.com/services/trackback/6a00d834522f2469e2014e5fcb4111970c 

Listed below are links to weblogs that reference Grocery Jobs Created by New King Soopers Marketplace :
 
Comments
 
This is very excellent article. Thank you for posting this.
 
Posted by: Investigation Services | March 12, 2011 at 12:06 AM 
 
a dentist office, fast food restaurant, and disabled housing facility are planning to locate at Northgate Village.
 
Posted by: ray ban | April 19, 2011 at 04:56 AM 
 
The King Soopers Marketplace itself will include a Starbucks, sushi bar, olive and antipasto bar, burrito bar, lobster tank, and grilling station. There also will be a jewelry store, pharmacy, home decor, bed and bath, kitchenware, toys, baby items, fuel center, and bank.
 
Posted by: Ray Ban Sunglasses | April 28, 2011 at 02:51 AM 
 
 http://www.maxipharmacy.com/ cialis compatibilty naproxen avodart cialis clomid diflucan dostinex glucophage facts on cialis cialis western.
 
Posted by: cialis to buy | May 24, 2011 at 10:49 PM 
 
The more details the handbag has-like hardware, and inner pockets-the more complicated the fabrication process. The final quality of a handbag is determined during this stage of the process. Any mistakes will affect how the bag looks and will hold up over time
 
Posted by: mulberry sale | July 04, 2011 at 09:31 PM 
 
Post68, cialis 20mg online, gxco3, viagra discounts, xrkk9, viagra no prescription, gqle1, buy cialis no prescription, xcbj9, online levitra
 
Posted by: coinsnopnus | August 16, 2011 at 04:03 AM 
 
If perhaps, a person in the position to get hired to play the stores and buying all the Lacoste polo tank top, the things they say try shopping online. There are a selection connected with retail outlets to supply any such trendy sportswear. Prior to selecting single, enable it to be sure that it truly is reputable as well as dependable. Likewise, check if they provide you with traditional things this is. Read all of the evaluations and even feed-back of the people online to possess a considerably better strategy. This can help that you take the proper judgement.
 
Posted by: lacoste Jackets | September 19, 2011 at 11:09 PM 
 
Hi! Sorry offtop! Del this post!

Apply now for Payday Loans and Cash Advances online. We search 100&apos;s of lenders to find the right No-Fax Paycheck Loan for you with one easy application.

Unplanned expenses, home improvements, car purchase, expensive borrowing to take care of...a number of reasons can take a toll on your financial health. So where do you get the money to deal with these expenses? Personal Loans of course! However there are some requirements that a borrower has to meet to get a guaranteed instant personal loan. A full time employment is an important criterion. Your credit score is also a factor that many lenders will consider before approving your instant personal loan. Homeowners have a distinctive advantage over tenants. Homeowners can avail secured personal loans unlike their counterparts. However the loan market has opened up too tenants as well and there are plenty of tenant loans with an instant online decision available today. By applying for personal loans you can get cash in two ways, the cash can be deposited into your bank account or you can avail the amount through a check. Online lending services allow you to choose from a number of independent lenders. Have you ever had days when you&apos;ve stretched your finances so thin that you do not even have money to spare for life&apos;s little pleasures, such as a drink at your favorite bar? Did your money trouble ever get to the point where you barely have enough to pay for gas? The amount one can avail in the ranging from f100 - f1500 with the flexible repayment term of 14-31 days. Interest rates are slightly high here as no security is attached with these loans. Plus, a bad credit holder can improve their poor credit ratings by making regular repayments. , payday loans guaranteed approval , one hour payday loans no faxing no credit check cash payday loans easy approval payday loans guaranteed approval payday loans online instant approval payday loans , You should only borrow as much as your capacity to make a repayment. You want to make use of the loan without getting into the risk of paying extended amount due to inability to pay back. He must be the citizen of USA. It tends to get difficult to deal with some unforeseen or unwanted emergencies, when you are already low on cash. For a person who relies on a fixed monthly income to take care of the expenses, it ruins the entire monthly budget. Further, raising the cash from finance or friends does not seem to be a good alternative, as it will demean your position. So the best option available is to consider availing instant payday loans. These loans are easy to avail and enable you to deal with any emergency needs in a convenient and suitable manner. If you do have an unexpected need for cash, a payday loan may be the best option for you.
instant payday loans , payday loans online overnight biggest cash payday loans same day payday loans payday loans for unemployed instant no teletrack payday loans , Cash until payday loans are the best way to get financial aid during an urgent crisis. The best feature of this loan is that these loans are approved fast and in very short time. Soon after approval, the loans amount gets transferred to the borrower&apos;s account within 24hrs. Cash until payday loans are generally unsecured in nature and does not ask the borrowers to pledge anything as collateral. These loans are the most appropriate option to meet up short-term expenses. An amount ranging from f100 and f1,500 can be obtainable with this loan. The loan amount needs to be repaid after you get the salary. Hitting a financial problem mid-month does not necessarily mean that you&apos;re in financial trouble. Sometimes a sudden cost arises that you hadn&apos;t expected and it needs to be paid immediately. If payday is still a few weeks away that may be tricky - but a fast payday loan may be the solution. , direct lenders payday
instant no fx payday loans no fax online payday loans for indiana instant online payday loan no fax no teletrack savings account payday loans overnight no fax payday loans easy payday loans no credit check payday loans for unemployed , online payday loans lenders , Even such loans are issued to them on the very same day when they post the application. The borrowers like this feature very much and prefer to get them at the times of urgency. So with the instant money obtained through these, they may fulfill any of their needs without any further delay. In addition to this, they are relaxed from many other complexities also. -Unexpected travel expenses Online Payday Loan Lenders The payday loan online has changed the landscape dramatically and allowed borrowers the flexibility to acquire funds from the comfort of their home. This fact alone has created a better environment for consumers but what about the cost? Today, the costs associated are more regulated than ever and are becoming less expensive yearly due to high demand and more competition. We found ourselves in that situation not to long ago and the short term funding that the guaranteed cash advances gave us was literally a life saver. When a bill pops up that you hadn&apos;t anticipated and your income simply won&apos;t stretch to make that extra payment, you have to find another way to cover it. That was when we first became exposed to these type of loans and learned what a real financial blessing they could be if you use them wisely. , Instant Approval Payday Loans
instant payday loans 400 easy loan payday quick jobless targeted payday loans cash stores cheap payday loans no fax direct payday loans instant decision , no fax advance teletrack payday loans payday loans no employment ver no credit check no teletrac payday loans with direct lenders and instant approval , payday lenders direct , direct lender payday cash loans money deposited instantly quick easy payday loans online easy payday loans no teletrack
In order to access the benefits of this loan an applicant should be a steady employed, and also have a valid bank account. These short term loans are formulated for financial emergencies and involve a simple online application process. The loan application is easy and can be completed within minutes. Fast Cash Advance Loan - How to Locate the Fastest Cash Advance Loan Online o Repayment terms and installments are easy and flexible. Lenders well understand that people with limited income might encounter unexpected and inevitable expenses in the mid of the month for which they might not be monetarily prepared. So, in such circumstances the need for instant cash becomes so urgent that he/she seeks cash before the next payday. Taking such things into consideration lenders have formulated the same day loans for bad credit. , Guaranteed Payday Loan , Applicant must attain the age of 18 years or above; These types of loans work in the same way as an online payday loan does but, there are a few major differences. One of the main ones of these being that you will be able to talk to a real live person if you have any questions or concerns. Most generally you will find these places located in low income to middle class neighborhoods. They are a great solution to a financial emergency if, they are used with caution. Instant cash advance loans solves all your finance related troubles instantly. These loans are a perfect way to come out of all your instant financial worries within no time. Despite preparing thorough budget, many times people face unexpected financial crisis due to sudden medical expenses or family responsibilities. In order to cop up with all immediate liabilities using instant cash advance loans is the best option. Employing the services of cash advance loan lenders has become quite popular these days. In fact, salaried individuals are increasingly employing the services of cash advance loan providers to fulfill their duties. , direct payday lenders
 
Posted by: usafefarm | November 14, 2011 at 03:16 AM 
 
The comments to this entry are closed.
	</body>
</document>
