<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005801" url="http://www.lowcarbfreedom.com/2003/12/fast_food_resta.html" time="2012-07-12-22:26" support="5" score="0.021749492955138908" bingtitle="Low Carb Freedom: Fast Food Restaurants" webtitle="Low Carb Freedom: Fast Food Restaurants">
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>You can always leave off the bun in any fast food ... New Diet Cookbook; New Carb Gram Counter Dr. Atkins ... The kinds of porportions you receive at fast food places are ...</description>
	<body>
		Low Carb Freedom 


 
Menu
 
 LowCarbFreedom Blog Home About Me&amp;My Blog Email Me Weekly Email Newsletter Signup 
 
Advertisements
 
 
 
 
 Archives 
 
 March 2011 February 2011 April 2009 May 2006 April 2006 January 2006 October 2005 August 2005 June 2005 May 2005 
 
Search Low Carb Freedom
 
 
 
   
 Web www.lowcarbfreedom.com 
 
 
 
Low Carb Resources
 
 All about the glycemic index (why white carbs are bad) Carb Counter About Atkins Atkins&apos; Recipes Very Large Carb&amp;Calorie Counter Jenny&apos;s Low Carb 
 
Diabetic Resources
 
 David Mendosa&apos;s Site 
 What They Don&apos;t Tell You About Diabetes 
 Diabetes Mine 
 
 
Low Carb Blogs
 
 Twelve Black Code Monkeys 
 Turtleway 
 Technorati Profile 
 Johnny Bowden Weblog 
 Livin&apos; La Vida Low-Carb 
 Kalyn&apos;s Kitchen 
 Wieght of the Evidence 
 
 
Weight Loss Surgery Blogs
 
 Living After WLS 
 
Low Carb Cookbooks
 
 
 Karen Barnaby: The Low-Carb Gourmet: 250 Delicious and Satisfying Recipes 
I have never enjoyed a low carb cookbook more than The Low-Carb Gourmet by Karen Barnaby. It makes low carbing sensuous and luxurious with a serious &quot;how to&quot; wrapping. Not only do you get to eat the box of chocolates, you learn how to recreate the experience again and again.
 
 Dana Carpender: 500 Low-Carb Recipes: 500 Recipes from Snacks to Dessert, That the Whole Family Will Love 

 
 Gavin De Becker: Protecting the Gift : Keeping Children and Teenagers Safe (and Parents Sane) 
Every parent should read this book.
 
 Robert C. Atkins: Dr. Atkins&apos; Three-Book Package: New Diet Revolution; New Diet Cookbook; New Carb Gram Counter 
Dr. Atkins started it all. Everyone should read this before they go on the diet.
 
 Fred Pescatore: Feed Your Kids Well : How to Help Your Child Lose Weight and Get Healthy 
This is where I learned to use olive oil all the time. Wonderful tips on dealing with kids.
 
 Ruth Glick: Fabulous Lo-Carb Cuisine 
I really like this cookbook. I love the recipe for a low-carb crust. She uses the spice thyme quite a lot, but I just substitute that for Old Bay Seasoning or something else.
 
 
Copyright
 
 
All contents
©Katherine Prouty
Permission to republish online is granted on the condition that you provide and cite the web address, the author name, and notify me where it has been published. 
 Add me to your TypePad People list Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed 
Counters
 
 
 

 
 
 
 «Chains with Low-Carb Menus | Main | Netrition.com Shopping List» 

December 31, 2003
 
Fast Food Restaurants
 
You can always leave off the bun in any fast food restaurant, although it makes it extremely difficult to eat on the run. I have done it. Here is a list of the biggest restaurants that you can drive through.

 McDonald&apos;s 

McDonald&apos;s has created a handy tip sheet for low-carb eaters that includes full nutritional information for low-carb substitutes. They get my thumbs up for most user-friendly, albeit low-tech method, of informing their customers. Sometimes quick and low tech is best.

 Read the tips/menus. 

 Wendy&apos;s 

Wendy&apos;s needs to look at what McDonald&apos;s did in terms of the nutritional information for low-carb dieters. Their &quot;build a menu&quot; is an interactive monstrosity that is way too complicated when you need a quick guide.

The best bet is to look at their total nutritional information and then pick and add it up on your own.

 Nutritional Information 

 Burger King 

Burger King&apos;s interactive menu is a bit better than Wendy&apos;s, but that isn&apos;t saying much. You need to click on the &quot;update&quot; button to get it to subtract out what you have deleted, like the bun. It took me a couple of tries before I figured out that it would do this. I kept hitting nutritional information and it would give me the Big Mac&apos;s nutritional information for the whole burger, including bun.

 Click here to see the nutrition wizard. 

Burger King also has a great carbohydrate sort that is quite useful though. I would use this , but you need to first click on nutrient sort and then on carbohydrates in the pull down menu. (Anyone who works at Burger King, please send me a static url to the carbohydrate sort.)

 Taco Bell 

They have a similar menu wizard to Wendy&apos;s. I wouldn&apos;t try to wade through it. Their printable nutritional information is just a pdf of their in-store brochure, way too hard to read or print with the dark green background. I don&apos;t think that they think their customers care about this type of information.

If you absolutely have to have their nutritional information, try this nutritional caculator , or the pdf .

 Hardees&amp;Carl Jr.&apos;s 

These two chains, run by the same company, just wrapped their burgers in iceburg lettuce and serve it in a paper half wrap. They also cut down on the ketchup because ketchup is loaded with sugar. Unfortunately, there aren&apos;t any of these in Massachusetts.

 Read about their new offerings! 

 Find their nutritional information. They have yet to update their site with the new offerings. They also have an interactive guide and a pdf available.

 Find their locations. 

Let me know what other fast food restaurants you want added.

 
 Posted by K on December 31, 2003 | Permalink 
 
Comments
 
now that is some good information! very helpful. perhaps this site isn&apos;t a total loss after all, i may stick around after all.
 
Posted by:
 bob | December 31, 2003 at 09:06 PM 
 
I don&apos;t generally eat at these places though once in a while I get cheeseburgers at McDonald&apos;s. I try not to do it too often though.
 
Posted by:
 Jim | December 31, 2003 at 09:22 PM 
 
No way! These places are disgusting! Who would eat there? Dirty food and it&apos;s bad for you! No thanks!
 
Posted by:
 Sue | January 01, 2004 at 01:39 PM 
 
Why do these places make tons of money? Convenience! (grin) And they can have their place in a low carb diet -- as long is it is done in moderation (and you leave off the french fries.)

Katherine
 
Posted by:
 Katherine | January 01, 2004 at 02:04 PM 
 
Good info - thanks for your trouble. Now isn&apos;t Subway coming out with something lo-carb?
 
Posted by:
 Anne Lewis | June 23, 2004 at 01:09 PM 
 
Lets think for a second please. We are trying to become healthier. 100 million people in this country are over weight or at the obisity rate. The kinds of porportions you receive at fast food places are horrible. Their small size drinks are other countries&quot;biggy size&quot;or&quot;super size&quot;The calories at places like McDonalds are outragous.. Not only is this a horrible way to eat, its not clean. Inspectors find mold and grime in KFC&apos;s soda nozzils all the time, mcdonalds most common violation is not washing hands, and burger king commonly undercooks their meat so if that meat contains any ecoli, it would remain in the meat unless coooked properly. To eat healthy may take some more time, it can not be a on the run kind of deal. Your body and health is important and you can take timeto order out from somwhere healthier, or make something. If any fast food restaurant, pick subway, all though their temperatures for meat are also commonly found to be too low. Please reseach before the next timeyou think about eating this food, or perhams watch the movie&quot;super size me&quot;
 
Posted by:
 melissa | April 27, 2005 at 12:56 AM 
 
Verify your Comment

Previewing your Comment
 
Posted by:  |  
 
This is only a preview. Your comment has not yet been posted.
 Your comment could not be posted. Error type: Your comment has been posted. Post another comment 
The letters and numbers you entered did not match the image. Please try again.

As a final step before posting your comment, enter the letters and numbers you see in the image below. This prevents automated programs from posting comments.

 Having trouble reading this image? View an alternate. 
 
 
 
 
Post a comment
 Comment below or sign in with TypePad Facebook Twitter and more... You are currently signed in as (nobody) . Sign Out 
(URLs automatically linked.)
 
Your Information

(Name and email address are required. Email address will not be displayed with the comment.)

 Name is required to post a comment 

 Please enter a valid email address 

 Invalid URL 
 Name:
 
Email address:
 
URL:
 

Comment:
 
 
Recent Posts
 
 Yikes! Gotta update this place! How can you eat low carb with NO work? Easy Low Carb Tuna Cakes Yes, we are back on low carb! Low Carb Ice Cream Go Lower Bars Now Available in US! Thomas&apos; Light Bagels Baja Bob&apos;s Martini Mixes Make GREAT non-alcoholic sugar free slushes! Great Low Carb Blog... Low Carb Slush Syrup from Target 
 
Must Read Low Carb Posts
 
 Low Carb Resolutions Low Carb Shopping List Low Carb Discontinued Product Watch 
 
 Categories 
 
 Food and Drink General Grocery Circular Low Carb Shopping List How To Low Carb Low Carb BJs Low Carb Costco Low Carb Crosby&apos;s Low Carb Eating Out Low Carb Journalism Low Carb Kids Low Carb Market Basket Low Carb News Low Carb Recipes Low Carb Shaws Low Carb Stop&amp;Shop Low Carb Trader Joe&apos;s Netrition.com Surgery: Gastric Bypass&amp;Lap Band 
 
Donate
	</body>
</document>
