<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005020" url="http://www.blogtoplist.com/rss/packaging.html" time="2012-07-12-21:32" support="1" score="0.000921523516918996" bingtitle="Packaging - Blog Toplist" webtitle="Packaging - Blog Toplist">
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="130"/>
	<description>Re-usable dispenser makes tape application ... bulk, he then repackages it in old soda ... Have you ever eaten at a fast food restaurant and noticed how much trash comes with ...</description>
	<body>
		RSS Subjects Submit Blog Edit Blog How it Works 
 RSS Subjects  Blogs about&quot;Packaging&quot; 

Packaging
 
 3M Scotch Tan Packaging and Mailing Tape, 2-Inch x 800-Inch, 6-Pack 
 2012-05-24 09:00:00 
 List Price: $18.99Deal Price: $15.19You Save: $3.80 (20%)3M 347 Scotch Tan Packaging and Mailing Tape, 2-Inch x 800-Inch, 6-Pack: Super strong clear packaging tape with over twice the holding power of the next leading brand. Sure Start dispenser ensures tape will not fall back onto the roll. Polypropylene. Ideal for mailing, packaging and storing.Expires Jun 7, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Jabra DRIVE Bluetooth In-Car Speakerphone - Retail Packaging - Black 
 2012-05-15 09:00:00 
 List Price: $59.99Deal Price: $40.27You Save: $19.72 (33%)Both easy-to-use and intuitive, the Jabra DRIVE in-car speakerphone connects with up to two mobile devices at a time and requires no setup, allowing drivers and passengers to have in-car phone conversations without compromising safety. The Jabra DRIVE also features A2DP technology, which allows you to stream music from a smartphone or Bluetooth-enabled MP3 player, listen to directions from your GPS applications, and more.Expires Jun 6, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Samsung WEP460 Bluetooth Headset [Retail Packaging] 
 2012-05-15 09:00:00 
 List Price: $39.95Deal Price: $14.99You Save: $24.96 (62%)On-the-go people need a headset that is lightweight and ready for action; not one that requires a lot of downtime charging. The SAMSUNG Mono Bluetooth Headset (WEP460) is designed for extended use at a great price.Expires Jun 7, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Scotch Heavy Duty Shipping Packaging Tape, 1.88 Inches x 54.6 Yards, 3 Roll 
 2012-05-14 09:00:00 
 List Price: $24.99Deal Price: $11.99You Save: $13.00 (52%)Scotch Packaging Tape with High Tech Film technology provides extra strength for package protection. Clear. Resists splitting and tearing. Ideal for mailing, moving and package sealing. Meets U.S. postal regulations for standard packages.Expires May 27, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Laura Scudder (1881 - 1959): Potato Chip Packaging Pioneer 
 2012-05-10 07:00:00 
 Did you ever eat Laura Scudder&apos;s Potato Chips -&quot;the noisiest chips in the world&quot;? They are&quot;just like you remember!&quot;Scudder started a food company in 1926 after careers as a nurse and an attorney. While she studied for the bar exam, she and her husband ran a restaurant. They later ran a gaso By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) ZAGG invisibleSHIELD for Apple iPhone 4&amp;4S - Retail Packaging - Clear 
 2012-05-07 09:00:00 
 List Price: $14.99Deal Price: $10.49You Save: $4.50 (30%)Created from a resilient film that was first used to protect U.S. Military helicopter blades from high-speed damage, the invisibleSHIELD is your personal electronics defender. This rugged film wraps around consumer electronics and keeps them functioning and looking great, just like the day they came out of the box.Expires May 21, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Duck Brand Bubble Wrap Protective Packaging, 12-Inch Wide Roll, 30-Feet x 0 
 2012-04-10 09:00:00 
 List Price: $11.99Deal Price: $10.07You Save: $1.92 (16%)Duck Brand Bubble Wrap cushions and protects your valuable items for shipping or storage. Original Bubble Wrap features a nylon, air retention barrier that minimizes air-in-bubble loss and maximizes object protection. More air, more cushioning! 30 foot roll is great for shipping and storage needs. Perforated at 12-inch intervals so you can either rip off a 12-inch sheet, or leave it attached and use the longer roll piece.Expires Apr 24, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Scotch Heavy Duty Shipping Packaging Tape, 1.88 Inches x 54.6 Yards, 3 Roll 
 2012-04-10 09:00:00 
 List Price: $17.99Deal Price: $13.99You Save: $4.00 (22%)Scotch(R) Packaging Tape with High Tech Film technology provides extra strength for package protection. Clear. Resists splitting and tearing .Ideal for mailing, moving and package sealing. Meets U.S. postal regulations for standard packages.Expires Apr 18, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Jabra DRIVE Bluetooth In-Car Speakerphone - Retail Packaging - Black 
 2012-04-04 09:00:00 
 List Price: $59.99Deal Price: $39.99You Save: $20.00 (33%)Both easy-to-use and intuitive, the Jabra DRIVE in-car speakerphone connects with up to two mobile devices at a time and requires no setup, allowing drivers and passengers to have in-car phone conversations without compromising safety.Expires Apr 22, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Duck Brand HD Packaging Tape, 1.88 inch x 54.6 Yard, Crystal Clear, 6 Rolls 
 2012-04-03 09:00:00 
 List Price: $22.99Deal Price: $17.69You Save: $5.30 (23%)High performance carton sealing tape is ideal for sealing boxes and protecting labels. Great for heavy duty packaging, shipping, and storage needs. 2.6 mil thick, crystal clear, easy to read through. Meets postal regulations. Super-strong tape protects your mailed and shipped materials. Re-usable dispenser makes tape application simple.Expires Apr 17, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Firm uses mushrooms to make eco-friendly packaging 
 2012-03-29 04:38:00 
 This will make all the eco-nuts feel warm and fuzzy.From usatoday.comTurns out that mushrooms — great in soups and salads — also make decent packaging material. Mushrooms are a key ingredient in pale, soft blocks produced by the thousands in an upstate New York plant. The blocks are used to cushion products ranging from Dell servers to furniture for Crate and Barrel.More precisely, the packaging blocks are made with mycelium — the hidden &quot;roots&quot; of the mushroom that usually thread beneath soil or wood. Two former mechanical engineering and design students in their 20s, Eben Bayer and Gavin McIntyre, figured out how to grow those cottony filaments in a way that binds together seed husks or other agricultural byproducts into packaging shapes.Look, capitalism works if government gets the hell out of the way. Manufacturers will go green if they can make a buck. &quot;We the people&quot; know what is best for us, we are not children and our Founding Fathers knew that. So back off and l... By: The Uncooperative Blogger Novero Rockaway - Bluetooth Headset - Retail Packaging - Red 
 2012-03-24 08:00:00 
 List Price: $99.00Deal Price: $89.99You Save: $9.01 (9%)Rockaway is a Bluetooth stereo headset that lets you listen to your favorite music in high quality audio-and even take calls - without getting tangled up in cords. Just connect to any Bluetooth enabled music player, phone, PC, laptop or tablet and move to the beat. This is an exclusive offer from Quantum Wireless and is fulfilled by Amazon with FREE Super Saver Shipping and Amazon Prime eligibility.Expires Apr 2, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret elago S4 Glide Case iPhone 4/4S (Snow White) - eco-friendly packaging 
 2012-03-24 08:00:00 
 List Price: $29.00Deal Price: $11.99You Save: $2.00 (59%)Keep the iPhone 4 safe&amp;protected in style with the S4 Glide Case. Unique design allows easy access to all buttons, controls&amp;ports without having to remove the case. Polyurethane coated to protect from scratches and for better grip. This is an exclusive offer from elado and is fulfilled by Amazon with FREE Super Saver Shipping and Amazon Prime eligibility.Expires Apr 2, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Novero Rockaway - Bluetooth Headset - Retail Packaging - Black 
 2012-03-17 08:00:00 
 List Price: $99.00Deal Price: $89.99You Save: $9.01 (9%)Rockaway is a Bluetooth stereo headset that lets you listen to your favorite music in high quality audio-and even take calls - without getting tangled up in cords. Just connect to any Bluetooth enabled music player, phone, PC, laptop or tablet and move to the beat. This is an exclusive offer from Quantum Wireless and is fulfilled by Amazon with FREE Super Saver Shipping and Amazon Prime eligibility.Expires Mar 26, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Plantronics Discovery 925 Bluetooth Earpiece - Black - Retail Packaging 
 2012-02-28 09:00:00 
 List Price: $149.95Deal Price: $44.99You Save: $104.96 (70%)At last, a high-performance Bluetooth earpiece that&apos;s also designed to make you look good. With an elegantly simple VFrame design and a onyx-black, diamond-shaped earpiece, the Plantronics Discovery 925 Bluetooth Earpiece lets you communicate hands-free with comfort and crystal clear performance.Expires Mar 10, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Jabra EASYGO Bluetooth Headset [Retail Packaging] 
 2012-02-23 09:00:00 
 List Price: $39.99Deal Price: $26.75You Save: $13.24 (33%)The Jabra EASYGO is stylish and discreet, and its lightness and shape make it a joy to wear.Expires Mar 5, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Over 40% off on OfficeMax Packaging Peanuts, elligible for Super Saver Ship 
 2012-02-01 09:00:00 
 List Price: $19.29Deal Price: $10.99You Save: $8.30 (43%)Anti-static material is reusable and recyclableExpires Mar 1, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret LG Tone (HBS-700) Wireless Bluetooth Stereo Headset - Retail Packaging - Bl 
 2012-01-28 09:00:00 
 List Price: $69.99Deal Price: $52.40You Save: $17.59 (25%)The LG Tone (HBS-700) Wireless Stereo Headset brings you the high quality audio experience of stereo sound with the convenience of Bluetooth technology.Expires Feb 11, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Apple?s Secret Packaging Room Revealed 
 2012-01-27 08:18:00 
 We’re not in possession to talk Apple’s unparalleled brand. We’re just a nugget. But let’s face it, Apple brand is gazzilion worth talking about even on small stuff that others might think is less important, the packaging. In an article from networkworld, the author explained the work behind Apple’s secret packaging room through the upcoming ... By: Technology at Hand Jabra SUPREME Bluetooth Headset - Retail Packaging - Black 
 2012-01-13 09:00:00 
 List Price: $99.99Deal Price: $73.92You Save: $26.07 (26%)Jabra SUPREME features the latest audio enhancement technology, delivering powerful sound through its 24mm speaker. Up to 6 hours battery life of talk time and 15 days of standby time. Noise reduction by Active Noise Cancellation.Expires Jan 28, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret LG Tone (HBS-700) Wireless Bluetooth Stereo Headset - Retail Packaging - Bl 
 2012-01-13 09:00:00 
 List Price: $69.99Deal Price: $47.99You Save: $22.00 (31%)The LG Tone (HBS-700) Wireless Stereo Headset brings you the high quality audio experience of stereo sound with the convenience of Bluetooth technology. Up to 10 hours of listening/talk time keeps you connected to your music and social life whenever you need it.Expires Jan 28, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Xentris Folio with Stand for Motorola Xoom - 1 Pack - Retail Packaging - Bl 
 2012-01-08 09:00:00 
 List Price: $29.99Deal Price: $12.99You Save: $17.00 (57%)&quot;Xentris Folio with Stand for Motorola Xoom - 1 Pack - Retail Packaging - Black. This is an exclusive offer from UnlockedCellPhoneKings and is fulfilled by Amazon with FREE Super Saver Shipping and Amazon Prime eligibility.&quot;Expires Jan 15, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret elago S4 Glide Case for iPhone 4/4S (Piano Black) - eco-friendly packaging 
 2012-01-01 09:00:00 
 List Price: $29.00Deal Price: $11.99You Save: $17.01 (59%)&quot;Keep the iPhone 4 safe&amp;protected in style with the S4 Glide Case. Unique design allows easy access to all buttons, controls&amp;ports without having to remove the case. Polyurethane coated to protect from scratches and for better grip. This is an exclusive offer from elado and is fulfilled by Amazon with FREE Super Saver Shipping and Amazon Prime eligibility.&quot;Expires Jan 8, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret elago S4 Glide Case iPhone 4/4S (Snow White) - eco-friendly packaging 
 2011-12-25 09:00:00 
 List Price: $29.00Deal Price: $11.99You Save: $17.01 (59%)&quot;Keep the iPhone 4 safe&amp;protected in style with the S4 Glide Case. Unique design allows easy access to all buttons, controls&amp;ports without having to remove the case. Polyurethane coated to protect from scratches and for better grip. This is an exclusive offer from elado and is fulfilled by Amazon with FREE Super Saver Shipping and Amazon Prime eligibility.&quot;Expires Jan 1, 2012 By: Pro Bass Fishing Strategies, Tips, Info and Secret Packaging Your Android App for Advertising Success 
 2011-12-21 07:39:00 
 Imagine walking into a grocery store and making your way down a seemingly endless aisle stocked with millions of products ? some of which have packages accurately detailing the contents and others consisting of plain wrappers providing little or no good information about the products inside. What will you purchase? How will you find what ...


Related posts:Mobile Banking Interest is Limited
Motorola rolls out Android 2.2 update to Milestone
LG Phones to Bundle Google Applications By: Mobile&amp;Technology News Free Duck Packaging tape at Walmart 
 2011-12-15 23:50:00 
 Many Walmart stores have 50ft Duck brand Packaging Tape for $1.00(in stationary or hardware aisles). Use this $1 off print coupon to get it free. Click here to see more Walmart deals on the Free Stuff Times money page ??Ths ?Free? Stuff ?Times?? . C om feed should only be read in feed readers, ... By: Free Stuff Times Safer Food Packaging 
 2011-12-07 13:37:00 
 Researchers at Queen&apos;s University in Belfast have found a way to keep food safe from farm to fork. They&apos;ve developed an oxygen-sensing package system that will let consumers know when too much air has touched their food, making it unsuitable for consumption. A simple color change on the packaging sh By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Should Food Quality Packaging Be Mandatory? 
 2011-12-07 13:36:00 
 The amount of food discarded by consumers is estimated at up to 25% of what is purchased. Should packaging that shows whether food is still suitable for eating be required to help reduce this unnecessary waste? What products would benefit the most from smart packaging?

The preceding article is a&quot;s By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) #6: OtterBox Defender Case for iPhone 4 (Black)[Retail Packaging] 
 2011-01-21 16:30:00 
 OtterBox Defender Case for iPhone 4 (Black)[Retail Packaging] by Otterbox 184 days in the top 100 (525)Buy new: $49.99 Click to see price91 used&amp;new from $17.00(Visit the Bestsellers in Cell Phones&amp;Accessories list for authoritative information ... By: Product Information Directory 5 Creative And Cool T-Shirt Packaging Designs. 
 2010-12-25 13:37:00 
 Prompt Design, a Thai design agency created a range of t-shirts that has recently been awarded a Gold Pentaward. Each of these t-shirts feature a graphic representation of a type of food or drink. These are folded inside vacuum packs, paper bags, plastic wrappers or disposable cups. Impressive!(Image credit: Heresod).Other Posts:Designer Face Masks.Hooks: Transform Your Room.Laptop Stands - What Is Your Choice.Customizable Clothing: Five Interesting Options.Re-Doing Your Bathroom Or Kitchen - Check These Tiles.Beautiful Work Of Art Created Using Common Ordinary Objects. By: algebra of life Iogear 56-in-1 Memory Card Reader/Writer (Bulk Packaging) (GFR281BK01) for 
 2010-10-01 06:47:00 
 IOGEAR&apos;s newest Universal Memory Bank, 56-in-1 Memory Card Reader/Writer, is an ideal solution for hi-speed, bi-directional image and data file transfer between your computer and multimedia devices. By: Hot Deals and Coupons #8: Crest 3D White Advanced Vivid Whitestrips, 14-Count Boxes (Packaging ma 
 2010-07-19 11:31:00 
 Crest 3D White Advanced Vivid Whitestrips, 14-Count Boxes (Packaging may vary) by Crest 89% Sales Rank in Health&amp;Personal Care: 28 (was 53 yesterday) (158)Buy new: $44.99 $21.51 20 used&amp;new from $18.98(Ranking is updated hourly. Visit the Mover... By: Product Information Directory #4: Plantronics Voyager 510 Bluetooth Headset [Retail Packaging] 
 2010-06-18 21:06:00 
 Plantronics Voyager 510 Bluetooth Headset [Retail Packaging] by Plantronics 1821 days in the top 100 (3189)Buy new: $99.95 $39.99 4 used&amp;new from $39.99(Ranking is updated hourly. Visit the Bestsellers in Cell Phones&amp;Service list for authoritative information on this product&apos;s current rank.) By: Product Information Directory BLISTER PACKAGING PROBLEM 
 2009-08-12 03:22:00 
 We are having difficulties with the blister packaging process.

 We have 2 printed cardboards that are pressed together using a Hot cold press.

 We have tried about everything, one side with Glue, two sides, thinner cardboard, thicker cardboard and we always have the same problem:

 When i By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Packaging and Labeling Equipment 
 2009-07-13 16:14:00 
 We are using imported labelling machine for our industry,i need a system basically which stops the machine in case if the label is missed in the container(basically a detection mechanism).Kindly help.

 R.Arun By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Multi layer Plastic film for flexible packaging 
 2009-06-15 15:23:00 
 can anybody enlight me?

 how many layers of materials are achieved/used in fexible packaging recently?

 What are the end products and what are the materials used?

 Regards

 Karan By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Fire Protection and Food Packaging 
 2009-06-01 05:38:00 
 Hi,

 We have a small scale food packaging unit and it is proposed to protect the unit from fire accidents from electrical point of view such as short circuiting,etc.Appreciate if some one can suggest the steps to be taken to avoid such type of accidents. By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Spell Cosmetics New Packaging 
 2009-05-12 11:44:00 
 Spell Cosmetics have redesigned there glosses packaging. Its now more eco friendly but does look suspiciously like nail polish.What do you guys think? Would you buy it or not? By: superficialgirls Insulation and Packaging Products Made With Mushrooms Roots From Ecovative 
 2009-04-18 06:13:00 
 Recently the co-founders of Ecovative Design, who live by the cradle-to-cradle philosophy, have invented two revolutionary new products from mushroom roots,&quot;&quot;Greensulate&quot;&amp;q-uot;and&quot;Acorn&quot;. These two products could be alternative products for energy conservation and waste reduction.&quot;Acorn&quot;is a compostable packaging material and&quot;Greensulate&quot;is an organic insulation. By: American Inventor Spot From Cradle To Cradle: Ecovative Design&apos;s Acorn? Packaging 
 2009-04-17 03:12:00 
 What happens to all the packaging inside of all the computer and printer and cell phone boxes? The preformed foam plastic, the peanuts, the bubble packaging, the sponge sheets... Waste in landfills, toxic waste. By: American Inventor Spot changing the packaging landscape-one bottle at a time 
 2009-04-10 17:54:00 
 Scott Amron must be eagerly awaiting the lawyer&apos;s letters because his brave enough to push corporate buttons for a good cause. Eager to point out the lack of progress with recycling from some of the bog soap companies, he&apos;s taken it upon himself to do it for them. Buying soap in bulk, he then repackages it in old soda bottles and resells it. There&apos;s clearly a giant gap in the marketplace for the bulk supplies bring your own packaging retailer. Obviously, there are co-op grocers doing this on a small scale and Whole Foods has a small operation doing this, perhaps it&apos;s going to take one of the large discounters to make a leap and do this.It plays straight into the frugality space with American&apos;s seemingly doing anything to save a dime, you can easily imagine some of these giant unused shopping malls being turned into food warehouses that allow folks to buy product at a considerable discount and based on a sliding scale that takes the size of your container into account. Those see... By: Influx Insights Designer Drinks Packaging Sports Fresh Look 
 2009-04-07 03:00:00 
 Imagine pulling a ripe banana, strawberry or kiwi fruit off the vine, plunging in a straw and drinking up the freshest fruit juice you ever tasted. These delightful designer fruit juice packages bring us one step closer to doing just that. By: American Inventor Spot Cooling Systems for Blister Packaging Equipment 
 2009-04-07 01:25:00 
 How to size and design a cooling system for blister packaging machine for tablets and capsules based on the following.

 1. Flow rate of tap water as coolant - 40 liters/hr.

 2. Inlet temperature to the blister machine- 20 deg. C.

 3. Out temperature from the blister machine - 50 de By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Same packaging? 
 2009-03-23 17:16:00 
 I just saw my Smashbox fusion soft light (yes it is &quot;smashed&quot;) and my Inglot eyeshadow together for the first time and they have exactly the same packaging. Same size material etc.Weirdness.... By: superficialgirls Biodegradable Packaging Design for McDonald?s: Could it Help? 
 2009-03-21 05:03:00 
 Have you ever eaten at a fast food restaurant and noticed how much trash comes with your burger, drink and fries? University of the Arts graduate student, Andrew Millar has noticed the amount of trash and has designed an alternative eco-solution to this wasteful problem. By: American Inventor Spot JOB OPENINGS AT HEINEKEN USA 
 2009-03-11 21:39:00 
 For those that are looking or know people who are looking for work, here are three open positions that Heineken is looking for fill. Click on the links below to download the full job descriptions, responsibilities and requirements. By: The Repblica Update Skin Board Packaging 
 2009-02-05 19:37:00 
 I am looking for Skin Board printers located in the western United States.

 Does anyone have any good sources they would like to share?

 Thanks!

 Sheila By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) Should Packaging Companies Promote Recycling? 
 2009-02-03 14:08:00 
 Everybody seems to be in favor of the idea of recycling packages, but in the end, whose responsibility is it for getting the job done? The packaging industry has been asked to design its products to encourage recycling, but is that the end of its responsibility? Or should the federal government step By: Conference Room 4 (CR4) KFC UK Goes For Eco Packaging 
 2009-01-27 13:00:00 
 Fast food restaurants are having a hard time in the UK over waste paper and packaging, in order for KFC to reduce their annual rubbish out by fourteen hundred tonnes, they are planning on changing their packing to a more eco friendly type.

Instead of the traditional cardboard boxes and clamshells, they will putting their food ... By: Keetsa! Blog - Eco-Friendly and Green New Packaging for Eco-friendly Milk 
 2009-01-25 04:34:00 
 brainchild, Consumerism, Dairy Free, Drinks, Eco Friendly, Food, Green Business, Green Design, greenbottle, inventors, marketing strategy, office waste paper, Recyclable, Recycle, recycled office

 Related posts
 
 Water Power in Australian Bikes
 Solekshaw Hits Eco-friendly and Employment Needs
 Recyclable Milk Bottle Container from the Green Bottle
 Picking Ideas from Eco-Fairs
 Paper Making Kit
 Models Strip Down For a Cause
 Inventor focuses on Environmentally-Friendly Homes
 FAO Schwarz ... By: Keetsa! Blog - Eco-Friendly and Green 
 
 114596 blogs in the directory.
Statistics resets every week.


 Contact | About 
©Blog Toplist 2012
	</body>
</document>
