<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005224" url="http://www.culinary-institutes.com/articles/take-pleasure-in-a-chef-career/" time="2012-07-12-21:45" support="1" score="0.0020891604191187073" bingtitle="Articles | Culinary Institutes - Culinary Arts Schools, Cooking ..." webtitle="Articles | Culinary Institutes">
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>While this presents a cultural loss on a number of ... Fast-food restaurant jobs don&apos;t have to be the dead-end ... How can something that tastes so bitter make my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Home School Search A-Z Culinary Schools Culinary Articles 
 Search School Directory
 Select Subject: ALL Baking and Pastry Catering Chef Training Cooking Culinary Arts Culinary Arts Management Hospitality Management Hotel Management Restaurant Management Enter Zip Code: 
 
 Strayer University 
 610 Uptown Blvd. Suite 3500
Cedar Hill, TX 75104 More Info &gt;&gt; 

 Strayer University 
 7701 Las Colinas Ridge Suite 450
Irving, TX 75063 More Info &gt;&gt; 

 Le Cordon Bleu College of Culinary Arts in Dallas 
 11830 Webb Chapel Road
Dallas, TX 75234 More Info &gt;&gt; 

 
 
 All Programs
 
 Baking and Pastry Catering Chef Training Cooking Culinary Arts Culinary Arts Management Hospitality Management Hotel Management Restaurant Management 
 
Culinary Articles
 
 Baking Careers Click to View Articles 
 
 A Baking Career Really Takes the Cake 
A beautiful cake is the centerpiece of so many of our celebrations. The moment of joy as a bride and groom cut a wedding cake can make all the hard work of baking school worthwhile.
 Amateurs Can Help Your Baking Education 
Amateur cooks who enter local baking contests are experts in their own right. They spend their time learning tricks and techniques you may not learn in baking school.
 Baking and Pastry School: Starting Your Career in Weddings 
For those with talent and dedication, wedding cake baking could be the first step toward a sweetly successful career.
 Baking Bread By Hand is High Class 
More and more of our food is machine made and prepackaged, but baking training will never go out of style. People will always appreciate hand made bread, and your baking career will flourish.
 Baking Training Comes In Handy For The Holidays 
Of course a baking career is a year &apos;round vocation, but there are so many more baking jobs to be done around the holidays. It&apos;s a time when your baking training will make you very very popular.
 Better Baking: Quick Decorating for Cakes and Pies 
Gain the skills to land a job in one of today&apos;s fastest-growing field -- Culinary. Find culinary program listed in this resource.
 Better Pastry Next Time 
Less than perfect results with your pastry? Pastry chef school teaches you to try, try again.
 Cakes: The Art and Science of Baking 
Cakes are often the visual centerpieces of weddings, birthdays, and other festive events. The chefs who create these masterpieces have the dual challenge of baking delicious desserts and designing a works of art. Cakes range from the traditional to the outrageous, and chefs need professional culinary training to meet consumer demands.
 Catering School Produces Good Cooks 
Several top chefs have described how a job in catering started their culinary careers. Catering schools teach more than how to make an open faced sandwich. You can learn enough to move from catering to a serious cooking career.
 Chocolate Uses You Won&apos;t Learn in Baking School 
One of the ingredients you&apos;ll become familiar with in your baking classes is chocolate. Here are a few uses of the delicious stuff that you probably won&apos;t learn at your baking and pastry school.
 Culinary Arts&amp;Craft: A Pastry Chef Career 
One of the stars of a fancy kitchen is the pastry chef. It&apos;s not the easiest career in the culinary arts, but going to pastry chef school will put you into very special category as a chef.
 Easy-to-Make Pastry Can Add Class to Your Meals 
Sometimes the simplest touches can add elegance to a meal. You don&apos;t have to go to pastry chef school to learn this simple form of puff pastry. But if you pursue a pastry chef career, you&apos;ll make variations on this recipe hundreds of times.
 Forget the Tapestry - Try the Art of Pastry! 
Gain the skills to land a job in one of today&apos;s fastest-growing field -- Culinary. Find culinary program listed in this resource.
 French Pastry School - Your Gateway to a World of Pastry Jobs 

If you have finished your chef training and are looking for a challenging and exciting career that will take you round the world, why not look for a cruise ship chef job?

 From Nuts to Donuts for Indiana Baking School 

If a new Indiana proposal goes through, one of the country&apos;s newest baking schools will be razed on the grounds of a former state hospital, once home to those suffering from mental illness. The plan is demonstrative of piqued public interest in baking as a career choice.

 Go for the Pastry 
If you have finished your chef training and are looking for a challenging and exciting career that will take you round the world, why not look for a cruise ship chef job?
 Italian Culinary Traditions: Desserts 

Mention Italian food and most people think of pasta or pizza. How often do Italian desserts come to mind? When you study culinary arts, however, you explore all the culinary traditions of a culture&apos;s food.

 No Need to Knead in Bread Baking School 
In today&apos;s bread baking schools, there&apos;s no need to get your hands dirty--in fact, there&apos;s no need to knead at all. Culinary students are learning that the art of baking bread is patience.
 Pastry and Politics: Hail to the Chef 

Former Arizona governor Fife Symington couldn&apos;t stand the political heat, so he got into the kitchen - and has a pastry chef career to show for his midlife job transition.

 Pastry Chefs Explore the Many Shades of Sweet 
Pastry chef school affords an excellent opportunity for pastry chefs to get to know sugar. The essence of pastry, sugar&apos;s subtle character can take a dessert from sweet to exquisite.
 Pastry Chefs Face a World Without Shortening 
New York City&apos;s ban on trans fats signals the end of an era in flaky, delicious, shortening-laden baked goods. With a pastry chef school education, however, you won&apos;t even miss this hazardous ingredient.
 Pastry Chefs Savor the Sweet Sorbets of Summer 
If you&apos;re experiencing your annual love affair with summer fruits, consider showcasing them in a refreshing sorbet. Sorbet is a year-round staple of the pastry chef&apos;s menu, a refreshing palate-cleanser to close any meal.
 Plating Is the Pastry Chef&apos;s Toughest Job 
Restaurant owners want to serve desserts made by pastry chefs with the best possible training. The pastry chef&apos;s job is to create items that will bring customers back again and again.
 Roland Mesnier: 25 Years as America&apos;s Pastry Chef 

Roland Mesnier recently stepped down from his post as Executive Pastry Chef at the White House. His career as the pastry chef in the White House has spanned 25 years and five presidents.

 Should I Go To a Pastry Chef School? 
Baking training can cover a very wide range of kitchen skills. Almost all culinary institutes teach basic baking of breads and cakes. If you want to become a fancy pastry chef, you&apos;ll probably have to attend a special school.
 Signature Desserts 
Do you have a couple of special desserts up your sleeve to end the meal with a bang? It&apos;s part of every good chef&apos;s education!
 The Secret of the Perfect Loaf Unlocked: Your Next Baking Class 
Gain the skills to land a job in one of today&apos;s fastest-growing field -- Culinary. Find culinary program listed in this resource.
 What Can Baking and Pastry School Do for You? 
If you are interested in a baking career, find out how attending baking and pastry school can prepare you for success in this field.
 Your Bread and Butter: What Baking Schools Can Do for You 

Love bread? Get started in a great bread baking career by taking classes at a culinary school.

 Your Guide to Baking and Pastry School 
Gain the skills to land a job in one of today&apos;s fastest-growing field -- Culinary. Find culinary program listed in this resource.
 Should You Bake with Artificial Sugar? 
We used to have one option to sweeten our food: sugar. Now there are pink, blue, and yellow packets that offer 100 times the sugar power without any calories. It&apos;s appealing for coffee, but what about for baking cookies?
 Unusual Ingredients in Pastry Chef&apos;s Culinary Arts Career 
Wolfgang Puck began his culinary arts practice as a child, when he cooked pastries with his mother in the kitchen. While pastries can be made as desserts, they are also often associated with breakfast. And if you think breakfast pastries consist entirely of doughnuts, scones, and croissants, think again.
 Culinary Tips for the Pastry Chef School Student 
Are cinnamon rolls your favorite part of breakfast? Do friends rave about your homemade pies? Do the difficulties of making baklava seem like exciting challenges to you? Perhaps you&apos;re destined for a career as a pastry chef.
 Pastry and Pleasure 
Humans are &quot;hard-wired to enjoy food,&quot; says writer-researcher Harriet Brown, &quot;it&apos;s a survival mechanism.&quot; Brown takes us to task for &quot;dutifully&quot; choking down healthy foods we don&apos;t like, eating on the run, and aggressively over-eating when we feel deprived. Perhaps we should be less diet conscious and more pleasure conscious in our eating habits. Would you like to contribute to this worthy cause?
 
 
 Chef Profiles Click to View Articles 
 
 Adventures of the Tailgating Chef 
Who knew that a stadium parking lot could rival a good restaurant? Tailgating cuisine isn&apos;t just about hot dogs anymore.
 Do Your Knives Say You&apos;re a Top Chef? 
Dull knives aren&apos;t just an embarrassment to the chef school graduate; a young chef with a dull knife can actually get fired.
 Entertaining At Your Best 
If you have finished your chef training and are looking for a challenging and exciting career that will take you round the world, why not look for a cruise ship chef job?
 From My Kitchen: Singing For the Customer&apos;s Supper as Part of Restaurant 
Food songs may not be on the menu at restaurant school, but you can&apos;t get through your restaurant career without hearing at least a few.
 From Prison to Professional Chef: The Tale of Jeff Henderson 

Here&apos;s how executive chef Jeff Henderson made it to the pinnacle of the culinary arts profession.

 Greek Pastry Chef Makes the Biggest Baklava of His Career 
A Greek pastry chef has given himself a huge job. He&apos;s trying to get into the Guinness Book of World Records by baking the world&apos;s largest baklava. It&apos;s not the kind of task they teach in pastry schools.
 Is Your Kitchen Ready for Spring? 
The best chefs are in tune with the seasons, and know which goodies to put on the menu in springtime.
 Now with MSG! Gourmet Chefs Revive the Unpopular Additive 
Perhaps it&apos;s an Alice Waters backlash: some gourmet chefs are adding chemical flavor enhancers such as MSG to menus hitherto dominated by fresh, simple ingredients.
 Personal Chefs Bring Haute Cuisine Home 
Chefs are hitting the culinary career jackpot by providing nutritious food for seniors and busy families.
 Pomegranates: The Cinderellas of the Culinary World 

These softball-sized red fruits with the electric crimson seeds have frequently confounded consumers unsure what to do with a pomegranate.

 Teflon: Do the Health-Risk Claims Stick? 
Teflon has gotten a bad rap in recent years, but with proper chef training, Teflon can be safe. Nevertheless, more and more culinary institutes and career chefs use copper or iron exclusively.
 The New Wine Pros 
Women and minorities, please apply if you see wine service in a culinary job description. Today, matter who you are or what your background, you can have a career as a sommelier.
 The President&apos;s Pastry Chef Makes a Change 
Pastry chefs can make their own career choices. Once you have that culinary degree from pastry chef school, you can steer your own ship. At least that seems to be the lesson to be gained from Thaddeus R. DuBois&apos; recent announcement.
 The Return of Fine Cuisine 
The lost art of fine cuisine is being rediscovered by average Americans everywhere. Classes at your local culinary arts school can make the difference in your ability to keep your New Year&apos;s resolution to eat better this year.
 The Rise (and Fall?) of Genetically-Engineered Bread 
Genetic engineers have manufactured a bionic wheat resistant to overmixing. It&apos;s great news for mass producers, but even better for the artisan bakers and bread baking schools who stand to encounter a growing demand for unprocessed food.
 White House Chef: One of the Best Private Chef Jobs in the Country 

If you are a politically-minded person, you might dream of becoming president. If your dream is a career as a chef, you might dream of becoming the president&apos;s chef. Cristeta Comerford realized that dream when she accepted the most sought after private chef job, head cook at the White House.

 Will the Top Culinary Schools Compete in the Salad Bowl ? 

How much of your culinary career will be spent competing with other chefs? Very few culinary arts schools have football teams, but today&apos;s culinary education should include a course on how to compete in the kitchen.

 The Chef and The Dietician: The New Dynamic Duo 
Chefs and dieticians have long worked together in a variety of institutional environments, such as wellness centers, hospitals, and long-term care facilities. Now, more of these professionals are integrating both fields to help clients understand food, and make delicious, healthy meals.
 The Perks of Being a Personal Chef 
You already know that careers in culinary arts can land you anywhere between Argentina and Amsterdam. But did you ever think that the most exciting of those places could be a perfect stranger&apos;s kitchen? If you&apos;ve never considered the lucrative world of the personal chef, then read on, and get ready to let your culinary school training work for you.
 Jamie Oliver Brings the Culinary Arts to British Schools 
Leave it to Naked Chef Jamie Oliver to stir up culinary controversy. A year ago, he began a well-intended campaign to apply the culinary arts to school lunches across Britain. His efforts, which the New Statesman labels a &quot;jihad against junk food,&quot; have whipped up his critics. Still, he counts Tony Blair--and hundreds of newly-informed school children--among his culinary fans.
 Flat Urban Chef Oasis 
While a flat urban oasis may be a Des Moines neighborhood with a Barnes and Noble and a Starbucks, the flat urban oasis referenced here is Urban Flats, a Florida restaurant and a great place to be a chef.
 
 
 Cooking Careers Click to View Articles 
 
 75 Years of Culinary Joy: Art&apos;s in the Eye of the Beholder 

In the age of high culinary arts and celebrity chefs, the publication of a fresh 75th anniversary edition of &apos;The Joy of Cooking&apos; reminds us that you don&apos;t need a culinary degree to create a bestselling cookbook.

 A Baking Career on the High Seas 
Imagine a luxury hotel that has no fixed address. That is the description of a cruise ship, and it could be the floating home of your baking career.
 A Career as a Chef is a Creative Career 
If you are a creative person who enjoys food and wine, you should consider a career as a chef. A chef&apos;s career is a real adventure. The chef&apos;s training process is not easy, but it is an exciting part of the journey.
 A Catering Career Can Be an Adventure 
If you&apos;d like new challenges and different menus almost every day, a catering career may be for you. There are plenty of catering jobs waiting for chefs with catering training.
 A Catering Career Profile: Caterer of the Year 
Jack Milan did not become Catering Magazine&apos;s Caterer of the Year 2004 by accident. His catering career began after he had already a successful corporate consultant and then started his own very successful restaurant.
 A Chef&apos;s Career Starts At Home 
Becoming a chef is a long, and often difficult process. Chef&apos;s training can be very demanding, but a chef career is very rewarding.
 A Culinary Career is All about Sharing 
Chefs used to be full of secrets. They guarded their recipes jealously and refused to allow anyone into their kitchens. But today&apos;s world of TV celebrity chefs has made sharing part of the game. They are proud of their culinary training and they want to let others enjoy it, too.
 A Culinary Degree Can Be a Ticket To Travel 
You can never imagine where your culinary degree might lead you. For some people, chef school is the ticket to a world of adventure. For one chef school graduate, it led to a fine catering job in the U.K.
 A Culinary Map of South Africa 

Chef Eduan Naude built his culinary career on specialties like worm, antelope, and crocodile. His sometimes shocking, always authentic menu pays tribute to the culinary arts of South Africa&apos;s diverse ethnic groups.

 A Fine Time for a Culinary Career in Wine 
With sommelier training from a culinary institute, you can raise your glass to a bright future in wine.
 A Successful Culinary Career Starts With a Successful Culinary Education 
Gain the skills to land a job in one of today&apos;s fastest-growing field -- Culinary. Find culinary program listed in this resource.
 Ana Sortun, Role Model for a Chef Career 
If you&apos;re a chef in training, be inspired by the award-winning culinary talent of Boston-area chef Ana Sortun.
 Being a Chef is a Creative Career 
Being a chef is hard work, but it is an exciting and rewarding career. The chef&apos;s work is in a creative class with that of painters and sculptors, but people get to eat the art.
 Beyond The Kitchen: A Career Path To The Top 
Not all chefs stay in the kitchen. Many take their culinary careers a step higher. They go to restaurant management school and learn to run an entire enterprise.
 Building a Culinary Writing Career 
Before you pick up the food writer&apos;s pen, plan for success with professional training.
 California Wines and Culinary Careers: A Perfect Pairing 
Award-winning California wines have done more than upset French vintners; they&apos;ve also ushered in a new era of haute cuisine, where bold wines are as crucial to the meal as crisp, local flavors.
 Catering Careers On the Upswing After 9/11 Setbacks 
Catering careers were unstable as the industry suffered many setbacks in the past few years. Now jobs in catering are on the upswing again, and more students are seeking catering training.
 Changing Careers: Transform your Culinary Passion into a Culinary Career 
Gain the skills to land a job in one of today&apos;s fastest-growing field -- Culinary. Find culinary program listed in this resource.
 Chefs Resurrect Ye Olde Culinary Arts 
From &apos;swan gizzard sauce&apos; to &apos;Texas Rattlesnake Chili,&apos; more and more chefs are establishing careers as culinary historians, recreating historic dishes from ancient recipes. But do these age-old delicacies actually taste good?
 Contract Catering Jobs Build Chefs&apos; Skills 
Graduates of culinary institutes have a whole world of culinary career paths to choose from. You probably won&apos;t start out as the top chef in a fancy restaurant when you graduate, but there are many other ways of honing and showing your skills.
 Culinary Art Careers Require Creative People 
There&apos;s a reason that the preparation of fine cuisine is taught at a culinary arts school. There is a lot of art in a culinary art career. The most successful graduates of culinary arts schools are the people who are the most creative and artistic in their approach to the work.
 Culinary Arts Classes on Land and Sea 
If you&apos;re a culinary arts aficionado, then summer offers you the chance to merge two terrific activities: vacationing and cooking.
 Culinary Arts: It&apos;s All in the Implements 
If you&apos;ve ever spent an hour in the cooking store mesmerized by a wall covered with cooking gadgets, this culinary arts advice is for you.
 Culinary Careers Part II: Chef Jobs 
Due in part to television programs, food channels, and America&apos;s obsession with dieting, chefs are more important and more famous than ever. Culinary Careers Part II will take a look at various chef jobs and what kind of chef training is required.
 Culinary Education can Teach you to Forget the Fries! 
There are lots of ways to prepare potatoes, other than mashed or fried. What other tricks do the culinary art schools have up their sleeves?
 Culinary Industry Goes Green with Organic Foods 
In the United States, the public&apos;s desire to eat and live in a healthier way is increasing, as people take particular notice of the origin of the food they purchase and consume.
 Disaster: It&apos;s All in the Hospitality Industry Job Description 
Katrina left destruction in its path, but adversity is just another part of a career in hospitality. Hospitality jobs are coming back--even in flood-ravaged New Orleans.
 Do You Have the Personality for a Hospitality Career? 
Culinary institutes can teach you everything about the culinary arts, but a hospitality career requires more than knowledge. You have to be ready to give the best you have to offer-and give it to complete strangers.
 Do You Have the Right Ingredients for a Career as a Chef? 
Today&apos;s chef might supervise a staff of other chefs at larger institutions, prepare food in their own restaurant, or showcase their culinary talents on a TV cooking show. What kind of chef career would you want training for?
 Foundations Provide Culinary Career Support 
The life of a chef can be a hard one. Who&apos;s got your back? Find out where you can turn for support while building your culinary career.
 From Sublime to Ridiculous: The Pastry Chef as Mad Scientist 
The New Gastronomy&apos;s pastry chefs roll dough with the rest of them--except they add everything from chlorophyll to calcium chloride to the recipe. For some truly crazy desserts, check out this new culinary art.
 Garde Manger Chef Jobs: Your Foot in the Kitchen Door 
As any reality cooking show tells us, the heat is on the hot line. Meanwhile, those whose chef careers place them on the cold line--the garde mangers--keep cool though the do a half dozen jobs.
 Get Paid to Become a Chef 
Changes in the federal rules for funding make it easier for you to get a chef school degree, both online and off. States and chefs groups help out, too.
 His Unusual Ailment Led Him to a Culinary Career 
Learn about a baker in California began a profitable profession in the culinary arts because ordinary cookies made him ill. He invented his own recipes and took his skills from baking class all the way to the bank.
 Invention is Part of a Chef&apos;s Job Description 
Your chef education will teach you all the fundamentals of cooking and how to follow recipes. When you start your chef career you&apos;ll need to invent the recipes that other people follow.
 Is There Art in a Culinary Art Career? 
The institutions that used to be called cooking schools now go by the descriptive title: culinary arts schools. Does the change have to do with marketing and promotion, or is there are real reason for the emphasis on art?
 Japanese Knives Give the Culinary Competition an Education 
Culinary artists from East to West are turning Japanese to get an education in cutlery--and finding that light, flexible blades make slicing and dicing a breeze.
 Jill of All Chef Trades? Or Master of One Culinary School? 
Most culinary degree seekers just want a job after they complete chef school, but it&apos;s the positions they seek early on that determine whether they&apos;re viewed as chef specialists or masters of many cuisines.
 Museum Chefs and the Art of Dining 
When most people think of visiting a museum, images of paintings, photographs, sculptures, and other genres of art come to mind.
 Now You&apos;re Cookin&apos;! Chef Careers in the Spotlight 
Culinary arts are popular in the kitchen and on TV. From Julia Child to Emeril, culinary training has been the first step toward a culinary career.
 Online Culinary Career Support: It&apos;s As Close As Your Computer 
There&apos;s a virtual culinary community at your fingertips, willing to share information with you about getting a culinary degree and having a cooking career.
 Private Chef Jobs in Hollywood and Beyond 
Your culinary degree can launch a career that goes way beyond the kitchen of a top restaurant. There are thousands of chef school graduates who never see the inside of a public kitchen--they take private chef jobs for the rich and famous.
 Research Chefs Get it Right (Eventually) 
If the mad dash from kitchen to dinner table isn&apos;t your culinary style, consider a career as a research chef. With the chance to fine tune a single recipe to your heart&apos;s content, your creations will reach a new degree of culinary perfection.
 Sweet Culinary Careers 
If anti-sugar news has you doubting the wisdom of a pastry chef career, you should be cheered by the recent successes of dessert-oriented restaurants, large and small.
 Sweet Deals for Chef-Entrepreneurs 
These inventive chefs would rather risk their culinary careers on their great ideas than go for the sure-fire paycheck.
 Take Pleasure in a Chef Career 
A culinary degree can put you on the road to a very enjoyable chef career, where you&apos;ll be at the top of the culinary arts pyramid.
 Television Chef Jobs Are on the Rise 
If you add some acting classes to your chef&apos;s education, you might land one of the growing number of chef jobs on television. And you&apos;ll probably make two or three times the average salary for a regular chef.
 The Best Start For Your Culinary Career 
A culinary career is an adventure. Like most adventures, your culinary career will be most rewarding if you prepare well. The best preparation starts with the best culinary schools.
 The Chef: Top of the Culinary Arts Ladder 
There are many different levels in the culinary arts. Not everyone in a culinary career is a chef. In better establishments, a chef&apos;s job description is very specific, and people are careful not to misuse the title.
 The Culinary Arts as Sport 
The culinary arts have become much more than just good cooking. Now they are also good television. How long before competition technique becomes a course in most culinary colleges?
 The Gourmet Chef de School Cafeteria 
The American school cafeteria. Perhaps not the epicenter of gourmet cuisine, but if chefs like Alice Waters and Ann Cooper have their way, your local elementary school could soon be serving five-star lunches.
 The Industrial Chef: A Stable Culinary Career 
If you have a passion for food, but aren&apos;t enthusiastic about running a four-star kitchen, consider a more stable culinary career as an industrial chef.
 The Magic Ingredients to Being like a Career Chef 
Have your guests wondering what you did to make your dishes different from everyone else&apos;s version - even better than most career chefs&apos; dishes.
 The Secret Lives of School Cafeteria Chefs 
Restaurants must produce large amounts of delicious food in a timely manner, with the help of a team of chefs striving to please discriminating diners.
 Think Outside the Restaurant Box for Culinary Arts Careers 
If you&apos;re investing in a culinary arts degree, be sure to cast a wide career net that includes onsite foodservice.
 Thoughts About a Hospitality Career 
There are lots of ways you can participate in the exciting life of a restaurant or hotel without becoming a chef. Have you thought about a hospitality industry job?
 Turn Your Chocolate Addiction into a Culinary Career 
If you&apos;re a chocoholic, why not get paid for indulging your deepest desires? With a culinary degree, aspiring chocolate tasters can turn their passion into a career selecting, buying, and marketing chocolate.
 Turn Your Love of Wine into a Hospitality Management Career 
Once you&apos;ve turned your passion for flinty whites and jammy reds into a wine and hospitality career, you&apos;ll want to make your personally lifestyle match your management position.
 Vegetarian Catering: Finding Your Culinary Career Niche 
Vegetarian cuisine expresses your culinary artistry in catering to the needs of diners who want healthy fare, for both everyday meals and special occasions.
 Versatile Vanilla and its Value to Your Culinary Career 
Sure, it smells good, but what is vanilla really good for--and how do we get it?
 What Effect will Katrina Have on Cajun and Creole Cuisine? 
What will come of chef jobs in the Big Easy? Will Creole and Cajun restaurants return to New Orleans or spread throughout the U.S?
 What&apos;s the Average Salary for Different Chef Jobs? 

As a qualified chef a wide range of jobs are open to you; the average salary for a chef varies according to the job description.

 Will Your Culinary Career Help You Become the First Chef in Space? 

The newest Star Wars movies are filled with death-defying light saber fights and star fighters moving at intergalactic speeds. You don&apos;t see a lot of is eating. What will a culinary arts career be like in if and when we mere humans mastr space travel? Will the culinary schools of the future include space cooking as a regular subject?

 Work on a Cruise Ship: For a Chef It Can Be a Dream Job 

If you have finished your chef training and are looking for a challenging and exciting career that will take you round the world, why not look for a cruise ship chef job?

 Your Culinary Career on Wheels 

Want some street cred for your culinary school degree? How about starting a coffee or catering cart and being your own boss?

 Your Hospitality Job Description: Caring for Strangers 

Once again, food establishments have become homes away from home for a world of travelers in constant motion. As a result, hospitality careers take on a whole new meaning and importance in our culture.

 Your Journey toward a Hospitality Management Career 

With a hospitality or tourism degree from a culinary institute or university, you can travel straight to the top of this exciting field.

 Use Your Culinary Career to Connect Kids and Food 
It&apos;s no secret that the sun is setting on the ritual of family dinners. While this presents a cultural loss on a number of levels, one of the worst is that today&apos;s children feel no connection to the food they eat. Culinary school graduates are perfectly poised to help recreate this connection, and groups like Spoons Across America are making it as easy as pie.
 How Can Your Culinary Career Help Others? 
All the big stars are doing it, and you can too. This winter, use your culinary arts skills for more than just putting food on the table. With the right inspiration, the right ideas, and your skills as a chef, you can feed hundreds, even thousands, with the proceeds from a single event.
 Saute Pan Elbow? Prevention is the Key to a Long, Comfortable Culinary Career 
As far as injuries go in the world of culinary careers , cuts and burns get all the glamour. But if you&apos;re a chef, you will be standing on rock hard floors, flashing knives like a ninja, and leaning over hot, boiling goodness on the stove for hours at a time. You&apos;ll also be moving as fast as you can to fill your orders. It&apos;s a recipe for disaster.
 Culinary Careers and the Art of Slowing Down 
Slow food? The very concept is amusing for anybody who has ever worked in a successful commercial kitchen, but it&apos;s catching on around the world. The Slow Food movement was started in Italy in 1989, a direct response to the popularity of the fast food restaurants and the lifestyle they encourage. According to the Slow Food homepage, &quot;Slow Food works to defend biodiversity in our food supply, spread taste education and connect producers of excellent foods with co-producers through events and initiatives.&quot;
 Get into a Chef-Entrepreneur Career, Girlfriend 
Advertising themselves as &quot;today&apos;s solution to the age-old dinner challenge,&quot; the sisters (and, okay, the brothers, too) who run My Girlfriend&apos;s Kitchen spend their days helping their patrons cook, not cooking for them. That&apos;s right. Imagine a chef career where you do the shopping, prep, and cleanup while your diners do the cooking! The idea is simple: clients cook a dozen take-home meals for themselves in a two-hour session. With a menu of 14 dishes that changes each month, clients never grow bored with the culinary offerings.
 Just Business: Tips for Starting a Catering Career 
Thinking of starting your own catering business? The rewards of working catering jobs seem obvious: you can create your own menu, work your own hours, and choose who your coworkers. But a culinary catering career extends far beyond a lof for food - business training is highly valuable. Even if you&apos;re a great cook, the business aspects of catering jobs can determine whether you succeed or fail.
 Culinary Institutes Promote Great Salad Ideas for Chefs 
Summer is here - the season of bikini diets and last-minute efforts to get in shape. This includes healthy eating, so as a chef, it&apos;s important to include good, nutritious food choices on your menu.
 Yuba: A Tofu Twist for the Culinary Career 

Soy has gained a lot of attention over the last several years, acclaimed by many as a source of complete protein and omega-3 fatty acids. But there are still some who find soy unappealing, including culinary career professionals such as chef Daniel Patterson, who, according to his article in the New York Times Magazine , felt that tofu was &quot;dull.&quot;

 Where Meat Comes From, and Other Culinary School Topics 

Wanting to grill those delicious specialty short ribs? No problem; simply go to the local grocery store, pick out the cut you want, oh, wait. You&apos;re the chef in charge of meat fabrication. In your restaurant , the meat is fresh. You&apos;ll just have to carve the cut you want.

 Good Business Science: The Art of a Hospitality Career 
You&apos;ve been there before. After waiting nearly half an hour to be seated, you sat in the dark for another half an hour before any waiter even acknowledged your presence. Finally, an unfriendly, rushed waitress took your order, but after forty-five minutes, the food still hasn&apos;t come.
 A Culinary Career: Beyond the Backyard Barbeque 
Summer is almost here, and it&apos;s common to kick off barbeque season by doing some Memorial Day grilling. Barbequing may be considered an easier way of cooking, but if you&apos;re aspiring to a culinary career, or are looking forward to restaurant chef jobs, an average barbeque just won&apos;t light your fire. Follow these tips for the best barbeque ever.
	</body>
</document>
