<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005666" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/top-dog-berkeley-185300" time="2012-07-12-22:15" support="2" score="0.004116288031533156" bingtitle="Top Dog - Reviews &amp; Menu - Elmwood - 2534 Durant Ave, Berkeley 94704" webtitle="Top Dog - Reviews&amp;Menu - Elmwood - 2534 Durant Ave, Berkeley 94704">
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001037" bing-rank="168"/>
	<description>Description: Top Dog is a Hot Dogs, American, and Fast Food restaurant where most ... Berkeley Menu, Berkeley Dog Menu, Top Dog Kielbasa, Top Dog Condiments Berkeley Menu ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 Top Dog Menu 

 Top Dog Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Berkeley Restaurants » Elmwood » Hot Dogs » Top Dog Share | 
Top Dog
 
 4.14286 star rating           
  4.1 rating over 4 reviews 
 (510) 843-5967 

 2534 Durant Ave ( ) 

 Berkeley , CA 94704-1771 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing View Hours 
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (4) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Top Dog is a Hot Dogs , American , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for a meal on the go , paid less than $10 , and tipped less than 15% . Tags: Hot Dogs, American, Fast Food, Good For Kids, Vegan, Takeout, and Good for groups Stats: 
 21 dishes entered by diners at Top Dog 2 users love Top Dog 
 Tips: 
 Top Dog&apos;s late hours make it an ideal after-party stop. Remember RC Cola? Believe it or not, it still exists and it&apos;s sold here. 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Top Dog? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Top Dog
 Write a review 
 4 reviews First reviewed by fattiusthebear 
 
&quot;gastronomique magnifique!&quot;

 95 helpful votes over 17 reviews 
 freshfunk5 
 17 Restaurant Reviews +95 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Top Dog freshfunk5 
 November 28, 2006 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 +6 0 +6 6 Votes   
Top Dog is top notch!
 
Top Dog is a fine establishment with the usual characters being the smoked-out college kids, late-night nerds, the crazy guy with a wild eye and random asian girls in their pajamas.

In college, Top Dog was THE place to go to after a night of drinking and frat partying. Nothing killed a crave like a Top Dog. (Smothered in your choice of sauerkraut, relish, onions, ketchup, all sorts of foreign mustards, etc.)

Nowadays, Top Dog is THE place to go to after a night of binge drinking and pub crawling. Kidding. But it’s open late and is the perfect late night snack. They have a wide assortment of sausages/dogs to choose from. Be on your toes when they take your order and when you pay. They run a tight ship.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
KIELBASA
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
i like kielbasas…and by that i mean the sausage not what Jack Black refers to as“kielbasa.”
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
&quot;because a bear&apos;s gotta eat well&quot;

 623 helpful votes over 156 reviews 
 fattiusthebear 
 156 Restaurant Reviews +621 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Top Dog fattiusthebear 
 August 9, 2006 
 3.0 
 3.0 star rating           
 +6 0 +6 6 Votes   
top dog in expensiveness
 
I love the hot dogs at Top Dog. But the downsides are too much. No only is a hot dog really expensive, but they are small portions and do not fill you up at all. You have to get at least a couple to fulfill hunger at all. The types of hot dogs they are have are neat and all taste great though. The place smells great too.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Jim B. 
 from Judy&apos;sBook 
 
March 14, 2007
 
 5 star rating           
 
Awesome dogs
 
This is a classic Berkeley joint. Been going there for 30 years. Great grilled dogs with excellent fixin&apos;s. Sauerkraut, onions, relish, 5 kinds of mustard. You must try all the dogs to determine your own favorite but mine are the Top Dog…

 read full review» 
 juju13es 
 from Citysearch 
 
March 13, 2007
 
 5 star rating           
 
smoked chicken apple hot dogs!
 
When I visited Berkeley, I had to go to the hyped up hotdog joint... I ordered the smoked chicken apple dog, and it was just delish! And it was cheap too and the wait was relatively short (a huge difference from waiting hours for…

 read full review» 
 Read 10 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at Top Dog

These dishes from the Top Dog menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
SMOKED CHICKEN APPLE
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
BIRD DOG
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
KIELBASA
 
 5.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Campus Flowers 
 5 reviews 4.5 stars Paper Heaven Walgreens Zebra Tattoo&amp;Body Piercing 
 92 reviews 5.0 stars PostalAnnex+ Framer&apos;s Workshop The 
 2 reviews 5.0 stars Moe&apos;s Books 
 17 reviews 4.5 stars Reprint Mint 
 3 reviews 5.0 stars U C Hair Salon&amp;Waxing 
 29 reviews 5.0 stars Postal Annex 
 Top Dog is located near the cities of Columbus, Regina, Albany, Rockridge, and Kensington. People found this by searching for: Top Dog Kielbasa, Berkeley Dog Menu, Top Dog Restaurant Menu, Top Dog Menu Berkeley, Top Dog Berkeley Menu, Toop Dog Berkeley Menu, and Top Dog Berkeley Durant. 
Featured in Berkeley
 
 3.875 star rating           
 Kirala 
 3.5 star rating           
 La Mediterranee 
 3.0 star rating           
 Thai Delight Cuisine 
 4.5 star rating           
 Musical Offering 
 4.5 star rating           
 Hong Kong East Ocean Restaurant 
 4.25 star rating           
 Yang Chow Restaurant 
 3.75 star rating           
 King Dong Restaurant 
 5.0 star rating           
 Taqueria Las Comadres II 
 5.0 star rating           
 Pearl of SIAM 
 5.0 star rating           
 Virginia Bakery 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 25 
 
Listed On
 
 My Restaurant Rotation by WinstonLiaw 

 Note: wieners are delicious

 Dishes: standard top dog is best, can&apos;t stand anything made from non-4-legged animals
 
Nearby Restaurants
 House of Curries Sweetheart Cafe LA Burrita Linguini Casual Gourmet Blackberry Ginger 
Link to Top Dog
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
Related Links
 Yelp Reviews The Delicious Life Blog Reviews on TripAdvisor 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
