<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005619" url="http://www.christianedwarehouse.com/cep/home.cfm?&amp;DID=6" time="2012-07-12-22:11" support="1" score="0.011868346621216504" bingtitle="Christian Ed Warehouse - Sunday School, Vacation Bible School, VBS ..." webtitle="Christian Ed Warehouse - Sunday School, Vacation Bible School, VBS, Bible Clubs">
			<query id="000601" bing-rank="111"/>
	<description>and material, VBS, Bible clubs, and digital lessons. Plus Everyday Free Shipping on orders over $99! Questions or to order by phone 800-854-1531</description>
	<body>
		Your #1 source for Sunday school 
 curriculum
and material, VBS, Bible clubs, and digital lessons.
 Plus Everyday Free Shipping on orders over $99! 
 Questions or to order by phone   800-854-1531 
 
 
   
 
 
 
 
 FREE Information 
 Insider eNewsletter All-Stars for Jesus Lesson Sampler Sunday School Samples Catalogs&amp;Information Teacher&apos;s Hints&amp;Tips Helpful Articles Elem. Bible Activity Lessons Sample 
 All-Stars for Jesus
Bible Clubs 
 FREE Lesson Sampler More Information Order Now FAQ FREE Downloads Bible Club Blog 
 Vacation Bible School 
 Browse All VBS Programs Special VBS Offers Order VBS Now VBS Downloads VBS Planning Timeline (PDF) Frequently Asked Questions VBS Tips Blog 
 Sunday School Store 
 Browse All Sunday School Programs Order Curriculum Now Children&apos;s Church Downloads Digital Lessons Online Bible Activity Lessons Classroom Decorations ClubTime Year-in-a-Box Kits 
 Sunday School
Curriculum Downloads 
 Downloads 
 Best Sellers 
 Best Sellers 
 Reproducible Books 
 Reproducible Books Games Crafts and Activities More Activities VBS Teacher Training Outreach Programs Bible Clubs Sunday School 
 Children&apos;s Ministry 
 Children&apos;s Church Large-Group Programs Games, Crafts, Activities Teacher Training Leadership Resources Nursery and Preschool 
 Youth 
 Youth Resources Preteen Resources 
 Digital Lessons, Crafts, Activities 
 Bible Foundations Curriculum Preschool Lessons Online Elementary Bible Activity Lessons Bible Basics/Christian Basics Youth Lessons VBS Downloads Coloring Pages, Games, Crafts, Activities 
 Classroom Decorations 
 View All Inspirational Classroom Decorations Banners&amp;Borders Bulletin Board Sets Attendance&amp;Incentive Resources Maps, Charts&amp;Posters 
 Bibles
	</body>
</document>
