<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005693" url="http://claremoreprogress.com/local/x1753194213/Juvenile-detention-costs-problems-ongoing" time="2012-07-12-22:16" support="1" score="0.0010485443260078308" bingtitle="Juvenile detention costs, problems ongoing » Top Stories ..." webtitle="Juvenile detention costs, problems ongoingTop StoriesClaremore Daily Progress">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>Roberts asked for a zoning change from AG ... March foreclosure activity down to near 5 ... free of charge during Rogers County Trash-Off Days, according to Rogers County ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Main Content Find a Job Post a Resume Career Advice Employers Select Price $100K or less $100K - $150K $150K - $200K $200K - $250K $250K - $300K $300K - $600K $600K or more Cars AG and HD Equipment Recreational 
 
 

 
 Home Progress e-Edition Top Stories Local Beats 
 Business Community Crime/Courts Education Government Religion Health It&apos;s Happening 
 Towns 
 Catoosa Chelsea Foyil Inola Oologah/Talala Owasso Verdigris 
 State/Nation Obituaries 
 Death Notices 
 Sports 
 Local Sports Progress Sports Network 
 Right Wing Randy? Opinion 
 Editorials Columnists Letters to the Editor 
 Features 
 All Features Births Engagements Weddings Anniversaries Forms 
 Classifieds 
 Wheels Monster Jobs Zillow Real Estate 
 Legal Notices 
 For the Record 
 TV Week Subscriber Services Contact Us Facebook Twitter Magazines&amp;More 
 Healthcare Directory Readers Choice Surrey Retirement Redefined Locally Owned 2011 
 
 
 Top Stories 
 Search 
Search Results
 Close Previous Now showing: of Next Previous Next Close December 27, 2007 
 Juvenile detention costs, problems ongoing 

 By JOY HAMPTON The Claremore Daily Progress Thu Dec 27, 2007, 10:55 AM CST 
 






Juvenile detention rate hikes, transportation costs and other problems associated with the detainment of adolescents continue to plague boards and agencies within the county and state. Rogers County Board of County Commissioners is among them.

Commissioners dealt with three issues related to the detention of juvenile offenders on the Board agenda Wednesday. A claim to the Office of Juvenile Affairs topping $6,000 for November, an increase in bed rate charges by Pottawatomie County, and the termination of the contract with Tulsa County for juvenile detention beds reflect rising costs and legal entanglements involved when dealing with juvenile offenders.

In November commissioners approved a modified contract for “Detention Services Agreement” with Tulsa County Juvenile Detention Center reflecting a “bed rate increase from $17.95 to $39.32 per day to cover the actual cost of operations,” a 119 percent increase that went into effect Dec. 1.

Now that contract has been terminated by Tulsa County.

According to Tulsa County Assistant District Attorney Linda Greaves, 11 detention services agreements with other counties were put on the Tulsa County commissioners’ agenda and were approved without prior legal review.

“They’re just not good contracts for my client,” said Greaves. “I believe they don’t have any legal viability. It has to do with how the contracts were drafted.”

She said the 11 contracting counties do not have juvenile bureaus, such as Tulsa County, and there is no reason those district attorneys would question the wording in the contracts.

“I wouldn’t expect any of the DAs to be familiar with the statutes that govern juvenile bureaus,” she said.

Greaves said the termination of the contracts had nothing to do with the recent increase in bed rates. Because of attorney-client privilege, Greaves said she could not go into specifics about the contracts though she did talk about medical expenses as one of the issues that she believes needs further clarification.

“Some of the terms are not based in law,” said Greaves. “The agreements are markedly unfavorable to my client.”

Greaves said this is the first time she has seen a detention services agreement between Tulsa and other counties during her 13 years with the District Attorney’s Office. She also said that whoever drafted the agreements didn’t have the appropriate legal knowledge to do so.

“At best, it’s a bad contract,” she said.

A search through 2006 documents for Rogers County did not find a contract with Tulsa County Juvenile Detention Center for that year.

Greaves said she could not comment on whether Tulsa County commissioners would send a new contract or whether Rogers County would be able to continue to use the Tulsa County juvenile facility.

Beds for juveniles are in high demand and Rogers County Sheriff’s deputies often have to transport juveniles long distances to facilities. The Tulsa detention facility is the closest in the area.

Among juvenile detention centers contracted by Rogers County for beds are facilities as far away as Cleveland, Canadian, Texas, and Beckham Counties.

Deputies are paid mileage and an hourly rate to transport juveniles to and from those facilities for court appearances, doctor’s appointments and other needs.

In August, a male adolescent between the ages of 14 and 16 escaped from custody when the keys fell out of the transporting officer Weldon Foster’s pocket onto the car seat during a brief rest stop.

The juvenile undid his handcuffs and leg irons and slipped away, according the Undersheriff Barry Lamb.

Lamb said when the juvenile was apprehended he was predictably headed to a familiar place.

“He just wanted to go home,” said Lamb.

Foster, who has since retired from transportation work, was one of a very few deputies willing to transport long distances. That trip to Beckham County detention was billed at 672 miles and 31 hours of work time according to county records.

Sometimes a deputy must leave the night before and stay in a motel in order to pick up a juvenile and have the detainee to court for an early appearance. In such a case the state-funded, Oklahoma Office of Juvenile Affairs (OJA) pays for the motel and meals.

Long miles and frequent trips expose deputies to risk of a juvenile escape, said Lamb who pointed out that adolescents are inclined to “inherently impulsive” and sometimes unpredictable behaviors.

Lamb said OJA identifies where beds are available, and the court orders the juvenile there. The Sheriff’s Department has no say in where adolescents in custody will be held, said Lamb.

Among those distant facilities Rogers County must utilize for juvenile detention beds is Pottawatomie County Regional Juvenile Detention Center (known as Glenn Dale Carter Hall).

The Pottawatomie facility amended its contract with Rogers County to raise bed rates from $19.77 per child per day to $20.39. The amended contract was approved by commissioners Wednesday.

A trip on May 1 to Pottawatomie County detention to transport a juvenile “to Court and return” was billed at 513 miles and 11 and a half hours by Foster according to county records. State funding, through OJA foots that bill.

The bed rate charges in the amended contract represent Rogers County’s percent of the full bed charges. Ideally, OJA pays 85 percent of the bed charges with the county responsible for 15 percent. Rates are based on a formula established by OJA and may not reflect actual costs.

Also funded through OJA are alternative juvenile detention costs such as home bound detention.

A claim was approved by commissioners for the month of November in the amount of $6,461 to OJA for reimbursement. The charges represented $1,890 paid for “Own Home Detention” and $4,571 worth of transportation expenses incurred by the county.

Transportation charges billed to OJA include mileage at .485 per mile and $12 per hour for the transporting officer’s time “as allowed by State Law” according to county records.

In other county business commissioners:

•set appeal hearing for Leo Roberts on a zoning request for Jan. 7. Roberts asked for a zoning change from AG (agricultural) to IL (industrial) at 5541 East 390 Road, Oologah

•approved payment of ODOT Claim form for $15,360, 30 percent of county bridge project from CBRI fund for engineering by Guy Engineering. Helm said the county had received $252,000 for the project and total engineering costs would run over $50,000

•took no action and did not open bids for Skid Steer Loader for District 3. Commissioner Kirt Thacker said one was purchased under the emergency declaration because it was needed

•signed the order reflecting the vote on the Petition to Withdraw lands from Limestone Fire Protection District. The petition was not granted

Contact Joy Hampton at 341-1101 or at news4@claremoreprogress.com
 Text Only Top Stories 
 Claremore student tracing Olympic history 
A Claremore student is on a journey to discover the history of the Olympic Games.

 July 12, 2012 1 Photo 
 Poll gives Mullin wide margin 
A recent poll of registered Republicans indicates Markwayne Mullin has a wide margin over his opponent George Faught.

 July 12, 2012 
 Curfew? Police chief reminds juveniles to observe local law 
There’s an old bit of parental wisdom long-passed down to children which cautions that“nothing good ever happens after midnight.”

 July 12, 2012 1 Photo 
 Only a Forum, Not a Debate 
Despite recent reports that Saturday’s GOP candidate forum in Claremore will be a debate, the event’s format has changed.

 July 12, 2012 
 Sanitation workers clean up with overtime pay 
Some citizens are questioning overtime for Claremore’s sanitation workers after recent budget reports showed a spike in the department’s payroll levels.

 July 12, 2012 
 Commission to decide SORC closure 
A plan to close one of two state-run facilities for the developmentally disabled is expected to come to a vote of the Oklahoma Commission for Human Services on July 24.

 July 11, 2012 
 American Airlines CEO says time to consider merger options 
The head of  American   Airlines  says it’s time to reach out to potential merger partners or investors, seven months into a bankruptcy restructuring.

 July 11, 2012 1 Photo 
 Claremore school district relocating administrative offices 
The Claremore Public School District’s phones and internet service will be down beginning today, while the central office relocates to the old Central Upper Elementary building located on 102 West 10th Street.

 July 11, 2012 1 Photo 
 FACE OFF: Faught, Mullin to confront issues during live debate 
The runoff election for Oklahoma’s 2nd Congressional District is heating up and Rogers State University Television will once again be bringing live coverage of the candidates.

 July 11, 2012 
 UPDATED: Sequoyah choir director arrested on rape, multiple sex charges 
A Claremore Sequoyah teacher is being held without bond in Rogers County Jail following his arrest on multiple sex crimes against a minor.

 July 10, 2012 1 Photo 
 More Top Stories Headlines 
 Poll 
George Faught and Markwayne Mullin will face off in a debate Monday evening at Rogers State University. Which of the two candidates for the GOP nomination for the District 2 Congressional seat do you support?
 George Faught
 Markwayne Mullin
      View Results Featured Ads AP Video Freeh: Penn St. Disregarded Children&apos;s Safety Report: Penn St. Officials Concealed Abuse Biden: Presidency About Character, Obama Has It US, China Square Off Over South China Sea Florida A&amp;M President Resigns in Wake of Scandal Research Murky on Danger of Asian Carp Invasion SOS Call for Historic Ship Docked in Philly New York Sees &apos;Manhattanhenge&apos; Sunset Rep. Jesse Jackson Treated for &apos;Mood Disorder&apos; Olympic Quest Began in H.S. for Female Wrestler Another California City Opts for Bankruptcy Investor: Missing Bank Director &apos;Stole&apos; My Money Columbus, OH Mayor: Glad Derailment Wasn&apos;t Worse Pelosi Expects Rep. Jackson to Explain Absence OH Woman Vanished on NC Vacation; Reward Offered Two Workers Rescued High Above Manhattan 
 Maps, Menus, Store hours, Coupons, and more... Find a business
 Location
 
 Popular Searches Apartments in claremore 
 Attorneys in claremore 
 Auto Dealers in claremore 
 Auto Parts in claremore 
 Auto Repair in claremore 
 Beauty Salons in claremore 
 Car Rental in claremore 
 Dentists in claremore 
 Doctors in claremore 
 Flowers in claremore 
 Hotels in claremore 
 Insurance in claremore 
 Loans in claremore 
 Mortgages in claremore 
 Movers in claremore 
 Pizza in claremore 
 Realtors in claremore 
 Restaurants in claremore 
 Storage in claremore 
 Tax Preparation in claremore 
 Travel in claremore 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com 
Site Map
 
 Contact Us 
 
 ©2012 Community Newspaper Holdings, Inc. · CNHI Classified Advertising Network · CNHI News Service 
Associated Press content©2012. All rights reserved. AP content may not be published, 
 broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Our site is powered by Zope . Some parts of our site may require 
 you to download the Flash Player Plugin .
 Privacy Policy | AP News Registry privacy policy 
 Terms and Conditions 
 Advertiser Index 
 Back to top 
Claremore Daily Progress
 315 W Will Rogers Blvd
 Claremore, OK
 74017
	</body>
</document>
