<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005765" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/408338-is-there-high-cholesterol-in-steamed-clams/" time="2012-07-12-22:24" support="2" score="0.0034054787481109187" bingtitle="Is There High Cholesterol In Steamed Clams? | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Is There High Cholesterol In Steamed Clams? | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="14"/>
	<description>Condiments. It&apos;s easy to go overboard on condiments for ... A 3/4 cup serving of breaded and fried clams from a fast food restaurant contains 87 mg of cholesterol, only 7 mg ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Health Managing Cholesterol Cholesterol in Fish&amp;Seafood Is There High Cholesterol in Steamed Clams? 
 
 Is There High Cholesterol in Steamed Clams? 
 Mar 28, 2011 | By Sandy Keefe Photo Credit Clams in dish image by kellykramer from Fotolia.com 
With heart disease reaching near epidemic proportions in the U.S., health care professionals are urging patients to reduce their risk factors through exercise and a diet low in cholesterol and saturated fats. In 2001, the National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute issued cholesterol guidelines in the form of a Therapeutic Lifestyle Changes diet that recommends keeping your daily cholesterol intake below 200 mg. Although some seafood products, including shrimp, contain significant amounts of cholesterol, clams are considerably lower in cholesterol.
 
The Basics

Cholesterol is a wax-like substance produced by clams, humans and other animals. Your body produces about 75 percent of the cholesterol you need to build healthy cells, produce vitamin D and hormones and regulate other functions. The remaining 25 percent comes from the animal foods you eat each day. If you take in more cholesterol than your body needs for essential functions, the excess cholesterol stays in your bloodstream and increases your risk of developing coronary artery disease, heart failure, heart attacks and strokes.
 
Cholesterol Content

The NHLBL recommends keeping your daily cholesterol intake below 200 mg. A single serving of clams, or about 12 small clams, contains 80 mg of cholesterol, which represents about 40 percent of your daily limit -- a moderate amount of cholesterol. To put this amount in perspective, consider that a large egg has 186 mg of cholesterol, half a roast chicken breast delivers 82 mg and a 3 oz. hamburger made with 80 percent lean beef has 77 mg.
 
Condiments

It&apos;s easy to go overboard on condiments for your steamed clams, but wise choices can limit the added cholesterol. Lemon juice, wine and garlic are all cholesterol-free, so you can comfortably add those to the clam broth. However, butter contains 31 mg of cholesterol in a single tablespoon. Adding 3 tbsp. of melted butter to your dozen steamed clams raises the total cholesterol content to 173 mg, or about 87 percent of the daily recommended limit.
 
Misconceptions

Although many people believe fried clams are higher in cholesterol than steamed clams, the difference is minimal. A 3/4 cup serving of breaded and fried clams from a fast food restaurant contains 87 mg of cholesterol, only 7 mg more than the steamed version. Since cholesterol is an animal product, the wheat flour used to coat the fried clams is cholesterol-free and brings down the overall cholesterol count. If you add 3 tbsp. of melted butter to your steamed clams, however, your entrée of a dozen steamed clams contains twice as much cholesterol as the serving of fried clams.
 
References

 National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute: What is Cholesterol? Food and Drug Administration: Seafood Nutrition Facts U.S. Department of Agriculture: National Nutrient Database Fat Free Kitchen: Cholesterol in Seafoods, Crab, Lobster, Oyster, Scallops, Shrimp and Clams 
 
Article reviewed by Tina Boyle Last updated on: Mar 28, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading 
 
 Raw Clams&amp;Cholesterol 
 
 Nutritional Value of Steamed Clams 
 
 Nutritional Information for Fried Clams 
 
 Benefits From Eating Steamed Clams 
 
 Are Clams Healthy to Eat? 
 
 How Do I Make Steamed Clams? 
 
 How Do I Properly Prepare Steamed Clams? 
 
 Fried Clams Nutrition 
 
 Nutritional Value of Clams 
 
 How to Cook Clams Indoors 
 
 How to Steam Littleneck Clams 
 
 Smart Shopping for Clams 
 
 How to Cook Clams on the Stove 
 
 How to Easily Cook Clams 
 
 Ways to Cook Venus Clams 
 
 Calories in Steamed Clams 
 
 How to Steam Clams Without a Steamer 
 
 Nutritional Value of Canned Clams 
 
 How Many Calories are in Steamed Softshell Clams? 
 
 Protein in Raw Clams 
 more advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 Is Clam Chowder High in Cholesterol? 
 
 Eureka 370A Enviro-Steamer Review 
 
 Calories in Cafe Steamers 
 
 What Is Good Cholesterol&amp;Bad Cholesterol? 
 
 How to Cook Willapa Bay Steamer Clams 
 
 Cholesterol Drugs to Help Lower Cholesterol Levels 
 
 How to Clean a Facial Steamer 
 
 How Much Cholesterol is OK in a Low-Cholesterol Diet? 
 
 Blood Sugar Levels&amp;High Cholesterol Levels 
 
 Clam Chowder Calories 
 
 Strategies for Reducing High Cholesterol on a Cholesterol Free Diet 
 
 How to Steam Clams in Shells in the Microwave 
 
 How to Cook Rice in a Steamer 
 
 Are There More Calories in Clam Chowder or California Medley Soup? 
 
 Do Cholesterol Drugs Do Any Good? 
 
 The Calories in Steamed Blue Crabs 
 
 Normal Range of Cholesterol Levels 
 
 If You Don&apos;t Eat Cholesterol, Will You Still Be at Risk for High Cholesterol Levels? 
 
 How to Steam Fresh Clams 
 
 What Are the Benefits of a Facial Steamer? 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
