<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005895" url="http://voices.washingtonpost.com/class-struggle/2010/04/why_waste_time_on_a_foreign_la.html" time="2012-07-12-22:34" support="19" score="0.036997509009833465" bingtitle="Class Struggle - Why waste time on a foreign language?" webtitle="Class Struggle
 - Why waste time on a foreign language?">
			<query id="000308" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000683" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001060" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000389" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000386" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000745" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000463" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="112"/>
	<description>“It is a waste of time and money in our schools ... Plenty of students enter college with credit ... place instantly, just like if he were at a Fast-Food Restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		&gt; Class Struggle  
Network News
 X My Profile 
 Friends&apos; Activity 
 View More Activity 


 

 
 
 Focus on Schools |
 In-depth coverage: Education Page | The Answer Sheet | Jay Mathews&apos;s Class Struggle» 
 About Jay Mathews 
Jay Mathews is an education columnist for The Washington Post. You can contact him at mathewsj (at) washpost.com .

 Want to learn more about Class Struggle? Metro Monday Admissions 101 On the Web Extra Credit Trends 
 Search This Blog   
 Recent Posts 
 What Jerry Bracey would have said about Locke High New film shows folly of Ivy envy Why low standards for education are good Why science careers, and courses, aren&apos;t so popular &apos;I was not allowed to take AP English&apos; 
 
 Entries By Category Admissions 101 Extra Credit Jay on the Web Local Living Metro Monday Trends dc schools Full Category Archive 
 Entries By Date 
 Full Weekly Archive 
 Subscribe 
 Select ... 
 RSS Feed Close What Jay&apos;s Reading... 
 EdTech Assorted Stuff Board Buzz Core Knowledge D-Ed Reckoning Thomas B. Fordham Institute Eduwonk EdWize Gotham Schools Joanne Jacobs Schools Matter Susan Ohanian This Week in Education 
 More Education News 
 Education Section X = Why? Challenge Index Schools&amp;Learning Tomorrow&apos;s Critics College Toolkit Search Local Schools Search D.C.&apos;s Charters 
 
Why waste time on a foreign language?
 
 [This is my Local Living section column for April 22, 2010.] 

My online discussion group, Admissions 101 , recently exchanged verbal blows over foreign language courses in high school. Most of us defended the conventional wisdom. Learning another language improves cognitive development, we said. It enhances academic skills, encourages a sense of the wider world and looks good to colleges.

But the dissenters scored some points. “It is a waste of time and money in our schools,” said a parent who remembered seeing empty language lab stalls. A high school teacher said that “language study is complete nonsense for most people. I’d wager close to 80.percent of kids taking foreign languages in high school do so because they have to.”

There is something to that. Most high schools, including those in the Washington area, do not require foreign language study for graduation. Virginia students need it only if they want to earn an advanced diploma. Maryland requires foreign language classes, but students can substitute technology courses if they want. The reason why a majority of Washington area high school students take foreign languages — Spanish is the most popular choice — is that selective colleges often require them.


 
How much do they learn? There is little evidence that many students achieve much fluency in high school. Two of my children were serious Spanish students, joined programs that had them live with families in Latin America and today, as adults, use the language in their work. But their parents were the more typical opportunists. We did what we had to do to get a good grade but developed few conversational skills.

My wife avoided the problem of speaking fluency altogether by taking Latin. That helps explain her great skill as a writer and editor of English, but she is happy her high school language is dead.

I also took Latin the first two years of high school, because that was what the most nerdy kids in the school were doing, and they were my peer group. Exhibit A is John Holdren, who grew up to be a Harvard professor of environmental policy and is President Obama’s science czar. When I was a ninth-grader, upperclassman Holdren bought me as his slave for the annual Latin Banquet. But my close observation of his behavior at that event led me to conclude he was more interested in talking to girls dressed in bedsheet togas, as he was, than in developing linguistic skills to discuss Pliny the Elder.

I switched to German for 11th and 12th grades. I learned little and got A’s. It wasn’t until I decided I wanted to be a reporter in China that I got serious about grammar, vocabulary and accent in a foreign tongue. It was very difficult , another reason why high school language students don’t get very far.

How students still look good on their report cards is easy to explain. Because much of the world is striving to learn English, Americans wonder why they should bother to learn other languages. We talk about the importance of foreign language learning to our national security, but we don’t mean it. If if we need speakers of exotic tongues, we import them.

We tell our children that their Spanish or Russian or Arabic or Japanese studies are important. But we give them high grades for little progress. Most colleges don’t require that applicants have more than two years. And from what I can see, based on what actually happens in high schools, learning a foreign language often is a waste of time.

 Read Jay&apos;s blog every day at http://washingtonpost.com/class-struggle .

Follow all the Post&apos;s Education coverage on Twitter , Facebook and our Education web page, http://washingtonpost.com/education . 
 2010 04 21 22 00 
ByJay Mathews | April 21, 2010; 10:00 PM ET
Categories:  Local Living  | Tags:  good grades for little work , low standards for instruction , the rest of the world speaks English so why try , why learning foreign language is a waste of time
	</body>
</document>
