<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005850" url="http://www.city-data.com/forum/portland/95587-how-much-food.html" time="2012-07-12-22:31" support="1" score="0.0006493256700130583" bingtitle="How much is food? (Portland, West Linn: sales, home, layoffs ..." webtitle="How much is food? (Portland, West Linn: sales, home, layoffs) -   City-Data Forum">
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>... maybe post some prices from their grocery receipt ... Fred&apos;s has better quality and a far better selection ... Which fast-food restaurant is it?, Portland Forum, 6 replies</description>
	<body>
		City-Data Forum &gt; U.S. Forums &gt; Oregon &gt; Portland How much is food? (Portland, West Linn: sales, home, layoffs) 
 
 User Name Remember Me Password 
 
 
 Register Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Search Blogs Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 Welcome to City-Data.com forum! Make sure to register - it&apos;s free and very quick! You have to register before you can post and participate in our discussions with 1 million other registered members. User profiles and some forums can only be seen by registered members. After you create your free account you will be able to customize many options, you will have the full access to over 15,000 posts/day about local topics and you will see fewer ads. 
 
 Jump to a detailed profile or search
site with 
 Search Forums   ( Advanced ) 
 Business Search - 14 Million verified businesses 
 Search for:  near:  
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 
 
 
   06-10-2007, 03:01 PM 
 insanityincredibly Member   Location: Tualatin, Oregon 47 posts, read 122,360 times Reputation: 31 
 How much is food? My little family and I are moving to Portland from Hawaii. I was wondering if anyone who lives in the area could maybe post some prices from their grocery receipt for me. I&apos;d like to compare a little, I&apos;m guessing things couldn&apos;t be more expensive than here. I know gas is only a little cheaper there, but I read that it was a lower octane rating than here. Anyway, just trying to gather as much as I can so we have a better idea of what we&apos;re in for. These forums are great, along with microsoft live for the birdseye views of the area, that&apos;s pretty much what we&apos;re basing our actions on. We&apos;d like to go to the West Linn area, I&apos;ve read good and seen good. Oh, and if anyone knows if a carpentry apprentice such as myself can find work fairly easily or not, let me know, otherwise there&apos;s always restaurant jobs right? Right on, right on, thanks in advance. 
 
 
 
 
   06-10-2007, 03:38 PM 
 Supernova7 Not a member   1,008 posts, read 2,052,064 times Reputation: 202 
 Why would you leave Hawaii? It&apos;s so beautiful there. I know the cost of living is very high but is that the reason? 
 
   06-10-2007, 03:58 PM 
 PNW-type-gal Crankier than average   Location: Agency Lake, Oregon 2,720 posts, read 4,538,748 times Reputation: 1763 
 There is a surprisingly large native (or part-Native) Hawaiian contingent in Portland, with some reasonable Hawaiian cafes.

If you go to an on-line grocery store (like safeway.com) that does home delivery, you can get an exact idea of what prices are. The on-line prcies tend to be a couple percent higher than actual in-store prices, but it&apos;s pretty close. The zip code for West Linn is 97068, you can put that in when the site asks for it.

If you shop sales and buy in-store it will be a bit less than these prices, but this&apos;ll give you an idea.

I know when I go to Hawaii, I change my eating style, and avoid things (like boxed cereal, dairy, cheese, steaks) that are cheap here and expensive there, and stick to locally grown vegies, fruit, fish from the fish market and rice. If you can find ono (wahoo) in the store here, it tends to be incredibly expensive. 
 
   06-10-2007, 04:47 PM 
 Supernova7 Not a member   1,008 posts, read 2,052,064 times Reputation: 202 
 A better question.. PNW GAL,

What are the popular&quot;discount&quot;grocery stores in Portland? I&apos;m not talking the Whole Foods or I believe it&apos;s called New Seasons in your region. In other words, where do people shop on a budget since everyone can&apos;t be a millionaire....: 
 
   06-10-2007, 05:12 PM 
 PNW-type-gal Crankier than average   Location: Agency Lake, Oregon 2,720 posts, read 4,538,748 times Reputation: 1763 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Supernova7 A better question.. PNW GAL,

What are the popular&quot;discount&quot;grocery stores in Portland? I&apos;m not talking the Whole Foods or I believe it&apos;s called New Seasons in your region. In other words, where do people shop on a budget since everyone can&apos;t be a millionaire....: 
 WinCo, Food 4 Less, Costco, WalMart - as long as you are buying in bulk. I don&apos;t shop at them because I don&apos;t buy in bulk and I don&apos;t appreciate WalMart&apos;s business model.

Since there are only two of us now, I shop at QFC, Fred&apos;s and Wild Oats (which Whole Foods is trying to buy but the FTC is holding up the merger), with side trips to Trader Joes: all depending on what I&apos;m buying and what&apos;s on sale. I like New Seasons quite a bit, but they aren&apos;t very close and I got a snotty answer when I asked them if they had any plans to build a store near me.

I also shop at the farmer&apos;s markets in season. I tend not to buy meat from the stores unless they carry local and non-massive-feedlot meat. I pay a lot more per pound, but we just eat less. 
 
   06-11-2007, 12:18 PM 
 Supernova7 Not a member   1,008 posts, read 2,052,064 times Reputation: 202 
 Thank you very much, that was most informative. I hear that Winco and Food 4 less are good stores. Are they scattered all over Portland or are they scarse? ....Thanks 

P.S..I don&apos;t like buying&quot;bulk&quot;either. It&apos;s a pain to transport, especially when you&apos;re not driving. Maybe I can flag down a scooter....lol 
 
   01-04-2009, 07:05 PM 
 portland area Junior Member   1 posts, read 2,514 times Reputation: 10 
 Winco clarification Winco is not a bulk store. It&apos;s employee owned. The prices are often half what you pay at conventional chain grocery stores. You do have to bag your own groceries (though they do provide plastic and paper bags and sell reusable ones). 
 
   01-04-2009, 08:54 PM 
 davefr Senior Member   Location: Oceanside and Chehalem Mtns. 714 posts, read 1,079,634 times Reputation: 446 
 Winco or super Walmarts are the best for prices.

I won&apos;t shop at Fred Meyer. (&gt;Walmart prices and&lt;Walmart quality) 
 
   01-04-2009, 10:00 PM 
 Minervah Senior Member   Location: Portland OR 6,802 posts, read 3,796,657 times Reputation: 5255
	</body>
</document>
