<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005572" url="http://www.unique-reception-theme-wedding-ideas.com/mcdonalds-weddings-mcweddings.html" time="2012-07-12-22:07" support="2" score="0.01457754810718779" bingtitle="McDonalds Weddings McWeddings - Unique Theme Wedding Ideas" webtitle="McDonalds Weddings McWeddings">
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>Mickey D&apos;s reception will not permit alcohol, since the fast food restaurant wants to ensure that the guests don&apos;t ... Will guests be permitted to order anything off the menu ...</description>
	<body>
		Home 

Nav Header

 News 

The Big Event

 Cakes Cars&amp;Limos Centerpieces Creative Ideas Decorations Etiquette Flowers Gifts Invitations Money Saving Tips Outdoor Ideas Photo Ideas Planning Guide Reception Decor Reception Ideas Unique Ideas Wedding Store Wedding Themes 

Beauty

 Bridal Attire Hairstyles 

More Resources

 Honeymoon Ideas Shower Ideas Wedding Resources 

Miscellaneous

 Contact Me Privacy Policy Terms of Use About Me 
 [ ? ]Subscribe To This Site 
 
 
 

McDonalds Weddings McWeddings

 

 McDonalds Weddings McWeddings 

So where will weddings take place next? Who would have ever thought that McDonald&apos;s would be in the wedding business?

I&apos;ve heard of couples hosting weddings in a backyard, old barn, vineyard, catering hall, field, beach, top of a mountain, park, and so on however, with couples tying the knot in Home Depot, Target and other out of the way places why not have your wedding reception at McDonalds?




 




Well, people in Hong Kong can now have McWeddings, a McDonald&apos;s wedding. As of January 1, 2011 McDonalds offered McWeddings packages including McDonald&apos;s food, pink invitation cards with the Golden Arches, a baked apple pie wedding cake, a dress made out of party balloons and kiddie party favors for guests. The cost in Hong Kong dollars is equivalent to $128 US dollars with the actual cost depending upon what your guests order.

The first formal ceremony (imagine saying your vows under the Golden Arch&apos;s) took place on Valentine&apos;s Day in downtown Hong Kong near the financial district.

Many couples meet, have dates and fall in love in the fast food chain so the concept of marrying with hamburgers and fries is considered OK.

Mickey D&apos;s reception will not permit alcohol, since the fast food restaurant wants to ensure that the guests don&apos;t get inebriated and act inappropriately in their family restaurant. So who needs a drink when you can toast with a premium iced coffee?

McDonald&apos;s in Hong Kong is not closing the restaurant to other patrons while your reception is taking place, so you will have many onlookers and well wishers who could also be party crashers or partay delights!

If you&apos;re not into spending a lot of money on your wedding and having a McDonald Wedding excites you, go to your nearest Mickey D&apos;s and talk to the Manager about hosting your wedding there.

 More Ideas for McDonalds Weddings McWeddings 

 

 Questions to ask about having McDonalds Weddings McWedding. 


 Will the restaurant close for a set period of time? You probably would prefer not to have passerby&apos;s drop in on your nuptials.

 Is it permissible to have your wedding ceremony on the grounds?

 Can you bring in a D.J. or other music if you would like to have dancing? Where will you be able to dance?

 Will guests be permitted to order anything off the menu or will the choices be limited?

 If the restaurant is closed to outside patrons can you bring in alcoholic beverages?

 Can you do your own decorating and how much before your wedding can you put up your decorations?

 What is the minimum and maximum number of guests that the restaurant will accommodate?

 Will there be ample parking for your guests?

 Will they provide a manager to oversee your reception? 


Economically minded couples are becoming more creative, so if McDonalds Weddings McWeddings interest you, check it out.



For your edification on 2/20/2011 I contacted McDonald&apos;s in Hazlet, NJ and was told they have no plans (at this time) to host weddings. I also asked if any information was available from their corporate headquarters and was told that no plans were in the works at this time.

Please review my reception links below for more information on wedding ideas.




 


Go from McDonalds Weddings McWeddings to Unique Reception Theme Wedding Ideas Home 



 Wedding Reception Ideas 

 Original Wedding Reception Ideas 

 Cheap Wedding Reception Ideas 

 Creative Wedding Ideas 

 Fun Ideas For Wedding Reception 

 Free Wedding Checklist 

 Click Here to read our disclosure regarding affiliate and advertising sponsors. 


 Pictures are copyrighted and cannot be used without written permission

© 2008 unique-reception-theme-wedding-ideas.com ® All Rights Reserved 
 
 SBI! 
 
 








 Custom Search 



Follow us on Pinterest 







 
 

Shop for a complete line of hair pins, combs, clips, veils, tiaras, headbands, feathers and extensions by clicking on the above.
	</body>
</document>
