<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005116" url="http://www.regina.worldweb.com/Regina/RestaurantsBars/FastFood/" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="1" score="0.0009296883880116809" bingtitle="Regina Fast Food Restaurants: Fast Food Restaurants in Regina ..." webtitle="Regina Fast Food Restaurants: Fast Food Restaurants in Regina, Saskatchewan">
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="17"/>
	<description>Regina Fast Food Restaurants Directory. Includes listings for Fast Food Restaurants ... In addition to offering great deals on hotel, airline and car rental reservations ...</description>
	<body>
		Regina Fast Food Global Search Local Search 
 Nearby Towns/Cities... ALL DESTINATIONS Lumsden, SK Regina Plan Your Trip» 
 Stay Play Eat Shop See Go Review Map All 
 Add» Review | Business | Event | Photo WorldWeb.com » Canada » Saskatchewan » Regina&amp;Area » Regina » Restaurants&amp;Bars » Fast Food 
 
Regina Fast Food
 •A WorldWeb.com Travel Guide to Fast Food in Regina , Saskatchewan . Listings Map Reviews Write a Review Tim Hortons Regina Tim Hortons has a number of locations in Regina and they all feature the chain restaurants signature donuts. The menu specifics include strawberry vanilla, old fashioned glazed and chocolate dip donuts, cream of broccoli and beef noodle soup and BBQ chicken wraps. Address: 1800 11th Ave | Regina, SK | S4P 0H8
 Telephone: 1 306 525-3188
 Address: 2102 11th Ave
 Telephone: 1 306 525-1339
 Address: 970 Albert St
 Telephone: 1 306 565-3366
 Address: 1700 Elphinstone Pk
 Telephone: 1 306 539-5063
 Address: 103 Albert St N
 Telephone: 1 306 949-0045
 Address: 2105 Victoria Ave E
 Telephone: 1 306 757-1800
 Address: 5201 Regina Ave
 Telephone: 1 306 757-2050
 Address: 3737 Wascana Pkwy
 Telephone: 1 306 585-4660
 Address: 4225 Albert St
 Telephone: 1 306 586-6440
 Address: 1960 Prince of Wales Dr
 Telephone: 1 306 347-5605
 Address: 4455 Rochdale Blvd
 Telephone: 1 306 352-2257
 Address: 2715 Gordon Rd
 Telephone: 1 306 584-4450
 Address: 4845 Harbour Landing Dr
 Telephone: 1 306 525-2006
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Burger King Address: 1808 Albert St | Regina, SK
 Telephone: 1 306 347-7757
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Dairy Queen Address: 1916 Elphinstone St | Regina, SK
 Telephone: 1 306 565-0099
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Hero&apos;s Address: Golden Mile Shopping Centre, 25th Ave and Albert St | Regina, SK
 Telephone: 1 306 584-9764
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info A&amp;W Restaurant Address: 115 E Victoria Ave | Regina, SK
 Telephone: 1 306 522-0422
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info California Gormet Subs Address: 4041 Albert St | Regina, SK | S4S 3R6
 Telephone: 1 306 586-6669
 Contribute: Write a Review | Add an Event | View Stats | Edit Info Near Casino Regina 
 Mulligans Lounge 
 
 Travel Packages 
 Anderson Vacations 
 Your One Stop Canada Travel Solution!
 All-Suite Hotel 
 HomeSuites in Regina, SK 
 When you can&apos;t be there,
stay close to home!
 Family Amenities 
 Days Inn Regina
Airport West 
 Located in the heart of Regina&apos;s Grasslands retail district!
 Indoor Waterslide 
 Days Inn Regina 
 A family-friendly hotel with plenty of modern amenities!
 Book Your Vacation! 
 Hotels Flights Cars Hotel City
 
 Check-in
 Check-out
 
 Adults
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Children
 0 1 2 3 4 
 
 View Hotel Listings My Reservations | Cancel a Reservation Please enter a city or airport code of 3 to 25 characters. Please enter the age of each child. 
 Airports 
From
 
To
 
 
 Compare surrounding airports 
 Depart
 Return
 Exact 
+/- 3 
 Adults
 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 Children
 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 
 
 More Search Options
 One Way | Multiple Destinations 
 Car Rentals 
Pick up car at:
 At an airport Other locations 
 Airport Code
 Different Dropoff?
 Yes No 
 Drop off car at
 At an airport Other locations Airport Code
 
 
Pick-up Date
 
Drop-off Date
 
Car Type
 5 basic types Compact Pickup Truck Economy Full Size Intermediate Luxury Van Premium Standard Sport Utility Convertible Station Wagon Specialty 
 
 More search options 
 
 
 Regina Tourism Directory 

 Lodging Tours&amp;Activities Visitor Attractions Restaurants&amp;Bars Shopping Transportation Rental Services Wedding Planner Real Estate Events Business Index Reviews 
 Business Owners/Managers 
Do you manage a business in Regina? If so, please search our tourism directory to ensure your company information is up to date and accurate. If you don&apos;t find a listing, we invite you to add a complimentary listing . If you want to increase your exposure to the millions of people who come to WorldWeb.com each month to plan their trips and vacations, please refer
to our advertising information . 
 
 

WorldWeb.com provides comprehensive travel information for Vancouver and beyond. In addition to offering great deals on hotel, airline and car rental reservations, WorldWeb.com connects you directly to companies servicing the tourism industry.
 Contribute
 Write a Review Add a Listing Submit an Event Share Your Photos 
 About WorldWeb.com
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Contact Us Advertising Info 
 
   Canada USA United Kingdom Ireland Australia New Zealand Italy France Caribbean 
 ©1994-2012 World Web Technologies Inc. 
Regina Fast Food
	</body>
</document>
