<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005319" url="http://orangecounty.citysearch.com/profile/598259/laguna_beach_ca/kfc.html" time="2012-07-12-21:52" support="3" score="0.013635806898083178" bingtitle="What People Are Saying About Kfc - Orange County, CA City Guide ..." webtitle="Kfc - Laguna Beach, CA, 92651 - Citysearch">
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>Orange County, CA Metro &gt; Laguna Beach &gt; Restaurants ... In Short – Established in 1939, this fast-food restaurant ... the kind that comes in those neat plastic trays ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Orange County, CA Metro &gt; Laguna Beach &gt; Restaurants &gt; Kfc 
Kfc
 (949) 497-5528 
 695 S Coast Hwy , Laguna Beach , CA | Directions  
 92651 33.537701 -117.779800 View Website 
 Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 50 % 100 2 2 Votes Add a Photo Cuisine: Fast Food , Chicken , Traditional American Price: $ Categories: Restaurants 
 View More 
 Payment Methods: MasterCard, Visa Restaurant Special Features: Cheap Eats , Carry Out , Family-Friendly Dining , Lunch Spot 
 View Less 
 Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (2) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Kfc 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Kfc
 Doesn&apos;t Recommend Contributor Joined 9 years ago June 22, 2008 
 For more than 60 years, this all-American institution has been serving its signature chicken and home-style sides.. In Short 
Established in 1939, this fast-food restaurant still makes its legendary fried chicken with the closely guarded blend of 11 herbs and spices originally created by founder Colonel Sanders. Modern additions to the menu include oven-roasted renditions of its chicken sandwiches, popcorn chicken, potato wedges and wraps. Classic sides include flaky, oversized biscuits, steaming-hot mashed potatoes and gravy, smoky-sweet baked beans and crisp, generously dressed coleslaw. Kids and adults love the &quot;little bucket&quot; parfaits of pudding desserts. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends RiverBoatQueen Joined 4 years ago 5.0 May 30, 2008 
 Best price for some great down-home food!. Next time you&apos;re out at Laguna Beach and you don&apos;t want to take out a second mortgage on your house in order for some fine dining, take a tip from the Queen and eat at the old White Man&apos;s KFC. Here&apos;s the inside scoop for you adventuresome types that can walk good on rocks. Park on a meter if you must and walk to the KFC - order a value meal (the kind that comes in those neat plastic trays) and then take the short hike down to the sea shore.... pull up a beach bolder and sit yourself down and enjoy some of the most spectacular views of the beach ever!

From your humble vantage point, you will dine in a spot more heavenly than Los Brisas, Hotel Laguna and the Beach House combined!!!!

Look at the beach house rentals next to you and think of this fact; the people renting those homes have to shell out thousands of dollars per week to have the same view you are having, only you are way smarter and are enjoying this stupdendously gorgeous breathtaking view - - - FOR FREE!!!!

Just because you read this review...you are going to knock the socks off your date, or your kids or whomever else you wish to impress --- Champagne tastes on a root beer budget, aren&apos;t the best things in life FREE? … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 Mosaic Bar&amp;Grille 30801 Coast Hwy 
 Laguna Beach, CA 
1.9 mi away Jack in the Box 1201 S COAST HWY 
 LAGUNA BEACH, CA 
0.5 mi away Taco Bell 699 N Coast Hwy 
 Laguna Beach, CA 
0 mi away 
 
Things to do near Kfc
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
