<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005098" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/278405-Kid-Cuisine-Shrek-ified-Game-(3-)-MAIL-IN-(10-6-10)" time="2012-07-12-21:37" support="7" score="0.021053586048085215" bingtitle="Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game (3+) MAIL-IN (10/6/10)" webtitle="Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game (3+) MAIL-IN (10/6/10)">
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="128"/>
	<description>If your package contains a green meal tray, you&apos;ve ... (PO Boxes are not permitted.), phone number, age of ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Contests - Sweepstakes Expired Contests / Instant Wins Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game (3+) MAIL-IN (10/6/10) 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Results 1 to 1 of 1 
Thread: Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game (3+) MAIL-IN (10/6/10) 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 07-24-2010,  01:12 PM #1 Trina134 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2008 Posts 347 
Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game (3+) MAIL-IN (10/6/10)
 *the&quot;3&quot;is NOT a typo - they spell out three in the rules
Two ways to enter:
1. (with purchase) - purchase specially marked packages of Kid Cuisine frozen meals. If your package contains a green meal tray, you&apos;ve won
2. (without purchase) - Consumers should mail in entries requesting a game ticket with a self addressed stamped
envelope to Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game, PO Box 1196, Grand Rapids, MN. 55745-1196.
Mail-in entries must include name, valid street address (street address, city, state, zip code)
(PO Boxes are not permitted.), phone number, age of entrant and e-mail address. All mail
in entries requesting a game ticket must be postmarked by September 6, 2010 and received
by September 13, 2010 

Grand Prize: Trip for four to Universal Studios Hollywood
2,000 First Prizes - one kid size medium or large Kid Cuisine Shrek T-shirt

 Limit one prize per person and/or household 

KID CUISINE SHREK-IFIED GAME
Official Rules
NO PURCHASE NECESSARY. A PURCHASE OR PAYMENT OF ANY KIND WILL NOT
INCREASE YOUR CHANCES OF WINNING. Game begins April 5, 2010 and ends October 6,
2010.
1. ELIGIBILITY: Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game (the Instant Win Game_ is open to legal
residents of the United States who are three (3) years and older at the time of entry.
Employees, officers and representatives of ConAgra Foods, Inc. (the Sponsor), N.C.L.
Graphic Specialties, Inc., (Administrator), Universal Studios, Inc., DreamWorks Animation
L.L.C. (Dreamworks) and their respective affiliates, subsidiaries and advertising agencies
as well as the immediate family (spouse, parents, siblings and children) and household
members of each such employee Subject to all applicable federal, state, and local laws and
regulations. Void where prohibited. Participation constitutes entrants full and unconditional
agreement to these Official Rules and Sponsors and Administrators decisions, which are
final and binding in all matters related to the Instant Win Game. Winning a prize is
contingent upon fulfilling all requirements set forth herein.
2. TIMING: The Instant Win Game begins on April 5, 2010 and ends October 6, 2010.
Administrators computer is the official time-keeping device for the Instant Win Game.
3 HOW TO ENTER: There are two (2) ways to enter: 1.) Receive a winning ticket seeded
and placed on the liner of the Kid Cuisine Meals with the Green Trays. 2.) By Mail -
Consumers should mail in entries requesting a game ticket with a self addressed stamped
envelope to Kid Cuisine Shrek-ified Game, PO Box 1196, Grand Rapids, MN. 55745-1196.
Mail-in entries must include name, valid street address (street address, city, state, zip code)
(PO Boxes are not permitted.), phone number, age of entrant and e-mail address. All mail
in entries requesting a game ticket must be postmarked by September 6, 2010 and received
by September 13, 2010. Sponsor and its agents (as defined in Section 1 above) are not
responsible for entries that for any reason are lost, late, damaged, misdirected, illegible,
incomplete or stolen, for postage due, late or lost mail. Entries requesting a game ticket
become the property of Sponsor and will not be acknowledged or returned. Vermont
residents may omit postage.
4. DETERMINATION OF WINNERS: Each winning ticket will be placed on the tray liner of a
Kid Cuisine Meal and accompanying a Green Tray. Also, each winning ticket will have a
unique number code which will represent a prize level. The winning Consumer should
contact the Fulfillment representatives at 877-775-9416 by October 6, 2010 and give them
the unique code depicted on the ticket which designates that ticket as a winner and the
category of prizes. This number will be answered by a live agent, Monday thru Friday, 8
a.m. to 11 p.m. C.S.T. until October 6, 2010, 10:59 p.m. Each potential winner
(parent/legal guardian if winner is a minor in his/her state of resident) will be required to
sign and return to Sponsor, within ten (10) days of the date it was sent, an Affidavit of
Eligibility, Liability and Publicity Release (Affidavit) in order to claim his/her prize. If a
potential winner fails to sign and return the Affidavit within the required time period,
potential winner forfeits prize. Potential winner must continue to comply with all terms and
conditions of these Official Rules and winning is contingent upon fulfilling all requirements.
In the event that a potential winner is disqualified for any reason, or the potential winner
does not call the Fulfillment representatives by October 6, 2010, the remaining prize(s) will
remain un-awarded.
5. PRIZES:
[A.] GRAND PRIZE (1): Grand Prize shall consist of a 3 day/2 night weekend (Saturday
night stay over required) trip for four (4) people to Universal Studios Hollywood consisting
of round-trip (r/t) coach airfare (via an airline carrier selected by Sponsor) between the
major US gateway city airport closest to the winner&apos;s home and Los Angeles (LAX) or
Burbank Airport, 2 consecutive nights accommodations (1 standard room, quadruple
occupancy, room&amp;room tax only) at a hotel selected by Sponsor, one (1) day admission to
Universal Studios Hollywood for four (4) people and r/t ground transfers between airport
and the selected hotel. The approximate total retail value of the prize is $2,500. NOTE: all
meals, gratuities, telephone calls, incidentals, additional ground transfers and any other
expenses not specified herein are the sole responsibility of the winner and their travel
companions. The Grand Prize winners and his or her travel companions must travel on the
identical itinerary. The Grand Prize winner must give a minimum of 45 days advance notice
of desired departure date and all travel must be completed within one (1) year of awarding.
All travel is subject to airline, hotel and Universal Studios Hollywood availability and holiday
and other blackout dates apply. If redeemer is between 18&amp;21 years of age, he/she must
be accompanied by an adult of at least 21 years of age in order to check in to the onsite
hotel. Minor traveling companion(s) must be accompanied by a parent or legal guardian and
redeemer and his/her traveling companions must travel on the same itinerary. The Grand
Prize winner and his or her travel companions will be required to provide appropriate state
or Federal government issued photo identification at time of travel. No changes will be
made to travel details once any portion of travel arrangements have been made. Grand
Prize may not be sold, traded, transferred, rescheduled to dates not within the fulfillment
period set forth above or refunded and is not redeemable for cash.
If an alternate winner selection is made necessary for any reason, it will be done in a
subsequent random drawing from among all eligible entries. Odds of winning the prize are
determined by the total number of eligible entries received for the Sweepstakes.
[B.] 2,000 FIRST PRIZES each consisting of one kid size medium or large Kid Cuisine Shrek
T-shirt. Approximate retail value: $10.00 each. A limited number of sizes are available.
Available sizes may be substituted should requested sizes become unavailable.
Odds of winning are as follows:
Grand Prize ----[1 Prize]-------- one [1] out of 14,292,000
First Prize-------[2,000 Prizes]---- one [1] out of 7,146
All claimed prizes will be awarded. Unclaimed prizes will not be awarded. No prize
substitutions or cash equivalent except at the sole discretion of the Sponsor if an advertised
prize becomes unavailable. Prizes are non-transferable. Limit of (1) one prize per person
and/or household. All federal, state and local taxes and expenses are the responsibility of
the individual winners.
6. RELEASE: By receipt of any prize, winner agrees to release and hold harmless Sponsor,
DreamWorks Animation L.L.C., Administrator and their respective subsidiaries, affiliates,
suppliers, distributors, advertising/promotion agencies, and prize suppliers, and each of their
respective parent companies and each such companys officers, directors, employees and
agents (collectively, the Released Parties) from and against any claim or cause of action,
including, but not limited to, personal injury, death, or damage to or loss of property, arising
out of participation in the Instant Win Game or receipt or use or misuse of any prize.
7. PUBLICITY. Except where prohibited, participation in the Instant Win Game constitutes
winners consent to Sponsors, Dreamworks Animation L.L.C., Universal Studios Hollywood
and their respective agents use of winners name, likeness, photograph, voice, opinions,
and/or hometown and state for promotional purposes in and media, worldwide, without
further payment or consideration.
8. GENERAL CONDITIONS: Sponsor reserves the right to cancel, suspend and or modify the
Instant Win Game, or any part of it, if any fraud, technical failures or any other factor
beyond Sponsors reasonable control impairs the integrity or proper functioning of the
Instant Win Game, ad deter by Sponsor in it sole discretion. Sponsors failure to enforce
any term in these Official Rules shall not constitute a waiver of that provision.
9. LIMITATIONS OF LIABILITY: The Release Parties are not responsible for: (1) any
incorrect or inaccurate information, whether caused by entrants, printing errors or by any of
the equipment or programming associated with our utilized by the Instant Win Game; (2)
technical failures of any kind, including, but not limited to malfunctions, interruptions, or
disconnections in phone lines or network hardware or software; (3) unauthorized human
intervention in any part of the entry process or Instant Win Game; (4) technical or human
error which may occur in the administration of the Instant Win Game or processing of
entries; or (5) any injury or damage to persons or property which may be caused, directly or
indirectly, in whole or in part, from entrants participation in the Instant Win Game or receipt
or use of any prize or while traveling to or from any prize-related activity. If for any reason
and entrants entry is confirmed to have been erroneously deleted, lost or otherwise
destroyed or corrupted, entrants sole remedy is another entry in the Instant Win Game,
provided that, if it is not possible to award another entry due to discontinuance of the
Instant Win Game for any reason, Sponsor, in its sole discretion, may elect to hold random
drawing from among all eligible entries received up to the date of discontinuance for any or
all the prized offered herein. No more than the stated number of prized will be awarded. In
the event that production, technical, seeding, programming or any other reasons cause
more than the stated number of prized as set forth in these Official Rules to be available
and/or claimed, Sponsor reserves the right to aware only the stated number of prizes by a
random drawing among all legitimate, un-awarded eligible prize claims.
10. DISPUTES: Entrants agrees that (i) any and all disputes, claims and causes of action
arising out of or connected with this Instant Win Game or any prizes awarded shall be
resolved individually, without resort to any form of class action, and exclusively by the
United States District Court for the District of Nebraska or appropriate Nebraska State Court
located in Douglas County, Nebraska; (ii) any and all claims, judgments and awards shall be
limited to actual out-of-pocket cost incurred, including costs associated with entering this
Instant Win Game but in no event attorneys fees; and (iii) under no circumstances will
entrant be permitted to obtain awards for and any other damage, other than actual out-ofpocket
expenses, and nay and all rights to have damages multiplied or otherwise increased.
SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW LIMITATIONS OR EXCLUSION OF LIABILITY FOR
INCIDENTIAL OR CONSEQUENTAIL DAMAGES, SO THE ABOVE MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.
All issues and questions concerning the construction, validity, interpretation and
enforceability of these Official Rules, or the rights and obligations of the entrant and
Sponsor in connection with the Instant Win Game, shall be governed by, and construed in
accordance with, the laws of the State of Nebraska, without giving effect to any choice of
law or conflict of law rules (whether of the State of Nebraska or any other jurisdiction),
which would cause the application of the laws of any jurisdiction other than the State of
Nebraska.
11. ENTRANTS PERSONAL INFORMATION: Information collected from entrants is subject
to Sponsors Privacy Policy ( http://conagrafoods.com/utililties/privacy.jsp ).
12. WINNERS LIST: List of winners is available by mail, by sending a self-addressed
envelope to: Shrek-ified Winners, PO Box 1196-W, Grand Rapids, MN 55745-1196. Mail-in
requests must include name, address [street address, city, state, zip] between May 1, 2010,
and October 20, 2010. Vermont residents may omit postage.
13. SPONSOR: ConAgra Foods, Inc. One ConAgra Drive, Omaha, Nebraska, 68102.
ADMINISTRATOR: N.C.L. Graphic Specialties, Inc.
2010 ConAgra Foods Inc. All rights reserved. Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
