<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005543" url="http://cet4-6.xdf.cn/201111/971555.html" time="2012-07-12-22:06" support="1" score="0.001063487950606517" bingtitle="2010年大学英语四级考试样题及标准答案 _ 新东方网" webtitle="2010年大学英语四级考试样题及标准答案 _ 新东方网">
			<query id="001092" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>... your meal at a fast food restaurant and you throw your uneaten food， food wrappers， drink cups， utensils and napkins into the trash can. ... the runoff collection pond ...</description>
	<body>
		新东方网首页 | 加入收藏 | 设为首页 | 课程大全 | 网站导航 

 您好，欢迎来到新东方！ 登录 免费注册 
 服务 选课报班 上课地点查询 在线测评 留学申请 在线咨询 学员服务中心 学习工具 资讯 学前 小学 中学 留学 英语 多语种 职业 学历 图片 专题 社区 学吧 问吧 论坛 
 首页 学前 小学 中学 留学 英语 多语种 学历 职业 

 学吧 问吧 论坛 图吧 视频 网上报名 下载中心 
 
 幼儿教育 | 幼升小 

 一年级 | 二年级 | 三年级 | 四年级 | 五年级 | 六年级 | 小升初 

 初一 | 初二 | 中考 | 高一 | 高二 | 高考 

 托福 | 雅思 | GRE | GMAT | SAT | SSAT | LSAT | ACT | AP | PTE | U-Excel | SLEP | A-level | O-level | 申请 | 游学 | 异域 | 维权 | BBC留学 

 听力 | 口语 | 语法 | 词  汇 | 写作 | 翻译 | 职场 | 新概念 | 剑桥 | 四 六 级 | 专四专八 | 托业英语 | 公共英语 | 职称英语 | 英语学习 | BBC英语教学 

 德语 | 法语 | 日语 | 韩语 | 西班牙语 | 俄语 | 意大利语 | 葡萄牙语 

 自考 | 成考 | 考研 | 专升本 | MBA考试 | EMBA考试 

 公务员 | 职业资格 | 财会 | 计算机 
 英语 新东方网 &gt; 英语 &gt; 四六级 &gt; 四级 &gt; 试题 &gt; 模拟题 &gt; 文章正文 
2010年大学英语四级考试样题及标准答案
 分享到： 
2011-11-29 14:45  作者：  来源：考试吧  字号： T | T 


 摘要： 难易度与真题相当的大学英语四级考试样题，预祝大家取得理想的成绩。 
 CET4试点考试样卷(一) 

 Part Ⅰ Writing (30 minutes) 

注意：此部分试题在答题卡1上。

Directions： For this part， you are allowed 30 minutes to write a campaign speech in support of your election to the post of chairman of the student union. You should write at least 120 words following the outline given below in Chinese：

1. 你认为自己具备了什么条件(能力、性格、爱好等)可以胜任学生会主席的工作

2. 如果当选，你将为本校同学做些什么

A Campaign Speech

 Part Ⅱ Reading Comprehension (Skimming and Scanning) (15 minutes) 

Directions： In this part， you will have 15 minutes to go over the passage quickly and answer the questions on Answer Sheet 1.

For questions 1-7， mark

Y (for YES) if the statement agrees with the information given in the passage;

N (for NO) if the statement contradicts the information given in the passage;

NG (for NOT GIVEN) if the information is not given in the passage.

For questions 8-10， complete the sentences with the information given in the passage.

Landfills

You have just finished your meal at a fast food restaurant and you throw your uneaten food， food wrappers， drink cups， utensils and napkins into the trash can. You don‘t think about that waste again. On trash pickup day in your neighborhood， you push your can out to the curb， and workers dump the contents into a big truck and haul it away. You don’t have to think about that waste again， either. But maybe you have wondered， as you watch the trash truck pull away， just where that garbage ends up.

Americans generate trash at an Astonishing rate of four pounds per day per person; which translates to 600，000 tons per day or 210 million tons per year! This is almost twice as much trash per person as most other major countries. What happens to this trash? Some gets recycled (回收利用) or recovered and some is burned， but the majority is buried in landfills.

How Much Trash Is Generated?

Of the 210 million tons of trash， or solid waste， generated in the United States annually， about 56 million tons， or 27 percent， is either recycled (glass， paper products， plastic， metals) or composted (做成堆肥) (yard waste)。 The remaining trash， which is mostly unrecyclable， is discarded.

How Is Trash Disposed of?

The trash production in the United States has almost tripled since 1960. This trash is handled in various ways. About 27 percent of the trash is recycled or composted， 16 percent is burned and 57 percent is buried in landfills. The amount of trash buried in landfills has doubled since 1960. The United States ranks somewhere in the middle of the major countries (United Kingdom， Canada， Germany， France and Japan) in landfill disposal. The United Kingdom ranks highest， burying about 90 percent of its solid waste in landfills.

What Is a Landfill?

There are two ways to bury trash：

Dump—an open hole in the ground where trash is buried and that is full of various animals (rats， mice， birds)。 (This is most people‘s idea of a landfill!)

Landfill—carefully designed structure built into or on top of the ground in which trash is isolated from the surrounding environment (groundwater， air， rain)。 This isolation is accomplished with a bottom liner and daily covering of soil.

Sanitary landfill—land fill that uses a clay liner to isolate the trash from the environment

Municipal solid waste (MSW)landfill—landfill that uses a synthetic (plastic) liner to isolate the trash from the environment

The purpose of a landfill is to bury the trash in such a way that it will be isolated from groundwater， will be kept dry and will not be in contact with air. Under these conditions， trash will not decompose (腐烂) much. A landfill is not like a compost pile， where the purpose is to bury trash in such a way that it will decompose quickly.

Proposing the Landfill

For a landfill to be built， the operators have to make sure that they follow certain steps. In most parts of the world， there are regulations that govern where a landfill can be placed and how it can operate. The whole process begins with someone proposing the landfill.

In the United States， taking care of trash and building landfills are local government responsibilities. Before a city or other authority can build a landfill， an environment impact

study must be done on the proposed site to determine：

the area of land necessary for the landfill

the composition of the underlying soil and bedrock

the flow of surface water over the site

the impact of the proposed landfill on the local environment and wildlife

the historical value of the proposed site

Building the Landfill

Once the environmental impact study is complete， the permits are granted and the funds have been raised， then construction begins. First， access roads to the landfill site must be built if they do not already exist. There roads will be used by construction equipment， sanitation (环卫) services and the general public. After roads have been built， digging can begin. In the North Wake Country Landfill， the landfill began 10 feet below the road surface.

What Happens to Trash in a Landfill?

Trash put in a landfill will stay there for a very long time. Inside a landfill， there is little oxygen and little moisture. Under these conditions， trash does not break down very rapidly. In fact， when old landfills have been dug up or sampled， 40-year-old newspapers have been found with easily readable print. Landfills are not designed to break down trash， merely to bury it. When a landfill closes， the site， especially the groundwater， must be monitored and maintained for up to 30 years!

How Is a Landfill Operated?

A landfill， such as the North Wake County Landfill， must be open and available every day. Customers are typically municipalities and construction companies， although residents may also use the landfill.

Near the entrance of the landfill is a recycling center where residents can drop off recyclable materials (aluminum cans， glass bottles， newspapers and paper products)。 This helps to reduce the amount of material in the landfill. Some of these materials are banned from landfills by law because they can be recycled.

As customers enter the site， their trucks are weighed at the scale house. Customers are charged tipping fees for using the site. The tipping fees vary from $10 to $40 per ton. These fees are used to pay for operation costs. The North Wake County Landfill has an operating budget of approximately $4.5 million， and part of that comes from tipping fees.

Along the site， there are drop-off stations for materials that are not wanted or legally banned by the landfill. A multi-material drop-off station is used for tires， motor oil， lead-acid batteries. Some of these materials can be recycled.

In addition， there is a household hazardous waste drop-off station for chemicals (paints， pesticides， other chemicals) that are banned from the landfill. These chemicals are disposed of by private companies. Some paints can be recycled and some organic chemicals can be burned in furnaces or power plants.

Other structures alongside the landfill are the borrowed area that supplies the soil for the landfill， the runoff collection pond and methane (甲烷) station.

Landfills are complicated structures that， when properly designed and managed， serve an important purpose. In the future， new technologies called bioreactors will be used to speed the breakdown of trash in landfills and produce more methane.

注意：此部分试题请在答题卡1上作答;8-10题在答题卡1上。

1. The passage gives a general description of the structure and use of a landfill.

2. Most of the trash that Americans generate ends up in landfills.

3. Compared with other major Industrialized countries， America buries a much higher percentage of its solid waste in landfills.

4. Landfills are like compost piles in that they speed up decomposition of the buried trash.

5. In most countries the selection of a landfill site is governed by rules and regulations.

6. In the United States the building of landfills is the job of both federal and local governments.

7. Hazardous wastes have to be treated before being dumped into landfills.

 关键字： 2011年英语四级考试 英语四级预测题 英语四级模拟题 四级冲刺预测试题 
 共6页: 上一页 1 2 3 4 5 6 下一页 
 

 
更多 模拟题 文章推荐

 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 2011年12月四级听力冲刺模拟题第8套 
 
 2011年英语四级考试 英语四级预测题 英语四级模拟题 四级冲刺预测试题 相关文章导读

 2011-11-29 2011年12月四级最后冲刺试题汇总 2011-11-29 2011年12月英语四级考试全真预测试卷(4) 2011-11-29 2011年12月英语四级考试全真预测试卷(3) 2011-11-29 2011年12月英语四级考试全真预测试卷(2) 2011-11-29 2011年12月英语四级考试全真预测试卷(1) 
 
版权及免责声明

 ① 凡本网注明&quot;稿件来源：新东方&quot;的所有文字、图片和音视频稿件，版权均属新东方教育科技集团（含本网和新东方网）所有，任何媒体、网站或个人未经本网协议授权不得转载、链接、转贴或以其他任何方式复制、发表。已经本网协议授权的媒体、网站，在下载使用时必须注明&quot;稿件来源：新东方&quot;，违者本网将依法追究法律责任。

 ② 本网未注明&quot;稿件来源：新东方&quot;的文/图等稿件均为转载稿，本网转载仅基于传递更多信息之目的，并不意味着赞同转载稿的观点或证实其内容的真实性。如其他媒体、网站或个人从本网下载使用，必须保留本网注明的&quot;稿件来源&quot;，并自负版权等法律责任。如擅自篡改为&quot;稿件来源：新东方&quot;，本网将依法追究法律责任。

 ③ 如本网转载稿涉及版权等问题，请作者见稿后在两周内速来电与新东方网联系，电话：010-62605566转5709。
 
热点排行

 托福 雅思 中考 高考 
 
 [ 托福写作 ] [托福写作]新东方50篇托福写作范文 [ 托福写作 ] 2012托福备考：托福写作优秀范文实例34 [ 托福写作 ] 2012托福备考：托福写作优秀范文实例70 [ 托福写作 ] 2011托福备考：托福写作优秀范文实例84 [ 托福名师指导 ] 朱雅然：托福口语考什么？ [ 托福名师指导 ] 史禺：托福写作考什么 [ 托福名师指导 ] 方舒：攻克托福口语的重音不准 [ 托福语法 ] 新托福四大逻辑关系全揭秘 [ 托福写作 ] 2012托福备考：托福写作优秀范文实例89 [ 托福阅读 ] [托福阅读]阅读难点关键句200句（181-200） 
 
 [ 雅思写作 ] 雅思议论文作文偏题原因及对策 [ 雅思口语 ] 雅思口语攻关秘籍：化抽象为具体 [ 雅思考试动态 ] 雅思学习新趋势：线上线下相结合 [ 雅思阅读 ] 雅思阅读备考四大关键词 [ 雅思口语 ] 雅思口语机考并非“草木皆兵” [ 雅思网友分享 ] 烤鸭分享：托福55一试雅思7分 [ 雅思名师辅导 ] [雅思基础阅读]泛读中雅思词汇的心有灵犀（2） [ 雅思听力 ] 雅思听力四步晋级：初听、细听、冷却、回暖 [ 雅思综合辅导 ] 雅思备考如何面对机经与预测 [ 特别推荐 ] 新东方网每日推荐：雅思听力场景词汇之银行篇 
 
 [ 中考作文 ] 初三学生优秀作文：爱是什么？ [ 语文 ] 2012年全国中考语文“热点”作家知识点(四) [ 地理 ] 初中地理知识点：《选修六 环境保护》检测试题 [ 地理 ] 初中地理练习：地理选择题专项训练（十七） [ 英语 ] 2012年中考英语选择题必用四技巧 [ 家长交流 ] 家有中考生 家长应密切关注八件事 [ 英语 ] 中考英语快速提高要养成20个习惯 [ 数学 ] 十一招教你如何检验数学考卷答案 [ 数学 ] 揭秘中考数学考试中的高分的秘诀 [ 中考快讯 ] 2012中高考考情发布 杭州家长热捧 
 
 [ 特色专业 ] 复旦大学公共经济学系专业介绍 [ 特色专业 ] 北京师范大学天文系专业介绍 [ 特色专业 ] 北京师范大学经济与工商管理学院专业介绍 [ 特色专业 ] 北京师范大学历史学院专业介绍 [ 自主招生 ] 2012年上海财经大学自主招生简章 [ 自主招生 ] 2012年西安电子科技大学保送生选拔实施办法 [ 自主招生 ] 2012年北京林业大学保送生招生简章 [ 自主招生 ] 2012“北约”自主选拔录取联合考试公告 [ 语文 ] 2010年重庆市语文高考真题 [ 数学 ] [高考数学知识点]不等式练习题2 
 
深度观察
 
 日本中小学生上学的出行方式（组图） 

针对国内近期频发的校车事故，我们在寻找解决方法的同时，作为邻居、且又是发达国家的日本在抓中小学生交通安全方面的...
 


 日本中小学生上学的出行方式（组图） 复旦大学冯玮教授深入解读高校自主招生 生命的宽度 孝子岂能靠“工程”培养？ 成功源于专注 
 
精彩问答

 【挑战】 孩子不讲诚信怎 随风而不动 圣诞节的电影有哪些？ long66 雅思听力如何提高？C3-8都 问题生 【挑战】怎么战胜考试恐 张莉莉 冬天了，宝宝赖床不肯起 梅灵 
 
提问
 
精彩推荐

 2012年全年雅思考试安排出台 新东方最新播报：新托福考试回忆录 新GRE®初体验：新东方网友亲历实录 备战GRE：打＂持久战＂怎么打？ 钱学森之问引发个性化教育培养模式思考 2012年国家公务员考试报考指南 
 
 更多精彩视频 热点视讯

 俞敏洪圆明园演讲引万人聆听(上) 俞敏洪亮相《天天向上》 妙语连珠话人生 俞敏洪北大演讲：从头笑到尾 咀嚼更有味 四级高分学员经验分享：在做题中积累经验 《功夫熊猫》经典台词解析1 创造梦想未来：2011新东方秋季校园招聘启动 
 
 更多精彩话题论坛精华 论坛精华

 有志者事竟成：经典励志英语100句 luckycat520 生命中最重要的一天 luckycat520 “搞砸了”的13种常用英语表达 Eileen城 10款未来版手机 luckycat520 给予爱的心伤痕累累却美丽 luckycat520 
 
 总裁信箱 | neworiental.org | 加入我们 | 联系我们 | 法律声明 | 教育导航 | 留言反馈 | 友情链接 | 企业微博 | English Website 

北京新东方教育科技（集团）有限公司

经营许可证编号：京ICP备05067667 | 京ICP证060601号 | 京公安备1101084985

Copyright 2011 Neworiental Corporation, All Rights Reserved

(C) 2011 新东方 版权所有
	</body>
</document>
