<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005672" url="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-2098997/Bye-bye-supersizing-hello-downsizing-Cut-calories-opting-smaller-portions--pay-food.html" time="2012-07-12-22:15" support="5" score="0.011211321629769974" bingtitle="Bye bye supersizing, hello downsizing: Cut calories by opting for ..." webtitle="Bye bye supersizing, hello downsizing: Cut calories by opting for smaller portions - but would you pay the same for less food?  | Mail Online">
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001058" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>... opting for smaller portions - but would you pay ... offering customers the option to downsize on fast food restaurant ... in the UK are when it comes to wrapping up my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Home News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz;     Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 Femail Home Jubilee Food Pictures Femail Boards Fashion Store Beauty MyDish Recipe Finder Baby Blog Deals 

 My Profile Logout Login 
 Find a Job M&amp;S;Wine Our Papers Feedback Thursday, Jul 12 2012 9PM  9°C 12AM 10°C 5-Day Forecast 
Bye bye supersizing, hello downsizing: Cut calories by opting for smaller portions - but would you pay the same for less food?

 
By Daisy Dumas 
 UPDATED: 21:05 GMT, 9 February 2012 
 
 Comments ( 30 ) Share 
 
 
 
 Supersizing has, in recent years, been linked to obese America. It perhaps stands to reason, then, that downsizing - exercising restraint when it comes to portion control - could help combat the obesity epidemic. 
 

 Encouraging new findings suggest that Americans could whittle down obesity levels by simply offering customers the option to downsize on fast food restaurant menus. 
 

 Not only are consumers open to trying smaller portions, found the study, published by Health Affairs yesterday, but they cut calories by doing so - and left the equivalent amount of food behind to that of a normal-sized portion. 
 
Simple solution: A third of customers chose to downsize to a smaller side dish, eating 200 fewer calories by doing so, according to a new study
 
 The findings may offer an alternative to dieting that is based upon calories of different food types, focusing instead on simply eating less. 
 

 Led by behavioural psychologist, Janet Schwartz, Tulane University researchers watched a group of diners at a fast food Chinese restaurant in Durham, North Carolina, reports ABC&apos;s Good Morning America . 

   
More...

 Fat? No, Adele is a normal human being... which is more than you can say for Karl Lagerfeld! Half of single women carry a pair of sexy knickers in their handbag…just in case 
 

 Unaware they were being observed, customers were given the choice to downsize to a smaller portion of a side dish. 
 

 The scientists found that a third of the customers opted for the smaller portion and by doing so, immediately omitted 200 calories from their meals. 
 

 Dr Schwartz told the programme&apos;s site that &apos;suggesting a smaller portion allows people to satisfy a desire for a food and does not force them to sacrifice what they want to eat&apos;. 
 
 
Fries with that? Morgan Spurlock famously popularised the term &apos;supersizing&apos;
 
 She explained that the a major stumbling block for dieters is that calories counts on foods have not helped to lower consumption levels.
 

 And, as &apos;substituting a salad for a Big Mac is not an appealing choice&apos;, it makes sense to simply encourage people to eat smaller portions of what they do like. 
 

 By instilling portion control into meal times, calories are restricted and the &apos;cultural&apos; urge to finish the plate is still satisfied. &apos;Culturally, Americans do not respond to the cue of &quot;feeling full.&quot; The cue to stop eating is only when the plate is empty&apos;, Dr Schwartz told GMA. 
 

 Teaching people that they can reduce calories without being wholly denied of certain foods will, the scientists hope, help them to look at meals, including drink options, differently. 
 

 While the restaurant had at first been tentative to offer the choice, fearing customers may feel offended and that value is a customer&apos;s key concern, managers soon found that the restaurant was saving money, too. 

 Morgan Spurlock famously coined the term &apos;supersizing&apos; in his documentary Supersize Me, which held a spotlight to the worrying culture of being offered to upgrade to a larger portion size for a small sum at major fast food chains such as McDonald&apos;s.
 

 At the North Carolina eatery, not only did a 25 cent price reduction for the downsized option prove irrelevant to customer&apos;s decisions, but the study confirmed the findings of an earlier report that suggested customers would accept less food if offered, but would not ask for a smaller portion, unprompted. 

 
MOST READ NEWS

 Previous 1 2 3 4 Next 
 
 Police hunt dealer who sold Tetra Pak wife Eva Rausing the... Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate... Horrific moment three young tigers attack and eat young cub... &apos;The way you brutally manipulated and exploited them is pure... Two hotel workers found NOT GUILTY of murdering a honeymoon... Doing the logo-motion: From McDonald&apos;s without its big... What a difference a trim makes! Neighbours breath a sigh of... &apos;The girl with this phone is dead, was smiling&apos;: The... Renter&apos;s revenge: Pictures which show the squalid aftermath... O2 hit by nationwide network failure: &apos;Millions of users&apos;... The human right to claim benefits: Jobless could sue for... McDonald&apos;s force Olympics bosses to ban all other... 
   
Share this article:
 
 Facebook Twitter Google+ Messenger LinkedIn Digg it Newsvine Fark Nowpublic Reddit 

 
 
 Print article Email article 
 
Comments ( 30 )
 
Here&apos;s what other readers have said. Why not debate this issue live on our message boards. 

The comments below have not been moderated.
 
 Newest Oldest Best rated Worst rated 
   View all 
wow.I was in the UK for 4 months...the waiters must have thought I was a real slob,....I asked to take home my un eaten food every day...I visited the same restaurants...like the same 5 anyway...I bet they had a good laugh at me.......

- Helena, Montana..., 11/2/2012 03:24
 Click to rate     Rating   2 
 Report abuse 
 
Ellie makes a good point - but while asking for the uneaten portion of your restaurant meal&apos;to go&apos;is commonplace in the States it is very unusual here in the UK and I think most of us are too embarassed to ask the waiter. Maybe if more of us got into the habit of requesting our leftovers to take home in a box it would become the norm in restauraants and we wouldn&apos;t be tempted to finish a meal just because we have paid for it though we aren&apos;t really hungry.

- Daddy Longlegs, Planet Earth, 10/2/2012 23:55
 Click to rate     Rating   4 
 Report abuse 
 
I take any food I don&apos;t eat away with me. I have no compunction about asking, either in the US or in the UK, where it is less common. I&apos;ve been pleasantly surprised by how willing various restaurants and pubs in the UK are when it comes to wrapping up my food for me. I hate wasting food. I&apos;ve paid for it, it&apos;s mine to take away!

- Ellie, Here, 10/2/2012 19:19
 Click to rate     Rating   9 
 Report abuse 
 
What&apos;s it called -&apos;The Bleedin&apos;Obvious Diet&apos;?

- Josie, Leeds, UK, 10/2/2012 19:00
 Click to rate     Rating   7 
 Report abuse 
 
A lot of modern restaurants now offer smaller plates and sharing plates. I think the whole culture of huge portions started when restaurants began using those big pasta style plates with the deep rim round the age - the bowl part of the plate is wide and has a bit of depth to it. It doesn&apos;t help when you add wine glasses that take a third of a bottle either. I can remember going out to wine bars in London in the 80s when you&apos;d get 5 - 6 glasses from a bottle because that was the size of the glasses you were given. You were only given larger glasses for red.

- Linda, Fife, 10/2/2012 17:34
 Click to rate     Rating   8 
 Report abuse 
 
I ask to have the meal cut in half and put in a box right when I get it, so I don&apos;t have good food staring at me when I&apos;m full :-) Now I have breakfast too.

- Alexis, San Diego, CA, 10/2/2012 17:28
 Click to rate     Rating   10 
 Report abuse 
 
I try to cut out carbs but then I eat much more meat- but then you should cut down on meat, as it can cause bowel cancer and fibre is needed for your stomach. 
I love milk but told it adds lots of extra calories, but supposedly women under 30 are supposed to have plenty for healthy bones in later life. 
Best have everything in moderation- because you can&apos;t win cutting things out completely!

- squirrel83, Sheffield, 10/2/2012 16:28
 Click to rate     Rating   12 
 Report abuse 
 
Does Britain have to go boxes?

- camilla villiams, Town, Country, 10/2/2012 14:14
 Click to rate     Rating   6 
 Report abuse 
 
lc, uk, 10/02/2012 09:36
The reason you think you need food like pasta and bread is because you&apos;re hooked on carbs. Human beings can survive perfectly well on meat, fish, eggs and vegetables and indeed can get to their ideal weight without feeling hungry. It&apos;ll take 3 weeks but you&apos;ll do it. Also you don&apos;t want to know what wheat does to your gut...not good. Read Wheat Belly to find out more.

- simon, Shropshire, 10/2/2012 13:22
 Click to rate     Rating   3 
 Report abuse 
 
Large meals put me off but I just leave what I can&apos;t eat. It&apos;s about self control. Just because it&apos;s there doesn&apos;t mean you have to eat it all.

- lenny, Wales, 10/2/2012 12:23
 Click to rate     Rating   17 
 Report abuse 
 
The views expressed in the contents above are those of our users and do not necessarily reflect the views of MailOnline.
 
We are no longer accepting comments on this article.
 Bing Site Web Enter search term: Search     
FEMAIL TODAY

 Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using M&amp;S;virtual technology &apos;This time, Justin messed with the wrong woman&apos;: Triumphant Tulisa settles legal action against ex over sex tape leak &apos;The truth has come out&apos; Gorgeous by day: Kelly Brook shows off her shape in sailor bikini as she enjoys amorous day with beau Thom Evans She&apos;s nautical but nice! Playful by night: Kelly Brook nearly pops out of her dress as she dances at the dinner table Thom&apos;s eyes almost popped out too at restaurant in Italy Kim and Kanye as you&apos;ve never seen them before! Couple pile on the pounds in frumpy portrait... with the help of a little trickery Divorce leaves Tom feeling flushed: Cruise visits loos THREE times in 20 minutes on Oblivion set Filming in Iceland &apos;Still shocked and saddened&apos;: Tom Cruise plans to see Suri &apos;very soon&apos; as he struggles to get to grip with being dumped by Katie Holmes Former Scientology chief claims church &apos;brainwashed Tom Cruise&apos;s children and turned them against Nicole Kidman&apos; Marty Rathbun left in 2004 Single lady style statement: Katie Holmes dons tight leather trousers for dinner date Younger, sexier image for Ms Holmes Doppelgangers! Joey Essex appears to be taking after Tom Cruise&apos;s style Uncannily similar jacket and shades to Top Gun star Lifting the summer spirit: Miranda Kerr sizzles as she debuts latest Victoria&apos;s Secret Cotton Lingerie range in sensual video No nudity, no sex, just cuddles: How one woman is making a living from snuggling - but for 38 an hour, would you pay to hug a stranger? Why This Morning&apos;s penis enlargement feature brought a tear to my eyes (for all the right reasons) PETER LLOYD found him brave Whittle-d down: Ricky becomes a one woman man again as he holds hands with new girlfriend while baring his chest (of course!) Year since Carley Stenson split That&apos;s no demure maxi! Miranda Kerr sexes up her floor-length dress with a plunging neckline and hip-high slit Two maxi dresses in a row The devil wears gym gear: Emily Blunt looks ready for the Olympics as she works up a sweat during gruelling work out session Want a body like Denise? Richards reveals the secret behind her slim frame as she works out in weight loss shorts It&apos;s that simple! Katy Perry in a spin as insurers try to ban her from wearing trademark rotating bra Experts are concerned about the resulting strain on her neck Paralympian rower bares all for ESPN&apos;s Body Issue and reveals &apos;for me, eating is one of the hardest things&apos; Inspiring Oksana Masters Mother in heart-breaking plea for return of son, three, &apos;missing&apos; in Corfu with Greek father amid tug-of-love custody battle Tom Cruise&apos;s lawyer to sue National Enquirer for &apos;hundreds of millions&apos; over &apos;vicious lies&apos; Branded Tom a &apos;monster&apos; and said he &apos;humiliated his wife&apos; Friends again: Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox enjoy reunite on night out after rift rumours They hadn&apos;t been seen together for months The Only Way Is Essex star Gemma Collins in hot water over hair salon tweets Not the only TOWIE star to plug for freebies Gisele Bundchen&apos;s naked ambition is laid bare in daring nude beach shoot for Vogue Paris Stripping back to basics It&apos;s Posh-er and hips! Made In Chelsea&apos;s Hugo Taylor and Natalie Joel sport matching outfits... but hers is cut a little lower Robert Blake launches into bizarre tirade at Piers Morgan in first interview since being sensationally acquitted of wife&apos;s murder Big Brother 2012: Psychiatrist rushed in as &apos;depressed&apos; ex Playboy model Shievonne Robinson makes suicide remark Been &apos;crying hysterically&apos; All by myself: Pregnant Camila Alves does some solo sightseeing in Berlin while her husband Matthew McConaughey promotes his new film She&apos;s learned her lesson! Lydia Bright teams up with Zoe Hardman to encourage the public to stay safe in the sun Been burnt before Getting down and dirty! British women&apos;s football team enjoy muddy bonding session as they prepare to open the Olympic Games Soldiering on: Bikini girl Rihanna lights up a suspicious roll-up cigarette as she unwinds in Barbados after family drama Chris Hemsworth... the human stroller: Thor star carries baby India Rose around on shopping trip - and leaves pram at home Hands on dad! Curse of the Vera Wang wedding gown? How eight celebrities who married wearing her designs have ended up divorced After her own divorce Woman with world&apos;s largest natural breasts claims 102ZZZ-cup assets require security to fend off admirers who &apos;chase her&apos; Annie Hawkins-Turner Fleetwood Mac reuniting for tour next year, reveals Stevie Nicks Play their first shows since 2009, Stevie confirmed Grimace and bear it: Christine Bleakley looks terrified with Frank Lampard at Universal Studios Not flashing those pearly whites What were you inking! The embarrassing matching tattoos that brand couples for life They take saying &apos;I love you&apos;, to a whole new level It&apos;s chest OR legs! Sarah Harding reveals her very thin figure in a cropped top AND low-riding shorts Didn&apos;t get the memo Raffaella Fico shows off her growing bump as she steps out after penning open letter to Mario Balotelli Maintains footballer IS the father Aunty Khloe on duty! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s sister looks after Mason while she spends time with newborn daughter Putting in some practise? A forlorn looking Rihanna goes back to her plaited roots... after returning home for grandmother&apos;s funeral Grieving loss of beloved grandmother Dolly You&apos;re not fooling anyone! Tulisa spends five hours having her hair dyed blonde... then tries to hide it with a wig Next time put the wig on properly Tulisa! Makes a change from tennis whites! Maria Sharapova reveals killer legs in sheer chiffon dress at ESPY awards Caused quite a racket &apos;One doctor suggested I abort her&apos;: Against all odds one of the world&apos;s smallest surviving babies finally goes home Kenna Claire Moore is a little miracle That&apos;s one pricey push-up! The bra dripping in diamonds and gold selling for $1million Contains 750 grams of gold They&apos;re his mini mes! Liam Gallagher&apos;s sons Lennon and Gene are a chip off the old block Perfected that mean and moody scowl Fifty Shades of Grey author&apos;s saucy tale was inspired by her Latin roots, says her mother Alexandra Mitchell has praised her daughter&apos;s erotic trilogy Making the most of her bikini body: Actress Louisa Lytton shows off her slim frame on holiday Before rehearsing for latest theatre show Lesbian sex scene in ballet thriller Black Swan makes it film with most complaints Some viewers described the scene as &apos;pornographic&apos; What would Marilyn say! Karolina Kurkova flashes a bit too much as she takes centre stage in a sexy photoshoot She took it a lot further! Angelina Jolie dresses her brood in angelic white... as Maleficent sticks to the dark side in head to toe black A woman of many talents &apos;Maybe it&apos;s time to go&apos;: Jennifer Lopez hints at American Idol departure as show seeks younger judges to rival Britney and Demi &apos;Duct tape over the camera and a $1,000 a night Presidential Suite&apos;: Inside Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s last weekend together Efforts to hide tension &apos;Look how broken up we look&apos;: Professor Green denies split from Millie Mackintosh Said he made up lesbian rumours 
     
DON&apos;T MISS

 &apos;I just can&apos;t function in the morning&apos;: What Nick Grimshaw told BBC boss moments before being offered top breakfast slot On Chris&apos; show today Pudsey goes Stateside! Talented pooch wins over U.S. audiences with an adorable performance on Jay Leno Entranced by their show Pictured: The moment Glee star Kristin Chenoweth received emergency medical treatment following injury on set Stretchered off set A bit of me time: Jessica Alba quaffs rose wine as she enjoys some bikini time with her mother in Amalfi As the children are away... EXCLUSIVE PICS: We get it, you&apos;re engaged! Katie Waissel can&apos;t keep her hands off model fiance Celebrating poolside in Los Angeles Mr Bigger: Sex And The City heart-throb Chris Noth succumbs to the middle-aged paunch Not the trim suited Mr Big he once was You can leave your hats on! Elle Macpherson&apos;s trendy son copies her jaunty style on holiday A trendsetter in her own family Bad womance! Lady Gaga has &apos;sleepover&apos; with Lindsay Lohan - but deletes series of tweets drawing attention to new friendship Why do the children of the rich so often turn into drug addicts? As the Rausings tragedy develops, CATHERINE OSTLER looks at how drugs are classless That will make their friends Greene with envy! Twilight beauty Ashley leads co-stars in greeting determined fans at Comic-Co Mr Bigger: Sex And The City heart-throb Chris Noth succumbs to the middle-aged paunch Not the trim suited Mr Big he once was Proud Eugenie poses in mortar board as she graduates... and she can&apos;t stop smiling Royal looked delighted at Newcastle University Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s amicable divorce is &apos;a sham as actor plans to keep Suri in Scientology&apos; He has &apos;planned her indoctrination&apos; No bingo wings here! Catherine Zeta-Jones shows off her toned arms in a pretty sundress as she hits the shops All that heavy lifting When in Rome: Roxanne Pallett goes for a Eastern-inspired dress at Bali spa opening Emmerdale star showed off a lot of flesh The perfect pairing! Christina Hendricks is the hostess with the most-ess in a plunging black dress You would have to be a mad man not to notice It takes a lot of work to look this good! Kim Kardashian heads to the gym after sharing bikini snap from sunrise shoot That&apos;s Barry&apos;s Bootcamp workout Miranda Kerr pretends to be demure in long floral dress... but still flashes her cleavage and legs Showed off her runway legs Can you fake the perfect cleavage? We put underwear to the test as a new bra promises to boost your assets at the tug of a string Cesc Fabregas&apos; girlfriend Daniella gets snap happy as he shows off his football skills on holiday in Sardinia Who can blame her? DIY Chelsea blow-dry: Can you get Kate&apos;s tumbling curls without professional help? MARIANNE POWER took up the challenge Stephen Dorff&apos;s model girlfriend is nowhere to be seen... as he&apos;s surrounded by bikini-clad babes in Ibiza Katharina Damm MIA How does a man cope when his wife wont stop breast feeding? Vicky&apos;s decision to continue with their three-year-old is inhibiting their closeness, says James She&apos;s a fan of Pink too! Singer steps out with Carey Hart and daughter Willow who is dressed head-to-toe in the girly colour Her number 1 fan THAT&apos;S how to wind down after Wimbledon! Roger Federer and wife soak up sun on luxury yacht... as Andy Murray battles rain in Britain &apos;Having sex too young ruined my love life&apos; Kristen Dugdale tells her tale of regret at losing her virginity at just 14 Curvy and proud Aubrey O&apos;Day slips into ANOTHER revealing bikini Lapping up the attention in Florida &apos;We should all be proud of her for being real&apos;: Kendra Wilkinson defends Jessica Simpson&apos;s post-baby body Can sympathise with her AMANDA PLATELL: &apos;Why I dumped the spy who loved me&apos; As Jools Oliver admits she snoops on Jamie, Amanda shares her cautionary tale Carefree Amber Heard puts on a show in strapless bustier But girlfriend Tasya fails to raise a smile amidst Johnny Depp rumours Channing Tatum confirms sequel to Magic Mike... and puts himself forward for 50 Shades of Grey movie Right choice to play Christian? Suri&apos;s smile: Katie and Tom&apos;s daughter has her spirits lifted on zoo outing with mother and grandma Kept her distracted at Central Park in New York Did Katie Holmes make secret calls to Nicole Kidman before blindsiding Tom Cruise with divorce? Claims she sought counsel from his ex Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate photographs of Prince William and Kate&apos;s island honeymoon Woman&apos;s Day cover too Leggy Jessica Biel is white hot in a short but sweet frock at the ESPY Awards Actress was a sight for sore eyes in flirty dress Ultimate girl-next-door: Freida Pinto promotes film in cutesy frocks (although only a celebrity changes three times) Diva behaviour! If it ain&apos;t broke! Emma Roberts parades her perfect pins in her favourite tiny shorts She&apos;s found a look she likes and she&apos;s sticking with it... Kim Kardashian and boyfriend Kanye West match in leather trousers and white tops Pair looked picture perfect in coordinating looks History Detectives say they have &apos;found&apos; Bob Dylans legendary electric guitar from Newport Folk Festival (though singer says hes had it all along) Catch me if you can: Kai gives Coleen and Wayne Rooney the run around on family day out in Liverpool Playing in the sunshine Fringe benefits! Anne Hathaway shows off healthier figure in classy black dress after admitting Les Miserables diet was &apos;not fun&apos; Meg Ryan displays her sinewy arms in tomboy outfit In same vein as Madonna, Sarah Jessica Parker, and Angelina Jolie It&apos;s obviously following her! A healthy and happy Sarah Harding can&apos;t keep the smile off her face She brought a bit of sun back from Ibiza Angels on wheels! Stunning Doutzen Kroes leads the Victoria&apos;s Secret models at charity spinning event So THAT&apos;S how they stay slim! He is a Sk8er Boi! Rachel Zoe puts son Skyler on wheels with his first skateboard Adorable 15-month-old tried his luck on the vehicle I do, I do, I do! Three brides, one dress and 50 years of true love Three generations from one family tell their stories Why DO so many women pretend the menopause doesn&apos;t exist? The 50-somethings don&apos;t want to own up to their age Chloe Sevigny was worried about transsexual role in Hit&amp;Miss as she poses in androgynous photoshoot Thought fans would be &apos;angry&apos; Salt in the wound: Former cocaine user Demi Lovato brands X Factor double act &apos;irresponsible&apos; over drugs rap Asked them to get off Fit for a diva! Mariah Carey puts Bahamas villa where she wed Nick Cannon on the market Luxurious house sits on the beach Big Brother housemates strip to their underwear for spray tans as they win party treats But bitching intensifies Showing off their sea legs: Kate Moss and husband Jamie Hince get playful as they jump in unison off luxury yacht in St Tropez Tom Cruise&apos;s loyal son arrives on Oblivion set to lend support amid divorce turmoil Connor, 17, jetted to Mammoth Lakes, California Tom Cruise finds release from divorce turmoil by shooting a laser gun on the set of Oblivion That&apos;s one hell of a stress relief! Zooey Deschanel holds her own against red carpet regulars Hayden Panettiere and Olivia Munn at ESPY Awards New Girl star can do glam as well as quirky Redhead bullied at school says real gingers will ALWAYS be outcasts no matter how many celebrities dye their hair because fakes &apos;don&apos;t have the gene&apos; Not afraid to show her wild side! Jennifer Hudson teams leopard print hotpants with leather top Performed at food festival She&apos;s too sexy for her shirt! Sports Illustrated model Jessica Perez rips off her vest before taking Paul Rudd for a run Blimey! By &apos;eck! Melanie Sykes gets racy and shows she&apos;s a speed demon as she leaves ITV studios on the back of a motorbike Riding pillion Dressed to frill: Rose McGowan is red hot in a ruffled dress as she hits the shops Actress showed off her trim figure Devoted aunties! Kim, Kendall and Kylie wear matching &apos;Mason loves Penelope&apos; necklaces Pendants were given to them by mother Kris Kris Jenner&apos;s marriage to Bruce in crisis after he walks in on her signing off email &apos;xoxo&apos; to ex boyfriend Todd Waterman At breaking point Katie Holmes&apos; final snub to Scientology -&apos;actress registers with Catholic church in New York&apos; Breaking free from Tom Cruise Jamie read you the riot act? Jools Oliver looks miserable as she heads home from the shops Follows her paranoia revelation Out with the old and in with the new red ride! Selma Blair buys son Arthur an updated stroller In time for his first birthday He&apos;s growing up fast! Cindy Crawford goes shopping with her 13-year-old son Presley He appears to be enjoying life as a teenager Kate Moss smoulders in femme fatale role for Salvatore Ferragamo Seen walking in heels around Berlin&apos;s gilded Russian embassy Lean in green! Hayden Panettiere shows off her slender figure in a strapless bikini Holidaying in Mexico Making a bold comeback! Dannii Minogue tweets pictures of herself in a stunning floor-length yellow lace dress Bang on trend! No more late nights, Grimmers! How nocturnal Nick Grimshaw went from friend of the stars to landing Radio 1&apos;s top job Pixie Geldof a pal Dressing down gets the kiss-off. When times are tough the &apos;lipstick effect&apos; sees women spending on clothes and cosmetics Now that&apos;s an advantage: Andy Murray has an ace time as he enjoys time off with girlfriend Kim Sears following Wimbledon Posed with fan &apos;I feel complete&apos;: Christina Milian layers low-cut tanks for hike with daughter Violet She&apos;s &apos;the love of her life&apos; &apos;You&apos;ll get divorced soon anyway!&apos; Vinny rips apart Snooki&apos;s engagement bombshell Jersey Shore cast ridicule her decision New love, new home: Giovanni Ribisi sells bachelor pad as he moves in with supermodel bride Agyness Deyn That&apos;s some love nest I&apos;m off! Chris Moyles tells listeners he is quitting his Radio 1 breakfast show Nick Grimshaw to replace self-styled Saviour of Radio 1 Clingy, needy and moody. It&apos;s Rachel who&apos;s expecting - but it&apos;s her dog who&apos;s gone all hormonal Pregnancy is having a strange effect on Maxi The best advert for her own collection! TOWIE&apos;s Lucy Mecklenburgh shines in a bedazzled bikini to launch swimwear range Totes amaze Miss Modest: Kelly Brook covers up her curves in a white vest, as boyfriend Thom Evans shows off his six-pack Picture perfect couple! Reaching new heights: Angelina Jolie shoots more of her own daring stunts as she resumes filming of Maleficent Dangling from a crane Two Cabs! John Prescott has to take taxi to and from Sir David Frost&apos;s summer party Hobbled along with a walking stick after breaking his foot World champion Ronnie O&apos;Sullivan is set to swap snooker cue for dancing shoes as he&apos;s lined up for Strictly Terminally ill mother marries partner after mystery donor known as &apos;Mary Poppins&apos; funds lavish ceremony Naomi&apos;s breast cancer has spread to her spine Amanda who? Dominic Cooper moves on from on/off lover Seyfried by kissing mystery brunette on holiday in Italy That was quick! Don&apos;t stand next to her in the pool! Jessica Alba flaunts her enviable bikini body as she continues to enjoy her Italian family holiday Family time! Legs that go on forever! Kendall Jenner accentuates her supermodel height in a mint bodycon minidress Teenager&apos;s style style Bet that hasn&apos;t got air conditioning! Melissa McCarthy smiles as she films through &apos;The Heat&apos; in a clapped-out old car On set in Boston Plenty to celebrate! Jessica Simpson takes new daughter Maxwell to 32nd birthday bash Went to The Beverly Hills Hotel Rafa Nadal swaps his tennis racket for a snorkel as he shows off his ace body on holiday in Sardinia Action-packed holiday Dakota Fanning lends teary Elizabeth Olsen a shoulder to cry on (but don&apos;t worry, it&apos;s only for a scene in their movie) How Facebook is behind a surge in plastic surgery Surgeons say internet users are repulsed by their looks in pictures on social media sites She Will Be Loved: Adam Levine sends new Victoria&apos;s Secret model girlfriend Behati Prinsloo into a spin on way back to hotel Lea Michele continues transformation into fashionista as she turns model for new Candie&apos;s campaign Retro-inspired collection &apos;Skin cancer wouldn&apos;t stop me&apos;: Tanning addict hasn&apos;t missed a day of her sunbed habit in ten years It&apos;s cost Trisha 32,000 Duchess of Cornwall gives flowers back to tearful toddler who had a change of heart after presenting posy Royal introduction for Ffion Going for gold! Michael Phelps strips down to show off his swimmer&apos;s body as he gets set for the Olympics Cover guy Forget Eden Wood! Three tiny new trash-talking pageant queens herald the return of Toddlers and Tiaras All starts tonight Addicted to water: Sasha&apos;s obsession started when she was just two years old She drinks up to 44 pints a day Is Kate Upton dating Justin Verlander? Sports Illustrated supermodel spends weekend with star Detroit Tigers pitcher Getting close They won&apos;t twist your testicles, Russell! Comedian steps out in baggy trousers as TV doctor warns tight jeans are bad for your privates 
 
 Today&apos;s headlines Most Read 
 
 Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using new M&amp;S;virtual technology We&apos;ve got high hopes with that body! British Olympic high jump hopeful Robbie Grabarz unveils a gold standard body... in tiny pants He&apos;s Christmas crackers! Experimental chef Heston Blumenthal unveils his festive menu for Waitrose...in July Don&apos;t sweat it, Zara! Royal Olympic hope admits she&apos;s &apos;nervous but excited&apos; as she tries out kit for size ahead of the Games Makes a change from tennis whites! Maria Sharapova reveals killer legs in sheer chiffon dress at ESPY awards Why This Morning&apos;s penis enlargement feature brought a tear to my eyes (for all the right reasons) 

 MORE HEADLINES 
 
 What were you inking! The embarrassing matching tattoos that brand couples for life Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using new M&amp;S;virtual technology &apos;I had so much fun&apos;: Princess Eugenie speaks of happy times as she graduates from university How does a man cope when his wife won’t stop breast feeding? Can you fake the perfect cleavage? We put underwear to the test as a new bra promises to boost your assets at the tug of a string... Having sex too young ruined our love lives: A THIRD of young women admit regrets about the way they lost their virginity... MOST READ IN DETAIL 
     
ADVERTORIAL FEATURES

 BirdsEye Win 1 of 5 Royal Family Breaks with BirdsEye Clinique&apos;s 3-Step System The best things in life come in 3. Click for your chance to WIN a years supply of Cliniques 3-step system &gt; 
 
 Back to top Navigation Popular 
 
 Home News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 Popular searches in femail: Daily Mail Facebook Daily Mail Femail Twitter Daily Mail Googe+ Anne Shooter&apos;s Food blog Liz Jones Fashion blog Sarah Ivens&apos; Baby blog 
 Sitemap Newsletters RSS Archive Text-based site Reader Prints Top of page 
 Daily Mail Mail on Sunday Widgets This is Network This is London This is Money 
 Metro Jobsite Mail Travel Find a property Motors Prime location Villa Holidays 
Published by Associated Newspapers Ltd

Part of the Daily Mail, The Mail on Sunday&amp;Metro Media Group
 ©Associated Newspapers Ltd Contact us Advertise with us Terms Privacy policy&amp;cookies
	</body>
</document>
