<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005685" url="http://www.chocolatecafeandcoffeeco.com/tusculumcollege.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:16" support="2" score="0.0008919186634496114" bingtitle="Tusculum College - Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Company" webtitle="Tusculum College - Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Company">
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... 10% discount off your entire bill ... gift for your favorite student! Pick one up at either of our locations, or order ... Not the typical fast food restaurant. It may take a ...</description>
	<body>
		Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Company 

Experience the difference.
 
 Home Our Menu Locations Tusculum College Catering In the News Order Online Contact Us Photo Gallery Testimonials Friends of the Cafe 
 
 Welcome Tusculum Students
 
Our Tusculum cafe is located directly across the street from the Doak House Museum at Tusculum College. Many Tusculum College students frequent Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Co. to take breaks from their studies and grab a quick, healthy bite to eat.

 

Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Co is a big supporter of Tusculum College at the Trailblazer level of the Pioneer club member.

 

 Tusculum Students receive a 10% discount off your entire bill, by presenting your student ID. 

 

 

From the Tusculum College website :

Founded in 1794, Tusculum College is the oldest college in Tennessee, the twenty-eighth oldest college in the nation, and the oldest coeducational institution affiliated with the Presbyterian Church (USA). The wooded 140-acre Tusculum College campus has eight buildings and the Tusculum Arch that are listed on the National Register of Historic Places. 

 

 

From the Doak House Museum website: 

The Doak House Museum is a non-profit, educational institution, established as a museum in 1975. The museum uses its collections and resources to promote the study and research of history, education, religion, and cultural heritage of the people of Northeast Tennessee and the state. 10,000 children and adults participate in the educational programs available at the Doak House Museum. 

 Gift cards make a great gift for your favorite student! Pick one up at either of our locations, or order online . 
 
Facebook
 
 
 
 Testimonials 
 
 &quot;Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Company is an absolute find in Greeneville, TN. The atmosphere is very relaxed, with lots of windows, a beautifully done metal ceiling, and lots of ava...&quot; Stephanie T New Haven, CT 
 Read more testimonials... 
 Recent Photos 
 
 
 
Chocolate Cafe and Coffee Co. 665 Erwin Hwy, Greeneville, TN 37745. Copyright 2010
	</body>
</document>
