<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005713" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/fuddruckers-bethlehem-344140" time="2012-07-12-22:20" support="1" score="0.002075409412576872" bingtitle="Fuddruckers - Reviews &amp; Menu - 2955 Linden St, Bethlehem 18017" webtitle="Fuddruckers - Reviews&amp;Menu - Bethlehem 18017">
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>Description: Fuddruckers is a Burgers, Sandwiches, and Fast Food restaurant ... You order &amp; pick up your food at the counter, saving money on tips. The nacho appetizers are ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 Fuddruckers Menu 

 Fuddruckers Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Bethlehem Restaurants » Burgers » Fuddruckers Share | 
Fuddruckers
 
 2.66667 star rating           
  2.7 rating over 2 reviews 
 (610) 625-4900 

 2955 Linden St ( ) 

 Bethlehem , PA 18017 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (2) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Fuddruckers is a Burgers , Sandwiches , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for fun with friends , paid less than $10 , and tipped less than 15% . Tags: Burgers, Sandwiches, Closed, Kid Friendly, Delivery, Family, Fast Food, Trendy, American, and Good For Kids Stats: 
 194 dishes entered by diners at Fuddruckers 1 user wants to eat at Fuddruckers 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Fuddruckers? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Fuddruckers
 Write a review 
 2 reviews First reviewed by RJones 
 
&quot;I eat meals when on business, I enjoy meals when at pleasure&quot;

 22 helpful votes over 21 reviews 
 PalateMan 
 21 Restaurant Reviews +16 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Fuddruckers PalateMan 
 June 15, 2009 
 2.0 
 2.0 star rating           
 +1 0 +1 1 Votes   
CLOSED
 
 CLOSED 
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
&quot;Powered by Tofu!&quot;

 202 helpful votes over 106 reviews 
 RJones 
 106 Restaurant Reviews +198 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Fuddruckers RJones 
 December 6, 2008 
 2.0 
 2.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Large Portion, Cheap Price
 
You get what you pay for at Fuddruckers, where they serve large portions at relatively cheap prices. A step up from a fast food place with a drive through, a step down from Chillies/ TGIF /Applebees. They have just enough varriety for a family to dine out, which is clearly their target customers. The place is decorated for children. You order&amp;pick up your food at the counter, saving money on tips.

The nacho appetizers are large enough to be a meal in themselves, and the staff actualy laughed at me for ordering them as an appetizer on my first visit.
The burgers are served without condements, and there is a condement bar with everthing from lettuce&amp;tomato to dressings, clearly designed for picky eaters.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Veggie Burger
 
 2.0 star rating           
 
Generic, filling, not particularly tasty.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
Best Dishes at Fuddruckers

These dishes from the Fuddruckers menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
1/2 LB. ORIGINAL BURGER, FRIES&amp;SODA OR DOMESTIC BEER
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
All-American Burger ( $6.00 ) 
 
 4.0 star rating           
 
fries ( $2.00 ) 
 
 4.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Stefano&apos;s Cafe 
 3 reviews 3.5 stars Perfect Images Styling Salon Walgreens 
 1 review 3.0 stars Flour Shop 
 1 review 5.0 stars From Hair to Eternity 
 27 reviews 5.0 stars Celebrations Hair And Tanning Bethlehem Windows Pearson Funeral Home Inc Rite Aid Rent-A-Center 
 Fuddruckers is located near the cities of Freemansburg, Fountain Hill, Saucon Valley Terrace, Hellertown, and Easton Pa 18045. People found this by searching for: 2955 Linden St Bethlehem, Pa 18017, Funruckers Rating, Old Fuddruckers Address In Bethlehem, Fudruckers In The Lehighvalley Pa, What Was The Location Of Fudruckers In Bethlehem, Fuddruckers Bethlehem, and Fuddruckers Restruant Veggie Burgers. 
Recommended Nearby
 
 5.0 star rating           
 Yianni&apos;s Taverna 
 4.0 star rating           
 The Melting Pot 
 4.0 star rating           
 Tap Room 
 3.5 star rating           
 Blue Grill House&amp;Wine Bar 
 3.5 star rating           
 Bruno Scipioni&apos;s Italian 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 2 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Fiesta Ole Supper Made Simple Stefanos Restaurant Macada Pizza 
Link to Fuddruckers
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism
	</body>
</document>
