<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005306" url="http://memotogame.typepad.com/memo-to-game/2010/03/mcdonalds-video-game-im-sorta-lovin-it.html" time="2012-07-12-21:50" support="2" score="0.004176821158527743" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s Video Game: I&apos;m Sorta Lovin&apos; It... - Memo to Game" webtitle="McDonald&apos;s Video Game: I&apos;m Sorta Lovin&apos; It... - Memo to Game">
			<query id="000326" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>... tub, fries and soft drink all seated on a tray. But ... but in gaming reality it could probably be any fast food restaurant. ... containing manipulation, corruption and a table of ...</description>
	<body>
		Memo to Game 

because indie games have something to say
 
 Home Archives Profile Subscribe 
 
 «My First (Official) Post! | Main | Trailer: All Star Karate (Wii)» 

03/30/2010
 
McDonald&apos;s Video Game: I&apos;m Sorta Lovin&apos; It...
 
 I&apos;m not a big fan of fast food restaurants. Given the amount of criticism aimed at such places, who could be a fan, really?

 

Mcdonald&apos;s Video Game describes itself as a&quot;digital parody&quot;and evidently takes a courageous aim at those famous golden arches.



The main menu screen is pretty disturbing. At first glance, it is as bright and colourful as anything the fast food franchise may have subjected to potential customers in the past. The image is a picture of a typical fast food meal; a burger tub, fries and soft drink all seated on a tray. But the splash of something red seems to indicate more than just ketchup...



The game itself has you managing a fast food franchise. Here, it takes inspiration of the McDonald&apos;s logo, but in gaming reality it could probably be any fast food restaurant. There&apos;s no inset goal to beat, all the game requires from you is to run the franchise and deal with any problems that may arise.



Problems do arise, both in and out of the workplace. Sooner or later, a watchman may complain there isn&apos;t enough feed for the cows or a supervisor may express concern over the unhappiness of their employees. Meanwhile, your once smiling customers may return with concerns over failing health issues.



It is how the game suggests you deal with these problems that truly disturbs. Running low on feed? How about adding industrial waste to the mix? Alternatively, how about some growth hormone to knock out a few extra burgers? If you want to play it natural and grow more crops, that&apos;s fine, though you might have to knock down rain forests or tribal villages in the process.



Recently badged or disciplined employees won&apos;t stay happy for long and
will eventually find job satisfaction through frowns and sometimes
spitting on the burgers. The latter image is amusing, recapturing what I can only hope is an urban myth (at least they&apos;re not doing anything else on the burgers!). After a while, you&apos;ll realise your employees can only stay happy for long, which means you&apos;ll need to replace them, but don&apos;t expect ex employees to take things lying down.



That&apos;s where the headquarters comes in and it&apos;s a real nasty place, seemingly containing manipulation, corruption and a table of squabbling businessmen in separate rooms.



The marketing staff appear as creative types who may well be stoned out of their mind. The game provides the chance to run advertising campaigns, starting with information on nutrition to resorting to other popular mascots all in further order to attract customers.



The PR desk is a handy tool for corruption. Unhappy ex employees? Corrupt a politician. Unhappy tree huggers? Corrupt an environmentalist. Unhappy (and perhaps unhealthy) customers? Corrupt a nutritionist.



All of this done with money, of course, and the businessmen found in the final room appear to think you never make enough of it. Every once in a while, the Executive Vice President will complain that&quot;growth is not sufficient&quot;, eventually forcing you to&quot;up&quot;your game which means cutting down natural resources, fattening cows, sacking employees and corrupting officials.



Just another busy day working in fast food or so McDonald&apos;s Video Game seems to think.

 MEMO TO GAME: Thanks for the depressing insight. 



You can play it for free here . Check it out.
 
 Posted at 03:23 AM | Permalink 

 Technorati Tags : flash , free , McDonalds , video game 

 | Reblog
 (0) 
 
Comments
 
 You can follow this conversation by subscribing to the comment feed for this post.
 
The comments to this entry are closed.
 
 D I R E C T O R Y 
 
 All Games 

 
 
Search
 
 Categories 
 
 Achievements Advermin Continue Fleeting Thought Gawping at guide Hot Men in Video Games Just Dancing memo to box memo to game Memo to Game Phase 2.0 Memo to Gay Minecrepe Moments in Survival Horror Much Uma About Multiplayer Moments Music Video New Game Notes from an Android User Site News The Cup of Tea Simulator the lair Trailer Breakdown Upcoming Visual Weekly Roundup WTF your word against mine 
 All written content copyrighted (c) 2009-2011 Memo to Game unless otherwise stated. 
 
 Memo to Game Powered by TypePad
	</body>
</document>
