<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005146" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/filippos-pizza-broasted-chicken-wauwatosa-201002" time="2012-07-12-21:40" support="1" score="0.0008293711652270965" bingtitle="Filippo&apos;s Pizza &amp; Broasted Chicken - Reviews &amp; Menu - Wauwatosa 53226" webtitle="Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken - Reviews&amp;Menu - 2330 N 124th St, Wauwatosa 53226">
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Order Delivery &amp; Takeout; Restaurant ... is a Pizza, American, and Fast Food restaurant where ... of pizza places in the area (Glass Nickel, Lalli’s, Toppers) you would expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu 
 Wauwatosa Restaurants » Pizza » Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken Share | 
Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken
 
 2.33333 star rating           
  2.3 rating over 4 reviews 
 (414) 607-1878 

 2330 N 124th St ( ) 

 Wauwatosa , WI 53226 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Read Reviews (4) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken is a Pizza , American , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for a meal on the go , paid less than $10 , and tipped less than 15% . Tags: Pizza, American, Fast Food, Sandwiches, and Subs Stats: 
 4 dishes entered by diners at Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken
 Write a review 
 4 reviews First reviewed by Shughart 
 
 1 helpful votes over 2 reviews 
 Romeo 
 2 Restaurant Reviews +1 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken Romeo 
 July 7, 2008 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 +1 0 +1 1 Votes   
Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken
 
Had their pizza and broasted chicken sent to my office for a client meeting. They delivered and it was great. I’ve had many different kinds before and keep going only to Filippo’s on 124th. That was 4 years ago and I still order for the office and take it home for the family. Outstanding.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
Pizza
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Tasty. Good crust. Great sauce. Good value.
 
Broasted Chicken
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
I usually don’t like fried chicken (like KFC ), but their season broasted chicken is awsome.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
 0 helpful votes over 3 reviews 
 JimmyTimmy 
 3 Restaurant Reviews 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken JimmyTimmy 
 August 10, 2009 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Disappointing
 
As a pizza lover, I was very upset with my experience. Food was okay, pick-up area was disgusting, customer service was horrible, and prices aren’t that great. Considering the large amount of pizza places in the area (Glass Nickel, Lalli’s, Toppers) you would expect great service and competitive prices… not at Filipo’s.

I will never go there again – very sad to see a family-run place get run into the ground. Clean up your act (both literally and figuratively) and lower your prices and maybe I’ll return.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken JimmyTimmy 
 August 10, 2009 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Disappointing
 
As a pizza lover, I was very upset with my experience. Food was okay, pick-up area was disgusting, customer service was horrible, and prices aren’t that great. Considering the large amount of pizza places in the area (Glass Nickel, Lalli’s, Toppers) you would expect great service and competitive prices…not at Filipo’s.

I will never go there again–very sad to see a family-run place get run into the ground. Clean up your act (both literally and figuratively) and lower your prices and maybe I’ll return.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
 2 helpful votes over 4 reviews 
 Shughart 
 4 Restaurant Reviews +2 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken Shughart 
 October 23, 2007 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Blah
 
Mozzerella sticks were cold, chicken strips were skimpy.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
chicken fingers
 
 1.0 star rating           
 
skimpy, they cheat you!
 
mozzerella sticks
 
 1.0 star rating           
 
cold and gross
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Hungryman9 
 from Citysearch 
 
August 10, 2009
 
 1 star rating           
 
Okay food coupled with awful customer service
 
Bad experience from call-in through dinner. Customer service was horrible, pick-up was very dirty (nervous about food prep), and okay food.

Nothing about the place is very pleasing and considering the environment that they cook in, I…

 read full review» 
 Read 5 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken

These dishes from the Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
chicken fingers
 
 1.0 star rating           
 
Pizza ( $15.00 ) 
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
Broasted Chicken ( $8.00 ) 
 
 5.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 EmbroidMe Sportsworld Sportsworld&amp;Shopsportsworld.com Eden&apos;s Home Improvements, LLC Once Upon A Child 
 4 reviews 3.5 stars Soccer World 
 1 review 4.0 stars AAA Psychological Associates Cardassi, Lawrence J, Phd - Psychological Associates Hochmuth, Mark C, Phd - Psychological Associates 
 Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken is located near the cities of West Allis, West Milwaukee, Elm Grove, Butler, and Brookfield. People found this by searching for: Filippos Wauwatosa, Broasted Chicken Wauwatosa, Filippo&apos;s Pizza Wauwatosa, Filippo Wauwatosa, Filippo&apos;s Pizza, Fillipos In Wauwatosa, Flippos Chicken, and Fillipos Elm Grove. 
Featured in Wauwatosa
 
 4.33333 star rating           
 Olive Garden 
 4.0 star rating           
 Milwaukee Chophouse 
 4.75 star rating           
 Marco&apos;s Pizza 
 3.5 star rating           
 Rich&apos;s House of Cakes 
 3.5 star rating           
 Amelia&apos;s 
 4.5 star rating           
 Louise&apos;s Italian Cafe 
 4.33333 star rating           
 Double Dragon 
 4.16667 star rating           
 Pepi&apos;s Pizza 
 4.33333 star rating           
 Red Lobster 
 3.83333 star rating           
 William Ho&apos;s 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Nearby Restaurants
 McDonald&apos;s Moosilini&apos;s Peach Garden Restaurant Happy Wok 
Link to Filippo&apos;s Pizza&amp;Broasted Chicken
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
