<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005307" url="http://www.myhuckleberry.com/Browse/Texas/Arlington/Food_and_Drink/Restaurants/All/Page-1.aspx" time="2012-07-12-21:50" support="3" score="0.01137594824016689" bingtitle="Arlington, TX Restaurants Page 1 - MyHuckleberry.com – Business ..." webtitle="Arlington, TX Restaurants Page 1">
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>... TX no matter what mood you are in. Ever heard of organic fast-food? Yea ... hospital-themed restaurant where you get to sit in a wheelchair and eat off a hospital tray.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In   |   Register FIND A BUSINESS EXPERT ANSWERS COUPONS CREDIT CARDS MY ACCOUNT 
 By Category   |   By Business Name   |   By Business Information   |   By Phone Number 
 FIND LOCATION Business Category (e.g. restaurants, florists) City, State or Zip Code 
 By Category   |   By Business Name   |   By Business Information   |   By Phone Number 
 FIND LOCATION Business Name (e.g. Environix, Ross) City, State or Zip Code 
 By Category   |   By Business Name   |   By Business Information   |   By Phone Number 
 FIND LOCATION Product or Service (e.g. organic food, graphic design) City, State or Zip Code 
 By Category   |   By Business Name   |   By Business Information   |   By Phone Number 
 PHONE Area Code + Number 
Browse Business Listings
 in Arlington, Texas for Restaurants
 Home &gt; Browse &gt; Texas &gt; Arlington &gt; Food&amp;Drink &gt; Restaurants Powered By Subgurim(http://googlemaps.subgurim.net). Google Maps ASP.NET Refine by Business Name All
 (553) 
 #
 (1) 
 A
 (19) 
 B
 (29) 
 C
 (53) 
 D
 (17) 
 E
 (8) 
 F
 (10) 
 G
 (11) 
 H
 (15) 
 I
 (10) 
 J
 (32) 
 K
 (7) 
 L
 (25) 
 M
 (41) 
 N
 (6) 
 O
 (10) 
 P
 (65) 
 Q
 (7) 
 R
 (18) 
 S
 (80) 
 T
 (48) 
 U
 (1) 
 V
 (5) 
 W
 (33) 
 X
 (1) 
 Y
 (1) 1 - 10 of 553 results Sort:    Standard A-Z Z-A Rating 
 Chili&apos;s Grill&amp;Bar 3830 S Cooper St
Arlington, TX 76015 (817) 467-9944 Chili&apos;s Grill&amp;Bar 924 E Copeland Rd
Arlington, TX 76011 (817) 261-3891 Dos Gringos Inc 125 Interstate 20 E
Arlington, TX 76018 (817) 557-9922 El Fenix Corp 4608 S Cooper St
Arlington, TX 76017 (817) 557-4309 Genroku Sushi and Grill 1020 W Arkansas Ln
Arlington, TX 76013 (817) 277-5888 Ho Ho Kitchen 111 S Bowen Rd
Arlington, TX 76012 (817) 861-3263 Jack in the Box 700 W Division St
Arlington, TX 76012 (817) 795-6974 Jack in the Box 753 W Lamar Blvd
Arlington, TX 76012 (817) 261-2888 Humperdinks Texas Llc 700 Six Flags Dr
Arlington, TX 76011 (817) 649-1962 Hysen&apos;s Nizza Pizza 7807 S Cooper St
Arlington, TX 76001 (817) 468-1999 
 Page  1   2   3   4   5   6   7   8   9   10   &gt;   &gt;&gt;   They say organic is orgasmic. There is a plethora of restaurants to choose from in Arlington, TX no matter what mood you are in. Ever heard of organic fast-food? Yea, me neither, but I&apos;m sure it&apos;s out there somewhere.


Arlington, TX Fine Restaurants


Are you tired of eating fast food? Break some barriers and enjoy some cuisine, especially at our fine restaurants in Arlington, TX.

We’re here to cure your food cravings. Do you love Italian food but can’t seem to find a good chicken parmigiana? We can help – we know all the hot spots.

With our help, you will find all of the fantastic restaurants that Arlington, TX has to offer. Whether you’re looking for Chinese, Italian, Japanese, fine dining, diners, drive-in, Thai, buffets, or cafes, we know the best places to eat. With so many fine restaurants here, it can be hard to choose a place to go!

Want to know which restaurants offer outdoor seating, dining specials, or require reservations or formal attire? Just ask. When you know all the detailed information for each food source, it&apos;s easy to choose a place to eat. It doesn&apos;t matter if you&apos;re very particular about your food.


Arlington, TX Featured Restaurants


Celebrate dining – remember, you only live once, unless you’re James Bond. Make the most of your short time on this Earth and eat some good foods.

If you are passionate about food and love trying new restaurants, we can give you some tips about new places to eat, featured food trends, and top foodie locations.

Give your kitchen a break and enjoy eating out and breaking bread with your family and friends. Our Arlington, TX is full of cuisines to sample and culinary delights to tantalize your taste buds. Indulge yourself. Visit a restaurant tonight in the area tonight.


New and Inventive Restaurants in Arlington, TX


There are so many new and inventive places to eat popping up in Arlington, TX! There are themed restaurants, ethnic restaurants, crossover restaurants, cutting edge restaurants and gimmicky restaurants just waiting to be enjoyed.

Do you want to eat soup out of a toilet? There&apos;s a Arlington, TX restaurant for that. It&apos;s not from a USED toilet. Where&apos;s your sense of adventure?

Maybe you want to eat in a hospital-themed restaurant where you get to sit in a wheelchair and eat off a hospital tray. The drinks and sauces are served out of syringes, with IV bags of chocolate and sugar pills for dessert. Some might find that idea creepy, but hey, it takes all kinds of people to make up the world.

companies, coupons, services, review, businesses, coupon, reviewed, scam, fraud, find, recommended, sued, lawsuit, con-artist, best, discount, cheapest, least expensive, inexpensive, affordable, discounts, same day, 24 hour, report, cheap, price, prices, cost and free
 ©2012
MyHuckleberry.Com Terms&amp;Conditions   |   Copyright&amp;Privacy Policy   |   Site Map   |   About Us   |   Support   |   Contact   |   Frequently Asked Questions   |   Index
	</body>
</document>
