<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005661" url="http://www.nabuzz.com/wienerwald-fast-food-eco-friendly-restaurant-interior-design" time="2012-07-12-22:14" support="1" score="0.0027527177734454496" bingtitle="Wienerwald Fast Food: Eco Friendly Restaurant Interior Design ..." webtitle="Wienerwald Fast Food: Eco Friendly Restaurant Interior Design - Restaurant - Nabuzz.com">
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>Tags: fast food restaurant, furniture plans, green and clean lounge, restaurant interior ... Leave a Reply</description>
	<body>
		Contact Us Copyright Privacy Policy Sitemap Submit Design 
 
 Nabuzz.com 

Furniture, Home Decor, Interior Design&amp;Decorating Ideas
 Search for: Home » Restaurant » Wienerwald Fast Food: Eco Friendly Restaurant Interior Design February 22, 2011 
Wienerwald Fast Food: Eco Friendly Restaurant Interior Design
 Category: Restaurant s p o n s o r e d   l i n k s 

 

This comfortable Wienerwald restaurant interior was completes this hang-out space. Actually, this place was not only can use as the common space for eat but also as a space for gathering with our family or friends. Today, the function of a food space was change. We will see the young generation love to spend their leisure time in restaurant space just for relax and enjoy their free time. There were also several officer or employee who use this place as the place for getting deal for their business. Through see those functions, these inspiring restaurant design plans were completed with the contemporary dining room and relaxed space for getting a conversation. The furniture plans have to combine with the interior plans so that thematic look will be perfect. This eco-friendly Wienerwald fast food chicken design was come from the color paint of the wall space (interior) and the supporting application of plants. Those natural restaurant inspirations can be seen in this green and clean bar lounge restaurant. [ Ippolito Fleitz ]

 

 
 
Photos Gallery: 
 
There are 6 pics in the Wienerwald Fast Food: Eco Friendly Restaurant Interior Design of this excellent Restaurant topic along with . Dont forget to checkout the entire 6 pics to not miss anything.
 Tags: green and clean lounge furniture plans fast food restaurant restaurant interior 
Post Related for Wienerwald Fast Food: Eco Friendly Restaurant Interior Design

 
 
 Elegant Black Restaurant Interior Pictures 
 
 Contemporary and Natural Interior Design Restaurant / Ubuntu by APPARATUS Architecture 
 
 Futuristic Restaurant Interior and Decoration Ideas 
 
 Contemporary L20 Restaurants Interior Design Inspiration 
 Share this post, let the world know:
 Tweet 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Subscribe to nabuzz

 RSS Twitter FB 
 
Category

 Apartment Bathroom Bedroom Coffee Tables Decorating Ideas Dining Room Fireplaces Flooring Furniture Garden Home Theater House Design How to&amp;Tips 

 Interiors Kids Kitchen Lighting Living room Luxury Design Modern Design Office Outdoor Design Restaurant Sofa&amp;Chairs Tables Uncategorized 
 
SPONSORED LINKS

 
 
Recent home design article

 
 Homey Artistic Contemporary Glass Coffee Table Designs with Vintage Plans 

 
It was the artistic contemporary wooden furniture that were be one of the most attractive and inviting for our home space [...] 
 Great Architectural of Concrete House Designs with Trendy Room Spacing 

 
This classic huge family room remodel was show the new identical landscaping from a home space that indicate the gathering [...] 
 How to Choose the Best Air Conditioner for Home 

 
These plain choosing personal AC ideas were presented for those who want to have the best air conditioner for their [...] 
 Best 2012 IKEA Kitchen Designs with Moderate and Remarkable Inspirations 

 
These entire 2012 IKEA kitchen inspirations were give us more inspiration and real kitchen sample for our home space. [...] 
 Remarkable Square Bathtub Designs with Low Design Ideas 

 
Again, here was the best bathroom furniture applications by Italian bathroom manufacturer Teuco, that will [...] 
 
Pictures Gallery


 modern furniture lighting fixtures bathroom furniture space saving kitchen modern house design italian furniture house furniture plans home appliance kitchen furniture bedroom furniture garden design ideas wooden furniture bathroom design ideas kitchen decorating ideas kitchen appliance home furnishing modern lighting modern bathroom Lovely designed by illuminatheme .
	</body>
</document>
