<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005952" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20081009102232AADNMUS" time="2012-07-12-22:38" support="4" score="0.007127609684520907" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Hourly pay rate for a cashier in canada...?" webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Hourly pay rate for a cashier in canada...?">
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>If you are here in Canada and got that salary at a fast food restaurant or ... If you have cashier experience you could get similar rates of pay at places ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Travel &gt; Canada &gt; Other - Canada &gt; Resolved Question 
 Bunty Member since: June 29, 2006 Total points: 24 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Hourly pay rate for a cashier in canada...?
 Hey guys.. I am from India..and recently got a job in Canada at Tim Hortons as a food staff/ attendant/cashier and they are paying me aout $11.75/ hour...also they asked me to sign a 2yr contract for that....
can anybody guide me...like will I save something, If i get this much salary and how much tax do we have to pay in canada..
please clear this doubts for me ...
Thanks 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by SteveN Member since: November 10, 2006 Total points: 52,826 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Are you already in Canada and applied for the job and were accepted at that salary? Or are you still in India and someone sent you an email saying that they are offering you a job at Tim Hortons for $11.75/hr?

If someone sent you an email offering a job, then beware as there are many scams out there and immigrants are being targeted for job offers, mainly from fake hotels in the past.

If you are here in Canada and got that salary at a fast food restaurant or coffee shop, you should be pleased. Most places like Tim Hortons will only pay the minimum wage salary for the province, probably around $7.50 to $9.00.

If Tim Hortons is not deducting your income taxes at source (in other words from your paycheck), then you will have to make sure that you put some money aside to pay income tax at end of the year. The income tax rates are listed below (see URL). You will also likely have deductions for employment insurance premiums, as well as Canada pension plan.

I&apos;m not sure I like the idea of signing a two-year contract. What did the contract state? That you will be in their exclusive employment for those two years? Or is it just that you can&apos;t go work for Dunkin Donuts in six months? But it is good pay for that type of workforce.

However, keep in mind that if you earn $12/hr in Calgary or Edmonton (Alberta), it may not be worth as much as making $10/hr in Moncton or Bathurst (New Brunswick). You still have to find a place to stay and pay your food, your utilities. If a small apartment in Calgary costs you $1000 a month, and the same apartment in Bathurst is only $550, you would have more take home pay that you are saving up in New Brunswick than in Alberta.

 
Source(s):
 http://www.cra-arc.gc.ca/tx/ndvdls/fq/tx… 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 3 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Hourly pay rate for … &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (3)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Amoeba Member since: October 03, 2008 Total points: 1,442 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Which province are you in?

I&apos;m surprised Tim Hortons pay that much, normally they pay only the min wage. I&apos;d say that in most provinces, a cashier would be paid at min wage (varies between $7.75 to $8.75), except in Western provinces where companies are forced to pay more due to labor shortages so in Alberta it&apos;d be like $12-13.

Regarding taxes, you have to pay 1.73% for EI and 4.95% for CPP (though there&apos;s a basic $67/week exemption for CPP). Federal income tax is 15% on income higher than about $9,600 (increasing to $10,100 next year), plus higher brackets uver $38k. Provincial income taxes vary by province. BC and Alberta have low taxes, so you don&apos;t pay any provincial taxes if you earn under $16,000. SK, MB, and the Maritimes have very high taxes. Ontario is in the middle. Quebec has the steepest progressive tax structure, you don&apos;t pay anything under $12,000 but after that the rates are by far the highest in Canada. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by freeside... Member since: July 07, 2006 Total points: 9,731 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Its not bad pay for a start up position as a cashier. You will make $470&quot;gross&quot;for a 40 hour week. As a single person (no dependants) they will deduct (Employment Insurance and Canada Pension Plan together about 5% of your wage. Income tax at that rate about another 8%) so on $470 you will&quot;net&quot;$408 a week give or take so clear about $1,800/month.
They
. You can survive on that as a single if you are splitting accomodations and food with other or family. You could manage on your own in basement suite or&quot;bachloer&quot;apartment living frugally./
Tim Hortons is very hard work as you are going all the time but some like that as it makes time go by. Here in Canada if someone has you sign a contract it just means you agree to work for two years at that salary without raises. But you are by no means obligated to work for Tim Hortons for 2 years. If you find something better in the meantime you are free to go elsewhere. Its nice if you give two weeks notice but a contract doesnt mean you have to work the whole term. (you may already know that but just in case).
If you have cashier experience you could get similar rates of pay at places like Zellers, Hudson Bay or food supermarkets. The unioned supermarkets like Dominion, Loblaws, Save on Foods pay better union wages up to $20/hr but they are tougher to find.

try http://www.monster.ca or http://www.workopolis.ca 

Good luck

 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Jim B Member since: June 15, 2008 Total points: 38,532 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 There is something WRONG with this picture.

The asker appears to be still in INDIA, so how can they be working at Tims ? Read the line about&quot;how much tax do we pay in Canada&quot;? If he /she is all ready working in Canada, that question would be answered on the first pay day, right ?


No one at Tims is on a contract . This is a SCAM .

Jim B. Toronto. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Canada 

 I want to go canada!!? Canadians, what do you call football (see details)? I had got a visit visa to Canada till 27th dec 2013 which is also my passport expiry date.? Where can i go on vaca? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Related Questions

 Working at Tim Hortons? What is special about Tim Horton&apos;s coffee? My co-workers… Do they have Starbucks of Tim Hortons in PEI? Is it possible to go a mile in canada without passing a… Do americans like tim hortons as much as canadians? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Travel 
 Canada 
 Calgary Edmonton Halifax Montreal Niagara Falls Other - Canada Ottawa Quebec St. John&apos;s Toronto Vancouver Victoria Winnipeg 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 Mortgage Rates 3.00%, 5 year variable rate ING DIRECT save your money INGDIRECT.ca 2012 Government Grants? Get A Grant Cheque in 30 Days. Never Repay. Do You Qualify? CanadianGovGrants.info/Rate Compare Cashier Salary Free July 2012 salary reports. Find Out What You Could be Paid! www.PayScale.com See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
