<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005470" url="http://www.greenecoservices.com/top-10-things-fast-food-restaurants-can-do-about-litter/" time="2012-07-12-22:02" support="17" score="0.04245942830790407" bingtitle="Top 10 Things Fast Food Restaurants Can Do About Litter | Green ..." webtitle="Top 10 Things Fast Food Restaurants Can Do About Litter | Green Eco Services">
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001037" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001235" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000641" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000129" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>The amount of trash that people throw out the window is incredible, it ... Believe me if you request a second napkin, you may or may not get one. It is only in the US ...</description>
	<body>
		Green Eco Services 

Your One Click Source For All Things Green
 
 HOME About Me Contact 
 
 Re-use- Make Money Recycle Litter-Trash-Garbage Building Eco Chic Environment Food and Drink Sports 
 You are here: Home / Walking Green / Top 10 Things Fast Food Restaurants Can Do About Litter 
Top 10 Things Fast Food Restaurants Can Do About Litter
 June 8, 2008 By Cathy 3 Comments 

 
 It is said that Fast Food wrappers make up about 33% of litter. I believe it! The amount of trash that people throw out the window is incredible, it is the #2 item that I pick up after cigarette butts. The average American eats fast food more than 150x per year 300 pounds of packaging waste are generated each year for each person. Take- out generates more that. 1.8 Million tons of packaging per year 

 TOP 10 Things Fast Food Places Can Do to Help the Environment 

1.) Join up with the closest school and offer‘internships’on helping them devise a litter program with the students.

2.) Get together with other‘ fast food restaurants ‘in their area, to promote recycling in the neighborhood.

3.) Put out Recycling Bins both inside and outside the restaurants and other places close by, especially in the strip centers.

4.) Promote with signage, PLEASE RECYCLE 

5.) Take the napkins and the plastic ware away and give with the order. When you go out of the country, you almost have to beg for a napkin or any eating utensils. Believe me if you request a second napkin, you may or may not get one. It is only in the US, these items are free for the taking.

6.) Do not leave out condiments on a table. When they are picking up the food, ask if they would like.

7.) Require Employees to do a daily trash pick up around restaurant.

8.) Only use Recyclable Containers and proudly announce it.

9.) Give seminars and lectures at your local schools on the benefits of recycling.

10.) Take part in cleaning up your litter, not only around the restaurant, but the neighborhood as well.

 What if Mr. Ed Eco had a Conversation with Frank Fast Food? 

Mr. Eco: Mr. Fast Food, as you know we have a problem with litter. It’s making our strip center look trashy, which is not good for either you or me. What do you think we could do about this? Quite honestly, even though I don’t live in this neighborhood, I’m a little tired of picking up people’s trash in my front yard as well.

Mr. Fast Food: Nothing, it’s not our problem, we pay too much rent already and the economy is slow, between the kids ripping me off, the coupons, paying the franchise fee, i gotta enuf to do and pay for. Plus, I never see any trash!

Mr. Eco: But what if, by spending a little time and effort and a few dollars we could garner good feelings and relationships with our neighbors, do you think we could increase business?

Mr. Fast Food: We already recycle in the back, and the inside is clean, what more do they want? Geez I can hardly get these kids to clean the bathrooms!

Mr. Eco: Let me ask you a question, how many condiments, napkins and plastic ware are wasted? How much do you think that costs you monthly? ( See Costs )

Mr. Fast Food: Hundreds of Dollars, it makes me sick to watch these people throw away 10- 20 napkins and the ketchup, mustard! They take handfuls of this stuff, and just throw it away.  Do you really think we could save? (see Blog) 

Mr. Eco: Mr Fast Food, I think if we invested in recycle bins both inside and out, quit putting out the all the utensils and condiments and make it a request upon the delivery of the food, with signage announcing what we are doing, we could more than make up the cost of the recycle bins and create good will.

Mr. Fast Food- That’s a thought! But it’s a hassle and the cost, I mean look at what they did in Santa Monica! Requiring containers to be recycled, what a rip-off!

Mr. Eco: I’m thinking that as the people get more and more educated about the effects of litter, we could be leaders in our community, set an example and did you know that 79% of consumers will support a company with a cause? The best part, not only would we save money, we could help save the environment as well. You know, we might have an easier time getting kids to come work for us, because they want to be with a clean and green company. We could save in the following ways:

1.) Get better and longer term employees, less training and advertising cost.

2.) Less wasted products

3.) Cleaner and safer environment.

4.) Excellent word of mouth advertising, (less cost in direct mail)

What do you think? Would you be willing to try it?

Resources:

Take Action: No More Refills 

 EPA Food Waste and Reduction Guide 

 How Fast Food Litter can Attract Rats 

 Oakland Trash 

 Fast Food Packaging Target 

Similar Posts:

 Trash Pickup May 31st. Morley Field Walking Green: Drink Litter Trash in Encinitas: June 2 Trash Pickup May 30th 


 
Costa Rica Eco-Tourism Filed Under: Walking Green Tagged With: Food and Drink , Pollution 
Comments

 Scot says: June 9, 2008 at 3:11 pm 
Thanks for the great tips and we really appreciate you mentioning our website–nofreerefills.org!
 INGAAS : says: October 28, 2010 at 4:36 am 
due to the busy schedules from work, most people would just prefer to eat on fastfoods ..
 Eating Disorder Treatment : says: October 31, 2010 at 10:42 pm 
fast foods are of course very popular these days because the price is cheap and there are lots of menu to choose from ..
 
 
Speak Your Mind Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
Subscribe to our RSS
 
Enter your email address:

 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
 

 
Tags
 Art AZ Building CA Clean and Non-Toxic CO Eco Chic Eco Office Eco Tourism Energy Environment Events Food and Drink Furniture GA Garden Gifts Green and Save Green Basics Green business Green Sports Health and Beauty Home IL Jobs Junk Mail KS MO NC NJ NM NY OH OR PA Pollution Recycle Reuse Sports Technology Transportation TX Used Building Materials WA Water 
Recent Posts

 Six Unusual Eco-Friendly Cars You Probably Didn’t Even Know Existed 21 Upcycled American Flags Upcycling Eyewear: Making Special Spex Books 100 Sites For Do It Yourselfers How Convenience Is Killing Our Planet 
 
Recent Comments

 Cathy on Top 11 Ways to Recycle and Reuse Baby Cribs James on Recycling Plastic Bottles And Trash Into Roofs Carol Shearin on Reclaimed Wood- Salvage- FSC Timber–Georgia Jeff Knapp on Reclaimed Wood Pallet Furniture shirlee lane on Reclaimed Wood- Salvage- FSC Timber- Indiana 
 
Friends

 Costa Rica Directory Optical Vision Resources The Optical Vision Site 
 
Green Directories

 Blog Catalog Environmental Total Blog Directory Green Blogosphere The Organic Home 
 
Resources

 Chasing Green Costa Rica Eco Business Eco Office Gals Eco Products That Work Ecotourism Holidays Everyday Trash For The Love Of Green Four Green Steps Get With Green Green Collar Economy Green Experience Greenhouse Environmental Management Leed Daily Opus Energy Reclaimed Home Recycling Retro Renovation VeruTEK – Going Green Technology Von Lowen Designs 
 
 Costa Rica Ecology 

 Cabo Blanco Park - Montezuma, Mal Pais Beaches - Costa Rica Mighty Rivers Eco-Farm, Costa Rica Caribbean Tours Varablanca - La Paz Waterfalls Gardens, Costa Rica Costa Rica Green Travel and Vacation Caribbean - Jungle Lodge - Parismina River Lagoon 
 
Categories

 Alabama (8) Alaska (5) Arizona (11) Arkansas (5) Art (28) Beauty (25) Building (97) Business (29) California (54) Clean and Non-Toxic (22) Colorado (9) Connecticut (6) Delaware (7) Eco Chic (86) Eco Tourism (25) Energy (31) Environment (54) Events (33) Family (15) Florida (8) Food and Drink (51) For Sale/ Wanted (21) Furniture (20) Gadgets (3) Garden/Landscaping (32) Georgia (13) Gifts (11) Glossary of Eco Words (3) Green and Save (21) Green Basics (15) Greening Your Office (23) Hawaii (9) Health and Beauty (37) Home Goods (15) Idaho (5) Illinois (10) Indiana (7) Iowa (9) Jobs (16) Junk Mail (20) Kansas (9) Kentucky (8) Litter-Trash-Garbage (106) Louisanna (8) Maine (6) Maryland (9) Massachusetts (7) Michigan (6) Minnesota (8) Mississippi (4) Missouri (8) Money (8) Montana (7) Music (1) Nebraska (7) Nevada (6) New Hampshire (4) New Jersey (12) New Mexico (12) New York (11) North Carolina (13) North Dakota (4) Ohio (11) Oklahoma (6) Oregon (10) Pennsylvania (11) Pet Peeves (3) Pollution (50) Re-use- Make Money (159) Recycle (106) Rhode Island (4) South Carolina (7) South Dakota (5) Sports (49) Suggested Reading (5) Technology (13) Tennessee (8) Texas (15) Transportation (31) Uncategorized (1) Utah (8) Vermont (5) Virginia (8) Walking Green (18) Washington (12) Washington DC (7) Wasted Water (34) West Virginia (5) Wisconsin (7) Wyoming (5) 
 
Pages

 About Me Contact 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (2) June 2012 (5) May 2012 (6) April 2012 (3) March 2012 (12) February 2012 (12) January 2012 (10) December 2011 (12) November 2011 (14) October 2011 (12) September 2011 (8) August 2011 (15) July 2011 (9) June 2011 (19) May 2011 (18) April 2011 (18) March 2011 (27) February 2011 (25) January 2011 (23) December 2010 (20) November 2010 (17) October 2010 (31) September 2010 (36) August 2010 (36) July 2010 (19) June 2010 (17) May 2010 (11) April 2010 (11) March 2010 (25) February 2010 (34) January 2010 (17) December 2009 (23) November 2009 (21) October 2009 (26) September 2009 (35) August 2009 (44) July 2009 (83) June 2009 (83) May 2009 (68) April 2009 (49) March 2009 (51) February 2009 (86) January 2009 (70) December 2008 (91) November 2008 (29) October 2008 (119) September 2008 (81) August 2008 (103) July 2008 (38) June 2008 (41) May 2008 (21) April 2008 (1) 
 Green and Save Eyewear 

 Are You Faxing Kidding Me? Optometrist Seeking CellPhone For Soldiers Ryo Yamashita Recycled Eyewear Smart Ways to Save Money by Making Your Business More Green 
 
 Natural Health For Eyes 

 100 Years Of Vitamins Eye and Neurological Disorders Related to Photophobia- Light Sensitivity New Report: Diabetic Eye Diseases Increasing Eat Right to Improve Your Eye Health
	</body>
</document>
