<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005807" url="http://www.nctimes.com/news/local/vista/article_7940fbd9-e545-53d1-b2d7-3fc6f0bfe864.html" time="2012-07-12-22:27" support="8" score="0.024006287209476417" bingtitle="VISTA: New Sonic carhops learn the ropes of serving, skating" webtitle="VISTA: New Sonic carhops learn the ropes of serving, skating : Local">
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001440" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000949" bing-rank="74"/>
	<description>Yvette Garcia laced up a pair of clean white roller ... on skates as they train to be carhops at the fast food restaurant ... Others practiced skating while carting trays of ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Subscriber Services Advertise Mobile Apps More 
 Contact Us 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 My Account 
 Edit Profile Logout 
 
 71° Hazy 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 83° 62° Saturday 75° 59° Sunday 74° 57° Monday 69° 55° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 
Topics

 Local SW Riverside County Business State Nation World Backpage Columnists Special Reports Weather Traffic Gas Prices Community News Calendar Events 
 
The Latest
 
 EAST COUNTY: Firefighters stopped a 2-acre grassland fire near the border 

EAST COUNTY ---- Firefighters stopped a 2-acre fire near Dulzura Thursday afternoon, according to the California Department of Forestry and Fi…
 
 GOOD HOPE: Three accused of possessing stolen weapons 

PERRIS ---- Three Long Beach men were arrested Tuesday in connection with possessing stolen weapons.
 
Recent

 ESCONDIDO: Noted philanthropist Jack Campbell dead at 69 TEMECULA: Burglary investigation leads to meth operation, four arrested OLYMPICS: Pepperdine track athlete making Olympics history for Saudi Arabia ESCONDIDO: Woodworking club to meet PERRIS: Missing woman located 
 
 Cities 
 
Topics

 Canyon Lake Carlsbad Del Mar Encinitas 
 
 Escondido Fallbrook Hemet Lake Elsinore Menifee 
 
 Murrieta Oceanside Poway Ramona Rancho Bernardo 
 
 San Marcos Solana Beach Temecula Valley Center Vista 
 
 Wildomar View all... 
 
 Sports 
 
Topics

 North County SW Riverside County NCT Varsity CAL Varsity Chargers Padres Olympics 
 
The Latest
 
 FOOTBALL: Seau&apos;s brain tissue released for study 

SAN DIEGO — Coroner&apos;s officials say Junior Seau&apos;s family has donated some of his brain tissue for research amid questions about whether damage…
 
 REGION: Junior Seau&apos;s brain tissue released for study, authorities say 

The county medical examiner&apos;s office has released football great Junior Seau&apos;s brain tissue to the National Institute of Health for studies to…
 
Recent

 COMMUNITY SPORTS: Camps and Clinics COMMUNITY SPORTS: Youth notices COMMUNITY SPORTS: Adult notices COMMUNITY SPORTS: Fundraisers PRO BASKETBALL: Budinger&apos;s career takes a turn with trade 
 
 Opinion 
 
Topics

 Blogs Cartoon Columnists Editorials Forum Letters to the Editor Perspective Submit a letter 
 
The Latest
 
 WALTERS: Big wheels keep on rollin&apos; 

OK, so the state Senate, by the narrowest of margins, has approved spending for an initial, 130-mile segment of the bullet train that Gov. Jer…
 
 BARONE: A muddled outlook for Olympics-ready London 

LONDON ---- The best view of Olympic Park is from the picture windows at the top floor of the John Lewis department store in the vast Westfiel…
 
Recent

 Jim Morin - 7/12/2012 Lisa Benson - 7/12/2012 HARROP: The worst financial scandal yet? RYAN: Teacher performance, does it count? EDITORIAL: Bankruptcy blues 
 
 Entertainment 
 
Topics

 Events Calendar Music Theater Movies Movie Listings Columnists Books Contests Games GO! TV Listings 
 
The Latest
 
 Shakespeare festival offers multilayered &apos;Merchant of Venice&apos; 

Shakespeare&apos;s plays, popular for their multi-dimensional characters embroiled in complex situations, are typically grouped into three categori…
 
 Carlsbad&apos;s public artists show their private side in new exhibit 

In the public art world, San Diego artist Paul Hobson is known for his monumental gates, like the black metal entryway to Carlsbad&apos;s Leo Carri…
 
Recent

 MOVIE FEATURE: Kitsch moves on from pair of flops to &apos;Savages&apos; Fox&apos;s Ed Henry goes with squares to add flair Rolling Stones celebrate 50 years on stage Chenoweth recovering after &apos;Good Wife&apos; accident 
 
 Crime 
 
Topics

 Courts Crime Map Arrest Log 
 
The Latest
 
 GOOD HOPE: Three accused of possessing stolen weapons 

PERRIS ---- Three Long Beach men were arrested Tuesday in connection with possessing stolen weapons.
 
 TEMECULA: Burglary investigation leads to meth operation, four arrested 

An investigation into a string of residential burglaries led Temecula officers to Menifee, where they uncovered a stash of stolen property and…
 
Recent

 ESCONDIDO: Sobriety, driver&apos;s license checkpoint planned Friday TRAFFIC: Wreck that blocked I-15 south car-pool lanes left one injured, authorities say ENCINITAS: Ponzi scheme mastermind starts federal prison sentence CRIME: Masked men spook armed guard, who fires gun CRIME: Encinitas man suspected driver in chase from Temecula 
 
 Topics 
 
Topics

 Business Education Faith and Values Food Health Home and Garden Military Sci-Tech Transportation Travel Photos 
 
The Latest
 
 Penn St. trustee: We&apos;re responsible for failures 

The chairwoman of Penn State&apos;s board of trustees says the panel &quot;accepts full responsibility for the failures that occurred&quot; in the Jerry Sand…
 
 APNewsBreak: Tube wear detailed at CA nuke plant 

Federal regulators Thursday disclosed the most detailed information to date on damage at California&apos;s idled San Onofre nuclear power plant, wh…
 
Recent

 Data firm: Global spending on drugs slows to 2016 Stone tools focus picture of ancient Americans Yahoo confirms theft of 450,000 users&apos; passwords NBC launches 2 apps to watch the Olympics Food briefs for July 12-18 
 
 Obits 
 Place an obituary 
 Classifieds 
 Place an Ad Buy/Sell stuff Pets Announcements Legal Notices Obituaries and Memorials Contact Us 
 Cars 
 Buy Sell Auto Directory Print Ads RVs, Boats, Motorcycles, etc. Virtual Auto Show Contact Us 
 Jobs 
 Find a Job Work For Us Post A Resume Contact Us 
 Real Estate 
 Place an Ad For Sale For Rent New Homes Agent Directory Print Ads 
 Get It! 
 
Topics

 Advertise with Us Business Directory Classifieds Coupons Marketplace Print Ads Special Sections Today&apos;s Deal 
 
Local Offers and Events
 
 See what Clients are Saying about us At La Costa Chiropractic! New Client Special! only $99. Includes consultation, exam&amp;X-Rays. Mention this offer when you call our Carlsbad office today (760) 438-9548 

&quot;I heard about La Costa Chiropractic&amp;Wellness from a co-worker and his wife who have been patients for a couple of years. I first came i…
 
 $145.00 NO CONTRACT PEST SERVICE - W.A. Stone Termite&amp;Pest Control 760/743-2847, 1-800-559-7999 

Pests covered: Ants, Spiders, Earwigs, Crickets, Wasps General pest
service up to 2500 sq ft. residential. 60 Day warranty.
All of our techni…
 
More local offers

 5,000 Mile Service $59.00 + Tax, call 760-480-0851 for an appointment or more information. Exp. 12/31/11 FREE - COMPLETE TERMITE INSPECTION - W.A. Stone Termite&amp;Pest Control 760/743-2847, 1-800-559-7999. New Year, New You - What you missed out on by not going to Botox Days with Dr. Moradi! $9.95/MO.-1st 3 Months. WATER SOFTENER RENTAL or Portable Exchange Tank Service. Escondido 800/752-3350. Your Local Appliance Experts, Great Prices, and Great Service! All Scratch&amp;Dent appliances are new with full factory warranty. In Vista, CA Call 760-724-8373 
 
 
 
 Hot Topics CALLAWAY LAYOFFS EMINENT DOMAIN CARLSBAD HILTON PROJECT IMMIGRANTS DETAINED HOME ALONE COUNTY SUED 
 
 Home / News / Local News 
 
VISTA: New Sonic carhops learn the ropes of serving, skating

Restaurant is set to open in Vista on Monday
 Print Email 2009-10-29T19:05:00Z VISTA: New Sonic carhops learn the ropes of serving, skating By CIGI ROSS - cross@nctimes.com North County Times October 29, 2009 7:05 pm  •  By CIGI ROSS - cross@nctimes.com (0) Comments × 
Related Photos
 « 
 
 » Sonic employees roll through the parking lot on skates as they train to be carhops at the fast food restaurant in Vista on Thursday. (Photo by Hayne Palmour IV - Staff Photographer) (6) More Photos 
Related Video
 × 
Training to be a Sonic Carhop
 
Hayne Palmour
 
New employees of Sonic, soon to open in Vista, learn how to serve fast food while on skates.
 
 Training to be a Sonic Carhop 
 
Yvette Garcia laced up a pair of clean white roller skates on
Thursday as part of a two-day training program for more than 30
carhops at the new Sonic Drive-In in Vista.

The 17-year-old said she&apos;s more accustomed to ice skates or
Rollerblades, but chose the white 4-wheelers for work at the
outdoor restaurant, which will open at 5:30 a.m. Monday at the
corner of South Santa Fe Avenue and Main Street.

&quot;For me it&apos;s a great first job,&quot; said Garcia, of Vista. &quot;It&apos;s
really exciting to be out here and around all these people.&quot;

Sonic restaurants are a throwback to 1950s drive-ins with no
indoor dining. Customers can congregate on patios or order via
car-side intercoms and roller-skating servers deliver their
food.

The Oklahoma-based chain has more than 3,500 locations
nationwide; the nearest Sonic locations are in Murrieta, Hemet and
Santee.

On Thursday afternoon, workers were still installing light
fixtures and painting the finishing touches at the restaurant while
employees wearing bright green, red and black shirts were learning
how to prepare signature items such as Tater Tots and Cherry
Limeades. Others practiced skating while carting trays of food or
directing traffic through the restaurants three staging areas.

Nicole Romero, who works at Sonic in Apple Valley northwest of
Los Angeles, helped train the Vista workers Thursday. She said not
all of the carhop hopefuls will make the cut.

&quot;We&apos;re going to make sure they can skate, brake, count change
and do it with a smile,&quot; Romero said. &quot;We have to pick out the ones
who can do it and have the attitude for it.&quot;

After carhops laced up their skates, which they must provide for
themselves, Romero told them they have three minutes and 33 seconds
to serve each drive-up stall.

&quot;Be fast, but be safe,&quot; she said.

Tim Shepard, a carhop in Santee, knows all about being safe on
skates. He was once hit by a customer driving through the Santee
restaurant&apos;s parking lot.

&quot;Watch out for cars,&quot; Shepard told the trainees. &quot;You will be
cutting across the drive-thru, so make sure you&apos;re aware of where
they are.&quot;

Nineteen-year-old Jackie Evans of Vista said she&apos;s one of about
20 local carhops who have been training at the Sonic in Santee
during the weeks leading to the opening of the new restaurant.

&quot;The job sounded so fun and there&apos;s nothing like this where
you&apos;re on skates,&quot; Evans said. &quot;It&apos;s hard, but once you get the
hang of it, it becomes like second nature.&quot;

Terron Yates, of Oceanside, heard about the carhop position at a
local job fair. Yates, 20, said he was an avid Rollerblader when he
was younger and is excited to find a job where he can be on
wheels.

&quot;You still get that sense of freedom,&quot; he said. &quot;It could be
difficult carrying trays with a lot of drinks, and (when we open)
the whole lot will be full. But I think my pockets should be good
from tips.&quot;

Contact staff writer Cigi Ross at 760-901-4067.
 
Tags
 Top , Coastal , Nct , News , Vista View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
Related Stories
 
 VISTA: City prepares for Sonic&apos;s traffic boom 
 
More Local News stories
 
 
 OCEANSIDE: Tri-City board to consider docking board member pay 
 
 VISTA: Vehicle crash briefly delays Sprinter service 
 
 VISTA: Hyatt sees opportunity in business park area 
 
 VISTA: Cooling it 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 North County Times. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Follow Us
 
Facebook
 
Like North County Times on Facebook
 
Twitter
 
Follow North County Times on Twitter
 Follow @nctimes 
Google+
 
+1 North County Times on Google+
 
Email
 
Get email updates from North County Times

 Email Updates 
 
Text Messaging
 
Get text message updates from North County Times

 Text Updates 
 
RSS
 
Follow North County Times via RSS

 RSS Feeds 
 
Gas Prices Map

 Lowest Vista Gas Prices 
 
About Vista

 City Hall 
200 Civic Center Drive., Vista, Ca. 92084; 760-726-1340 or 760-639-6132; e-mail: info@cityofvista.com

 Vista Sheriff&apos;s Station 
325 S. Melrose Drive, Suite. 210, Vista, CA 92081; Dispatch: 858-565-5200; Business: 760-940-4551

 Public Works 
760-639-6176

 Vista Fire Department 
760-643-2801 - Non-emergency; Station No. 2 - 1050 Valley Drive; Station No. 3 - 1070 Old Taylor St.; Station No. 4 - 2121 Thibodo Road; Station No. 5 (South Melrose Fire Station) 2009 S. Melrose Drive; Station No. 6 (Wildwood Fire Station) 651 E. Vista Way

 Vista employee salaries 

Connect with Us
 
 In the Newsroom 
 Coastal Editor: Melanie Marshall 760-901-4079, mmarshall@nctimes.com

 Vista Reporter: David Ogul 760-901-4067, dogul@nctimes.com

 Community News: 760-839-3300 commnews@nctimes.com
 
 Advertising 

 Coastal Retail Manager: Bill Williamson
760-740-3506, bwilliamson@nctimes.com
 
 Submit photo Submit an event Submit a video Register to comment Promote your business 
 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
Most Popular
 
 Articles Comments Facebook 
 
 1 FRENCH VALLEY: Record-setting helicopter pilot dies in Lake Skinner crash 2 CRIME: Amber, Chelsea&apos;s families &apos;deeply hurt&apos; by new book 3 TEMECULA: Toddler dies after being hit by truck 4 ESCONDIDO: Council ponders changes amid red-light camera losses 5 FALLBROOK: Agency sues man to collect $474K pension overpayment 
 
 1 LETTERS: NCT, July 10, 2012 (142) 2 LETTERS: NCT, July 9, 2012 (141) 3 LETTERS: NCT, July 6, 2012 (132) 4 LETTERS: NCT, July 5, 2012 (204) 5 LETTERS: NCT, July 11, 2012 (111) 
 
 Get It Offers 
 View more... 
 Scratch&amp;Dent Means Big Savings For YOU! Hundreds of models to chose from. All Scratch&amp;Dent appliances are new with full factory warranty. In Vista,CA Call 760-724-8373. 
 
 16 Reasons I&apos;m the Real Estate Agent for You! - Lorraine Best, Realtor in Temecula, CA 951-233-6334 
 
 Are You Planning A Bachelorette Party? 15% Off ALL Bachelorette Party Supplies At Deja Vu Love Boutique in Vista, CA Call (760) 598-5889 Today! 
 
 Do You Love to Golf in Carlsbad? Come Golf With Us and Help Us Celebrate Our Fifth Anniversary at The Crossings at Carlsbad, CA All July! 
 
 Featured Businesses 
 More... 
 Shake 10 Whole Body Vibration 
 
 Three Sisters Salon 
 
 Detour Salon&amp;Store 
 
Find a local business
 I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
Services

 Advertise with Us Subscriber Services Contact Us Mobile Site RSS 

More Websites

 Today&apos;s Deal Local Businesses Sell It San Diego Special Sections Local Coupons Parade 
 ©Copyright 2012, North County Times , 207 E. Pennsylvania Ave. Escondido, CA 92025 | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy | Find Area Businesses 
Find Area Businesses
 
 Escondido Apartments Escondido Attorneys Escondido Auto Dealers Escondido Auto Parts Escondido Auto Repair Escondido Beauty Salons Escondido Car Rental Escondido Dentists Escondido Doctors Escondido Flowers Escondido Hotels Escondido Insurance Escondido Loans Escondido Mortgages Escondido Movers Escondido Pizza Escondido Realtors Escondido Restaurants Escondido Storage Escondido Tax Preparation Escondido Travel More Escondido… San Marcos Apartments San Marcos Attorneys San Marcos Auto Dealers San Marcos Auto Parts San Marcos Auto Repair San Marcos Beauty Salons San Marcos Car Rental San Marcos Dentists San Marcos Doctors San Marcos Flowers San Marcos Hotels San Marcos Insurance San Marcos Loans San Marcos Mortgages San Marcos Movers San Marcos Pizza San Marcos Realtors San Marcos Restaurants San Marcos Storage San Marcos Tax Preparation San Marcos Travel More San Marcos… Vista Apartments Vista Attorneys Vista Auto Dealers Vista Auto Parts Vista Auto Repair Vista Beauty Salons Vista Car Rental Vista Dentists Vista Doctors Vista Flowers Vista Hotels Vista Insurance Vista Loans Vista Mortgages Vista Movers Vista Pizza Vista Realtors Vista Restaurants Vista Storage Vista Tax Preparation Vista Travel More Vista… Poway Apartments Poway Attorneys Poway Auto Dealers Poway Auto Parts Poway Auto Repair Poway Beauty Salons Poway Car Rental Poway Dentists Poway Doctors Poway Flowers Poway Hotels Poway Insurance Poway Loans Poway Mortgages Poway Movers Poway Pizza Poway Realtors Poway Restaurants Poway Storage Poway Tax Preparation Poway Travel More Poway… Carlsbad Apartments Carlsbad Attorneys Carlsbad Auto Dealers Carlsbad Auto Parts Carlsbad Auto Repair Carlsbad Beauty Salons Carlsbad Car Rental Carlsbad Dentists Carlsbad Doctors Carlsbad Flowers Carlsbad Hotels Carlsbad Insurance Carlsbad Loans Carlsbad Mortgages Carlsbad Movers Carlsbad Pizza Carlsbad Realtors Carlsbad Restaurants Carlsbad Storage Carlsbad Tax Preparation Carlsbad Travel More Carlsbad… Featured 
 × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Use your existing www.nctimes.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with www.nctimes.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
