<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005932" url="http://www.themeparkinsider.com/accidents/highlights3.cfm" time="2012-07-12-22:35" support="1" score="0.00038941204660628513" bingtitle="What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know - Theme Park Insider" webtitle="What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know">
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="143"/>
	<description>... park regulation bill that required parks to ... bus, driven my own car, swam in the ocean, stepped into a slippery tub, crossed the street, and eaten at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Park Reviews Hotel Reviews Travel Tips Tickets Discussion 

 Log In Register 
 
 
 Home &gt; Accident Watch &gt; Discussion Highlights 
 E-mail this page 
 The following comments reflect the views of their authors, and not necessarily those of Theme Park Insider or the other contributors on this page. 
 What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
Message posted by Robert Niles (via 163.192.21.17) on September 28, 2001 at 6:31 PM (ET)

Perhaps California theme parks won’t have to report injury accidents at their parks to the state after all. Thanks to some last-minute legal maneuvers from the industry, led by Disney, the state is close to approving rules that will require parks to report only accidents involving death or permanent disability.
The California legislature in 1999 passed a theme park regulation bill that required parks to report all accidents involving injury. Legislators finally acted after a Christmas Eve 1998 accident at Disneyland in which a man was killed, through no fault of his own , while waiting to board a boat ride at the park.
But in passing the law, the Legislature gave the theme park industry the loophole it’s now exploiting--by crafting a confusing standard for what accidents would have to be reported.
For those of you who care to read the legalese, here’s the sentence in question: &quot;Each operator of a permanent amusement ride shall report or cause to be reported to the division immediately by telephone each known accident where maintenance, operation, or use of the permanent amusement ride results in a death or serious injury to any person unless the injury does not require medical service other than ordinary first aid.&quot;
The trouble is that federal Occupational Safety&amp;Health Administration defines &quot;serious injury&quot; as &quot;any injury...which requires inpatient hospitalization for a period in excess of 24 hours for other than medical observation or in which [involves] a loss of any member of the body or suffers any serious degree of permanent disfigurement.&quot;
Industry lawyers contend that lawmakers intended to use that definition. But, obviously, that kind of injury is quite a bit more substantial than one that &quot;does not require medical service other than ordinary first aid.&quot;
First aid is just that, the *first* aid that a patient receives after an injury. If a paramedic has to be called to the scene, or if the patient is taken to a physician, that patient’s moved beyond &quot;first aid&quot; and is getting more serious treatment.
So there’s a gap between the types of injuries that the parks must report and those that they don’t need to under the law. And it’s a big gap--including things a reasonable person would consider serious, such as broken arms, sprained ankles, concussions and lacerations requiring stitches.
Disney’s lobbyists have convinced the state’s lawyers to ignore that gap. They’ve argued that &quot;ordinary first aid&quot; includes any treatment for any condition that doesn’t fit the OSHA definition of &quot;serious.&quot;
In other words, says the industry, if you break your arm when a roller coaster derails, the entire process from ride workers checking on you, to paramedics putting the arm in a splint, to your transport to a hospital, to X-rays and your arm being set by a physician is &quot;ordinary first aid.&quot;
Funny, I don’t seem to remember learning how to take X-rays, hook up IVs and set fractures when I earned my First Aid merit badge in Boy Scouts.
But that’s the definition Californians will have to live with, unless there is a last-minute change of heart in the Office of Administrative Law.
And that means that the state Division of Occupational Safety and Health will not be allowed to investigate perhaps hundreds of theme park accidents involving fractures, concussions and other injuries, because they won’t meet the definition of &quot;serious&quot; under the industry’s interpretation of the law.
Disney recently settled a lawsuit with a woman who suffered a brain aneurysm after riding Disneyland’s &quot;Indiana Jones Adventure&quot; rather than turn over a list of all accidents involving brain injuries at its parks that the judge in the case had demanded.
The industry’s zeal to avoid bad publicity by keeping its accidents secret threatens the public’s safety and health. Park visitors ought to have a right to know if people have been hurt on a particular ride. And if people have been hurt, the state should have a right to examine the ride, and if it find the ride unsafe, to shut it down.
That’s what California lawmakers intended to have happen when they passed this law in 1999. And that is what should be happening now. The Legislature needs to revise this law next session, and make its language so clear that not even Disney’s lawyers can twist it.
 You can help the public find out about the accidents that Disney and the theme park industry want to hide. Visit the Accident Watch pages here at Theme Park Insider . 
[Update: Oct. 31, 2001. It&apos;s official. The state has announced its regulations. And it&apos;s punted to the theme parks. The parks will get to decide what injuries they consider &quot;serious.&quot;]

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Robert Niles (via 165.121.116.236) on September 30, 2001 at 10:38 PM (ET) 
 

I wanted to clarify what information Disney does collect about accidents at its parks, based on my experience as a Disney attractions cast member several years ago.
Disney documents every minute of downtime on every attraction in its parks. And, it requires its employees to submit an accident incident report whenever they see a guest get hurt or ill on the premises. They will also file report if a guest reports an injury or illness.
If the guest is mobile and does not appear at risk for further injury, the cast member will escort that guest to first aid. Under no circumstances are guests simply to be told where first aid is and go there themselves.
But if a guest cannot easily get to First Aid on his or her own, or if the cast members present even suspect that the guest needs immediate attention or would be at additional risk if they tried to move themselves, an &quot;alpha unit&quot; is called. These are paramedics (in Florida, employed by Disney&apos;s Reedy Creek Improvement District) who respond to accidents or illnesses on property.
These are the kind of accidents that I believe the California Legislature intended Disney, and other theme park operators, to report. I cannot speak for other parks, since I have not worked for them, but I know that all of these accidents are recorded by Disney, and could easily be reported to the state within minutes of their occurance.


 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Bryan Fear (via 209.242.132.51) on October 2, 2001 at 3:13 AM (ET) 
 

When I was at Knotts a month ago and someone died, it prompted me to do some research on the internet about deaths in parks. ( What ultimately led me to this board. ) While I can&apos;t come close to the firsthand experience above, I did notice that well over 95% of the accidents were PREVENTABLE by the CUSTOMER! The park was not negligent in most cases. That blanket statement includes people who are just too da**ed fat to be on certain rides in the first place. The latest death at Knotts was also preventable, assuming a low-fat diet was followed or common sense was used about knowing one&apos;s limitations.

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Robert Niles (via 163.192.21.20) on October 2, 2001 at 1:28 PM (ET) 
 

All the more reason to publicize theme park accidents. If the public saw just how many of these incidents occur--and how many could be prevented--perhaps more people would do the right thing and be careful when they go to parks.
Not all accidents are the fault of the victim. (And certainly, little kids can&apos;t be expected to know how to behave if their parents don&apos;t tell them.) But there is so much that people can do to increase their chances of staying safe at a park. That&apos;s why I want people to know what&apos;s at stake, who&apos;s getting hurt, and what can be done to prevent additional injuries and deaths.


 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Anonymous (via 216.227.111.101) on October 18, 2001 at 4:00 PM (ET) 
 

The legislature, if passed, will be absurd! What idiot believes theme parks need to report every &quot;mis-fire&quot; on their mechanical rides ? It&apos;s a machine, people. It has flaws to some extent, and we all assume a risk when riding them. I don&apos;t think the theme parks need to be cluttering up their routines with having to report damages to those whom choose to partake in these rides. This reporting will only defer the parks&apos; ability to remain in the market. If they &quot;tattle&quot; on themselves, then poeple will stop attending the parks for fear they may get hurt, which will ultimately put them out of business. It is a negative publicity no company in the amusement industry needs... If you think you may be hurt, stay off of the damn ride !

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Bryan Fear (via 66.75.17.12) on October 18, 2001 at 8:56 PM (ET) 
 

THANK YOU! Glad to see someone else sees it like this. While I admit people have a right to know certain things, these rides ARE machines. You have to be as careful around them as around cars, electrical appliances, and every other hazard in life. I just find it ridiculous that a park should have to know an individuals tolerances on a ride. There&apos;s no way they can tell how one guy&apos;s artery-clogged body will endure a ride better than some guy who is in good shape. People who feel that rides should post the amount of fatalities and injuries on a given ride should also have to post the IQ of each person injured and their physical condition. I find that many peolpe sho suffered internal injuries ( annuerysm, heart-attack, etc. ) were all in poor physical condition and should never have gotten on the ride. ( Not &quot;fat&quot; necessarily, just in bad physical condition. ) I&apos;ve known plenty of people who appear &quot;not fat&quot; to have worse heart conditions than many heavyset people. You have GOT to KNOW your own body and tolerances. And if not, don&apos;t be surprised when the grim reaper greets you at the ride&apos;s exit.

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Tim Hillman (via 198.26.123.38) on October 22, 2001 at 11:56 AM (ET) 
 

Why all of the hard emotions about this issue? The right to information about things that can affect our well being is an accepted standard in our society. When you pick up a prescription, you can get a sheet listing the common side effects of the drug. Why? Because you know your body better than your doctor. Whenever you buy paint or solvents or any other chemicals, you have a right to be furnished a Material Safety Data Sheet. Why? Because you know how you plan to use it. Why not provide the same opportunity on amusement park rides?
I don&apos;t see the drawbacks to having national legislation to track accidents on thrill rides. Parks would benefit because their insurance rates would go down (at least for the responsible parks) and they wouldn&apos;t get sued as often. Bad operators and bad rides would be identified and hopefully removed. Enthusiasts would also be rewarded with better, safer, and more thrilling rides. Everybody wins.
One thing that I have learned over the years is to gather information before I make a decision. If I have no information on which to base my decision, how can I make an intelligent choice?
Now, those of us who are feeling morally superior to the fat people who ride rides they shouldn&apos;t, need to remember this. They trusted the ride designer and the ride operator to protect them. How many times have you willingly placed yourself in the same position?

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Bryan Fear (via 66.75.17.12) on October 29, 2001 at 2:48 AM (ET) 
 

Those rides are NOT churned out of a mad scientist&apos;s labratory where he giggles in glee at the thought of children getting mutilated. They are made by companies with investors and insurance companies to report to. The company has a responsibility to make a product that does not kill. Each ride is rigorously tested before it is offered for sale. Their income and livlihood depends on making non-lethal rides. For this reason, I find it hard to think that any ride manufacturer chooses to cut corners and make an unsafe ride for the sake of cost-effectiveness. A theme park ride is safer than most things NASA has sent into space.
So, the question is &quot;How many times have you willingly placed yourself in the same position?&quot; Every time I have ridden on an airplane, gotten on a bus, driven my own car, swam in the ocean, stepped into a slippery tub, crossed the street, and eaten at a fast food restaurant. Life is like pointing a loaded gun at your head and hoping that a combination of minimal safety checks and blind luck will keep you alive.
Life is NOT a Volvo with 6 airbags moving 15mph in the slow-lane of the freeway, nor would I ever want to see it reduced to that. Like the last poster said, just use your head and it won&apos;t be a problem. If you have any doubts about your health, don&apos;t ride.


 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Jason Herrera (via 205.188.192.182) on November 2, 2001 at 4:12 AM (ET) 
 

Let me come in with my point of view... First off the question needs to be asked, &quot;Why Does Disney Hide so much?&quot;
You&apos;ll find most of the time from my companies reserach, that Disney is to blame for most of the mishaps inside of the park.. The focus is usually directed in the wrong direction... Everyone get&apos;s involved with the &quot;big,&quot; accidents, but the little accidents, which I like to call, &quot;Downplayers,&quot; are the key accidents that need to be focused on more... While at Disneyland on January, 28th 2001 I witnessed 5 downplayers within a matter of 120 minutes (2 hours) and this is from one attraction! Downplayers are the type of accidents which get Disney into trouble, because they are so poorly treated by Disneyland staff... Take this injury for instance.. We had a 20-25 year old male slip on a puddle of water about 20 yards infront of us, he was limping around in some pain, asked a castmember for some ice, Castmember told him straight out to walk to first aid, and this is at Big Thunder mountain... for all of you, who&apos;ve been to Disneyland, that is one heck of a walk, not add to that a sprained ankle.... Not a wise decision on Disney&apos;s part... Can&apos;t blame the castmember he was doing what he was told to do... Sprained ankle could have been a Fractured ankle or even possibly a sublexed calcaneous... walking to first aid tears a ligament even worse... BOOM! Lawsuit.. so now do you people see why Disney has so much to hide??
I ask that if any of you posters have a question, please feel free to leave me an e-mail, and I&apos;ll get back to you ASAP! Thank you....

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Joe Lane (via 168.191.70.27) on November 4, 2001 at 8:18 PM (ET) 
 

As with many other subjects, ride safety is one that has its own fine line. We&apos;re dealing with a topic that raises questions on a person&apos;s right to information and the park&apos;s right to be a &quot;successful business&quot;, that is, if withholding honest information that could possibly save lives and hurt a park&apos;s profit margins could be considered deterants to &quot;successful business&quot;.
By now, most park&apos;s do (and should) post information on adverse effects of a ride, much like a prescribed drug. It is a person&apos;s responsiblity to read these warnings and follow all rules--that alone would lower injuries dramatically. My opinion on accident reports is that the information should at least be available to those who seek it--and hoop-jumping should not be necessary to retrive such information. Likewise, these reports should not be constantly waved in our face like an O.J. Simpson or Elian Gonzales incident.
There are a lot of stupid people in this world, that do stupid things and get themselves hurt. There are a lot of untruthful people in this world, who do unhonest things for their own personal benefit. Sometimes, due to unforseen circumstances, accidents just happen! And everyday, we must face that risk, that something out of anyone&apos;s sphere of influence may go wrong, or that we may run into one of those stupid, untruthful people that can hurt themselves, others, or us. That can&apos;t be helped: get over it.
Finally, as much as Disney tries to be an honest business, I sincerely doubt that everyone in the Disney Corp. is open and honest about what goes on. In a way, they MAY (may, mind you) be making profits at the blatent disregard for the safety of others, and, I&apos;m sorry if you disagree with me, but if this is the case for Disney or ANY theme park, then this is just plain wrong.
Okay, I&apos;m done ranting--hope I haven&apos;t offended anyone in my above opinion.

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Anonymous (via 204.216.176.135) on November 6, 2001 at 2:08 PM (ET) 
 

What would be the point in riding a ride or roller coaster that does not represent a real threat? I mean the whole idea used to be the rush you got from riding a dangerous ride which you survived.
All of you who swear to be die hard Theme Park enthusiasts sound like a bunch of wimps. What the rest of the world thinks about our United States seems to be holding true. They say that we, here in America, are raising a bunch of (and excuse me here but this is what they say) pussies. And, for all pertinent reasons, I believe this to be true.
The whole, we have to protect people form themeselves attitute has hurt this country a great deal. Remember that although this attitude has raised a less violent society it has also soften us up. There&apos;s a downside to everything. Since we do not have really horrible problems like the rest of the world does, We focus on and complain about the stupidest things.
Yes, I realize that some of the deaths on rides could have possibly been avoided but so could so many other deaths that we don&apos;t even pay attention to.
How many people have died on theme park rides in the past 10 years? About 20? Yet thousands of Americans perish in the freeway every year. Why don&apos;t you complain about that and stop driving?
Thousands more a year get murdered by repeat offenders that should have been in jail doing hard labor but no, they&apos;re in there watching cable T.V. and getting out in 3 years just to go out and do it again. And why? Because of people like you who are soft and think 20 years in the tank with hard labor for a convicted rapist is to harsh a punishment. Let&apos;s just give him 5 years and let him out in three with good behavior. And yes, please feed him turkey in Thanks Giving. Treat him well, because he has to be healthy enough to go out and do it again.
And there&apos;s the whole Firestone thing. Are you kidding me? Yes, Firestone is completely at fault for those deaths and should pay or even should get closed down. But yet people continue to buy there products. Why? That&apos;s like someone abusing your kid one day and then continue to take your kid to that person on subsequent days. We do this because we are a soft society who complains and yells but does not take real action. We can bitch all day but don&apos;t have the b*&amp;^%lls to act.
Bottom line, Theme park rides are not what this society has to be focused on as far as safety is concerned because we have much more serious issues that hurt so many other people. And, we, as a society, have to be less sensitive to this whole thing. Our society has to really grow some big brass B*&amp;^%$@lls!!!

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Jason Herrera (via 152.163.197.188) on November 6, 2001 at 4:15 PM (ET) 
 

It&apos;s kinda comical on how amusement park accidents have been a major focus here in the united states... but now some people want to blow them off... well from research conducted in 2000 by my company we found this; in one amusement park for one day, we counted 95 injuries... Now there is something wrong there... Not to mention this was considered a, &quot;slow day!!&quot;
So there is cause for major concern... these injuries need to be addressed and taken care of properly, or the amusement park industry will continue to get burnt...

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Robert Swinarski Jr (via 63.173.250.239) on November 6, 2001 at 5:02 PM (ET) 
 

Historically speaking, how many people were killed by amusement park rides in the early 20th century parks at places like Coney Island and other, less reputable, &quot;amusement parks&quot;?
I&apos;m sure that the number was MUCH higher than today (in a percentage standpoint at least- there are millions of more people going to these parks than there were then). So in defense of the parks, serious saftey standerds have been put in place and are keeping our rides safe.
However, every time there is a new faster, meaner, stronger ride, there is the potential for a worse and worse injury. Are we so naive to think that the amusement parks created these saftey standerds entirely on their own and by their free will? No, it was due to the action of the (dare I say it) Federal and State governments responding to huge numbers of reports of accidents, deaths and injuries. I&apos;m sure that many unscrupulous theme park owners in that early day and age would agree with so many of the postings on this thread: &quot;we don&apos;t need to worry, we just need to go to XYZ park and pay to ride!&quot;
If society wants to maintain the level of security and safety that we believe we have at theme parks, watchdogs need to be aware of what is happening and where it is happening to be able to say &quot;hey! There are an awful lot of problems coming from this park! We need to let them know that we won&apos;t go until these needs are addressed!&quot;
If we don&apos;t do that and stick our head in the sand, then we don&apos;t deserve to have that level of saftey we want. Activism is not being &quot;anti&quot; anything. It is ensuring that the things we love and like will maintain that status in our lives. If you don&apos;t care about XYZ park, you won&apos;t want to see if there were any accidents there. However, if you love it and enjoy that place, you will want to know everything that you can about the place you spend your time at. I don&apos;t think that Disney or anyone needs to surpress that type of information.

 Re: What Disney Doesn&apos;t Want You to Know 
 Message posted by Joe Lane (via 168.191.68.134) on November 6, 2001 at 10:50 PM (ET) 
 

Correct me if I&apos;m wrong, but the majority of the time, when an accident happens on the road or even at work, somebody has to file a accident report. These reports are placed on file and are avaliable to those who seek the information from them.
So what do theme parks gain from not filing accident reports? They can concentrate more on providing quality service at their parks. Biggest bunch of bull I&apos;ve ever heard. This is political and money matters, and because they&apos;re a multi-million dollar company, it seems like they&apos;re using their resources and bad business practices to avoid losing money and attendance.
We&apos;re not asking the parks to advertise the safety record of their rides, just keep a report on hand so that those people interested can pursue the information.
Is that too much to ask?
One more thing: Americans are not &quot;pussies&quot;, we just have the &quot;uncommon&quot; sense to recognize when something can be a threat to our well-bring.

 
Search Theme Park Insider
 
News, Video and Live Updates
 
Reader Reviews, by Theme Park

United States Top 10 * 

 Walt Disney World&apos;s Magic Kingdom Disneyland Epcot Disney&apos;s Animal Kingdom Disney&apos;s Hollywood Studios Disney California Adventure Universal&apos;s Islands of Adventure Universal Studios Florida SeaWorld Orlando Universal Studios Hollywood * By 2010 attendance 

International parks

 Disneyland Paris Hong Kong Disneyland Tokyo Disneyland Tokyo DisneySea Universal Studios Japan Universal Studios Singapore 

Readers&apos; Top Themed Rides

 Harry Potter and the Forbidden Journey The Amazing Adventures of Spider-Man Twilight Zone Tower of Terror Splash Mountain Haunted Mansion 

Top Roller Coasters

 Millennium Force Manta Apollo&apos;s Chariot The Voyage Behemoth 

Top Live Shows

 Fantasmic! Festival of the Lion King IllumiNations: Reflections of Earth World of Color Fantasmic! 

Top Movies/Animated Shows

 Impressions de France Mickey&apos;s PhilharMagic Despicable Me: Minion Mayhem Walt Disney: One Man&apos;s Dream Soarin&apos; Over California 

Theme Park Reviews, Features, Advice

 Stories from a Theme Park Insider Theme Park Insider Awards How to get the best deals on tickets Which Walt Disney World ticket should I buy? How to stay safe when visiting theme parks What&apos;s under construction for 2012? 

Theme Park News Archive

2012
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. 

2011
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Dec. 

2010
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Dec. 

2009
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Dec. 

2008
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Dec. 

2007
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Dec. 

2006
 Jan. Feb. Mar. Apr. May Jun. Jul. Aug. Sep. Oct. Nov. Dec. 

2005
 Dec. 

2004-2005
 Staff column archive 
 
 
©1999-2011 Robert Niles .
&quot;Theme Park Insider&quot;®is a registered trademark of Robert Niles.
 About Theme Park Insider - Rules for Writing and Rating - Privacy Policy - Contact the Editor
	</body>
</document>
