<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005878" url="http://encycl.opentopia.com/F/FA/FAR" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="6" score="0.0022037358604355935" bingtitle="Encyclopedia entries starting with FAR - Who or What is ..." webtitle="Encyclopedia entries starting with FAR - Who or What is Encyclopedia entries starting with FAR? Find out more">
			<query id="001325" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000322" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000759" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000509" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>Fara is the name of a number of places: Fara ... appear on liquids enclosed by a vibrating receptacle. ... Farmer Boys is a fast food restaurant chain in the Southern ...</description>
	<body>
		Encyclopedia 
 Encyclopedia: FAR...
 
 Encyclopedia : F : FA : FAR (1830 articles)
 

 F.A.R.T. the Movie 
 F.A.R.T. the Movie, created in 1991, is about a man named Russell who has an obsession with farting. His girlfriend Heather despises farts and become angry with Russell because all he does is watch television and fart. She tells him that if the television turns into fart jokes, then Russell won&apos;t ev.. 
 F.A. Ridley 
 Francis Ambrose Ridley, usually known as Frank Ridley (22 February, 1897–27 March, 1994) was a marxist and secularist of the United Kingdom. Contents 1 Life2 Political activities3 Secularist activities4 Publications5 Bibliography Life Ridley was educated at Sed.. 
 Far 
 Far may refer to: The Far East, or South and Southeast AsiaThe Russian Far East* Far Eastern Republic* Far Eastern Federal DistrictFAR Manager, a Win32 Norton Commander cloneFAR Rabat, a Moroccan football clubFar infrared astronomyFar Ultraviolet Spectroscopic Explorer, a space-based telescopeFar .. 
 Far&apos;Falastin 
 Far&apos;Falastin is a notorious Syrian prison located near Damascus. The United States used a process called extraordinary rendition to transport a number of terrorist suspects to Far&apos;Falastin where they were subjected to interrogation that included torture. In addition, the participation of German off.. 
 Far, Far Away 
 Far, Far Away is a song by the band Wilco, from their album Being There. .. 
 Far-field radiation pattern 
 To meet Wikipedia&apos;s and make it more accessible to a general audience, this article may require[Cleanupcleanup].The introduction to this article provides insufficient context for those unfamiliar with the subject matter.Please help Wikipedia by improving the introduction according to th.. 
 Far-red 
 Far-red light is light at the extreme red end of the visible spectrum, between red and infra-red light. Usually regarded as the region between 700 and 800 nm wavelength, it is dimly visible to some eyes. It is reflected or transmitted by plants because of the absorbance spectrum of chlorophyll, and .. 
 Far-western blotting 
 Far-western blotting (occasionally west-western blotting) is a variation of Western blotting used to identify interactions among proteins. In many ways the processes are similar, but whereas Western blotting uses an antibody as the probe, far-western blotting uses another protein. Methods In conven.. 
 Fara 
 Fara is the name of a number of places: Fara, Orkney, an island in ScotlandFara, a village in the District of Safad, destroyed in the 1948 Arab-Israeli WarFara, a Département of Burkina Faso This article consisting of geographical locations is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page, a li.. 
 Fara&apos;id al-Simtayn 
 Part of the series on Hadith collections[v]·[d]·[e]Most famous Sunni six major collections (Al-Kutub al-Sittah): Sahih Bukhari Sahih MuslimSunan al-SughraSunan Abi Da&apos;udSunan al-TirmidhiSunan Ibn Maja/Al-Muwatta Shi&apos;a collections: Nahj al-.. 
 Fara, Orkney 
 Fara is a small island in Orkney, Scotland, lying between Flotta and Hoy. It has been uninhabited since the 1960s. Fara should not be confused with the island of Faray near Eday. External links Grid reference .. 
 Farabeuf 
 Farabeuf, Louis Hubert (1841-1910), French surgeon who is said to have introduced hygiene in French medical schools. His statue dominates the central court of the National School of Medicine in Paris and the main amphitheater of it is also named after him. Farabeuf wrote some short chirurgical bookl.. 
 Farabundo Martí 
 --&gt; Agustín Farabundo Martí (born May 5, 1893, Teotepeque – died February 1, 1932) was a revolutionary in El Salvador. Early on, he worked with Nicaraguan revolutionary leader Augusto César Sandino, although they broke over political disagreements. Farabundo Marti, a communist, led with t.. 
 Farabundo Martí National Liberation Front 
 The Farabundo Martí National Liberation Front (in Spanish: Frente Farabundo Martí para la Liberación Nacional, FMLN) is a revolutionary and socialist political party in El Salvador. The FMLN was formed as an umbrella group of five revolutionary Marxist organizations in El Salvador in 1980, with.. 
 Farad 
 Two electrolytic capacitors. The one on top is axial and rated for 1000µF and the one on the bottom is radial and rated for 10µF. The farad (symbol: F) is the SI unit of capacitance. Definition A capacitor has a value of one farad when one coulomb of stored charge causes a potential differen.. 
 Farad&apos;n 
 Farad&apos;n is a fictional character in the Dune universe created by Frank Herbert. Farad&apos;n is a major character in the science fiction novel Children of Dune by Frank Herbert.[Spoiler warningSpoiler warning]: Plot and/or ending details follow. Farad&apos;n is given the name Harq al-Ada by Empe.. 
 Faraday 
 For other uses, see (disambiguation)}}}. In physics, the faraday (not to be confused with the farad) is a unit of electrical charge; one faraday is equal to the charge of 6.02×1023 electrons (one mole). The faraday is no longer in general use and has been replaced by the SI unit coulomb; o.. 
 Faraday&apos;s law 
 Faraday&apos;s law can mean: Faraday&apos;s law of induction (electromagnetic fields)Faraday&apos;s law of electrolysis This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same title. If an referred you to this page, you may wish to change the link to point directly to.. 
 Faraday&apos;s law of electrolysis 
 Faraday&apos;s law of electrolysis states that: The mass of a substance produced at an electrode during electrolysis is proportional to the number of moles of electrons (the quantity of electricity) transferred at that electrodeThe number of Faradays of electric charge required to discharge one mole o.. 
 Faraday&apos;s law of induction 
 Faraday&apos;s law of induction (more generally, the law of electromagnetic induction) states that a magnetic field changing in time creates a proportional electromotive force. The relation between the rate of change of the magnetic flux through the surface S enclosed by a contour C and the electric fi.. 
 Faraday, West Virginia 
 Faraday is an unincorporated community in McDowell County, West Virginia, USA. It lies just north of the border with Tazewell County, Virginia on County Route 9. External links .. 
 Faraday (crater) 
 Crater characteristics Coordinates .. 
 Faraday (disambiguation) 
 Faraday may refer to: Michael Faraday, a British scientist (a physicist and chemist)faraday, a unit of electrical charge named after the scientist See also faradFaraday cage This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same title. If an referred y.. 
 Faraday cage 
 A Faraday cage is an enclosure designed to exclude electromagnetic fields. It is an application of Gauss&apos;s law, one of Maxwell&apos;s equations. Gauss&apos;s law describes the distribution of electrical charge on a conducting form, such as a sphere, a plane, a torus, etc. Intuitively, since like charges r.. 
 Faraday constant 
 In physics and chemistry, the Faraday constant is the amount of electric charge in one mole of electrons. The Faraday constant was named after British scientist Michael Faraday. It is used in electrolytic system calculations to determine the mass of a chemical species that will collect at an electro.. 
 Faraday cup 
 A faraday cup is a metal (conductive) cup meant to recatch secondary particles. (See Black body (details)). When a beam or packet of ions hits the metal it will be charged while the ions are neutralized. The metal can then be discharged to measure a small current equivalent to the number of discharg.. 
 Faraday cup electrometer 
 The Faraday cup electrometer is the simplest form of an electrical aerosol instrument used in aerosol studies. It consists of an electrometer and a filter inside a Faraday cage. Charged particles collected by the filter generate an electric current which is measured by the electrometer. According .. 
 Faraday Discussions 
 Faraday Discussions is a scientific journal covering the papers presented at a long-running series of chemistry conferences which are also called Faraday Discussions. The journal was originally published by the Faraday Society. Since that society merged with the Chemical Society (founded in 1841).. 
 Faraday effect 
 In physics, the Faraday effect or Faraday rotation is a magneto-optical phenomenon, or an interaction between light and a magnetic field. The rotation of the plane of polarization is proportional to the intensity of the component of the magnetic field in the direction of the beam of light. The Fara.. 
 Faraday Flashlight 
 The Faraday Flashlight (formerly known as the EverLife Flashlight) is an electronic flashlight heavily marketed via direct marketing campaigns beginning in 2002. Unlike conventional flashlights, the Faraday Flashlight does not use conventional batteries, instead relying on a capcitor and charging m.. 
 Faraday isolator 
 A Faraday isolator or optical isolator is an optical component which allows the transmission of polarised light in only one direction. They are typically used to prevent unwanted feedback into an optical oscillator (A laser cavity is a good example.) The operation of the device depends on the Farad.. 
 Faraday paradox 
 This article describes the Faraday paradox in electromagnetism. There is a different Faraday paradox in electrochemistry: see Faraday paradox (electrochemistry). The Faraday paradox (or Faraday&apos;s paradox) is an experiment that illustrates the limitations of Michael Faraday&apos;s law of electromagnetic.. 
 Faraday paradox (electrochemistry) 
 The Faraday paradox was a once inexplicable aspect of the reaction between nitric acid and steel. Around 1830, the English scientist Michael Faraday found that dilute nitric acid would attack steel, but concentrated nitric acid would not. The attempt to explain this discovery led to advances in el.. 
 Faraday rotator 
 Polarization mechanism due to the Faraday effect A Faraday rotator is an optical device that rotates the polarization of light due to the Faraday effect, which in turn is based on a magneto-optic effect. The Faraday rotator works because one polarization of the input light is in ferromagnetic.. 
 Faraday School kidnapping 
 The Faraday School kidnapping occurred on 6 October 1972 at a one-teacher school in the village of Faraday in Victoria, Australia. Edwin John Eastwood and Robert Boland entered the school armed with a shotgun at about 3:00pm and forced the teacher Mary Gibbs and all six pupils (aged 5 to 11) who we.. 
 Faraday Society 
 The Faraday Society was a British society for the study of physical chemistry, founded in 1903 and named in honour of Michael Faraday. It published Faraday Transactions from 1905 to 1971, when the Royal Society of Chemistry took over the publication. Of particular note were the conferences called F.. 
 Faraday Transactions 
 Faraday Transactions was a scientific journal originally published by the Faraday Society in 1905. That society merged with other Societies in 1980 to form the Royal Society of Chemistry. From 1972, when merger negotiations commenced, it was published by the Royal Society of Chemistry as the Jour.. 
 Faraday wave 
 Faraday waves are nonlinear standing waves that appear on liquids enclosed by a vibrating receptacle. They are named after Michael Faraday, who first described them in an appendix to an article in the Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London in 1831. If a layer of liquid is placed .. 
 Faradian Islam 
 Faradian Islam is an African American social and religious movement based on the teachings of W.D. Fard, Elijah Muhammad, the Nation of Islam, and the Nation of Gods and Earths. The term comes from the pronunciation of Fard, which is fuh-RAHD. External links[Nation of Islam official Web site.. 
 Faradina Mohd. Nadzir 
 Faradina Mohd. Nadzir (known to her fans as Dina) was the runner up for the first season of Malaysian Idol. She only discovered her singing voice at the age of 16. A very down to earth girl from Johor Bahru, she&apos;s best known for her rock chick hand signs. During her audition, she came in style bei.. 
 Farafangana 
 Farafangana is a town on the south-east coast of Madagascar approximately 400 kilometres south of the capital Antananarivo. The Roman Catholic Diocese of Farafangana is based in the town, led by Bishop Benjamin Marc Ramaroson. .. 
 Farafenni 
 Farafenni is a town in The Gambia, lying on the Trans-Gambia Highway just south of the border with Senegal. It is an important market town. .. 
 Farafra, Egypt 
 The Farafra Oasis (Arabic: ا???ة) is a big oasis located in Western Egypt near latitude 27.06° North and longitude 27.97° East. It is located in the Libyan Desert near Dakhla and Bahariya. Farafra has 4,000 inhabitants in its single village and is mostly inhabited by Bedouins. Located near Far.. 
 Farag Foda 
 Dr. Farag Foda (فرج فوده, 1946 - 8 June 1992) was an important Egyptian thinker, human rights activist, writer, and columnist. Based in Cairo, he was noted for his critical articles and sharp satires about Islamic fundamentalism in Egypt. In many newspaper articles, he demonstrated weak po.. 
 Farah 
 Farah (فرح )is the name of a number of people and places. It means &apos;joy&apos; in Arabic. People: Joseph Farah (journalist)Mohamed Farrah Aidid (1934–1996), Somali politicianFarah Pahlavi (b.1938), née Dibah, the last Empress of IranNuruddin Farah (b.1945), Somali novelistFarrah Fawcett (b.1947), A.. 
 Farah, Afghanistan 
 Farah is both a city and a province in western Afghanistan. The Farah River runs through it. Geographically the province is approximately 18,000 square miles, making it (comparatively) more than twice the size of Maryland, or half the size of South Korea. The province is bounded on the north by H.. 
 Farahani 
 Farahani is a common family name in Iran. It may refer to: Musicians Agha Ali Akbar Farahani, musician and tar-playerAgha Mirza Abdollah Farahani, musician and setar-playerAgha Mirza Hossein Gholi Farahani, musician and tar-player Politicians Gha&apos;em-Magham FarahaniMajid Farahani Actors Behzad Fa.. 
 Farahnaz Pahlavi 
 Farahnaz Pahlavi (born March 12, 1963) is a daughter of Shah Mohammad Reza Pahlavi of Iran and his third wife Farah Diba. She is the eldest daughter between Mohammad Reza Pahlavi&apos;s two daughters. Education&amp;Work She studied at the Niavaran Special School in Tehran and at the Cairo American College.. 
 Farah City District 
 Farah City District is a district in Farah Province, Afghanistan, containing the main city of Farah. Its population, which is 85% Pashtun and 10% Tajik, along with other ethnic groups, was estimated at 159,310 in September 2004. References[UNHCR District Profile], compiled August–.. 
 Farah Damji 
 Farah Damji is the publisher and editor of the lifestyle magazine Another Generation for the Indian diaspora of the United Kingdom. The magazine was formerly known as Indobrit, but the name was changed due to a legal dispute with another founder partner. She is the daughter of property tycoon Amir.. 
 Farah Fath 
 Farah Fath (born May 1, 1984 in Lexington, Kentucky) is an American television actress. She has played the role of Miriam Elizabeth &quot;Mimi&quot; Lockhart on the NBC soap opera Days of Our Lives since 1999. She is the third actress to have played the role, but the only one to have been on contract. Trivia.. 
 Farah islam 
 This does not cite its [[Opentopia:Citing sources|references or sources]]. You can [[Opentopia:WikiProject Fact and Reference Check|help]] Wikipedia by introducing appropriate citations. Farah Islam is a socialite who has gained fame for reportedly having affairs with top military men of Pakistan .. 
 Farah Khan 
 Farah Khan is an Indian film director although she is better known for her choreographical work. She choreographed for the film Jo Jeeta Wohi Sikander, this was followed by many more dance hits. She met actor, Shah Rukh Khan on the sets of Kabhi Haa Kabhi Naa, they have been friends ever since. .. 
 Farah Noor Adams 
 Farah Noor Adams (c. 1971–October 7, 2005) was a Scottish woman who was murdered in Glasgow in 2005. She was a part-time youth worker, aged 34, a Muslim, separated from her husband, bringing up a daughter aged eight. She was murdered while exercising on a footpath beside the River Kelvin in .. 
 Farah Pahlavi 
 Farah Diba-Pahlavi Farah Diba, as she appeared during the visit of US president Richard Nixon to Iran on May 30, 1972. The Empress of Iran, Farah Pahlavi (born October 14, 1938 in Tehran, Iran) (born as Farah Diba) was the third wife of Mohammad Reza Pahlavi of Iran and the last (and onl.. 
 Farah Province 
 Farah (فراه) is one of the thirty-four provinces of Afghanistan. It is in the west of the country. Its capital is Farah. The people of Farah have a reputation for being very courageous and hard working and being interested in land and money, the latter mainly due to the deprivation Farah has.. 
 Farah River 
 The Farah River is a river in western Afghanistan. The river originates in the Band-e Bayan Range and flows for 560 km to the Helmand swamps on the Afghanistan-Iran border. The town of Farah is located on the river. .. 
 Faraid Head 
 Faraid Head is a small peninsula on the northern coast of Sutherland, Highland, Scotland, located two miles to the north of the village Balnakeil and three miles north of Durness. At the point is located a small radar station built in the 1950&apos;s to house a ROTOR radar system to provide radar cover.. 
 Faraizi movement 
 The Faraizi movement was founded by Haji Shariatullah by Bengali Muslims. After returning from Mecca (hence the title Haji) after a 20 year hiatus Shariatullah, seeing the degraded Muslims of Bengal, called on them to give up un-Islamic practices and act upon their duties as Muslims (Faraiz). The m.. 
 Farai Chideya 
 Farai Chideya, a political journalist and radio host, has contributed articles for national publications and commentary for television news. See these two references for biographical material and photographs: (1) http://www.strongbat.com/farai.html (2)http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?.. 
 Faraj ben Salim 
 Faraj ben-Sālim, Moses Farachi of Dirgent, Ferrarius, Franchinus was a Sicilian-Jewish physician and translator; flourished in the second half of the thirteenth century. He was engaged by Charles IV, Duke of Anjou as translator of medical works from Arabic into Latin. In this capacity he rendered.. 
 Faraj Said Bin Ghanem 
 Faraj Said Bin Ghanem (Arabic: فرج سعيد بن غانم) (b. 1937) was the Prime Minister of Yemen from 14 May 1997 to 29 April 1998. |- style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot; .. 
 Farakhpur 
 Farakhpur is a census town in Yamunanagar district in the state of Haryana, India. Demographics As of 2001 India census[Geographic references#IndiaGRIndia], Farakhpur had a population of 8738. Males constitute 54% of the population and females 46%. Farakhpur has an average literacy rate.. 
 Faraklata 
 FaraklataΦαρακλάτα Map Map not yetavailable --&gt; Statistics Prefecture: Kefalonia Province: Kranoi Municipality: Argostoli Municipal district: Faraklata (seat) Elevation: -lowest: -centre: -highest: western part (about 200 m)Argostoli Gulf281 meastern .. 
 Farallah 
 Farallah is a fictional character appearing in the Marvel Comics universe. He is a powerful mystical entity (possibly a demon), and a member of the Octessence. External Link[Farallah at DrStrange.nl].. 
 Farallon de Medinilla 
 Farallon de Medinilla is the eleventh independent island in the Northern Mariana Islands chain situated 45 miles north of Saipan. It is the second smallest in the chain, only Zealandia Bank is smaller. It is an uninhabited coral island which is approximately 1/2 square mile in area. Its highest elev.. 
 Farallon de Pajaros 
 Farallon de Pajaros Elevation: 360 meters (1,181 feet) Coordinates: Archipelago  Geography  Politics  Economy  Campaign .. 
 Farallon Islands 
 Farallon Islands, with border of Farallon Islands National Wildlife Refuge The Farallon Islands are a group of islands and rocks found in the Gulf of the Farallones, off the coast of mainland San Francisco, California. They lie 27 miles (43 km) outside the Golden Gate, 20 miles (32 km) south .. 
 Farallon Plate 
 The Farallon Plate was an ancient, wholly oceanic tectonic plate, which began subducting under the west coast of the North American Plate—then located in modern Utah—as Pangaea broke apart during the Jurassic period. Over time the central part of the Farallon Plate completely subducted.. 
 Farallon Steamship Disaster 
 The Farallon Steamship Disaster was the disaster of a wooden steamship that hit Black Reef in Cook Inlet and sank in Alaska in January 1910. Everyone on board evacuated to a near-by island and had to survive for a month in a mid-winter climate before they were rescued. Steve K. Lloyd wrote a book .. 
 Faramans 
 Faramans is the name of two commune in France: Faramans, in the Ain départementFaramans, in the Isère département This article consisting of geographical locations is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page, a list of pages that otherwise might share the same title. If an referred you h.. 
 Faramans, Ain 
 Faramans Country     France Région Rhône-Alpes Départment Ain Arrondissement Bourg-en-Bresse Canton Meximieux INSEE 01000 Postal Code 01800 MayorCurrent Term ?2001-2007 Intercommunality Longitude Latitude Altitudes .. 
 Faramarz Gharibian 
 Faramarz Gharibian (in Persian: فرامرز قریبیان), Actor and Director, Born November 17, 1941, Tehran, Iran. Learning film acting in the School of Visual Arts, US (1971), he started his career with a short role in &apos;Come Stranger&apos; (1968, Masoud Kimiay). His first professional debut was Soi.. 
 Faramir 
 This article is about Faramir, son of Denethor. For information about the Hobbit, see Faramir Took. External links[Faramir]at The Thain&apos;s Book[There He Came]- A Faramir tribute and fansite Preceded by:Denethor II Stewards of Gondor Followed by:Princes of Ithilien .. 
 Faramir Took 
 In the literary works of J. R. R. Tolkien, Faramir Took, later Thain Faramir I is the eldest son of Thain Peregrin I. Born in the year 1430 of the Shire Reckoning, he married Goldilocks, the third daughter of Samwise Gamgee (one of the Ring Bearers and Faramir&apos;s father&apos;s old friend). Faramir became .. 
 Faramondo 
 Faramondo (&apos;Pharamond&apos;) (HWV 39) is an opera in three acts by George Frideric Handel to an Italian text adapted from Apostolo Zeno&apos;s Faramondo&apos;. Contents 1 Performance history2 Roles3 Synopsis4 Sources Performance history It was first performed at the King&apos;s Theatre, London .. 
 Faran 
 Faran is &quot;a great roan horse,&quot; the mount of Sparhawk in the Elenium and the Tamuli series&apos; of books by David Eddings. He is famous for his bad temper, but this may not be his entirely his fault. In one of the later books the child-goddess Aphrael tells Sparhawk that Faran only has a bad temper becau.. 
 Faranah 
 Faranah is a town in central Guinea, lying by the River Niger. Sekou Touré was born in what was then a village, and after becoming president developed it with a mosque, palace and conference centre. It lies immediately south west of the Haut Niger National Park. .. 
 Faranah Prefecture 
 Faranah is a prefecture located in the Faranah Region of Guinea. The capital is Faranah. The prefecture covers an area of 13,000 km.² and has an estimated population of 167,000. Prefectures of Guinea Boké Region: Boffa | Boké | Fria | Gaoual | Koundara Conakry Region: Conakry Farana.. 
 Faranah Region 
 The Faranah Region is located in east-central Guinea. It is bordered by the countries of Sierra Leone and Mali and the Guinean regions of Kankan, Mamou, Nzérékoré, and Labé. Regions of Guinea Boké | Conakry | Faranah | Kankan | Kindia | Labé | Mamou | Nzérékoré .. 
 Farancia 
 Farancia is a genus of colubrid snakes. It consists of two species, one commonly referred to as the rainbow snake and the other commonly referred to as mud snake. They are native to the eastern half of the United States. Contents 1 Description2 Behaviour3 Species4 References.. 
 Farancia abacura 
 The Mud Snake (Farancia abacura) is a species of non-venomous, semi-aquatic, colubrid snake that is found in the southeastern United States. Contents 1 Description2 Behavior3 Geographic range4 Subspecies5 Myths6 References Description Mud Snakes grow to an average.. 
 Farandole 
 For the 1945 film, see Farandole. The farandole is an open-chain community dance popular in the County of Nice, France. Believed to derive from the medieval branle, it bears similarities to the gavotte, jig, and tarantella. The carmagnole of the French Revolution is a derivative. Traditionally led.. 
 Farang 
 Farang (in Thai: ฝรั่ง), sometimes pronounced falang, is the generic Thai word for a white foreigner. It is closely related to the Khmer word Barang. Africans or African-Americans will be occasionally referred to as farang dam (black farang, in Thai: ฝรั่งดำ). While gener.. 
 Farangi 
 Farangi A term for foreigners in Persian, possibly linked to the Franks. The word in Arabic is similar and the word Farangi also appears in Urdu and Hindi in reference to foreigners. It can have a derogatory connotation. Of trivial interest is the fact that in French Polynesia the word for a white .. 
 Faraquet 
 Faraquet was a rock band from Washington D.C. sometimes placed in the math rock genre. They were formerly on Dischord Records. Personnel Devin Ocampo: vocals, guitar, drums/percussion, keyboards, banja, baritone guitar, trumpet.Chad Molter: drums/percussion, vocals, piccolo bassJeff Boswell: bass,.. 
 Faras 
 Faras, known in ancient times as Pachoras, was a major city in Lower Nubia in modern Egypt. The site of the city was flooded by Lake Nasser in the 1960s, and is now permanently underwater. Before this flooding, extensive archeological work was conducted by a Polish archeological team. Dating back t.. 
 Farasan 
 Farasan may refer to: Farasan Islands - archipelago in the Red SeaFarasan Island - largest island of the archipelagoFarasan - largest city of the archipelago This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same title. If an referred you to this page,.. 
 Farasan (city) 
 Farasan (Arabic: فرسان) is the largest town of the Farasan Islands, in the Red Sea. Islands are a part of the Jizan Province, far southwestern part of Saudi Arabia. It is located on the Farasan Island at around[16°42′8″N, 42°7′6″E]. External links[Photo of Farasan Is.. 
 Farasan Island 
 Farasan Island (Arabic: جزيرة فرسان; transliterated: Jazyrat Farasan) is the largest island of the Farasan Islands, in the Red Sea. It is located some 50 km offshore from Jizan, far southwestern part of Saudi Arabia. It is located at around[16°42′21″N, 41°59′0″E]. Th.. 
 Farasan Islands 
 Farasan Islands (Arabic: جزر فرسان; transliterated: Juzur Farasan) is a large coral island group in the Red Sea, belonging to Saudi Arabia. It is located some 40 km offshore from Jizan, far southwestern part of country. It is located at around[16°46′21″N, 41°58′0″E]. It .. 
 Faravahar 
 Faravahar, believed to be a depiction of a Fravashi. The Faravahar in the Seal of Darius I The Faravahar (Avestan) or Farohar (middle Persian) is one of the best known symbols of the Zoroastrian religion. What the figure symbolizes is disputed. While it is currently thought to repres.. 
 Faravid 
 Faravid is one of the Kings of Cwenland and Finland according to Norse sagas. Faravid allied with the Norwegian king to beat invading Karelians, and made two successive war trips on them. Faravid is also a name of Finnish magazine of northern Finnish historians. .. 
 Faraway, So Close! 
 Faraway, So Close! is the English title of In weiter Ferne, so nah!, a 1993 film by German director Wim Wenders, written by him, Richard Reitinger and Ulrich Zieger. It is a sequel to Der Himmel über Berlin (Wings of Desire) with which it shared lead actors Otto Sander and Bruno Ganz. The film won .. 
 Faraway Hill 
 Faraway Hill was the first soap opera broadcast on an American television network, running on the DuMont Television Network from October 2, 1946 to December 18, 1946. David P. Lewis, the writer and director, had a budget of around $300 an episode. For many years A Woman to Remember was considered th.. 
 Faraway Places 
 The Faraway Places is an indie rock band. Originally formed in Boston, Massachusetts as Solar Saturday, they changed their name after moving to Los Angeles, California. Members Chris Colthart - guitar, vocalsDonna Coppola - keyboard, vocalsJeff Wright - bassScott Barber - bassChris Phillips - drums.. 
 Faraway Rainbow 
 This article concernsa Noon Universe novel byBoris and Arkady Strugatsky [[Noon: 22nd Century]] An Attempt to Escape Faraway Rainbow Hard to Be a God Disquiet Inhabited Island The Little One A Guy from Purgatory Beetle in an Anthill The Time Wanderers Faraway Rainbow (Д.. 
 Faray 
 Faray is a small island in Orkney, Scotland, lying between Eday and Westray. The low-lying island was inhabited until the 1930s and is now home to an important grey seal colony. Faray should not be confused with the island of Fara, near Hoy. .. 
 Faraya Mzaar Kfardebian 
 Faraya Mzaar Kfardebian or Faraya-Mzaar, also known as Ouyoune el Simaan or Aayoun Al Simane, is the most prominent ski area in Lebanon. The area has around 40 downhill pistes (trails) and 16 main lifts, 13 of them chairlifts, and skiing ranges between heights of 1310m at (Faraya), 1850m (Ouyoune e.. 
 Faraz Anwar 
 Faraz Anwar (born 15th July, 1976) is a Pakistani Progressive Metal guitarist known for his solo instrumental work and his band Mizraab. Contents 1 Biography2 Session Playing3 Own Projects/Bands4 Discography4.1 Abstract Point Of View (2001)4.2 Untitled (Internet Rel.. 
 Faraz Bhatti 
 Faraz Bhatti is a Liberal Democrat politician in the City of Manchester. He is a councillor in the Whalley Range ward. He stood for election to the Stretford and Urmston constituency in the 2005 General Election. External links[Faraz Bhatti PPC]profile at the site of Liberal Democrats&amp;.. 
 Faraz Rabbani 
 Shaykh Faraz Rabbani, is a scholar and researcher of Islamic law and translator of several Arabic works to the English language. A student and teacher of the mainstream Hanafi school of Islamic law, Rabbani is of Pakistani-Canadian background, graduating from the University of Toronto with a degree .. 
 FARA 83 
 FARA 83 Specifications Cartridge: 5.56 x 45 mm System of operation: gas piston, rotating bolt Length (stock extended): 1000 mm (39.37 in) Length (stock folded): 745 mm (29.33 in) Weight: 3.95 kg (8lb 11oz) Barrel: 452 mm (17.8 in) Rifling: 6 grooves, right hand twist Magazin.. 
 Fara Filiorum Petri 
 Fara Filliorum Petri is a comune and town in the Province of Chieti in the Abruzzo region of Italy Abruzzo·Communes of the province of Chieti Altino | Archi | Ari | Arielli | Atessa | Bomba | Borrello | Bucchianico | Canosa Sannita | Carpineto Sinello | Carunchio | Casacanditella | .. 
 Fara intoarcere 
 To meet Wikipedia&apos;s and make it more accessible to a general audience, this article may require[Cleanupcleanup].The introduction to this article provides insufficient context for those unfamiliar with the subject matter.Please help Wikipedia by improving the introduction according to the.. 
 Fara San Martino 
 Fara San Martino is a comune and town in the Province of Chieti in the Abruzzo region of Italy Abruzzo·Communes of the province of Chieti Altino | Archi | Ari | Arielli | Atessa | Bomba | Borrello | Bucchianico | Canosa Sannita | Carpineto Sinello | Carunchio | Casacanditella | Casa.. 
 Farbelism 
 Farbelism is a term used to describe the repetitive formula of color study unique to artist[David Scott Moyer]. Coined in 1992 with input from an admirer of his work during the[Scottsdale Celebration of Fine Art]who said, &quot;I love how you put those little farbels on there!&quot; L.. 
 Farber, Missouri 
 Farber is a city in Audrain County, Missouri, United States. The population was 411 at the 2000 census. Geography Farber is located at[39°16′29″N, 91°34′31″W](39.274844, -91.575362)[Geographic references#1GR1]. According to the United States Census Bureau, the cit.. 
 Farber disease 
 Farber disease (also known as Farber’s lipogranulomatosis or ceramidase deficiency) describes a group of rare autosomal recessive disorders that cause an accumulation of fatty material in the joints, tissues and central nervous system. The disorder affects both males and females. Disease onset is.. 
 Farboud 
 Farboud Sports Cars is an exotic UK car manufacturer that was formed in 2004. It is under the ownership of Chris Marsh, a car producer and designer. Farboud is currently finalising production of the Farboud GTS as of Summer 2006. The marque of the company is a yellow bow and arrow taken from the cha.. 
 Farbrausch 
 Farbrausch is a German group of demomakers which made themselves especially famous in the demoscene in December 2000 with a 64kb intro called &quot;fr-08: .the .product&quot;. Using techniques like procedural textures, scenes and animations together with a high-quality software synthesizer, &quot;.the .product&quot; i.. 
 Farb (onomastics) 
 Onomastics and disambiguatonal informations about thre words and last names that forms Farb-, Farbe-, Farber, -farb# On onomastics in Judaism, there are many variants: Farb, Farband, Farber, Farbman, Farbmann, Goldfarb, Gottfarb, etc. Contents 1 Farb2 .. 
 FARC-EP Chain of Command 
 Note, this article is under construction. Feel free to add any relevant information, see the discussion page for details or ideas. The FARC military leadership is divided as follows, for details of each section, see the detailed descriptions below: 1) The Central High Command (Estado Mayor Centra.. 
 FARC-EP Eastern Block 
 The FARC-EP&apos;s Eastern Block is considered by many to be the strongest military faction of the guerrilla group. It is divided into groups of 50-400 combatants which help patrol and control different areas of Colombia&apos;s Eastern and Central-Eastern territory. The specific divisions of the group are a.. 
 Farcaster 
 In the Hyperion universe, a farcaster is a type of teleporter. The farcaster was an invention of the TechnoCore, the race of artificial intelligences that branched off from humanity to pursue its own ends circa 2100-2200. Operating on the premise that a singularity can punch holes through time in sp.. 
 Farce 
 A farce is a comedy written for the stage, or a film, which aims to entertain the audience by means of unlikely and extravagant - yet often possible - situations, disguise and mistaken identity, verbal humour of varying degrees of sophistication, which may include puns and sexual innuendo, and a fas.. 
 Farcet 
 Farcet–in Huntingdonshire (now part of Cambridgeshire), England–is a village north east of Yaxley. .. 
 Farce of the Penguins 
 .. 
 Farciennes 
 Farciennes is a municipality located in the Belgian province of Hainaut. On January 1 2005 Farciennes had a total population of 11,122. The total area is 10.39 km² which gives a population density of 1,070.93 inhabitants per km². It is located on the entre-Sambre-et-Meuse in the periphery of Char.. 
 Farcry 
 Farcry may mean: Far Cry the videogameFarcry CMS This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same title. If an referred you to this page, you may wish to change the link to point directly to the intended article. .. 
 Farcry CMS 
 Farcry is an open-source, enterprise-level Content Management System(CMS) built on ColdFusion. External Links[Farcry CMS website].. 
 FARC Military Strategy in 2005 
 In early 2005, the Fuerzas Armadas Revolucionarias de Colombia – Ejército del Pueblo (&quot;Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia – People&apos;s Army&quot;, or FARC-EP), launched what has been interpreted as their active response to Colombian president Alvaro Uribe&apos;s security strategy and to the military.. 
 Fard 
 Fard also farida (فرض &quot;obligation, duty&quot;) is an Islamic Arabic term which denotes a religious duty. The word is also used in Urdu and Hindi (spelled farz) in the same meaning (i.e. ye mera farz hai). fard or its synonym wajib is one of the five qualifications (al-ahkam al-khamsa) into which Fiqh.. 
 Fardalen 
 Fardalen is a valley stretching west from Øvre Årdal in the minicipality of Årdal. The highest located road in Norway has its path throug the valley, reaches more than 1 400 meters above see close to the famous mountain Store Skagstølstind and ends up in Fortun. .. 
 Farda Fardão Camisola de Dormir 
 Farda Fardão Camisola de Dormir is a Brazilian Modernist novel. It was written by Jorge Amado in 1979. .. 
 Fardeen Khan 
 Fardeen Khan (born 8 March 1974) is a popular Indian actor. His father, Feroz Khan, was a popular actor in the 70&apos;s. Contents 1 Biography2 Personal life3 Filmography4 External links Biography The son of famed actor/director Feroz Khan. While he was born and brought up in In.. 
 Fardella 
 Fardella may refer to: An Italian city, the Fardella (commune).Vincenzo Fardella di Torrearsa, President of the Italian Senate, (1870 - 1874)Philosopher Michelangelo Fardella, (1646-1718) This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same title. If.. 
 Fardella (commune) 
 Fardella is a town and comune in the province of Potenza, in the Southern Italian region of Basilicata. Basilicata·Communes of the province of Potenza Abriola | Acerenza | Albano di Lucania | Anzi | Armento | Atella | Avigliano | Balvano | Banzi | Baragiano | Barile | Bella | B.. 
 Fardella crime family 
 The factual accuracy of this article is[Accuracy disputedisputed]. Please see the relevant discussion on the[.. 
 Farden Township, Minnesota 
 Farden Township is a township in Hubbard County, Minnesota, United States. The population was 994 at the 2000 census. Geography According to the United States Census Bureau, the township has a total area of 93.7 km² (36.2 mi²). 87.2 km² (33.7 mi²) of it is land and 6.5 km² (2.5 mi²) of it (6.. 
 Farder Coram 
 Farder Coram is a very old, wise Gyptian in the trilogy His Dark Materials, by Philip Pullman. His advice is always important for John Faa, the Gyptian king. Farder Coram is arguably the second - in - command of the boatloving nation.[Spoiler warningSpoiler warning]: Plot and/or ending d.. 
 Fardingbag 
 This page is a candidate to be [[meta:Transwiki|moved]] to Wiktionary. If the page can be[How to edit a pagere-written]to be[Wikipedia is not a dictionarymore than a dictionary entry], please do so and remove this message. Before you move this content to Wiktionary, please ve.. 
 Fardon v Attorney-General (Qld) 
 Fardon v Attorney-General (Qld) (2004) 210 CLR 50 was a case decided in the High Court of Australia regarding the separation of powers. Contents 1 Background2 Decision3 See also4 References5 External links Background Queensland passed legislation regarding sex offender.. 
 Fardunjee Marzban 
 Fardunjee Marzban or Fardoonjee Marazban (1787-1847), printer and newspaper editor, founded the first vernacular newspaper on the Indian subcontinent. Fardun came from a family of Parsi-Zoroastrian priests, perhaps of Surat or Navsari in Gujarat, and initially trained for the priesthood. His father.. 
 Fard (land records, India) 
 Fard, the term used in India, for a copy of agricultural land ownership record as kept in Tehsil. To meet Wikipedia&apos;s and make it more accessible to a general audience, this article may require[Cleanupcleanup].The introduction to this article provides insufficient context for those unfam.. 
 Fare 
 A fare is the fee paid by a traveller allowing him or her to make use of a public transport system: rail, bus, taxi, etc. In the case of air transport, the term airfare is often used. The fare paid is a contribution to the operational costs of the transport system involved, either partial (as is fr.. 
 FarEasTone 
 FarEasTone is a GSM/WCDMA mobile phone operator in Taiwan. Far EasTone was awarded two wireless (GSM 900 and GSM 1800) service licenses in January 1997. Far EasTone launched its service and the first fully integrated dual-band system in the world in January 1998 to provide high-quality GSM services.. 
 Farebox recovery ratio 
 The farebox recovery ratio of a passenger transportation system is the proportion of the amount of revenue generated through fares by its paying customers as a fraction of the cost of its total operating expenses. Most systems aren&apos;t self-supporting, so advertising revenue and government subsidies .. 
 Farecast.com 
 Farecast is a novel site that tries to predict how airline prices will change so consumers can get the cheapest rate. Currently it is in beta, although a June 1, 2006 New York Times article said the site would include most major cities by the end of the year. External links http://www.farecast.com.. 
 Fareed Haque 
 Fareed Haque (b. 1963) is a fusion guitar virtuoso of Pakistani and Chilean descent. He is renowned for balancing classical and jazz styles his jam band collaborations including, but not limited to, ones with Paquito D&apos;Rivera, Dave Holland, Sting, Joe Henderson, Lester Bowie, Arturo Sandoval, Rober.. 
 Fareed Zakaria 
 Fareed Zakaria Fareed Zakaria (born January 20 1964) is a writer and journalist specializing in international relations. He writes a regular column for Newsweek, which also appears in Newsweek International and often in The Washington Post. He was named editor of Newsweek International in Oc.. 
 Fareena Alam 
 Fareena Alam (born 1978 in London) is Editor of Q News, a leading British Muslim Magazine. Fareena is of Bangladeshi Chittagonian parentage and she grew up in Singapore. During this time she was elected as the president of the United Nations Students&apos; Association, National University of Singapore,.. 
 Fareham 
 Arms of Fareham Borough Council The market town of Fareham lies in the south east of Hampshire, between the cities of Southampton and Portsmouth, roughly in the centre of the South Hampshire conurbation. It gives its name to the borough comprising the town and the surrounding area. To the so.. 
 Fareham (borough) 
 Borough of Fareham Shown within Hampshire Geography Status: Borough Region: South East England Admin. County: Hampshire Area:- Total Ranked 275th74.24 km²Admin. HQ: Fareham ONS code: 24UE Demographics Population:- Total ()- Density .. 
 Fareham (constituency) 
 Fareham County constituency Fareham shown within Hampshire, and Hampshire shown within England Created: 1885, 1974 MP: Mark Hoban Party: Conservative Type: House of Commons County: Hampshire EP constituency: South East England Fareham is a constituency represented in the House of.. 
 Fareham railway station 
 Fareham railway station is a railway station in the town of Fareham in Hampshire History Fareham station was first opened by the LSWR in 1841 on the line from Eastleigh to Gosport. Later additions connected Fareham station with Southampton, Portsmouth and along the coast towards Brighton. Ther.. 
 Fareham Red 
 Fareham Red Bricks - famous red tinged clay bricks, from Fareham, Hampshire. The most notable building constructed of these distinctive bricks is London&apos;s Royal Albert Hall .. 
 Fareham Town F.C. 
 Fareham Town F.C. is a football club based in Fareham, England. They have reached the 1st round proper of the FA Cup four times in their history. For the 2006-07 season, they are members of the Wessex League Premier Division. |- !colspan=&quot;3&quot; style=&quot;background:#ccf; text-align:center;&quot;|Wessex Lea.. 
 Fareinigte Partizaner Organizacje 
 The Fareinigte Partizaner Organizacje (United Partisan Organization; referred to as FPO by its Yiddish initials) was a Jewish resistance organization that took part in the Wilno (Vilna) ghetto uprising during World War II. The partisan organisation was established by Zionist partisans - their leader.. 
 Fareless Square 
 Fareless Square is an area within Portland, Oregon where all TriMet bus and MAX, as well as Portland Streetcar transit rides are free. Prior to May 1, 2005, rides within the area on C-TRAN&apos;s express routes were also free. This free transportation area is similar to Seattle&apos;s Ride Free Area (served.. 
 Farel Dalrymple 
 Farel Dalrymple is a US artist and alternative comics creator. He is best know for his award-winning comics series Pop Gun War. Overview One of the founders of the New York City-based Meathaus Collective, Farel Dalrymple has received several awards, including a Xeric Foundation grant, a 2002 Socie.. 
 Farepak 
 Farepak has been operating since 1981 at a site in Swindon, Wiltshire, England. It employs 130 staff and up to 150 temporary packers during hamper production. Farepak has an annual turn over of £70m (2004), mainly generated from its core business in Christmas hampers. The origins of Farepak Hamp.. 
 FareStart 
 FareStart is a non-profit organization in Seattle, Washington, USA, that operates a unique program to help get the homeless off the street. It was started as a regular soup kitchen, but its founders then realized that, if they trained their clients to help prepare the food, it would give them the jo.. 
 Fares (Gaafu Dhaalu Atoll) 
 Fares Island Summary Belongs to Gaafu Dhaalu Atoll Location Population 830 Length 780 m Width 540 m Distance from Malé 442 km Administrative Information Island Chief Island office phone +960 6840014 Island office fax +960 6840014 Fares (Dhivehi:ފަ.. 
 Fares and ticketing on the Light Rapid Transit 
 The Light Rapid Transit system in Singapore has collected fares by using a variety of ticketing measures throughout its history. Contents 1 Fares1.1 EZ-Link Card Adult Fares1.2 EZ-Link Card Senior Citizen Fares1.3 EZ-Link Card Child&amp;Student Fares1.4 Standard Ticket Fare.. 
 Fares and ticketing on the Mass Rapid Transit 
 Because the rail operators are government-assisted profit-based corporations, fares on Singapore&apos;s Mass Rapid Transit (MRT) system are currently aimed at least in breaking-even to at least compensate for their costs of running the system. The rail operators collect fares by selling electronic ticket.. 
 Fares Fares 
 Fares Fares (b. 29 April 1973) is a Swedish-Lebanese film actor. He is the brother of film director Josef Fares, and has several times played major parts in his movies (Jalla! Jalla!, Kopps). He has also starred in Bang Bang Orangutang and Kill Your Darlings. External link .. 
 Farès Fellahi 
 Farès Fellahi (born May 13, 1975 in Sétif) is an Algerian football player who, as of 2004, was playing for Entente Sétif. He was part of the Algerian 2004 African Nations Cup team, who finished second in their group in the first round of competition before being defeated by Morocco in the quarte.. 
 FareTax 
 Do you mean: FairTax, a tax reform proposal in the United States to replace most federal taxes in that country with a national retail sales tax and monthly tax rebate to households.Fare paid for Taxicab or on other Public Transport.Taxes on airfare by an Airline or an Airport. This is a[disamb.. 
 Fareway 
 Fareway is an American retail grocery store chain based in Boone, Iowa. It has more than 80 stores, most of them in Iowa and a few in Nebraska and Illinois. The company was founded by Fred Vitt and Paul Beckwith in 1938, and is still owned and controlled by the Beckwith family today. Fareway store.. 
 Farewell 
 Farewell may refer to: A parting salute to people departing on a journey, or to people or places someone has long known but is now parting from, perhaps permanently.Symphony No. 45 (Haydn), known as the Farewell SymphonyFarewell (Gil Evans album), a 1986 album by Gil EvansFarewell (Diana Ross&amp;the.. 
 Farewell, My Lovely 
 It has been suggested that some sections of this article be split into a new article entitled Farewell, My Lovely (film). ([Discuss]) Farewell, My Lovely is a 1940 novel by Raymond Chandler, the second novel he wrote featuring Los Angeles private eye Philip Marlowe. Three movie adaptati.. 
 Farewells 
 Farewells is the English title for Pożegnania, a film released in 1958, directed by Wojciech Has. The film is an adaptation of a highly lyrical and reflective novel by Stanislaw Dygat, with a screenplay written by Dygat and Has. Taking place in Poland during the late 1930s and early 40s, this mela.. 
 Farewells and Fantasies 
 Farewells And Fantasies was the 1997 box set of singer/songwriter Phil Ochs, chronicling his career from 1964 through 1970. With its non-chronological running order, it plays like three separate albums, each showcasing a different side to the enigmatic Ochs. Track listing What&apos;s That I Hear?The .. 
 FAREWELL (album) 
 Farewell is Tomiko Van&apos;s first original studio album under the avex trax label. The album was released on March 29, 2006 with no singles released before it. Contents 1 Information2 Track listing2.1 CD2.2 DVD3 Personnel4 Production5 Charts6 External links .. 
 Farewell (Diana Ross&amp;the Supremes album) 
 Farewell is a 1970 live album by Diana Ross&amp;the Supremes. The album was recorded during the final night of the group&apos;s engagement at the Frontier Hotel in Las Vegas, Nevada on January 14 1970; the show was Diana Ross&apos; final performance with Supremes Mary Wilson and Cindy Birdsong. At the conclusi.. 
 Farewell (Oingo Boingo) 
 &quot;Farewell: Oingo Boingo Live From The Universal Amphitheater&quot; was Oingo Boingo&apos;s final live concert performance in 1995 (the video and audio version of the performance came out in 1996). DISC 1: 1. &quot;Insanity&quot; 2. &quot;Little Girls&quot; 3. &quot;Cinderella Undercover&quot; 4. &quot;Controller&quot; 5. &quot;Burn Me Up&quot; 6. &quot;.. 
 Farewell (Rod Stewart song) 
 &quot;Farewell&quot; is the name of a song written by Martin Quittenton and Rod Stewart. Stewart released it on his 1974 album Smiler. When released as a single in the United Kingdom, the song became a top 10 hit as part of a double A-side with his medley &quot;Bring It on Home to Me/You Send Me.&quot; In the United .. 
 Farewell address 
 A farewell address is a speech given by a political figure upon the occasion of retirement. In U.S. history, the first was George Washington&apos;s farewell to his troops in 1783. The most influential of all such speeches was George Washington&apos;s Farewell Address of 1796, in which he advised against war.. 
 Farewell and Goodnight (song) 
 &quot;Farewell and Goodnight&quot; Song by The Smashing Pumpkins From the album Mellon Collie and the Infinite Sadness Album released 24 October 1995 Recorded March - August 1995 Genre Alternative Rock Song Length 4:22 Record label Virgin Records Producer Alan Moulder, Billy Corgan, Flood &quot;Fare.. 
 Farewell Angelina 
 Farewell Angelina was a 1965 album by Joan Baez. The album represented a further shift from the strictly traditional folk music with which Baez began her career in that, for the first time, she included electric backup in the form of Bruce Langhorne&apos;s electric guitar (which was nonetheless subtle).. 
 Farewell Bend State Recreation Area 
 Farewell Bend State Recreation Area is in Baker County, Oregon, United States. External links[Farewell Bend State Recreation Area].. 
 Farewell Dossier 
 The Farewell Dossier was a collection of documents containing intelligence gathered and handed over to NATO by the KGB defector Colonel Vladimir Vetrov (code-named &quot;Farewell&quot;) in 1981-1982, during the Cold War. An engineer, he was assigned to evaluate information on Western hardware and software, .. 
 Farewell Fantastic Venus 
 Farewell Fantastic Venus is a science fiction anthology edited by Brian Aldiss and Harry Harrison. It was first published in 1968 as a direct respose to the information returned from the first space probes sent to Venus, especially the first atmospheric probe to return data, Venera 4. The first da.. 
 Farewell Islets, Torres Strait 
 Farewell Islets are islands 5km North East of Badu Island, Torres Strait in the Bligh Channel and 70 km North of Thursday Island Queensland, Australia in the Torres Strait. This island is one of the Torres Strait Islands Aerial photos&amp;maps Coordinates:[-10.050° 142.067°][Maps.. 
 Farewell My Concubine 
 Farewell My Concubine (Traditional Chinese: ; Simplified Chinese: }}}; pinyin: ; Translation: Overlord Leaves Concubine) is a Chinese Fifth Generation film directed by Chen Kaige in 1993. It is considered by critics to be one of the main pillars of the Fifth Generation movement that turned the eyes.. 
 Farewell My Friend 
 &quot;Farewell My Friend&quot; is a song written by Dennis Wilson for his 1977 solo album Pacific Ocean Blue. The song was released as the B-side of the &quot;River Song&quot; single. Details Written by: Dennis WilsonAlbum: Pacific Ocean BlueTime: 2 min 26 secProduced by: Dennis Wilson/Gregg Jakobson Performers Denn.. 
 Farewell My Summer Love 
 Farewell My Summer Love, like One Day in Your Life before it, was a compilation of archived Michael Jackson recordings released by Motown in 1984 as a &quot;lost&quot; Michael Jackson solo album. The nine songs featured on the album were originally recorded in 1973 but had not been previously released. T.. 
 Farewell of Slavianka 
 Farewell of Slavianka (in Russian Прощание славянки - Proshchanie Slavianki) is a Russian patriotic march, written by the composer Vasily Agapkin in honour of the Bulgarian women bidding farewell to their husbands who left for the First Balkan War. The march premiered in Tambov in 1.. 
 Farewell Old Friends 
 Farewell Old Friends is an album by Bleach. It was released in 2005 under Tooth&amp;Nail Records. This is Bleach&apos;s last album and was released after the band disbanded. Track listing Write It DownClear the AirGonna Take Some TimeTook It by the HandConditionTo the TopSufficientWeight of It AllGood a.. 
 Farewell speech 
 A Farewell speech is a speech given by an individual leaving a position or place. They are often used by public figures such as politicians as a form of conclusion to the preceding career (such as that given by Ronald Reagan); or as statements delivered by persons relating to reasons for their leavi.. 
 Farewell Spit 
 NASA satellite image of Farewell Spit Location of Farewell Spit Sand dunes on Farewell Spit Farewell Spit is a narrow sand spit situated at[40°31′S 172°52′E], at the northern end of the South Island of New Zealand. Known to the Māori as Tuhuroa, it runs eastwards.. 
 Farewell Summer 
 Farewell Summer is a novel by Ray Bradbury, scheduled to be published on October 1, 2006. It is a sequel to his 1957 novel Dandelion Wine, and is set one year later in the autumn of 1929. The story concerns a war between the young and the old in Green Town, Illinois, and the sexual awakening .. 
 Farewell Tour 
 Farewell Tour is the first live album by American rock band The Doobie Brothers, released in 1983. (see 1983 in music). Contents 1 Track listing2 Personnel3 Production4 Charts Track listing &quot;Slippery St. Paul&quot; (Simmons)[excerpt from THE DOOBIE BROTHERS, 1971]&quot;Taki.. 
 Farewell To Arms 
 This article is about a band; A Farewell to Arms is a similarly-named novel by Ernest Hemingway. Farewell to Arms is a post-hardcore band from Storrs, Connecticut. The band includes singer Justin Smith, Michael Marzano II and Michael Ryan on guitars, Francis Ferrall on keyboards, Peter Wieland on .. 
 Farewell to Legs 
 &quot;Farewell to Legs&quot; is a short story by P. G. Wodehouse, which first appeared in the United States in the July 14 1935 edition of This Week, and in the United Kingdom in the May 1936 issue of the Strand. It was included in the U.K. collection Lord Emsworth and Others, (1937), and in the U.S. edition .. 
 Farewell to Manzanar 
 Farewell to Manzanar is a memoir published in 1972 by Jeanne Wakatsuki Houston and James D. Houston. It was made into a movie in 1976 staring Yuki Shimoda, Nobu McCarthy, Pat Morita, and Mako. The book describes Wakatsuki Houston&apos;s and her family&apos;s experience being detained at the Manzanar inter.. 
 Farewell to Nostrodamus 
 Lupin III: Farewell to Nostradamus (Japanese title: Rupan sansei: Kutabare! Nastradamus) was a 1995 movie. Lupin III Characters Lupin the 3rd | Daisuke Jigen | Goemon Ishikawa XIII | Fujiko Mine | Inspector Koichi Zenigata Manga Lupin III | Lupin III - World&apos;s Most Wanted | Lupin III S.. 
 Farewell to Nova Scotia 
 &quot;Farewell to Nova Scotia&quot; is a popular folk song from Nova Scotia of unknown authorship. It is believed to have been written just prior to or during the First World War. &quot;Farewell to Nova Scotia&quot; brings the listener back to an age when Nova Scotia was renowned for &quot;wooden ships and iron men&quot;. In mo.. 
 Farewell to Paradise 
 Farewell to Paradise (1973) is the fourth and final solo album by baroque pop singer/songwriter Emitt Rhodes. Track listing All songs by Emitt Rhodes &quot;Warm Self Sacrifice&quot;&quot;See No Evil&quot;&quot;Drawn to You&quot;&quot;Blue Horizon&quot;&quot;Shoot the Moon&quot;&quot;Only Lovers Decide&quot;&quot;Trust One More&quot;&quot;Nights Are Lonely&quot;&quot;Bad Man&quot;&quot;In .. 
 Farewell to the King 
 Farewell to the King is a 1989 film directed by John Milius. It stars Nigel Havers, Frank McRae, Gerry Lopez and Nick Nolte. The screenplay by John Milius is based on the book by Pierre Schoendoerffer. The original music score is composed by Basil Poledouris. Tagline: In the midst of war, one man.. 
 Farewell to the Sea 
 Published in 1987, Farewell to the Sea is the third book in Reinaldo Arenas&apos; Pentagonia which critics have often argued as his best. Set on a Cuban beach immediately following the revolution, a disenchanted poet mourns for the new suppression while his wife longs for the connectivity that she can n.. 
 Farey 
 Farey may mean: John Farey, Sr. (1766-1826), English geologistFarey sequence, a mathematical construct named after himJohn Farey, Jr. (1791-1851), his son, mechanical engineer This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same title. If an referre.. 
 Farey sequence 
 In mathematics, the Farey sequence of order n is the sequence of completely reduced fractions between 0 and 1 which, when in lowest terms, have denominators less than or equal to n, arranged in order of increasing size. Each Farey sequence starts with the value 0, denoted by the fraction 0⁄1,.. 
 Fare control 
 --&gt; SmartRider fare gates at the Joondalup Line platform, Perth Station. Fare control is the system to make sure that people, e.g. in a train station, pay their fare. A fare control area can be an area at an entrance or exit with turnstiles or fare gates, or alternatively the area between .. 
 Fare Strike 
 A fare strike is a direct action in which people in a city with a public transit system carry out mass fare evasion. Jumping turnstiles, boarding buses through the back or very quickly through the front, and leaving doors open in subway stations are all tactics by which people can participate. Often.. 
 Fare Thee Well 
 Fare Thee Well can refer to: Fare Thee Well (song), an Irish balladFare Thee Well (poem), an 1816 poem by George Gordon Byron, 6th Baron Byronfare-thee-well, a phrase meaning a state of perfection. This is a[disambiguationdisambiguation]page: a list of articles associated with the same .. 
 Fare Thee Well (poem) 
 Fare Thee Well is an 1816 poem by George Gordon Byron, 6th Baron Byron. Background Lord Byron married and fathered a child with Annabella Milbanke in 1815, but they separated in 1816. In March of that year, Byron composed &quot;Fare Thee Well&quot; and enclosed a note that said, &quot;Dearest Bell --- I send you.. 
 Fare Thee Well (song) 
 Fare Thee Well (or &quot;Ten Thousand Miles&quot;) is an Eighteenth Century folk ballad, in which a lover bids farewell before setting off on a journey. The lyrics include a dialogue between the lovers. The first published version of the song appeared in 1710. The song has been recorded, most notably by Jo.. 
 Farfa 
 Farfa is an Italian name which can refer to: A place name in the province of the Lazio in Italy, as:* Farfa River* Farfa (town)* Farfa Abbey, one of the main medieval abbeys in Italy A personal name, as: * Farfa (poet), an Italian Futurist poet (1881-1964) This is a[disambiguationdisambiguati.. 
 Farfalle 
 Farfalle is a type of pasta. Commonly known as &quot;bow-ties&quot; the name derives from the Italian for butterfly. Farfalle comes in several sizes, but has a distinctive bowtie shape. Usually the farfalle is formed from a square of pasta with two sides trimmed in a ruffled edge, and the center pinched t.. 
 Farfallino Alphabet 
 redirect [[Template:Not verified]] Farfallino Alphabet(Alfabeto Farfallino) Spoken in: Italy Region: &gt; Classification: Alfabeto Farfallino Spoken with: Italian See also: Language games The farfallino alphabet is a language game used primarily in Italy. It is usually used by children for am.. 
 Farfel 
 Image:Farfel in an aluminum tray Farfel (Yiddish: פֿאַרפֿל, farfl; from Middle High German varveln) are small pellet-shaped noodles, made of either flour mixed with egg or matzo. Farfel is most prevalent in Jewish cuisine, where it is a seasonal item used in Passover dishes. In this .. 
 Farfel the Dog 
 Farfel the Dog was a hound dog puppet that appeared in commercials for Nestlé&apos;s Quik from 1953 to 1965. Farfel, with assistance from ventriloquist Jimmy Nelson and fellow puppet Danny O&apos;Day sang &quot;N-e-s-t-l-e-s, Nestlé&apos;s makes the very best, chocolate.&quot; Danny sang:&quot;N-e-s-t-l-e-s, Nestlé&apos;s makes .. 
 Farfetch&apos;d 
 is one of the 395 fictional species of Pokémon in the Pokémon franchise (a series of video games, anime, manga, trading cards and other media created by Satoshi Tajiri). Farfetch&apos;d takes its name from the English expression &quot;far-fetched&quot;, meaning &quot;on the border of unbelievability&quot;. It could also.. 
 Farfisa 
 Farfisa is a brand name for a series of electronic organs and later multitimbral keyboards, made in Potenza Picena in the Marche region of Italy. The organs were marketed for years in the United States by the Chicago Musical Instrument Company. With several compact, easily-portable, and inexpensive.. 
 Farfisa Beat 
 &quot;Farfisa Beat&quot; was released as a single in Denmark and Germany in 1980, and Switzerland in 1981. The song is from Squeeze&apos;s third album, Argybargy. Track listing &quot;Farfisa Beat&quot; (2:56)&quot;Here Comes That Feeling&quot; (2:05)External links[Squeeze discography at Squeezenet].. 
 Fargate 
 Fargate is a pedestrian precinct and shopping area in Sheffield, England. It runs between Barker&apos;s Pool and High Street opposite the cathedral. It was pedestrianised in 1973. In his &quot;[A DESCRIPTION OF THE TOWN OF SHEFFIELD]: the author, Joseph Woolhouse wrote in the year 1832 at the t.. 
 Farge 
 Farge is a small port on the Weser River north of Bremen. It is part of Bremen-Blumenthal, which is one of the districts of the state of Bremen. History During World War II Farge was the site of an oil-storage depot and the Valentin submarine pens that were attacked by the Royal Air Force on 27 Mar.. 
 Fargesia 
 Fargesia is a genus of medium to small mountain clumping bamboos, found in alpine conifer forests of West and Southwest China. Taxonomy This genus is sometimes considered a synonym of Thamnocalamus. .. 
 Fargett 
 Fargett is a fictional planet in the Star Ocean universe. Its first and so far, only appearance is in the first game in the series, [[Star Ocean: Fantastic Space Odyssey]]. Very little is known about the geography of the planet, except that it is very barren, and devoid of almost all life. It als.. 
 Fargo 
 Fargo can refer to: Fargo, ArkansasFargo, GeorgiaFargo, North DakotaFargo, OklahomaFargo (film) by Joel and Ethan CoenFargo (truck), a brand of truckFargo (Chrono Cross), a ship captain in the SquareSoft RPG Chrono Cross.The NATO reporting name of the Mikoyan-Gurevich MiG-9 fighter aircraftThe ammu.. 
 Fargo, Arkansas 
 Fargo is a town in Monroe County, Arkansas, United States. The population was 118 at the 2000 census. Geography Fargo is located at[34°57′19″N, 91°10′38″W](34.955140, -91.177179)[Geographic references#1GR1]. According to the United States Census Bureau, the town ha.. 
 Fargo, Georgia 
 Fargo is a city in Clinch County, Georgia, United States. As of the 2000 census, the city had a total population of 380. Formerly a town, it was incorporated by the Georgia state legislature in 1992, effective on April 1st of that year. Geography Fargo is located at[30°41′12″N, 82°34.. 
 Fargo, North Dakota 
 Fargo is a city in Cass County, North Dakota in the United States. It is the county seat of Cass County. The population was 90,599 at the 2000 census (2006 estimate: 102,254), which makes it the largest city in North Dakota. Along with Moorhead, Minnesota, it forms the center of the Fargo-Moorhead .. 
 Fargo, Oklahoma 
 Fargo is a town in Ellis County, Oklahoma, United States. The population was 326 at the 2000 census. Geography Fargo is located at[36°22′24″N, 99°37′22″W](36.373449, -99.622749)[Geographic references#1GR1]. According to the United States Census Bureau, the town has.. 
 Fargo-Moorhead 
 Fargo-Moorhead is a common name given to the metropolitan area comprising Fargo, North Dakota, Moorhead, Minnesota, and the surrounding communities. These two cities lie on the North Dakota-Minnesota border, on opposite banks of the Red River of the North. The larger Fargo-Moorhead area also encom.. 
 Fargo-Moorhead Beez 
 The Fargo-Moorhead Beez was a professional basketball club based in North Fargo, North Dakota that competed in the International Basketball Association beginning in the 1995-1996 season. They were the 1995-1996 and the 1997-1998 International Basketball Association champions. The team folded along.. 
 Fargo-Moorhead RedHawks 
 Fargo-Moorhead RedHawks Founded 1996 Home field Newman Outdoor Field Based in Fargo, ND/Moorhead, MN Colors red, black, silver League Northern League Manager Doug Simunic The Fargo-Moorhead RedHawks (or simply the FM RedHawks) is an independent minor league base.. 
 Fargodome 
 The Fargodome is an indoor arena located in Fargo, North Dakota. It opened in 1992. It is the home of the North Dakota State University Bison football team. The arena also plays host to many large concerts, sporting events, and trade shows. The Fargodome has seen increased competition in recent .. 
 Fargo (film) 
 Fargo is a 1996 neo-noir film created by brothers Joel and Ethan Coen. It tells the tale of a used car sales man (William H. Macy), a pregnant police chief (Frances McDormand), and two bumbling hit men. The film was well received by critics and won many awards. It is commonly known for the heavy no.. 
 Fargo (truck) 
 Fargo truck in Batey ha-Osef Museum, Israel. Fargo was a brand of truck manufactured and sold in Canada by the Chrysler Corporation. Fargo trucks were almost identical to Dodge trucks, save for trim and name, but were sold by Chrysler-Plymouth dealers. Production began in the late 1920s; the.. 
 Fargo Air Museum 
 The Fargo Air Museum is an aviation related museum in Fargo, North Dakota. It is located near Hector International Airport in the northern part of the city. The museum includes many historic aircraft of which 90% are in flying condition. There is also a full-scale replica of a Wright brothers fly.. 
 Fargo Civic Center 
 The Fargo Civic Center is an indoor arena located in Fargo, North Dakota. It hosts trade shows, sporting events, entertainment events, meetings, and community events. The main arena can hold around 3,000 people during concerts and 1,500 during a basketball game. External link[Fargo Civic Ce.. 
 Fargo Country Club 
 The Fargo Country Club is an 18-hole golf course located at 509 26th Avenue South in Fargo, North Dakota. It measures 6900 yards from the back tees. External links[Fargo Country Club][North Dakota Golf Association website].. 
 Fargo North High School 
 Fargo North High School is an American high school located in Fargo, North Dakota. It is the oldest existing high school in the city, after Central High burned down in 1966. It currently serves about 1,000 students and is a part of the Fargo Public Schools system. The official school colors are b.. 
 Fargo Public Schools 
 Fargo Public Schools (FPS) is a system of publicly-funded K-12 schools in Fargo, North Dakota. There are fifteen elementary schools, three middle schools, and two high schools. FPS also operates an alternative high school. Enrollment in FPS schools is around 11,000 and the system employs over .. 
 Fargo Rock City 
 thumb Fargo Rock City is a book by Chuck Klosterman. It is a history of heavy metal music, with a particular emphasis on the hair metal that flourished during Klosterman&apos;s formative years in the mid-to-late 1980s, through its demise in the early 1990s, and potential rebirth in the late 1990s. .. 
 Fargo Shanley Catholic 
 Fargo Shanley Catholic is a Catholic high school in Fargo, North Dakota, that is part of the Fargo Catholic School Network. Its athletic teams are called the &quot;Deacons&quot;. Athletic History State Class &quot;A&quot; Boys Basketball Champions: 19971998 State Class &quot;A&quot; Girls Basketball Champions: 1980198219831989.. 
 Fargo South High School 
 Fargo South High School is a secondary school located in Fargo, North Dakota. Fargo South High School is a part of the Fargo Public Schools. Grade levels: 9-12Mascot: The BruinsSchool colors: Brown and GoldAs of 2006, it had around 1589 students and 101 instructors. Contents 1 Athletics1.1&amp;.. 
 Fargo Theatre 
 The Fargo Theatre is an art deco movie theatre in downtown Fargo, North Dakota. It was built in 1925. It was restored in 1999 to its historic appearance and now is a center for the arts in the Fargo-Moorhead metropolitan area. External link[Fargo Theatre website].. 
 Farhad 
 --&gt; Farhad is the name of 4 kings in the Persian Empire. Farhad Mehrad (1943 - 2002), widely known as Farhad in Iran, was an Iranian pop musician and singer. Farhad is also the name of a legendary character who fell in love with Shirin, the wife of Khosrau II of Persia. This is a[disambiguati.. 
 Farhad Ardalan 
 Farhad Ardalan (in Persian:فرهاد اردلان, Born 1339 Tehran, Iran) is an Iranian High Energy physicist and University lecturer. He is known for the proposal of the para-string theory, construction of modular invariant partition functions for WZNW models via orbifold method, classification .. 
 Farhad Darya 
 --&gt; Farhad &apos;Darya&apos; Nasher (born September 22, 1962 in Gozargaah, Kabul province of Afghanistan) is a world renowned Afghan singer. Farhad Darya, a very popular Afghan singer who sings in both Farsi and Pashto. Contents 1 Life2 Music3 In Film4 Discography5 External.. 
 Farhad Manjoo 
 Farhad Manjoo (born 1978) is a staff writer for Salon.com. Manjoo graduated from Cornell University in 2000. While there, he wrote for the Daily Sun student paper. Before taking a staff position at Salon.com, he wrote for Wired News. Manjoo frequently writes on new media, politics, and controversi.. 
 Farhad Mehrad 
 An editor has expressed a concern that the subject of the article does not satisfy one of the guidelines for inclusion on Wikipedia on one of the following topics:[Notability Academics]([Notability proposed])[Notability Biographies][Notability Books](&lt;!
	</body>
</document>
