<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005753" url="http://www.modthesims.info/download.php?t=70222" time="2012-07-12-22:23" support="2" score="0.0014899042814938046" bingtitle="Mod The Sims - &quot;WallWindows&quot; glass set V.3" webtitle="Mod The Sims -WallWindowsglass set V.3">
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>Mod The Sims &gt; Downloads &gt; Build Mode &gt; Doors &amp; Windows &quot;WallWindows&quot; glass set V.3</description>
	<body>
		Home   Register   News   Help   Create   Downloads   Community   Site   Search   
 Welcome to 
 Mod The Sims 
 Online: 2782 News: Latest Creator News :
 New Creators - June! , 16th Jun 2012 at 06:47 PM ModTheSims3? MTS3? Sims 3 Custom Content? 
We&apos;re not going anywhere! MTS2 is renaming to ModTheSims and expanding for TS3 content. Accept no imitations - this is the official ModTheSims site! Just installed the Sims 3 patch or about to? 
 Read this article for helpful advice about patching and keeping your custom content working! Want to create your own clothes for the Sims 3? 
 Read this guide for a tutorial! Remember Me? Have an account? Sign in: 
 pass: 
 If you don&apos;t have an account, why not sign up now ? It&apos;s free! sponsored by:
 Other sites: SimsWiki 
 
 Mod The Sims &gt; Downloads &gt; Build Mode &gt; Doors&amp;Windows &quot;WallWindows&quot;glass set V.3 
 Add To Favourites 

 Site-wide Announcements Come join us in our live chat ! 

 
 MTS is currently running a donation drive !
Support the site by making a donation (and get yourself a cute little heart):

 
 
 Creator Numenor 
 The ModFather
 

Thanked 187214 Times in 187 Posts
 38 Achievements 
 View Profile View journal 
 Ad section Overview Download Install Instructions Comments (861) Related Pages Posted 17th Jun 2005 at 01:48 AM

- Updated 10th Nov 2008 at 08:45 AM by Numenor : Fixed inline image


 - Viewed 965488 times. Direct link to this thread 861 Comments / replies ( Who? ) 


, 541 times favourited


, 8885 times thanked Tags: # wallwindow , # glass , # transparent , # greenhouse Information (Click for more details): New Mesh This is a Maxis Recolour which means that it is a recolour of an item that already exists in your game. Please check the Expansion pack requirements to see which game pack it recolours. This is a new mesh, and means that it&apos;s a brand new self contained object that usually does not require a specific Expansion pack (although this is possible depending on the type). It may have Recolours hosted on MTS2 - check the sidebar. This is a new mesh recolour, and means that you will need to download the particular mesh itself in order for this to show up in your game. See the Meshes Needed section or read the text for more information. This is a featured upload! It showcases the best talent and creativity available on MTS and in the community. WALLWINDOWS (GLASS SET) V. 3
by Numenor 
 
 
 
--------------------------------------------------------

 22 JUNE 2006 - ADDED: GARAGE DOOR (Nightlife required) 

 15.JAN.2006 - UPDATED: WALL BOUNDARY - If you have downloaded the Seamless or the Standard set since the release of V.3 (09 jan 2006), please REDOWNLOAD the attached&quot;WallWindow_Seamless_BASIC_set_UPD-15jan06.zip&quot;file.
What&apos;s new: Now the Wall Boundary can be placed on upper floors, and will not delete any more the fences. Please note that you can put wall-mounted objects on the same wall where there is a WallBoundary, but you can&apos;t put windows on that wall.
Note also that tou can put two WallBoundaries on the two sides of a straight wall, but you can use only one side of the diagonal walls (this limitation can be workarounded using the&quot;move_objects on&quot;cheat).
This new version of the WallBoundary is compatible with the old versions: therefore, your old lots will work fine without editing them. But since this version is improved, you may find useful to replace only some wallboundaries (for instance, the old ones that&quot;delete&quot;the fences).


 09.JAN.2006 
After more than 30,000 downloads and almost 9 months since the first release, it&apos;s time for a complete renewal of the WallWindow set.
This thread has grown too long and untidy, and needs a good clean up. 

 WHAT&apos;S NEW 
 First off, the layout of this thread: all the info are now contained in the&quot;WallWindow documentation&quot; - downloadable below - that describes (with pictures) the various WallWindow items and their usage. The documentation is provided in RTF and PDF format, so that anyone can easily open it, even using the WordPad program provided by Windows. Important changes have been done to almost all the WallWindows items: the UVmapping, the meshes, the alignments (no more&quot;gaps&quot;between angled windows!), even the price of the items (for a better displacement in the game catalogue). See the documentation for details. 

 WHAT IS *NOT* CHANGED 
 Fear not! All the lots that include the old WallWindow v.2 will still work: only, they will look better! And all the existing recolours will apply flawlessly to the new v.3. 

 FOR THE NEWCOMERS: WHAT IS THE WALLWINDOW SET? 
It&apos;s a set of windows, doors and other items that have in common these two feature: 1) they are made of glass; 2) they completely cover a wall section, side to side and floor to ceiling. The WallWindows can be used to build glass walls, big display windows, greenhouses, and many many other beautiful things 

 FAQ: HAVE I TO DOWNLOAD ALL THIS STUFF? 
The minimum requirement is the&quot;Seamless BASIC set&quot;(and the Documentation, where you can find info about the content of the various archives).

 FAQ: WHERE CAN I FIND THE TRANSPARENT FLOOR TILES THAT ARE SHOWN IN THE PICTURES? HOW TO BUILD THAT TRANSPARENT ROOF? 
They were made by RGiles, and can be downloaded HERE . A tutorial for building the glass roof is HERE 

 HOW TO INSTALL 
Put all the packages in the Downloads folder: no furter actions are required. You&apos;ll find the WallWindow items in the Build Mode catalog, among the other windows, doors, arches and columns.

 FAQ: MY COMPUTER DOESN&apos;T TOLERATE&quot;RAR&quot;FILES, CAN YOU PLEASE POST A&quot;ZIP&quot;? 
OK, you won... YES! Here are the ZIPs!


----------------------------------------------------------

And now, just for the records, a&quot;cleaned up&quot;version of the older post follows:


08 DIC 2005 - ADDED: INWARDS Slanted Corners and Vertical-to-slanted INWARDS Junction
08 DIC 2005 - UPDATED: Half-fake door
02 DIC 2005 - ADDED: Slanted Sliding Door and Vertical-to-slanted Junction
28 NOV 2005 - ADDED: Slanted Windows (5-pieces set)
26 NOV 2005 - IMPORTANT UPDATE: Fake Door.
26 NOV 2005 - ADDED:&quot;Half-Fake&quot;Door (as per request by Niol)
25 NOV 2005 - ADDED: Fence and Gate (many thanks to Niol for his complete beta-testing and his advices )
02 NOV 2005 - ADDED: Opaque recolour pack (as per request by Jonesi).
02 NOV 2005 - ADDED: Seamless FAKE Door (as per request by Redeth20)
23 OCT 2005 - ADDED: Curved DOOR 135
16 OCT 2005 - ADDED: Glass Column set (as per request by Mojo_Leowski2)
15 OCT 2005 - UPDATED: Wall Boundary (again)
11 OCT 2005 - UPDATED: Wall Boundary
09 OCT 2005 - UPDATED: Curved 135 WallWindow
08 OCT 2005 - ADDED: Curved 135 WallWindow
28 SEPT - Fixed again the Wall Boundary
27 SEPT - Fixed the&quot;Flashing Purple&quot;issue with the hidden windows
18 SEPT - Fixed the rar containing the INVISIBLE GLASS
13 SEPT - Added: Invisible recolour for the glass and Wall Boundary
04 AUG - Luslipz73 has created some very nice recolours ( LINK )
30 JUNE - Added a special&quot;Invisible Recolour&quot;for the handles
30 JUNE - Additional recolours for the WallWindow set has been made by FatD ( LINK )
27 JUNE - Both sets have been updated: now the handles are recolourable
25 JUNE - Mira04 has posted her beautiful recolours ( LINK )
25 JUNE - HoneyB has created some very nice recolours ( LINK )
25 JUNE - Added Frosted Glass recolour
21 JUNE - Fixed STANDARD Double Door diagonal
21 JUNE - Fixed Recolour template
18 JUNE - Tiggy027 has created some beautiful frames for the WallWindow glass set ( LINK )
17 JUNE - Due to the numerous requests, I&apos;ve completely reworked the WallWindow set. Now you can have it in two flavors: Standard and Seamless.

Please report any issue, and feel free to request additional items. I don&apos;t promise anything , but I&apos;ll try to fulfil you requests. 
 8885 people have said thanks to Numenor for this download. 
 For more information about this creator and their policies or details, click here .   Screenshots Screenshots Expansion / Stuff Packs Required 

You must have the expansion or stuff packs listed above installed to use this custom content. Please see the post text for any exceptions. This is a New mesh All the items needed for you to use this download should be here on this page. You can check the &quot;Related Pages&quot; tab, if visible, to see if there are alternative colour schemes. Download files 
 D/L Filename Size Downloads WallWindow_Seamless_CURVED_set.zip 77.2 KB 139,899 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_CurvedDoor135_main.package 46,381 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Curved Door 135° - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Curved135_diagonal.package 37,253 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Curved 135° (diagonal) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Curved135_main.package 128,224 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Curved 135° - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Curved270.package 27,684 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Curved 270° - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_CurvedDoor135_diagonal.package 39,917 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Curved Door 135° (diagonal)
  
 46381 Defl:X 11186 76% 01-08-06 19:51 d24b8b12 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_CurvedDoor135_main.package
 37253 Defl:X 5151 86% 01-08-06 22:01 0bba682a Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Curved135_diagonal.package
 128224 Defl:X 48694 62% 01-08-06 22:00 a904ac1b Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Curved135_main.package
 27684 Defl:X 3904 86% 01-08-06 22:00 ca3cde02 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Curved270.package
 39917 Defl:X 9235 77% 01-08-06 19:51 2f4311a0 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_CurvedDoor135_diagonal.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 279459 78170 72% 5 files WallWindow_Seamless_SLANTED_set.zip 39.9 KB 135,292 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_JunctionRight.package 26,951 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (right junction) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_SlidingDoor.package 50,522 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted Sliding Door - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_Straight.package 23,289 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (straight) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_Vertical2SlantedJunction.package 24,921 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Vertical-to-Slanted junction - by Numenor
Useful to create a junction between an internal wall and a slanted window.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_Vertical2SlantedJunctionInwards.package 26,097 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Vertical-to-Slanted junction - INWARDS - by Numenor
Useful to create a junction between an internal (vertical) wall and a slanted window facing INWARDS.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerLeft.package 25,112 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (left OUTWARDS corner) - by Numenor
This piece is to be placed at the room cornar, when the Slanted windows are facing OUTWARDS  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerLeftInwards.package 26,257 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (left INWARDS corner) - by Numenor
This piece is to be placed at room corners, when the slanted windows are facing INWARDS.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerRight.package 25,142 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (right OUTWARDS corner) - by Numenor
This piece is to be placed at room corner, when the Slanted windows are facing OUTWARDS.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerRightInwards.package 26,289 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (right INWARDS corner) - by Numenor
This piece is to be placed at room corner, when the Slanted windows are facing INWARDS.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_JunctionLeft.package 26,918 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - Slanted (left junction) - by Numenor
  
 26951 Defl:X 4530 83% 01-08-06 19:44 efe31ec9 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_JunctionRight.package
 50522 Defl:X 7781 85% 01-08-06 19:55 5f750c2e Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_SlidingDoor.package
 23289 Defl:X 2696 88% 01-08-06 19:40 51c8cdae Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_Straight.package
 24921 Defl:X 3146 87% 01-08-06 19:44 06defdaf Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_Vertical2SlantedJunction.package
 26097 Defl:X 3211 88% 01-08-06 19:45 70f50710 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_Vertical2SlantedJunctionInwards.package
 25112 Defl:X 3230 87% 01-08-06 19:41 a4545387 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerLeft.package
 26257 Defl:X 3286 88% 01-08-06 19:41 dd68a9ee Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerLeftInwards.package
 25142 Defl:X 3204 87% 01-08-06 19:42 fe4eece6 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerRight.package
 26289 Defl:X 3280 88% 01-08-06 19:43 cda12649 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_CornerRightInwards.package
 26918 Defl:X 4516 83% 01-08-06 19:43 dca95a68 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Slanted_JunctionLeft.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 281498 38880 86% 10 files WallWindow_Seamless_FAKE+HIDDEN_set.zip 33.0 KB 131,888 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_HiddenWindow_main.package 41,441 Mesh Seamless HIDDEN WallWindow - by Numenor
This window is supposed to HIDE into the walls!  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_FakeDoor.package 32,498 Mesh Seamless WallWindow *Not-Moving* Door - by Numenor
This is a *door* that looks like a window, and *doesn&apos;t move* when the sims enter it.
Useful for &quot;special effects&quot; :)  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Half-FakeDoor.package 57,689 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Half-Fake Door - by Numenor
This door looks like a normal WallWindow door, but it&apos;s visible FROM ONE SIDE ONLY. From the other side you can see only the wall.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Half-FakeDoor_diagonal.package 31,337 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Half-Fake Door (diagonal) - by Numenor
This door looks like a normal WallWindow door, but it&apos;s visible FROM ONE SIDE ONLY. From the other side you can see only the wall.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_HiddenWindow_diagonal.package 54,194 Mesh Seamless HIDDEN WallWindow (diagonal) - by Numenor
The Monticello Federal-style window has narrow proportions with simple casing and slender mullions. Its neo-classical origins transform it into an architectural expression of power, wealth and influence. It looks well-placed amidst its brethren: the Monticello full-length window and the Monticello door.Here Comes the Sun: Any room can benefit from the sunlight shining through a well-placed window.  
 41441 Defl:X 4451 89% 01-08-06 19:40 5c36d181 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_HiddenWindow_main.package
 32498 Defl:X 4067 88% 01-08-06 19:53 e98bc642 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_FakeDoor.package
 57689 Defl:X 8715 85% 01-08-06 19:53 7d26f7c3 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Half-FakeDoor.package
 31337 Defl:X 7572 76% 01-01-06 15:40 d5d6c638 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Half-FakeDoor_diagonal.package
 54194 Defl:X 8081 85% 12-31-05 17:15 38b63085 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_HiddenWindow_diagonal.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 217159 32886 85% 5 files WallWindow_Seamless_EXTRA_items.zip 75.7 KB 133,606 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_LargeColumn_AllGames.package 36,605 Mesh WallWindow - Large Glass Column
This column is part of the WallWindow set by Numenor.
Please visit www.numenor-moddings.com for full Licence Agreement.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_2StoreyColumn_UNI-NL-Only.package 57,513 Mesh WallWindow - Large Glass Column - 2-Storey
This 3-storey column is part of the WallWindow set by Numenor.
Please visit www.numenor-moddings.com for full Licence Agreement.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_3StoreyColumn_UNI-NL-Only.package 79,421 Mesh WallWindow - Large Glass Column - 3 storey
This 3-storey column is part of the WallWindow set by Numenor.
Please visit www.numenor-moddings.com for full Licence Agreement.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Column.package 32,272 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Column - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_FenceGate_Standard.package 56,979 Mesh WallWindow Seamless Fence Gate
This gate is part of the WallWindow set - by Numenor
Do not clone. Visit www.numenor-moddings.com to read the Copyright Policy.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_main.package 11,242 Mesh WallWindow Seamless Fence (mesh)
This fence is part of the WallWindow set - by Numenor
Do not clone. Visit www.numenor-moddings.com to read the Copyright Policy.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Blue.package 4,167 Unknown WallWindow Seamless Fence (recolour) - Blue glass
This fence is part of the WallWindow set - by Numenor
Do not clone. Visit www.numenor-moddings.com to read the Copyright Policy.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Clear.package 4,190 Unknown WallWindow Seamless Fence (recolour) - Clear glass
This fence is part of the WallWindow set - by Numenor
Do not clone. Visit www.numenor-moddings.com to read the Copyright Policy.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Green.package 4,190 Unknown WallWindow Seamless Fence (recolour) - Green glass
This fence is part of the WallWindow set - by Numenor
Do not clone. Visit www.numenor-moddings.com to read the Copyright Policy.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Red.package 4,144 Unknown WallWindow Seamless Fence (recolour) - Red glass
This fence is part of the WallWindow set - by Numenor
Do not clone. Visit www.numenor-moddings.com to read the Copyright Policy.  
 36605 Defl:X 10053 73% 01-08-06 19:59 b7eda237 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_LargeColumn_AllGames.package
 57513 Defl:X 16008 72% 01-08-06 19:59 3ad12eaf Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_2StoreyColumn_UNI-NL-Only.package
 79421 Defl:X 24954 69% 01-08-06 20:00 bfe80641 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_3StoreyColumn_UNI-NL-Only.package
 32272 Defl:X 5774 82% 01-08-06 19:58 4c94952a Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Column.package
 56979 Defl:X 12388 78% 11-24-05 12:29 0e8f259f Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_FenceGate_Standard.package
 11242 Defl:X 2424 78% 01-08-06 20:04 381cb47b Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_main.package
 4167 Defl:X 1024 75% 01-08-06 20:03 92592d35 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Blue.package
 4190 Defl:X 1030 75% 01-08-06 20:05 b97722a7 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Clear.package
 4190 Defl:X 1023 76% 01-08-06 20:05 83767e2f Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Green.package
 4144 Defl:X 1019 75% 01-08-06 20:05 595fcada Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Fence_Recolour_Red.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 290723 75697 74% 10 files WallWindow_RECOLOUR_PACK.zip 364.5 KB 139,297 
 Package file Size Type Description 09-13-05 23:06 0 Recolour   Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_OpaqueColourPack.package 383,739 Recolour   Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_FrostedGlass2.package 177,675 Recolour   Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_FrostedGlass1.package 177,675 Recolour   Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_RecolourTEMPLATE.package 186,042 Recolour   06-30-05 14:45 0 Recolour   
 925 Defl:X 374 60% 09-13-05 23:06 5a73014d Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_InvisibleGlass.package
 383739 Defl:X 226665 41% 11-02-05 10:59 417118a6 Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_OpaqueColourPack.package
 177675 Defl:X 86224 52% 06-25-05 00:55 bf118720 Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_FrostedGlass2.package
 177675 Defl:X 52968 70% 06-25-05 00:55 60434a59 Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_FrostedGlass1.package
 186042 Defl:X 5462 97% 06-27-05 19:21 ea209752 Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_RecolourTEMPLATE.package
 925 Defl:X 377 59% 06-30-05 14:45 3b31b4e3 Numenor_WallWindow_(Standard+Seamless)_InvisibleHandles.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 926981 372070 60% 6 files WallWindow_documentation_(RTF).zip 8.96 MB 76,624 52344415 Defl:X 9393397 82% 01-09-06 23:42 e0b40d0e WallWindow documentation.rtf
-------- ------- --- -------
52344415 9393397 82% 1 file WallWindow_Seamless_BASIC_set_UPD-15jan06.zip 89.9 KB 161,749 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Arch_diagonal.package 29,957 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Arch (diagonal) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Arch_main.package 41,428 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Arch - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Door_diagonal.package 48,083 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Door (diagonal) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Door_main.package 58,000 Mesh Seamless WallWindow Door - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_DoubleDoor_diagonal.package 70,886 Mesh Seamless WallWindow DoubleDoor (diagonal) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_DoubleDoor_main.package 71,681 Mesh Seamless WallWindow DoubleDoor - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Window_diagonal.package 53,750 Mesh Seamless WallWindow (diagonal) - by Numenor
The Monticello Federal-style window has narrow proportions with simple casing and slender mullions. Its neo-classical origins transform it into an architectural expression of power, wealth and influence. It looks well-placed amidst its brethren: the Monticello full-length window and the Monticello door.Here Comes the Sun: Any room can benefit from the sunlight shining through a well-placed window.  Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Window_main.package 73,167 Mesh Seamless WallWindow - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_main.package 36,319 Mesh WallWindow - Wall Boundary
Use this to &quot;close&quot; the wall side, where it joins an invisible or seamless window/door.
Made by Numenor - Do not clone - Visit www.numenor-moddings.com for full copyright policy..  Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_diagonal.package 19,552 Mesh WallWindow - Wall Boundary (diagonal)
-  
 29957 Defl:X 3427 89% 01-08-06 19:48 60349cc3 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Arch_diagonal.package
 41428 Defl:X 9199 78% 01-08-06 19:48 979deb33 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Arch_main.package
 48083 Defl:X 8067 83% 01-08-06 19:50 7d113120 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Door_diagonal.package
 58000 Defl:X 9040 84% 01-08-06 19:50 f99d5e2a Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Door_main.package
 70886 Defl:X 12418 83% 01-08-06 19:55 22af5fd3 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_DoubleDoor_diagonal.package
 71681 Defl:X 11911 83% 01-08-06 19:54 f2b3591f Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_DoubleDoor_main.package
 53750 Defl:X 7983 85% 01-08-06 19:49 9102b558 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Window_diagonal.package
 73167 Defl:X 17761 76% 01-08-06 19:36 e92cf795 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_Window_main.package
 36319 Defl:N 8105 78% 01-14-06 17:06 44cf335b Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_main.package
 19552 Defl:N 2412 88% 01-14-06 17:15 7fcdd673 Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_diagonal.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 502823 90323 82% 10 files WallWindow_Standard_Set_(DISCONTINUED)_UPD-15jan06.zip 109.0 KB 113,290 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Window_diagonal.package 54,033 Mesh Standard WallWindow (diagonal) - by Numenor
The Monticello Federal-style window has narrow proportions with simple casing and slender mullions. Its neo-classical origins transform it into an architectural expression of power, wealth and influence. It looks well-placed amidst its brethren: the Monticello full-length window and the Monticello door.Here Comes the Sun: Any room can benefit from the sunlight shining through a well-placed window.  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Window_main.package 72,215 Mesh Standard WallWindow - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Door_diagonal.package 57,313 Mesh Standard WallWindow Door (diagonal) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Door_main.package 68,380 Mesh Standard WallWindow Door - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_DoubleDoor_diagonal.package 89,950 Mesh Standard WallWindow DoubleDoor (diagonal) - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_DoubleDoor_main.package 98,245 Mesh Standard WallWindow DoubleDoor - by Numenor
  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_HiddenWindow_diagonal.package 42,190 Mesh Standard HIDDEN WallWindow (diagonal) - by Numenor
This window is supposed to HIDE into the walls!  Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_HiddenWindow_main.package 41,693 Mesh Standard HIDDEN WallWindow - by Numenor
This window is supposed to HIDE into the walls!  Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_diagonal.package 19,552 Mesh WallWindow - Wall Boundary (diagonal)
-  Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_main.package 36,319 Mesh WallWindow - Wall Boundary
Use this to &quot;close&quot; the wall side, where it joins an invisible or seamless window/door.
Made by Numenor - Do not clone - Visit www.numenor-moddings.com for full copyright policy..  
 54033 Defl:X 8129 85% 01-08-06 19:47 8981093d Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Window_diagonal.package
 72215 Defl:X 17767 75% 01-08-06 19:46 d603e873 Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Window_main.package
 57313 Defl:X 11913 79% 01-08-06 19:56 ad3c39d5 Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Door_diagonal.package
 68380 Defl:X 17878 74% 01-08-06 19:56 50fa13af Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_Door_main.package
 89950 Defl:X 14515 84% 01-08-06 19:57 a613256d Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_DoubleDoor_diagonal.package
 98245 Defl:X 20099 80% 01-08-06 19:57 fe0ee811 Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_DoubleDoor_main.package
 42190 Defl:X 4495 89% 01-09-06 21:09 19a38dc9 Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_HiddenWindow_diagonal.package
 41693 Defl:X 4526 89% 01-09-06 21:09 455ef546 Numenor_WallWindow_Standard_HiddenWindow_main.package
 19552 Defl:N 2412 88% 01-14-06 17:15 7fcdd673 Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_diagonal.package
 36319 Defl:N 8105 78% 01-14-06 17:06 44cf335b Numenor_WallWindow_WallBoundary_main.package
-------- ------- --- -------
 579890 109839 81% 10 files WallWindow documentation_(PDF).zip 4.35 MB 61,828 4577914 Defl:X 4563628 0% 02-10-06 18:36 43cc8d28 WallWindow documentation.pdf
-------- ------- --- -------
 4577914 4563628 0% 1 file WallWindow_Seamless_GarageDoor_NL-REQUIRED.rar 12.1 KB 112,655 
 Package file Size Type Description Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_GarageDoor.package 88,811 Mesh WallWindow Seamless Garage Door
by Numenor - DO NOT CLONE  
 Size Packed Ratio Date Time Attr CRC Meth Ver
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 Numenor_WallWindow_Seamless_GarageDoor.package
 88811 12312 13% 22-06-06 23:02 .....A. 349A6543 m5b 2.9
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 1 88811 12312 13%   Need help with downloading or installing content? Click this link! 
 
   
 
 861 Comments / Replies ( Who? ) 
 Page 1 of 35 1 2 3 4 Next&gt; Last » Jump 
 Jump to page: 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 35 1 2 3 4 Next&gt; Last » Jump 
 Jump to page: 
 
 
 
 Basic Download and Install Instructions: 

1. Download: Click the download link to save the .rar or .zip file(s) to your computer.

2. Extract: Use WinRAR (Windows) or Stuffit (Mac) to extract the .package file(s) from the .rar or .zip file(s).

3. Place in Downloads Folder: Cut and paste the .package file(s) into your Downloads folder:

 Windows XP: Documents and Settings\(Current User Account)\My Documents\EA Games\The Sims 2\Downloads\
 Windows Vista: Users\(Current User Account)\Documents\EA Games\The Sims 2\Downloads\
 Mac: Users\(Current User Account)\Documents\EA Games\The Sims 2\Downloads\ 


 Need more information? 

 For a full, complete guide to downloading complete with pictures and more information, see: Game Help: Downloading for Fracking Idiots . 

 Custom content not showing up in the game? See: Game Help: Getting Custom Content to Show Up .
 Anyone can use both .rar and .zip files easily! On Windows, use WinRAR . On Mac, use Stuffit .
 If you don&apos;t have a Downloads folder, just make one. See instructions at: Game Help: No Downloads Folder . 
 Tags # wallwindow , # glass , # transparent , # greenhouse Recolours There are 9 recolours of this mesh on MTS2:
 
 Click to see more...   Arabian Dream-middle eastern flavor window set 
   Testers Wanted:re-colors for Numenors wall windows 
   Updated 10-22: Creative/special recolors for Numenor&apos;s wall-window set 
   Recolour Template for&quot;WallWindows&quot;sets 
 
 These recolours may or may not be endorsed by this mesh creator. Recommendations Users who thanked this download also thanked:
 Designer LadderStairs - spacesaver! (2 tiles) Pack of FULLY ANIMATED spiral stairs Urban Reflections Part 2: The Glass Elevator Testers Wanted: Transparent Floor Tile Set &quot;Malibu Glass&quot;Series windows and doors The Eclectic Expressions Set The Pond in July (Small Update) Excell Exteriors Bay Window System - Set #1 **Base Game Compatable** *UPDATED - PLEASE RE-DOWNLOAD* Ladder with custom animations Waterfall shower - and tons of rocks! :D Overview Download Install Instructions Comments (861) Related Pages 
 
 Share this on... Twitter del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Search this Thread 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Some icons by http://dryicons.com . Contact Us - Archive - Top 
 
 861 Comments | Share this Top
	</body>
</document>
