<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005269" url="http://www.cruiseopinion.com/rcireviews/rccl-enchantment8.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:49" support="9" score="0.011530307693239109" bingtitle="rccl-enchantment8 - CruiseOpinion - #1 cruise review site on the ..." webtitle="rccl-enchantment8">
			<query id="001205" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001394" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000703" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000954" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000985" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001268" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000265" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000577" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>level fast food restaurant. The menu was uninspired in terms of ... I can&apos;t say there were enough to keep them busy ... It was also a good place to sit and read when you did not ...</description>
	<body>
		Note - this page contains multiple reviews. 

Name: Brenda J. Beyerlein
Email: bjbeyerlein@yahoo.com 
Age: 39
Occupation: Business Owner
NumberOfCruises: 4
TravelAgent: No
Ship: RoyalCaribbean-Enchantment
SailingDate: January 31, 1999
Itinerary: Western Caribbean
FoodDiningRoom: 90
CruiseDirector: 85
CabinComfort: 83
FoodRoomService: 90
CruiseStaff: 70
CabinAmenities: 89
FoodLidoDeck: 80
DiningRoomService: 95
CabinQuietness: 90
FoodMidnightBuffets: 78
CabinSteward: 90
ShoreExcVariety:
FoodVariety: 70
DeckService: 90
ShoreExcValue:
GoodForHoneymoon:
CasinoStaff: 92
PrivateIsland:
GoodForFamilies:
LoungeService: 85
TenderService: 95
GoodForSeniors:
BeautySalonStaff:
EntertainmentLounges: 89
WheelchairAccess:
ExerciseFacilities: 88
EntertShowLounge: 90
OverallPortsofCall: 90
BeautySalon: 87
EntertainmentPoolside: 75
CruiseActivities: 75
Casino: 85
AirSeaProgram:
MedicalFacilities: 90
ShipCleanliness: 80
EmbarkDisembark: 88
DiscoNightclubs: 79
DeckSpace: 90
Stabilization: 90
ShopsOnBoard: 90
SpaceRatio: 92
OverallCruiseValue: 75
Submit: Submit Review
Date: 25 Feb 1999
Time: 21:14:28
Remote Name: 209.153.185.134
Remote User:

Comments

I would like to begin by stating that this is my first cruise with RCCL, and probably my
last. I have cruised several
times and found the other cruise lines to be all around better cruises. To begin there was
a group of 28 people
who cruised together. Some of us had cruised before and some had never cruised at all. The
general consensus
of all, was that RCCL was NOT what we had expected. We found that the cabins were
extremely small in
comparison to the other ships. Our cabin was an inside cabin because we felt that we would
never really be
spending much time in it as we would be visiting with our friends. We were shocked though
to find that they were
as small as they were. Also we found that we had mold and mildew inside our shower and on
the shower curtain.
We commented on this to our room steward and figured it would be taken care of in a timely
manner. We by the
end of the week it still wasnt. We also were looking for something in our luggage
which we had stored under the
beds, and were appalled at what we saw there! The carpet in our cabin was stained really
bad also. I guess that I
imagined a much nicer and cleaner room considering that the ship is only 1 years old.
We also received upon
embarkation 3 room keys and asked for another, as there were 4 of us staying in the cabin
and were told we
couldnt have one. So for the remainder of the week, we had to juggle room keys which
was a real pain.

I would like to say that I found the food to be very good in the main dining room. I think
that the food at the
Windjammer Cafewas not that great. The breakfast and lunches were not much
different in variety from day to
day. I found this to be extremely boring. There were also days when they closed early and
times when there was
no place on the boat to eat, except to order in your room from room service. The pizzeria
even closed in the
afternoon and didnt reopen until very late in the evening. On the other cruise lines
that I have been on, there
was always an abundance of food. I also found that the Windjammer Cafewas dirty and
the wait staff not very
efficient. We noticed a smashed ketchup packet on the floor on Monday afternoon and
unbelievable it was still
there on Saturday evening during the Midnight buffet! I really dont think that they
didnt see it, I just think that it
was easier to ignore it. Unfortunately it didnt go away!!

I would also like to comment on the entertainment provided. The shows that were held after
dinner were average
to very good. But the entertainment after the shows, was non existent or really bad. There
was a band that would
play 1 hour, maybe 1 hours. I came home and rechecked the daily events letter left in
our room every evening,
and found that we didnt miss it, there just wasnt anything happening! The
disco was a joke, playing 90s retro
disco music? I have never heard of this type of music, and was told by the staff D.J. that
I must live in the sticks,
because ALL the major Clubs play this kind of music. Well, I didnt appreciate his
comment. I do have 2 teenage
daughters who were at home, but boy did I wish they had been with us, so I could have
gotten their opinions. I
had and have still never heard of the music that was played in the disco. There were
some 16 year old
Venezuelan girls, 126 of them to be exact, and even though the ship rules were no on under
18 allowed, they
sure didnt seem to realize they didnt belong in the disco, nor did the ships
staff. Yes, they were even serving
them alcohol. Im not a total prude, but 16 is a little young, when the ships
drinking age was 21, and it was very
obvious that they were not 21. Some even looked younger than 16. Enough on this subject.
Probably the biggest
complaint I have with RCCL is that the staff was very, very rude and uncooperative. I had
the opportunity to
discuss the coldness and standoff actions of the staff and found what this particular
employee said, very
unsettling. I wouldnt go into great detail, for his sake, but the crew has very
strict rules they must follow, or they
will be terminated immediately. I asked him if this meant that his conservation with us
shouldnt be happening,
and he said probably not. I then asked why he would chance the brief conservation with us,
and it was only
because we were in port and the ship had very few passengers aboard, and the staff was
also in port. Sad I
thought. The next day I went to the Pursers desk and asked if they new approximately
what time an excursion
might be back and was adamantly told that the Shore Excursion Desk was to my left and I
might want to step over
there and ask them. Now understand that this is less than 15 feet apart, if that, and they
were closed, due to the
fact that we were in port! I then stated that they were closed until later, and toldI guess then you will have to
come back. I was really upset with their coldness and rudeness. I was only trying to
figure out what time my
husband might be getting back from golfing! I wanted him to go to the falls and climb them
with the rest of the
group, and we were all willing to wait for him if he wasnt going to be long.
Unfortunately, I got mad and left, and
let the staff ruin my day. My finally episode with the Pursers Desk was even worse.
It was the final night of our
cruise, and I was packing. I stopped our room steward and asked him when I might expect
our purchases of
liquor to our stateroom, from the shop we purchased it at in Grand Cayman. The steward
looked at me and
stated that I should of had it the day before. He then politely told me to go to the
Pursers desk and there they
could help me. Boy was he wrong!! They informed me that it wasnt there problem, and
I should have told them
yesterday that I didnt get it. Well every other cruise lines we have even been on,
your liquor didnt come until the
last night. This is the policy of the other lines so that you drink their liquor and not
yours. I have no problem with
this rule, so I wasnt at all concerned until Saturday evening. The purser desk said
that they would try and locate
the person in charge of handling problems, but didnt know if they could reach her.
Reach her, my gosh, its a
boat!! She should be pretty easy to find. They then said no, shes not easy to find,
because it was her night off,
and she doesnt have a pager! What about that loud speaker that works at all other
times, I asked. They looked
dumbfounded at me like I was the idiot. Well 4 hours later, they found her. I dont
think they looked before I went
back the 3rd time. She then informed me that the ship wasnt really responsible, but
they would see if they could
help me. I informed her that the shop that we purchased the liquor at was a recommended
shop of the ships and
she said oh well. They decided that they would look into this the next week or two, and we
should be notified of
their findings at a later date. Then she told me I should have been up to the
Pursers desk earlier, before that
ships stores closed and they probably could have replaced some of the rum cakes, and
liquor from their
inventory. Me, come up there earlier?? I had been there 4 hours earlier, before the shops
closed, but she was
unavailable, so could we go now and get them? No was the answer I received, because they
were at that time
doing their inventory and taking anything now would mess up there figures. What a lame
excuse.

I was never so glad to be home from vacation, and when someone at my business asks how it
went, I refer to it
asThe Cruise from Hell. There are some positive sides to our vacation. We had
read on the Internet that there
was never enough chairs by the pool side. We never had any problem finding a group of
chairs for at least 4 of
us. There were some pool activities that we enjoyed watching. The solarium was also a nice
feature that we
found the men in the group to enjoy. We girls could lay in the sun and still have the
company of our husbands.
The guys played alot of shuffleboard on sea days and also entered the ping pong tournament
once.

The general areas of the ship we kept in a pretty clean state. The dining room staff was
accommodating also.

The ports of call were also nice. It was not my first time to the 3 islands, only Key
West. I wish that the engine on
the ship hadnt been broken and we could have spent more time in the port. I think
that there was alot more to
see, but we didnt really have enough time to venture far. Cozumel is probably on of
my favorite ports. We rented
a jeep, at the suggestion of someone at this web site and found it to be a great idea. I
have previously been to
Cozumel 2 times already and just wanted to see other thing besides the recommended tours
the ship offers. We
went to the Chankanaab National Park for snorkeling and really enjoyed this. The fish and
coral are
unbelievable!! There were lockers for rent along with little shops to rent your equipment
if you dont have your
own. We have our own, so I dont know if it was a good price or not. The gardens at
the Park are really worth
spending the $7.00 to see. We saw alot of beautiful flowers, animals, and trees. I would
recommend this to
anyone. What I found to be the most shocking, was the other side of the island. I guess I
never really gave much
thought to the ocean current, and what the other side would be like. Boy were we
surprised! The blow holes were
really neat and enjoyed walking out on the shoreline and the rocks. I would caution
anyone, that the undertow
can be extremely dangerous also. We stop at a little resort and had a great authentic
Mexican lunch. It was great
and very reasonable. The little roadside shops were also fun to shop at. I guess when I go
to these islands, I
enjoy seeing their culture and seeing how they live. Sad at times, but it only makes you
appreciate you own life.

I think that Jamaica leaves little to explain. All that anyone has ever told you about
Jamaica, is probably true and
accurate. Unfortunately it can be a dangerous country to visit. I would recommend to
visitors to take an excursion
from the ship. I did that the last time I was in Jamaica and felt much safer than this
time. I would highly
recommend the horseback riding on the beach if you enjoy riding. It is really great! The
horses arent old nags
like I expected, but very nice ones. The falls are also fun to climb and even just visit
and take pictures if you dont
feel up to the climb. The vendors on your way out take NO for an answer fairly well also.
We never had any
problems by just saying No.

Grand Cayman is very overrated as far as Im concerned. I have a very hard time
paying the prices they ask for
the products they sell. The liquor is about the only thing I have ever found to be a good
deal. This was my 3rd
trip to the island and find that it gets more expensive every year. We paid $27.00
(American) for 2 hamburgers,
fries, and 2 soft drinks-in a cup. I guess when our friends ordered 4 Pina Coladas, and
were charged $42.50, I
really decided the prices are outrageous. While in Grand Cayman be sure and try the rum
cake, and be sure to
bring some home to your family and friends, as the small cakes make great gifts,

The disembarkation process went really well. I think that we were off the ship and had our
luggage by 9:30 a.m.,
which really wasnt to bad considering all the people and luggage that needs to be
claimed.

All in all, this was probably the worst cruise I have ever been on, and like I said,
Im sure it will be the last one for
my husband and I with RCCL.
 
Name: Dennis and Debra Moyer
Email: Moyerfam@pa.net 
Age: 46&amp;44
Occupation: Store manager and RN
NumberOfCruises: 2
TravelAgent: Yes
Ship: RoyalCaribbean-Enchantment
SailingDate: 2/28/99
Itinerary: Western Caribbean
FoodDiningRoom: 95
CruiseDirector: 90
CabinComfort: 99
FoodRoomService:
CruiseStaff: 90
CabinAmenities: 95
FoodLidoDeck: 90
DiningRoomService: 99
CabinQuietness: 99
FoodMidnightBuffets: 85
CabinSteward: 90
ShoreExcVariety: 85
FoodVariety: 80
DeckService: 90
ShoreExcValue: 80
GoodForHoneymoon:
CasinoStaff:
PrivateIsland:
GoodForFamilies: 90
LoungeService:
TenderService: 80
GoodForSeniors: 80
BeautySalonStaff:
EntertainmentLounges: 85
WheelchairAccess: 80
ExerciseFacilities:
EntertShowLounge: 80
OverallPortsofCall: 90
BeautySalon:
EntertainmentPoolside: 90
CruiseActivities: 90
Casino: 85
AirSeaProgram: 85
MedicalFacilities:
ShipCleanliness: 90
EmbarkDisembark: 95
DiscoNightclubs:
DeckSpace: 85
Stabilization: 85
ShopsOnBoard: 801
SpaceRatio: 85
OverallCruiseValue: 88
Submit: Submit Review
Date: 10 Mar 1999
Time: 14:21:16
Remote Name: duppp08.mllr2.perry.pa.net
Remote User:

Comments

We took this cruise for our 25th anniversary and were overall quite pleased with our
experience. We used the day
ahead program and were disappointed that we didn&apos;t leave Harrisburg until late in the
afternoon Saturday and
didn&apos;t arrive in Miami until 10 PM that night. On our previous curise flew out early on
Saturday and had time in
Miami for sight seeing. We might not have used the day ahead program had we known how late
we would arrive in
Miami. But there are definite advantages like not having to worry about luggage or check
in at the pier however.
Luggage goes straight to the ship and check in is done in the hotel. The food and service
in the main dining room
was excellent.

When our waiter found out it was our anniversary they brought us a cake and sang &apos;Happy
Versary&apos;.
Lunch selection in the dining room was poor and we found the Wind Jammer to be a much
better lunch spot. The
hot dogs, hamburgers, and pizza by the solarium pool over the lunch hour was great. We got
back late from an
excursion late one day and ate dinner at the Wind Jammer and found the dinner selection
skimpy. We found some
of the staff at the Wind Jammer to be aloof, much different than our other cruise on Royal
Caribbean. The best
luncheon we had there was the day our dining room waiter was there. He saw to it our table
was bussed promptly
etc. I was a little surprised how candid his conversation was about the new Voyager about
to be launched. He was
rather verbal about some of the employees unhappiness with the company building bigger and
bigger ships when
the current ones are sailing at 60% capacity. We really loved the solarium pool. We had
read on other reviews
complaints that the deck chairs were in short supply on at sea days. We also found a
shortage of deck chairs just
before lunch but if you hung out for awhile eventually people left and you were able to
find a chair. The
entertainment was fair to good at best. The production numbers were of fair quality. The
singing was good but the
overall program left at lot to be desired.

The comedians were quite good however. One problem seem to be a drop
in the amount of activity between 10 PM and Midnight. The show ended at 10 PM and it was
1130 PM or later until
anything else began. It made staying up for the Midnight buffets difficult. I also found
announcements for bingo, the
casino, horse racing, and art autions to be quite irritating. I felt they were trying to
squeeze more money out of us.
The shore excursions were good. We did the jeep safari in Mexico and the Dunns River Falls
and Prospect
Plantation in Jamaica. The beach on the jeep safari was wonderful. I did find the shopping
a little disappointing. We
weren&apos;t told about all the shops just off the pier in Cozumel so I didn&apos;t go leave the
ship until just before our shore
excursion. I was dismayed to realize I could have done some shopping without taking the
taxi to town. Grand
Cayman and Jamaica were disappointing for shopping unless you wanted jewelery or liquor.
We did buy new
wedding rings in Jamaica and are quite pleased with our purchase. Overall we were pleaseed
with the cleanlines
and maintanence of the ship. We had an ocean view room on the main deck and were very
happy with the size,
amount of closets and storage, and the view.


 
Name: Scott Shelton
Email: sshelton@mpinet.net 
Age: 46
Occupation: Network Engineer
NumberOfCruises: 1
TravelAgent: No
Ship: RoyalCaribbean-Enchantment
SailingDate: 2/21/99
Itinerary: E. Carribean
FoodDiningRoom: 93
CruiseDirector: 96
CabinComfort: 94
FoodRoomService:
CruiseStaff: 95
CabinAmenities: 93
FoodLidoDeck:
DiningRoomService: 97
CabinQuietness: 94
FoodMidnightBuffets: 92
CabinSteward: 98
ShoreExcVariety: 95
FoodVariety: 91
DeckService:
ShoreExcValue:
GoodForHoneymoon: 92
CasinoStaff:
PrivateIsland:
GoodForFamilies: 89
LoungeService:
TenderService: 92
GoodForSeniors: 93
BeautySalonStaff:
EntertainmentLounges:
WheelchairAccess:
ExerciseFacilities: 88
EntertShowLounge:
OverallPortsofCall: 91
BeautySalon:
EntertainmentPoolside: 90
CruiseActivities: 90
Casino:
AirSeaProgram:
MedicalFacilities:
ShipCleanliness: 95
EmbarkDisembark: 94
DiscoNightclubs:
DeckSpace: 88
Stabilization: 89
ShopsOnBoard: 90
SpaceRatio: 90
OverallCruiseValue: 95
Submit: Submit Review
Date: 19 Mar 1999
Time: 11:31:36
Remote Name: 138.210.134.108
Remote User:

Comments

This was a first time cruise for me and my wife. We live in Florida, so it was convenient
getting to the Port of Miami.
We boarded a comfortable bus in Orlando at 6:30am, Sunday and drove to Miami. It took
about four hours, but
time went by quickly, watching a couple of movies in route. We arrived at the dock at
10:30am and we were some
of the first people in line to board. They did not start boarding, however, until 11:30am,
but that was ok. After
getting on the ship, we used our cell phone to call Orlando, to say farewell to our house
sitter and talk with our 15
year old son. Then, we had a very filling lunch in the Windjammer Caf. We liked eating
there for breakfast and
lunches. The food was good; some of cakes and pastries could stand some improving though.
Tried to always get
a table by the window, to get a scenic view, as we ate. That first day was very sunny, so
we got a head start on sun
tanning and relaxing on deck while others were arriving and boarding. We received a free
room- upgrade from the
1st deck to 7th deck, along with a free bottle of non-alcoholic champagne (thanks to our
travel agent-Margie), so it
made our cruising experience even nicer. Our cabin person was from India and did a top
notch job. Our luggage
did not show up at the room until about 5pm, but we got them in time to be dressed for the
6pm seating in the main
dining room. When we were seated that first night, I found that we were at a window table
with a good group of
people. The food was great throughout the week, with a good variety and selection. Our
waiter was from Turkey
and his assistant from Poland. They both did an outstanding job. The headwaiter showed up
almost every night
and helped some of the table guests with things like taking lobster meat out the shell,
etc. There was a minor
incident, when I found a small piece of a nutshell in the banana bread. I told the waiter
and at the next meal, the
headwaiter gave us a free bottle of Champagne. I gave it to the rest of the table, since I
don&apos;t drink, but I thought
that was very considerate.

The first two days at sea were a little cloudy, but we kept busy investigating the ship or
just lying, around and
relaxing. We observed a Sexy Legs contest for the men, near the pool. After seeing the
winners in the different
divisions, I could of beat the guy that won the Most Hairy legs, but oh well, it was funny
watching. The evening
shows were very entertaining, some of the best in the cruise liner industry, based on what
I have read and heard.
Most nights, we went to bed by 10:30pm or so. One night, my wife went up to check out the
midnight buffet, She
said it looked wonderful. Although our room was on the inside, there was a channel on the
TV that showed a live
view from the bridge, looking ahead to where we were going. It is the next best thing to a
window, but I think I will
get a room with a window next time. Our room was located a short distance down the hall
from the game room,
which had a balcony. Occasionally, I would bring a chair outside there, sip on a cool
drink and watch the ocean go
by.

The First port was St. Martin. The ship anchored just off shore and waiting for the tender
was no big deal. We had
a rental car reserved and found out that we would be able to be the first ones ashore
because of that, so that was
pretty neat. The tender is not a little wooden boat with an interesting looking person
rowing you ashore to a
deserted looking island and being greeted by a small group of natives dancing around a
fire like you see in the ad
on TV. But it was a motorized boat that held about 120 people and it moved everyone ashore
pretty quickly. When
we reached the shore, we were greeted by a lot of local people..everyone from hair
braiders to taxi drivers. After
taking a taxi to the rental car location, we found the manager had gone to town for an
hour, but we finally got our
car and were on our way. We drove around the island seeing many beautiful beaches,
stopping every now and
then to snorkel or lie in the sun. Saw a few nudies, when we were on the French side of
the island, but didn&apos;t stare
too long. Some of the roads were very rough and the hills were like that roller coaster
ride at Busch Gardens.
Heading back to drop the car off, I stopped to get gas. Everything was in liters and the
conversion wasn&apos;t straight in
my mind, so the service station attendant could have ripped me off. No prices were posted.
All I do know is, $7.00
worth of gas got pumped pretty darn quick. Anyway, we got back to ship safely and all in
all, we enjoyed our time at
St. Martin.

The Second stop was St. Thomas. Beautiful harbor with very scenic surroundings. The port
and island seamed to
be cleaner and more organized that St. Martin. Before we could depart, all foreign
passengers had to report to the
immigration officials. There was a couple that took forever to report in. They must have
been sleeping or
something, but they were finally located and their passports reviewed. After that delay, a
few irritated passengers
were ready to have them&quot;walk the plank&quot;. But all that passed and we were on our
way in a van taxi, to Red Hook,
to catch the ferry to St. John. It runs on the hour and we missed it by 15 minutes. Too
bad about that we had the
delay back at the ship. St. Johns was the most beautiful island of all. After arriving at
Cruz Bay, we took a taxi to
Trunk bay to snorkel the underwater trail, but when we got there, it was unusually rough
and the water cloudy. It
was enjoyable and relaxing anyway. My wife and I returned to St. Thomas in time to do a
little shopping, but wished
we had stayed longer at St. Johns. On our way to shop, we heard a lady, yelling,&quot;I
need a taxi, I need a taxi, when
you want one you can never get one! I am going to report this to the Chamber of
Commerce!&quot;, and immediately taxi
drivers made their presence. There is always someone in the crowd that is a complainer.
Taxis were readily
available, everywhere, so I don&apos;t know why she was having such a problem.

Well, before we knew it, it was time to leave St. Thomas, but we would take with us, the
wonderful experiences of
our excursions in these beautiful islands. In route back to Miami, we stopped over at
Nassau with its light blue
waters. We did some snorkeling at a nearby beach and saw all kinds of sea life. Then, that
after noon, cruised
back to Miami and our debarkation. We docked early Sunday morning. The offload went very
smoothly, found our
baggage with no problem. As I sat there, waiting for the Cruise Connection bus, I watched
the new passengers
arrive and wait to board the next cruise with the look of excitement and anticipation on
their faces. I reflected back
upon our time spent in the past week, wishing we could board with them and do it all over
again. However, life must
go on. The bus arrived and we boarded, all tanned, rested and with peace in our hearts
knowing that maybe
someday we would experience another cruise to some far away place. But for now, we have
the forever memories
of the time we spent together on this lovely trip to a tropical paradise.

See you again someday, Royal Caribbean. - Scott&amp;Gail Shelton
 
Name: Gordon Stromkins
Email: gstromkins@sd46.bc.ca 
Age: 42
Occupation: Teacher
NumberOfCruises: 3
TravelAgent: No
Ship: RoyalCaribbean-Enchantment
SailingDate: July 98
Itinerary: Western Carribbean
FoodDiningRoom: 95
CruiseDirector: 85
CabinComfort: 90
FoodRoomService: 96
CruiseStaff: 95
CabinAmenities: 90
FoodLidoDeck: 80
DiningRoomService: 95
CabinQuietness: 95
FoodMidnightBuffets: 85
CabinSteward: 95
ShoreExcVariety: 90
FoodVariety: 95
DeckService: 80
ShoreExcValue: 85
GoodForHoneymoon: 85
CasinoStaff:
PrivateIsland:
GoodForFamilies: 80
LoungeService: 80
TenderService: 80
GoodForSeniors: 99
BeautySalonStaff:
EntertainmentLounges: 96
WheelchairAccess: 96
ExerciseFacilities: 99
EntertShowLounge: 90
OverallPortsofCall: 85
BeautySalon: 90
EntertainmentPoolside: 90
CruiseActivities: 90
Casino: 88
AirSeaProgram:
MedicalFacilities:
ShipCleanliness: 95
EmbarkDisembark: 80
DiscoNightclubs: 90
DeckSpace: 95
Stabilization: 90
ShopsOnBoard: 90
SpaceRatio: 99
OverallCruiseValue: 95
Submit: Submit Review
Date: 05 Apr 1999
Time: 11:39:07
Remote Name: 206.87.192.10
Remote User:

Comments

This was the third cruise for my wife and I. The others were on RCCL Nordic Empress and
Holland&apos;s Westerdam.
This was the best yet, even though we brought my mother-in-law along.

We used our usual, cheapest cabin strategy. Got one that fit the three of us just fine. I
got the bunk that hung
down from the ceiling.

We went ashore at all the stops, Key West, Cozumel, Jamaica, and Georgetown. Cruise lines
overcharge for their
excursions, so in Key West we took a local bus tour for half the money. Granted, we&apos;d been
there before. In
Mexico, took the line&apos;s tour to Tulum, as I didn&apos;t want to miss it. Ochios Rios, grabbed a
cab to town for beach and
shopping. A little scary, but what the hay? Georgetown, went snorkeling on our own for
free from a hotel&apos;s facilities.
We knew we could do that because we have friends who used to live there. Place called
Sunset House that we
walked to. Maybe a half mile to the right or where the tenders dock.

The ship herself was perfect. Cruise ships have become somewhat of a hobby of mine. Must
have a dozen books,
and read brocures all the time. Narrowed it down to Enchantment or Granduer as my top
choices. Stops and price
fit, to we were set. Layout and decore are perfect. PERFECT, I tell you! Crew and food as
to be expected on a
first-rate vessel.

We ran one entire day-at-see in a strong gale...that&apos;s one or two levels down from a
hurricane...and I don&apos;t think
most people even noticed. Very stable.

 
Name: Henry&amp;Judith Beumler
Email: beumler@erols.com 
Age: 57
Occupation: President, Dimensions Health Network
NumberOfCruises: 2
TravelAgent: No
Ship: RoyalCaribbean-Enchantment
SailingDate: May 23, 1999
Itinerary: Western Caribbean
FoodDiningRoom: 78
CruiseDirector: 88
CabinComfort: 95
FoodRoomService: 79
CruiseStaff: 85
CabinAmenities: 95
FoodLidoDeck: 81
DiningRoomService: 95
CabinQuietness: 95
FoodMidnightBuffets: 69
CabinSteward: 100
ShoreExcVariety: 95
FoodVariety: 75
DeckService: 70
ShoreExcValue: 95
GoodForHoneymoon:
CasinoStaff: 85
PrivateIsland:
GoodForFamilies:
LoungeService: 65
TenderService: 95
GoodForSeniors: 85
BeautySalonStaff:
EntertainmentLounges: 90
WheelchairAccess:
ExerciseFacilities:
EntertShowLounge: 79
OverallPortsofCall: 90
BeautySalon:
EntertainmentPoolside: 92
CruiseActivities:
Casino: 88
AirSeaProgram: 90
MedicalFacilities:
ShipCleanliness: 85
EmbarkDisembark: 99
DiscoNightclubs: 85
DeckSpace: 95
Stabilization: 95
ShopsOnBoard: 92
SpaceRatio: 95
OverallCruiseValue: 75
Submit: Submit Review
Date: 31 May 1999
Time: 19:27:52
Remote Name: 207-172-45-48.s48.tnt5.brd.va.dialup.rcn.com
Remote User:

Comments

This was our second cruise. Our first cruise was to the Eastern Caribbean on the Century
with Celebrity Cruises and
since we had a limited window to take this cruise and there were no Celebrity Cruises
available to the Western
Caribbean we thought Royal Caribbean would be an acceptable substitute. They had, after
all, just bought Celebrity
Cruise line so we thought theircorporate culture&apos; and service philosophy would be
similar. We did our homework
and compared the size of the ships, passengers to crew ratios, and read the comments on
this site (although most
of them were over a year old) to determine if the cruise would meet our needs. There were
some very negative and
some not so negative but few in our age range (55 and 57) that were not at least
acceptable. All of the following
comparisons are therefore based on our experience with Celebrity and comparing those to
our most recent
experience on Royal Caribbean. I will make these comments in the same sequence as the
above rating categories
to let you follow our rating process.

Food-Dining Room - 78 - The food was what you would get at Red Lobster, Denny&apos;s, TGI
Fridays, or other upper
level fast food restaurant. The menu was uninspired in terms of overall selection although
they did have some
excellent soups but these were few and far between on a seven days, expensive cruise. The
salad dressings could
and may have come from bottles. The vegetables were 50/50 frozen to fresh. All courses
were small portions, the
appetizers being extremely so, and the most memorable example being the lobster tails
which the experienced
RCCL cruisers warned us to order two at the start. My wife ordered the grouper and was
served a filet that was not
grouper, her favorite fish, and we have yet to identify the species. The meat was never to
order, we like medium
rare, and was consistently overdone, to include the prime rib. Deserts were equally dull,
which meant ordering ice
cream, two scoops, as the most consistent expectation. Even this was not up to Baskin
Robbins 31 Flavors (forget
Ben and Jerrys) and the pistachio did not have bits of nut. Souffles looked good but were
tasteless as were the
accompanying sauces. The final insult was the baked Alaska which was served in precut
individual servings but
definitely not freshly prepared because even the quarter inch meringue was frozen. I might
also mention that we
were seated a table of six (two other delightful and experienced cruising couples) in a
back room out of the main
seating in the lowerMy Fair Lady&apos; dining room. Both couples had used RCCL cruises
in the past and stated the
food did not meet their previous expectations but that it was about average. This had
definitely not been our
experience on Celebrity where every evening meal was apresentation&apos; and every
selection was what you would
have found in an expense account restaurant such as Ruth&apos;s Chris, Morton&apos;s, or the 701 in
Washington, D.C.

Food-Room Service - 79 - We did not order food to the room but the overall service to the
room was slow. We did
order coffee each morning and beverages at other times.

Food-Lido Deck - 81 - Again, nothing exceptional. We would have both breakfast and lunch
in this area which is
known as the Windjammer Restaurant. We did not use the hamburger and pizza grill area in
the Solarium. Breakfast
was good in that made to order omelettes and the basic scrambled eggs, bacon, and sausage
were prepared
without incident. The French toast was not particularly good and the attempt at biscuits
and gravy with brown gravy
was a complete disaster. The fruit selection was common, cantaloupe and some honeydew
melon with occasional
watermelon. No mangos, papaya, or kiwi fruit, but they did have pineapple. They also had
the usual assortment of
pastries. They did have lox and some other breakfast cold items but again, nothing that
was truly spectacular.
Lunch was about the same with emphasis on a very limited hot buffet and selection of
prepared salads and a
nonexistent salad bar. You would think that in a hot weather area, they would have a more
dramatic selection of
salads and salad dressings but both areas lacked imagination. They did have a sandwich bar
that preparedwrap&apos;
sandwiches and deli like submarine sandwiches which were very good. No ice creams at the
noon meal nor frozen
yogurt dispenser. Again the contrast with Celebrity where the noon buffet meals were like
the midnight buffets and
showed enthusiasm, interest, and imagination with numerous choices.

Food-Midnight Buffets - 69 - They were nonexistent with the exception of the one gala
event. At all other times they
would pass around finger foods in the casino or other common areas. On Celebrity there was
a midnight buffet
every night with a theme of one type or another such as Mexican food night, Caribbean food
night, etc. I think that
most cruise lines will be cutting back on this event as they are not well attended and
probably are money losers for
the lines. It appears that RCCL has made this decision. If you want something to eat late
at night on RCCL you
order room service and hope you do not fall asleep before it gets there. It is also
interesting that there were very few
hors d&apos;oeuvres in the cocktail lounges at any time of the day or night.

Food-Variety - 75 - I think I have covered all of this above but the following will serve
to sum up the experience:
uninspiring with limited quantity and selection. If your main reason to go on a cruise is
a fine dining experience, this
is not the ship nor the chef for you.

Good for Honeymoon - Not rated. Good for Families - I can&apos;t rate this because I did not
use the services but there
did seem to be a lot of children on board and numerous children&apos;s activities. I can&apos;t say
there were enough to keep
them busy, however, because they were always underfoot. In the evening you would be
sitting in the cocktail lounge
for a relaxing before dinner drink only to have a bunch of preteens go roaring through the
area. The crew, by the
way, did nothing to enforce decorum in these areas.

Good for Seniors - 85 - All of our table had plenty to do and did not feel pressured to do
more nor did they find
there were not enough activities. As the youngest couple in this group, we did more of the
active things but all of us
had a good time.

Wheelchair Access - We did not need these services but there were at least five (5)
wheelchair passengers and two
who were on excursions with us. On board activities were not a problem at all and they
appeared to be having a
good time. I am assuming the handicapped accessible areas in the bathrooms and other areas
met OSHA
requirements for grab rails and access but I did not inquire about this.

Overall Ports of Call - 90 - Western Caribbean was great!! The ports of call were Key
West, Cozumel and Playa del
Carmen in Mexico, Ochos Rios in Jamaica, and Georgetown in Grand Cayman. These were much
better in terms of
the overall experience. Most noted was that in the Eastern Caribbean we quit taking the
tours because every one
stopped half a dozen times at the side of the road tee shirt sales and souvenir stands.
There was only one such
incident in Mexico and the rest of the tours did not stop for those sorts of things. The
method of selecting your tours
was haphazard but since we got all of our first choices, I can&apos;t really complain. They
have you fill out a tour selection
form at the start of the cruise and then dump them in a box where they sort them out and
deliver them to your room
the next day. They should at least have a date stamp so the first come have a better
chance of getting their
selections. One couple did not get any first selections but were able to talk their way
onto some of the tours they
wanted later.

Cruise Activities - We did not really participate in any of the activities but they did
seem to be well run and we did not
hear any complaints about them. We did witness the activities around the pool such as the
dance classes, sexy legs
contest, belly flop competition, and water volleyball which all had excellent
participation. Everyone seemed to enjoy
the activities.

Medical Activities - We did not use but they were directly accessible in the main elevator
area and clearly identified.

Disco/Nightclubs - 85 - They were good in that there seemed to be a club for everyone. It
was clear that the Crown
Viking Lounge was for the singles and the young rockers while the other lounges were for
other sets. Our favorite
was the piano bar in the Schooner Lounge but we did not spend a lot of time there. The
problem once again was
the uncontrolled children and the staff&apos;s unwillingness or inability to limit their access
to what was clearly an adult
area.

Shops on Board - 92 - Very good with a much larger variety than on the Century. The value
was excellent compared
to shops on shore or stateside and the quality was also very good.

Cruise Director - 88 - Very good but just a little over the edge which is hard to say
about a cruise director who is
required by their job description to be a bit over the edge. Ken Rush has been doing this
for a while and is slick but
more than a little full of himself.

Cruise Staff - 85 - Helpful when their services were required but did not go out of their
way to be friendly. They
displayed competent professionalism, which is good but not excellent. Now would also be a
good time to mention
that the Celebrity Cruise - Century had a unique feature that allowed you to check the
current status of your
shipboard account by clicking on your TV screen in your room. That way you did not have to
wait to the end of your
cruise to try and match all of the receipts you had been saving to theofficial&apos;
tally of the ship&apos;s accounting system of
your on board credit card.

Dining Room Service - 95 - If it had not been for our Waiter - Mr. Moses and Assistant
Waiter - Mr. Januiszc, the
meals would have been down right tedious. The only other thing that made them memorable
was the excellent
company of our table mates. The wine steward was also outstanding and learned to pronounce
every single last
name at the table which were not easy last names to pronounce. We truly did have good
people but they were over
stretched. They had too many tables to take care of and therefore could not devote the
time to making this service
exceptional. Again a comparison to the Century where your table was never without a waiter
or assistant waiter who
insured you did not wait for water or anything else. Where the waiter waited until every
guest was served and had
tried their food. One memorable experience was not having the steak rare enough on the
Century and they took it
back and replaced it then the head waiter insisted on carving it at the table . . . now
that is service!! On this cruise,
the Head Waiter was seldom around, self-centered and a bore. On this cruise, we sent one
thing back and waited
almost the entire meal for a replacement and then it wasn&apos;t right either. We quickly
learned to order two things and
just keep quiet. Now would also be a good time to interject that the other people cruising
were also not really clued
in either. Onformal night&apos; there were few who were in formal attire, a few more who
were wearing suits, but most
appeared lucky to be wearing a coat and tie. Again, the cruise staff did not correct them
but let them into the dining
room. There were supposed to be shirts worn in all dining areas but this was not enforced
in the Windjammer. In
short, the dress code was largely ignored by the passengers and nothing was done by the
crew to enforce it.

Cabin Steward - 100 - Another truly bright spot and an exceptionally outstanding star. Mr.
Warner, had our room
cleaned whenever we stepped out. On our first moment in the cabin he was right there to
introduce himself and
noted that we had two single beds instead of the double or queen that we had requested. By
the time we got back
from making our shore excursion selections, the bed had been replaced and made up. We did
not have any cute
folded towels but he did arrange the pillows differently each day but the bottom line is
that he always had the cabin
made up when we came back from shore excursions or just from lunch or breakfast.

Deck Service - 70 - They were humorless, rarely there when needed, too few in number, too
busy talking among
themselves, and provided barely adequate surly service. The bartenders at the pool bar
were very good and knew
their business but again, overworked because of the lack of support by the deck service
staff. The one exception to
this were the guys that ran the towel service and kept the deck chairs clean and arranged.
We have to agree that
these are the hardest working guys on the ship. They were constantly picking up after
trashy passengers, keeping
the deck chairs arranged, and apparently working 24 hours a day. They were truly hard
working dedicated
professionals. A great group!!!

Casino Staff - 85 - They were both friendly and professional which is tough in a casino.

Lounge Service - 65 - Poor to bad. Long wait for the initial order in a lounge that was
far from crowded, unfriendly
service, and poor return time. I recognize there is a difference betweenhovering&apos;
and good service buthovering&apos;
was not a problem on this ship. Getting good service was a problem. This was a staff that
did not understand that
the focus of maintaining employment was getting repeat customers by providing outstanding
service to people who
can and are willing to pay for it at mostly exorbitant rates.

Beauty Salon Staff - We did not use their services because we could not get scheduled for
the services at the times
we wanted to use them. The staff was friendly and professional when asked questions about
their services.

Exercise Facilities - We did not use them but they did have an excellent fitness program
and a very well equipped
exercise area.

Beauty Salon - We did not use.

Casino - 88 - The casino was somewhat confusing and gave the impression of being jammed in
a very small space.
The slot machines were not well organized in terms of being separated by type and the
distance between them was
tight. We are not big people and we had trouble maneuvering in this area, especially since
it was the main transit
area between the theater and the rest of the ship. Good idea, poorly executed. I might
also mention that these
machines did not appear to pay off as often but then, that is why they call it gambling.

Ship Cleanliness - 85 - Our stateroom and hallways were excellent but there were some
stained carpets and
common areas that needed vacuuming. This was minor but the fact that we noticed it at all
was different from our
previous experience. Enchantment of the Seas is a gorgeous ship in so many respects. The
use of art work and the
crediting of the art was exceptional. The use of glass, brass, and wood with the
complementary color schemes were
truly outstanding. Little touches like the day of the week carpets in the elevators were
exceptional. These things
made you really look at the ship and when you did, you saw that not all the glass was
clean and not all of the floors
had been vacuumed. Again, this could have been due to the large number of children,
preteens and teenagers who
were roaming the ship at all hours of the day and night and who never seemed to be without
something to eat in
their hands. These same children had no qualm about dropping what they were eating
anywhere (in addition to
eating anywhere) and again, there were no rules enforced to change these habits.

Deck Space - 95 - We had read on this and other sites that deck space was at a premium but
we did not find this to
be a problem. We normally ate breakfast at about 8:00 a.m. and always found an excellent
space by the pool to
sunbathe. Too much in my case when I fell asleep and turned into Lobster Man. We preferred
the outdoor pool to
the Solarium and we did hear that there was not a lot of room in the Solarium area. We did
look at that area but did
not think it offered the best chance of good sun. Bottom line. Plenty of deck space and we
did not have a problem.

Space Ratio - 95 - The interior space was used well and never felt crowded. You did have
rush when the shows let
out of the theater but that was to be expected. Overall the ship is very well designed and
very well used with the
above exception noted in the casino.

Cabin Comfort - 95 - Excellent cabin. We were in 7056, close to the middle of the ship
with a balcony. We will never
be without a balcony again because this gives you that added bit of privacy and comfort
that a regular cabin does
not. We used the balcony for early coffee and to watch the ship dock or depart. It was
also a good place to sit and
read when you did not need any more sun and wanted a little more quiet than you could get
at pool side. The
bathroom could be larger but it was adequate and the best we have had so far. Storage was
adequate. This ship
does not store your suitcases but requires you to store them under your bed. Great idea
for stashing your
purchases and keeping a running idea of what will fit for your return and what will not.

Cabin Amenities - 95 - The balcony has been mentioned but the room had a TV with three
movie channels and the
usual run of shore excursion and shopping information. A neat addition was the ship cam
that showed a view out the
front of the ship and ship information such as the speed, direction, distance and time
traveled, distance and time to
next port, etc. They did not have the direct billing account previously mentioned. The
cabin had sufficient outlets
well placed for hair dryers and curlers, and the lighting was excellent. One really good
feature was that you could
turn off the ship intercom so you did not have to listen to the calls for the art auction
or the latest bingo tournament.

Cabin Quietness - 95 - Very quiet but you could feel the engine vibration and ship
movement very slightly.

Shore Excursion Variety - 95 - Very good selection of tours and things to do!! I would
highly recommend the
following:

Key West - Just get off the ship and do your own thing. Key West is so small that you can
do almost anything you
want and still have more than enough time to do three more things. We took the house and
garden walking tour
which was interesting. The conch train tour is also an excellent way to get acquainted
with the city. The Treasure
Museum and story of the Atocha treasure is particularly fascinating and worth the price of
admission. The Jimmy
Buffet bar is a must for the parrot heads for an early morning Bloody Mary or a break in
the shopping. Kino sandals
can&apos;t be missed but the surly people working there can. One great cigar factory and lots
of other places to buy
them. Hemingway&apos;s house should be seen and visited but the polydactyl cats are no longer
for sale even if they
were allowed on your ship.

Playa del Carmen and Cozumel - The ruins at Tulum are worth the trip. This was a great
tour and we had an
excellent Mayan guide who gave us not only the history of the site but his perspective as
a Mayan as well. This was
probably the best tour we have ever been on and it is truly impressive. Not going on this
tour is like going to Egypt
and passing up a chance to see the pyramids. The worst part of the tour was the really
stupid box lunch we were
given by the ship but from the quality of the rest of the food, well, it actually fit
right in. We also had plenty of time for
shopping in Cozumel and supper at Pancho&apos;s in the Cinco Soles store area. Do not miss the
opportunity for a meal
a Pancho&apos;s. You will not have time for supper but the lunch menu is excellent and they
have great margaritas. The
shopping is also excellent with a lot of good bargains and a wide selection.

Ochos Rios - Jamaica has become a real question mark and that is too bad. We took the
excursion to Firefly, which
was Noel Coward&apos;s estate (and the pirate Henry Morgan&apos;s lookout) and the Coyaba River
Garden. The river garden
was very well planned and contained many well-marked plants. The guide was not
particularly helpful but it was a
very nice park and easy walk among some interesting botanical specimens. Firefly was
somewhat better and you
could easily see the attraction that Jamaica had for Coward and Ian Fleming. It is truly a
beautiful island. The guides
on the bus were friendly and helpful. When it came time to return to the ship, they
offered to take us shopping at
one of the two shopping centers and to Dunn&apos;s River Falls for extra money. There were
enough of us who wanted to
go shopping that this made it worth the extra four dollars. The shopping area we selected
was the Taj Mahal which
was close to the port area. There were a lot of shops in this area and after some
bargaining we were able to buy
Blue Mountain coffee at $14.00 a pound for 100% coffee. The key we had been told was to
make sure it was 100%
coffee and not a blend. You may be able to do better but here again, you have the problem
of dealing with the
Jamaicans who make it very clear they are after one thing, your money. They are not the
least bit charming or
friendly about it. Now that is not true of all the Jamaicans many of whom were friendly
and went to great lengths to
tell you that there was a strong desire for more tourists but it was obvious the cruise
staff went out of their way to
make sure you were in safe areas and carefully watched. We heard the tours to Dunn&apos;s River
Falls was also good
but not worth the money.

Georgetown - Grand Cayman is a snorkeling and diving paradise and so I went snorkeling. I
have seen more reef
life and been in better places on Grand Cayman but this was excellent. You could see
everything from all the
varieties of reef fish to tarpon hanging about the coral. There were two snorkel sites and
the wreck site was not
worth the effort. I would have preferred a second reef. It was worth the money, however,
and I would recommend it.
Shopping is excellent but expensive as the Cayman dollar is about $1.25 to $1.00 US when
we were there. We ate
at the Captain Bryan&apos;s Hog Sty Bay Caf for conch salad and fritters plus the local
Stingray beer. People who went
on the Stingray City tour loved it, by the way.

Shore Excursion Value - 95 - Excellent value for the money. All of the tours were well run
and well managed. The
ship&apos;s crew could have been better organized, coffee could have been provided in the
theater with muffins or fruit
but overall it was well done. Again, the best part was the tours went when they said they
would, did not stop for a
bunch of souvenir shops, and stayed on schedule.

Private Island - Not available on this tour.

Tender Service - 95 - Well run, clean, on time, efficient, and very well done.

Entertainment Lounges - 90 - The different shows in the lounge areas were excellent. They
took too many breaks
for too long but they were of routinely high quality. The piano bar was especially good
and the trio in the
Champagne Lounge in the Centrum was an excellent dance band. DJ&apos;s are DJ&apos;s so what can you
say? Music too
loud but there were mostly kids and young adults so it was probably about right.

Entertainment Show Lounge - 79 - The original comedian, Dave Heenan, and the comedy
juggler Dan Bennett,
could have stayed home. The Wave Revue Singers and Dancers were probably quite good but
they did a really
dumb show. LaRaf were illusionists but they did not present anything new although they did
the metamorphosis
exchange in record time in the middle of the audience. Norm Crosby is always good but
again, not really any new
material. The one bright spot was a new singer and impressionist, Martin Dube who started
slow but ended in
bringing the only standing ovation on the trip. He has an outstanding voice range and can
imitate both men and
women.

Entertainment Pool side - 92 - An excellent Caribbean steel band trio who really did their
best to make it a party and
did just a super job.

Air/Sea Package - 90 - I think these are the way to go but I still do not understand why
you can&apos;t get assigned
seating as opposed to having to get to the airport so darned early just to make sure you
have a seat on the flight.

Embark/Disembark - 99 - I think Royal Caribbean has finally figured it out. They meet you
at the airport, they check
you in at the airport, they handle the luggage so that when you get the ship you walk on
board check into your
room, sign up for the tours they have an excellent buffet waiting and they deliver the
luggage. Ours was smooth as
silk but they did lose one of our table mates suitcases for a day. Disembark was just as
smooth with color coded off
load tags, airport luggage check in at the pier, and transport bus waiting. Very well
done!!!

Stabilization - 95 - We were blessed with smooth sailing and calm seas for the entire
cruise.

Overall Cruise Value - 75 - Meals, Customer Service, Entertainment on Board, Ports of
Call, and Excursions are the
big five when it comes to the reasons to take a cruise. In three of the five areas, meals,
customer service, and
entertainment, Royal Caribbean - Enchantment of the Seas - was far below average. Although
there were bright
spots in each of these areas, the aggregate result was only fair. The biggest single
detriment was the overall
attitude of the staff and their collective lack of commitment to service. You had to seek
service as opposed to being
presented with choices. The attitude was one of not wanting to be bothered with taking
care of paying customers
because they were busy talking with each other. This brings up an interesting dilemma. Is
this due to a low ratio of
crew to passenger or just a lack of crew training? In some situations, the main dining
room for example, there were
clearly too few staff for the number of passengers. This was not the case in the lounges
where the waiters were
standing around talking as opposed to taking care of the passengers. If the cruise lines
are going to keep building
bigger ships they better have a much better trained crew because the ratio will continue
to drop. Another problem
was the failure of the crew to enforce the dress code and maintain adult areas for adults.
There is no reason for a
teen or preteen to be in a lounge especially when they are not being accompanied by an
adult. If you have rules
then enforce them. Formal night is formal. Coat and tie or you do not enter the dining
room. These are things the
travel agents know and tell you about so make the rules stick.

Final comment: I think the cruise lines would be surprised if they knew how many current
cruisers do not welcome
bigger ships and would gladly trade them for better service and better meals. I think they
would also be surprised by
how many adults would sign up for an all adult cruise (no one under the age of 18) to some
of these same locations.

 
Name: Lori Martini
Email: lmartini@lakeland.net 
Age: 37
Occupation: Tourism
NumberOfCruises: 5
TravelAgent: No
Ship: RoyalCaribbean-Enchantment
SailingDate: May 23, 1999
Itinerary: Western Caribbean
FoodDiningRoom: 87
CruiseDirector: 94
CabinComfort: 94
FoodRoomService:
CruiseStaff: 89
CabinAmenities: 94
FoodLidoDeck: 79
DiningRoomService: 94
CabinQuietness: 90
FoodMidnightBuffets:
CabinSteward: 92
ShoreExcVariety: 89
FoodVariety: 85
DeckService: 89
ShoreExcValue: 79
GoodForHoneymoon:
CasinoStaff: 89
PrivateIsland:
GoodForFamilies: 94
LoungeService: 90
TenderService: 90
GoodForSeniors:
BeautySalonStaff:
EntertainmentLounges: 89
WheelchairAccess:
ExerciseFacilities: 85
EntertShowLounge: 89
OverallPortsofCall: 89
BeautySalon:
EntertainmentPoolside: 85
CruiseActivities: 89
Casino: 89
AirSeaProgram:
MedicalFacilities: 79
ShipCleanliness: 89
EmbarkDisembark: 90
DiscoNightclubs: 89
DeckSpace: 89
Stabilization: 85
ShopsOnBoard: 89
SpaceRatio: 89
OverallCruiseValue: 90
Submit: Submit Review
Date: 07 Jun 1999
Time: 15:00:23
Remote Name: lac.tsolv.com
Remote User:

Comments

We arrived ready to board the Enchantment of the Seas around 1 p.m. on May 23, 1999. I was
traveling
with my husband, 15 year old daughter&amp;13 year old son. The embarkation process was
flawless!! No
lines, no waiting, no hassles. Ten minutes from curb to cabin. Phenomenal! We were not
escorted to our
cabin as on other cruise lines, but instead greeted and told how to get to our cabin.

Our cabin,#7014 had a balcony and was a ample size even for four people. Plenty of storage
space and
the room itself was light&amp;airy. Delightful. Our cabin steward (Sherman) was
attentive when we needed
him to be and out-of-sight when we wanted him to be. It was fun every evening to come into
the cabin and
see how he had arranged the pillows and my nightgown, different every night. He looked out
for our kids,
was pleasant, eager to help and simply a pleasure (even when I dropped my favorite earring
behind the
refrigerator).

Our dinning room server, Tin (short for Bahatin) did a splendid job with the help of his
new assistant Anna.
The service was excellent although it really seemed to confuse them that we were very
light eaters and
that I only wanted the main course (the ship shape meal) and perhaps a taste of a dessert.
Sitting at a
table for eight, they were concerned that we were sitting too long while the others
enjoyed their various
courses. That didnt bother me at all as I very much enjoyed listening and sharing
the daily events of with
our table mates. The food was ok. Not bad, but not fabulous. Quality, not quantity, is the
key for me.
Holland America has them beat hands down on food however the excellent service shown by
Tin makes up
for the lackluster food.

Breakfast and lunches in the Windjammer were so-so. Not much selection. Basically the same
fare every
day. It wasnt until the third day that I became aware of the omelet/bagel
(breakfast) and sub/carved meat
(lunch) station on the inside of the Windjammer. Windjammer meals were a quick fix and if
you like
starches&amp;sugars, youll think you died&amp;went to carbohydrate heaven . The
dinning room served a nice
leisurely breakfast&amp;lunch but with so many activities and so little time, fooddowntimejust wasnt big on
our list. My husband&amp;kids enjoyed the solarium for pizza, burgers&amp;fries. I
enjoyed the solarium because
it was less congested at that pool and bar. I never was able to snag a lounge chair in
this area but it was a
wonderful retreat from the over stimulation of the main pool activities or once I had
achieved my quota of
sun for the day.

Before I start on the ports, I should say that we sailed the same itinerary twice before
in the past 2 years
on Holland America. We were familiar with the ports and what we wanted to do in each.

Key West - They boys were going snorkeling on the Fury Catamaran again so my daughter&amp;I decided to
just walk around town a bit and check out the shops. Great deals on Hobo Bags and some
very cool
shoes! The merchants are delightful and half of the fun is experiencing the locals. Of
course it just
wouldnt be a trip to the Keys without experiencing Margaritaville and I must say
that I like it so very much
more than the new tourist traps of the same name in a few larger cities. It is the
original and not to be
missed. Parrotheads are alive and well.

Cozumel - Headed to Chankanaab on our own, first thing in the morning. Kids to snorkel,
the hubby&amp;I to
scuba dive. Here is where my trip took a turn for the worse. After about 20 minutes of
diving, I admitted to
myself that I simply wasnt feeling very well. My throat ached, I was tired&amp;stuffed up. This is thekiss of
deathto scuba divers. We decided to cut our time short there and shop a little in
the port with the kids.
The merchants are about the same as in the past and we knew which we wanted to see.
Panchos
Backyard is always on our itinerary but we just didnt want to take time out to eat.
After doing the usual
shopping we took the kids back to the ship, (I prefer the pier in town but our ship
anchored at the new pier
about three miles from downtown.) and headed back to Carlos&amp;Charlies on our
own. After a few drinks
and dancing, (didnt seem to mind the sore throat so much thanks to the margaritas),
it was time to go. I
wish that the ship stayed in port longer like some of the other cruise lines.

I mentioned that I wasnt feeling well. Quite a few people on the ship were ill. The
ships doctor said our
table mate&amp;another couple we mingled with had bronchitis. By mid week, I had met
over a dozen people
with symptoms just like mine. Some had gone to the doctor some had not. This is the worst
chest cold, I
have ever had! Made for a pretty miserable few days on vacation. Not much energy, no
voice, couldnt
breath through the nose, a real downer. Impossible to scuba dive.

Day at sea - Sun and relaxation. Ahhh, the life. The best part of my vacation, was the
balcony in our
stateroom. I cannot put into words the serenity I felt sitting out there every morning
around 6 am while the
kids were sound asleep. Just sitting there sipping my coffee in my pajamas. Not feeling
well, that was the
very best part of my entire trip and wish I could do that every morning for the rest of my
life. Oh, the simple
pleasures of life. (Note to self: build in budget the cost of room with balcony from now
on).

Jamaica - The kids have been out until 2 or 3 am every night since we boarded the ship at
kids activities.
At first I was apprehensive for them to stay out so late, but there truly are scheduled
activities for them into
the wee hours. The staff was wonderful and the kids had a simply fantastic time. So when
we arrived in
Ocho Rios, the kids slept in late so Mark&amp;I headed to the Jamaica Grand Hotel (on
our own) to use their
beach&amp;pool. This is a lovely resort and they welcome visitors for the day ($10 each)
from cruise ships. In
the past, we had already done the falls, the Martha Brae, horseback riding etc.. so we
just wanted to kick
back&amp;relax. In the afternoon, we took the kids shopping. Of all the times we have
been to Jamaica, we
have never had a problem with the people. I hear the horror stories but cannot say that we
have ever had
a problem. In fact, on this trip, we were not approached a single time by a street person
and we walked to
and from the two shopping plazas. It is an economically poor island with tourism being its
largest source of
income. We respect it for what it is and enjoy our time their every time we visit.

Grand Cayman - I must say, this has always been my favorite island. It is clean, safe,
beautiful and yes,
expensive. The shops are pleasant and the tours are wonderful. Stingray City and/or the
sandbar are a
must but theAquariumis also a fabulous dive spot. Seven mile beach is
gorgeous, I could go on&amp;on.
Throughout the week I didnt spend much money in the ports, I just didnt feel
like shopping but instead let
the kids do their souvenir shopping. Grand Cayman is where I take exception. Five rum
cakes, some
Stingray Beer, a few Patties, a Kipling Bag, a diamond ring and a lovely emerald,
sapphire, ruby&amp;
diamond bracelet later, we boarded the ship. Somehow my nasty cold seemed a smidgen better
J. Side
note: on our way to the pier while aboard the tender, we were uncomfortably close to a
funnel cloud on the
water. The locals called it a water spout. It was a little unnerving but now that I am
safe at home I anxiously
await our pictures from the film processor so I can see if we got a good shot of it.

Day at sea - Time to pack and do all the ship shopping you can, not to mention get some
sun and
socialize one last time with new found friends. This day is always so sad. Its
almost over and you know you
cant take home your cabin steward, and waiter.

Tidbits: My first trip to the liquor shop on board (to purchase cough drops) I noticed
Absolute Vodka w/
Citron for $12.99. Such a deal. Purchased one to take back home. When in Grand Cayman, at
the
Tortuga Store, same bottle, $8.99.

Even though the teens activities are very organized and had a wonderful staff, my daughter
had 23 cds
taken from her backpack in the teen room while she was on the dance floor. This should not
be a
reflection on the ship or the staff, (was most likely taken by another teen) but just a
reminder to all, even
though the cruise may seem like absolute bliss, the reality is that people will be people,
so dont let your
guard down with your valuables.

We met up with others that we met through this web sight. It was a joy to see them
throughout the week,
on excursions, a lunch or in the casino. Very nice.

Evening shows - Comedians were the lineup the first 2 nights. I was not impressed at all.
In fact, the first
gentleman was soo bad, people were leaving. Second night was better but kind of soured my
impression
on the shows as that was our last for the cruise. Ironically, we have never missed a show
on any of our
other sailings. My kids reported back that the remaining shows were quite good, but we
instead found
walks on the deck, casino fun or stayed in the cabin watching a movie more to our liking.

Disembarkation - The four of us decided to go up to the Viking Crown Lounge to wait as our
tag color was
gray and we fully expected to be last off the ship. Small price to pay for living in
Florida and being able to
drive yourself to the ship. There were only 4 other people perched in the lounge high
above the rest of the
ship. It afforded us not only a peaceful place to wait as opposed to the other public
areas, it also provided
us a wonderful panoramic view of the area. Once our color was called and we left the
Enchantment, we
saw hundreds of people clamoring over the same luggage. It was so humorous. This is when I
realized the
vacation had done exactly what I needed it to. Help me to unwind. Had I seen this same
scene before my
week at sea, I would have snapped and been furious at such unorganized chaos. Instead, I
stood still and
broke into genuine laughter. Back to reality. We found our luggage (all 8 pieces) side by
side and we were
off to our car in less than 5 minutes, but I will remember with a smile the sight of all
those pushing, shoving
people scrambling for their luggage for a very long time to come.

In conclusion,, Enchantment of the Seas is a beautiful ship, her staff is courteous,
energetic and eager to
please. Tipping is an expectation for services rendered and I found myself wanting to
extend more than
the expected amount. Having sailed previously on Royal Caribbean, NCL&amp;Holland
America, I honestly
can say that the service on Royal Caribbean is tops. I do wonder if the tipping is the
reason for that?
Perhaps Holland America needs to rethink their position.

I would be amiss if I concluded without mentioning our Head Waiter. (although I cant
remember his name).
This was my 5th cruise in as many years and can say that this was the first time I met a
head waiter. He
was humorous, attentive, bright and dependable. He stopped at our table nightly and
conversed with the
entire table. On the last night as tips were being distributed, we literally had to wait
at our table about 10
minutes due to the fact that all the other tables were tipping/saying good-byes to him as
well. Worth the
wait. Watch out Ken Rush, our wonderful Italian head waiter is gaining popularity on you!

All in all, we had a wonderful cruise. My daughters comments wereDid you ever
notice that everyone is
always so happy, friendly&amp;nice, on a cruise?, (even though it was her
cds that were lost). My son
mentionedOf all the cruises we have been on, I have seen this cruise director (Ken
Rush) more than any
of the others. He is everywhere and talks to everyone!(We mentioned this to Mr.
Rush and he seemed
genuinely grateful).

If you sail the Enchantment of the Seas, the makings of a glorious time are there. The
rest is up to you.

Lori Martini





 Back to RCCL Enchantment 

 

 

 Want to book your cruise at a great rate ? Click here .
Questions or comments? Mail to webmaster@cruiseopinion.com .
Copyright 1996-2001 CruiseOpinion.com. Last modified: January 17, 2000.
	</body>
</document>
