<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005060" url="http://ecorporateoffices.com/InternationalDairyQueenInc-2147" time="2012-07-12-21:35" support="11" score="0.029967876168735932" bingtitle="International Dairy Queen, Inc Corporate Office | Headquarters ..." webtitle="International Dairy Queen, Inc Corporate Office | Headquarters Contact Phone Number&amp;Address | Reviews">
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000145" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000339" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000157" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>I gave that back as well and did not even receive an ... Well, the front counter person prepared several dairy orders ... I&apos;m not suggesting sophisticated,it is a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		International Dairy Queen, Inc Corporate Office | Headquarters 
 7505 Metro Blvd. Minneapolis, MN 55439
(952)830-0200 




 Reviews For International Dairy Queen, Inc Corporate Office 

 Dave 6/11/12 
 While most of the comments on this site are complaints, I actually wanted to give kudos to the Flatwoods KY DQ. The service there may not always be the fastest but I get great service from every employee. The environment is welcoming and most of the servers have an attitude as if they know you. It&apos;s Great! It has this old time country dinner feel to it. Thanks DQ! 



 tina 6/18/12 
 We ate at store #11916and not only was there horrible customer service but the worker said not telling us about a deal we missed out on wasn&apos;t his problem. He told us his boss said he didn&apos;t wnt him suggesting the deals to people ... horrible and I will not be coming back here. 



 doesitmatter 7/3/12 
 Dairy Queen SERIOUSLY needs to RECYCLE!!!!!! What a blight on the environment... the one in Middlefield, Ohio is only a couple of blocks from the Recycle Center... they go through tons of plastic... and when approached about recyling, they simply said &quot;no one wants to do it&quot;. DUH.... I hope you&apos;ll join in and boycott the inconsiderate greedy _____! 



 Terry Searls 6/24/12 
 Went to the Dairy Queen at 3303 Lincoln Wat East in Mishawaka In. this evening, and the person in front of me ordered (2) Buster Bars among other things for her children. The girl behind the counter handed (2) Dilly Bars instead. Unknowing, the two little guys opened the dilly Bars and began licking them and realizing they weren&apos;t Buster Bars, put them back in the paper sleeve and mom told the girl they were wrong. The waiter took them and put them back in the freezer for resale , and give them two Buster bars. I then explained to the girl that once food passes over the counter and comes back, you can&apos;t resale it, and that the little guys licked on those Dilly Bars. I even explained this to the evening shift manager who then give me attitude for even saying anything. The Dilly Bars remained in the freezer for resale when I left the store. This must be common practice at this location. Buyer beware. :) I will call the store Manager tomorrow and the health department. 



 JLG 6/28/12 
 My kids and I love the Loogootee Indiana Dairy Queen. We always get great service and friendly smiles. My 11 year old makes sure she tells them every time we go there that they are the best DQ that we have ever been to. Keep up the great work Loogootee! 



 jonathan macaganone 6/29/12 
 i was at the dairy queen in ghent n.y in the drive thru for over twenty minutes at the window with no one telling me why it was taking so long i ordered chicken strips and a chicken sandwich. as we looked threw the window we saw people sitting on counters talking to each other laughing and our food boxes were right there all they had to do was hand them to us we are pissed off and will tell everyone we know not to go there ever again they are unprofessional and very disrespectful. i will be posting this on facebook to 



 Sherry 5/26/12 
 Got a Banana sunday today and it was ice cream with sliced bananas. Could have made that at home - no kind of syrup - nothing. We also got a strawberry sunday at same time - just sliced strawberries, no stawberry syrup. It wasn&apos;t good and wasn&apos;t worth what we paid for it. The location of this place was on the corner of 19th street and N. Grand Ave. E, Springfield, IL 62702. I will take my business to Sonic. 



 john schwartz 5/27/12 
 I raced to dairy queen to make it before 10:30,got there at 10:22and they would not serve me because they were closed at 10:22.thats bull.... 



 joe ramirez 5/5/12 
 rvice.I love these store. But today 5-5-12 my girlfriend went to get a banana split for me and her. Like we always do or food. But she didn&apos;t see the menu board outside and went to the window.when she got there the girl told her that the menu board was in the back. No one was in line.I work in food service.and it about making the money for the company and customers 



 5/7/12 
 Yes. I would like to talk to someone in human resource, its, adout a employee in .Memphis,eara,Is there a tolal free number that I can call and talk to someone that want link me to this conversation 



 Anonymous 4/27/12 
 The head manager of DQ in Goodland, Kansas is horrible. She smokes pot everyday and comes to high a lot. I know this because she told me. The bad thing is that the boss even knows it and is not doing anything about it. Tina McClary the head manager doesn&apos;t even come to work at all except once a week but she still clocks herself in and out for everyday that she wasn&apos;t there. She harasses one of the employees. She acts like a 2 yr. old and she doesn&apos;t even handle complaints like a manager is suppose to. 



 Anonymous 5/2/12 
 The Dairy Queen in St.Croix Falls WI and Osceola WI are horrible. I have worked there, and through all the reviews and complaints nothing has got any better. There is only one blizard machine that doesnt even have a long enough shaft to mix the ice cream in a large blizard. So if you get a large Bliz, malt, or shake...The Stuff at the bottom will not be mixed in. To wipe things down there is one bucket with Sanitizer that doesnt get changed all day. You use the same bucket and same dirty water to wipe down the counters and the blizard machine. Keep in mind we cut the bananas on the bare counter and if candy falls out onto the counter they just throw it back into the blizard. Washing your hands is not pushed at this DQ. And I PROMISE YOU the employees hands touch your ice cream. Every year there is usually a mouse problem. There are times where they set traps IN THE STORE and they catch mice all the time. The food takes forever to get because there is only one cook, and the equipment to make the ice cream is so old that it takes forever to get to the costumer. Not to mention the two guys running are sick old men that used to only higher girls and will do anything they can to rip you off on your money you worked for.
This DQ needs new managment 



 Anonymous 5/1/12 
 I go to dq in goodland kansas almost everyday and i see the head manager Tina McClary come in high almost every time she is there. She told me she smokes weed everyday and also told me where she keeps it. She hardly ever comes in to work. But she still clocks herself in and out as if she was there but really wasn&apos;t. Tina isn&apos;t even certified to be a manager and the inspector told her she needs to but she won&apos;t cause she knows she won&apos;t pass. Danny which is the boss and owner of dq even knows about it all but lets it happen. If tina don&apos;t like you she cuts your hours for no reason and acts like a 2 year old when you ask her why she cut your hours and makes up some lame excuse and lies about it. When you ask danny for a raise he tells you that you will get it but if you go to h&amp;r;block they tell you that you haven&apos;t gotten any pay raise at all. So there for your paycheck gets cut short every time. Whats sad is that danny does it to your paycheck and what you don&apos;t get tina gets. Tina and Danny both let a 17 year old close the place at night without anyone 18 years or older there. 



 Rachel Griffin 4/15/12 
 I am giving Dairy Quessn in Middleton, Massachusetts ZERO stars on customer service. Last night I took my children to DQ and arrived and walked in the store at 9:00pm and the girl behind the counter told me it was 9:02pm and they were closed. There were people in there ordering and the door was open and we were in the store prior to it closing. My husband was getting our disabled son out of the car and was waiting outside with our son who wanted his ice cream. We left Dairy Queen and drove half a mile down the road to a family owned homemade ice cream store where customer service is held to a higher standard. Dairy Queen should be training there staff not to refuse customers because one bad experience will be shared and posted to thousands. 



 red gusto 4/16/12 
 my family and love going to the dairy gueen store in the augusta mall. but lately that store has been in a sham, they are always out of products, one time out of ice cream, can you believe that.and 3 time there was one worker, working by herself, it took 25minutes to get my family order, as for the hotdogs they are small than the ones we use to buy. I will not be going back to that store. 



 Lisa Jolley 3/19/12 
 My boyfriend and I stopped in the DQ yesterday for a quick lunch.
6205 Bardstown road Louisville, KY (Fern Creek)
We walked to the counter to order, and the 2 girls behind the counter both turned around and walked away!! There was never a &quot;welcome&quot;, &quot; be right with you&quot; nothing!!
One girl came back up and took our order (Kaelin). After telling her twice we just want the sandwiches not the meals, she finally got it. She closed the cash drawer and walked away without giving me my change back. I asked for it when she returned with my tea. My tea with absolutely no ice whatsoever. When I asked her if I could have some ice please, she said okay, I can get that for you. For me, like she was now doing me some big favor!!
She gave me the tea back and set a number 7 on the counter. We assumed it was ours and took it to a table, once we found a clean one! There were no napkins in the entire store except on the front counter. Empty napkin containers, no napkins.
Another employee was hopefully on her break sitting near the rear of the store eating, as she needed a napkin. She gets up goes to the empty napkin dispenser, then to the front counter to get a napkin. Never filling the dispenser. Of course she was busy, as now her boyfried had appeared for his free drinks..
We were made to feel as though we had greatly inconvenienced them by chosing to eat lunch there.......NEVER AGAIN .. 



 J. Morris 3/11/12 
 This is regarding the DQ on st rout 45 in Lakewood Tn. I asked for a banana milkshake and the guys were fooling around. He cut up a half banana on a counter that was &quot;dirty&quot; with other food products like oreos, etc. The &quot;banana milkshake&quot; consisted of a little milk,&amp;vanilla ice cream with a little banana chopped up in it. It was a vanilla ice cream shake with banana chunks sunk to the bottom. A banana milkshake is supposed to taste like banana, not vanilla ice cream. I ask him what else he&apos;s supposed to put in it and he said &quot;this is how they told me to make it&quot;. I&apos;ve had banana milkshakes from DQ in the past and they&apos;re supposed to put some sort of powdered flavoring in it.
bad, bad, bad. I have zero desire to return. 



 Tim parnell 3/5/12 
 I will NEVER go to the Washington, pa dq on jefferson avenue. I received a cold cheeseburger where the cheese was not even melted. I sent it back in receiving another cheeseburger that had an inch of mustard and ketchup that you could not even pick it up. I gave that back as well and did not even receive an apology or even what can we do for you at a later time. This was the worst experience I have ever encountered. 



 2/17/12 
 Why does my dairy queen not sell dilly bars anymore? I want a dilly bar! 



 LaNae Williams 2/1/12 
 The Dairy Queen of Clinton, has a dog inside the store. I went to get icecream an the dog was in the store, employees said it was owners dog. That&apos;s very nasty an unprofessional, and unsanitary! 

 

 1/30/12 
 Terrible service @ the dairy queen on middle rd. Refused to give me my food or money back 



 Robert Craven 1/24/12 
 i started as a manager at dairy quenn in huntington wv on 5th ave about a week ago. last sunday i started my shift about a hour in to it i noticed that two employees walk outside to smoke i then went in to the office and told the other shift manager if he wanted to be the bad guy or did he want me two that there were two employees smoking and we would get in trouble for it if we didnt say anything . at that point the owner walked around the corner and said what the f*ck am i paying you two motherf*ckers for to hang out in the office while the employees are out back f*cking smoking! i then said i just told the other shift manager and we were going to say something right now. he then said what the f*ck ever! I then said whoa whoa whoa. he said whoa whoa whoa my a*s ! I said hey you cant speak to people that way that it was illeagel .he said f*ck you if if you dont like it get the f*ck out ! i said hey i have benn doing nothing but working sense i got here. he then said f*ck you ! i replyed saying buddy im 30 years old and im not going to be talked to that way . he said if i didnt like it hit the f*cking road ! i said so your firing me . he replyed saying no but if you dont like it then hit the f*cking road! I then said then your firing me and i expect my check in 72 hours . he replied with f*uk you fat f*cker !
Wow what a way to set an example 



 Jean Rader 1/22/12 
 After seeing your promo on TV advertising the medium blizzard for $2.99, I stopped at the Dairy Queen at Chandler Fashion Center in Chandler, Az to order one. I was refused the promo price with the coment &quot;We don&apos;t do that here. We don&apos;t have to.&quot; Is this true and if it is true, why does your TV comercial not include this exclusion? This is the second time I have been refused a corporate special price at this location. 



 lindsey garcia 1/16/12 
 Dairy queen on little York n bauman well someone should investigate cause I ate their once found hair in my Burger they accuse me n said it wuz mine own hair. Next I saw roaches. 



 Jeff 12/13/11 
 I live in West Frankfort Illinois. The man that owns the dairy queen here is nothing but a pervert and has no idea what customer service is all about. Every time we go there the young girls get our order wrong and are rude. The girl at the window today got pissed because I asked for a drink tray and a bag for our food. Now, I was in the drive through so you would think they would put the food in a bag anyway and seeing that I was the only one in the truck with more than one drink, it should have been common knowledge that I may need a drink tray. I called and told the owner that the girl in the window was very rude, He told me that he found it hard to believe that his workers are rude and hung up on me. I called back to ask for the corporate number and I heard him tell the girl to hang up. I then called back again to ask for the number and tell him that I would be reporting him to the b.b.b. and he told me that if I ever call his store again that he would file harrasment charges against me. My wife and I will never do buisness with them again. I have a 16 year old daughter and she has come home several times telling us how one of her friends or someone she knows quit their job at this dairy queen because the owner was trying to make them go to his house for a &quot;meeting&quot;. He never hires over weight girls, I have only seen one guy in there besides him, and there are not girls over the age of 20. This guy needs to be investigated!!! 



 ms Cai 12/6/11 
 I am a missionary writer Assigned to help the everyone once this writing Assignment from God himself is finished. I asked the manager if I could set in the dining area and work a few hours some time,and I do have severe food allergies and cannot eat teh food, I must eat organic only, and no sugar and low on salt. and he said&apos; yea, sure, people come here to work on their laptop and don&apos;t necessarily purchase anything.&apos;...some time later when the Lord lead me to go there, I had only gone there 4 times, over the past 4 months after asking him. And then suddenly he approached me with telling me to leave, after darkness came upon him. When I had only been there just over an hour, and needed to do work and use their wi-fi. I have to walk to get there. it is closer for me to go, than other places. it put me behind in the communication with others that was needed and the work that is needing to be done. He said he had no complaints, just did not like it when I did nto purchase anything, when I asked if I could purchase anything for a $1 and give to my neighbor, he still got nasty and told me that I had to eat it there, even after I reminded him I am highly allergic to preservatives and cannot eat the food. Even after I offered to purchase something for my neighbor, he still told me &apos;I want you to leave&apos;....I had seen other people, men come and work hours with their own snack bags and did not purchase food. Was he prejudice, against seeing my Bible on the table as I work.? Was he going along with other wrong doers in the community to be ugly toward those in need, the poor in the area?

God be merciful for the ignorant ones, and help us to help them see God&apos;s light before it is too late. This Dairy Queen was at St Charles city mo, they seem to be against Christmas music, but keep the place clean otherwise. Pray for them. they sure need it. 



 Steve Lumbert 12/1/11 
 I go to the Dairy Queen on Main Street in Marion Illinois. I really do love some of the items you have, I wish all locations carried the Orange Julius. Now when I order a bad of Dilly Bars I would expect them to be the same quality&amp;same size &quot;Every&quot; time I order them. I would like to have someone explain to me why when I went to purchase them this time they were the &quot;THINEST/SKIMPIEST&quot; bag of Dilly Bars I think I have ever seen! I would expect them to be made from a &quot;mold&quot; of some kind so as to prevent something like this happening but when I pay over $11.00 for a bag of them&amp;that is what I get it is extremely disappointing. I have been there many times&amp;have had skimpy ones before but these take the cake. I could have taken 2 of them&amp;smashed them together to equal the size of what they should have been. I hope someone reads this&amp;actually does their job to check into the &quot;Quality&quot; your company name is serving to your customers. In this day&amp;age when hard working American&apos;s can go anywhere to spend their money for a treat&amp;this is what they get is unexcuseable. I hope someone up in the chain of command reads this&amp;actually does their job to act on it as I as well as your other customers should get &quot;WHAT WE PAID FOR!&quot; 



 andrea mcneal 11/3/11 
 I went through the drive thru at the dairy queen in Frankfort Kentucky on John Davis drive and they need to have more training on the meaning of fast food. I waited 20 minutes for then to take my money and give me my food and 5 minutes of that 20 was waiting for them to take my order. The lady at drive thru had a bad attitude and slammed the window. 



 Aaron Lee 11/7/11 
 Hello my name is Aaron Lee . I am a owner operator A+Maintenance&amp;more. I do floor care and janitors work . Its come too attention that your stores are mainly ceramic floors ? I myself think that your floors can make or brake you if they looked shiny and clean almost like ice and would help grip your feet when it was slick it would because you thought outside the box for a moment and your sales person looked at your store front like I have and thought wow if we would make our store fronts look cleaner then when people would walk in and see a nice clean floor that has a sealer on with 2 coats of wax that could be skimmed and buffed one time every 1\4 it would drive sales up because anyone thats anyone know if the dont look clean then it dont matter how clean the rest of the store is ? With this said it should make you raise a brow ? Tell the head maintenance if they want a hand or your sales department to feel free to contact me at 1(260)701-4200 you can find us on the web at Aplusmaintenance.net 



 MARY WAGAR 9/24/11 
 MY NAME IS MARY WAGAR, I CANT BELIEVE THAT AFTER TELLING MY NIECE HOW WONDERFUL A DAIRY QUEEN ICE CREAM IS. SO I STOP BY THE DAIRY QUEEN IN CORONA CALIFORNIA. JUST OFF 6TH ST. OMG IT WAS NOTHING BUT ICE MILK. I WOULD OF SAID SOMETHING BUT WE WERE ON ON WAY HOME. IT SEAMS TO ME THAT THE OWNER OF THIS STORE MUST B BUYING A CHEAP MIX TO PUT INTO THE FROSTY MACHINE. I WOULD HOPE THAT CORPORATE WOULD CHECK THESES PLACES OUT. I TRIED A DAIRY QUEEN IN GARDEN GROVE CALIF, THE NEXT WEEK SO MY NIECE COULD TRY THE REAL THING, BINGO.... IT WAS PERFECT. SO I GUESS ITS NOT ALL D.Q. OWNERS TRYING TO FOOL US. THANK GOD. BUT IM STILL DISAPOINTED IN CORONAS D.Q. 



 Candi 8/19/11 
 I went and got my kids lunch to take to school. I was in shock when the owner would only let me have ONE ketchup per child. When I asked for another one, he told me that I could not have any more that it cost 6 cents a pack and wasn&apos;t gonna give me another. I told him I will take my business to McDonald&apos;s and he said well go. 



 Debi 9/16/11 
 I would just like to request that you bring back the cotton candy blizzard!!! I live in Tifton GA and everyone here loves it and it has been a couple of years since we have seen it. It is one of the best ones EVER. Thanks!!! 



 Dewayne O&apos;Neal (edoneal@earthlink.net) 8/22/11 
 Dairy Queen (in the Stuckey&apos;s building) at exit around 174 I-20 East 005 County Road from Eastaboga in Talladega County, Alabama. Do not go there! Had a grade of 88 or 78 I think was posted behide the counter which was covered with flies which I mashed them on the counter when they landed so the mangement could see. No Strawberries nor Bananas. They sold me a shake with no bananas in it and did not warn me, very bad, asked for a refund. Need to shut that place down because DQ is not India quality! Restrooms in the same building were nasty and stunk!.... 



 Tonya Somers 9/11/11 
 I would love to see you open one in Wilsonville Oregon...this town is really growing and fast....they finally added 4 more stores and 10 new restaurants...there was nothing in this town ... BUT ... alot of money and horses...please open one here.

www.tonyasomers.com 



 kathy engle 9/12/11 
 I was at the dairy queen location at 615 armour rd. north kansas city, mo 64116, phone number 816-842-2345 on 9-10-11. I wanted to try the $5.00 blizzard deal, in which you get burger, fries, drink, and mini blizzard. I asked if I could get the blizzard later, after I consumed my burger and fry in the parking lot, and because I didn&apos;t know what flavor i wanted. The poorly trained employee told me NO that I had to get it in the drive thru window immediately. I also had to repeat my order F I V E times thats ( F I V E ) times, probably more. I also had wanted a childs meal and she couldn&apos;t get that correct either. I was born an AMERICAN, I SPEAK ENGLISH, and I also SPEAK CLEARLY. Since I didn&apos;t want the BLIZZARD immediately, I wanted to change the order. She couldn&apos;t understand that either. Finally another voice came on the speaker, and I told him that she couldn&apos;t understand SHIT, he told me that I didn&apos;t have to curse. I said that I did, because she couldn&apos;t understand or take a s simple order. I AM the PAYING PUBLIC, I wanted to spend MY MONEY at DAIRY QUEEN, but was met with animosity by the DUMB-ASSES that are hired by DAIRY QUEEN. I have loved since I was a kid, NO MORE. I will never give my HARD EARNED MONEY TO DAIRY QUEEN. I had to drive out of my way to go there that day, because I do not live close. NEVER AGAIN!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! The moronic idiot who told me that I don&apos;t have to curse, if it was a managerial type has no right to tell me what to do anyway. I think you need to re-think your hiring practices. If they can&apos;t take a simple order, they shouldn&apos;t be working the drive thru window anyway. The asshole who told me not to curse, should be FIRED!!!!!!!!!!! Your commercials also suck!!!!!!!!!!!!! It was always a treat for me to go to DAIRY QUEEN-----NO MORE!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 



 L. S. Hoyle 9/14/11 
 I was traveling I-85 N recently and noticed the Dairy Queen sign at the Haw River, NC - exit 150 and decided to gas up and get ice cream. The manager, Rameka L. Smith, who was on duty at the Dairy Queen was so personable and delightful. Her attitude would have immediately turned a negative day into a positive one. You could tell she loves her job and is totally focused on making everyone have a &quot;pleasant&quot; day. Any time I am traveling in that directions, I will definitely take exit 150 to stop in at that Dairy Queen. 



 Benita P 7/11/11 
 I went to Dairy Queen in Douglasville GA on Fairburn Rd. today for lunch and was served a hamburger with a roach in it. I always remove my bun and examine my burgers before eating them and I noticed the dead roach lying in between my 2 pickles. I drove about 5 miles to take the sandwich and fries back and I was asked if I wanted something else. Are you crazy???? I had ordered a cone and ate it on the way home so I was given a $2.12 refund for the burger combo only. I will never eat there again. No responsibility was taken and with the placement of the bug it&apos;s hard for me to believe it was not placed there deliberable. I&apos;&apos;ve been eating at DQ all my life but today was my last visit. 



 Anna 8/6/11 
 I love Dairy Queen but i would love if there was a key lime pie blizzard its my favorite kind of pie and i was wondering since you made a pumpkin pie blizzard you could make a key lime pie blizzard. Thanks 



 Barbara Miller 7/19/11 
 Just trying to let someone at corporate know that your latest series of ads are among the dumbest and most annoying ever - bubbles filled with kittens? pinatas filled with Mary Lou Rettin? Get a new ad firm! 



 M. Wayne Denning 7/19/11 
 I am going to wear a sandwich board and hand out copies of these comments. I want to ask everyone to join me. Dairy Queen should not be in business based on my experience and these reviews! 

 

 Gayle 7/29/11 
 The buyer in your store located on HWY 50 in Carson City, NV does not know how to perform his/her job. The store is frequently out of items listed on your menu.

Also, one should not have to ask repeatedly for a napkin, and then be handed a wad of crunched up napkins. Napkins should be served with the meal.

I would also like to know if your staff is properly trained on how to prepare your food? Each time I order a blizzard, it is always prepared differently, and fried food is frequently served burnt.

In today&apos;s economy, I would think that businesses would like customers to return. 



 Walter Wilrs 8/1/11 
 My name is Wally and just saw an add on t.v. for the nutter butter blizzard... Once we got to Dairy Queen...they said the don&apos;t have it yet. Now, I believe if you place an add on t.v. all stores should carry that item. Does false advertising stand out or what? 



 Julie Chronos 6/21/11 
 I ordered a full sheet ice cream cake for my daughter&apos;s 12th birthday. I ordered M&amp;Ms;and Snickers as the filling for the ice cream cake because my daughter is allergic to wheat/gluten intolerant. She loves this cake. We have ordered it before and never had a problem. But this year at 8:30pm when I went to serve the cake to 25 hungry preteens there was some sort of cookie crunch in the cake and my daughter could not eat her own birthday cake! The store owner and the woman who made the cake were rude and would not take responsibility for their mistake. The woman who took the order claimed she told me the cookie crumb filling would be in the cake as she took me over to the sign when in fact she never left the counter as she wrote the order. If she had told me about the filling I would certainly not order something that my daughter is allergic to! The truth is I ordered M&amp;M;and Snicker filling because that is what she can eat and not have an allergic reaction! Why would I tell the woman what I do not want in a cake?! I ordered what I want in the cake! 



 Julie Chronos 6/21/11 
 I went to the Dairy Queen in Tinley Park in Il. on 159th and Harlem.I ordered a full sheet ice cream cake for my daughter&apos;s 12th birthday. I ordered M&amp;Ms;and Snickers as the filling for the ice cream cake because my daughter is allergic to wheat/gluten intolerant. She loves this cake. We have ordered it before and never had a problem. But this year at 8:30pm when I went to serve the cake to 25 hungry preteens there was some sort of cookie crunch in the cake and my daughter could not eat her own birthday cake! The store owner and the woman who made the cake were rude and would not take responsibility for their mistake. The woman who took the order claimed she told me the cookie crumb filling would be in the cake as she took me over to the sign when in fact she never left the counter as she wrote the order. If she had told me about the filling I would certainly not order something that my daughter is allergic to! The truth is I ordered M&amp;M;and Snicker filling because that is what she can eat and not have an allergic reaction! Why would I tell the woman what I do not want in a cake?! I ordered what I want in the cake! 



 sarah 6/24/11 
 I was at the Dairy Queen in clinton missouri and recieved the worse service of my life. When I asked to speak to the manager, she was very rude and inconsiderate. I will never go back to this location. 



 Anonymous 6/25/11 
 The owner and manager of the store located in Albany, Oregon is a very angry mean guy. He treats a lot of his employees terribly, even talks badly about them to other employees. I have no idea how someone so terrible could be in the position he is in. He should be ashamed of himself, and shame on the DQ corporation for allowing it to happen. 



 Will Deuling 6/12/11 
 I took my Family to DQ on us 41 in Bradenton, Fl for a little treat after some fishing.

My Wife ordered a the World&apos;s Nastiest Banana Split, my son got a oreo cookie blast
and I got a nasty Blizzard.They don&apos;t even use real ice cream any more. We now hate DQ. 



 Penny G 6/21/11 
 I went to the Dairy queen in Granite Falls, Minnesota the other day with a friend. We were getting 3 blizzards. One each for us and then one for my husband who was at working waiting. When we went in we noticed first of all that the floor was filthy. There was food all over the floor, along with napkins and trash. After my friend and I placed out order we noticed that there was a woman who was taking out the trash, which btw was located right beside the shake machine. She was tugging on the bagtrying to get it out of the can. As she tugged on it she would flip her hair out of her face and did I mention it was right next to the shake machine?? Not only that but after she got the FULL trash bag out of the can she carried it to the back, HOLDING IT OVER THE COUNTER WHERE THE FOOD WAS SITTING. Then she came back in the front without washing her hands and started making people&apos;s food. She played with the can to move it out of her way and did it again! My friend and I were almost sick to our stomachs. Now we look over at the cook behind the counter cooking food on the grill. He had gloves on and took them off, scratched his head and then used his bare hands to handle someone&apos;s food. This is the ONLY Dairy Queen we have here in Granite Falls and I am sure I am not the only one who noticed this. Finally after 20 minutes of watching this, they handed us our blizzards. When the girl handed me mine, she threw the spoon on the counter and it landed in a wet spot of &quot;something&quot; so I asked for another one. She acted as if I was breaking a law. Once we got our &quot;treats&quot; we noticed that the blizzards were made mostly of milk and had no flavor. By the time I drove a mile down the road all 3 of them were nothing but liquid. It was not that hot outside either.We both told everyone we came in contact with that evening NOT to go to that Dairy Queen and why. I will Never go back and I am calling the Health Department and letting them know how nasty your chain of stores has gotten. It is obvious from reading these posts that we are not the only one who has problems with your food chains. Maybe you either need to pay your people more OR you need to do a sweep and get rid of all the lazy people in every store! Outraged and will NEVER go back! Congrats! You just lost more customers! 



 JoA nn 6/2/11 
 My husband and I had a craving for a Blizzard when on our way home. Went several miles out of our way into Stockton, Ca. We went to Dairy Queen on Thornton Ave. The place was very busy as there were only 2 employees to prepare orders. One female in the back preparing cooked food and one female in the front preparing dairy orders and collecting money. Well, the front counter person prepared several dairy orders, collected money, prepared orders, collected money, etc. Never once did she either wash her hands after handling cash or wear any gloves . I asked her about this and she looked at me like I was from Mars. Will NEVER go back there again. Also, think that Corporate Headquarters should be made aware of this particuler location&apos;s unsanitary procedures. 



 Dianna Allison 6/5/11 
 I visit the Dairy Queen in Florence Oregon all the time and I just wanted to say that their food is awesome, there staff the VERY best around and I would recommend this DQ to ANYone ANYwhere as the very best ever.. Thank you Florence DQ my whole family loves you!!! 



 marisol rose 5/19/11 
 O N YESTERDAY I WAS VERY ANSIUOS TO GO TO THE NEW DAIRY QUEEN IN RISCHLAND,MISS 39218.I WAS A VERY MISTAKE. THE FOOD WERE BAD VERY BAD, THRY ALSO GIME 5 PIECEAND I PAY FOR 6. THE MANAGER WAS NO FRIENDLY. I WAST YOU TO KNOW THAT IS A TERRIBLE PLACE TO GO 



 keith 5/8/11 
 i have a friend that owns some dq franchises and even he is embarrassed with these stupid new ads,please people tey and act like your customers have brains unlike your ad committee 



 William Werremeyer 4/12/11 
 I worked in Dairy Queen for 7 years of my life. Thru high School and 5 years after and at the young age of 23 purchased my first business. I operated a Dairy Queen store in the town of Clinton Indiana for 10 years. We had one of the old franchises with a 29 cent rate on the mix and that was it. I truly loved that business and was and still am very proud of the Dairy Queen product. I tell you all that just to say this. I am not only disappointed but embarrassed to view these new Dairy Queen ads about pants turning around and shaving bunnies. Maybe I am missing the intent but so are many others because there is not a day that goes by that some one doesn&apos;t comment on these commercials. I really do not think that anyone would stop going to Dairy Queen because of these ads but it is an embarrassment to me as a former owner. Dairy Queen has no competition in the world as far as I see it. We had and have the best product out there. The price has changed tremendously but what hasn&apos;t. In my opinion this advertising it not measuring up to the quality of the product. Thanks for taking the time to read what a former Dairy Queen operator after 17 years of service has to say. William Werremeyer wasic@aol.com or 812 305 0580. 



 James P Ropp 4/8/11 
 I like D. Q and have been a customer for over 58 years but with the prices going up I found it is cheeper to take my grandchildren to Mcdonalds for a cone. The price is 2 for $1.00 and with 13 grandchildren that would be a grate price. All your products are grate but at todays prices we need to think of money. I have been in the Air Force and Your Company has DQ in the middle East and they are just as good as here. But over seas things are less money. James 



 Jan 4/4/11 
 I don&apos;t know why your commercials have to have cavemen or animals in them. It certainly doesn&apos;t entice me to run to DQ. It just makes me want to barf! 



 Dianna Allison 3/28/11 
 Have been living in Florence Oregon for about a year and have gone to the Dairy Queen here, but I never will again. I am currently being treated for cancer and so my taste buds are in awful shape. I went in and asked for a burger with NO cheese and when I got home with my order not only was there cheese on my burger but the fries were stale and cold. I will admit when I called I was not the nicest person in the world but I did not YELL. I requested a new burger and returned promptly to pick it up. Not did the owner yell at me in front of other customers she was VERY rude. I will never go to that Dairy Queen again. 



 pearl waters 3/20/11 
 i picked up a grilled chicken today for lunch..it was pretty in appearance..But the dressing(ranch) was spoiled and hot it was not cool or cold. I was very disappointed. I lve in fairmont wv..I will keep going to DQ I love it... 



 michele spring 3/14/11 
 PLEASE DO SOMETHING ABOUT THE STUPID,STUPID COMMERCIALS! I WANT TO SHOOT MY TV EVERY TIME ONE COMES ON. CAN&apos;T YOU AFFORD ANYONE TO DO YOUR ADVERTISING? IT IS REALLY ELEMENTARY! The food is good and costs enough -could You make it a little more up-scale? I&apos;m not suggesting sophisticated,it is a fast food restaurant, but maybe a place families would entertain. You are amuzing the wrong audience! 



 Brooke Bowersock 3/11/11 
 my Husband, children and I went to dairy queen in Wapakonmeta OH, for lunch we went through the drive thru b/c my husband works second shift and had to get ready for work when we ordered our food the drive thru wrung the order up wrong, didn&apos;t let my husband finish ordering his meal and his chocolate shake wasn&apos;t Chocolate to say the least. My children didn&apos;t get their frozen treat with their kids Meals and my frenchfrie were ice cold almost like they stuck frozen fries with my meal and then on top of that when I called to speak to the manager they hung up on me. I&apos;m pissed amd doubt I will ever eat there again. 



 Melvin Mierkey 3/11/11 
 1303 N BISHOP
ROLLA, MO 65401-2151
573-364-7200
My wife and a family friend visited the above location on Fri night March 11,2011
were they ordered 4 Banana splits 2 reg and 2 special ordered when the Manager went to give my wife the sacks containing the deserts my wife went about checking them to ensure that they were correctly made the manager told my wife that even if they were not correctly made that they could not afford to re-make 1.99 deserts - they of course were not correctly made when my wife attempted to get them corrected the manager told her and our family friend to leave the business. She got home and was in tears told me about it (we live less than 3 mins away from the business) I returned to the dq location with the splits walked directly to the counter and asked for the manager witch the person got with no problem the manager came to the counter and I asked first for the corporate number she refused to give it to me telling me that she was not only the manager but the owner and the corporate so the &quot;buck stops here&quot; (her words) also she refused to give her name. I started to ask about what happened with my wife and she stopped me mid sentence and informed me that the splits were correct and that DQ could not afford to remake to order I went to pull out one of the splits and the bag ripped and they fell to the floor at this time she told me and my witness to leave which I did upon returning home I got on the net looked up the corp&apos;s phone number talked with and gave David - ex 672 my take on this event also informing him that I would be shooting a MSG to you about this horrid event. I am not wanting my money back I AM wanting a written apology from the manager/owner of the Rolla Mo location to my wife and a re-commitment from said owner/manager to customer service to the surrounding community.
M.Wm.Mierkey
mmierkey@yahoo.com
109 E.4th Street
Rolla, Mo 65401 

 

 Michael Perryman 3/10/11 
 Tonight my pregnant daughter, grandson and wife went to the dairy queen on ridge road in griffith, indiana. We haven&apos;t been to a DQ in a while and this trip reminded us why. The food was disgusting - GROSS! I spent $25 on food that for the most part ended up in the garbage. Fries were cold and stale, onion rings were all broken with the breading falling off. The kids meal grill cheese was cold and chewy as if it had been sitting around for a while. My pork sandwitch was mainly sauce. I wouldn&apos;t mind spending money on food that was edible, but really? this food was terrible and we will never go back to the dq on ridge road. 



 sue bennet 3/5/11 
 i went into the dairy queen on grand ave in billings mt and marcel was fantastic . great food and wonderful service by this man.keep up the good job! 



 Mildred 3/6/11 
 I have been going to the D.Q on collage hill in Texarkana Tx. for many of years.and pretty much know some of the employees by name (very friendly staff) so yes i WAS a satisfied customer until recently. in the past few months i noticed a new manager. don&apos;t know how he got this position and don&apos;t care . but i will tell you that he one of the rudest people I have seen in a long time . He not management material, any manager that yells and speaks to the employees the way he does in front of customers. and from what i understand he has a relative that works in a local D.Q in the same town that is also a manager, she is not any better then he is . i have heard them both threaten these employees with there jobs, if they didn&apos;t do exactly what they were told when they were told. and i also heard them both say they had the pull to get rid of any one they wanted.(VERY UNPROFESSIONAL). and in the past few weeks i noticed several good employees that no longer work there. I have ask to speak to this manager and was told he was to busy. as a manager myself I think your Corporate Office should be monitoring and evaluating your store managers. some people are just not cut out for those high positions 



 Jeene Wright 2/11/11 
 I have had a great time at my local DQ Greenwood South Carolina. I enjoyed everything at the resturant from being neat and clean and wonderful customer service. I love that store... 



 David McPheeters 1/2/11 
 I visited wheelersburg Ohio the last week of december for a business meeting. My second day in town I decided to have lunch at the Dq there in the wheelersburg area. I travel alot due to my career path that I have chose and I was extemely impressed by the friendliness this operation offered. The young lady that took my order was one of the nicest ladies I have ve across in a long while. I sat in the lobby a little longer than I needed and just watched as she talked with customers of all ages and sexes. She was a natural sweet individual and could tell she actually enjoyed her job with pride. I was so content with the whole experience that I dined there the rest of my stay for lunch. So often duringy travel I have just normal experiences that this one has stuck in my mind. I am looking forward to my next trip back, maybe she will still remember my order. Thanks for a memorable experience. 



 12/20/10 
 I am Kevin Howell the financial officer for the Military Order of the Purple Heart Beirut Chapter 642 in Jacksonville NC. This afternoon I went to the DQ located hon Hway 17 Jacksonville to make arrangements to buy and pick up Chicken strips for 50 people on Saturday morning, 20 November 2010. The female store manager said she had to call the District Manager, a female named Tracy, and let her know. I found this confusing. She came back and said that they could not make up the order because I did not give them enough time. I asked if DQ had a limit on how many chicken strips a customer could purchase and she said no. So I said why can&apos;t I order a bunch of chicken strips for saturday. I was prepared to pay immediatley. She said I had to talk to her boss, Tracy and dialed the number on her phone. I intorduced myself to Tracy and explained what I wanted to buy and she went off on me telling me she was tired of people trying to get something for nothing. At no time did I request anything free. I deliberately used the term buy. I was shocked at her rudeness and said Sheesh,lady calm down. She then went ballistic and I hung up. We have 310 member of the Military Ordeer of the Purple Heart in our Chapter and over 60,000 Marines based here. It should take about 5 minutes of tweeting to get the word out. Additionally, the event is a 3 state conference being held here so word should spread pretty quickly. The Military Order of the Purple Heart is not looking for freebies, we pay our own way. 



 Melanie 12/6/10 
 I am very disappointed in Dairy Queen&apos;s corporate decision not to bring back Peppermint blizzards during the Christmas season. I look forward to December at Dairy Queen, just for that reason. 



 Kevin Howell 11/16/10 
 I am Kevin Howell the financial officer for the Military Order of the Purple Heart Beirut Chapter 642 in Jacksonville NC. This afternoon I went to the DQ located hon Hway 17 Jacksonville to make arrangements to buy and pick up Chicken strips for 50 people on Saturday morning, 20 November 2010. The female store manager said she had to call the District Manager, a female named Tracy, and let her know. I found this confusing. She came back and said that they could not make up the order because I did not give them enough time. I asked if DQ had a limit on how many chicken strips a customer could purchase and she said no. So I said why can&apos;t I order a bunch of chicken strips for saturday. I was prepared to pay immediatley. She said I had to talk to her boss, Tracy and dialed the number on her phone. I intorduced myself to Tracy and explained what I wanted to buy and she went off on me telling me she was tired of people trying to get something for nothing. At no time did I request anything free. I deliberately used the term buy. I was shocked at her rudeness and said Sheesh,lady calm down. She then went ballistic and I hung up. We have 310 member of the Military Ordeer of the Purple Heart in our Chapter and over 60,000 Marines based here. It should take about 5 minutes of tweeting to get the word out. Additionally, the event is a 3 state conference being held here so word should spread pretty quickly. The Military Order of the Purple Heart is not looking for freebies, we pay our own way. 



 Heather 10/23/10 
 Ok, Dairy Queen is a daily stop my fiancae likes the SOFT serve ice cream the Chocolate.. We go to Dairy Queen in Cambridge Ohio at least twice a day any buy quarts of Chocolate ice cream.. 2 days ago we went through the drive thru and ordered 2 quarts and we pay get the ice cream and get down the road to find out that the ice cream had came out of the freezer.. I went back to the drive thru and I was so mad I told the store manager who was at the window I was like seriously can I have some Ice Cream thats not frozen and that had just came out of the freezer he took the bag outta my hand and walked over to the guy who had gave us the bag and said they dont want this.. Im sorry but no when I Pay 6.98 for 2 quarts of Ice cream from a store that serves SOFT SERVE ICE CREAM Y would I want Ice cream that had been put in a quart container and been frozen not only does the color change but it does not taste the same.. If i wanted frozen ice cream I would have went to Wal-mart and paid 2 dollars for a half gallon.. I am still mad about this and I was not treated right when I returned the Ice Cream.. Then yesterday my fiancae went to Dairy Queen and spacefically asked for 2 quarts of chocolate not frozen he gets home and the first quart was out of the machine and the second one had been frozen.. Im sorry but when you ask for something as a customer as reasonable as soft serve out of a machine you should get what you want.. I am not happy with what has happen and now Its sad that I have to drive 25 min to another Dairy Queen that treast and gives there customers what they ask for. 



 candice 10/17/10 
 On October 6,2010 i went trough drive thur to get something to eat, and ther was a gernal manager was going off on this other person outside in front of all of the customer in drivethur, and i heard her tell this black guy that she will punch him in the face, and as of a manager u can not tell anyone like that cause u can have a law suit, and i am not the only person who heard this, i think she would be fired from her job, Dairy Queen of Dawson Springs, Ky.. 



 10/12/10 
 The Dairy Queen in Moshiem, TN has very poor management!! They have constant rodent problems (rats), problems keeping stuff in stock, problems keeping the place clean it&apos;s always filthy. I was eating there one day and there was this awful large rodent run across the floor, I believe this Dairy Queen needs some serious work!! If not soon it should just be shut down, tore down, and re-built with a new management!!! I&apos;ve never seen such a dirty, filthy, smelling restaurant in my life, it should be welcoming and introducing, yet it&apos;s the complete opposite! It has a horrible smell, there&apos;s always flies sworming around you to where you get so fed up you can&apos;t eat your food, something really needs to be done to this place, they always get complaints, whether it has to deal with the management or the food it&apos;s a never ending piece of crap hole!! P.S. I WORK THERE!! PLEASE DO SOMETHING ABOUT THIS IT&apos;S GETTING OUT OF HAND!! 



 kell thorp 10/6/10 
 WELL MY OPINION ON THE DAIRY QUEEN COMPLETELY, I DO NOT THINK THAT U SHOULD HAVE FAMILY MEMBERS WORKING AT THE SAME STORE, AND THE HEAD MANAGER TAKES UP FOR HER FAMILY REMEMBERS. BEFORE SHE DOES HER OTHER EMPLOYEE&apos;S, AND SHE HAD THREATEN THEM BEFORE. I THINK THAT IT SHOULD BE AGAINST THE POLICY FOR FAMILY REMEMBERS BE HIRED IN THE SAME STORE. 



 STeve 4/25/10 
 My family and I went to two different Dairy Queen (DQ) locations because we were informed about th buy one get second blizzard for .25 cents. However this ad was not honored by many local stores.
We believe this advsertsing should have NOT been provided on TV, because my family was excited on this offer, but rather we spent the actual; retail price and were mislead by the advertisement.
Although we enjoyed the blizzards,
I will not shop at any DQ store from this day on..... 



 Dave 5/24/10 
 The Dairy Queen in Welland Ontario is ripping off it&apos;s clients.

They have a 2 for $5 deal for small dipped cones but when you ask for the 2 cones, you&apos;re charged more if you didn&apos;t ask for the deal.

Why do I have to ask for the deal? IT&quot;S IN PLACE ALREADY!!! Would they make it smaller maybe? I don&apos;t know but it&apos;s a bait and switch if I ever did see one! 



 Patrick 5/23/10 
 I went to purchase two blizzards and the total came to be $6.01. Are we serious. This is obviously poor price management. Why would you price something to come out to be one penny more. I know this has to make people angry b/c it made me angry that I had to receive 99 cents in change. Blizzards are your top sellers how about shifting your prices to be customer friendly. 



 Barbara Pearce 9/13/10 
 I was very disappointed in my crispy chicken wrap when I got one at my local dairy queen here in Elyria OH,where was the meat? When the chicken wrap first came out it had as much meat as the wrap and the lettuce was fresh too. I enjoy going for food and ice cream every once in awhile I never had a problem until last night. Thank you for your time 



 Pam 6/11/10 
 My daughter worked for you Carrollton, Georgia store the summer 2009...she was laid off when school started back&amp;was told to come back summer 2010&amp;she would be rehired, she re-applied&amp;spoke to the manager whom she obtained the application from...she was later told by another employee that they DO NOT rehire! This is not true...they just rehired a manager that can&apos;t even pass a drug test&amp;had to take days off to attend a DUI class!...My daughter never received a seperation notice also...this is no way to run a business...it&apos;s sad to know this is who is serving our children ice cream! 



 cindy morrison 9/2/10 
 you have a store in jasper tn that whomever your manager is needs to be replaced all I know is that she is from india (or one of those country) my daughter angie easterly ordered a birthday cake for her 19yr old daughter to be picked up tonight (sept 2) and when she went to pick it up it wasn;t done as orkered with the gel frosting instead it had plastic over it ,when one of the girls tried to help the so called manager took the cake in the back and said she would not sale her nothing.Needless to say my daughter is still totally upset. This is a customer that has ordered many cakes before as has my other daughter and was NEVER treated so rudely.Now I intend to not only complain about this on facebook with the stores address and number but also in the local paper and radio.I want to know that you have at least called this awful women or done something for this customer.You can have them make a cake as ordered to be ready by my grandaughters birthday tomorrow and call me to pick it up.My daughter is a good piller of that community and works in the office of the local bank and no one is going to treat her like that.MY name is Cindy Morrison you have this e-mail and my number is 423-667-3526 her number is 423-827-7083 Angela Easterly 



 Kris B 7/28/10 
 I have always gone to a Dairy Queen for your wonderful soft ice cream..It was sweet, flavorful,&amp;creamy. Today, I had my usual sundae Peanut Buster Parfait, at the South Hill Puyallup, Wa. store..It was terrible..are you cutting cost???It was like iced 1% milk..Nothing..no flavor. Please bring back the original!!!! 



 ryan 8/10/10 
 Every time I come to dq it takes about 15 minutes to get from the drive thru box to the actual pick up window. There service is terrible. I will not go again.
 

 

 Stanton 8/11/10 
 I went to the dairy queen grill and chill location on Tudor Rd in Anchorage AK, never will I go there again. They have really terrible service. The people are not that friendly. It takes forever to get any food and some people just leave because it takes so long. Back in May for my daughters birthday I ordered two cakes from this location, the day we went to pick them up was also the day of the party. They ended up making us late to set up the party, and on top of that they did not even do the cakes right, they messed up our order and did not even make the second cake and gave us another cake that was already made as an apology but that cake was a totally different color and then they want to argue about it in front of other customers. They need to fire and rehire all new people. Just last week me and my wife went there again to give them a second try, they swiped our debit card three times charging our account all three times. The manager got lippy with me about it and did not refund our money. I went back in there today to inform them that the refund had not gone through my account and that the charges were still on my account and I wanted my money back and I wanted to be compensated for the inconvenience. He told me to wait a few more days and the money would be taken off our bank account. But we ended up getting a free lunch out of the deal. Another thing that happened was when they made us our free lunch, I was waiting patiently for about 15 minutes while all the workers were running around with their heads cut off, I notice that one of the workers in the back was not wearing any gloves and was handling all the food. When the server brought my food to me I said to her that the guy that is not wearing gloves needs to put some on and not a single customer would want to eat that food that he touched and requested the food be remade because of it. She tried telling me that it was fine and that they wash their hands before they start working. WOW you bet your sweet ass I will not go back to that place. I CALLED THE MUNICIPAL OF ANCHORAGE AND THE HEALTH INSPECTOR AND REPORTED THEM FOR UNSANITARY BEHAVIOR. 



 PAT GOSNELL 8/13/10 
 POOR SERVICE,DIRTY BATH ROOMS FLOORS.I DON;T THINK I EVER SEEN IT THIS WAY BEFORE.THEY FORGOT OUR ORDER SO FINLEY I GOT UP TO SEE ABOUT IT THEY JUST FORGOT THEY SAID.KITCHEN WAS FILTHY BUNCH A YOUNG PEOPLE DON&apos;T LIKE OR DON&apos;T KNOW WHAT THEY ARE DOING DIDN&apos;T SEE A MANAGER TABLES WERE A MESS AND THEY WERE ALL IS A LITTLE BUNCH EATING AND LAUGHING THIS IS A BIG ONE PLEASE DO SOMETHING TO KEEP IT FROM CLOSING ALSO. 100 DORMANCENTRE DR SPARTANBURG S.C. 



 SMM 8/5/10 
 The Dairy Queen in Newport, TN needs to be closed and bull-dozed........the management is rude and totally unfair and unethical toward it&apos;s emplyees.the kitchen and counter area is FILTHY, the emplyees are uninterested and not focused on their tasks, as well as untidy and dirty. The food product is poor and oftentimes, product which has fallen on the floor is still served to the customer, this was disclosed by two former emplyees...They were forced to serve the contaminated product of face dismissal...........PLEASE, PLEASE remove your affiliation with that particular DQ, it is so beneath the standards that have been associated with DQ over the years....I no longer frequent the DQ in Newport, and often wonder what Warren Buffet would think of this particulare representative of one of his Bershire-Hathaway investments.....he peronally would lock the doors and start the dozing 



 Erica James 6/27/10 
 I went to Dairy Queen in Norcross, GA (P&apos;tree Ind Blvd), I was in drive thru and was told to &quot;wait a minute&quot; which took more than 5 minutes. I then just drove around to the window to speak with the cashier, who was sitting down smoking a cigarette along with 3 other employees!. Their appearances were HORRIBLE, they were dripping in sweat, smelled of smoke, no one washed their hands and all I was told was the a/c was not working and they felt under paid and needed a smoke break! I then noticed the health score of 87 and asked why it was so low, one of the cashiers told me, &quot;well that&apos;s not even the right score, it&apos;s actually lower, the managers just didn&apos;t want to take it down.&quot;
I asked then to speak with the manager who told the cashier to tell me she was too busy to talk! I had it, so I drove around to go inside. I immediately noticed, the a/c infact was not working, the cooks in the kitchen had no gloves and touched every item with their BARE HANDS! I then asked for the manager again, the cashier pointed to her, she was siiting down eating with an employee who wasn&apos;t even helping out her co-workers.

I walked over to her and asked why was she too busy to talk, &quot;because I am eating,&quot; she said quite rudely. Finally, I asked for both of their names, the manager is Kathy (has a strong accent) and the employee was Tina. I believe they both should be fired simply because they are not helpful, Kathy needs more practice on communication skills, as I was walking to their table the conversation was about somebody&apos;s boyfriend, the staff needs a positive manager, working a/c and nobody seems to understand one another. Lastly, why is half the staff hispanic and don&apos;t speak English, they don&apos;t work well with Americans and I will contact the Health Dept regarding the score and Fox 5 news regarding the spanish speaking employees for citizenship which I believe they don&apos;t have!

Hopefully something can be done to help out this Dairy Queen!!!! 



 Katie Kelly 7/15/10 
 I just recently went to the South Eagan, Minnesota Dairy Queen. I would have to say it was the best experience that I have had at any fast food restaurant by far!!!! My two kids insisted we go to dairy queen for diner because it was a hot humid day and they obviously wanted ice cream afterwards. We got there around 7 and lobby was packed full, I was hesitant at first to eat there but you could see the determination in the employees to help the customers. So we wait only about 10 min. before they got to us and they were so nice, they apologized for the wait and were excited to take our order. We went to go sit down to get out of the way for the other customers, and about 5 minutes later our food was brought out to us and AGAIN we got another apology for the wait. I just couldnt believe how good their customer service was and how the girl that took our ordered remembered our faces! 



 laina king 7/17/10 
 HI, I stopped in today to get a medium hot fudge sundae at the Dairy Queen in Summit Place Plaza, Silverthorne Colorado 0n HWY 6. It was hotter than blue blazes in the store, with door wide open--no A/C. This is absurd at these prices--$3.00 for something that should sell for $1.00 or less. Then when I got my sundae I noticed that now the hot fudge or whatever the chemical material is that they use for hot fudge, doesn&apos;t even melt into the dairy queen material (it&apos;s not ice cream so I don&apos;t call it that). The fudge should at least melt or blend into the white material. It doesn&apos;t. I realize that there are many chemicals being used but this is a bit rediculous.

also, these tiny little containers for $2.90 cents. I really think Dairy Quenn needs to do something. It wasn&apos;t even satisfying--no real flavor just sweet taste.
What a diappointment.


 



 Ryan P 7/23/10 
 Just stopped in at a dairy queen in eugene Oregon off of river road and noticed an employee blowing his nose in the back corner. Right after he proceeded to refill the pickle jar with his hands and no gloves right after. Just a heads up I will not be visiting this branch again. Thank you 

 Page 1  Page 2  Page 3  Page 4  Page 5  





 Write A Review For International Dairy Queen, Inc Corporate Headquarters 
Note: This is not to be used to contact International Dairy Queen, Inc Corporate Offices nor is this site affiliated with them in any way. The purpose of this site is supply you with their phone number and address as well as share your thoughts about International Dairy Queen, Inc. Your review will be posted and available for anyone to read so please keep that in mind when posting personal information. 

 
 
 Your Name Your Rating (5 Stars) Best (4 Stars) Better (3 Stars) Good (2 Stars) Fair (1 Stars) Poor 
 
 
 Other Headquarters 
 REI Corporate Office 
 Verizon Wireless Corporate Office 
 Twitter, Inc Corporate Office 
 Food Lion, Llc Corporate Office 
 Burger King Corporate Office 
 Crate And Barrel Corporate Office 
 Darden Restaurants, Inc. Corporate Office 
 DKNY Corporate Office 
 Mercedes Benz Corporate Office 
 Farm Fresh Corporate Office 
 Kohls Corporate Office 
 Ryder Corporate Office 
 Mr. Goodcents Corporate Office 
 Groupon, Inc. Corporate Office 
 Toys R Us Corporate Office 
 Big Lots Corporate Office 
 McDonald&apos;s Corporate Office 
 Hardees Corporate Office 
 Ideal Image Corporate Office 
 Olive Garden Corporate Office 
 La Quinta Corporate Office 
 Experian Corporate Office 
 Sports Authority Corporate Office 
 Adidas Corporate Office 
 Fisher Price Corporate Office 
 more 
 

 
 Copyright2009-2012 eCorporateOffices - Privacy Policy - Contact Us - Location - Radio - Textbook 
All reviews on this website are user-generated and we take no responsibility of any kind for the content which is posted. We do not know the accuracy of the reviews.
	</body>
</document>
