<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005982" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/07/versailles_40-year_anniversary.php" time="2012-07-12-22:39" support="1" score="0.0007087695197081822" bingtitle="Versailles&apos; 40-Year Anniversary Party - Miami Restaurants and ..." webtitle="Versailles&apos; 40-Year Anniversary Party - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="82"/>
	<description>Crowds waited in long lines outside for a seat ... I wrote about Versailles I promised to tell the ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Last Night 
Versailles&apos; 40-Year Anniversary Party
 By Riki Altman Wed., Jul. 13 2011 at 1:07 PM Categories: Last Night 
 Pin It 
 
 Photo by Riki Altman 
 ​Last night, 300 VIPs and hundreds of hungry Versailles &apos; diners flooded the intersection of Calle Ocho and SW 36th and 37th Avenues to celebrate the 40th anniversary of Miami&apos;s most popular Cuban restaurant.
 
 
 Photo by Riki Altman 
 Under a white tent attached to the dining room, VIPs gathered to listen to a live band, drink complimentary Bacardi cocktails and Hatuey beer, watch professional dancers shake their stuff, and munch on appetizers like bacalao, fried yucca, ham croquettes, empanadas, and chicharrones de pollo. Politicians with slicked-back hair, dark suits, and American flag pins were spotted mingling with local celebrities while television news crews did their best to document the goings on outside.

As for some of the fashion statements made, uh, let&apos;s say empanadas were way more successful.

 
 
​ Crowds waited in long lines outside for a seat, eager to take advantage of rollbacks that entitled them to meals priced as they were in 1971. Who can resist a $1 medianoche?

 
 Photo by Riki Altman 
​ Once inside, diners were also treated to strolling musicians.

We managed to corner Nicole Valls, granddaughter of founder Felipe Valls, who works in operations management for the restaurant and asked her a few quickie questions:

 
 Photo by Riki Altman Felipe Valls, Jr. and his daughter Nicole 
​ New Times: You obviously weren&apos;t born until after this restaurant was already a success, but do you remember the first time you came in? 

 Nicole Valls: I remember coming in as a kid. I worked at the bakery when I was 15.

 In the last blog I wrote about Versailles I promised to tell the readers what your restaurant&apos;s plans are for Castro&apos;s dying day .

Last time, we were caught off guard when the media reported he had supposedly died. This time, the stations have reserved spots: CNN, Univision... We have a map with everyone&apos;s spots. The police have to close off Eighth Street. Any news of Cuba hits and people flock over!

 We heard perhaps some changes are underway. Tell us about those. 

We are going to remodel the interiors with nicer materials--but we&apos;re keeping the mirrors! We have plans to expand, adding a new kitchen and bakery and a new souvenir store.

 Any more news? 

We launched our website today. And we&apos;re on Twitter and Facebook. We still have people who come every day. They come after concerts, parties, the clubs. But we&apos;re going to use social media to bring in the younger people.

 What are your thoughts, looking over this group of people celebrating your family&apos;s milestone? 

We&apos;re so grateful for it!

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Location Info
 
Venue



Map
 
 Versailles Bakery 

3555 SW 8th St., Miami, FL

Category: Restaurant 
 
 10 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Versailles Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
I should have gone and wore my Che Guevarra t- shirt and armed myself with a stun gun.
 

TotalComments: 1
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
The Corner
 View Ad | View Site 
Mo&apos;s Bagels&amp;Deli
 View Ad | View Site 
Alma Mexicana
 View Ad | View Site 
Pasta Folie&apos;s
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Reviews for Whisk, Villa Azur and Tap 42 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
