<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005120" url="http://wn.com/Mobile_payment__Point_of_sale" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="3" score="0.002284732876711833" bingtitle="Mobile Payment Point of Sale - World News" webtitle="Mobile Payment Point of Sale">
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001316" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000593" bing-rank="120"/>
	<description>Point of sale (POS) (also sometimes referred to as Point of purchase (POP) ) or checkout is the location where a transaction occurs, Mobile Point of Sale (POS ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, 12 July 2012 upload Login Edit 
 go to the top About WN Contact Feedback Privacy Policy ©2012 World News Inc., all Rights Reserved 
 Mobile Payment Point of Sale Tweet sms this page email this page 
 Videos Images Wiki News Related Video Details Twitter Collage Shopping 
 
 Point of sale Mobile payment 

 Related News Top Headlines 

 mobile payment point of sale 

 mobile payment point of sale 

 Related Sites People Places Video Suggestions 

 WN Shopping Ebay Publications 
 
 

 Open Collage in a new Window Email the Collage 
 Loading... 
 Sorry your browser does not support IFRAME Loading suggestions ... 
 Atari 520ST Barcode Brand Brand ambassador Brand management Broadcasting Cash drawer Cash register Computer software Credit card Digital marketing Dillard&apos;s Direct marketing Drip marketing EBay EFTPOS Epson Fast food restaurant Fujitsu Gene Mosher Hospitality IBM In-game advertising Intel 8008 Internet marketing ISO 8583 IT Retail JavaPOS Local area network Los Angeles Times Loyalty marketing Managed care Market research Market segmentation Marketing Marketing activation Marketing ethics Marketing management Marketing operations Marketing strategy McDonald&apos;s Mexica MICROS Systems Microsoft Microsoft Windows Mobile marketing NCR Corporation OPOS Panasonic (brand) Pathmark Peer-to-peer Point of sale Premium (marketing) Pricing Printing Prize (marketing) Product marketing Product placement Programming language Publication Publicity Radiant Systems Receipt Retail Retailing Sales Sales promotion Salon software Self checkout Service (economics) Sex in advertising Software Squirrel Systems Sun Microsystems Talk Point of sale Target Corporation Template Marketing Touchscreen Underwriting spot UnifiedPOS ViewTouch Visual merchandising Wikipedia Cleanup Wireless POS 
 

 
 Microsoft 
Microsoft Corporation is a public multinational corporation headquartered in Redmond, Washington, USA that develops, manufactures, licenses, and supports a wide range of products and services predominantly related to computing through its various product divisions. Established on April 4, 1975 to develop and sell BASIC interpreters for the Altair 8800, Microsoft rose to dominate the home computer operating system (OS) market with MS-DOS in the mid-1980s, followed by the Microsoft Windows line of OSs. The ensuing rise of stock in the company&apos;s 1986 initial public offering (IPO) made an estimated four billionaires and 12,000 millionaires from Microsoft employees. Microsoft would come to dominate other markets as well, notably the office suite market with Microsoft Office.
 http://wn.com/Microsoft 




 
 Gene Mosher 
 http://wn.com/Gene_Mosher ViewTouch 
 http://wn.com/ViewTouch 




 
Make changes yourself !
 LOGIN to EDIT and SAVE this page. 
 Send this Playlist by SMS Email this Page 
 Mobile Point-of-Sale Solutions 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:30 Published: 08 Mar 2012 Updated: 25 Mar 2012 
Author: firstdata First Data&apos;s range of mobile point-of-sale solutions make taking payments on the road fast and secure. First Data Mobile Pay, VeriFone PAYware Mobile and the FD400Ti terminal make it possible for merchants to pay lower card-present rates. http://wn.com/Mobile_Point-of-Sale_Solutions 
 GBmobile Mobile Point of Sale: iPod Touch 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 4:18 Published: 18 Jan 2010 Updated: 13 Apr 2012 
Author: globalbaymobile This is a video of how Global Bay&apos;s Mobile POS solution can run on the iPod Touch which integrates to MOST Point of Sale systems. Call us for more info: 908-822-7100 or www.globalbay.com http://wn.com/GBmobile_Mobile_Point_of_Sale_iPod_Touch 
 Bitcoin - Point of sale system 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:13 Published: 23 Aug 2011 Updated: 01 May 2012 
Author: javonyt See github.com for code and more details. Discussion at bitcointalk.org . http://wn.com/Bitcoin_Point_of_sale_system 
 Mobile Point of Sale (POS) Software by Retail Anywhere 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 3:42 Published: 04 Dec 2009 Updated: 17 Jan 2012 
Author: retailanywhere Retail Anywhere Mobile Point of Sale (POS) incorporates the power and functionality of a traditional POS workstation into a mobile device that allows you to service customers anywhere at anytime. Whether youre hosting a summer sidewalk sale, vending at an outdoor sporting event or even conducting transactions in-flight, put the power of Retail Anywhere&apos;s POS system in the palm of your hand. Visit www.retailanywhere.com http://wn.com/Mobile_Point_of_Sale_POS_Software_by_Retail_Anywhere 
 CHARGE Anywhere Mobile Point of Sale Software&amp;Intermec CN3 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:57 Published: 03 Sep 2008 Updated: 03 Apr 2012 
Author: CHARGEAnywhereMKTG CHARGE Anywhere Mobile Point of Sale software and the Intermec CN3 with PW50 printer and magnetic card swipe. Process credit card transactions anywhere in the world with the worlds most rugged handheld computer. http://wn.com/CHARGE_Anywhere_Mobile_Point_of_Sale_Software_Intermec_CN3 
 Openbravo Mobile Web / Multi-Touch Preview (Web POS example) 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 11:32 Published: 14 Apr 2012 Updated: 23 Jun 2012 
Author: openbravo See for yourself the kind of state-of-the art mobile user experiences coming out of Openbravo&apos;s global open source labs. Our user-centric experiences are not only productive and leverage the latest multi-touch mobile hardware options, they are also a joy to execute. Your Barcelona-based hosts are Openbravo User Experience Guru Rob Goris and Retail specialist Elena Martinez, who will use a prototype to demonstrate some of the use cases we are developing. The focus of this particular prototype is our Web POS (Point of Sale) client, which is one very exciting new addition to the Openbravo for Retail solution. This video will give you a feel for the kind of integrated, mobile web experiences you can expect from Openbravo. Specifically note these points about our mobile web vision: - this user experience is representative of the forthcoming Web POS functionality, and - it clearly demonstrates the kind of mobile web UIs that will be generated using Openbravo&apos;s device-neutral, model-driven technology, and - it shows the power of a centralized, real time database that serves both retail back office and store-level needs--easily accessed by great web UIs from a choice of traditional PCs / POS terminals or mobile devices Note that this is a prototype / concept video, and hence does not precisely represent the initial Web POS product version. As a development philosophy, we&quot;start with the end in mind&quot;from the (Market + UX) vision perspective, and then use our agile development&lt;b&gt;...&lt;/b&gt; http://wn.com/Openbravo_Mobile_Web_Multi-Touch_Preview_Web_POS_example 
 GBmobile Mobile Point of Sale: iPod Touch V2 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:52 Published: 08 Feb 2010 Updated: 23 May 2012 
Author: globalbaymobile Back by popular demand, here is another video shot of our mobile point of sale solution designed for the iPod Touch + iPod Sled unit. This video shows the complete POS life cycle in under 2 minutes. Retailers, ask us how we can enable your stores with this solution! Call 908-822-7100 or cpark@globalbay.com http://wn.com/GBmobile_Mobile_Point_of_Sale_iPod_Touch_V2 
 Mobile Payment SquareUp: SalesVu Beats Square at Brian&apos;s Brew 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 3:54 Published: 24 Aug 2011 Updated: 10 Jun 2012 
Author: KapMooProductions Hey this is Brian from Brian&apos;s Brew. I recently switch from Square to SalesVu. SalesVu is the best point of sale and mobile payment solution I&apos;ve ever seen. SalesVu&apos;s card reader is more stable and more secure than Squares. Their rates are better. With Square, if I enter the card manually, because of an account that I have on file or a scratched card, they want to charge 3.5%. With SalesVu, it&apos;s still 2.7% for manually entered cards. With Square if I do more than a $1000 I have to wait 30 days for the funds to post. With SalesVu, it doesn&apos;t matter how much I do, it&apos;s still the next day. I love this SalesVu app because it just blows Square out of the water. It is the best point of sale. Square is very basic. You put items on there, once you get over 20 items you have trouble finding everything, but with this SalesVu app, you can look at it through category, you can look at it alphabetically, you can program the list where, the top of list is what you&apos;re selling the most. You can find anything in seconds. It&apos;s very user friendly. I love how I can just program modifiers in, if someone wants to make a latte a soy latte I can have that charge as a modifier. You can&apos;t do that with Square. There&apos;s a great part of the app that connects with facebook. It&apos;s fantastic for viral marketing. There&apos;s a discount button on the app that&apos;s not on Square. You can program it to be what ever kind of discount you want. That&apos;s not anything close to what Square offers. The great thing about&lt;b&gt;...&lt;/b&gt; http://wn.com/Mobile_Payment_SquareUp_SalesVu_Beats_Square_at_Brian&apos;s_Brew 
 FLAVIUS. ipod touch pos. ipad pos 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:56 Published: 30 Apr 2010 Updated: 01 Jun 2012 
Author: gnsjapan 2009/02 start - Captured Live on Ustream at www.ustream.tv with the Ustream Mobile App http://wn.com/FLAVIUS_ipod_touch_pos_ipad_pos 
 mPOS - Mobile Point of Sale Transaction iPhone App 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 5:19 Published: 10 May 2009 Updated: 26 Dec 2011 
Author: jefftube2134 mPOS is our Mobile Point of Sale Transaction iPhone App which was made for the Spring 2009 Course E6998 at Columbia University in the Computer Science Department http://wn.com/mPOS_Mobile_Point_of_Sale_Transaction_iPhone_App 
 Benefits of Mobile Point-of-Sale Technology 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:47 Published: 18 Aug 2011 Updated: 18 Aug 2011 
Author: RadiantSystemsInc Christian Nahas, Vice President of Radiant&apos;s Retail division, speaks about what the benefits of mobile technology are and how it works with traditional retail point-of-sale technology. http://wn.com/Benefits_of_Mobile_Point-of-Sale_Technology 
 iPhone Mobile credit card reader.mov APCO MERCHANT SERVICES 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:46 Published: 25 Mar 2011 Updated: 05 Feb 2012 
Author: APCOmerchants APCO Merchant services 888.353.5800 mobile payment solutions. AMS-VELVET accept credit cards and debit cards from your iPhone, iPad and iPod. APCO&apos;s selection of mobile card readers is ideal for processing payments ON THE GO, away from a register or point-of-sale terminal. The robust iPhone, iPad and iPodmobile merchant processing solutions are secure, easy to set up and a welcome convenience to your customers. Mobile credit card readers, Mobile debit card readers. IPhone attachments. http://wn.com/iPhone_Mobile_credit_card_readermov_APCO_MERCHANT_SERVICES 
 PayMaster Mobile POS Demo using Sled / Barcode Scanner / Card Reader 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 6:41 Published: 05 Aug 2010 Updated: 11 May 2012 
Author: AppMastersLLC The PayMaster system uses the same handheld device that is used in Apple stores along with their EasyPay application. Our PayMaster application connects the handheld barcode scanner / credit card reader with your existing POS systems. PayMaster™Software&amp;Handheld Mobile POS is leading all retailers into the Retail Revolution™Guests shop freely anywhere in the store and complete their purchases without waiting in long lines. Every associate provides one-on-one personal service from sale to check out. Improve the guest&apos;s shopping experience and your customer service index. http://wn.com/PayMaster_Mobile_POS_Demo_using_Sled_Barcode_Scanner_Card_Reader 
 Mobile POS System using Sled and iPod with Barcode Scanner / Card Reader 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 12:16 Published: 04 Aug 2010 Updated: 16 Jan 2012 
Author: AppMastersLLC The PayMaster system uses the same handheld device that is used in Apple stores along with their EasyPay application. Our PayMaster application connects the handheld barcode scanner / credit card reader with your existing POS systems. PayMaster™Software&amp;Handheld Mobile POS is leading all retailers into the Retail Revolution™Guests shop freely anywhere in the store and complete their purchases without waiting in long lines. Every associate provides one-on-one personal service from sale to check out. Improve the guest&apos;s shopping experience and your customer service index. http://wn.com/Mobile_POS_System_using_Sled_and_iPod_with_Barcode_Scanner_Card_Reader 
 Mobile Point Of Sale 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 5:38 Published: 04 Aug 2009 Updated: 20 Apr 2012 
Author: NewWestTech Mobile POS software demo - New West Technologies - MXP www.newestech.com http://wn.com/Mobile_Point_Of_Sale 
 LikePOS - Erply&apos;s new POS system with PayPal integration and social features 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:41 Published: 24 May 2012 Updated: 19 Jun 2012 
Author: ERPLYsupport The all new Erply-PayPal mobile payment system LikePOS on women&apos;s boutique store&quot;Sway&quot;in CA. It&apos;s all about better social interaction with your customers. Check-in with mobile and accept PayPal payments in-store. http://wn.com/LikePOS_Erply&apos;s_new_POS_system_with_PayPal_integration_and_social_features 
 Bit-Pay Mobile Checkout 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:44 Published: 22 Sep 2011 Updated: 15 Jun 2012 
Author: bitpay Alison and Ashly demonstrate live point-of-sale Bitcoin payments using Bit-Pay Mobile Checkout. bit-pay.com http://wn.com/Bit-Pay_Mobile_Checkout 
 Mobile Wallet Service - demo video 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 4:53 Published: 22 Feb 2010 Updated: 19 Sep 2011 
Author: touchatag Toon Coppens from Alcatel-Lucent touchatag demonstrating the Alcatel-Lucent Mobile Wallet Service (MWS). MWS provides flexible payment and marketing services to operators and enterprises. In this demo both proximity payment and person to person money transfer are shown. Next to this, MWS provides support for m-commerce and remote ticketing. In this demo an iPhone, a Point-of-Sale (POS) terminal and an NFC mobile handset are used. Showing different scenarios of the mobile wallet service: payment, loyalty and coupons http://wn.com/Mobile_Wallet_Service_demo_video 
 Vend POS&amp;PayPal in Rare Device, San Francisco 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:06 Published: 24 May 2012 Updated: 24 May 2012 
Author: VendHQ Find out how Vend web-based pos integrates with PayPal for a seamless payment experience. Let your customers pay for goods and services using their PayPal account on a smart phone. http://wn.com/Vend_POS_PayPal_in_Rare_Device,_San_Francisco
	</body>
</document>
