<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005968" url="http://dot-job-descriptions.careerplanner.com/FAST-FOODS-WORKER.cfm" time="2012-07-12-22:38" support="20" score="0.0850393412180613" bingtitle="FAST-FOODS WORKER - Job Description" webtitle="FAST-FOODS WORKER - Job Description">
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001322" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001467" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>1) Serves customer of fast food restaurant: Requests customer order and depresses keys of multicounting ... serving or storage areas and assembles items on serving tray or ...</description>
	<body>
		Discover The Path To A Better Career Sign-In | Cart 
   Click here for Careers that match your Personality   
 Home Career Test Career Counseling Products Free Personality Test Assessments Resumés Find a Job Job Descriptions Articles Videos   
     
 Click here to find the perfect career 
   
 
 
&quot;FAST-FOODS WORKER&quot;
 Job Description and Jobs 
 Click here to find the perfect career 

 
Job Description:

 1) Serves customer of fast food restaurant: Requests customer order and depresses keys of multicounting machine to simultaneously record order and compute bill. 


 2) Selects requested food items from serving or storage areas and assembles items on serving tray or in takeout bag. 


 3) Notifies kitchen personnel of shortages or special orders. 


 4) Serves cold drinks, using drink-dispensing machine, or frozen milk drinks or desserts, using milkshake or frozen custard machine. 


 5) Makes and serves hot beverages, using automatic water heater or coffeemaker. 


 6) Presses lids onto beverages and places beverages on serving tray or in takeout container. 


 7) Receives payment. 


 8) May cook or apportion french fries or perform other minor duties to prepare food, serve customers, or maintain orderly eating or serving areas. 

 
Thanks for visiting CareerPlanner.com
How can we help you with your career?

 1) Use Career Testing to find the perfect career 

 2) Use Career Counseling to discover your career direction 

 3) Use Personality Type Testing to learn what really motivates you 

 4) Is your resume getting you enough interviews?
See How To Write The Perfect Resume . 
 
 

 Click here for&quot;FAST-FOODS WORKER&quot;Jobs 


 See the Future Outlook and Educational Requirements for&quot;FAST-FOODS WORKER&quot; 

 
 
Our Most Popular Products
 
 
 Discover the type of
work you will be
passionate about! 
 
 
 Click here for the
Best Career 
Choices
for Your 
Personality! 
 
 

 Click here for the
Perfect Resume! 
 
 
Career Test Video 

 
Myers-Briggs
Personality Test Video 
 

FREE !!!

 CareerPlanner Monthly Newsletter 

 Tips for Your Career and Your Job

Click here to Sign Up 
 
End Of Job Description for:&quot;FAST-FOODS WORKER&quot;
DOT:  311.472-010
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 

 
 © Copyright 1997-2012, CAREERPLANNER.COM ® Inc. All Rights Reserved 

 
 Newsletter Sign Up | About Us | Press Room | Contact Us | Privacy Policy | Refund Policy 
 Career Articles | Links to Career Sites | Linking To Us | Quote of The Day | Site Map 
 List of Careers | Career Videos | Outlook for Careers | Career Tests | List of Jobs | RSS 
 Affiliates | Career Testing for Your School or Organization 
 Offer Our Assessments To Your Clients 
 Michael T Robinson
	</body>
</document>
