<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005077" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/1785840" time="2012-07-12-21:36" support="2" score="0.00968448058868213" bingtitle="Should fast food restaurants have to post information about how ..." webtitle="Should fast food restaurants have to post information about how many calories are in their products? | Answerbag">
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="151"/>
	<description>... but its on the back of that paper thing they give you a tray ... How often, if ever, do you eat fast food hamburgers? What fast food restaurant&apos;s hamburgers do you eat most ...</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Food And Dining / Fast Food / Fast Food (General) 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
Should fast food restaurants have to post information about how
many calories are in their products?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 9 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by Little Miss Dangerous on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Post no, but have readily available, yes. It&apos;s all about making informed decisions. Some people would be surprised to learn that a grilled chicken salad minus mayo is actually healthier for them then the salad they just choked down. 
 
Comments

 
Thanks LMD.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
You&apos;re very welcome, as always :)

 Report 
 
by Little Miss Dangerous on November 4th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Just-A-Pineapple on November 2nd, 2009
 
 If they had some leaflets near the counter for people who want to know about it, that would be good.
I can tell you that most people that go into fast food restuarants are not caring about the calories. 
 
Comments

 
Thanks Just-A for the info.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Zack on November 2nd, 2009
 
 I&apos;ve never heard of a person who stop eating a big mack or whopper because it had too many calories in it. 
 
Comments

 
what is the fastfood salad craze over ?
.
PS kudos on the hitomi pic XD

 Report 
 
by Sympho de Proggy on November 2nd, 2009
 
Thanks Zack.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by lovestocook on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Some upscale restuarants should be required to post the calories and fat. Many chefs cook very high fat using a lot of buuter and cream. 
 
Comments

 
True lovestocook.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by -Icy- on November 2nd, 2009
 
 in our area is a big poster on all burger kings and mcdonalds. i ask because i must figure meds. and they have always provided a nutrition guide without delay. +5 
 
Comments

 
That&apos;s good Jen.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by ak_spook on November 2nd, 2009
 
 i dont see whats the point. no one reads it and everyone knows its bad for u 
 
Comments

 
Not all choices are bad and with proper information one can make an informed choice.

 Report 
 
by Little Miss Dangerous on November 2nd, 2009
 
Thanks AK.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
all choices are bad. even the&quot;healthy&quot;subs still contain more carbs/fat/calories than what ur suppose to have in a day. thats just one sub. in 2 hours you&apos;ll be hungry again so you eat even more and get more fat/calories/carbs.

 Report 
 
by ak_spook on November 4th, 2009
 
That&apos;s simply not true. With three kids and being on the go often, I can (and do) come up with healthy options at MOST fast food places. Since you mentioned subs, Subway has at least eight 6&quot;subs which contain 230-370 calories, 3-6g of fat (no trans fat), and 44-59g carbs. Each (except the veggie sub) is quite filling, a great source of lean protein, and well within proper parameters for being considered a healthy meal--no where near exceeding a recommended daily total (even for a shorty like me). Ideally, you *should* eat every 2-4 hours for optimal nutrition and metabolic advantage. Most people don&apos;t eat often enough and then make unhealthy choices. All things in moderation ak ;)

 Report 
 
by Little Miss Dangerous on November 7th, 2009
 
ur not suppose to intake more than a 1000 calories. u would stay under that if u ate only 3 subs not including ur drinks and snacks with the meal also not including other drinks and snacks.

me i eat alot but its like u said separate them in smaller meals so u can get ur metabolism up which will help to lose the waight and not have to suffer giving up yor favorite foods. a good choice everyone once in awhile helps aswell

 Report 
 
by ak_spook on November 8th, 2009
 
Whoa, who said you are not supposed to eat more than 1000 calories?! That is less than the daily maintenance for me to maintain my small frame with no activity. I need to eat at least 1500 calories just to keep up with my basic bodily functions. On 1700-2000 calories I can lose 2 lbs a week with proper food choices and activity. Trying to stick to an arbitrary 1000 calorie diet is exactly why so many people fail at proper nutrition and weight loss. Good choices MOST of the time is what works...proper nutrition consistently...with&apos;treats&apos;in moderation.

 Report 
 
by Little Miss Dangerous on November 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 6 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by BigEvan on November 2nd, 2009
 
 i think they all do but its on the back of that paper thing they give you a tray 
 
Comments

 
Thanks Big Evan for the info.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Lady Alathia of Vulcan on November 2nd, 2009
 
 I think the information should be available if asked, but I don&apos;t think they should have to scrawl it on the walls in neon lighting.

A posted link to an informational website is sufficient, in my opinion. The site should also include the restaurant&apos;s ingredients and some information about preparation (meat is heated to X degrees, etc). 
 
Comments

 
I&apos;ve found a few different things to a couple of national chains...

http://www.mcdonalds.com/usa/eat.html
http://www.tacobell.com/nutrition/default.aspx

I guessed their homepage URL, and then the nutritional facts page was linked on the very top portion of the main pages.

 Report 
 
by Matrixbarf on November 2nd, 2009
 
McDonalds also prints the basic nutritional information on all their packaging now.

 Report 
 
by Lady Alathia of Vulcan on November 2nd, 2009
 
Kewlies (^_^)

 Report 
 
by Matrixbarf on November 2nd, 2009
 
Thanks LAdy Alathia for a detailed answer.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 4 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Sharona Life is a Tale Told by an Idiot on November 2nd, 2009
 
 I think most of them have some information, but I don&apos;t know how easily accessible it is. 
 
Comments

 
Thanks Hari.

 Report 
 
by keithold is a prodigal bagger on November 2nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 Do you agree with doctors who claim Pres. Obama should STOP eating HOT DOGS? 
by Scorpio7 on May 10th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 What is your favorite foods and drinks from Carl&apos;s Jr? 
by XT on April 15th, 2012
 
 | 4 people like this
 
 Which fast foods is better? Burger King or Carl&apos;s JR? 
by XT on April 15th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Has anyone noticed fast food chicken like KFC have been selling chicken not big enough to be adult? 
by -O-uknow on April 29th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 have you noticed food at the grocery store is shrinking? 
by LT_Aldo_Rain on May 17th, 2012
 
 | 2 people like this
 More Fast food (General) See only professionally researched Fast food (General) questions 
 
You&apos;re reading Should fast food restaurants have to post information about how many calories are in their products?
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 With so many people claiming that they stay away from fast food restaurants, how do they still stay so crowded? 
 
 Do you think the&apos;healthy food&apos;items at fast food restaurants are really healthy? 
 
 After an experiment, what was found in fast food restaurants, that had more bacteria then water in a toilet? 
 
 Why don&apos;t restaurants and fast-food joints toss out the ends of tomatoes instead of putting them on our sandwiches? 
 
 Why is it that people that work in fast food restaurants are so cheap with the condiment packets? 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 How many calories are in the Ore-Ida Fast Food Fries, Extra Crispy? 
 
 Do fast food restaurants accept credit cards? 
 
 How do you eat low carb at fast food restaurants? 
 
 How many calories are in the Yours Truly Restaurants Ceasar Salad? 
 
 How many calories are in the Yours Truly Restaurants Egg Whites? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 Fast food places should post the nutrition facts on the wall next to the menu Minuses of posting nutritional information in fast food restaurants Why dont fast food places have nutrrition facts on there products Sex while skydiving Should fast food restaurant be required to provide nutrition info 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
