<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005917" url="http://wn.com/whataburger" time="2012-07-12-22:35" support="5" score="0.0173045985389748" bingtitle="Whataburger - World News" webtitle="Whataburger">
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Whataburger is known for its distinctive A-framed, orange-and-white striped roofed buildings (newer buildings are built similar to other fast-food chains, though the ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, 12 July 2012 upload Login Edit 
 go to the top About WN Contact Feedback Privacy Policy ©2012 World News Inc., all Rights Reserved 
 Whataburger Tweet sms this page email this page 
 Videos Images Wiki News Related Video Details Twitter Collage Shopping 
 
 Related News Top Headlines 

 whataburger 

 whataburger 

 Related Sites People Places Video Suggestions 

 WN Shopping Ebay Publications 
 
 

 Open Collage in a new Window Email the Collage 
 Loading... 
 Sorry your browser does not support IFRAME Loading suggestions ... 
 24 7 A&amp;W;Restaurants A-Frame house A1 Steak Sauce Alice, Texas Arby&apos;s Argo Tea Arizona Arthur Treacher&apos;s Asian cuisine Au Bon Pain Auntie Anne&apos;s Austin, Texas Back Yard Burgers Bahama Buck&apos;s Baja Fresh Baking Baskin-Robbins Beard Papa&apos;s Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s Bess Eaton Big Boy Restaurants Biggby Coffee Biscuit Blake&apos;s Lotaburger Blimpie Boloco Braum&apos;s Breakfast Brigham&apos;s Ice Cream Bruegger&apos;s Bruster&apos;s Ice Cream Burger Chef Burger King Burger Time Burgerville Cafe Rio California Tortilla Captain D&apos;s Caribou Coffee Carl&apos;s Jr. Carvel (restaurant) Checkers (fast food) Chick-fil-A Chicken (food) Chowking Chronic Tacos Cinnabon Coffee Beanery Cold Stone Creamery Cookie Corpus Christi Hooks Così (restaurant) Cousins Subs Culver&apos;s Dairy Queen Daphne&apos;s Greek Cafe David Foster Wallace Del Taco Dippin&apos; Dots Dog n Suds Drink Drive-through Druther&apos;s Dunkin&apos; Donuts Dunn Bros El Pollo Loco Erbert&amp;Gerbert&apos;s Fast food Fatburger Firehouse Subs Fish (food) Five Guys Florida Food Fort Worth, Texas Fosters Freeze Friendly&apos;s Frozen dessert Fuddruckers Gino&apos;s Hamburgers Golden Spoon Green Burrito H. Salt Esquire Hamburger Hardee&apos;s Hogi Yogi Honey Dew Donuts Hot &apos;n Now Hot dog Hot Dog on a Stick Houston Chronicle Hurricane Ike Häagen-Dazs In-N-Out Burger Infinite Jest Ivar&apos;s Jack in the Box Jack&apos;s Jamba Juice James Coney Island Jason&apos;s Deli Jersey Mike&apos;s Subs Jimmy John&apos;s Johnny Rockets Jollibee Kelly&apos;s Roast Beef Kingsville, Texas Krispy Kreme Krystal (restaurant) Lee&apos;s Sandwiches Lenny&apos;s Sub Shop Long John Silver&apos;s Maid-Rite Manchu Wok Marble Slab Creamery Max Brenner Max&apos;s of Manila McDonald&apos;s McDowell&apos;s McGarrah Jessee Menchie&apos;s Mexican cuisine Mighty Taco Milio&apos;s Sandwiches Mister Donut Mr. Hero Mrs. Fields Mustard (condiment) Nathan&apos;s Famous Naugles Newport News Circle Odessa, Texas Onion Orange Julius Original Tommy&apos;s Panda Express Panera Bread Peet&apos;s Coffee&amp;Tea Pensacola, Florida Pick Up Stix Pickled cucumber Pinkberry Pioneer Chicken Planet Smoothie Portal Companies Portal Food Portal Texas Pretzelmaker Qdoba Mexican Grill Quiznos Rax (restaurant) Red Mango Restaurant Richmond-Petersburg Rita&apos;s Italian Ice Robeks Runza (restaurant) San Antonio, Texas Sandwich Sandy&apos;s Sarku Japan Schlotzsky&apos;s Seafood Shake Shack Shipley Do-Nuts Smashburger Smoothie King Sneaky Pete&apos;s Sonic Drive-In Starbucks Steak &apos;n Shake Steak Escape Subway (restaurant) Swensons T.J. Cinnamons Taco Bell Taco Bueno Taco Cabana Taco del Mar Taco John&apos;s Taco Mayo Taco Palenque Taco Tico Taco Time Taquito Tastee-Freez TCBY Ted&apos;s Hot Dogs Tennessee Tex-Mex Texadelphia Texas Texas Coastal Bend Thaï Express Tim Hortons Togo&apos;s Tropical Sno Tubby&apos;s Tully&apos;s Coffee Wahoo&apos;s Fish Taco Watsonburger Wendy&apos;s Wetzel&apos;s Pretzels What-A-Burger Whataburger Whataburger Field Which Wich? Wienerschnitzel Winchell&apos;s Donuts Winstead&apos;s WWE WWE Raw WWE SmackDown Yogen Früz Yogurtland Yoshinoya Yum-Yum Donuts Zippy&apos;s 
 

 
 Alice, Texas 
Alice is a city in and the county seat of Jim Wells County, Texas, United States, in the South Texas region of the state. The population was 19,010 at the 2000 census. Later in 2009, the population was an estimated 19,682. Alice was established in 1888. First it was called Bandana , then Kleberg and finally Alice after Alice Gertrudis King Kleberg , the daughter of Richard King, who established the King Ranch.
 http://wn.com/Alice_Texas Austin, Texas 
Austin is the capital of the U.S. state of Texas and the seat of Travis County. Located in Central Texas on the eastern edge of the American Southwest, it is the fourth-largest city in Texas and the fifteenth most populous city in the United States. It was the third-fastest-growing large city in the nation from 2000 to 2006. Austin has a population of 786,382 (2009 U.S. Census estimate). The city is the cultural and economic center of the metropolitan area, with a population of 1,750,224 (2009 U.S. Census estimate), making it the 35th-largest metropolitan area in the United States.
 http://wn.com/Austin_Texas Florida 
Florida () is a state of the United States. It is located in the Southeastern United States, bordering Alabama to the northwest and Georgia to the north. Much of the state&apos;s land mass is a large peninsula with the Gulf of Mexico to the west, the Atlantic Ocean to the east and the Caribbean to the south. Florida was admitted as the 27th U.S. state in 1845, after a three hundred year period of European colonization.
 http://wn.com/Florida Fort Worth, Texas 
Fort Worth is the seventeenth-largest city in the United States of America and the fifth-largest city within the state of Texas. Located in and the western edge of the American South, the city is a cultural gateway into the American West and covers nearly in Tarrant, Parker, Denton, and Wise counties, serving as the seat for Tarrant County. According to the 2010 census estimates, Fort Worth had a population of 727,575. It has been estimated that by 2030 it will have 1,211,665 residents. The city is the second-largest cultural and economic center of the region.
 http://wn.com/Fort_Worth_Texas Kelly&apos;s Roast Beef 
&apos;&apos;&apos;Kelly&apos;s Roast Beef&apos;&apos;&apos; is a regional fast food restaurant chain located in Massachusetts. The chain was founded in 1951 in the city of Revere on Revere Beach by two partners, Frank V. McCarthy and Raymond Carey. Neither man wanted it named after him, so they decided to name it after a mutual friend, Thomas Kelly, a florist in Dorchester.
 http://wn.com/Kelly&apos;s_Roast_Beef Kingsville, Texas 
Kingsville is a city in and the county seat of Kleberg County, Texas, United States. The population was 25,575 at the 2000 census. It is the principal city of the Kingsville Micropolitan Statistical Area, which is part of the larger Corpus Christi-Kingsville Combined Statistical Area.
 http://wn.com/Kingsville_Texas Newport News Circle 
 http://wn.com/Newport_News_Circle Odessa, Texas 
Odessa is a city in and the county seat of Ector County, Texas, United States. It is located primarily in Ector County, although a small portion of the city extends into Midland County. Odessa&apos;s population was 96,943 at the 2000 census. As of 2009, the population of Odessa was 100,807. It is the principal city of the Odessa, Texas Metropolitan Statistical Area, which includes all of Ector County. The metropolitan area is also a component of the larger Midland–Odessa, Texas Combined Statistical Area, which had a population of 261,435 as of July 1, 2008. estimate.
 http://wn.com/Odessa_Texas Original Tommy&apos;s 
&apos;&apos;&apos;Original Tommy&apos;s&apos;&apos;&apos; is a hamburger restaurant chain in Southern California, United States. It is known for its chili-cheeseburgers.
 http://wn.com/Original_Tommy&apos;s Pensacola, Florida 
Pensacola is the westernmost city in the Florida Panhandle and the county seat of Escambia County, Florida, U.S. As of the 2000 census, the city had a total population of 56,255 and as of 2006, the estimated population was 53,248.
 http://wn.com/Pensacola_Florida San Antonio, Texas 
 http://wn.com/San_Antonio_Texas Tennessee 
Tennessee () is a U.S. state located in the Southeastern United States. It has a population of 6,214,888, making it the nation&apos;s 17th-largest state by population, and covers , making it the 36th-largest by total land area. Tennessee is bordered by Kentucky and Virginia to the north, North Carolina to the east, Georgia, Alabama, and Mississippi to the south, and Arkansas and Missouri to the west. The Appalachian Mountains dominate the eastern part of the state, and the Mississippi River forms the state&apos;s western border. Tennessee&apos;s capital and second largest city is Nashville, which has a population of 626,144. Memphis is the state&apos;s largest city, with a population of 670,902. Nashville has the state&apos;s largest metropolitan area, at 1,521,437 people.
 http://wn.com/Tennessee Texas 
Texas () is the second-largest U.S. state by both area and population, and the largest state in the contiguous United States.
 http://wn.com/Texas Texas Coastal Bend 
The Texas Coastal Bend refers to the flat area of land along the Texas coast. It is home to many cities including Brownsville, Corpus Christi, Kingsville, Port Lavaca, Galveston, Victoria, Beaumont, and Houston. The Coastal Bend includes the barrier islands of Texas and the Laguna Madre. According to the United States 2000 Census the Texas Coastal Bend had a population of 6,332,801.
 http://wn.com/Texas_Coastal_Bend 




 
 David Foster Wallace 
 http://wn.com/David_Foster_Wallace Sandwich 
A sandwich is a food item, often consisting of two or more slices of bread with one or more fillings between them, or one slice of bread with a topping or toppings, commonly called an open sandwich. Sandwiches are a widely popular type of lunch food, typically taken to work or school, or picnics to be eaten as part of a packed lunch. They generally contain a combination of salad vegetables, meat, cheese, and a variety of sauces. The bread can be used as it is, or it can be coated with any condiments to enhance flavor and texture. They are widely sold in restaurants and cafes.
 http://wn.com/Sandwich 




 
Make changes yourself !
 LOGIN to EDIT and SAVE this page. 
 Send this Playlist by SMS Email this Page 
 Whataburger Commercial 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:30 Published: 13 Oct 2006 Updated: 21 Jun 2012 
Author: styloroc2000 Whataburger Commercial http://wn.com/Whataburger_Commercial 
 The Whataburger Challenge - 8 Patties 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 4:12 Published: 11 Mar 2007 Updated: 12 May 2012 
Author: Redphoenix2k1 8 Patty Whataburger eaten in 15 minutes with a bonus Apple Pie. http://wn.com/The_Whataburger_Challenge_8_Patties 
 Hitler is Fired From Whataburger 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 3:50 Published: 15 Jul 2009 Updated: 18 Jun 2012 
Author: stranded170 Hitler finds out from his staff that after his third write-up, he has been fired from Whataburger. http://wn.com/Hitler_is_Fired_From_Whataburger 
 I Know I&apos;m Home (Whataburger Song) 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:39 Published: 27 Jul 2011 Updated: 19 Jun 2012 
Author: latimerthegreat A song we wrote during a road trip back from California after a 7 month absence from Whataburger. Written by Tyler Barabas, Laura Cheek and Ian Latimer. For more musical goodness from Tyler go to www.tylerbarabas.com (Transposed to G for guitar. For Uke play in C, same shapes) G Rollin&apos;through the desert in the hot sunshine FC Haven&apos;t been home since Christmas time G Only need one thing and it&apos;s hard to find FC Just 700 miles til the Texas line Well - G Stuck in a car for days on end FC Rollin&apos;up the mountains in the blowing wind G The tank is empty, Morale is low FC But when we get home there&apos;s one place to go F 11 to 11 might be breakfast time C But there&apos;s 24 hours to get in line GFC You Ain&apos;t - Never had a burger like a Whataburger GFC They Make - A Ketchup so fancy it&apos;ll please your hunger GFC I Can&apos;t - Wait until I order then I get my number FCG Cause now I know I&apos;m home G We moved out to the west coast FC Where there&apos;s No such thing as Texas toast G There&apos;s not much to write home about FC Except the soggy french fries from In and Out F (Get loud!!) Well I want a burger with some Jalapenos C Some crispy french fries not a wet potato GFC You Ain&apos;t - Never had a burger like a Whataburger GFC They Make - A Ketchup so fancy it&apos;ll please your hunger GFC I Can&apos;t - Wait until I order then I get my number FCG Cause now I know I&apos;m home CHICKEN BISCUIT BREAKDOWN G How you like your chicken biscuit? (honey butter chicken biscuit) F How you like your chicken biscuit? (honey&lt;b&gt;...&lt;/b&gt; http://wn.com/I_Know_I&apos;m_Home_Whataburger_Song 
 Mel Tillis Whataburger Commercials 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:04 Published: 08 Aug 2006 Updated: 20 Jun 2012 
Author: samred Mel Tillis Whataburger Commercials http://wn.com/Mel_Tillis_Whataburger_Commercials 
 Whataburger Fight 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 3:36 Published: 26 Apr 2010 Updated: 21 Jun 2012 
Author: xxsteven69xx This video was uploaded from an Android phone. http://wn.com/Whataburger_Fight 
 Gotta Get me some WhatABurger! 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 1:19 Published: 15 Jun 2010 Updated: 04 Jun 2012 
Author: giveitnowone Jay Leno with Josh Brolin taking about whataburger in Corpus Christi on the tonight show. http://wn.com/Gotta_Get_me_some_WhatABurger! 
 Whataburger Prank 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 6:06 Published: 03 Jun 2007 Updated: 05 May 2012 
Author: short334 well... That is not me doing this prank this is my boy JT....enjoy...lol http://wn.com/Whataburger_Prank 
 IcedOutEskimoz Whataburger 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 3:18 Published: 19 Dec 2005 Updated: 03 Jun 2012 
Author: mauskarn Everyone has their favortite fast food. If you&apos;ve ever been to Whataburger in Houston you&apos;ll appreciate this. White-boy rap at its finest. http://wn.com/IcedOutEskimoz_Whataburger 
 WHATABURGER SERVICE 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:32 Published: 13 Oct 2011 Updated: 14 Jun 2012 
Author: fpomarketing http://wn.com/WHATABURGER_SERVICE 
 Can You Eat Healthy At Whataburger - Whataburger Food Review 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 8:02 Published: 22 Mar 2012 Updated: 20 Jun 2012 
Author: BryanMarcelLifestyle Whataburger Food Review - Can you eat healthy at Whataburger. Whataburger food is the same low quality food that most fast food restaurants use. Whataburger does use some questionable ingredients in its food: partially hydrogenated oil or trans fat is in the chicken strips. Azodicarbonamide - a known carcinogen is in the bread, both white and whole grain wheat. The wheat bread also uses ethoxylated mono and diglycerides which allows Whataburger to skip adding shortening in the bread making process. Whataburger coats it&apos;s tomatoes with vegetable wax, beeswax, petroleum and/or shellack. Petroleum and shellack are odd ingredients for food. Even for fast food. www.bryanmarcel.com http://wn.com/Can_You_Eat_Healthy_At_Whataburger_Whataburger_Food_Review 
 Claude Stuart - Whataburger - Ft Worth TX Hyena&apos;s 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 0:26 Published: 28 Feb 2008 Updated: 22 Aug 2011 
Author: PIXXXL Claude Stuart - Whataburger - Ft Worth TX Hyena&apos;s Feb 22 2008 http://wn.com/Claude_Stuart_Whataburger_Ft_Worth_TX_Hyena&apos;s 
 Cheeseburger Josh at Whataburger in Texas 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 3:33 Published: 29 Mar 2010 Updated: 22 Jun 2012 
Author: ropersonline The&quot;Cheeseburger Josh&quot;Whataburger fight video -- reposted with the annoying commentary removed. The retarded watermark is still all over it though. If anyone knows a good version without that watermark, it&apos;d be cool if you could tell me the link. I tried removing the watermark with avidemux2_gtk, but it crashed on me. http://wn.com/Cheeseburger_Josh_at_Whataburger_in_Texas 
 Whataburger RAP 
 Order: Reorder Duration: 2:47 Published: 21 Mar 2010 Updated: 19 Apr 2012 
Author: FALAFELKING4sho We went to order some food. Legitly. Sittin&apos;at the drive thru of Whataburger If i were a German I&apos;d say&quot;Ich habe Hunger&quot;Got a few dollars, some dimes, and some quarters So get yo buttons ready cuz here comes my order I need one NUMBA 2 with american cheese Hold the lettuce, pickles, and tomatoes please No mayo, no mustard, or fancy ketchup Only barbecue sauce. AND DON&apos;T LET UP. I got a drink in mind so do not fear Its my one true love and thats ROOT BEER For my buddy over here he&apos;d like a numba 4 Wait a sec thats chicken, you&apos;re a dirty WHORE We come to Whataburger to get our beef on If ya want some poultry then go to Chikfila son! One more thing i&apos;d like a dessert Cinnamon Rolls, six couldn&apos;t hurt Gimme a crap load of napkins to go with that Put it all in one big Whataburger sack Man thats a lotta food God i&apos;m fat All this foods gonna make my butt sag http://wn.com/Whataburger_RAP
	</body>
</document>
