<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005588" url="http://mikeysburgersandfries.net/index.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:08" support="3" score="0.008033881350430346" bingtitle="Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries" webtitle="Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries">
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001187" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>If you’re still not happy, we’ll refund your money. So tell your friends. ... About Mikey’s Burgers And Fries - Learn more about our fast food restaurant; You can order ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Burgers And Fries Menu About Mikey’s Burgers And Fries Contact 
 Home Burgers And Fries Menu About Mikey’s Burgers And Fries Contact 
 
 
 
Howell, MI Fast Food

Also serving Brighton, MI

Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries
 
 Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries of Howell, MI is your home for top-quality, low-priced, classic American fast food. If you love fresh, Angus steak burgers, hand-dipped milkshakes, and fresh-cut French fries, then our burgers and fries menu is for you!

We make your burger your way, and, if you’re not happy, we’ll remake it. If you’re still not happy, we’ll refund your money.

So tell your friends. When they want fast food, Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries is the“can’t lose”choice.

 Learn More About Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries: 

 Burgers And Fries Menu - Fresh Angus beef burgers, 7”hot dogs, Coney dogs, fresh-cut French fries, poutine, hand-dipped milkshakes, root-beer floats, Boston Coolers About Mikey’s Burgers And Fries - Learn more about our fast food restaurant 

You can order ahead or request delivery.

 Contact Mikey&apos;s Burgers and Fries today at 517-376-6265 to request delivery of the area’s best fast food. You can also come and order in person.

We’re located at 4245 E. Grand River Ave., Howell, MI 48843 inside the Sunoco Gas Station.

Browse the website for more information about our products and services.
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home  |  Burgers And Fries Menu  |  About Mikey’s Burgers And Fries  |  Contact 
©2011 Yellow Book USA, Inc. All Rights Reserved | Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
