<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005975" url="http://www.hypnosiscenter.com/omni-guarantee.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:39" support="1" score="0.0006562333899068143" bingtitle="HypnosisCenter.com | Omni Hypnosis Product Guarantee" webtitle="HypnosisCenter.com | Omni Hypnosis Product Guarantee">
			<query id="000552" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... will be made ONLY upon receipt by us ... How to Order; Customer Service; About Us ... Park, just off Red Hill near 5 &amp; 55. We will FAX you a map upon request, or happily give you ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | About Us | Privacy Policy | Shipping and Returns | Conditions Of Use 

Hypnosis Training: Learn Hypnosis and Hypnotherapy Certification
- Basic and Advanced
 
 Omni Hypnosis Center Video Training Return and Exchange Policy

Please read carefully before placing your order!

 Mechanically defective video/audio tapes may be exchanged for the SAME TITLE ONLY WITHIN 60 DAYS OF PURCHASE. Video, audio tapes or books may NOT be returned for reasons based on content. Books will be exchanged only if damaged in shipping and only for the same title. Exchanges will be made ONLY upon receipt by us of the defective merchandise. We can not be responsible for return shipping cost.
 
 Home Page Hypnosis Training » 
 Hypnotherapy Certification Advanced Hypnotherapy Learn Hypnosis Online Distance Learning State Registered Schools Student Feedback&amp;Photos Selecting a Hypnosis School Sponsor a Course 
 Hypnosis Sessions 7 th Path Self-Hypnosis® Books, CDs&amp;DVDs » 
 Hypnosis Training CDs Self-Hypnosis CDs Hypnosis Session CDs Weekly Online Supervision CDs Hypnosis Books Hypnosis Training Videos Free Product Samples Graduates-Only How to Order Customer Service 
 About Us » 
 Our Hypnotherapists Our Staff Virtual Tour 
 Free Hypnosis Resources Hypnosis FAQs Help » 
 Ordering Help 
 Contact Us 
 
 Course Schedule 

 Hypnosis Certification 

 July 9 - 20, 2012 October 29 - November 9, 2012 
 Early Registration Discount: Save $600! 

 Week of Power–Advanced Hypnosis Training Course 

Pre and Post Workshop at the 2012 NGH Annual Convention in Marlborough, Massachusetts.

 August 5 - 9, Sunday thru Thursday and August 13 - 14, Monday thru Tuesday 
 Free Live Chat Software 
Mon-Fri: 9AM-6PM PST
 
 Become a VIP member : 

 Early notification of new articles, scripts, and other free items. Save money on classes through early enrollment programs. Get our informative newsletter. More benefits! 
 
Name:
 

Email:
 

 
 
 Vets and Active Duty Get Additional 20% Off Discount On Courses
 
 Click for Details 
 Elronn Ferguson Tustin, CA Susan Just Minneapolis, MN Trainer Linda Damara Singapore Celeste Hackett Dallas, TX Trainer Darwin Gillett Boston, MA Jill Arnold White Rock, BC Peggy Kelly Toronto, Canada Trainer Alexandra Bley Palo Alto, CA Fran Palumbo Fairfield, CT Steve Roh Philadelphia, PA Jolene Wright Vancouver, WA Nancy Philpot Austin, TX Meredith Locher Los Angeles, CA Cynthia Thurman Raleigh, NC Annika Lundqvist Stockholm, SE Fauziah Shah Singapore Trainer Ron Bishop Henderson, NV Laney Coulter Portland, OR Pete Tan Singapore Trainer Paul Dixon Auckland, New Zealand Trainer Jacqueline Fairney Newport Beach, CA Mercedes Carrady San Juan, Puerto Rico Terence Ford Los Angeles, CA Jean Conway Greenfield, MA Rachael Hudson London, United Kingdom 
 
 

 

 
 
Contact Information

Banyan Hypnosis Center For Training&amp;Services is located at 1431 Warner Ave. Suite E, Tustin, CA 92780 in the Warner Corporate Park, just off Red Hill near 5&amp;55. We will FAX you a map upon request, or happily give you directions on the telephone/cell phone.

 
 Telephone: 

714-258-8380

800-965-3390
 
 Fax: 

714-258-8374
 
 Mailing Address: 

1431 Warner Ave Suite E
 Tustin, CA 92780
 
 E-mail: 

 Contact Us 
 
 Back To Top
	</body>
</document>
