<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005553" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/waffle-house-crappy-service-racism-improperly-cooked-eggs-a-bad-meal-and-a-ba/" time="2012-07-12-22:06" support="6" score="0.01014459252300419" bingtitle="Waffle House, crappy service, racism, improperly cooked eggs, a ..." webtitle="Waffle House, crappy service, racism, improperly cooked eggs, a bad meal and a bad experience! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>... had to flag down a waitress to tell her that I would like to place an order ... the waitress came over with my food put ... Here are some super hot fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Turtle Wax Ice review - it goes on easy, but offers little protection for your car&apos;s paint if any from the sun! Sister Wives Complaint - TLC Reality Television Show That Should Be Taken Off The Air! Burger King in Lafayette Louisiana review - sucky service and staff! Auto Zone auto parts store review - its understaffed and has very, very long waits! Facebook Review – A Social Networking Site Created As a Harvard University Project is Taking a Turn For The Worse Rooms to Go, Furniture That is Delivered With a Used Look!! 3M headlight lens restoration system review - this headlight cleaner ruined my headlight lenses! Discovery Kids Animated Aquarium Complaint - These Products Create More Problems Than Excitement For Children Cricket Wireless - a review - great plans, outdated cell phones, bad customer service and weird harrassing phone calls! Belkin Wireless G Router with 4-Port Switch Complaint - Horrible Router Products With Absolutely Terrible Foreign Tech Support! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Waffle House, crappy service, racism, improperly cooked eggs, a bad meal and a bad experience!
 By countryboy1 
I had the worst customer service I have ever had at my nearby Waffle House!
 



I was hungry for lunch and I remembered there was a waffle house down the street and the thought of some hot pancakes and eggs was really quite enticing. So I went to the Waffle House. Inside it was fairly packed but there was an open table and I sat at it. It was a good 10 minutes before anyone even noticed that I was sitting there and they just kept walking right on by.

I finally had to flag down a waitress to tell her that I would like to place an order and needed to see a menu. She gave me a stern look and said can’t you see we’re busy? She then snapped back saying I’ll get to you when I’m good and ready. Read there that should have been an indication to me that this was not going to be a good eating experience. But the way I looked at it was I was a paying customer, I was not being mean, there was an open seat and this was a restaurant and I wanted to eat.

But apparently this waitress that was rude to begin with was in charge of my section. Finally she came by and tossed a menu my way without saying a word and left. She did not come back to take my order. So I finally got up and went to the cooks counter and proceeded to tell the cook what I wanted to order and that apparently I wasn’t going to be served over there. They took down what it was I wanted to eat which was rather simple; three hotcakes, eggs sunny side up and bacon or sausage if they didn’t have any bacon.

The cook told me the waitress would bring it over to me. A few minutes later the waitress came over with my food put it down in front of me, gave me a real stern look and then left. She never offered to get me anything to drink and that was that.  So I looked at the plate but she put in front of me and the pancakes looked okay, but the eggs were definitely not done sunny side up.  They weren’t even cooked all the way to where they would be safe enough to eat.  The eggs were very runny and look like they had just come out of the shell.

 Never pay for a movie again! Download the latest and hottest movies free and safely! Click here to find out how! 

I couldn’t eat the eggs like that and I certainly couldn’t eat the pancakes that the runny eggs had leaked all over.  I was not going to risk salmonella poisoning over this.  So apparently now the waitress was very mad with me and the cook was on her side and I could see by looking up at the two of them were talking and looking at me.  The waitress was actually pointing at me and then talking to the cook whom then gave me a dirty look also.  At this I just got up and quietly left the restaurant without paying because I’m not that I pay for that crap.

Now there’s something else you should probably know here.  This Waffle House was on the poorer side of town and I was the only white person in the establishment.  I am 100% positive that this was the reason that I was treated so rudely uncooked eggs.  You see, I see this as being 2010, the Europe a black man has become president of the United States in that racism is seen as a thing from years past.  I view all people of different races as the same.  And I treat all them exactly the same.  I treat everyone as I would have them treat me.

But I guess racism, in whatever capacities, still exists today.  My Waffle House experience was classic reverse racism.  Now if I was a black man and it was all whites in the restaurant and I had been treated half that bad, the whole media would be in an uproar, Al Sharpton would probably be marching the streets along with the Black Panthers at how atrocious this incident was and how it ripped at the hearts of black America.


 Your Ad Here 


Regardless of the color my skin, whether I am white, black, red, yellow or even green, I was a polite, paying customer that just wanted to order a very simple order of pancakes and eggs.  I was planning on leaving a nice tip for the waitress and having a nice, relaxing meal.  Instead I get singled out because I’m a white person entering or encroaching upon the black establishment.  Where is Al Sharpton now to further the fight for my cause and my rights as an American?

I clearly had my rights violated, unlike Crystal Mangum whom completely lied and even through the lies it was amazing to see how fast Al Sharpton came to her aid.  He called for and wanted immediate justice and wanted the Duke lacrosse players found guilty without due process.  He and other civil rights activists tried to great such a big stink that most people in the shoes of the Duke Lacrosse players would have just given up and pled guilty even though they weren’t.

 Learn how to download the latest movies, music, software, games and more 100% free and safe with the best in VPNs! 

I have to applaud the Duke lacrosse players for standing their ground.  If I came from a rich background I would probably make a lawsuit out of this with Waffle House, but I didn’t and there are no civil rights leaders around to take up my cause because I’m a white man in a black man’s world.  But, I did find a way to get back at that Waffle House.  I called the health department and reported the restaurant for the undercooked eggs they served me and I told them why in the hope that they would send in undercover white health department agent out to order and receive the same treatment and then hit them with a huge fine.

I don’t know if that aspect of it worked or not, but something did because I read in the local government newspaper that that exact waffle house was hit with numerous health code violations and fined big time.  This showed up in the paper about four weeks later.  That made me so happy.  But out of this experience I will never ever eat at a Waffle House ever again.  Besides, IHOP has much better pancakes and I am treated just like everyone else there.  I will go to IHOP from now on for pancakes and eggs.



 
Posts Related to Waffle House, crappy service, racism, improperly cooked eggs, a bad meal and a bad experience!

 
 Hot fast food restaurant complaints here on ReportYourComplaint! 

Here are some super hot fast food restaurant complaints from our readers and contributors here on ReportYourComplaint.com! // Here are some of the latest and ...
 
 TGIFriday’s–Horrible customer service and experience!! 

// I went to dinner the other night at TGI Fridays with my husband.  When we had gotten there early before dinner time so we ...
 
 Presto Electric Griddle–Amazing, Easy, and Inexpensive Method of Cooking! 

// Last week was my birthday and I had asked for a Presto griddle because I love to cook for my family.  I have seen ...
 
 Wal-mart, racism and rude employees at the deli counter! 

// I went to Wal-Mart with my kids to get some groceries recently. All was fine until I got to the deli counter to order ...
 
 Racism at Taco Bell–free food if you are black and rude customer service if you are not black! 

// Apparently the employees and management staff at my local Taco Bell and decided server back to a reverse version of the 1950&apos;s and 60&apos;s. ...
 
 
 Tags: bad customer service , chain restaurants , complaint , Customer service , disgusting , fast food , food , franchise , Horrible , horrible customer service , horrible service , Not recommended , racism , restaurant , reverse racism , review , rude , sucks , Terrible , undercooked food , unfair business practices , unhealthy , untrustworthy , Waffle House 
 
13 Responses to Waffle House, crappy service, racism, improperly cooked eggs, a bad meal and a bad experience! 
 Newer Comments→ 
 Pete T. on July 12, 2010 at 1:41 AM 

The Waffle House sucks. I go to iHop instead. Their pancakes and coffee are awesome and so is their service.

Like or Dislike: 2   1 
 Michelle C. on August 9, 2010 at 10:39 PM 

Waffle House sucks. I stopped going there a very long time ago.

Like or Dislike: 2   1 
 Susie on August 21, 2010 at 11:48 AM 

Had a similar experience at Waffle House, but our I Hop is the same way so we’re stuck.
Call Waffle House 1-800 number to complain. It works.

Like or Dislike: 1   1 
 كازينو on September 4, 2010 at 11:12 AM 

We don’t have the Waffle House here in Iraq. Do you know how we could get one? I wouldn’t mind having some waffles for breakfast nearby.

Like or Dislike: 2   0 
 Oh Really? on October 21, 2010 at 11:34 PM 

You know what you need to shut your white dumb racist ass up. I’m so sick&amp;tired of white people.
 
Hot debate. What do you think? 1   10 
 Idiot on February 22, 2011 at 6:31 PM 

Waffle House does not serve pancakes. Hence the name.

Like or Dislike: 3   1 
 Allen on March 3, 2011 at 8:36 AM 

Now I have to say, any“Runny Egg”is not safe and can carry salmonella! All eggs must be cooked well done to be 100% safe.

Also, I have never been mistreated at a waffle house, no matter what side of town was on.

Plus, whenever I walk into a busy waffle house, or any restaurant for that matter, I stand for a few minutes and ensure that I’m noticed by a waitress who politely tells me to sit wherever, and then i’m promptly served.

Like or Dislike: 0   2 
 rachel on May 29, 2011 at 11:51 PM 

Sunny side up eggs are never flipped so one side is uncooked. That is what makes that side“sunny.”Clearly you wanted your eggs over in some way. In waffle house lingo: over light-flipped but still very funny, over medium-hard white runny yolk, over well-all hard. One thing that is important to notice about a busy waffle house is the lack of such things as hostesses, computers, bussers, and dishwashers. waffle house servers have a lot more on their plates than most other servers. did it cross your mind that the waitress really was busy and you made yourself look like an ass by being so impatient and getting up and going to the cook to put yourself ahead of other customers?

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 donna on July 3, 2011 at 6:13 PM 

My husband,sister and I went to a local waffle house a few days ago, while there my husband was jumped by 4 black guys. I did step in because no one else in this waffle house was doing anything to stop it because of this I was punched 4 times in the arm by one of these men. After this altercation and ME calling the cops from my cell phone these men were allowed to get in their car and drive away before the cops came. Once the cops arrived everyone there except one waitress tried to blame it on us saying it was a racist thing. It was a racist thing but not on our part. Thank goodness the cops saw this and they were very understanding in the whole situation. One thing that bothers me is that the whole staff at waffle house allowed this to occur and they never called the cops they never asked the other guys to leave they just stood their and watched as the racial remarks were made toward my husband and me and while the threats were made. I can honestly say ill never return to this waffle house

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 charlene on December 8, 2011 at 10:28 AM 

Wow!
I’m not a bit surprised that this complaint is directed twords the waffle house. Everytime i have wanted to reminisce on the fluffy, delightful flavor of waffle house waffles’when i was a child it came crashing down with a disgusting stomach ache or poorly served salad. I’m not going back to the waffle house or will i ever be contributing to that slum of a diner ever again. Its dirty, cold when its suppose to be warm and hot when it should be cool. Ive had wonderful memories in this establishment from when my grams took me after church but not its filled with salmonella and in need of a Tetnis shot. If there are some descent ones left then I’m super jealous! They use to be worth a dam.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 Newer Comments→ 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
