<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005089" url="http://firexkiraxcosplay.deviantart.com/" time="2012-07-12-21:36" support="1" score="0.0026319042976744645" bingtitle="FireXkiraxcosplay on deviantART" webtitle="FireXkiraxcosplay on deviantART">
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>To hold me and tell me you love me. I have you, To love me for me, and ... [] Stolen a tray from a fast food restaurant. [] I open up to others easily.</description>
	<body>
		deviantART 
 Browse Art Prints Shop T-Shirts&amp;Gear Groups Deviants 
 Sta.sh dA muro Chat Journals Today Forum Find More Art 
 Daily Deviations Discover beta Critiques Critiqueable Wallpaper Random 
 Random Deviant Random Deviation Random Group 
 
 Search Username or Email 

 Password 
 Stay logged in 
 Login 
 Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour Lost Password? Deviant Login Buy Art Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear Buy adCast Buy Premium Upgrade Shop   Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour 
 
~ FireXkiraxcosplay 
PUT. THE BUNNY. BACK. View Badges! + Watch Send a Note Give 
 Profile Gallery Prints Favourites Journal 
 About Me Literature / Student Member Aidan Christopher Male/United States Groups #Child-AbuseAwareness 
   Recent Activity Deviant for 2 Years Needs Premium Membership Statistics 390 Deviations 3,531 Comments 8,389 Pageviews 390 Deviations
 3,531 Comments
 8,389 Pageviews
 4 Scraps
 74 Watchers
 0 Critiques
 1 Forum Post
 2,017 Favourites More Stats This deviant&apos;s full pageview
graph is unavailable. Member Aidan Christopher Male/United States Birthday May 29 # Child-AbuseAwareness 
   # 2RiteLuvOnHrArms 
   Last Visit: 2 days ago PUT. THE BUNNY. BACK. Art Zone Personal Zone Misc. Zone 
 This is the place where you can personalize your profile!
But, how? 
 By moving, adding and personalizing widgets. You can drag and drop to rearrange. You can edit widgets to customize them. The bottom has widgets you can add! Some widgets you can only access when you get a premium membership. Some widgets have options that are only available when you get a premium membership. 
 

 We&apos;ve split the page into zones! 
 Certain widgets can only be added to certain zones. &quot;Why,&quot; you ask? Because we want profile pages to have freedom of customization, but also to have some consistency. This way, when anyone visits a deviant, they know they can always find the art in the top left, and personal info in the top right. Don&apos;t forget, restraints can bring out the creativity in you! 
 

 Now go forth and astound us all with your devious profiles! 
 OK 
 
 
 Join Now  
 Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear  
 Advertise Here 
 [x] 
 Newest Deviations
 Because Because you&apos;ve made me forget the way I was touched
The way I was hit
The things I was called
The people who lied
And how much it hurt.

Because of the way you make me feel loved
How you remind me that I&apos;m wonderful
Or cute
Or handsome.

Because of the way you never forget things
Like our anniversary
When I have things going on
Things about my friends
And my secrets.

Because of the way you understand
That sometimes, I just can&apos;t be touched because I&apos;m anxious
Or that I don&apos;t want to be alone when I&apos;m upset
Or that I want to be left alone when I&apos;m angry
Or that I just really need to rant.

So for all of this, I just want to say Because by ~ FireXkiraxcosplay 3 Comments Real boy I&apos;m a real boy.
I hold doors.
I lead when I dance.
I let ladies go first.

I&apos;m a real boy.
I like to rough house sometimes.
I like building things.
I like looking at cars.

I&apos;m a real boy.
I&apos;m strong.
I&apos;m polite.
I&apos;m protective.

I&apos;m real boy.
I&apos;m just missing some parts.
I have a couple extra.
But I&apos;m still a real boy. Real boy by ~ FireXkiraxcosplay 11 Comments Reasons Perhaps there&apos;s a reason for everything
An answer to every ting,
A time for a bing,
And a feeling to spread your wings.
Maybe there&apos;s no rhyme or reason
No explination when things are ceasing
And moods are changing with the season
But troubles aren&apos;t easing
I tend to like the way it feels
Like my heart is holding electric eels
And I&apos;m no longer sure what&apos;s real
But maybe I don&apos;t mind at the end of the deal.
Maybe time is a deadline to reform
Not sure what had happened before
But knowing it&apos;s no longer the form
You can choose who you hate
And you can choose who you date
You don&apos;t decide your fate
But only which key gets the Reasons by ~ FireXkiraxcosplay 2 Comments Canada by ~ FireXkiraxcosplay 2 Comments Browse Gallery 
 Real boy
 
 Real boy 

 

 Apr 28, 2012, 1:06:40 PM by ~ FireXkiraxcosplay Literature / Poetry / Emotional / Urban&amp;Spoken Word 
 I&apos;m a real boy.
I hold doors.
I lead when I dance.
I let ladies go first.

I&apos;m a real boy.
I like to rough house sometimes.
I like building things.
I like looking at cars.

I&apos;m a real boy.
I&apos;m strong.
I&apos;m polite.
I&apos;m protective.

I&apos;m real boy.
I&apos;m just missing some parts.
I have a couple extra.
But I&apos;m still a real boy. 11 Comments Real boy April 28 11 comments 8 favourites 
 Watchers
 
~ VikingRawr 
~ xpanicattheps3x 
~ LoseSomebody 
* BushieBrows 
~ miyukimitarashi 
~ babyabcynth 
~ Misuto-Amestris 
~ ribbonBBY 
* KateMochi 
~ darkmind98 
~ TheExperimentZero 
~ TimeForCookies 
~ AskTheSeaDwellers 
~ NoxCosplayPhotos 
* dustinbunnell 
~ Genius74 
~ KadentheFallen 
* maxf234 
~ whitefire22 
~ EchoInTime129 All Watchers 
 Friends
 
~ VikingRawr 
* BushieBrows 
~ zemeah 
~ Misuto-Amestris 
* KateMochi 
~ darkmind98 
~ TheExperimentZero 
~ AskTheSeaDwellers 
~ ShadowofaThought21 
* maxf234 
~ whitefire22 
~ EchoInTime129 
~ pokepark2 
~ CrimsomLight 
~ PrivateGenocide 
~ AlaskaSan 
* Arkham-Insanity 
~ WolfPrincessInLove 
~ KimikoTakeshita 
~ grellofthecentury All Friends 
 Donate
 ~ FireXkiraxcosplay has started a donation pool! 45 / 675 
 Name what you want, give me an offer, and I&apos;ll try and make it work. 
 Donate! 
 You must be logged in to donate. 
 ~ pokepark2 
 Donated Sep 14, 2011, 3:24:00 PM 
 10 ~ pokepark2 
 Donated Sep 13, 2011, 3:03:01 PM 
 10 ! mello-butterfly98 
 Donated Jun 9, 2011, 2:49:24 PM 
 5 ~ oliv07112 
 Donated Jun 3, 2011, 6:47:20 PM 
 20 
 
 deviantID
 ~ FireXkiraxcosplay Aidan Christopher 
Artist | Student | Literature United States That&apos;s me on the right. I&apos;m with Sky from Foxy Shazam and my best friend is on the left.
My name is Aidan or AC , and I don&apos;t have a real age. I&apos;m a thousand souls old. I enjoy writing poetry and taking photographs. I also enjoy drawing and playing music, listening to it as well. I play double bass as my major and key board, viola and cello as my minors. I am a PK (Priest&apos;s kid), my mother is becoming a priest.
I live with my mom and my big brother and I hope to become a photographer or director. I enjoy watching anime when I&apos;m not writing and also spending time with the people I love. Like , my cousin and best friend.
AC

Homophobia means:
* I am the girl kicked out of her home because I confided in my mother that I am a lesbian.
* I am the prostitute working the streets because nobody will hire a transsexual woman.
* I am the sister who holds her gay brother tight through the painful, tear-filled nights.
* We are the parents who buried our daughter long before her time.
* I am the man who died alone in the hospital because they would not let my partner of twenty-seven years into the room.
* I am the foster child who wakes up with nightmares of being taken away from the two fathers who are the only loving family I have ever had. I wish they could adopt me.
* I am one of the lucky ones, I guess. I survived the attack that left me in a coma for three weeks, and in another year I will probably be able to walk again.
* I am not one of the lucky ones. I killed myself just weeks before graduating high school. It was simply too much to bear.
* We are the couple who had the Realtor hang up on us when she found out we wanted to rent a one-bedroom for two men.
* I am the person who never knows which bathroom I should use if I want to avoid getting the management called on me.
* I am the mother who is not allowed to even visit the children I bore, nursed, and raised. The court says I am an unfit mother because I now live with another woman.
* I am the domestic-violence survivor who found the support system grow suddenly cold and distant when they found out my abusive partner is also a woman.
* I am the domestic-violence survivor who has no support system to turn to because I am male.
* I am the father who has never hugged his son because I grew up afraid to show affection to other men.
* I am the home-economics teacher who always wanted to teach gym until someone told me that only lesbians do that.
* I am the man who died when the paramedics stopped treating me as soon as they realized I was transgendered.
* I am the person who feels guilty because I think I could be a much better person if I did not have to always deal with society hating me.
* I am the man who stopped attending church, not because I don&apos;t believe, but because they closed their doors to my kind.
* I am the person who has to hide what this world needs most, love.
* I am the person who is afraid of telling his loving Christian parents he loves another male.

Re-post this if you believe homophobia is wrong. Please do your part to end it. Now really, go! Truly I tell you, an institution that protects and supports hatred on any level can never be one of love.

Bisexuals...
...aren&apos;t confused
...aren&apos;t greedy
...needn&apos;t be 50:50
...aren&apos;t gender binary
...are Queer
...need a community
...can be faithful
...can have 1 partner
...don&apos;t always alternate
...don&apos;t have it easier
...aren&apos;t a phase
...aren&apos;t bi-sexuals
...might be &apos;barsexuals&apos;
...aren&apos;t spreading HIV
...might be your partners
...aren&apos;t everyone
...are real

&quot;Bisexuality? Oh, it&apos;s just a phase!&quot;
&quot;No - that&apos;s just a phrase!&quot;

Love is perfect whoever it&apos;s between.
♂+♂=♥
♀+♀=♥
♀+♂=♥

Wife: 
Wife: 
Son: 
Daughter-in-law: 
Daughter: 
Mother: 
Sister: 

Current Residence: Michigan
Favourite genre of music: techno/rock/metal/j-pop/j-rock/goth/emo/
Favourite style of art: Hrum...&gt;.&gt;
Operating System: you....pervert...? Vista
MP3 player of choice: iPod
Skin of choice: smooth 
Favourite cartoon character: Too many to list!
Personal Quote: Family is love, not blood Interests Favorite movies Rent Favorite bands / musical artists Broken Toy Airplanes, NeverShoutNever!, Blue October, Kimya Dawson, ect Favorite games Sims 2 or Left 4 Dead Other Interests Anime, Music, Poetry, Yaoi and Cosplay 
 Come chat with Crystal and I~? 

 

 May 12, 2012, 10:48:37 AM by ~ FireXkiraxcosplay Journals / Personal 
 [link] No Comments Come chat with Crystal and I~? May 12 No Comments No Favourites More Journal Entries 
 AdCast - Ads from the Community
 [x] 
 Webcam
 
 Groups
 
 Admin of 2 Groups Member of 28 Groups 
 
# 2RiteLuvOnHrArms 
# Child-AbuseAwareness 
# Asian-Stamps 
# StriderEgbert 
# Broken-Hearted-Poets 
# AllTheUglyDeviants All Groups 
 Comments
 
 Add a Comment:   Preview   Add Comment Emoticons Load All Images ~ xpanicattheps3x Jun 7, 2012   Hobbyist General Artist you like foxy shazam and homestuck omg c: you&apos;re perfect ok

--
~I know the world&apos;s a broken bone, but melt your headaches, call it home..
--
(ﾉ◕ヮ◕)ﾉ*:･ﾟ✧&quot;I&apos;m a princess ok someone fetch me my crown&quot;
--
you ninnymiffin.
--
idk man I just like bands, homestuck, video games, and batman \(・ω・)/ Reply ~ FireXkiraxcosplay Jun 7, 2012   Student Writer Nonono...Shhh.
That&apos;s you.

--
 
I&apos;m an ectobiologist. ;D Reply ~ xpanicattheps3x Jun 7, 2012   Hobbyist General Artist screams no yOU

--
~I know the world&apos;s a broken bone, but melt your headaches, call it home..
--
(ﾉ◕ヮ◕)ﾉ*:･ﾟ✧&quot;I&apos;m a princess ok someone fetch me my crown&quot;
--
you ninnymiffin.
--
idk man I just like bands, homestuck, video games, and batman \(・ω・)/ Reply ~ FireXkiraxcosplay Jun 8, 2012   Student Writer SHHHH
just let me love you.

--
 
I&apos;m an ectobiologist. ;D Reply (1 Reply) ~ Megasourusrex May 29, 2012   Student Digital Artist I didn&apos;t get so say this at school cuz i was a big sick depressing person today
but...
HAPPY BIRTHDAY AIDAN!!!!!!!!!!!!

--
I love sweet delicious strawberry toaster treats

[✔] Romance Roleplayer
[✔] Action Roleplayer
[✔] fantasy Roleplayer Reply ~ LoseSomebody May 12, 2012 Aidan!.... Hey- hey AIDAN!!!!....... Hai :3

--
&quot;Don&apos;t make me bite you. Oh wait, I can&apos;t. You&apos;ll turn into a werewolf.&quot;
&quot;There&apos;s no such thing as werewolves.&quot;
&quot;Says you.&quot;
O.O Reply ~ FireXkiraxcosplay May 13, 2012   Student Writer Hi! I probably know you but I don&apos;t recall your name! c:

--
 
I&apos;m an ectobiologist. ;D Reply ~ LoseSomebody May 14, 2012 Aww you love me, you let me invade your house from time to time, we have bitch sessions.... 

--
&quot;Don&apos;t make me bite you. Oh wait, I can&apos;t. You&apos;ll turn into a werewolf.&quot;
&quot;There&apos;s no such thing as werewolves.&quot;
&quot;Says you.&quot;
O.O Reply ~ FireXkiraxcosplay May 14, 2012   Student Writer OHOHOH! HIIIII HANNAH

--
 
I&apos;m an ectobiologist. ;D Reply (1 Reply) ~ darkmind98 May 12, 2012   Student Writer Hehehe! You&apos;re gonna loooooooove the video!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

--
I just want you to be happy, even if it&apos;s not with me...

The scary stuff makes me happy... the happy stuff gets me bored.


I love a good love story, even if it&apos;s not mine. Reply 
 Previous 1 2 3 ... Next 
 Go To Page: Go Add a Comment:   Preview   Add Comment Emoticons ©2012 deviantART. All rights reserved About Us | Contact Us | Developers | Careers | Site Tour | Help&amp;FAQ Advertise | Premium Membership Etiquette | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
