<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005420" url="http://www.ktsm.com/news/three-arrested-after-fight-at-northeast-fast-food-restaurant" time="2012-07-12-21:58" support="1" score="0.0021207199712365617" bingtitle="Three Arrested After Fight at Northeast Fast Food Restaurant ..." webtitle="Three Arrested After Fight at Northeast Fast Food Restaurant  | KTSM News Channel 9">
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Three Arrested After Fight at Northeast Fast Food Restaurant ... picking on my son last yr after he had returned back to school from a horrible car ...</description>
	<body>
		Contact Us KTSM News Team Careers 
 
 login register 
 Search Home 
Connect with us:

 KTSM on Facebook KTSM on Twitter Subscribe to our RSS feeds Connect with Mobile Devices 
 
 News 
 Decision 2012 Local News Troubleshooters 
 Weather 
 Dayplanner National Temperatures Radar Seven Day Forecast Temperatures 
 Sports 
 Olympics Zone Ultimate Football Guide Applebee&apos;s NC9 Overtime Bracket Bonanza 
 Community 
 Contests Events 
 Submit an Event 
 See It. Shoot It. Share It. Photo Galleries 
 Features 
 Health Source Forever Younger Feeling Right at Home Making Your World Brighter Let&apos;s Cook El Paso 
 Station Info 
 Contact Us TV Schedule Full NBC Episodes 
 
 
Three Arrested After Fight at Northeast Fast Food Restaurant
 News 
 Kai Porter Weekend Anchor/Reporter 
 
 Share 
 
 Tweet Share on Facebook Email this page Print this page 
 Report a Problem 
ADVERTISEMENT
 9 Comments 
 POSTED: Monday, October 17, 2011 - 10:21

 UPDATED: Thursday, October 20, 2011 - 20:24
 
Related
 
 Man Arrested in Connection to Sunday&apos;s Deadly Shooting Police Searching for Suspects Who Tried to Rob Fast Food Restaurant Overnight Re: Three Arrested After Fight at Northeast Fast Food Restaurant Police Investigating Overnight Fight Man In Serious Condition Following Parking Lot Fight 
 
EL PASO–Three men are charged with aggravated assault after police said they beat up three good Samaritans outside of a Northeast El Paso fast food restaurant.

Officers arrested Ernesto Torres, 18, Nathan McPherson, 18, and Carlos Maldonado, 19, on Sunday.

Police said the men got into a fight with another group of other men in the parking lot of a Whataburger Sunday morning, when the three victims tried to break it up. Police said Torres, MnPherson and Maldonado punched and kicked the victims in the body, head, and face.

Two of the victims were taken to the hospital with injuries, one remains in serious condition, police said.
 
Comments News Comments 
 
yreyes911 October 18, 2011
at 6:35pm 
 
I know all 3 of these boys. All played football and are great athletes and excellent students. They wouldn&apos;t hurt a fly. In fact they&apos;ve always offered a hand to those who needed them and that says quite a bit about their character. Maybe the 3 were just defending themselves. Anyway Im saddened that this has happened to them and i wish them the best of luck to them and their parents. These are good boys and come from good families.
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
..... October 18, 2011
at 1:21pm 
 
All graduates of Parkland High
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
jtgordon October 18, 2011
at 7:29am 
 
These 3 r my sons..if they only knew that im always watching thm, mayb thn mayb they would of jus gone inside the restaurant n got they food and left.. i shouldnt b lookin at the news n da internet to see this. they knw better n they were never taught to act this way...gentlemen, i hope u get 2 c dis post..im all da way out here, n ya&apos;ll r actin like animals..wht da ---- is wrong wit ya&apos;ll? u better get it straight real fast cuz i will b there sooner thn u think.

DAD
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
jones liza October 20, 2011
at 2:46pm 
 
wow where were u when i needed to talk to a parent when these kids were picking on my son last yr after he had returned back to school from a horrible car accident staples still in his head wtf is wrong with the younger generation
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
Estebanelpaso October 19, 2011
at 7:04pm 
 
They all have different names. You must have taught them to be responsible adults.
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
grandgee October 17, 2011
at 2:08pm 
 
Of course El Paso is safe, unless you are in the &quot;right place at the wrong time&quot;..Name your poison...
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
Estebanelpaso October 18, 2011
at 8:37am 
 
El Paso is safe, if you have protection from the Cartel.
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
huffmanj October 17, 2011
at 1:58pm 
 
Guy on the bottom looks like he&apos;s 40 years old!!!
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 
Estebanelpaso October 17, 2011
at 12:58pm 
 
I am glad that El Paso is so safe!
 
 reply Printer-friendly version 
 Post new Comment You have 500 characters left. Login or Register 
You must login or register to post this item.
 I have a username&amp;password I am a new user and would like to register Username: Enter your KTSM News Channel 9 username. Password: Enter the password that accompanies your username. Choose a Username: Spaces are allowed; punctuation is not allowed except for periods, hyphens, and underscores. E-mail address: A valid e-mail address. All e-mails from the system will be sent to this address. The e-mail address is not made public and will only be used if you wish to receive a new password or wish to receive certain news or notifications by e-mail. Password: Confirm password: Provide a password for the new account in both fields.   West Texas Weather 
86°F

Cloudy

High: 88°F Low: 72°F 

Wind: N at 7 mph

 More Weather | Radar | 7 Day Forecast | Dayplanner 
 
ADVERTISEMENT
 
 
 
 
 
 Special Features 
 Ultimate Football Guide Health Source Forever Younger Feeling Right at Home Making Your World Brighter Let&apos;s Cook El Paso 
 Contests 
 Going for the Gold 
 More Contests 
 
ADVERTISEMENT
 
 Closed Captioning Privacy Policy Terms of Service Public Files 
 
NewsChannel 9 - KTSM

801 N. Oregon
El Paso, Texas 79902
 TEL: (915) 532-5421
 FAX: (915) 496-4590
 EMAIL: webmaster@ktsm.com 
 
 West Texas News 
 
 KTSM on Facebook KTSM on Twitter Subscribe to our RSS feeds Connect with Mobile Devices 
 
 Contact Us KTSM News Team Careers 

Copyright©2012 ComCorp of El Paso Inc. All rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
