<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005590" url="http://www.scribd.com/hemanhe/d/48345719-IEP-Goal-Bank" time="2012-07-12-22:08" support="5" score="0.008194705571703147" bingtitle="IEP Goal Bank" webtitle="IEP Goal Bank">
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001240" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>... Intermediate Gross Motor-object control-throw ... Objective #16 Read and follow storage and cleaning ... Clear table and empty tray at fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Content Area English Functional Academics Independent Living Mathematics Mathematics Readiness Motor Recreation and Leisure Self-management and Daily Living Social Emotional Speech and Language Study Skills Vocational/Career Education To search the contents of the Goal Bank for a specific item, press Ctrl + F. The Goal Bank has been designed to allow users to locate specific goals as used in the eSIS SPED Full software. Click on a Content Area to proceed to specific Content Strands. From there, locate the specific strand and click to locate the Individual Goals. IEP Goals and Objectives Bank (Redmond, Oregon)   English E1 Comprehension (readiness) E2 Decoding and Word Recognition (readiness) E3 Literature E4 Phonemic Awareness (readiness) E5 Print Awareness And Letter Knowledge (readiness) E6 Reading Accuracy And Fluency E7 Reading Comprehension E8 Writing E9 Writing E10 Writing E11 Writing E12 Writing E13 Writing E14 Writing E15 Writing E16 Writing (readiness) Functional Academics FA1 Communication FA2 Communication FA3 Communication FA4 Communication FA5 Communication FA6 Communication FA7 Finance FA8 Finance FA9 Finance FA10 Finance FA11 Mathematics Content Strands Table Of Contents Table Of Contents   FA12 Mathematics FA13 Mathematics FA14 Mathematics FA15 Mathematics FA16 Reading FA17 Reading FA18 Reading FA19 Time Management FA20 Time Management FA21 Writing Independent Living IL1 Community Safety IL2 Community Safety IL3 Community Safety IL4 Community Safety IL5 Community Safety IL6 Community Safety IL7 Eating Out IL8 Eating Out IL9 General Shopping IL10 General Shopping IL11 Grocery Shopping IL12 Grocery Shopping IL13 Grocery Shopping IL14 Grocery Shopping IL15 Mobility IL16 Travel IL17 Travel IL18 Travel IL19 Travel IL20 Using Community Services Table Of Contents of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
IEP Goal Bank
 Download or Print 1,497 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 02/07/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
