<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005038" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/59933491/365-Meditations-for-Men" time="2012-07-12-21:33" support="1" score="0.002634924236472752" bingtitle="365 Meditations for Men - Scribd" webtitle="365 Meditations for Men">
			<query id="000067" bing-rank="51"/>
	<description>The other day as I stood in a long line at a fast-food restaurant, I grew ever more ... d forgotten what I intended to order, so as I quickly scanned the menu board ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download     365 Meditations for Men M. R. Howes, Editor James A. Harnish • Kel Groseclose • Vance P. Ross • Robert H. Lauer • James W. Moore • Paul E. Miller • J. Ellsworth Kalas • John Killinger • Walter Kimbrough • Martin L. Camp • James R. King Jr. • Bruce Fish • Tim Philpot Dimensions For Living, Nashville Copyright Information   Introduction The fact that you have picked up this book means that you do not fit the stereotypical view of men held by many--that men are not interested in spiritual things or in meditation on a daily basis. Nor does this book fit a stereotype. These 365 daily meditations will not give you a mere pat on the back, or just a nice spiritual boost--though you will receive encouragement and inspiration. You have in your hands a ringing call for reality, a challenge to be a strong man of faith--in your family, in your church, in your community. Thirteen talented male writers have come together to reflect on key themes of interest to today&apos;s Christian men. Each writer explores one topic for four weeks, providing an entire year&apos;s worth of encouragement and instruction for a man&apos;s spiritual journey. All thirteen writers call on you to act, to put your faith to work. They challenge you to become leaders, mentors, models for others, to make a difference in your world. One of the recurring themes is that Christian men are called to enter God&apos;s army, to join in the battle between good and evil. At the same time they challenge you not to get so busy, so active, that you never learn what quietness and silence can do to renew your life and rejuvenate you for service. The writers talk about what it means to be real men--to be both kind and tough, to be vulnerable, to give and forgive, to be able to handle both success and failure. They offer you the companionship of the Scriptures, as well as lessons from their own experience, and provide support and counsel for coping with problems like discouragement or fear. They call you to excellence, and at the same time remind you of the love and patience of our Savior Jesus Christ, who understands failure and doubt and is confident of your perseverance and ultimate triumph. They point you to the Holy Spirit, who provides the power to live the Christian life. Other characteristics of real men, these writers suggest, are that • they are men of vision; • they are men of prayer; • they are willing to ask for directions (did you know that not asking for directions is “a terminal male disease”?); • they are willing to wait for results; of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
365 Meditations for Men
 Download or Print 1,878 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 07/13/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
