<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005218" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/11/29/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030.html" time="2012-07-12-21:45" support="4" score="0.01644152728359969" bingtitle="Wienerschnitzel ATM Burglary: Napkin Falls, Revealing Suspect&apos;s ..." webtitle="Wienerschnitzel ATM Burglary: Napkin Falls, Revealing Suspect&apos;s Face In Surveillance Video (VIDEO)">
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="31"/>
	<description>... 2011, at about 2:15 a.m., two men broke into a Wienerschnitzel fast food restaurant in ... When one of the suspects replaced the napkin, his cover-up foiled and ...</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 LA Around Town LA Restaurants Justice For Kelly Thomas LA Lakers 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 42k Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k GOP Votes To Repeal Obamacare Again 21k Romney Campaign Releases New Ad Accusing Obama Of Spreading Lies 7k When Did Romney Leave Bain? 11k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Business 
 WATCH: Evidence Ex-Wall Street Trader May Have Taken Cyanide 2k Here Are The 16 Banks Under Investigation Over The Libor Scandal 371 Paul Krugman Slams Times Colleague, CNBC 3k America&apos;s Best States to Live In 250 Evander Holyfield&apos;s Unable To Avoid Foreclosure On $14 Million Mansion 697 
 Like 34k   Go to Business More in Business 
 Small Business Money 
 You might also like 
 World Tech Media Culture Sports Weird News Crime 
 Entertainment 
 Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 1k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 47 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 16 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 Media 
 Katie Couric Speaks Out About Ann Curry&apos;s &apos;Today&apos; Ouster 412 Gallup: Confidence In TV News At New Low 4k Anderson Cooper&apos;s Coming Out Was Planned For Months 264 WATCH: Greg Gutfeld Freaks Out 2k Katie Couric&apos;s Photo Shows Up In Unexpected Place 21 
 Like 46k   Go to Media More in Media 
 Eat The Press Calderone: The Backstory 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment TV Comedy Arts Books Religion Moviefone 
 Food 
 LOOK: The World&apos;s Most Expensive Foods 126 Cooking Legend Dies At 90 29 PHOTOS: Jaw-Dropping Knife Ads Are Fairly Graphic Chain Food Showdown: The Best&amp;Worst Spinach Dips 13 Teen Hospitalized For Addiction To Coke -- No, The Other Kind 20 
 Like 17k   Go to Food More in Food 
 Recipes Chefs Restaurants Desserts Cocktails Wine Beer 
 You might also like 
 Kitchen Daily Stylelist Home Travel 
 Culture 
 There Is Something Wrong With This Rock 199 10 Movies To Watch At Comic-Con 2012 27 50 YEARS 83 Guess Who&apos;s Playing Janis Joplin? 659 Culture&apos;s World Records 
 Like 14k   Go to Culture More in Culture 
 Arts Books TV 
 You might also like 
 Black Voices Latino Voices Gay Voices Comedy Impact Education Religion 
 Style 
 PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 47 PHOTOS: Everyone Got Dressed Up For The ESPY Awards 2012 10 Would You Get Plastic Surgery For Fat Toes? 151 PHOTO: Rose McGowan Flashes Her Bra 84 Princess Eugenie Trades In Her Fascinator For A Mortar Board 42 
 Like 31k   Go to Style More in Style 
 Beauty Photoshop Fails Royals Wardrobe Malfunctions Models Celebrity Style Michelle Obama Style 
 You might also like 
 Women Parents Weddings 
 Arts 
 Incredible Posters Of Famous Literary Quotes Body Painting Gone (Even More) Wild 36 These Nylon Creatures Will Haunt Your Dreams 18 Stunning Testimonies Of Queer Youth 14 Behold The Lego Coliseum! 23 
 Like 22k   Go to Arts More in Arts 
 Painting Film Design Photography Theater Dance Architecture 
 You might also like 
 Culture Books New York 
 San Francisco 
 PHOTOS: Huge Artist Coming To The SFMOMA 11 San Francisco Boycotts Apple Products 298 &apos;Largest Pot Shop On The Planet&apos; In Danger Of Shutting Down 404 Local Restaurant Gives California The Finger 240 Environmentalists Seek To Destroy SF&apos;s Main Source Of Drinking Water 63 
 Like 6k   Go to San Francisco More in San Francisco 
 Around Town Restaurants Real Estate Impact Best of San Francisco 
 You might also like 
 Tech Food Culture Sports GPS for the Soul 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 
 Moviefone AOL Real Estate Patch.com 
 Los Angeles 
 Around Town Restaurants Real Estate LA Impact Best of LA My LA Gavin Smith 
 
 
Wienerschnitzel ATM Burglary: Napkin Falls, Revealing Suspect&apos;s Face In Surveillance Video (VIDEO)
 
 First Posted: 11/29/11 02:33 PM ET   Updated: 11/30/11 11:21 AM ET 
 React Amazing
 Inspiring
 Funny
 Scary
 Hot
 Crazy
 Important
 Weird
 Follow   Video , Wienerschnitzel ATM Burglary , Anaheim Wienerschnitzel , Anaheim Atm Burglary , Anaheim Atm Robbery , Atm Burglary Surveillance Video , Atm Robbery Surveillance Video , Santa Ana Wienerschnitzel , Santa Ana Atm Robbery , Santa Ana Burglary , Two-Men-Wanted-Atm , Los Angeles News 
share this story
 Get Los Angeles Alerts Sign Up Submit this story digg reddit stumble 
One burglar&apos;s attempt to cover up a surveillance video with fast food napkins resulted in him staring close-up into the camera, giving police a clear shot of his face.

As MSNBC reports , on November 22, 2011, at about 2:15 a.m., two men broke into a Wienerschnitzel fast food restaurant in Anaheim. They entered through the drive-in window and covered the surveillance video with napkins and fast food sticker labels. The suspects proceeded to use a pallet jack to take the store&apos;s ATM machine, which contained about two thousand dollars, and transport it to a possible waiting vehicle.

However, at one point during the robbery, a napkin fell from one of the surveillance cameras. When one of the suspects replaced the napkin, his cover-up foiled and the camera caught a straight-on image of his face.

 According to CBS , the photographed suspect is described as 1) &quot;a black male, 5&apos;7&quot;, medium build with black hair and mustache.. seen wearing all-black clothing including gloves and a Dickies baseball cap.&quot; The second suspect is described as &quot;a black male, also 5&apos;7&quot;, medium build, all-black clothing and gloves.&quot;

Police are asking anyone with information about either suspect to call Detective Chris Cooper at (714) 765-1185.
 CORRECTION: A previous version of this story stated that the restaurant was located in Santa Ana, CA. It is located in Anaheim, CA. FOLLOW 
 HUFFPOST LOS ANGELES ON Facebook: Like 10k Twitter:   Get Alerts CONTRIBUTE TO THIS STORY 
 Send Corrections Send us a Link Contact us 

 Send a Tip Send Photos/Videos Comment 
 
 
 Video 
 One burglar&apos;s attempt to cover up a surveillance video with fast food napkins resulted in him staring close-up into the camera, giving police a clear shot of his face.

As MSNBC reports, on November... One burglar&apos;s attempt to cover up a surveillance video with fast food napkins resulted in him staring close-up into the camera, giving police a clear shot of his face.

As MSNBC reports, on November...   Loading... TOP LINKS ON THIS TOPIC 1 of 2 
 Surveillance photo released in Anaheim Wienerschnitzel ATM burglary | PHOTOGRAPHS 
 
 Police: 1 arrested in Wienerschnitzel ATM heist | burglary, restaurant, police - News - The Orange County Register 
 
 Santa Ana ATM Burglary: Men Break Into Wienerschnitzel, Steal ATM - ktla.com 
 
 Police: 2 wanted in Wienerschnitzel ATM heist | black, atm, police - News - The Orange County Register 
 
 Two Men Allegedly Steal an ATM from Anaheim Wienerschnitzel - Orange County Criminal Lawyer Blog 
 
 Two Men Burglarize Anaheim Wienerschnitzel | NBC Los Angeles 
 Around the Web: 

 Surveillance photo released in Anaheim Wienerschnitzel ATM ... 

 Santa Ana ATM Burglary: Men Break into Wienerschnitzel, Steal ... 

 Police: 2 wanted in Wienerschnitzel ATM heist The Orange County ... 

 Police: 2 wanted in Wienerschnitzel ATM heist - Local News ... 

 Two Men Burglarize Anaheim Wienerschnitzel | NBC Los Angeles 

 ATMSecurity.com ATM Security news ATM Security issues ATM ... 

 Suspects Sought In ATM Burglary At OC Weinerschnitzel « CBS Los ... 

 Anaheim Crime - Topix 

 Twitter Trackbacks for Police: 2 wanted in Wienerschnitzel ATM heist ... 

 Wienerschnitzel Burglar Hot Dogs for Camera - Orange County ... 

 Filed by Kathleen Miles  |  
 More in Los Angeles... 

 San Bernardino Bankruptcy Means Many Bills, Few... Officer Pat Cronin&amp;Officer Jamie Carganilla,... Kip Arnold, Suicidal LA Teacher Accused Of... Manuel Ramos, Fullerton Police Officer Involved In...     
 Comments 405 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 
Previewing Your Comment.
This comment has not yet been posted You have exceeded your word limit by   words. Please click the &quot;Edit&quot; button and shorten your comment.

 Post Comment Edit Cancel 

You can post to us this information Contact us Click here to leave a comment.

HuffPost High School welcomes a lively, thoughtful debate in the comment section. Keep in mind that the articles here are penned by young authors, so please keep criticism respectful, and help us to keep this a safe and supportive place for writers of all ages to contribute. Post Comment Preview Comment To reply to a Comment: Click &quot;Reply&quot; at the bottom of the comment; after being approved your comment will appear directly underneath the comment you replied to. Post Comment Preview Comment To reply to a Comment: Click &quot;Reply&quot; at the bottom of the comment; after being approved your comment will appear directly underneath the comment you replied to. 
 Share your Comment: 
 Post to Facebook. Post to Blogger. Post to Twitter. Post to WordPress. Post to TypePad. Post to Tumblr. Post to Yahoo! 
 Blogger login: Blogger password: Select blog:   refresh list Remember me: 
 
 Wordpress host: Wordpress login: Wordpress password: Remember me: 
 
 TypePad host: TypePad login: TypePad password: Select blog:   refresh list Remember me: 
 
 Tumblr login: Tumblr password: Remember me: 
 Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Recency  |  Popularity Page:  1   2   3   4   5   Next ›   Last »  (9 total) 1Davelow 66 Fans 08:23 PM on 11/30/2011 He Should of Used a Brawney Napkin Instead... 1Davelow: He Should of Used a Brawney Napkin Instead... http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/1Davelow/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120967859.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER Bills Catz Don&apos;t believe everything you think. 348 Fans 02:01 PM on 11/30/2011 Yo dude, you&apos;re doing it wrong! Bills_Catz: Yo dude, you&apos;re doing it wrong! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Bills_Catz/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120892076.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER Bruce Negron &quot;We are each responsible for all of our experience 128 Fans 12:55 PM on 11/30/2011 Guess the alarm wasn&apos;t working either, I wonder who made that mistake? Bruce_Negron: Guess the alarm wasn&apos;t working either, I wonder who made http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Bruce_Negron/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120878252.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program ninjacb he who endures, conquers 362 Fans 12:17 PM on 11/30/2011 GAWD. i was actually trolling around looking for something to make me laugh. and here it be. thank you, stupid criminal. you have done yourself a disservice but certainly brightened my day. ninjacb: GAWD. i was actually trolling around looking for something to http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/ninjacb/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120870608.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 coreten 218 Fans 11:54 AM on 11/30/2011 Another proof that anyone who has an intelligence level less than a vegetable, should not try to make a living this way. coreten: Another proof that anyone who has an intelligence level less http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/coreten/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120866050.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 PC0207 76 Fans 11:35 AM on 11/30/2011 I so needed the laugh this morning...thank you!!! lmao PC0207: I so needed the laugh this morning...thank you!!! lmao http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PC0207/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120862296.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 PeoplePower2011 5 Fans 11:20 AM on 11/30/2011 TAKE IT BACK FROM THE 1 PERCENT!!!

Thats what Im talking about. leave this guy alone, its about time the rich paid their fare share!!! PeoplePower2011: TAKE IT BACK FROM THE 1 PERCENT!!! Thats what Im http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PeoplePower2011/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120859437.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Katesrose 10 Fans 11:51 AM on 11/30/2011 Fare share? It&apos;s the people like you that condone the criminal behavior that in the long run costs our country even more money. The expenses incurred by just one criminal act (police, lawyers, prison, etc.) would astound you. But hey...what do YOU care? Your ignorance is showing. You don&apos;t know the difference between FARE and FAIR. Perhaps you missed out on your fair share of brains when you were born. So sad... Katesrose: Fare share? It&apos;s the people like you that condone the http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Katesrose/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120865324.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program ninjacb he who endures, conquers 362 Fans 12:20 PM on 11/30/2011 you consider wienerschnitzel in the 1%. honey, your enthusiasm is great but you need to direct it to the real culprits. this was just a stupid person, doing a stupid crime, at a stupid restaurant. i mean seriously. how much money do you think a wienerschnitzel would have in their atm? probably a sum total of $20. for their one customer a day. come on. go to the politics section and get all angry. ninjacb: you consider wienerschnitzel in the 1%. honey, your enthusiasm is http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/ninjacb/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120871260.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER haval2 what to say? 3792 Fans 10:32 AM on 11/30/2011 he should be a hit on comedy night in prison. haval2: he should be a hit on comedy night in prison. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/haval2/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120850508.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER h23154 310 Fans 10:16 AM on 11/30/2011 Now they know that the next time they should staple the napkins to their faces. h23154: Now they know that the next time they should staple http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/h23154/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120847754.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER PCPrincess I&apos;m probably gaming. 350 Fans   03:57 PM on 11/30/2011 LMAO!!!! PCPrincess: LMAO!!!! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PCPrincess/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120915605.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER omegas3 Such is Life.... 474 Fans 10:08 AM on 11/30/2011 dumb asses omegas3: dumb asses http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/omegas3/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120846228.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 TYRANNASAURUS UGH!....people don&apos;t taste good. 514 Fans 09:57 AM on 11/30/2011 ATM Burglary Gone Very, Very Wrong.....

HAHAHAHAHAA.....Another example of super intelligence from the human race. TYRANNASAURUS: ATM Burglary Gone Very, Very Wrong..... HAHAHAHAHAA.....Another example of super http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/TYRANNASAURUS/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120844445.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 gumbo1049 polytechnician 359 Fans 09:57 AM on 11/30/2011 We will be seeing him on The Worlds Dumbest soon. gumbo1049: We will be seeing him on The Worlds Dumbest soon. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/gumbo1049/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120844441.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 CoastalNC Good thoughts create good things 2804 Fans 09:41 AM on 11/30/2011 Nothing like having a plan....haha. CoastalNC: Nothing like having a plan....haha. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/CoastalNC/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120841885.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER OldCowboy Against stupidity the Gods contend in vain. 345 Fans 09:20 AM on 11/30/2011 D.U.M.B. S.H.*.T. OldCowboy: D.U.M.B. S.H.*.T. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/OldCowboy/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120838801.html History  | Permalink  | Share it neoliberal site 10 Fans 09:24 AM on 11/30/2011 LOL! neoliberal_site: LOL! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/neoliberal_site/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120839324.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER nypapajoe 735 Fans 09:09 AM on 11/30/2011 Bet this fool is a career criminal recently released from jail for similar crimes! nypapajoe: Bet this fool is a career criminal recently released from http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/nypapajoe/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120837096.html History  | Permalink  | Share it neoliberal site 10 Fans 09:26 AM on 11/30/2011 Just finished nearly a full of watching Bait Car and now this,... EVERY ONE of the bait car episodes found only blacks and Hispanics steeling cars and now this... why do civil rights leadwers try to sanitize the idisproportionate crime...hence incarceration to &apos;racism&quot;? They&apos;re not fooling anyone. neoliberal_site: Just finished nearly a full of watching Bait Car and http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/neoliberal_site/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120839643.html History  | Permalink  | Share it BeansAndGreens 24 Fans 09:48 AM on 11/30/2011 Put some hidden cameras in Wall Street executive offices and you&apos;ll see plenty of white people committing crimes. BeansAndGreens: Put some hidden cameras in Wall Street executive offices and http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/BeansAndGreens/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120843022.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 centsable 2324 Fans 10:35 AM on 11/30/2011 Watch Bait Car again, I saw three white guys take the bait and one black guy who didn&apos;t touch the car, but called police. centsable: Watch Bait Car again, I saw three white guys take http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/centsable/wienerschnitzel-atm-burglary_n_1119030_120851019.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
     Page:  1   2   3   4   5   Next ›   Last »  (9 total) new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost av%2BoIzr1NlDiMVVHOmqGvq5HJnwj5Ye6EMvIMCP8iiUEoTzg6H5IOXjw6mzxIm76glaGIN245NYThlmrmVBDrcLjY5Jf%2Fkxb n23g1KxNmTj6iRfnNUuLgvP%2FVIDSQQiY9zw0a%2F0RtTu9lEN4RMznsY5dv18uzp6qh4OX3jPasfoynjVbDFrTpQ3dA2QU8NM%2B 1 of 2 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 
 Like 6k World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss 
 Like 7k Photos Of Kardashian Baby Are A Hard Sell 
 Like 66 &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts 
 Like 4k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 
 Like 1k Kim Kardashian Tweets Yet Another Bikini Pic 
 Like 35 Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh 
 Like 456 Katie Holmes Used Disposable Phones To Orchestrate Divorce 
 Like 496 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 
 Like 1k Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of HuffPost Local 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
