<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005862" url="http://www.newstimes.com/news/" time="2012-07-12-22:31" support="1" score="0.0005373721260322451" bingtitle="News - NewsTimes" webtitle="News - NewsTimes">
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>Md. becomes first to OK password protection bill ... A local woman is suing a now-shuttered fast-food restaurant after ... A celebration banquet will take place Sunday at 1:30 ...</description>
	<body>
		( skip this header )
 
 Register Sign In 


 
 Traffic Weather FAQ Subscriber services e-Edition 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012
 
 newstimes.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Obituaries Opinion Blogs 

 Shopping Classifieds Jobs Homes Rentals Cars 

 Index▼ 
 Close [X] Quick links to other pages on this site | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Check It Out: Were you SEEN? Man, bouncers crash through window Meatballs recalled due to listeria Crash sends baby to hospital Hunting serial bank robbers 
 
 Local Police Reports Regional National World Politics Science and Technology 
 
 Baseball Football Basketball Hockey Other High School UConn WestConn High School Football 
 
 Markets 
 
 Movies Music Arts Television Comics Horoscope Games Lottery 
 
 Columnists 
 
News
 
 
 
 Jason Rearick / The News-Times 

 FBI shuts down Bridgewater town hall, removes documents 
 First Selectman William Stuart, reached on his cellphone, said he was not in town hall on Wednesday, he was out haying a field.

Board of... 
 
 National News 
 
 
 Dem leader to GOP: Compromise to avert defense cut 
 
 Migrant&apos;s widow welcomes US probe of border death 
 
 Inquiry: Penn St. officials concealed sex abuse 
 
 Lawmakers furious over China-made Olympic uniform 
 
 Thousands fall victim to utility payment scam 
 

 More National News» 
 
 World News 
 
 
 9 dead, 2 missing in Mont Blanc summer avalanche 
 
 Rolling Stones celebrate 50 years on stage 
 
 Chilean hate-crime legislation signed into law 
 
 Syria defections raise hopes among Assad opponents 
 
 New Arafat medical file released in death probe 
 

 More World News» 
 
 Political News 
 
 
 Biden paints ominous picture of Romney presidency 
 
 Website sued by Obama camp pulls disputed goods 
 
 Documents conflict on when Romney left Bain 
 
 Fewer auto closings reduce US unemployment claims 
 
 AdWatch: Obama ad hits Romney&apos;s tax plan 
 

 More Political News» 
 
 
 &apos;Probable cause&apos; to try Heath for murder 
 
John Pirro
 
DANBURY -- A Superior Court judge determined Thursday afternoon that there is... more» 
 
 Photo 
 
 Cops: Woman stole jewelry from widower 

Libor Jany
 
A 38-year-old New Fairfield woman turned herself in Wednesday on several... more» 
 

 
 Head-on collision forces road closure in Ridgefield 

Staff reports
 
RIDGEFIELD -- Emergency personnel responded to a reported head-on collision... more» 
 

 
 Route 7 crash sends baby to hospital 

Staff reports
 
NEW MILFORD -- A 22-year-old woman and a 1-year-old baby were transported to... more» 
 

 
 High-speed rail service proposed for Danbury 
 
Dirk Perrefort
 
If Amtrak officials have their way, city residents in the future could hop on... more» 
 
 Photo 
 
 FBI shuts down Bridgewater town hall, removes documents 
 
Susan Tuz and Nanci Hutson
 
Bridgewater: Federal investigators execute search warrant, remove document boxes more» 
 
 Photo 
 
 Man charged with abusing girl, 4 

Staff reports
 
DANBURY -- A city man was arrested Tuesday afternoon on charges he physically... more» 
 

 
 N.C. man charged in fatal 2011 crash 


 
DANBURY -- A North Carolina man was charged with negligent homicide as the... more» 
 

 
 Cops: Man, bouncers crash through window 


 
A Waterbury man was arrested for his involvement in an altercation with two... more» 
 

 
 Cops: Woman, 67, assaulted officers 

Libor Jany
 
A 67-year woman who was accompanying a friend to the hospital became... more» 
 

 
 Driver charged after hitting bird bath 

Staff reports
 
Officers were called shortly before 4 p.m. to a home on Ellsworth Avenue,... more» 
 

 
 Firefighters respond to hazmat situation in Bethel 

Staff reports
 
BETHEL -- Firefighters are at the scene of a suspected carbon monoxide leak... more» 
 

 
 Police: Erratic driving leads to DUI arrest 


 
NEW MILFORD -- A 45-year-old New Milford man was charged with driving under... more» 
 

 
 Serial bank robbers sought by cops 
 
Associated Press
 
The FBI offered a $50,000 reward Tuesday for help in capturing what it... more» 
 
 Photo 
 
 Brookfield man charged wiith DUI 


 
NEW MILFORD -- A 54-year-old Brookfield man was charged with drunken driving... more» 
 

 
 
 Local News 
 
 
 Reading, meeting, party scheduled 


 
 The discussion will focus on memories of Washington Depot, specifically stories about the people, businesses and buildings in town before it was changed by the Flood of 1955.

Festivities will... More» 

 Danbury News-Times 


 
 City gets money for 58 more preschoolers 
 
 Ex-town leader charged in accident 
 
 Seniors find second life in music 
 
 Ridgefield Library gets temporary home 
 

 More Local News» 
 
 Police Reports 
 
 
 Cops: Woman stole jewelry from widower 

Libor Jany
 
 A 38-year-old New Fairfield woman turned herself in Wednesday on several outstanding warrants for burglary and credit card theft, police said.

Police records show that she faces a range of... More» 

 Danbury News-Times 


 
 Head-on collision forces road closure in Ridgefield 
 
 Man charged with abusing girl, 4 
 
 N.C. man charged in fatal 2011 crash 
 
 Cops: Man, bouncers crash through window 
 

 More Police Reports» 
 
 Regional 
 
 Associated Press Copyright 2012 Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
Updated 04:12 p.m., Thursday, July 12, 2012
 
 State trooper shoots, kills man on Route 8 

Associated Press
 
 A man armed with a knife was shot to death after a confrontation Thursday morning with a state trooper on Route 8.

The trooper, identified Thursday afternoon as Lt. Clayton Brown, the commanding... More» 

 Connecticut Post 


 
 Stolen puppy found in West Haven 
 
 Cops: Man had 35 pounds of pot, guns 
 
 Former Donovan finance director pleads not guilty 
 
 Fire damages Bridgeport house 
 

 More Regional News» 
 
 Most Read | Most Commented | Most Emailed 
 
 FBI shuts down Bridgewater town hall, removes documents Route 7 crash sends baby to hospital Man charged with abusing girl, 4 High-speed rail service proposed for Danbury Cops: Woman stole jewelry from widower Cops: Man, bouncers crash through window Head-on collision forces road closure in Ridgefield 
 
 Former Bethel leader has accident Defends fairness of mandatory health insurance for everyone FBI shuts down town hall Danbury reaches out to absent students Cops: Man, bouncers crash through window Margaret McKitty: Democrats have been too nice for too long Woman, 67, charged with assaulting officers Malloy backs striking HealthBridge workers High-speed rail service proposed for Danbury Danbury man faces assault charges 
 
 FBI shuts down Bridgewater town hall, removes documents High-speed rail service proposed for Danbury New Fairfield woman charged with credit card theft Seniors find second life in music FBI conducts records search at Bridgewater Town Hall Feds bust major Danbury area pot growing ring Man severely burned after soaking logs with alcohol 
 
 Top Ads Cars | Jobs | Homes | Rentals 

 
No Top Ads for Cars are currently available. To search all Cars listings, please visit: ingearct.com 
 
 
 All Cars 
 
 Top Ads Cars | Jobs | Homes | Rentals 

 
GOSS METRO PRESSMAN

 HEARST MEDIA SERVICES CT, is looking for an experienced Part Time Goss Metro Pressman. Day shift/night... (more) 

shift. Various hours to help cover for all time off including last minute call outs for sick time, needs to be very flexible. This is a non-union shop.

Please send resumes to employment@hearstmediact.com and indicate Metro Pressman in subject line. (less) 
 
PORTFOLIO MANAGER for Asia&amp;Europe Credit sought by Manchac Capital LLC (Greenwich, CT) to mng a portfolio of non-U.S.... (more) 

invest.s for mngd acct. of major hedge fund. Req. deg. in Busin. Admin., Econ., Fin., or rel.&amp;exp. as Trader / Anal. in Asian&amp;European mark. Req. exp. as Portfolio Mngr; mngng credit&amp;volatility focused portfolio; executing trades incl. bonds, credit deriv.,&amp;equity deriv. for non-U.S. mark., incl. Asian mark.; constructing finan. valuation models using Cashflow, LBO, Black Sholes,&amp;Merton; conducting co.-specific&amp;indus.-wide research&amp;formulating trading strat. based on research. Apply to resume@manchacllc.com. (less) 
 
COMPUTERS:
Implementation Consultant- (Stamford, CT): Dvlp bus. processes, configure apps&amp;implmt solutions, provide tech... (more) 

expertise&amp;consultancy services on bus. apps&amp;functional specs, recommend architecture&amp;dvlp custom solutions for apps in Life Sciences industry. Reqs deg&amp;exp incl consulting in pharmaceutical environment, customer facing exp&amp;exp w/delivering enterprise s/ware implmtns, PM tools&amp;d/base exp, SDLC exp. Up to 75% travel to unanticipated client locations in US. Email resume to careers@arisglobal.com, req #2012900. ArisGlobal is an Equal Opportunity Employer/ Committed to Diversity (less) 
 
COMPUTER/IT: S.A.C. Capital Advisors, L.P. seeks Vice President, Risk Developer in Stamford, CT to dvlp quantitative analysis... (more) 

of lrg risk datasets to support both day-to-day&amp;long term mgmt of Risk&amp;performance. Req&apos;mnts: Bachelor&apos;s degree in Info Systems Mgmt, Comp Sci, or rel. field or equiv&amp;3 yrs of exp dvlping quantitative data storage systems w/ user interface systems incl aggregation&amp;rules engines on behalf of a global fin&apos;l srvcs institution. Exp must incl dvlping risk mgmt systems&amp;valuation engines; designing performance&amp;P&amp;L;attribution systems; translating fin&apos;l algorithms into code;&amp;designing&amp;dvlping programs utilizing SQL Server, C# WinForm,&amp;Auto sys. E-mail resume to: recruiting2012@sac.com&amp;reference job code. 
WC06252012CP. NO CALLS PLEASE. EOE/M/F/D/V (less) 
 
FINANCE: S.A.C. Capital Advisors, L.P. seeks Associate in Stamford, CT to produce investor&amp;counter-party risk reports... (more) 

detailing fund performance, exposure by strategy, asset class,&amp;currency. Req&apos;mnts: Bachelor&apos;s degree in Accntg, Bus Admin, Econ, Finance, or a rel. field or equiv&amp;3 yrs of exp conducting complex fin&apos;l analysis of invstmnt products&amp;mng&apos;g projects on behalf of a global fin&apos;l srvcs institution. Exp must incl analyzing&amp;presenting a wide variety of performance data&amp;risk metrics, incl volatility calculations, Sharpe ratios, rate of return analysis, risk exposures, liquidity, capital planning,&amp;side pocket reporting; performing special projects incl responding to ad-hoc requests from investors;&amp;building out the performance&amp;risk reporting infrastructure. E-mail resume to: recruiting2012@sac.com&amp;reference job code 
AV07022012CP. NO CALLS PLEASE. EOE/M/F/D/V (less) 
 
SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER
FactSet Research Systems, Inc., Norwalk, CT: Design, implement, and test client-facing applications... (more) 

and features using C++. Provide clients with data in a variety of formats. Responsible for creating and managing automated processes to calculate data using scripting languages. Req&apos;s: Bachelor&apos;s degree, or higher, or foreign equiv., in CS or rel. field&amp;at least 3 yrs of software engineering industry exper. All stated exper. must include hands-on work w/ Object Oriented programming language such as Java, C#, or C++. Stated exper. must include at least 1 yr of hands-on work w/: C++; Perl; A Unix/ Linux shell-scripting language; UI design for client-facing applications;&amp;Managing production databases. Qualified applicants should mail resumes to Melissa Manna , HR, FactSet Research Systems, Inc. 601 Merritt 7, Norwalk, CT 06851 with reference to Job Code: FSSE01. (less) 
 
 
 All Jobs 
 
 Top Ads Cars | Jobs | Homes | Rentals 

 
NEW MILFORD O.H.
SUN. 7/8, 1-4pm. 5 Bonnie Vu Lane Terrific 4BR 2.5BA Col. on 1.8 lvl. acres in quiet subdivision. Freshly... (more) 

painted interior, refin. Hdwd flrs, new countertops. Great oppty! Come see for yourself - $329.9k. Dir: Rt109 to Ridge Rd. to Chapin Rd. to Bonnie Vu. Roberta Allen, WRRE 203-994-8593 (less) 
 
BETHEL 3 apprv 1+ ac bldg lots 4 sale by owner. $99,900 each. 203-743-4469
 
 
 All Homes 
 
 Top Ads Cars | Jobs | Homes | Rentals 

 
BRIDGEPORT FURN. ROOM
373 Noble Ave. $150/wk$500/mo.
Call 203-864-0927
BridgeportCTapartmentsforrent.com
 
NEWTOWN Houseshare, female.
2 lrg. rms., bath, pool, all utils inc. $525. 1st/last/sec. 203-942-0023
 
NEW MILFORD Furn rms $120/wk Cable/Elec Wrk Ref. 860-350-3548
 
STAMFORD
HURRY IN LIMITED AVAILABILITY!
Beautiful 2BRs, Split level town-home design. Gas heat&amp;central air.
Eat-in kitchen... (more) 

w/deluxe appliances Priv bckyrd decks. Wshr/Dryr hk-up. $1580 per month.
RIPPOWAM PARK APTS
203-357-9710
*Income restrictions apply (less) 
 
BRIDGEPORT NEWLY done apts. Spacious rooms. 2BR, 3BR&amp;4BRs. Section 8 definitely welcome. $900-$1350. For more info 203-572-8691
 
DERBY 1BR new kitch, new bath, new carpets, Off st prkg. Stv/fridge incld. Resp landlord seeking resp tenant. $700/mo+sec.... (more) 

203-732-2615 (less) 
 
 
 All Rentals 
 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
 
News-Times

 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Obituaries Opinion Living Blogs Traffic Weather 
 
Services

 Customer Care Contact Us Advertise With Us Terms of Service 
Marketplace
 Classifieds Find Danbury jobs Jobs Homes Rentals Cars 
 
Other editions

 Home delivery e-Edition Mobile iPhone Android RSS Facebook Twitter 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Danbury Car Dealerships in Danbury Cleaning Services in Danbury Family Doctors in Danbury Furniture Stores in Danbury Injury Attorneys in Danbury New Car Dealers in Danbury Real Estate Agents in Danbury Real Estate Attorneys in Danbury Restaurants in Danbury 
 
Our Partners

 Connecticut Post Darien News Fairfield Citizen Greenwich Citizen Greenwich Time HealthyLife CT New Canaan News New Milford Spectrum Norwalk Citizen Stamford Advocate The News-Times Westport News Ad Choices 
 
 ©2012 Hearst Communications Inc. A quadrantONE partner ©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
	</body>
</document>
