<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005248" url="http://www.bizjournals.com/seattle/blog/2012/02/taco-time-northwest-out-to-show-its.html" time="2012-07-12-21:47" support="5" score="0.005414081759465719" bingtitle="Taco Time Northwest goes green and local to mark 50th anniversary ..." webtitle="Taco Time Northwest goes green and local to mark 50th anniversary - Puget Sound Business Journal">
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="83"/>
	<description>On Numbers; MPI: Meetings Mean Business; App Reviews ... But Taco Time Northwest is not your typical fast-food restaurant ... the quandary faced by anyone standing with a tray ...</description>
	<body>
		A message from The Business Journals:

We have detected you are using Internet Explorer 6, an outdated browser that we no longer fully support and Microsoft suggests upgrading for a more secure, faster, and functional web browsing experience. Use these links to download a new browser or upgrade your existing browser: Internet Explorer 9 | Firefox | Safari | Google Chrome 

If you received this message in error or choose not to upgrade at this time, please feel free to continue to the page you have requested.
 
This was printed from Puget Sound Business Journal
 
 The Business Journals Digital Network: The Business Journals Local Business Directory Book of Lists Upstart Business Journal 
 
 Subscribe - Get 4 FREE issues 
 Bizjournal logo 
 Login Register 
 Search 
 Choose a city 
 Albany Albuquerque Atlanta Austin Baltimore Birmingham Boston Buffalo Charlotte Cincinnati Columbus 

 Dallas Dayton Denver Greensboro/Winston-Salem/High Point Honolulu Houston Jacksonville Kansas City Los Angeles Louisville Memphis 

 Milwaukee Minneapolis/St. Paul Nashville Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh/Durham Sacramento San Antonio 

 San Francisco San Jose Seattle South Florida St. Louis Tampa Bay Washington, D.C. Wichita 
 Home 
 Receive Morning Call Email Receive DailyUpdate Email Contact the Newsroom Follow us on Twitter, Facebook Latest Tech News on TechFlash 
 News 
 Blogs Premium Companies Industries Photo Galleries Press Releases My News 
 People 
 People on the Move Executive Profiles Names in the News Beginners to Big Shots 
 Events 
 Business Events Nominations 
 Exclusives 
 Beginners to Big Shots MPI: Meetings Mean Business National Blogs Social Madness 
 How-To 
 Marketing Funding Human Resources Technology Growth Strategies How-To Videos 
 Buy 
 Subscriptions Book of Lists MyBookofLists Sales Leads Reprints Whitepapers 
 Find 
 City Guide Commercial Real Estate Search Businesses for Sale 
 Jobs 
 Find a Job Post a Job Employers Jobs FAQ 
 Contact Us 
 About Us Help 
 
 
Blog» Puget Sound BizTalk Puget Sound BizTalk 
 
 twitter 

 Email Print Reprints Comments 
 
Send this story to a friend




 Email address of friend (insert comma between multiple addresses): Your email address: Copy Me Add a brief note: Send Email Processing... 
 Taco Time Northwest goes green and local to mark 50th anniversary
 
Puget Sound Business Journal by Glenn Drosendahl, Contributing Writer
 Date: Tuesday, February 28, 2012, 12:21pm PST - Last Modified: Thursday, March 1, 2012, 4:30pm PST View photo gallery (2 photos) Taco Time Northwest 
Taco Time Northwest&apos;s original location in 1962 in White Center, at Seattle&apos;s southern border
 Glenn Drosendahl Contributing Writer- Puget Sound Business Journal 
 Fresh, local and green are the trends of our times, especially at chef-driven restaurants where the first two are practically musts. 

 At fast-food restaurants, however, the priorities tend to be different. More like quick and cheap. 

 But Taco Time Northwest is not your typical fast-food restaurant chain, say the folks who run it, and they’re doing their best to get that point across. 

 To celebrate the 50th anniversary of when great-grandpa Frank Tonkin Sr. opened his original Taco Time in White Center at Seattle&apos;s south border – and subsequent growth of the family-run business to 73 restaurants, primarily in Western Washington – Taco Time Northwest has launched initiatives that underline a commitment to fresh, local and green. 

 The Mexi-Fries (spicy tater tots) will be made with Washington potatoes. In May, Caesar soft tacos will have romaine lettuce from the Kent Valley. Soon, the pinto beans could be coming from Quincy. 

 “We’ve always had a commitment to fresh quality food,” TTNW President Robby Tonkin said. “The new twist is not only fresh quality but also local sources. In most fast food restaurants, you just don’t see that. Usually big distributors bring in the food from somewhere else.” 

 Taco Time Northwest already was getting Northwest beef from Petschl’s Quality Meats, based in Tukwila, and its cheddar from Darigold , the dairy farmers’ cooperative based in Seattle. The tortillas are made fresh daily at La Mexicana in White Center. 

 The goal now is to get even more local, Tonkin said, partly to support local businesses and partly because closer means fresher. 

 Taco Time Northwest’s green initiative addresses the quandary faced by anyone standing with a tray of assorted cups and wrappings in front of multiple recycling bins and wondering what goes where. More than half of the group’s restaurants that are near a commercial composting company will have entirely compostable wrappings. 
 
 Page 1 2 3 
 | View All 

 
See all your followed company news on your personalized dashboard .

To access the full benefits of bizWatch and receive a weekly email with aggregated news on all the companies you are following, please provide your email address below.
 Sign Up Now 
You must have a bizjournals account to follow a company.
Please Log In or Register .
 
Related:
 Retailing&amp;Restaurants 
 twitter 
Recent posts:

 Ask.com to throw Seattle a party in Wallingford park NBC may buy Microsoft&apos;s share of MSNBC.com Microsoft cutting jobs in advertising, marketing Underwater on your mortgage? Hang out with Zillow and feds online 
 &lt;Older posts Newer posts&gt; 
Comments
 
If you are commenting using a Facebook account, your profile information may be displayed with your comment depending on your privacy settings. By leaving the &apos;Post to Facebook&apos; box selected, your comment will be published to your Facebook profile in addition to the space below.
 
Inside Puget Sound Business Journal
 
Most Popular
 
 Most popular Slideshows Facebook Twitter Emailed Mobile 
 
 A taste of new Seattle Center eatery options (slide show) Microsoft patents fingerprint ID for touch screens Navy signs $700M, 3-year Microsoft software license Thinking about buying a laptop? Decide.com says do it now Seattle startup Qthru lets you skip the grocery store line FBI: Enumclaw finance adviser stole $2M, faked suicide StartupCity turns interns into entrepreneurs Netflix shares leap on gains in streaming Colorado hotel firm buying Seattle Hilton Hotel Report: Microsoft, Amazon among the least transparent firms 
 
 Toughest 5 golf courses in Wash. state (slide show) A taste of new Seattle Center eatery options (slide show) Seattle startup Qthru lets you skip the grocery store line Cheers for arrival of space shuttle trainer (slide show) What ‘Seattle process’? Big wheel turns up fast 
 See more slideshows» 
 
 Analyst: Alaska Airlines merger with American not likely 
 
 Roger Ellman commented on Netflix shares leap on gains in streaming on Friday, July 6th
 
 Teri L Travis commented on Seattle startup Qthru lets you skip the grocery store checkout line on Tuesday, July 10th
 
 Shawntay Smith commented on Snohomish County&apos;s aerospace growth: Umbra, Aerojet, Asco on Wednesday, July 11th
 
 Mark Swartz commented on American Airlines mulls merger with Alaska Airlines, others on Wednesday, July 11th
 
 
Like the Puget Sound Business Journal
 
PSBJ

 @PSBJ 

 #SocialMadness heats up as @ julepmaven takes on @ seattlemaven in the final round. Vote here! http://t.co/qMc8NscD #socialmedia http://t.co/CcsRx6Dn to throw Seattle a party in Wallingford park http://t.co/PPByX8rY AVI BioPharma changes name to Sarepta, splits stock http://t.co/CToh9U9N 
 
 Colorado hotel firm buying Seattle Hilton Hotel World&apos;s going to need a lot more pilots: Boeing Restaurants join fight to protect Bristol Bay salmon Seattle startup Qthru lets you skip the grocery store line Thinking about buying a laptop? Decide.com says do it now Snohomish County&apos;s aerospace growth: Umbra, Aerojet, Asco Toughest 5 golf courses in Wash. state (slide show) 
 Sign up for email newsletters See more emailed stories» 
 Download the free iPhone app Download the free Android app 
 View mobile site Learn more about our mobile apps» 
How-To: Marketing
 
 Sometimes the best sales managers embody good parenting UH Foundation rebrands itself to prepare for next 10 years No (business)man is an island: We all need partners 
 View More How-To: Marketing 
Email Subscriptions
 The latest local business news delivered to your inbox every afternoon. Sign Up Now or Add More Newsletters 
People on the Move
 See More People on the Move Search and Contact all People on the Move 
Seattle Jobs
 
 Marketing Manager Newland Communities | Bonney Lake, WA Director of Operations and Finance Museum of Glass | Tacoma, WA Executive Director, University Communications Washington State University | Pullman, WA Assistant Controller Ecova | Tacoma, WA Assistant Controller Ecova | Seattle, WA 
 Post a Job | View More Jobs Listings Online 
 News People Events Exclusives How-To Buy Find Jobs Contact Us My Account 
 Services 
 Book Of Lists Commercial Property Local Business Directory Jobs myBookofLists Search Subscribe to Paper 
 Subscriptions 
 Subscribe to Paper Trial Subscription Renew subscription Single copies Digital edition Premium content Subscriber FAQs Help Book Of Lists Change Mailing Address 
 Tools 
 Newsletters Syndication/RSS Twitter Mobile Submit People on the Move Mobile App LinkedIn Today 
 About 
 Advertise Contact Us About the paper About the business journals 
 Affiliates 
 Upstart Business Journal Sports Business Journal SportsBusiness Daily Sporting News Mass High Tech TechFlash Sustainable Business Oregon Hemmings Motor News 
 
©2012 American City Business Journals. All rights reserved. Use of this Site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement (updated 3/14/12) and Privacy Policy (updated 3/14/12).

 Your California Privacy Rights .

The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of American City Business Journals.

 Ad Choices .
	</body>
</document>
