<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005852" url="http://covertaffairs.com/blog/tag/kapahulu-restaurant" time="2012-07-12-22:31" support="2" score="0.0020819276347685766" bingtitle="Kapahulu Restaurant | Private Chef Hawaii | Honolulu Personal Chef ..." webtitle="Kapahulu Restaurant | Private Chef Hawaii | Honolulu Personal Chef | Culinary Insider">
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>... hear that someone touched there food and then expect ... Papa John’s do a good job specially for a fast food restaurant. ... (Tip: Don’t order the fried rice, its very heavy ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME SERVICES RATES CLIENTS TESTIMONIALS ABOUT RESERVATIONS GIFT CARDS BLOG CONTACT SMALL BITES STARTERS ENTREES DESSERTS DRINKS RECIPES ART 
 

 

 
Posts Tagged‘Kapahulu Restaurant’
 
 Izakaya Nonbei 
 Tuesday, September 13th, 2011 
 Overall Review: 

 Service : Izakaya Nonbei used to be one of our all time favorite Japanese restaurants in Hawaii, however, last year it was sold and has changed substantially. One of the past owners is still working for the restaurant and she assured me that the cook was the same (although the main chef was her father so we are not sure how they could be if they moved?). When the food arrived about 30% of the dishes where as good as we remembered but the rest of the food was disappointing. When we asked to return a horribly overcooked fish she took it back to the kitchen and then returned it to us saying“the chef touched it and said its moist inside”…. first and foremost no one wants to hear that someone touched there food and then expect them to continue to eat it! secondly we know overcooked fish when we see and taste it. It was disappointing service for sure. Specially when the past owners where so nice and the food was impeccable.

 Foo d: The food was so so. Someone who has never been to the Old Nonbei may think its great, but after years of patronage we feel the food has suffered in the transition. Some of the items are still good so if you are in the neighborhood and in the mood for sushi or Japanese by all means go….. but if you have been an old Nonbei fan say so long and just move onto another Japanese restaurant. Even the green tea was different–must be a cheaper brand.

 Favorite Dishes: Karei Karaag (Cabbage&amp;Small fish) Eggplant&amp;Mushrooms, Miso Rice Cake, Small Fried Shrimp Appetizer and the ice Otokoyama sake of course!

 Atmosphere : The new Nonbei ambiance is kind of modern inside. They have ground floor tables as well as regular tables and the inside is very small (about 5-6 tables total) plus the small sushi bar. The real killer is that they have a huge flat screen TV on the wall which really detracts for the restaurants classiness. Honestly who wants to go to a nice restaurant and have to watch TV? its distracting and doesn’t belong in this restaurant at all.

 Consistency: Well the old Nonbei was incredible consistence for years, however, this new location isn’t going to get a second chance from us anytime soon. If we do for some reason feel generous we will go back and update this restaurant review!

 Parking : Nonbei has a small parking lot out front with about 10 spots in total. When full it can be super hard to get in and out but at least they do have some parking. Otherwise you can always park across the street at Safeway and walk across the street.

 Price Range: Low-Medium ($6-$25) per Entree 
Corkage Fee $20 per Bottle
Reservations Accepted&amp;Recommended
Take Out Available 

 Address: 
3108 Olu St.
Honolulu, HI 96816
 Tel: (808) 734-5573 
 

 Hours of Operation: 
Dinner Mon, Wed-Sun 5:00 p.m.–10:00 p.m.
Closed Tuesday
 
 
 
Whole Fried Flounder
 
 
Fried Shrimp
 
 
Cold Tofu
 
 
 
 
Eggplant&amp;Mushroom
 
 
Cabbage&amp;Small Fish
 
 
Miso Rice Cake
 
 
 
 
Tags: free parking , Japanese Food , Kaimuki Restaurant , Kapahulu Restaurant , Sake , Sushi , Sushi Bar 
Posted in Japanese , Restaurants | No Comments» 
 
 Uncle Bo’s 
 Wednesday, August 3rd, 2011 
 Overall Review: 

 Service : The service was really excellent at Uncle Bo’s on Kapahulu. The waitress was a real pro, full of smiles and very candid. She was on top of her game and didnt miss a beat from the moment we sat down till the moment we paid the check. In fact, we had a coupon and forgot to read the fine print indicating we had to come after 8pm she spoke to the manager on our behalf (so we could redeem our voucher) and we really appreciated all her help and attentiveness. The only not so memorable in a good way service was the hostess who tried to seat us in the back room because we didnt have a reservation. The restaurant had plenty of empty tables out front so it was a bit particular that we had to ask a few times not to site in the dark, cold back of the restaurant especially when arriving for dinner so early at 6:30pm. The manager finally interviewned and told her she could seat in front with everyone else! ha ha ha

 Foo d: The food was not so great at Uncle Bo’s its average but nothing really stands out as delicious or memorable which you look for from a restaurant and keeps you coming back time and time again. Everything we ordered was very overly sweet including the Baby Back Ribs, Clams and Pork Kabobs. You can find a good assortment of pupu’s, pastas, pizzas, seafood&amp;poltry entrees at Uncle Bo’s with a asian-pacific meets italian theme to it. We also ordered a“Crab  Salad with Avocado”but where disappointed when it only had 3 small little pieces of crab a few pieces of avocado and the rest was all ham and a traditional cob salad. It was very boring and miss marketed for sure. The best thing we ordered was the Spicy Tuna Wraps, they where creamy and very tastily but not even remotely spicy. 
 

 Favorite Dishes: Spicy Tuna Wraps

 Atmosphere : The atmosphere at Uncle Bo’s is nice. The restaurant has high ceilings and interesting artwork. The restaurant used to be Anti pastas so one wall has some interesting stanglass windows with garlic and other italian themed pictures covering it. The feel is trendy especially with the dark walls, floor and hanging chains. The front of the restaurant is lovely, however, the back of the restaurant has a completely different ambiance with low ceilings and rather dark / constricted. Our recommendation is to make a reservation and request the front seating area or go another time. The bar only has about 4-5 stools so its more of a place to mingle while waiting for a table than to grab a quick bite.

 Consistency: We go to Uncle Bo’s every once and a while but it has been about a year since the last time we went. We are not particular impressed any time we have been with the food but it was convenient with the kapahulu location and late hours to grab pupus with friends, however, now that the new Side Street opened down the street i’m sure we will not be back to Uncle Bo’s for a good  long while (the pork chop at side street is to die for!).

 Parking : Uncle Bo’s does not have free parking but there is a small private parking lot right next to the restaurant which costs $5 or you can find metered street parking which is free after 6pm and usually pretty easy to come by at night. If you have troubles across the street is another paid parking lot with ample spots as well.

 Price Range: Medium ($12-$27) per Entree
Corkage Fee $10 per Bottle
Reservations Accepted&amp;Recommended
Take Out Available

 Address: 
559 Kapahulu Ave
Honolulu, HI 96816
 Tel: (808) 735-8311 
 Website: http://www.unclebosrestaurant.com 

 Hours of Operation: 
Monday-Sunday: Dinner–5:00 p.m.–2:00 p.m.
 
 
 
 
Crab&amp;Avocado Salad
 
 
Clams
 
 
Spicy Ahi Wrap
 
 
 
 
Baby Back Ribs
 
 
Pork Kebabs
 
 
Decor
 
 
 
 
Tags: Asian Pacific Food , Kapahulu Restaurant , Local Kine Grindz , Seafood , street parking 
Posted in American , Asian Pacific , Bars , Italian , Local Kine Grindz , Restaurants | No Comments» 
 
 Papa John’s Pizza 
 Monday, June 13th, 2011 
 Overall: 

 Service : The services is great at Papa John’s. From the delivery boys to the pizza makers the team at Papa John’s do a good job specially for a fast food restaurant. In fact, we had a pretty bad experience with a new location and after writing to corporate was pleasantly surprised to receive 2 free large pizza cards in the mail–now thats good service!

 Foo d: The pizza is good at at Papa John’s. From thin crust to regular the dough is not oily and the ingredients are fresh as promised. The chicken wings and other items are not as much of a slam dunk but if you are in the mood the honey Chipotle Wings are pretty tasty.

 Favorite Dishes: Thin Crust Pizza with Chicken, Peppers, and Onion, Hawaiian Pizza

 Atmosphere : Well since we NEVER eat at Papa John’s its really hard to say but I have been into a few locations and they are always clean which is a plus for the ambiance. Really its not a place you want to site and eat unless maybe its raining outside or if you are hungry after some drinks on your way home and itching for some slicest.

 Consistency: The Kapiolani blvd location has always had the best and most consistent pizza in our option. After we moved to a new district we have struggled with pizza consistency and often times the wrong ingredients are on the pie or its cold when it arrives which never used to happen…. so i guess it depends on your location and the management!

 Parking : Most Papa John’s locations have some designed spots for pickup or are in locations where they have ample parking so if you are swinging by after work don’t worry you should be in good shape no matter what.

 Price Range: Medium-High ($16-$26.99) per Large Pizza (Papa Johns always has Daily Specials so Ask!) 
Take Out Available
 FREE DELIVERY 

 Address: 
Papa John’s Store #1752
611 Kapahulu Ave
Honolulu, HI 96815
 Tel: (808) 733-7272 

 Papa John’s Store #1751
1646 Kapiolani blvd
Honolulu, HI 96814
Tel: (808)592-7272
 website: http://www.papajohns.com/index.html 

 Hours of Operation: 
Open Daily 10 a.m.–9:30 p.m.
 
Thin Crust Specialty Pizza
 
Tags: Free Delivery , free parking , Honolulu Restaurant Review , Kapahulu Restaurant , Kapiolani Restaurant , Pizza 
Posted in American , Delivery Food , Fast Food , Restaurants | No Comments» 
 
 Genke Sushi 
 Saturday, January 29th, 2011 
 Overall Rating: 

 Service : The service is good at Genke Sushi restaurants in Hawaii. The staff is super friendly and very attentive. In fact, at the Kapahulu location in particular we have had the best service and before you even realize you need something your waiter is either bringing it or right by your side to fulfill your request which is always great when you go out.

 Foo d: The food isn’t anything super fancy or even very creative but its good and cheap! Genke Sushi has a fun conveyor belt which rotates around the diners with various sushi rolls and food items like salads, edamame, etc. It is really a great way to enjoy a quick meal because while ordering off the menu you can grab an appetizer roll to hold you over. Basic items you can expect on the menu include Miso soup, Sashimi, Teriyaki Bowls, Salads, Udon Noodles, etc.
 Genki Sushi Menu For Download 

 Favorite Dishes: Spicy Tuna Hand Roll, California Hand Roll, Salmon Cream Cheese Roll, Softshell Crab Roll, Tempura Roll, Edamame, and Miso Soup

 Atmosphere : The ambiance at Genke Sushi is very open and clean. The conveyor belt is the focus on each location (as it should be!) but Genke Sushi does a good job of building restaurants which are warm and inviting. The logo guy is unforgettable and is featured throughout art in each location making Genke Sushi a unique place to take out-of-town guests.

 Consistency: Genke Sushi is very consistent. Each time we go we always eat the Ahi Tuna hand roll and it tastes exactly the same each time.

 Parking : Each Genke Sushi location has free parking! the location in Honolulu which is hardest to park is the location on Kapahulu which only has about 10 parking spots, however, you can generally find a spot on the street or in Safeway’s lot across the street.

 Price Range: Low ($1.50-$4.80) per Dish 
No BYOB!
Reservations Not Accepted
Take Out Available 

 Address: 
Kapahulu
885 Kapahulu Avenue
Honolulu, HI 96816
(808) 735-7700
 Website: / http://www.genkisushiusa.com/

Ala Moana Center
1450 Ala Moana Blvd.#2096
Mall Level
Honolulu, HI 96814
(808) 942-9102

Ward Center
1200 Ala Moana Blvd.
Building 3, Bay 3
Honolulu, HI 96814
(808) 591-5600

Many more Genke Sushi locations! check website for full list
 Hours of Operation: 
Sun-Thurs: 11 a.m.–9 p.m.
Fri-Sat: 11 a.m.–10 p.m.
Takeout Available Daily: 11 a.m.–9 p.m.

 

 

 
 
Tags: Ala Moana Center Restaurant , Chain Restaurant , Honolulu Restaurant Review , Japanese Food , Kapahulu Restaurant , Sushi Bar , Ward Center Restaurant 
Posted in Fast Food , Japanese , Restaurants | No Comments» 
 
 Side Street Inn 
 Thursday, July 29th, 2010 
 Overall : 

 Service : The service is wonderful at the new Side Street Inn on Da Strip! from the moment the valet opened the car door, to the moment we were seated the service was excellent. The staff was smiling, happy, and down right pleasant through the entire meal. Its rare to find such good service and it commendable!

 Food : The food is served family style so its the perfect place to go with lots of friends&amp;family for pupus or dinner. The menu is very typical of a local style restaurant with lots of Asian and Island flavors, lots of meat dishes, appetizers and overall good grindz.  Each dish was served hot, fresh and in a timely manner so its no wonder the place was packed!

 Favorite Dishes: Nalo Green Salad (big and delicious), Pork Chops, Hoisin BBQ Baby Back Ribs (all ribs are just delicious!), Garlic Soy Beans, and drum roll….Peanut Butter Crunch dessert. Sooooo freaken good!  (Tip: Don’t order the fried rice, its very heavy and not very crispy)

 Atmosphere : The new side street in has a great atmosphere. The restaurant has ample seating and airy high ceilings prefect for absorbing all the noise. The Side Street in has both booth and table seating making it a very homey, bright and modern restaurant you can feel comfortable wearing anything in.

 Consistency: We have only been to this new location once but the food is consistently tasty with the other Side Street Inn location on 1225 Hopaka St.

 Parking : Oh the parking…yes not our favorite part of the evening seeing as the only convenient place to park is the valet service provided by the restaurant at a $5 fee without tip! Don’t get me wrong…I’ll pay for valet but if I eat at the restaurant I hope to get a better deal than $7-$8 per a visit. Of course you can always find free street parking on Kapahulu if your lucky. 
 

 Price Range: Medium ($8-$20-Market Price) per Entree 
No BYOB Allowed
Reservations Recommended
Take Out Available 

 Address: 
614 Kapahulu Ave.
Honolulu, HI 96815
Tel: (808) 591-0253 or 596-8282
 Website: www.sidestreetinn.com 

 1225 Hopaka St.
Honolulu, HI 96814
Tel:(808) 591-0253 or 596-8282 

 Hours of Operation:
Hopaka St–Sunday – Saturday 2:00 pm – 2:00 am
Da Strip–Please call restaurant as hours for new location are TBD 
 
 
 
Steamed Fresh Fish
 
 
Pork Chop
 
 
Tags: Honolulu Restaurant Review , Kapahulu Restaurant , Local Kine Grindz , Valet Parking 
Posted in American , Asian Pacific , Bars , Breakfast / Brunch , Hawaiian , Local Kine Grindz , Restaurants | No Comments» 
 
 Taco Ricos 
 Thursday, March 18th, 2010 
 Overall : 

 Service : The staff was really nice but the restaurant didn’t have a bathroom, bottle opener, or any sour cream. Also they ran out of fish tacos and they never offered us any water during our short meal there. The second time we went they did have the fish but it was precooked and cold. The staff was also pretty slow so don’t go here if you are in a rush!

 Food : The food is simple and what you would expect from a traditional street Mexican vendor. The tacos are small, round, and wrapped in double corn tortillas. The restaurant has a great condiment bar with interesting toppings and home made salsa. The meat tacos where dry and old tasting (you can get a variety plate of 5 tacos for $9) but the fish was delicious and made the trip worth while. That being said…last time we went the fish tacos where to wet and not so good for the price.

 Favorite Dishes: Fish Tacos (it’s fresh catfish!), (from the condiment bar–Salsa Verde, Pickled Red Onion, Cilantro)

 Atmosphere : The ambiance is overall pretty ghetto. The inside is very minimalistic and a really cool exterior paint job. The music is custom mixed for the shop and really adds to the authentic Mexican experience. Taco Ricos is definitely the kind of place you could wear anything to or be as drunk as you want without consequence. The restaurant only has 2 tables and some bar seating so its more of a eat and run type of establishment.

 Consistency: Taco Ricos is not very consistent. Its really hit or miss but the last two times have been big misses so we don’t recommend this restaurant very highly.

 Parking : Taco Ricos is on Kapahulu street so the best place to park is on the street which is metered.

 Price Range: Low ($5-$12) per Entree
No Corkage Fee!
(TIP: They don’t have a wine opener so drink beer or bring a screw top wine) 

 Address: 
 Tacos Ricos
525 Kapahulu Avenue
Phone: (808) 834-8222 

 
 
Tags: Hole In The Wall , Honolulu Restaurant Review , Kapahulu Restaurant , Mexican Food , no corkage fee , Tacos 
Posted in Fast Food , Hole In The Walls , Mexican , Restaurants | 4 Comments» 
 
 Pyramids 
 Monday, March 1st, 2010 
 Overall : 

 Service : The service is pretty good but the best part is the costumes they make the staff wear. They are both tacky and hilarious!!

 Food : If your itching for some Middle Eastern food Pyramids is your best bet on the Island. The menu is traditional with selections like Shawarmas, Moussaka, Hummus, Falafel, Baba Ganoush along with other Middle Eastern favorites. We recommend going for lunch where they have a $12 buffet as dinner can get a bit pricey. The buffet is enough food to eat like a king and you can try a little of everything! The only thing to keep in mind is that Pyramids does not provide belly dancing entertainment for lunch.

 Favorite Dishes: Spanakopita, Hummus, Lamb Kebabs, Chicken Shawarma and Chicken Salad.

 Atmosphere : The atmosphere is about the best thing going for this restaurant. Its fun, well decorated, causal and for dinner they have live entertainment! The overall experience is very lively and if you are in the mood for something different you can’t beat the staff costumes and the middle eastern decor.

 Consistency: It’s consistently OK–would only go if wanted some free entertainment and was in the mood for some belly dancing!

 Parking : Street parking can be challenging as the restaurant is located on Kapahulu but they do have free parking behind Pyramids if you circle around the block. Make sure to let them know you parked in the designated lot when you are seated since there are no parking stubs to validate.

 Price Range: Medium ($16-$25) per Entree
Corkage Fee: $10 per Bottle
Take Out Available
Reservations: Not needed for Lunch but recommended for Dinner
Entertainment Provided! 

 Address: 
 758 Kapahulu Avenue
Honolulu, HI 96816-1196
Phone: (808) 737-2900
 Website: http://habibihawaii.com/pyramid.html 

 Hours of Operations:
Monday-Saturday
11 a.m.- 2 p.m (Lunch&amp;Buffet) 5:30 p.m.-10 p.m (Dinner)
Sunday: 5 p.m.- 9 p.m (Dinner only) 
 
 
Tags: Free Entertainment , free parking , Honolulu Restaurant Review , Kapahulu Restaurant , Middle Eastern Food 
Posted in Egyptian , Middle Eastern , Restaurants | No Comments» 
 
 


 
RSS Feed 
Facebook 
Twitter 

 Visit our Food&amp;Wine Photo Blog 
 
Do you“LIKE”Covert Affairs?
 
 Receive The Free Honolulu
Culinary Insider Newsletter! First name: E-mail address: Close 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 (1) May 2012 (7) April 2012 (4) March 2012 (4) January 2012 (1) December 2011 (2) November 2011 (5) October 2011 (6) September 2011 (6) August 2011 (6) July 2011 (11) June 2011 (11) May 2011 (7) April 2011 (8) March 2011 (14) February 2011 (10) January 2011 (18) December 2010 (14) November 2010 (9) September 2010 (3) August 2010 (6) July 2010 (3) June 2010 (2) April 2010 (2) March 2010 (12) February 2010 (2) August 2009 (1) April 2009 (4) 
Categories

 Ingredients 
 Antioxidants Fruit Oil Veggies 
 Recipes 
 Appetizers Breakfast Desserts Entrées Holiday KTA–Published Salads Sauce Sides Snack Soup 
 Restaurants 
 American Asian Pacific Bars 
 Brewery Happy Hour Night Club Wine Bar 
 Bistro Breakfast / Brunch Chinese Contemporary Delivery Food Diner Egyptian Fast Food Food Truck French Greek Hawaiian Hole In The Walls Indian Italian Japanese Kama&apos;aina Specials Korean Local Kine Grindz Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Plate Lunch Scandinavian Soul Food Southern Food Steakhouse Tapas Thai Vietnamese 
 Whats New 
 All-Inclusive Promotions Seasonal Menus 
 Wine 
 Country of Orgin 
 Argentina Australian Chilean Italy Romania Spanish USA 
 Price 
 $10-$20 $25-$50 $30-$40 Under $10 
 Red Rosé White 
 
 
 

 
 
 

Copyright©Covert Affairs LLC. All Rights Reserved.  Terms&amp;Conditions . Website by Square One Internet Solutions
	</body>
</document>
