<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005329" url="http://www.shopping.com/cecilware-parts/products" time="2012-07-12-21:52" support="3" score="0.01598422319031129" bingtitle="&quot;cecilware parts&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="cecilware parts- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>... impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant ... switch Side mounted control panel 1/4&quot; water line ... Moisture &amp; Powder Collection Tray Prevents excess ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Cecilware    less» Shopping 
 cecilware parts 
 Showing results for &quot;
cecilware parts
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ 
 Whipper motor CD75A for Cecilware Cappuccino Machine Whipper motor CD75A for Cecilware Cappuccino Machine 
 ( In stock ) 
Whipper motor for Cecilware cappuccino machines. Part# CD-75A (CD75A) for GB-3, GB3-LD cappuccino machine. Solve your squealing/broken motor problems yourself. Only 3 wires and two to deal... More 

Whipper motor for Cecilware cappuccino machines. Part# CD-75A (CD75A) for GB-3, GB3-LD cappuccino machine. Solve your squealing/broken motor problems yourself. Only 3 wires and two to deal with and you&apos;ll have a new motor installed. The part shown may be the same OR the equivalent of the factory part. Sold each motor. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /whipper-motor-cd75a-for/JJCl1Qi59GHeb9Se86te0Q==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $92.69 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Cecilware NHV2-UL NHT Granita Dispenser Cecilware NHV2-UL NHT Granita Dispenser 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) Granita Dispenser, double 2-1/2 gal. cap. clear bowls w/graphic top, manual fill, s/s exterior finish, suction cup compression seal system, programmable defrost timer, 115v/60/1, (2) 1/2 hp, 15amps w/cord Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-nhv2ul-nht/4s10j0pD1lemPXQdKmIufw==/info $2,766.04 No Shipping Info Visit Store -47% 
 Natural Gas Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; Gas Lava Rock Charbroiler - 75,000 BTU Natural Gas Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; Gas Lava Rock Charbroiler - 75,000 BTU 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Easily prepare delicious chicken, burgers, grilled vegetables, and more with the Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; gas lava rock charbroiler! Great for kitchens where space is at a premium, this 75,000... More 

Easily prepare delicious chicken, burgers, grilled vegetables, and more with the Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; gas lava rock charbroiler! Great for kitchens where space is at a premium, this 75,000 BTU unit lets you easily delight customers with delicious foods thanks to the 36&quot; x 15 1/2&quot; cast iron cooking grate and reusable lava rock briquettes that create authentic charbroiled taste and appearance. Each of the unit&apos;s six burners are independently controlled for maximum convenience, and boast higher levels of power to give you optimum production capabilities while maintaining a small footprint! This unit features heavy-gauge steel unibody construction, a stainless steel front, 2 1/2&quot; adjustable legs, and a removable, non-corrosive aluminum drip pan for convenience and durability. The Cecilware CCB1836 has a 3/4&quot; NPT gas manifold pipe and is NSF Listed. Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details. Choose fuel type. Overall Dimensions: Left to Right: 36&quot; Front to Back: 18&quot; Height: 10 1/2&quot; CCB1836 NATURAL GAS From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /natural-gas-cecilware/Q6em77TKz31r6dadJWd4bA==/info The WEBstaurant Store $2,414.00 $1,269.00 47% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Baso Gas Safety Valve- Anets P8903-96, Cecilware L016a, L016f Baso Gas Safety Valve- Anets P8903-96, Cecilware L016a, L016f 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
 PART TYPE: BASO SAFETY VALVE OUR PART #: 5233 MANUFACTURER /PART #&apos;S: ANETS: P8903-96 CECILWARE: L016A, L016F HICKORY: 180 STAR: 2J8958 LIST PRICE: $160.00 DESCRIPTION: Safety Valve, BASO... More 

 PART TYPE: BASO SAFETY VALVE OUR PART #: 5233 MANUFACTURER /PART #&apos;S: ANETS: P8903-96 CECILWARE: L016A, L016F HICKORY: 180 STAR: 2J8958 LIST PRICE: $160.00 DESCRIPTION: Safety Valve, BASO Millivolt, Gas In/Out 3/8&quot; NPT, Pilot In/Out 1/4&quot; CCT, BTU 110,000. APPLICATIONS/Mode ls: ANETS: Gas Fryers where applicable CECILWARE: Fryers: FM28, FM28A, GF8, GF10, GF16, GF16A, GF28, GF28A HICKORY: Ovens/Ranges Where Applicable STAR: Gas Fryers: 215B (S/N 2156323&amp;UP), 403 Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /baso-gas-safety-valve/3u30VXo9W_iqyUxYpDiR3w==/info $116.95 +$13.91 shipping Visit Store -49% 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware ESP1-220V 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware ESP1-220V from $2,743.88 49% Off 4 stores See Details 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB3MD10-LD Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,3 Flavor 12D147 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB3MD10-LD Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,3 Flavor 12D147 
 ( In stock ) 
Hot Beverage Dispenser, 3 Flavor, Capacity 3-1/5 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 11-1/2 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black,... More 

Hot Beverage Dispenser, 3 Flavor, Capacity 3-1/5 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 11-1/2 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black, Holds (1) 10 Lb. (2) 5 Lb., Includes Cappuccino Graphic, Standards Ul,nsf,cul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/2dyZf-VL7KBlBaN7c65wmA==/info Grainger $2,996.00 +$49.12 shipping Visit Store 
 Cecilware 3 Gallon Twin Automatic Coffee Urn Cecilware 3 Gallon Twin Automatic Coffee Urn 
 ( In stock ) 
Automatic Coffee Urn; Stainless steel construction; Twin 3 gallon capacity; Brews in 1 lb batches; Adjustable by-pass; Automatic push button agitator; Cycle stop switch; Side mounted... More 

Automatic Coffee Urn; Stainless steel construction; Twin 3 gallon capacity; Brews in 1 lb batches; Adjustable by-pass; Automatic push button agitator; Cycle stop switch; Side mounted control panel; Solid state timer&amp;new liquid level control system; 1/4&quot; water line required; Specify voltage when ordering; (3-phase voltage available); 120V/208V/60/1- ph; 29A/6,000W; 120V/240V/60/1- ph; 34A/8,000W; 33.5&quot;W x 28.5&quot;H x 17.5&quot;D; One year parts &amp;labor warranty; ETL listed; NSF certified Less 
 Tundra Specialties Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-3-gallon-twin/PBlQTVG0BSBQz0K0Eke0Rg==/info Tundra Specialties $2,041.58 No Shipping Info Visit Store -47% 
 Liquid Propane Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; Gas Lava Rock Charbroiler - 75,000 BTU Liquid Propane Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; Gas Lava Rock Charbroiler - 75,000 BTU 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Easily prepare delicious chicken, burgers, grilled vegetables, and more with the Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; gas lava rock charbroiler! Great for kitchens where space is at a premium, this 75,000... More 

Easily prepare delicious chicken, burgers, grilled vegetables, and more with the Cecilware CCB1836 36&quot; gas lava rock charbroiler! Great for kitchens where space is at a premium, this 75,000 BTU unit lets you easily delight customers with delicious foods thanks to the 36&quot; x 15 1/2&quot; cast iron cooking grate and reusable lava rock briquettes that create authentic charbroiled taste and appearance. Each of the unit&apos;s six burners are independently controlled for maximum convenience, and boast higher levels of power to give you optimum production capabilities while maintaining a small footprint! This unit features heavy-gauge steel unibody construction, a stainless steel front, 2 1/2&quot; adjustable legs, and a removable, non-corrosive aluminum drip pan for convenience and durability. The Cecilware CCB1836 has a 3/4&quot; NPT gas manifold pipe and is NSF Listed. Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details. Choose fuel type. Overall Dimensions: Left to Right: 36&quot; Front to Back: 18&quot; Height: 10 1/2&quot; CCB1836 LP GAS From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /liquid-propane-cecilware/gr_aqba6GbsqoSpm06Veng==/info The WEBstaurant Store $2,414.00 $1,269.00 47% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ea/99/21/56699176-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+Model+A.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=9&amp;d;=179.82&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware Model A 
 Cecilware Model A from $179.82 4 stores See Details http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/53/36/78/504e4b53437578776a746f6c355a7948775a51-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=10&amp;d;=1064.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Grindmaster Cecilware FE-100 Twin 3 gallon Coffee Urn Grindmaster Cecilware FE-100 Twin 3 gallon Coffee Urn 
 ( In stock ) 
This is not the best photograph, the urn is in really good shape. Cecilware FE-100 Automatic Dual Coffee Urn Brewer - two 3 gallon urns. New Cecilware urns sell for about $3000.00 so you... More 

This is not the best photograph, the urn is in really good shape. Cecilware FE-100 Automatic Dual Coffee Urn Brewer - two 3 gallon urns. New Cecilware urns sell for about $3000.00 so you can save yourself alot of money by buying a pre-owned twin urn. This is ideal for hotels, or anyplace that holds large events. Hooks up to a waterline. Cecilware is well known in the industry for their fine quality coffee urns. Quality designed, engineered, and constructed stainless steel. Ideal for large events. Brews consistently perfect coffee batch after batch.Two 3 gallon urns( Uses 3 gallon paper filters). Mistake proof, push button - coffee/water formula is automatically locked into brewing cycle. This is a PRE- OWNED machine. It has been cleaned, serviced, and inspected by qualified technicians and is in excellent working condition. Electical: 120/240V AC, 60Hz, single phase, 3 wire Water Connection: 1/4&quot; tubing Dimensions: 18&quot;D X 25&quot;H X 33 1/2&quot;W Comes with a 30 day warranty. Local pick up or call 800-283-2726 for freight quote. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmaster-cecilware/S6xPNKSCuxwjtol5ZyHwZQ==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,064.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/65/4e/5a/3747663856595137684c7474534779696d3051-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=11&amp;d;=76.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Thermostat, Rx 200-375, Cecilware L345a - (new Style) Fits: Efp, Efs, Fmp, Fms Thermostat, Rx 200-375, Cecilware L345a - (new Style) Fits: Efp, Efs, Fmp, Fms 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
........SAVE $......... TIRED OF PAYING RETAIL (PLUS SHIPPING) FOR COMMERCIAL APPLIANCE PARTS? PLEASE CHECK US OUT! YOU WILL BE GLAD YOU DID.. .About This Item PART TYPE:THERMOSTAT RX (NEW... More 

........SAVE $......... TIRED OF PAYING RETAIL (PLUS SHIPPING) FOR COMMERCIAL APPLIANCE PARTS? PLEASE CHECK US OUT! YOU WILL BE GLAD YOU DID.. .About This Item PART TYPE:THERMOSTAT RX (NEW STYLE) OUR PART #: 5180 MANUFACTURER /PART #: CECILWARE: L345A LIST PRICE: $84.00 DESCRIPTION: Thermostat, RX, 200-375 Degrees, With Stuffing Box. Cap 36&quot;, Bulb 3/8 x 5 5/8&quot; APPLICATIONS/Mode ls: CECILWARE: EFP(30, 40, 65) EFS (30, 40, 65), FMP (30, 40, 40B, 40BSS, 65, 403), FMS (30, 40, 54, Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /thermostat-rx-200375/eNZ7Gf8VYQ7hLttSGyim0Q==/info $76.95 +$11.91 shipping Visit Store -49% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/3e/c8/e5/120084162-100x100-0-0_grindmaster+cecilware+esp2+220v.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=12&amp;d;=3119.91&amp;rt;=mr 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware ESP2-220V Espresso Machine 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware ESP2-220V Espresso Machine Espresso Machine, Automatic, Home, Coffee Style: Pad, 480 Cups, 260 Watts from $3,119.91 49% Off 5 stores See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/57/32/7233586c43304d47783262414c674164464441-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=13&amp;d;=5468.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 7776E Amw Twin Midline Pump Urns 12D170 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 7776E Amw Twin Midline Pump Urns 12D170 
 ( In stock ) 
Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 34 In., Depth 16-3/4 In., Height 33-1/10 In., Voltage 220, Amps 50, Watts 8500, Material Stainless Steel, Color... More 

Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 34 In., Depth 16-3/4 In., Height 33-1/10 In., Voltage 220, Amps 50, Watts 8500, Material Stainless Steel, Color Stainless Steel, Includes 25 Paper Filters, Standards Nsf, Ul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/6W2r3XlC0MGx2bALgAdFDA==/info Grainger $5,468.00 +$107.52 shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/37/79/45/756934487563624133326576456566722d6177-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=14&amp;d;=709.29&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware Powdered Hot Chocolate Mini Whipper Cecilware Powdered Hot Chocolate Mini Whipper 
 ( In stock ) 
Mini-Whipper; Powdered hot chocolate dispenser; One 8 lb hopper; Stainless steel construction; 1/2 gallon water tank capacity; Push button dispense operation; Easy cleaning, touch button... More 

Mini-Whipper; Powdered hot chocolate dispenser; One 8 lb hopper; Stainless steel construction; 1/2 gallon water tank capacity; Push button dispense operation; Easy cleaning, touch button rinse system; 1/4&quot; water line required; 120V/60/1-ph; 15A/1,800W; 9&quot;W x 16&quot;D x 24&quot;H; Two year parts &amp;labor warranty; Includes power cord&amp;plug (NEMA 5-15P) Less 
 Tundra Specialties Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-powdered-hot/7yEui4HucbA32evEefr-aw==/info Tundra Specialties $709.29 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/32/56/62/49687a4e6b79784335556e625643634d625651-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=15&amp;d;=2035.16&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB4M-5.5-LD-PC Space Saver Series Cecilware GB4M-5.5-LD-PC Space Saver Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78... More 

Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78 burst cap, lit. display, black texture finish, 1/4&quot; water with Portion Control Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb4m55ldpc/2VbIhzNkyxC5UnbVCcMbVQ==/info $2,035.16 No Shipping Info Visit Store -44% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/20/64/95/22057640-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+CS+3.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=16&amp;d;=376.4&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware CS-3 12-Cups Coffee Maker 
 Cecilware CS-3 12-Cups Coffee Maker Coffee Maker, Office, 12 Cups, 1800 Watts from $376.40 44% Off Free Shipping 2 stores See Details -48% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/63/70/79/6745375846522d45354639792d5a346c443851-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=17&amp;d;=1389.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/4PE Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/4PE Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/3PE four bowl 5.4 gallon... More 

Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/3PE four bowl 5.4 gallon premix cold beverage dispenser. At only 28 1/2&quot; wide, this 4 bowl premix cold beverage dispenser features four 5.4 gallon refrigerated bowls for long-lasting refreshment while sacrificing minimal countertop space! With the ability to set the dispenser for fast or gentle agitation to accommodate fruit juice and dairy products, it is perfect for serving fruit juice, iced tea, iced coffee, and other refreshingly chilled drinks. The Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/4PE beverage dispenser&apos;s 1/7 hp compressor that uses R134A refrigerant will keep your beverages chilled and ready for consumption for hours at a time. It requires a 120V electrical connection and is UL and NSF Listed. Dimensions Height: 26 1/2&quot; Width: 28 1/2&quot; Depth: 18 1/2&quot; Also known as 20-4PE, 20 4PE, and 204PE. 20/4PE From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-arctic-economy/cpygE7XFR-E5F9y-Z4lD8Q==/info The WEBstaurant Store $2,650.00 $1,389.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/37/34/33/5a4241576d596b5a7076456a6838716e554151-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=18&amp;d;=1645.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3M210W-LD-U 3 flavor cappuccino machine Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3M210W-LD-U 3 flavor cappuccino machine 
 ( In stock ) 
Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal SystemVSRS Ensures the powdered mix remains dry to... More 

Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal SystemVSRS Ensures the powdered mix remains dry to eliminate clogging, caking and bridging. Moisture&amp;Powder Collection Tray Prevents excess moisture&amp;product powder from reaching the vacuum motor. Direct Drive Auger System Ensures perfect hopper alignment&amp;silent running . PowerWhip Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. Self Cleaning Rinse system is touch button easy&amp;rinses the entire whipper chamber with hot water at the end of each cycle. Quick Change Transparency Simply lift up 2 tabs and pull out the graphic. Hopper Capacity:(2)10,(1) 5lbsTank Capacity: 3.2gallonsBurst Capacity 78Dimensions: 14 3/4&quot; x 22&quot; x 34&quot;Plumbing 1/4&quot; waterlineElectric al: 120V, 1.8KW, 15A Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/743ZBAWmYkZpvEjh8qnUAQ==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,645.25 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/32/5a/64/53495568504b566a704b492d66425364595541-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=19&amp;d;=1899.41&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB4M-5.5-W-LD Space Saver Series Cecilware GB4M-5.5-W-LD Space Saver Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78... More 

Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78 burst cap, lit. display, black texture finish, 1/4&quot; water with Hot Water Dispense Button Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb4m55wld/2ZdSIUhPKVjpKI-fBSdYUA==/info $1,899.41 No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/66/59/71/355653454d6a5f4a4734516f524b6430455141-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=20&amp;d;=1838.13&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware PIC-5 - Hot Chocolate/Cappuc cino Dispenser, Five Head Unit, 8 in Cup Clearance Cecilware PIC-5 - Hot Chocolate/Cappuc cino Dispenser, Five Head Unit, 8 in Cup Clearance 
 Hot Chocolate/Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 head unit, direct drive hoppers, 34-3/4&quot;H, 20-1/2&quot;W, 24-3/4&quot;D, 8&quot;cup clearance, 1-1/2 gallon drain tray, back lit merchandiser front, channel mounted side graphics, oversized push buttons, UL, NSF ( Cecilware - PIC-5 ) ( In stock ) 
Hot Chocolate/Cappucc ino Dispenser, 5 head unit, direct drive hoppers, 34-3/4&quot;H, 20-1/2&quot;W, 24-3/4&quot;D, 8&quot; cup clearance, 1-1/2 gallon drain tray, back lit merchandiser front, channel mounted... More 

Hot Chocolate/Cappucc ino Dispenser, 5 head unit, direct drive hoppers, 34-3/4&quot;H, 20-1/2&quot;W, 24-3/4&quot;D, 8&quot; cup clearance, 1-1/2 gallon drain tray, back lit merchandiser front, channel mounted side graphics, oversized push buttons, UL, NSF ( Cecilware - PIC-5 ) Less 
 KaTom Restaurant Supply 177 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-pic5-hot/fYq5VSEMj_JG4QoRKd0EQA==/info KaTom Restaurant Supply $3,588.00 $1,838.13 49% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/41/33/35/37496f313345484d5a6270686259756c647567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=21&amp;d;=4263.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB5M10-LD-RH Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,5 Flavor 12D148 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB5M10-LD-RH Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,5 Flavor 12D148 
 ( In stock ) 
Hot Beverage Dispenser, 5 Flavor, Capacity 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 18 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black, Holds (1)... More 

Hot Beverage Dispenser, 5 Flavor, Capacity 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 18 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black, Holds (1) 10 Lb. (4) 5 Lb., Includes Cappuccino Graphic, Standards Ul,nsf,cul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/A357Io13EHMZbphbYuldug==/info Grainger $4,263.00 +$78.00 shipping Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4f/73/63/68765036376a687541656e6f6762654a4f3877-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=22&amp;d;=1677.74&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware 3 Gallon Single Automatic Coffee Urn Cecilware 3 Gallon Single Automatic Coffee Urn 
 ( In stock ) 
Automatic Coffee Urn; Stainless steel construction; Single 3 gallon capacity; Brews in 1 lb batches; Adjustable by-pass; Automatic push button agitator; Cycle stop switch; Side mounted... More 

Automatic Coffee Urn; Stainless steel construction; Single 3 gallon capacity; Brews in 1 lb batches; Adjustable by-pass; Automatic push button agitator; Cycle stop switch; Side mounted control panel; Solid state timer&amp;new liquid level control system; 1/4&quot; water line required; Specify voltage when ordering; (3-phase voltage available); 120V/208V/60/1- ph; 26A/5,300W; 120V/240V/60/1- ph; 29A/7,000; 21.5&quot;W x 28.5&quot;H x 17.5&quot;D; One year parts &amp;labor warranty; ETL listed; NSF certified Less 
 Tundra Specialties Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-3-gallon-single/OschvP67jhuAenogbeJO8w==/info Tundra Specialties $1,677.74 No Shipping Info Visit Store -48% http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/6c/49/4135367a324255744b32494f4d6e32377a7877-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=23&amp;d;=1579.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD four bowl 5.4 gallon... More 

Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD four bowl 5.4 gallon premix cold beverage dispenser. Because each bowl has its own motor, the four bowls operate independently of one another so that you have greater control over your beverages. At only 28 1/2&quot; wide, this 4 bowl premix cold beverage dispenser features four 5.4 gallon refrigerated bowls for long-lasting refreshment while sacrificing minimal countertop space! With the ability to set the dispenser for fast or gentle agitation for juice or dairy beverages, it is perfect for serving three types of fruit juice, iced tea, iced coffee, and other refreshingly chilled drinks. The Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD beverage dispenser&apos;s 1/7 hp compressor that uses R134A refrigerant will keep your beverages chilled and ready for consumption for hours at a time. It requires a 120V electrical connection and is UL and NSF Listed. Dimensions Height: 26 1/2&quot; Width: 28 1/2&quot; Depth: 18 1/2&quot; Also known as 20-4PD, 20 4PD, and 204PD. 20/4PD From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-arctic-deluxe/PlIA56z2BUtK2IOMn27zxw==/info The WEBstaurant Store $3,008.00 $1,579.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/1c/00/d7/41077090-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+EL6.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=24&amp;d;=200.82&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware EL6 Deep Fryer 
 Cecilware EL6 Deep Fryer With Adjustable Thermostat, Without Filtration system from $200.82 49% Off Free Shipping 3 stores See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/33/72/6d/777839664857736e364148386453686d694677-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=25&amp;d;=2280.6&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB5M-210-LD-U Feature Flavor Series Cecilware GB5M-210-LD-U Feature Flavor Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 6.0 gal. water tank cap., (3)5lb.&amp;(2) 10lb hopper powder product cap. ea, 98... More 

Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 6.0 gal. water tank cap., (3)5lb.&amp;(2) 10lb hopper powder product cap. ea, 98 burst cap., lit. display, vertical lift door, black texture finish Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb5m210ldu/3rmwx9fHWsn6AH8dShmiFw==/info $2,280.60 No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ff/12/c5/55185818-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+JAVA+GIANT+2.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=26&amp;d;=2633.88&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware JAVA GIANT 2 
 Cecilware JAVA GIANT 2 $2,633.88 49% Off 1 store See Details http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/44/41/34/68435673546d7a507276544979583444423277-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=27&amp;d;=1556.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3P-LD Pourover 3 flavor dispenser Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3P-LD Pourover 3 flavor dispenser 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware cappuccino/hot chocolate dispenser machine Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal... More 

 Cecilware cappuccino/hot chocolate dispenser machine Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal SystemVSRS Ensures the powdered mix remains dry to eliminate clogging, caking and bridging. Moisture&amp;Powder Collection Tray Prevents excess moisture&amp;product powder from reaching the vacuum motor. Direct Drive Auger System Ensures perfect hopper alignment&amp;silent running . PowerWhip Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. Self Cleaning Rinse system is touch button easy&amp;rinses the entire whipper chamber with hot water at the end of each cycle. Quick Change Transparency Simply lift up 2 tabs and pull out the graphic. Hopper Capacity:(3)5 1/2lbsTank Capacity: 2 1/2 gallonsBurst Capacity 50Dimensions: 11&quot; x 22&quot; x 34&quot; Electrical: 120V, 1.8KW, 15A Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/DA4hCVsTmzPrvTIyX4DB2w==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,556.25 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/37/79/386874715831516477395466754b546d444751-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=28&amp;d;=1625.74&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB3M-10-LD-U Feature Flavor Series Cecilware GB3M-10-LD-U Feature Flavor Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 3 flavor manual disp. oper., vert. lift door, 8-1/2&quot;cup clearance, power whip, 3.2gal. water tank cap.,(2)5lb.&amp;(1)10lb powder prod. cap. hoppers,... More 

Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 3 flavor manual disp. oper., vert. lift door, 8-1/2&quot;cup clearance, power whip, 3.2gal. water tank cap.,(2)5lb.&amp;(1)10lb powder prod. cap. hoppers, 62 burst cap., lit. disp., blk txt fnsh, 1/4&quot; wtr Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb3m10ldu/67y8htqX1Qdw9TfuKTmDGQ==/info $1,625.74 No Shipping Info Visit Store -39% http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/59/41/56/565f66456f587153343348306371704d617051-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=29&amp;d;=164.57&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware Step-up Coffee Warmer Triple 8inx21inx15in SW3 Cecilware Step-up Coffee Warmer Triple 8inx21inx15in SW3 
 Step-Up Coffee Warmer15&quot;H x 21 D x 8&quot;W Triple warmer with manual controls Stainless steel body 120v/60/1 ( In stock ) Step-Up Coffee Warmer15&quot; H x 21 D x 8&quot; W Triple warmer with manual controls Stainless steel body 120v/60/1 Instawares, LLC 371 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-stepup-coffee/YAVV_fEoXqS43H0cqpMapQ==/info $270.00 $164.57 39% Off +$14.81 shipping Visit Store -49% http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/33/48/66/2d523453316d75693270432d4e763436574c41-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=30&amp;d;=2340.19&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB6M10LD-R/H - 6-Flavor Fast Flow Cappuccino Dispenser w/ 4.2-gal Capacity, 98-Burst 120 V Cecilware GB6M10LD-R/H - 6-Flavor Fast Flow Cappuccino Dispenser w/ 4.2-gal Capacity, 98-Burst 120 V 
 Destination Cappuccino Dispenser, fast flow, 6 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot;cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gallon water tank capacity, (1) 10lb&amp;(4) 5lb powder product capacity each, 98 burst capacity, lit. display, black texture finish, right hand door hinge, 1/4&quot;water (Cecilware) 120 V ( Cecilware - GB6M10LD-R/H ) ( In stock ) 
Destination Cappuccino Dispenser, fast flow, 6 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gallon water tank capacity, (1) 10lb&amp;(4) 5lb powder product capacity... More 

Destination Cappuccino Dispenser, fast flow, 6 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gallon water tank capacity, (1) 10lb&amp;(4) 5lb powder product capacity each, 98 burst capacity, lit. display, black texture finish, right hand door hinge, 1/4&quot; water (Cecilware) 120 V ( Cecilware - GB6M10LD-R/H ) Less 
 KaTom Restaurant Supply 177 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb6m10ldrh/3Hf-R4S1mui2pC-Nv46WLA==/info KaTom Restaurant Supply $4,568.00 $2,340.19 49% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/46/48/71/394474574d7958626e36647774663758727a51-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=31&amp;d;=12279.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 81010E Amw Twin Space Saver Urn 12D172 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 81010E Amw Twin Space Saver Urn 12D172 
 ( In stock ) 
Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 10 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 35 In., Depth 21-1/2 In., Height 37 In., Voltage 220, Amps 80, Watts 15000, Material Stainless Steel, Color... More 

Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 10 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 35 In., Depth 21-1/2 In., Height 37 In., Voltage 220, Amps 80, Watts 15000, Material Stainless Steel, Color Stainless Steel, Includes 25 Paper Filters, Standards Nsf, Ul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/FHq9DtWMyXbn6dwtf7XrzQ==/info Grainger $12,279.00 +$121.06 shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/d2/30/4f/109669636-100x100-0-0_grindmaster+fe200.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=32&amp;d;=1689.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Grindmaster FE200 
 Grindmaster FE200 from $1,689.00 3 stores See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/41/63/55/456e4f4263386f3449734f6963703469423567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=33&amp;d;=132.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Thermostat D1/d18, 100-200, Cecilware L029a, L029c, L029f, Hubbel P59060 Thermostat D1/d18, 100-200, Cecilware L029a, L029c, L029f, Hubbel P59060 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
 PART TYPE: THERMOSTAT D1/D18, 100-200 DEGREES CECILWARE: L029A, L029C HUBBEL: P59060 LIST PRICE: $144.00 DESCRIPTION: Thermostat, D1/D18, 100-200 Degrees, With Bezel&amp;Knob. Stuffing Box... More 

 PART TYPE: THERMOSTAT D1/D18, 100-200 DEGREES CECILWARE: L029A, L029C HUBBEL: P59060 LIST PRICE: $144.00 DESCRIPTION: Thermostat, D1/D18, 100-200 Degrees, With Bezel&amp;Knob. Stuffing Box. Cap 48&quot;, Bulb 3/8 x 5 3/4&quot; APPLICATIONS/Mode ls: CECILWARE: BC (1,2,240,301,302) (All after 7/92); CME-(10E, 15E), ME-(10E,15E); Series: AWB, CH, CL, CRS, FD, FE (Except FE1OOG), INS, MPO HUBBEL: Water Boosters where applicable Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /thermostat-d1d18/AcUEnOBc8o4IsOicp4iB5g==/info $132.95 +$14.91 shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4a/58/6b/5a715a785a4c386a34624b514954746e4d3367-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=34&amp;d;=274.5&amp;rt;=mr 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware AL-LEN Coffee Dispenser Model C Refurb Grindmaster- Cecilware AL-LEN Coffee Dispenser Model C Refurb 
 ( In stock ) 
Seller refurbished unit. Cecilware AL-LEN Model C Ground Coffee Dispenser. Quickly and easily enjoy freshly ground coffee in bulk without hassle or mess. Ideal for coarse ground to extended... More 

Seller refurbished unit. Cecilware AL-LEN Model C Ground Coffee Dispenser. Quickly and easily enjoy freshly ground coffee in bulk without hassle or mess. Ideal for coarse ground to extended yield coffee. The unit dispenses fresh grounds directly into a stainless steel cartridge cup. Included hopper holds up to 6 pounds of coffee at a time for added convenience. Create controlled portion sizes from 1.33 ounces up to 11 ounces. Dimensions: 18.5&quot;H x 9.25&quot;W x 9.25&quot;D MPN Model C Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/JXkZqZxZL8j4bKQITtnM3g==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $274.50 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/79/6e/44664943346f784a7930574c635361757a2d67-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=35&amp;d;=1812.53&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB3P-LD-SMT Pour Over Series Cecilware GB3P-LD-SMT Pour Over Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Pour Over Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 3 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 2.0 gal. water tank, 2.0 gal. reservoir cap., (3) hoppers w/4 lb. pdr product cap... More 

Pour Over Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 3 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 2.0 gal. water tank, 2.0 gal. reservoir cap., (3) hoppers w/4 lb. pdr product cap. ea., 22 burst cap., lit. display, black finish with Smartsense Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb3pldsmt/6ynDfIC4oxJy0WLcSauz-g==/info $1,812.53 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/37/31/37/575f324b66316a72444f396a73644a64463851-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=36&amp;d;=2579.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware GB5M-210-LD-U-PC Feature Flavor Series Cecilware GB5M-210-LD-U-PC Feature Flavor Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 6.0 gal. water tank cap., (3)5lb.&amp;(2) 10lb hopper powder product cap. ea, 98... More 

Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 6.0 gal. water tank cap., (3)5lb.&amp;(2) 10lb hopper powder product cap. ea, 98 burst cap., lit. display, vertical lift door, black texture finish with Portion Control Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware/717W_2Kf1jrDO9jsdJdF8Q==/info $2,579.25 No Shipping Info Visit Store -48% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/35/75/46/4a316f7055637262444b34764e663766643551-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=37&amp;d;=959.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 120V Single Phase Cecilware CME15EN 15 Gallon Chinese Hot Water Boiler 120V Single Phase Cecilware CME15EN 15 Gallon Chinese Hot Water Boiler 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
An excellent addition to any busy Chinese restaurant, this Cecilware CME15EN hot water boiler provides you with a convenient, affordable way of keeping piping hot water flowing for the... More 

An excellent addition to any busy Chinese restaurant, this Cecilware CME15EN hot water boiler provides you with a convenient, affordable way of keeping piping hot water flowing for the preparation of your hot teas, soups, and more! Crystal clear Chinese labeling makes operation a breeze for any Chinese-speaking employee, while an automatic refill system ensures you&apos;re never caught unprepared. A solid state liquid level control system provides added peace of mind. - Precise, multi-setting thermostat with hold setting - Dial thermometer for precise monitoring - Sleek, durable stainless steel body for long-lasting service - Reliable Tomlinson no-drip faucet prevents waste - Unit must be hardwired; a cord and plug are not included. Choose voltage. - Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details and installation requirements. Overall Dimensions: Left to Right: 18&quot; Front to Back: 19 3/4&quot; Height: 30 1/2&quot; CME15EN 120/1 From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /120v-single-phase/5uFJ1opUcrbDK4vNf7fd5Q==/info The WEBstaurant Store $1,838.00 $959.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/34/36/4b/2d5843325f4f7162416a3059516a7657754741-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=38&amp;d;=593.24&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware B-SGP 2401 - Automatic Dual 2.5-L Fresh Single Coffee Brewer for Thermal Server 120/240/1 V Cecilware B-SGP 2401 - Automatic Dual 2.5-L Fresh Single Coffee Brewer for Thermal Server 120/240/1 V 
 Precision Brew Coffee Brewer, for Thermal Server, fresh brew, automatic, digital controls, single brewer, brews into a 2.5 liter vacuum insulated gravity container (not included), dual voltage, stainless steel finish, NSF, (Grindmaster) 120/240/60/1 V ( Cecilware - B-SGP 2401 ) ( In stock ) 
Precision Brew Coffee Brewer, for Thermal Server, fresh brew, automatic, digital controls, single brewer, brews into a 2.5 liter vacuum insulated gravity container (not included), dual... More 

Precision Brew Coffee Brewer, for Thermal Server, fresh brew, automatic, digital controls, single brewer, brews into a 2.5 liter vacuum insulated gravity container (not included), dual voltage, stainless steel finish, NSF, (Grindmaster) 120/240/60/1 V ( Cecilware - B-SGP 2401 ) Less 
 KaTom Restaurant Supply 177 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-bsgp-2401/46K-XC2_OqbAj0YQjvWuGA==/info KaTom Restaurant Supply $1,158.00 $593.24 49% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/67/77/71/6c38757836455466456e4e3242697233694541-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=39&amp;d;=14888.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 87710E Amw Twin High Speed High Volume Urn 12D171 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 87710E Amw Twin High Speed High Volume Urn 12D171 
 ( In stock ) 
Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 10 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 46 In., Depth 21-1/2 In., Height 33-1/10 In., Voltage 220, Amps 80, Watts 15000, Material Stainless Steel, Color... More 

Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 10 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 46 In., Depth 21-1/2 In., Height 33-1/10 In., Voltage 220, Amps 80, Watts 15000, Material Stainless Steel, Color Stainless Steel, Includes 25 Paper Filters, Standards Nsf, Ul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/gwql8ux6ETfEnN2Bir3iEA==/info Grainger $14,888.00 +$121.06 shipping Visit Store -49% http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/19/dc/e6/38907867-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+CEC+BC302E+Coffee+Brew+Center+wWater+Tap.jpg?p=yVnUd3XP9V&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2003%3A52%3A47%20PM&amp;r;=40&amp;d;=1716.21&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cecilware BC302E-twin 36-Cups Coffee Maker 
 Cecilware BC302E-twin 36-Cups Coffee Maker Coffee Maker, Commercial, 36 Cups, 6300 Watts from $1,716.21 49% Off 2 stores See Details 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Parts 
 Preisvergleich. Angebot anzeigen. Bis zu 85% bei Produkten sparen 
 www.delupe.de/GeldSparen 
 
   
Related Guides:
 
 My Top Tried-and-Tested Shoes for Work and Play 
 by zoeleavitt Since feet are probably the pickiest part of your body,... 1 
 Dallas Cowboys 1994 Michael Irvin White Jersey With 75th Patch 
 by ospop If you are an avid football fan, you will probably have a... 0 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -47%
	</body>
</document>
