<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005874" url="http://www.tvguide.com/tvshows/the-league/episodes-season-3/299011" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="1" score="0.0004248644632816924" bingtitle="The League Episodes - The League Full Episode Guides from Season 3 ..." webtitle="The League Episodes - The League Full Episode Guides from Season 3 on FX | TVGuide.com">
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>... Taco competes in a jingle contest for a fast-food restaurant; Pete ... who wants Kevin and Jenny&apos;s wedding cocktail napkins ... Direction Mind: Conservative Site Mistakes Bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Follow Us on Twitter Android App iPhone App iPad App 
 Sign In Sign Out New User Sign Up Profile Management 
 Home What&apos;s on TV 
 TV Listings New Tonight Today&apos;s Live Sports Sports Listings Fall TV Schedule 2012 Summer TV Schedule Movies on Demand Soaps 
 Watchlist 
 Your Watchlist Celebrity Watchlists Friends&apos; Facebook Favorites Latest Tweets What is a Watchlist? 
 News 
 Today&apos;s News Fall Preview 2012 Fall TV Scorecard Summer TV News TV Guide Video Exclusives TV Show Recaps Jump The Shark 
 Sports 
 Today&apos;s Live Sports Sports Listings NCAA Basketball MLB NBA NHL 
 Full Episodes 
 Your Watchlist Online Video Guide 
 Photos 
 New Fall TV Shows 2012 TV Duos Pick &apos;Em Game Summer TV Summer Movies Red Carpet 
 Movies 
 Movies on TV Movies On Demand Summer Movie Premiere Calendar Trailers 
 TV Guide Network 
 TV Guide Network TV Guide Network Channel Locator TV Guide Network On Demand Top Infomercial Products 
 TV Guide Magazine 
 Matt Roush Keck&apos;s Exclusives The Biz Cheers&amp;Jeers Photos Videos Subscribe Media Kit 
 
 What&apos;s Hot TomKat Divorce Mega Buzz Daniel Tosh Apologizes for Rape Joke Celebrity Chef Dead at 29 Follow TheLeagueFX 
 The League Episodes on FX 

2009, TV Show
 
 Main Photos Videos TV Listings Episodes News Cast&amp;Details 
 Seasons: 
 1 
 The Shiva Bowl (Original Airdate Dec 10, 2009) The Usual Bet (Original Airdate Dec 3, 2009) Mr. McGibblets (Original Airdate Nov 19, 2009) Sunday at Ruxin&apos;s (Original Airdate Nov 12, 2009) The Bounce Test (Original Airdate Nov 5, 2009) The Draft (Original Airdate Oct 29, 2009) 
 2 
 The Sacko Bowl (Original Airdate Dec 9, 2010) Kegel the Elf (Original Airdate Dec 9, 2010) Ramona Neopolitano (Original Airdate Dec 2, 2010) High School Reunion (Original Airdate Nov 18, 2010) The Expert Witness (Original Airdate Nov 11, 2010) The Tie (Original Airdate Nov 4, 2010) Ghost Monkey (Original Airdate Oct 28, 2010) The Anniversary Party (Original Airdate Oct 21, 2010) The Marathon (Original Airdate Oct 14, 2010) The Kluneberg (Original Airdate Oct 7, 2010) The White Knuckler (Original Airdate Sep 30, 2010) Bro-Lo El Cunado (Original Airdate Sep 23, 2010) Vegas Draft (Original Airdate Sep 16, 2010) 
 3 
 The Funeral (Original Airdate Dec 22, 2011) St. Pete (Original Airdate Dec 22, 2011) The Guest Bong (Original Airdate Dec 15, 2011) The Light of Genesis (Original Airdate Dec 8, 2011) The Out of Towner (Original Airdate Dec 1, 2011) Thanksgiving (Original Airdate Nov 17, 2011) Carmenjello (Original Airdate Nov 10, 2011) Yobogoya! (Original Airdate Nov 10, 2011) Bobbum Man (Original Airdate Nov 3, 2011) Ol&apos; Smoke Crotch (Original Airdate Oct 27, 2011) The Au Pair (Original Airdate Oct 20, 2011) The Sukkah (Original Airdate Oct 13, 2011) The Lockout (Original Airdate Oct 6, 2011) 
 
 
 The League Season 3 episodes
 Dec 22, 2011: The Funeral 
 Dec 22, 2011: St. Pete 
 Dec 15, 2011: The Guest Bong 
 Dec 08, 2011: The Light of Genesis 
 Dec 01, 2011: The Out of Towner 
 Nov 17, 2011: Thanksgiving 
 Nov 10, 2011: Carmenjello 
 Nov 10, 2011: Yobogoya! 
 Nov 03, 2011: Bobbum Man 
 Oct 27, 2011: Ol&apos; Smoke Crotch 
 Oct 20, 2011: The Au Pair 
 Oct 13, 2011: The Sukkah 
 Oct 06, 2011: The Lockout 
 
 The Funeral Season 3, Episode 13

 Dec 22, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode The race is on for the Shiva and the Sacko Bowls in the Season 3 finale. Taco teams up with Chicago Bears RB Matt Forte, but one of the guys can&apos;t manage his team, leaving the League to figure out who&apos;ll run it for him. read more 
 
 St. Pete Season 3, Episode 12

 Dec 22, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Kevin and Jenny bet boldly on the playoffs; Taco wants Ruxin to get more involved with Taco Corp.; and Pete has a devilish plan to send Ruxin to the Sacko Bowl. read more 
 
 The Guest Bong Season 3, Episode 11

 Dec 15, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Pete&apos;s new girlfriend wants to help him with his team lineup; Kevin&apos;s past at the DA&apos;s office comes back to haunt him; Ruxin runs afoul of his company&apos;s e-mail policy; and autocorrect gets everybody in trouble. read more 
 
 The Light of Genesis Season 3, Episode 10

 Dec 8, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Kevin thinks his Krav Maga instructor (Eliza Dushku) might have feelings for him; Jenny tells Andre a secret; the guys must rescue Ruxin from a cult when Pete&apos;s prank backfires. read more 
 
 The Out of Towner Season 3, Episode 9

 Dec 1, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Chuck (Will Forte), a League player from out of town, visits and is not at all like what the guys remember him to be. Meanwhile, Kevin and Jenny get in over their heads with a drug dealer; and Taco goes on a radical diet. read more 
 
 Thanksgiving Season 3, Episode 8

 Nov 17, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Ruxin&apos;s father (Jeff Goldblum) shows up unexpectedly for Thanksgiving; Andre&apos;s sister (Sarah Silverman) is on the prowl at the gang&apos;s Thanksgiving dinner; Taco makes an edible investment; and Kevin and Jenny have a problem with the new family pet. read more 
 
 Carmenjello Season 3, Episode 7

 Nov 10, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Kevin and Jenny lack privacy; Sofia accuses Ruxin of &quot;breast favoritism&quot;; Pete tries to defend his high-school track record. read more 
 
 Yobogoya! Season 3, Episode 6

 Nov 10, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Jenny jeopardizes Ruxin&apos;s chance to work on a big case with his boss, Mr. Hudabega (Ray Liotta); Taco competes in a jingle contest for a fast-food restaurant; Pete nurses a grudge against a traffic cop. read more 
 
 Bobbum Man Season 3, Episode 5

 Nov 3, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Jenny forgets a special anniversary she shares with Kevin; Andre seeks lineup Nirvana; Taco sets up an offline social network he calls My Face; and the guys resurrect their old game of phone chicken and bring back Bobbum Man (to Kevin&apos;s dismay). read more 
 
 Ol&apos; Smoke Crotch Season 3, Episode 4

 Oct 27, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Kevin doesn&apos;t like the fact that he&apos;s getting older; a desperate Ruxin enlists Rafi to help him get rid of his au pair; Taco finds someone who wants Kevin and Jenny&apos;s wedding cocktail napkins; Pete learns a new sexual position, and regrets it. read more 
 
 The Au Pair Season 3, Episode 3

 Oct 20, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Ruxin hires a hot au pair (Brie Larson) for baby Geoffrey and fears that Taco will sleep with her; Andre explores online dating; and Kevin cheats on Jenny. ESPN fantasy-football guru Matthew Berry appears as himself. read more 
 
 The Sukkah Season 3, Episode 2

 Oct 13, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Draft day proves to be a bust for everyone, but no one trusts anyone else enough to make a trade. Meanwhile, Jenny goes back to work in real estate; and Ruxin tries to get baby Geoffrey into a Jewish preschool. read more 
 
 The Lockout Season 3, Episode 1

 Oct 6, 2011 episode details 

 Watch Episode Ruxin&apos;s reign (of terror) as league champion continues as Season 3 begins. But the guys are cooking up a grand plan for Andre&apos;s final Sacko Bowl punishment, with help from Rafi and Dirty Randy (Seth Rogen). read more 
 Are You Watching? Loading ... Advertisement 
 Cast&amp;Details 
 Premiered: October 29, 2009, on FX Rating: TV-MA User Rating: (70 ratings)
 Add Your Rating: Premise: Ensemble comedy about a disparate group of guys (and a gal) involved in a fantasy-football league. 
 
Cast
 Mark Duplass 
 Pete Stephen Rannazzisi 
 Kevin Nick Kroll 
 Ruxin Paul Scheer 
 Andre Jon Lajoie 
 Taco Katie Aselton 
 Jenny 
 more The League cast&amp;details 
Our Partners
 
 &apos;The Dark Knight Rises&apos; IMAX Poster: Bane Is Terrifying (PHOTO) PublishDate = 7/12/2012 12:54:42 PM &apos;Cosmopolis&apos; Trailer: Robert Pattinson Is Free In A Way He&apos;s Never Known (VIDEO) PublishDate = 7/12/2012 8:29:54 AM &apos;Django Unchained&apos;: Win A Limited Edition Comic-Con T-Shirt PublishDate = 7/11/2012 4:02:35 PM Vanilla Ice -- Britney&apos;s &apos;Ice, Ice Baby&apos; Dance was &apos;F**king Amazing&apos; PublishDate = 7/12/2012 4:00:00 PM Tom Cruise Didn&apos;t Settle Katie Holmes Divorce Because of Any &apos;Secrets&apos; PublishDate = 7/12/2012 2:56:00 PM &apos;Lost&apos; Star Dominic Monaghan -- &apos;Swamp People&apos; Is Cruel ... SHUT IT DOWN!!! PublishDate = 7/12/2012 1:55:00 PM African-American Reverend To Megyn Kelly: Obama Is Taking Black Vote For Granted PublishDate = 7/12/2012 7:50:46 PM Katie Couric Reacts To Odd New Role As Face Of Iraq’s Electricity Ministry: ‘I’m Calling My Lawyer… I’m Kidding’ PublishDate = 7/12/2012 7:45:48 PM 
 
Advertisement
 
Related Websites
 
You might be also interested in the following websites:

 The League Profile, Episodes, News, Cast&amp;Crew, Character Bios, Interviews, Videos, Forums, and Free Prizes at TVStar.com Check out The League at Inside Pulse The League news and spoilers @ Series and TV The League news at HollywoodChicago.com The League news episode guide and video at AceShowbiz.com 
 
Most Popular TV Shows
 
 American Idol NCIS Big Bang Theory Voice Person of Interest 
 more popular tv shows 
Most Popular Celebrities
 
 Rihanna Kim Kardashian Matthew McConaughey Katy Perry Kate Middleton 
 more popular celebrities 
Most Popular Movies
 
 The Amazing Spider-Man Ted Brave Savages Magic Mike 
 more popular movies 
Top Videos
 
 BEST NUDE SCENES EVER! Young and the Restless White Collar Pretty Little Liars The Bachelorette 
 more top videos 
 Help Media Kit Privacy Terms of Use Copyright Policy Lionsgate About Us Sitemap RSS Widgets Mobile
	</body>
</document>
