<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005081" url="http://www.ecrater.com/view-feedback.php?storeid=50863" time="2012-07-12-21:36" support="2" score="0.002389872480019723" bingtitle="Feedback reviews for kawaiibobo - eCRATER - online marketplace ..." webtitle="Feedback reviews for kawaiibobo">
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>... kind seller, worked with me through my order ... Outstanding seller, great items, nice prices, very fast shipping, the best! thanks: Kamio Japan Fast Food Restaurant Letter Set ...</description>
	<body>
		advanced search 
 
 
 
Seller: kawaiibobo 
 Feedback score: 99.98% 

 

 
   Overall Past Month Past Year 728 9 147 4 0 0 1 0 0 unrated 786 18 173 
 
 Comment Item(s) Date 
 
 I got everything fast and safe :) Peanuts Snoopy Letter Set with Stickers 2011 Kawai, etc. 07/12/2012 Very Prompt =] San-X Japan Mamegoma Letter Set with Stickers Kawa 07/11/2012 I love this shop and seller! Always great selection and price! Q-Lia Japan Sugar Clover Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 07/09/2012 Everything came in great condition! Lovely! Crux Japan Plum Rice Bowl Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 07/05/2012 Recommended seller: Lovely quality, fast shipping, good communication. Mind Wave Japan Yuru Bird Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 07/05/2012 Thanks. Fast shipping Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma Letter Set with Stickers 2 06/25/2012 loved it, long time getting here, worth the wait! Sanrio Japan Sugarbunnies Plush Strap by Taito (E), etc. 06/24/2012 Fantastic package and speedy shipping! Thank you. I will buy again! Kamio Japan Fluffy Hedgehog Memo Pad with Stickers, etc. 06/22/2012 all was great Active Japan Merry Christmas Dogs Sticker Sheet (B, etc. 06/21/2012 Hands down the best store for kawaii things! Will DEFINITELY be back! ^__^ Kamio Japan Animal Restaurant Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 06/21/2012 I loved the cute designs. Thank you!! Sanrio Japan Chi Chai Monchan Letter Set with Stic, etc. 06/06/2012 excellent seller.A++++++++++++++++++ Kamio Japan Fairy Tale World Epoxy Sticker Sheet (, etc. 06/05/2012 very good seller! Passport Japan Hannari Tofu on a Floatie Plush Cha 05/30/2012 excellent seller.A++++++++++++++++++++ P. Work Japan Summer Festival Epoxy Sticker Sheet , etc. 05/29/2012 yanna&apos;s store is fun to shop at! thanks, yanna! fast dlvy--pkg rec&apos;d 5/25/12 Crux Japan Thank You for Happiness Letter Set Kaw, etc. 05/25/2012 Great service as always :D Q-Lia Japan Soda Chan Memo Pad with Stickers Kawai 05/24/2012 Placed many orders and never disappointed~another awesome kawaii experience~will be back~THANK YOU!! Crux Japan Happy Clover Club Loose Memo Sheets Kaw, etc. 05/23/2012 this took about 2 weeks to come but it was well worth the wait, thankyou :) Q-Lia Japan Alphabets Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 05/23/2012 I love the Thanks Crux Kamio Q-Lia San-X Loose Memo Sheets Lot of 60, etc. 05/22/2012 Item received intact and seller very helpful. Pool Cool Japan Funny Tea Time Letter Set with Sti 05/21/2012 fast shipping thanks San-X Japan Iiwaken Letter Set (B) 2010 Kawaii, etc. 05/21/2012 Super fast shippment, excellent communication and auper, super cute Nyanko!! San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Burger Series Bur 05/19/2012 Thank You So Much!!! My sister and I love everything. THANKS A LOT for the Free Gift. Crux Japan Stars and Friends 2-Section Memo Pad wi, etc. 05/17/2012 Received items, thank you very much! San-X Japan Mamegoma Sweets Factory Memo Pad with , etc. 05/17/2012 Everything perfect, wonderful seller! Korino Japan Jellyfish Plush Charm Strap (B) Kawai 05/14/2012 the transaction was simple an easy Crux Japan Natto Chan Glitter Sticker Sheet Rare K 05/14/2012 I love everything! I message you about wanting to buy again. More memo pads and loose sheets :D Crux Japan Water Drops Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 05/10/2012 I love the sticker ^^ Thanks Kamio Japan Nyanko Princess Sticker Sack Kawaii 05/06/2012 This is my 5th time ordering. Very fast shipping, Items well packaged, no complaints here!!! Sanrio Japan Jewelpet Letter Set with Stickers 201, etc. 05/05/2012 excellent seller.A++++++++++++++++++++++ Mind Wave Japan Monster Parade Sticker Sheet Kawai, etc. 05/01/2012 excellent seller.A++++++++++++++++++++++ Pool Cool Japan Takoyaki Puffy Sticker Sheet Kawai, etc. 05/01/2012 I love Kawaiibobo Mind Wave Japan Bear&apos;s Cocoa Letter Set with Stick, etc. 04/30/2012 Items as decribed and thanks for the freebies!!!! San-X Japan Bird and Sakura Washi Paper Sticker Sa, etc. 04/29/2012 Received my order quickly and communication was great! I love your store!!! Kawaii heaven!! Tanpopo Japan Panda Snacks Bubble Sticker Sheet Ka, etc. 04/28/2012 i love my itmes fast shipment great transaction Mind Wave Japan PacoPaco Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 04/27/2012 Everything was wonderful! Kamio Japan Dolly Hamster Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 04/26/2012 love my item Daiso Japan Panda Mart Fancy Long Memo Sheets Kawa 04/25/2012 Thank you! :) Japan Mind Wave Berry Bear Mini Memo Pad, etc. 04/25/2012 Thank you! ^.^ Kamio Japan Strawberry Soda Chan Mini Memo Pad Kaw, etc. 04/24/2012 Awesome seller! Great selection of hard to find items! Kamio Japan Charming Pops Mini Memo Pad (B) Kawaii, etc. 04/20/2012 Fast shipping, packaged well. Thanks! Kamio Japan Rainbow Friends Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 04/18/2012 Loved everything, and everything came so quick! Q-Lia Japan Hannari Tofu Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 04/16/2012 ~*Pandalicious Love*~soOoOoOOOOOooo kawaii~thank you for offering such amazing kawaii products!!!!!! Kamio Japan Homemade Panda Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 04/15/2012 Amazing!!! ~*in kawaii heaven!!*~ DOMO ARIGATO Crux Japan Lovely Animal Friends Memo Pad with Sti, etc. 04/13/2012 Fast shipping and great item! Thank you! San-X Japan Jewel Cat Memo Pad with Stickers (B) 2 04/12/2012 Excellent Ecrater Shop and Seller..always sends quickly and purchases are wonderful.. Q-Lia Japan Tiny Cafe Mini Envelopes with Stickers, etc. 04/11/2012 Quick shipping! Thank you ^_^ Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Dango Mascot Charm Strap , etc. 04/11/2012 Awesome seller, great selection of hard to find items! Pool Cool Japan Happy Present Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 04/10/2012 Awesome seller great selection of hard to find items! Crux Japan Chocolatte Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 04/10/2012 I liked everything I ordered. Sanrio Japan Chococat Sticker Sack 2005 Kawaii, etc. 04/01/2012 Quick shipment! Items as described! Sanrio Japan Chibimaru Letter Set with Stickers in, etc. 04/01/2012 Lovely Kamio Japan Alpaca Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 03/31/2012 Everything arrived as said and look exactly like pictures. Love them! Crux Japan Bear&apos;s Sweet Home Letter Set with Stick, etc. 03/22/2012 always a pleasure to shop at kawaiibobo! pkg rec&apos;d fast--3/22/12 Kamio Japan Tiny Kittens Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 03/22/2012 Everything arrived as said and look exactly like pictures. Love them! Mind Wave Japan Cat Melody Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 03/21/2012 Thank you! :) Kamio Japan Mogo Mogo Rabi Memo Pad with Stickers 03/21/2012 fast shipping and great communication. Q-Lia Japan Happy Fairy Story Jewel Sticker Sack K, etc. 03/19/2012 arrived very quickly, thank you! San-X Japan Sentimental Circus Mini Memo Pad (C) 2, etc. 03/19/2012 SUPER GREAT! Sanrio Licensed My Melody Christmas Sticker Sheet 03/18/2012 just got it today awesome condition thank you! Mind Wave Japan La Petite Chambre Letter Set with , etc. 03/16/2012 great lovely fast shipping!! Kamio Japan Panda Burger 3-Section Coupon Memo Pad, etc. 03/15/2012 Great~ San-X Japan Tarepanda Letter Set with Stickers 200, etc. 03/15/2012 Delivered in a timely manner and looked just as described. Very cute Lemon Japan Cafe Style I Love Cafe Time Letter Set 03/13/2012 quick shipment, everything as described Crux Japan Happy Sandwich Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 03/12/2012 yanna is a great ecrater seller! pkg rec&apos;d fast--3/8/12 Pool Cool Japan Twin Pandas Puffy Sticker Sheet Ka, etc. 03/08/2012 Items as described and I enjoyed the freebies!!! Kamio Japan Happy Foods Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 03/07/2012 Ecellent Ecrater Seller.. always ships fast and has great items.. Thank you so much!! San-X Japan Mamegoma Mini Letter Set with Stickers, etc. 03/06/2012 Everything arrived as said. Love them! Crux Japan Rainbow Droplets Sticker Sack Kawaii 03/05/2012 got here very quickly! Mind Wave Japan Puch Matryoshka Sticker Sheet Kawa 03/01/2012 Amazing! Best kawaii selection available! Very sweet person!! Thank you!! Mind Wave Japan Spooky School Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 02/29/2012 lovely product fast delivery a+++ seller San-X Japan Sabokappa Plush Keychain (B) 2008 Kawa 02/29/2012 Items as described, fast shipping and free sticker sack!!! Mind Wave Japan Monster Night Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 02/28/2012 4th time ordering&amp;As always, Extremely fast shipping, Products packaged safely. Thank you♥ Pool Cool Japan Brilliant Girls Erasers in Case Ka, etc. 02/25/2012 great lovely fast shipping!! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Where&apos;s Joey Mini Memo Pa, etc. 02/24/2012 As always, a pleasure to order from. Fast shipping, friendly. Thanks for the treats. Sanrio Japan Chi Chai Monchan Letter Set with Stic, etc. 02/21/2012 fast delivery from US and great packaging, a pleasure to deal with LAM Planning Vegetable Plush Strap New with Tag Ka 02/18/2012 great lovely fast shipping!! Q-Lia Japan We Love Sweets Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 02/16/2012 Your shop is awsome Kamio Japan Panda on Food Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii 02/15/2012 Item as described, fast shipping, seller always adds more items often!!! Mind Wave Japan Summer Piece Seal Sticker Sack (A), etc. 02/13/2012 Super fast shipping and adorable items, Thank you so much. =) San-X Japan Wanco Tenshi Chihuahua Loose Memo Shee, etc. 02/07/2012 Items as decribed and fast shipping!!! San-X Japan Kiiroitori with Heart Plush Keychain S, etc. 02/02/2012 Excellent Crux Japan Dolly Princess Memo Pad with Stickers K 01/31/2012 Love it Crux Japan Fruits Girls 3-Section Coupon Memo Pad 01/31/2012 Fabulous Crux Japan Powerful Girls Book-Shaped Memo Pad wit, etc. 01/31/2012 Have bought many times from this Seller; always happy with purchase ... ARIGATO!!!! Crux Japan Magical Myu Chan Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 01/30/2012 Item as described and I am glad you had this memo because I have been looking for it!!! Kamio Japan Jelly Friends Memo Pad with Stickers K 01/28/2012 Love it Crux Japan Girls Type Tabbed Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 01/25/2012 I LOVE KAWAIIBOBO~~ Great seller, great packaging, great item!! I am a regular customer!! A+++ Banana Brand Japan Bees and Flowers Epoxy Sticker , etc. 01/23/2012 great seller thanks Kamio Japan Fairy Tale World Mini Memo Pad (O) Kaw, etc. 01/22/2012 Super fast shipping thanks a bunch... I&apos;ll buy from you again.... Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Japan Only Sticker Sack ( 01/21/2012 I like it. Thank you very much. San-X Japan Sabokappa Heart Cactus Plush with Scen 01/21/2012 As always, very happy with seller, transaction! Korino Japan Jellyfish Plush Charm Strap (A) Kawai 01/18/2012 Awesome. Kamio Japan Fairy Tale World Mini Memo Pad (M) Kaw 01/11/2012 Super cute items! Very fast shipping. Thank you! Daiso Japan Panda&apos;s Cafe Memo Pad with Stickers Ka, etc. 12/30/2011 Thank you Kamio Japan Little Happy Holidays Loose Memo Sheet, etc. 12/25/2011 very nice and quick. thanks from germy Kamio Japan Happy Sakura Days Letter Set with Post, etc. 12/25/2011 Quickly shipped and well-wrapped. Super cute items! Thank you! Q-Lia Japan Happy Fruits Puffy Sticker Sheet Rare , etc. 12/23/2011 Thank you Rement Japan Kyoto Love Sweets Desserts Miniatures, etc. 12/20/2011 Everything perfect -- always a pleasure to shop here! Passport Japan Hannari Tofu Limited Edition Plush , etc. 12/16/2011 Yanna is a wonderful seller! very kind, courteous. Thank you, Yanna! pkg rec&apos;d 12/15/11 Q-Lia Japan Kawaii Animals Hard Gel Sticker Sheet , etc. 12/15/2011 They are cute! Thanks so much Q-Lia Japan Joyful March Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 12/12/2011 Great item communication and fast shipping Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Squirrel Mascot Charm Str 12/08/2011 2nd time buying. Excellent again! Items arrived in less than 3 days. Pool Cool Japan Rabi Cafe Erasers in Case Kawaii, etc. 12/05/2011 Wonderful transaction! I loved my stickers! Thanks a bunch! :) Kamio Japan Soda Vending Machine Jewel Sticker Sac 12/04/2011 Thank you Rement Japan Farm House Miniatures Complete Set of, etc. 11/28/2011 Items just as described. Fast shipping n a free gift! Sanrio Japan Kuririn Hamster Mascot Charm Zipper P, etc. 11/26/2011 Amazing, as always! Kamio Japan Cutie Ring Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 11/24/2011 Great items, arrived quickly. Excellent seller! Active Japan Merry Christmas Epoxy Sticker Sheet (, etc. 11/23/2011 super nice seller! Yanna has awesome kawaii treats. pkg rec&apos;d fast--11/16/11 Lemon Japan Sweet Animals Puffy Sticker Sheet Kawa, etc. 11/16/2011 Very fast shipping, and packaged super well!! Thanks a ton!!! Sanrio Japan Cinnamoroll Letter Set with 2 Sheets 11/08/2011 Hi! Do you have express mail? it is the one that gets to people&apos;s houses in 3 to 5 days if you do Sanrio Japan Baby Cinnamon Cinnamoroll Spiral Note, etc. 10/30/2011 great sight and went well Lemon Japan Happy Wanco Long Erasers Set of 2 Kawa, etc. 10/30/2011 all is good San-X Japan Cute Puppies Microstickers Sticker She, etc. 10/25/2011 all is good Kamio Japan Corgi Bakery Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 10/25/2011 Received very quickly in perfect condition. Thanks! LAM Planning Steamed Bun Plush Strap New with Tag 10/11/2011 all is good Active Japan Merry Christmas Dogs Sticker Sheet (B 10/10/2011 Thank you Rement Japan Snacks Shop Miniatures Complete Set o 10/09/2011 quick! Mind Wave Japan Animal Matryoshka Sticker Sheet Ka 10/05/2011 ultra recommended! loved items, service and super fast shipping! thank you Yanna! Kamio Japan Happy Foods Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 10/03/2011 Excellent! Fast Shipping, Exactly as ordered, will buy again. Q-Lia Japan Pop n Bear Letter Set with Stickers Ka, etc. 09/30/2011 Arrived in excellent condition. Game Boy Advance Advance Wars 2 Black Hole Rising 09/22/2011 brilliant as always :) xx Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma Variety Sticker Strip with, etc. 09/20/2011 Super Cute Notepad! Crux Japan Party Time Is Coming Memo Pad with Stic 09/19/2011 Very, very happy w seller&amp;purchase!!!! San-X Japan Mikan Bouya Plush Cell Phone Strap Kaw, etc. 09/19/2011 Love it Q-Lia Japan Hamu Hamu Hamster Sticker Album Kawaii 09/17/2011 Excelent Purchase !! Thanks Sanrio Japan Winki Pinki Letter Set with Stickers 09/16/2011 fast shipping, great item, accurate description. A+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ seller San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Cat Dim Sum Serie 09/15/2011 Very fast dlvy, awesome kawaii selections! pkg rec&apos;d 9/15/11 Crux Japan Sugar Time Doll Memo Pad with Stickers , etc. 09/15/2011 Product as advertised --- thanks Iwako Japan Panda Diecut Eraser (Yellow) Kawaii 09/12/2011 Really kind seller, worked with me through my order errors. Youmec Japan Kuma Restaurant 3-Section Coupon Memo, etc. 09/11/2011 Product was as described. Seller was informative about shipping time. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Angel Business Card Holde 08/31/2011 Adorable, and fast shipping! Thanks so much! Morning Glory Korea Cats Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 08/27/2011 As usual, always satisfied with my transactions. Thank you! Daiso Japan Mr. Cafe Au Lait Letter Set with Stick, etc. 08/26/2011 Super fast shipping and great product. Highly recommended. Thank you so much! Q-Lia Japan Moonlight Story Book-Shaped Memo Pad K, etc. 08/25/2011 Thank you, again, for having this cool online store!! pkg rec&apos;d fast--8/25/11 Kamio Japan Animal Concert Candy Seal Sticker Shee, etc. 08/25/2011 Fast shipping, quick replies, perfect! Will buy again :) San-X + Green Camel Japan Nagomimakuri Plush Strap, etc. 08/23/2011 fast shipping great seller! San-X Japan Nyanko Cat Nyanko Burger Loose Letter , etc. 08/21/2011 ALl these are soo cool!!! Mind Wave Japan Happy Medical Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 08/19/2011 It&apos;s pretty cool. San-X Japan Tottemo Kantankun Very Simple Letter S 08/19/2011 Super cute! Kamio Japan Panda Mart Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 08/15/2011 This is cute!!!!! Love it Crux Japan Panda Post Letter Set with Stickers and 08/02/2011 Great stuff! Crux Japan IQ Laboratory Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 08/02/2011 fast shipping Passport Japan Hannari Tofu Plush in Container (Pi 08/01/2011 Fast shipping! Thank you! Passport Japan Hannari Tofu Plush in Container (Wh, etc. 07/29/2011 My daughter&apos;s delighted Pool Cool Japan Sweetfull Bear Notebook Kawaii, etc. 07/17/2011 ^.^ Recieved order today! Was caught off guard with extras. o-o; Loved everything! Wonderful seller! Wizard Japan Ham Ham Party Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 07/16/2011 This is one of my favorite Kawaii characters and I love, love, love the dark stuff San-X Japan Sentimental Circus Letter Set (A) 2010, etc. 07/15/2011 These are cute!! I love Chocolate Bear, well I love anything Kawaii. Crux Japan Chico&apos;s Story Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 07/15/2011 Loved everything I received. Thank you so much Kamio Japan Happy Noodle Bowls Mini Memo Pad Kawai, etc. 07/11/2011 Thank you so much for the fast shipping :) I LOVE my new plushies :) thank you for the Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma with Sugar Cube Plush (C) , etc. 07/08/2011 Good quality! Very cute! Some adorable extras sent along. Very happy. :) Kamio Japan Happy Seals Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/05/2011 great Crux Japan Funky Doku Rock Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/05/2011 Excellent quality and the shiping is fast. Will buy from the seller again 100%. Crux Japan Bear Burger Shop Box Erasers Set Kawaii, etc. 07/05/2011 Super quick service, thank you! Hallmark Japan Summer Festival 3D Card with Envelo 07/04/2011 +++ Perfect Transaction! +++ Thank you! +++ Kamio Japan Caramel Pop Letter Set with Stickers K, etc. 07/01/2011 Very nice seller! Sent pkg out fast. items rec&apos;d 7/1/11 Crux Japan Cute Sweets Marshmallow Puffy Sticker S, etc. 07/01/2011 Always PERFECT! Excellent seller! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty and Teddy Bear Letter Set 06/28/2011 Item arrived in perfect condition and quickly. Keep well informed of order progress. Thank you Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Flower Plush New with Tag 06/28/2011 Received it yesterday. They are awesome. Kamio Japan Happy Memorial Sky Letter Set Kawaii 06/26/2011 I love shopping at Yanna&apos;s store! So much fun! Thank you, Yanna! pkg rec&apos;d 6/25/11 Lemon Japan Fruit Girls Block Mini Sticker Sheet K, etc. 06/25/2011 Quick shipping, wonderful products! Extra gift included. AMAZING. Very thankful for such quality! Crux Japan Funny Punch Funny Friends Mini Memo Pad, etc. 06/23/2011 Great products! Fast shipping! Thanks! Maruneko Club Japan Birthstone Series Mini Plush S, etc. 06/23/2011 Favourite seller ever!!! Will always recommend Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty and Friends Prism Sticker, etc. 06/21/2011 This set is cute too Daiso Japan Happy Sunny Days Letter Set with Stick 06/20/2011 These sets are super cute too Crux Japan Little Sweet Girl Letter Set with Stick, etc. 06/20/2011 This set is super cute. Arroved promptly. Crux Japan Cheerful Bear Letter Set with Stickers 06/20/2011 This is a cute letter set. Except I didn&apos;t see the exact amount of envelopes in the package... Q-Lia Japan I Love Pancake Letter Set with Sticker 06/17/2011 Fast and reliable! Sanrio Japan Tokidoki for Hello Kitty Small Spiral 06/14/2011 This letter set is cute. Perfectly secured and packed in a tight envelope. Kamio Japan Healing Days Letter Set with Stickers 06/14/2011 Excellent Ecrater Shop.. love to buy from here.. highly recommended shop! Great items!Awesome Seller Kamio Japan Happy Ice Cream Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 06/13/2011 Memo pad was gorgeous, came in PERFECT condition! Great seller! Kamio Japan Awawa Chan Memo Pad with 3D Cover Kawa 06/12/2011 LOVE this seller, I&apos;m a returning happy customer :-) Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Glitter Sticker Sheet 200, etc. 06/12/2011 Very happy with seller, purchase!!!! Bread Plush Charm Keychain Strap Lot of 3 Kawaii, etc. 06/09/2011 This came in a box. Safely bubble wrapped items. Fast shipping. Q-Lia Japan Black Candy&apos;s Letter Set with Stickers, etc. 06/08/2011 As usual, wonderful seller. Thanks! =) San-X Japan Nyanko Cat Peach Plush New with Tag 20, etc. 06/07/2011 I&apos;ve been a frequent buyer. The orders always arrive on time, neat package! Very happy w/ kawaiibobo San-X Japan Suki to issyo Loose Letter Set (Elepha, etc. 06/07/2011 Fast shipping. Friendly service. Great products. Love this place. Now, just waiting on my refund. Q-Lia Japan Happy Mushrooms Letter Set with Sticke, etc. 06/06/2011 Came quickly - looked for this item for a long time - couldnt find. Got it at the web site right aw San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Cat Hot Dog Plush 06/06/2011 These 2 items finally came in. Tightly packaged and arrived in a short time! Great! Kamio Japan Frank&apos;s Cake&amp;Cafe Letter Set with St, etc. 06/04/2011 Perfect! Excellent seller, excellent product. Thank you so much! I´m sure I´ll be back. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Mini Letter Set with Stic, etc. 05/24/2011 Woo i love them^^ it only took 5 day! didn&apos;t think it would get here that fast^^ Best serves!!! Sanrio Japan Chococat Nail Stickers 2005 Kawaii 05/23/2011 ALWAYS super wonderful! Thanks again love the plush! : ) San-X Japan Nyanko Cat Student Plush New with Tag , etc. 05/23/2011 Thanks for fast shipping! Kamio Japan Happy House Friends Sticker Sack Kawai, etc. 05/17/2011 Very happy with seller, purchase!!!! Passport Japan Hannari Tofu Santa Plush Keychain S, etc. 05/11/2011 Received in good time and as described, thank you! LAM Planning Strawberry Plush Strap (B) New with T 05/11/2011 Very fast shipping, great seller! Kamio Japan Pop Magic Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 05/10/2011 Arrived very quickly, very happy with the products. Overall exceptional, will definatly buy again :) San-X + Green Camel Japan Mamegoma in Boot PVC Mas, etc. 05/09/2011 came in quickly, kawaii :3 Crux Japan Rainbow Droplets Tabbed Memo Pad Kawaii 05/08/2011 AWSOME! Really quick delivery, well wrapped up and perfect condition. thank you. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty and Strawberry Sticker Sh 05/04/2011 Love these cute erasers! I recieved the order very quickly Lemon Japan Hamster Erasers in Case Set of 4 Kawai, etc. 05/03/2011 Amazing seller, quality products and unbelievably fast shipping. Doesn&apos;t get any better than this!! Q-Lia Japan Candy Dolls Epoxy Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 05/03/2011 Love the color of what the envelopes look like, the packaging was perfectly wrapped. GOOD Q-Lia Japan The Bear is Loved Letter Set with Stic 05/02/2011 fast shipment, thank you very much Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Matryoshka Memo Pad (B) 2, etc. 05/02/2011 Very good Sanrio Japan Mashumaromitaina Spiral Notebook 2007 05/02/2011 Received. Thank you very much! Q-Lia Japan Hannari Tofu Diecut Mini Memo Pad (Yel, etc. 05/02/2011 a super ecrater seller! Thank you kindly for everything. pkg rec&apos;d 4/28/11 Q-Lia Japan I Love Cat Letter Set with Stickers Ka, etc. 04/28/2011 Great as always. Will buy from again :) Lemon Japan Animal Friends Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 04/23/2011 Excellent seller, Excellent communication,Excellent pacakaging,Fast shipping,Will purchase again Pool Cool Japan Animal Clinic Puffy Sticker Sheet , etc. 04/22/2011 LOVE THEM! Great Seller! Great Transaction! Thanks! Sanrio Japan Badtz-Maru Keroppi Cinnamoroll Mini S, etc. 04/16/2011 Excellent seller,Excellent communication,Excellent packaging,,Will purchase again,, Kamio Japan Cat&apos;s Restaurant Puffy Sticker Sheet K, etc. 04/11/2011 Has the cutest and most unique items. Love it!! Crux Japan Bunny&amp;Squirrel Sweet Cakes Mini Memo , etc. 04/11/2011 Excellent Ecrater Shop.. love to buy from here.. highly recommended shop! Great items!Awesome Seller Mind Wave Japan Usacolle Friends Puffy Sticker She, etc. 04/09/2011 I loved both of the cute designs. Thank you!! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty and Friends Letter Set wi, etc. 04/04/2011 A+++++ seller!! Japan Pucca Chocolate Letter Set with Stickers Kaw, etc. 04/02/2011 Great seller, great communciation, fab items-many thaks! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Angel Business Card Holde, etc. 03/30/2011 Great seller!! Crux Japan Tissue San Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 03/28/2011 I am positive to make the order. San-X Japan Street Scene Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 03/27/2011 Thank you! Mind Wave Japan Bugs Popo Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 03/25/2011 A perfect eCrater seller! Thank you for everything! pkg rec&apos;d fast--3/24/11 Crux Japan Babyangel Animals Sticker Sheet with St, etc. 03/24/2011 My order got here so fast and in great condition. Very Happy. Kawaiibobo is great! Kamio Japan Onigiri Friends Sticker Sack Kawaii 03/19/2011 Super fast shipping yet again. Thank You. Kamio Japan Fluffy Hedgehog Memo Pad with Stickers, etc. 03/05/2011 Everything as described, adorably packaged, fast shipping, would buy again. Thanks! Kamio Japan Soda Vending Machine Jewel Sticker Sac, etc. 03/03/2011 FANTASTIC SELLER!!!! Can&apos;t wait to buy again! :) San-X Japan Kamonohashikamo Hedgehog Plush Keychai, etc. 03/02/2011 Awesome products...great shipping...love it! Crux Japan Love Love Melody Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 03/01/2011 Super fast shipping! Thank You :) San-X Japan Kogepan Cup of Soup Memo Pad with Stic, etc. 02/27/2011 It is always a pleasure to shop at this store. Yanna is great! fast dlvy--pkg rec&apos;d 2/25/11 Kamio Japan Happy Lucky Sticker Sheet from Memo Pa, etc. 02/25/2011 Excellent seller,great communication and great packaging, Q-Lia Japan Cork Seal Happy Animals Sticker Sheet , etc. 02/24/2011 +++ Perfect Transaction! +++ Thank you! +++ Lemon Japan Dogs and Cats Puffy Mini Sticker Sheet, etc. 02/23/2011 Arrived very quickly! So cute and such a good deal!! Thank you!! San-X Japan Strawberry Yogurt Kun Mascot Charm Zip 02/19/2011 Kawaii LooOooOoOve x 4 = amazing memos; amazing seller ... *~THANK YOU!!!!~* San-X Japan Mamegoma Sweets Factory Memo Pad with , etc. 02/12/2011 Really great! Highly recommend! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Magnet Trinket 2010 Kawai 02/10/2011 Received item. Great seller, thank you so much! Pool Cool Japan Strawberry Foods Sticker Sack Kawa 02/09/2011 Great products and fast shipping. Kamio Japan Lovely Dogs Stamp Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 02/07/2011 so nice to deal with! Thank you for everything! pkg rec&apos;d fast--2/7/11 Crux Japan Plum Cats Memo Pad with Stickers Kawaii, etc. 02/07/2011 Very fast delivery and good service! Highly recommended - thanks! Pool Cool Japan Milky Bear Mini Memo Pad Kawaii 02/06/2011 good communication - great item - recommended Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Angel Business Card Holde 02/04/2011 THANK YOU sOooOo much for my kawaii goodies ... and xtras too!!!... so much, oh my!!! ~*Sweet*~ San-X Japan Mamegoma Sticker Sack (D) 2007 Kawaii, etc. 02/03/2011 great purchase as always San-X Japan Kamonohashikamo and Chicks Plush New w 02/02/2011 +++ Perfect Transaction! +++ Thank you! +++ Lemon Japan Happy Food Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 02/01/2011 +++ Perfect Transaction! +++ Thank you! +++ Pool Cool Japan Strawberry Cake Sticker Sack Kawai 02/01/2011 FAST service, A+ items! I&apos;m 100% happy and would buy here again! :) Sanrio Japan Deery Lou Pink Mini Sticker Sheet Kaw, etc. 01/31/2011 Good Pineapple Panda PVC Keychain Cell Phone Strap Kawa, etc. 01/28/2011 Perfect !! thank you so much from France :) I am very happy ! Onsen Manju Vinyl Coin Bank New in Box Kawaii 01/28/2011 Great product, timely delivery! Mind Wave Japan Cat Faces Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 01/24/2011 Reliable. San-X Japan Mamegoma Mini Plush Strap Kawaii 01/23/2011 Perfect transaction! Will buy from again. Thank you very much! A++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++ San-X Japan Momo Flying Squirrel Plush Tissue Box 01/21/2011 Excellent products, I wait refund ship, thanks!!! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Ehime Regional Diecut Mem, etc. 01/18/2011 great Crux Japan Happy Sandocchi Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 01/15/2011 The Best Excellent Seller, Excellent packaging&amp;Excellent communication,Excellent Items,A+++++++++, Q-Lia Japan Cork Seal Colorful Bears Sticker Sheet, etc. 01/14/2011 Great seller. Game Boy Advance GBA Kingdom Hearts Chain of Memor 01/14/2011 Thank you for the cute stuff!!! :-D Kamio Japan Fusen Kumachan Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 01/14/2011 Excellent Ecrater Seller..love to shop here..has so many cute items always to buy from..Thank you Crux Japan Wonderful Burger Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 01/13/2011 Great packaging! Eikoh Japan Onsen Manju Plush in Box (D) Kawaii 01/13/2011 got it on time Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Pattern Loose Letter Set , etc. 01/12/2011 the friend I gave it to loved it! Thanks! Korino Jellyfish Plush Strap (B) New with Tag Kawa 01/11/2011 great transaction always a pleasure to do buisness with :) Maruneko Club Japan Christmas Plush (Christmas Tre 01/10/2011 pkg rec&apos;d 1/3/11. Yanna has awesome kawaii selections! Thank you so much! Q-Lia Japan Whipped Cream Sticker Sheet from Memo , etc. 01/03/2011 Excellent seller, I recommend 100 %!!! (Brazil) Sanrio Japan My Melody Stationery Letter Set with , etc. 01/01/2011 so cute thank you great seller :) San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko On A Stick Plush 01/01/2011 Arrived much more quickly than expected! Thanks! Kamio Japan Happy Polar Bear Letter Set Kawaii 12/28/2010 Excellent seller,perfect packaging,Fast ship,great communication,Will purchase again,, A+ Q-Lia Japan Cork Seal Cupcake Animals Sticker Shee, etc. 12/26/2010 Great items, and speedy delivery. Will buy from again. Thanks! Passport Japan Hannari Tofu Mini Plush Strap (Gree, etc. 12/21/2010 Thank you again for this wonderful assortment of kawaii goodies! pkg rec&apos;d 12/16/10 Q-Lia Japan Cream Sisters 3-Section Coupon Memo Pa, etc. 12/16/2010 A wonderful seller. Very reliable and ships super fast. A real pleasure to purchase from. A++++++ Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty in Kimono Plush New with , etc. 12/15/2010 Another perfect transaction! Wonderful seller. A real pleasure to deal with. Kamio Japan Pop&apos;n Friends Chick Diecut Eraser Kawa, etc. 12/07/2010 delivers fast, has awesome kawaii item selection! pkg rec&apos;d 12/3/10 Crux Japan Sweet Sketch Memo Pad with Stickers Kaw, etc. 12/03/2010 fine Maruneko Club Japan Black and White Cow Plush New 11/29/2010 Arrived in a timely manner. Great seller, will recommend to friends! Thank you! Japan San-X Pote Hamu Hamster Planner Refill Kawai, etc. 11/19/2010 Wonderful item, great price and great shipping Crux Japan Fuwa Fuwa Clover Letter Set with Sticke 11/19/2010 Love this shop :) San-X Japan Kireizukinseikatu Memo Pad with Sticke 11/18/2010 Thank you :) love this shop Q-Lia Japan Smile Lemon Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 11/18/2010 Brand new, i love sweet paradise, love the packaging! Q-Lia Japan Sweet Paradise 3-Section Coupon Memo P 11/18/2010 Love Kamio Japan Birthday Cake Cream, thank you so much! i love the packaging! Kamio Japan Birthday Cake Cream Memo Pad Kawaii 11/16/2010 fast, great service; great products LAM Planning Steamed Bun Baby Plush Strap New with, etc. 11/08/2010 1000% recommended! awesome seller! will buy from again! thanks yanna! ;) Mind Wave Japan Winter Peaceful Seal Sticker Sack , etc. 11/06/2010 As always, PERFECT SELLER!!! San-X Japan Nyanko School Series 2-in1 Plush New w, etc. 11/05/2010 Quick shipping, upgraded to priority w/DC, great packaging, excellent communication, thank you! Youmec Japan Orange Marmalade Diecut Memo Pad with 11/05/2010 Reliable and kind seller. A pleasure to deal with. Perfect transaction. A++++++ Sanrio Japan Chibimaru Mascot Charm 2005 Kawaii, etc. 11/03/2010 I LOVE BOTH Kamio Japan Cream Friends&amp;Awawa Chan Amusement Park Mini Memo pad!. i love them! Kamio Japan Cream Friends Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 10/27/2010 fast shipping..good seller Sanrio Japan Cinnamoroll Pack O&apos; Stickers 2008 Kaw 10/25/2010 great customer service, fast shipping Sanrio Japan Little Twin Stars Letter Set with Sti, etc. 10/25/2010 Excellent seller! Fast shipping! Thank you! Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma Sticker Sack 2006 Kawaii 10/25/2010 Highly recommended seller. Reliable and honest. Super fast shipping. A pleasure to deal with. Andante Japan Sleeping Dog Chihuahua Plush Keychai, etc. 10/23/2010 Extremely fast shipping! Awesome! San-X Japan Kamonohashikamo Memo Pad with Stickers 10/22/2010 thank you, yanna, for all of the awesome stationery you offer! pkg rec&apos;d 10/22/10 Q-Lia Japan Neco to Watashi Letter Set with Sticke, etc. 10/22/2010 Fast shipping, thank you Sanrio Japan Pandapple Beanbag Plush New with Tag 10/22/2010 Kind and honest seller. A pleasure to do business with. Super fast shipping. Maruneko Club Japan Brown Cow Plush Kawaii, etc. 10/20/2010 Great selection and fast shipping. :) Crux Japan My Best Friend Mini Memo Pad with Stick, etc. 10/17/2010 Fast shipping and very cute. Many thanks! San-X Japan Ham Ham Chan Hamster Mini Spiral Notep 10/16/2010 Honest and reliable seller. Super fast shipping! Pleasure to do business with. A++++++ Sanrio Japan Tokidoki Hello Kitty Charm Cell Phone 10/16/2010 great experience! Sakura Japan Year Of The Cow Sticker Sheet (C) Kaw 10/11/2010 love the plushies! thank you so much again! A+++ (^_^)/ xx San-X Japan Nyanko Shell Big Plush in Net Kawaii 10/08/2010 love the plushies! thank you so much again! A+++ (^_^)/ xx San-X Japan Nyanko Clam Big Plush in Net Kawaii 10/08/2010 fast shipment San-X Japan Mamegoma Plush Keychain Strap Kawaii 10/07/2010 Super cute items and very fast shipping, Thank you so much! ^-^v San-X Japan Wanco Tenshi Chihuahua Loose Memo Shee, etc. 10/07/2010 Excellent Ecrater Shop and Seller..always a pleasure to buy from.. love to buy from this shop!!! Q-Lia Japan Obake Party Night Letter Set with Stic, etc. 10/04/2010 Perfect as usual! Thank you! Q-Lia Japan It Is Hungry Food Letter Set Kawaii 10/01/2010 great transaction, thank you! Q-Lia Japan Onigiri Pencil Kawaii 10/01/2010 Everything is so wonderful, thank you very much!! Daiso Japan Welcome To Mushroom World Letter Set w, etc. 09/29/2010 Always a pleasure :D!!!! Japan Crux Love Pop Monster Letter Set, etc. 09/27/2010 Excellent Ecrater Seller..always pleased with my purchases and love to shop here..Thank you!!! San-X + Green Camel Japan India Shokudo Bear Plush, etc. 09/25/2010 perfect transaction! always a pleasure! thank you so much! :))) Sanrio Japan Pankunchi Plush New with Tag 2007 Rar 09/24/2010 Super fantastic as always!! Thanks again Yanna!:) San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Burger Series Piz, etc. 09/18/2010 Love the product. Will be back again! Kamio Japan Strawberry Milky Mini Envelopes with S, etc. 09/18/2010 always pleasant to buy from Yanna! Thank you--rec&apos;d item 9/18/10 Kamio Japan Happy March Jewel Sticker Sack Kawaii 09/18/2010 Great Seller! Super Fast Shipping! San-X Japan Nyanko Tea House Letter Set with Stick 09/16/2010 Excellent Ecrater Shop and Seller..thank you for the extra item too.. love everything..very pleased Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Hearts Mini Envelopes wit, etc. 09/16/2010 Great store, cute stuff. Crux Japan Obake Chan Memo Pad (A) Kawaii, etc. 09/09/2010 Another great transaction! Thank you! Youmec Japan Fruit Candies Fortune-Telling Sticker 09/05/2010 Very prompt Iwako Japan Japanese Sweets Cup of Green Tea Diecu 09/02/2010 Great job kawiibobo - fast shipping&amp;nice service Pool Cool Japan A Lot Of Cats Puffy Sticker Sheet , etc. 08/25/2010 Such a pleasure to purchase from Kawaiibobo, I highly recommend this seller :) Kamio Japan Magical Room Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 08/21/2010 Love my sticker!!! Thank you so much and have received in a timely manner :] San-X Japan Nyanko Burger Sticker Sheet 2004 Kawai 08/20/2010 FAST shipping and the products are amazing! Great seller! Mind Wave Japan Lucky Animal Letter Set with Stick, etc. 08/18/2010 Good Mind Wave Japan Lucky Animal Memo Pad with Postcar, etc. 08/17/2010 Fast shipping! Thank you!! :) San-X Japan Sweet Face Sticker Sack (D) 2004 Kawai, etc. 08/14/2010 Fast shipping, careful packaging, and a very considerate seller~ will buy from again!! San-X Japan Nyan Nyan Nyanko Mini Memo Pad (A) 200, etc. 08/02/2010 Always a great pleasure to buy from Kawaiibobo store, highly recommended. San-X Japan Vegetables Family Orange Loose Letter , etc. 08/01/2010 Great transaction! Arrived quickly. Creative Yoko Japan Sirotan Diecut Letter Set with 08/01/2010 Got it in a week! Definately going to order again!! Kamio Japan Cafe Cafe Letter Set with Stickers (A) 07/31/2010 GREAT SELLER! FAST Shipping, Will buy from again! San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Cat Summer Series 07/27/2010 GREAT SELLER! FAST Shipping, Will buy from again! San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Cat in Roll Hot S 07/24/2010 excellent seller! always delivers fast, packs well. box rec&apos;d 7/22/10 Crux Japan Nyanko Bakery Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 07/22/2010 A+++Luv this seller!!!!!!!!!!!! Sanrio Japan Little Twin Stars Sticker Sheet 1999 , etc. 07/18/2010 Outstanding seller, highly recommended, very pleased, thanks San-X Japan Mamegoma Diecut Letter Set with Sticke, etc. 07/18/2010 wonderful transaction!!! Sanrio Japan Hitsuji (My Melody&apos;s Friend) Bracelet 07/12/2010 Great items, smooth transactions, fast shipping, outstanding seller, thanks Q-Lia Japan Warm Family Small Letter Set with Stic, etc. 07/11/2010 Always a great pleasure to shop at KawaiiBobo. Perfect seller, Thanks!!!!! Daiso Japan Love Mail Letter Set with Stickers Kaw, etc. 07/11/2010 Everything received in a timely manner :) Would def. come back again! :) Thank you so much! Kamio Japan Nyanko Cafe Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/10/2010 always a pleasure to purchase kawaii from yanna! Thanks so much. rec&apos;d pkg 7/9/10 Kamio Japan Animal Kingdom 3-Part Coupon Memo Pad , etc. 07/09/2010 Awesome, awesome seller, great items, fast shipping! Would/will order from again! Strapya Next Japan Pig Feet Plush Phone Strap Kawa, etc. 07/06/2010 Excellent seller! Great communication, quick shipping, and very secure packaging. Thank you! Q-Lia Japan Chocolate Friends 3-Section Coupon Mem 07/04/2010 Thanks! Kamio Japan Happiness Animals Sticker Sack Kawaii 06/30/2010 Everything arrived quickly and in perfect shape. Thank you!! Kabaya Japan Puppy in Carrier Bag Plush Keychain (, etc. 06/25/2010 Thanks for the fast shipping and great service! Mind Wave Japan Friends Letter Set with Stickers K, etc. 06/21/2010 Outstanding seller, great shop, fast shipping, highly reommended, thanks. Sanrio Japan Puroland Letter Set with Stickers 199, etc. 06/20/2010 Thank You so much 4 the wonderful gift!You are my favorite seller!Fast shipping&amp;wonderful service! Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Purin Dog Foil Sticker Sheet , etc. 06/19/2010 excellent as always! great products, communication, everything. rec&apos;d pkg 6/18/10 Kamio Japan Nyan Nyan Diary Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 06/18/2010 i just dont like paypal Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty and Apples Loose Letter S 06/13/2010 It is always a great pleasure to buy from Kawaii Bobo Shop. Sanrio Japan Coro Coro Kuririn Hamster 2-in-1 Stic, etc. 06/13/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, perfect packing, very pleased, thanks. Q-Lia Japan Warm Family Epoxy Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 06/13/2010 WOW!!! Amazing stickers ... love, love, love ... FABULOUS STORE, EXCELLENT SERVICE!!! THANK YOU!!! Mind Wave Japan Summer Piece Seal Sticker Sack (B), etc. 06/12/2010 perfect trans.!!! Super Fast shipping!!! Will return soon! Sanrio Japan Little Twin Stars Sticker Sheet 2004 , etc. 06/08/2010 Perfect experience, thank you. Will buy from again. Kamio Japan Happy Peaceful Time Giraffe Loose Lett 06/07/2010 Best kawaii store on eCrater; awesome service; five-star rating; THANK YOU!!!! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Carnival Letter Set with 06/06/2010 Best kawaii store on eCrater; awesome service; five-star rating; THANK YOU!!!! San-X Japan Kamonohashikamo Memo Pad with Stickers, etc. 06/06/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, fast shipping, very pleased, thanks Sanrio Japan Pankunchi Letter Set with Stickers 20, etc. 06/06/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, fast shipping, very pleased, thanks Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma Letter Set with Stickers (, etc. 06/06/2010 Thank you San-X Japan Mamegoma Sticker Sack (C) 2007 Kawaii 06/06/2010 Great seller, fast shipping. Thanks so much! Sanrio Japan Chococat Sticker Sack 2006 Kawaii, etc. 06/05/2010 all very nice Mind Wave Japan Hedgehog and Mushroom Epoxy Sticke 06/01/2010 My bags finally arrived!!! Thank you for your efficient turn around and great communication. Candy Town Cute Animals Box Erasers Set of 5 Kawai, etc. 05/31/2010 thanks. Q-Lia Japan Puppet Pets Sticker Sack Rare Kawaii, etc. 05/29/2010 Fast Shipping! Great Seller! Always Perfect! Thanks Again! Sanrio Japan Little Twin Stars Trinket (Red) 2003 , etc. 05/28/2010 I&apos;m very happy with my memos! Thank you for careful packaging and fast ship!! Also, the cute gift :) San-X Japan Baby Boo Memo Pad with Stickers (B) Ka, etc. 05/21/2010 Yanna is super to deal with! Awesome selection, fast shipping. box rec&apos;d 5/20/10 Kamio Japan Odekake Wanko Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 05/20/2010 Fast ship, item as described. Thanks for a great transaction! Made in Japan Octopus Diecut Erasers Set of 2 Kawa, etc. 05/20/2010 Wonderful seller! Fast shipping and good quality! Thank you!! Passport Japan Hannari Tofu Mini Plush Strap (Sesa, etc. 05/17/2010 Fast shipping and perfect quality. Thank you for the extra free memo sheets! :D San-X Japan Sleepy Angel Loose Memo Sheets #131 Ka, etc. 05/17/2010 Thank you again, yanna, for always excellent service! pkg rec&apos;d very fast--5/13/10. love it all! Mind Wave Japan Sweetie Town Letter Set with Stick, etc. 05/13/2010 In excellent condition fast shipping love it thank you San-X Japan Mamegoma In Costumes Memo Pad with Sti 05/07/2010 Perfect Seller! Looking forward to do more business with POMPOMPURIN ITEMS! Thank You once again! Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Purin Dog Terry Cloth Plush K 05/07/2010 Outstanding shop, great variety of items, the easiest way to shop, fast shipping, thanks Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty The Shinjuku Kitty Story , etc. 05/02/2010 Excellent Seller. Good communication. All items are perfect and fast shipping to the UK. Thank you! Japan Sanrio Hello Kitty and Favorite Things Stick, etc. 04/29/2010 Thank you! Showa Note Japan Mame Shiba Puffy Sticker Sheet Ka 04/28/2010 Perfect seller, wonderful items, fast shipping, a great shop very pleased, thank you Pool Cool Japan Wonderful Space Sticker Sheet Kawa, etc. 04/25/2010 A highly recommended seller, a wonderful shop with a great variety of cute items, thank you Kamio Japan Cafe Cafe Letter Set with Stickers Kaw, etc. 04/25/2010 Outstanding seller, always a pleasure to do business with, thanks Midori Japan Aquarium Animals Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 04/19/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, fast shipping, highly recommended, thanks Crux Japan Happy Warm Days Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 04/18/2010 thanks Crux Japan Fruit Friends Memo Pad with Stickers Ra 04/17/2010 Always a pleasure! Thanks!! A++ San-X Japan Rilakkuma Relax Bear Plush Cell Phone , etc. 04/17/2010 Outstanding seller, always a big pleasure to buy from Kawaii Bobo Shop, thanks. Kamio Japan Happiness Rabbit Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 04/17/2010 Outstanding seller, always a pleasure to shop at Kawaii Bobo store, great items, fast shipping. Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Purin in Space Letter Set wit, etc. 04/17/2010 Always a pleasure buy from Kawaii Bobo Shop, smooth transaction and fast shipping, thanks San-X Japan Tarepanda Letter Set with Stickers 200, etc. 04/11/2010 It is always a pleasure to buy from Kawaii Bobo Sho San-X Japan Happy Colors Puppies Letter Set 2009 K, etc. 04/11/2010 Outstanding seller, always a big pleasure to shop at Kawaii Bobo store. Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma Letter Set with Stickers K, etc. 04/10/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, fast shipping, very pleased, thanks San-X Japan Nakayoshi Net Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 04/03/2010 thank you, yanna, for all the wonderful kawaii items you sell! rec&apos;d box 4/1/10 Crux Japan Cream Party Mini Memo Pad (Used) Rare K, etc. 04/01/2010 very cute items thank you Affect Japan Cute Animals Box Erasers Set of 6 Kaw, etc. 03/27/2010 Thank you for packing so well; ALWAYS excellent service; A+A+A+ rated kawaii store; THANK YOU!!!! Crux Japan Colorful Frogs Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 03/27/2010 Wonderful seller! Kamio Japan Skull Small Container Keychain Kawaii 03/27/2010 Wonderful seller! A++ :) San-X Japan Tarepanda on Ball Strap by Yujin Kawai, etc. 03/24/2010 will shop here again&amp;forever! :) Sanrio Japan Chibimaru Psychic Dice Eraser, etc. 03/23/2010 Wonderful seller, items are cute and in mint condition! Kamio Japan Tiny Tiny Apartment 2-in-1 Block Erase, etc. 03/22/2010 I was happy to shop at ecrater! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Japanese Food Memo Pad (B, etc. 03/22/2010 very cute items thank you Q-Lia Japan Milky Baby Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #4, etc. 03/18/2010 an excellent seller! great items, delivers fast. pkg rec&apos;d 3/18/10 Very Berry Japan A Lot Of Dogs Puffy Sticker Sheet, etc. 03/18/2010 Wonderful seller, items are cute and in mint condition! Q-Lia Japan Petit Hamu Life Hamster Schedule Stick, etc. 03/17/2010 Wonderful seller, items are cute and in mint condition! Crux Japan Bunny and Squirrel Eraser with Roller K, etc. 03/17/2010 A highly recommended seller, very easy to shop and the fastest shipping, thanks! Sanrio Japan Pandapple Letter Set with Stickers in, etc. 03/14/2010 very fast shipping and a good transaction overall. Mind Wave Japan A House In The Forest Letter Set w 03/13/2010 Amazing! Thank you ^_^ Pool Cool Japan Rock One&apos;s World Block Eraser Kawa, etc. 03/13/2010 FAST shipping! kawaii plush! THANK YOU again! (^_^)/ A+++ San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Cat Summer Series 03/12/2010 Thanks A+++ San-X Japan Mamegoma Diecut Erasers in Bottle 2008, etc. 03/12/2010 Will definitely buy from again! Perfect A++ Kamio Japan Niko Niko Animals Sticker Sheet Kawaii 03/12/2010 Very well packaged and no pages bent love it! thank you! :D Crux Kamio Q-Lia San-X Loose Memo Sheets Lot of 60, etc. 03/10/2010 Excellent sale in every way!! Super fast ship and cute plush - thanks so much! San-X + Green Camel Japan Nyanko Cat Festa Selecti 03/07/2010 Perfect as always! Thank you! Sanrio Hello Kitty Stickers with Collectible Tin K, etc. 03/05/2010 arrived promptly&amp;in great condition :-) thanks! Q-Lia Japan Petit Animals Sticker Sheet Kawaii 03/04/2010 Quick shipping, 100% satisfied returning customer! Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Purin Spiral Notebook with St, etc. 03/03/2010 My Favorite Seller! You are the best! (^-^) Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Purin Sticker Booklet by Band 03/03/2010 Wonderful seller! Thanks for another great transaction! Mind Wave Japan Twin Miu Princesses Memo Pad with , etc. 03/03/2010 perfect it was exactly what I wanted; arrived quickly Active Japan Cherry Blossoms Sakura Epoxy Sticker 03/03/2010 Excellent Ecrater Shop and Seller.. shipped fast..wonderful shop! Love to buy from here..Thank you!! San-X Japan Baby Boo Mini Envelopes with Stickers , etc. 03/03/2010 Cutest letter sets and fast delivery with great care. Mind Wave Japan Merry Trip Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 03/01/2010 Perfect quality. Thank you for the extra ones! :) San-X Japan Hamster Games Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii, etc. 02/28/2010 Everything was in perfect condition and arrived super quick!! Thank you!! :D Kamio Japan I Love You Bear Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 02/24/2010 LOVE my item :D! Always a pleasure. Crux Japan Love Love Sweets Memo Pad with Scratch- 02/22/2010 Have made many purchases from seller; items always packed&amp;shipped in xcellent condition~Thank You! Q-Lia Japan Tropical Kousagi Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 02/21/2010 Repeat customer! Excellent seller! Thank You! Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Purin Puffy Sticker Sheet 200, etc. 02/20/2010 always a pleasure :D. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Parfaits Puffy Sticker Sh, etc. 02/20/2010 fast shipping and great products - thanks again! Mind Wave Japan Friendship Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 02/19/2010 I would highly recommend this seller to all kawaii collectors! pkg rec&apos;d 2/19/10. Thanks, yanna! Kamio Japan Sugar Pet Puffy Sticker Sheet with Emb, etc. 02/19/2010 super seller! pkg of multiple purchases rec&apos;d promptly on 2/19/10 Q-Lia Japan Magical World 3-Section Coupon Memo Pa, etc. 02/19/2010 Excellent! Thank you for everything! Sakura Japan Year of the Tiger Washi Paper Sticker, etc. 02/19/2010 good! San-X Japan Kogepan Loose Letter Set (B) Kawaii 02/16/2010 Love this seller! Always a perfect transaction! Ill be back as always! Mind Wave Japan Twinkle Crown Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 02/15/2010 thaNKS! perfect! Crux Japan Nurse Angels Memo Pad Kawaii 02/09/2010 excellent seller, every time! Thank you, Yanna! Pkg rec&apos;d fast--2/8/10 Wizard Japan 2009 Year of the Cow Sticker Sack (B), etc. 02/08/2010 A real pleasure to work with again, super fast shipping, lovely items, great packaging. Japan Crux Unko Chan Mini Memo Pad, etc. 02/06/2010 Wonderful seller! Excellent transaction. Thanks for the extra memo! ^_^ Japan Sanrio Hello Kitty Mini Letter Set with Stic, etc. 02/05/2010 The best seller on ecrater! Nicely packed with care:) Sanrio License Pom Pom Purin Ice Cream Sticker She, etc. 02/04/2010 Super Excellent Ecrator Shop and Seller.. packaged wonderful and received so quickly..love to shop! Daiso Japan Girl Friends Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 02/02/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, nice prices, very fast shipping, the best! thanks Kamio Japan Fast Food Restaurant Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 01/31/2010 always a plesure :d Daiso Japan Cute Sweets Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 01/30/2010 Always a pleasure :D. San-X Japan Nyanko Burger Mini Letter Set with Sti, etc. 01/30/2010 Honest and A-M-A-Z-I-N-G Seller! Highly Recommend! THANK YOU SO MUCH! Crux Japan My Love Bear Letter Set with Stickers K 01/29/2010 Thanks So Much! - Fast shipping! Great Seller!!! Japan Kamio Mermaid In Love Mini Memo Pad 01/29/2010 +++ Perfect +++ Thank you +++ Mind Wave Japan Je Prends Cette Chambre Letter Set, etc. 01/25/2010 Outstanding seller, cute items, easy way to shop, I love this shop, thanks Crux Japan Sweet Happiness Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 01/24/2010 Outstanding seller, great items, fast shipping, very pleased, thank you. Seiwapro Japan Nyan Nya Letter Set with Stencil Ka, etc. 01/22/2010 excellent, as always! thank you for such awesome kawaii items! pkg rec&apos;d 1/22/10 Pool Cool Japan Animal&apos;s Orchestra Sticker Sheet K, etc. 01/22/2010 excellent seller! pleasant communication. pkg rec&apos;d quickly--1/22/10 Crux Japan Happy Faces Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 01/22/2010 Received items fast! Love everything. Thanks for the extras! Crux Japan I Love Friendship Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 01/21/2010 Very cute letterset! Thank you so much Crux Japan Story of Children Letter Set with Stick 01/19/2010 An outstanding seller, highly recommended, great items, thank you Komoda Japan Happy Clover Letter Set with Stickers, etc. 01/17/2010 rec&apos;d pkg very fast--1/14/10. excellent seller to deal with! Pool Cool Japan Kirarin Animals Mini Memo Pad Kawa, etc. 01/14/2010 Cute Received Thanks :) Kamio Japan Panda Cafe Memo Pad with Stickers Kawa, etc. 01/13/2010 I received the items fast San-X Japan Green Tea Spiral Notebook Rare 2002 Ka, etc. 01/12/2010 Outstanding seller, always a pleasure to do business with, the best! thank you Kamio Japan Awawa Chan Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #9, etc. 01/09/2010 Thank you once again! Kamio Japan Classy Bear Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 01/08/2010 Outstanding seller, fast shipping, highly recommended, thank you Mind Wave Japan Cute Puppies Stamps Sticker Sheet , etc. 01/07/2010 Thank you for having awesome kawaii items! pkg rec&apos;d 1/7/10. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Year of The Tiger 2010 Ep, etc. 01/07/2010 Thanks, great as always! Pool Cool Japan Peach Face Tabbed Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 01/06/2010 A wonderful seller, adorable items, fast shipping and great communication. A big thanks Q-Lia Japan Chobitto Pig Loose Letter Set (C) Kawa, etc. 01/05/2010 it was easy and cheap thank you Kamio Japan Nakayoshi Kinoko Mushroom Loose Memo S, etc. 01/05/2010 Always a pleasure :D. Mind Wave Japan Berry Bear Memo Pad with Stickers , etc. 01/03/2010 A highly recommended seller, the best, great communication and the fastest shipping, thank you Kamio Japan Puppy&amp;Kitty Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 01/03/2010 Outstanding seller, highly recommended, great items and super fast shipping, thank you San-X Japan Snow Bunnies Loose Letter Set (A) Kawa, etc. 01/01/2010 Got my order quickly, very pleased. San-X Japan Mamegoma with Duckie Mascot Charm Zipp 12/30/2009 +++ Perfect +++ Thank you +++ San-X Japan Sweet Harmony Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 12/29/2009 A super great seller, great items at good prices, perfect packing and the fast shipping, highly reco Crux Japan Cheerful Bear Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 12/27/2009 Prompt as always! Thanks again! Crux Japan Hi! School Girl Flake Stickers with Dia, etc. 12/23/2009 Shipped pretty fast, item as described, would buy from again Sanrio Japan Pankunchi Plush New with Tag Kawaii 12/23/2009 Everything was perfect! It&apos;s so cute and no damages, scratches or anything. LOVE THIS SELLER! San-X Japan Momopanda Sitting on Sofa Plush New wi 12/20/2009 thanks! Crux Japan Fuka Fuka Animal World Puffy Sticker Sa 12/18/2009 Thank you soo much! Fast Shipping! A++++ seller! Thank you for extras! :) Kamio Japan Jewelry Girls Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 12/17/2009 Outstanding seller, highly recommended. Great items, perfect packing and fast shipping, thank you. Sanrio Japan Charmmy Kitty Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 12/13/2009 second order from this shop&amp;am very happy with the fast shipping, thanks! Q-Lia Japan White Teeth Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 12/11/2009 Very cute and fast shipping! Highly recommend! Q-Lia Japan Shiny Horoscope Loose Memo Sheets Kawa, etc. 12/06/2009 Outstanding seller, highly recommended, wonderful items, fast shipping, thanks Japan Chihuahua Puppy Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 12/06/2009 Outstanding seller, highly recommended, adorable items, great packing and fast shipping, the best!, Kamio Japan Happy Friend Loose Letter Set (C) Kawa, etc. 12/05/2009 Outstanding seller, great items, perfect packing and super fast shipping, thank you Wizard Japan Cat and Dog Puffy Sticker Sheet Kawai, etc. 12/04/2009 Outstanding seller, great items, perfect packing and super fast shipping, thank you. San-X Japan Tarepanda Sticker Sheet 1999 Kawaii, etc. 12/04/2009 FANTASTIC eCrater experience...ALWAYS a TOP-NOTCH Seller...A+++ Mind Wave Japan Winter Selection Merry Christmas E, etc. 12/03/2009 Thanks! Pool Cool Japan Bath Gel Jewel Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 12/03/2009 very fast shipping and great items - thanks so much! Kamio Japan Choco Choco Town Letter Set with Stick, etc. 12/03/2009 excellent seller! always delivers fast, and the goodies included are wonderful! Rec&apos;d 12/3/09 Wizard Japan Happy Happy Clover Memo Pad with Stic, etc. 12/03/2009 AWESOME! AS ALWAYS! THANK YOU SO MUCH! Crux Japan Sweet Boo Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 12/03/2009 Fast Ship and Perfect As ALways! Kamio Japan Charmed Girl Letter Set Kawaii 12/03/2009 Outstanding seller, fast shipping, great packing, very pleased, thanks Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Variety Letter Set (D) Ka, etc. 11/29/2009 thanks Crux Japan Hi! School Girl Memo Pad Kawaii 11/25/2009 I love the memo pads! Thank you! Crux Japan Cake Chan Memo Pad with Coloring Sheets, etc. 11/21/2009 Cute sticker sheets! Well-packaged! Thank you! Crux Japan Ghost Party Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 11/20/2009 Perfect as always Crux Japan Panda&apos;s Post Sticker Sheet Kawaii 11/19/2009 Amazing as always! Thank you so much! Y-Mail Japan Sweet Happy Time Letter Set with Stic, etc. 11/19/2009 very nice seller, let me know when items shipped, thank you!! Q-Lia Japan Snow Friend Loose Memo Sheets, etc. 11/16/2009 So Adorable! Just as described! Amazing and Sweet Seller! San-X Japan Cute Puppies Long Coupon Memo Pad with 11/14/2009 i love these stickers so much! thanks! Crux Kamio Q-Lia San-X Sanrio Loose Stickers Lot o, etc. 11/13/2009 awesome seller, great communications, very good packing of items, too. rec&apos;d 11/12/09 Wizard Japan Sweet Festival Letter Set with Sticke 11/12/2009 an excellent seller every time! pkg rec&apos;d super fast--11/12/09 Crux Japan Plum Cats Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #72, etc. 11/12/2009 always a pleasure to deal with this wonderful seller! pkg rec&apos;d 11/6/09 Kamio Japan Milk Chan Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #13, etc. 11/06/2009 Very fast service and great products as usual - thanks! Mind Wave Japan Happy Travel Letter Set with Stick, etc. 11/05/2009 FAST SHIPPING! Thank you! A+ Seller Mind Wave Japan Mug Chocolate Memo Pad with Sticke, etc. 11/04/2009 Excellent, efficient, very nice seller! (I am a happy repeat customer.) :-) Sanrio Japan Charmmy Kitty Tabbed Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 11/03/2009 Thank! You! Fast shipping! Mind Wave Japan Happy Animals Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 10/30/2009 Perfect Sale as always! Trust this seller! Perfect in every way! Sanrio Japan Little Twin Stars Variety Letter Set , etc. 10/26/2009 Very well-wrapped and quickly shipped! One of my favorite sellers! I&apos;ll definitely be back. Thanks! Youmec Japan Sweet Candies Sticker Flakes in Box R, etc. 10/25/2009 Outstanding seller, super fast shipping, great prices, the best!!!, thank you Sanrio Japan Hoshinowaguma Mini Letter Set with St, etc. 10/23/2009 Thank you! Q-Lia Japan Colorful Drops Loose Memo Sheets Kawai, etc. 10/23/2009 Thanks! rec&apos;d pkg 10/22/09. always a pleasure to buy from! Sanrio Japan Frooliemew Sticker Sheet 2004 Kawaii, etc. 10/22/2009 I loved this item. Very satisfied. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Mini Letter Set with Stic 10/20/2009 Perfect Sale as always! Thank you once again! I love this seller! Daiso Japan Berry Cake Sisters Letter Set with Sti, etc. 10/18/2009 Thanks! Kamio Japan Cute Animals Jewel Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 10/17/2009 Fast shipping and very cute paper! Thank you! :) Crux Japan Magical Peace Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 10/14/2009 Great, thank you! Mind Wave Japan Cherry Blossoms Sakura Sticker She, etc. 10/14/2009 Absolutely fabulous store&amp;seller! Looove my new plush&amp;extras! Thanks again San-X Japan Nyanko Burger Nyanko Plush Keychain Ka, etc. 10/13/2009 Highly recommended seller... will buy again..Thanks Sanrio Japan Pankunchi Diecut Letter Set with Stic, etc. 10/12/2009 Outstanding seller, always a pleasure to do business with. Fast shipping, great packing and wonderfu Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Hakodate Letter Set in Bo, etc. 10/11/2009 The perfect seller! Excellent communication, fast shipping!!! Thank you so much for the extras!! San-X Japan Runaway Chick Mini Envelopes 2004 Kawa, etc. 10/08/2009 Great seller! Everything was well-packaged and quickly shipped. I&apos;ll definitely be back! Thanks! Q-Lia Japan Happy Sweets Letter Set with Stickers 10/07/2009 Great, fast shipping, thanks! Q-Lia Japan Joyful and Delicious Loose Letter Set , etc. 10/05/2009 DID NOT RECEIVE ITEM. Sanrio Japan Badtz Maru Sticker Sheet 2001 Kawaii 10/05/2009 VERY Pleased AGAIN! FAST SHIP-GREAT COMMUNICATION-HONEST SELLER! THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR EVERYTHING!! Crux Japan Little Twin Melody Loose Letter Set Kaw, etc. 10/03/2009 thanks! Crux Japan Fluffy Bear Sticker Flakes w/Cases Kawa 10/01/2009 always a pleasure to buy from :D Mind Wave Japan Summer Piece Seal Sticker Sack (D) 09/30/2009 Very Pleased as usual! I love your store! Fast and Excellent Care Shipping! Sanrio Japan Cinnamoangels Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 09/28/2009 Great products and service as usual. Kamio Japan Flower Drop Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #, etc. 09/24/2009 Adorable! Will be back again soon! Excellent Shipping Time and care in packaging! A+ Seller! Kamio Japan Sweet Gift Puppies Origami Memo Pad Ka 09/23/2009 Wonderful seller! Fast shipping! I am very happy with my purchase, Thanks so much! San-X Japan Palette&apos;s Sweet Street Letter Set Kawa 09/22/2009 Excellent Seller..items shipping promptly..great condition..will buy from again.. great shop! Crux Japan 12 Star Girls Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 09/21/2009 Will be back again for sure! Fast Shipping! THANK YOU! Kamio Japan Milk Chan Yellow Loose Letter Set (B) , etc. 09/19/2009 Very Pleased with items! Awesome Seller! Crux Japan Bear&apos;s Sweet Home Mini Memo Pad (B) Kaw, etc. 09/19/2009 Very cute and fast shipping! Highly recommend! Daiso Japan Happy Skull Letter Set with Stickers K, etc. 09/17/2009 fast shipping, awesome product!! Sanrio Japan Cinnamoroll Fuzzy Bobblehead Kawaii 09/15/2009 Thanks! Crux Japan Apple Town Memo Pad Kawaii 09/14/2009 pkg rec&apos;d 9/14/09. excellent seller, excellent communication. Thank you! Crux Japan Happy Picnic Puffy Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 09/14/2009 always pleasant to deal with. Thank you for everything! rec&apos;d 9/14/09 Mind Wave Japan We Are Friend Letter Set with Stic, etc. 09/14/2009 fast shpping! thank u ! Mind Wave Japan Summer Piece Seal Sticker Sack (B) 09/13/2009 awesome as always :D Crux Japan Sweets Shop Memo Pad with Tracing Sheet, etc. 09/13/2009 Outstanding seller, great prices, fast shipping, nice packing, a big thanks Sanrio Japan Tuxedo Sam Memo Pad by Sun Star Kawai, etc. 09/13/2009 Excellent Seller..items were great..very pleased..will buy from again..Super!!! Mind Wave Japan Dolly Girl Memo Pad with Stickers , etc. 09/11/2009 Thank you so much for a great sale, 3rd time I have ordered VERY HAPPY! FAST Ship&amp;Well Packaged!! Kamio Japan Sweet Fairy Puppy Loose Letter Set (C), etc. 09/11/2009 I got all of my items in perfect condition&amp;super fast. I am ALWAYS HAPPY with this seller! THANKS! Japan Happy Animals Elephant Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 09/08/2009 Fast shipping, great packaging, Thank You! Kamio Japan Flower Angel Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 09/04/2009 Thanks! Kamio Japan Cube Friends Memo Pad with Stickers, etc. 09/03/2009 Excellent transaction, great seller!! Tokidoki Cactus Pups Figure (B) Kawaii 09/03/2009 thank u. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Love Letter Set Kawaii 08/29/2009 I LOVE this eCrater Seller and will order from her again, and again and again!!! A+++ Sanrio Japan Kuromi Rock Band Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 08/26/2009 A+++ Fast shipping. Reliable. Package was wrapped perfectly. Will buy again :D Thanks! AAA+++++++ Dumplings Plush Straps Set of 6 Kawaii 08/25/2009 Thanks but not brand new as described. Plush has a little stain on back Sanrio Japan My Melody Plush Hand Puppet New with 08/19/2009 Very fast shipping! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Mini Letter Set with Stic 08/15/2009 ANOTHER Five Star transaction with kawaiibobo...Her stuff is THE BEST!!! :-D Swimmer Japan Pink Poodle Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 08/14/2009 Another SUPER FAST&amp;SUPER AWESOME order from kawaiibobo!!! *THANKS SO MUCH* ^___^ Kamio Japan Awawa Chan Winter Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 08/11/2009 Outstanding seller, great items, fast shipping, best prices, highly recommended, a big thanks, Q-Lia Japan Cherish A Puppy Loose Letter Set (D) K, etc. 08/09/2009 I hope you sell more san-x pens! Love it!!! San-X Japan Mamepyon Pen Kawaii, etc. 08/09/2009 Thank you so much! San-X Japan Pink Squirrel Memo Pad with Stickers L, etc. 08/07/2009 Fast delivery. Sanrio Japan Sugarbunnies Variety Letter Set with , etc. 08/07/2009 Thank u very much! perfect! happy! Yayy!!! San-X Japan Kogepan Loose Letter Set (I) Kawaii, etc. 08/05/2009 I am a REPEAT CUSTOMER who LOVES kawaiibobo&apos;s items!!! She ships FAST&amp;is VERY professional...A+++ Mind Wave Japan Girls Rock &apos;N&apos; Roll Sticker Sack K 08/04/2009 Fast and easy! Game Boy Advance GBA Advance Wars Strategy Video G 08/03/2009 love my item :D. Q-Lia Japan Happy Fairy Story Memo Pad Kawaii 08/03/2009 Very fast shipping and good service as usual. Q-Lia Japan Happy Shake Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/29/2009 Total kawaiiness; loOoooove this store; fabulous seller; thank you (((hugggiesss)))!!!! Japan Q-Lia Kira Kira Wish Angels Mini Memo Pad, etc. 07/29/2009 kawaiibobo is a FANTASTIC Seller and a PLEASURE to deal with. I really LOVE my memo pad...THANKS! Crux Japan Hone Hone Sweets Mini Memo Pad Kawaii 07/28/2009 ~PREFECT~ great communication&amp;fast shipping! thank you so much! (｡ Q-Lia Japan Happy Fairy Story Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/28/2009 Thanks! Q-Lia Japan Happy Shake Memo Pad (C) Kawaii, etc. 07/28/2009 Well pack, fast ship, great communication. Much appreciated extra gift. Highly Recommended! Thnk You Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Buttons Memo Pad with Sti, etc. 07/27/2009 Super fast shipping and e-mail response! Cute products! Thank you!!! Midori Japan Lucky Charms Sticker Sack Kawaii 07/24/2009 Outstanding, always a pleasure to do business with this seller. San-X Japan Petit Wanco Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 07/21/2009 I love my items. Thank you! Kamio Japan Apple Bear Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/19/2009 Thanks! Q-Lia Japan Happy Fairy Story Memo Pad Kawaii 07/19/2009 Thanks! Q-Lia Japan Happy Fairy Story Memo Pad Kawaii 07/19/2009 Thanks! Q-Lia Japan Happy Fairy Story Memo Pad Kawaii 07/19/2009 yea no comment Game Boy Advance GBA Yu-Gi-Oh The Eternal Duelist 07/13/2009 :) Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty PVC Soccer Strap Kawaii 07/13/2009 Outstanding seller, great prices, fast shipping, great! thanks Kamio Japan Happy Seals Puffy Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 07/12/2009 thanks! Q-Lia Japan 12 Star Angels Jewel Sticker Sack Kawa 07/12/2009 great products, good emails, fast delivery! pkg rec&apos;d 7/11/09. would recommend highly! Q-Lia Japan Ponet Room Kitten Diecut Memo Sheets i, etc. 07/11/2009 thanks. Crux Bunny&amp;Squirrel Stickers w/Case Kawaii, etc. 07/06/2009 Outstanding seller, great items, nice prices, the best!!!!! San-X Japan Sweet Face Penguin Loose Letter Set (D, etc. 07/04/2009 Adorable items, great prices, thank you!!!! San-X Japan Puppy School Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 07/01/2009 LOVELY as always!!! Thank you so much! Sanrio License Pom Pom Purin with Plush Sticker Sh, etc. 06/29/2009 Great items, great prices, very pleased, thanks Crux Japan Happy My Life Puppy Loose Letter Set (C, etc. 06/28/2009 very nice homepage, great prices! Kamio Japan Happy Peaceful Time Hippo Loose Letter, etc. 06/27/2009 Very nice home page. Sanrio Patapatapeppy Owl Sticker Sheet, etc. 06/27/2009 ok Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Regional Limited Edition 06/26/2009 Wonderful seller. Great communication! Fast shipping! A++++ Japan Kamio Medicine Chan Mini Memo Pad, etc. 06/24/2009 super seller! pkg rec&apos;d 6/22/09--super fast! Thank you for the kawaii goodies! Crux Japan Angel Rabbits Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 06/22/2009 Thanks! Q-Lia Japan 12 Zodiac Angels Memo Pad Kawaii 06/21/2009 Quick shipping and great products - thanks! Kamio Japan The Three Little Bears Letter Set with, etc. 06/19/2009 Thanks! Crux Japan Hi! School Girls 2-in-1 Sticker Sheet K, etc. 06/18/2009 Thanks! Q-Lia Japan Nomikake Long Coupon Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 06/17/2009 Fast shipping, very nice seller...items are very cute/ will buy again Crux Japan Nattochan Loose Letter Set (D) Kawaii, etc. 06/15/2009 100%satisfied! fast shipping, free gift, packaged carefully. I love this store :) Daiso Japan Welcome to Mushroom World Letter Set w, etc. 06/14/2009 Another amazing order from my favorite ecrater store; huge selection of kawaii; fast ship~Thank You~ Sanrio Japan My Melody Baby Diecut Mini Memo Pad K, etc. 06/09/2009 Well packed, fast ship, Great communication, Highly Recommemded, Thank you!! =) Sanrio Japan Tenorikuma Bee Memo Sheets with Holde, etc. 06/08/2009 Items shipped quickly and just as pictured. Love them! Q-Lia Japan Sunny Room Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 06/05/2009 fast delivery! No problems. Crux Japan Animal Hospital Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 06/04/2009 very cute items, thank you so much!! Kamio Japan Cute Mix Memo Pad (A) Kawaii, etc. 06/02/2009 Great . Thank you Q-Lia Japan Sweet Cafe Mode Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 06/01/2009 Very fast shipping, products as described -- really good seller. Daiso Japan Cherry Blossom Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 06/01/2009 love ther memo pad. always great to shop from hear ;D Crux Japan Girls Crepe Shop Memo Pad Kawaii 05/31/2009 arrived quickly in perfect condition, thanks! Q-Lia Japan Hidamari Sanpo Summer Letter Set with 05/29/2009 Fast transaction, although I have not received item yet Piyo Piyo Duckie Plush Keychain New With Tag Kawai 05/28/2009 loved them! thank you thank you!! Mind Wave Japan Lucky Animal Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 05/28/2009 Fabulous store, fast ship&amp;excellent service, ~*thank you*~ for the lovely items and &quot;gift&quot; too!!! Crux Japan Plum Cats Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #72, etc. 05/22/2009 awesome as always :D Crux Japan Happy Pudding Memo Pad with Stickers Ka 05/21/2009 another great order. love your shop. thanks Q-Lia Japan Candy Friends Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii, etc. 05/20/2009 Totally Awesome Seller! Products were Excellent! Sanrio Japan Usahana Air Balloons Letter Set with , etc. 05/18/2009 Fabulous seller; fast ship; goods received in perfect condition; will buy again; THANK YOU!!!! San-X Japan Nyan Nyan Nyanko Cotton Candy Loose Le, etc. 05/15/2009 wonderful! thank you so much. San-X Japan Kogepan Mini Letter Set with Stickers , etc. 05/14/2009 very cute items and great packaging. thank you so much! Kamio Japan Chara Mix Origami Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 05/11/2009 Totally Awesome Seller! Products were Excellent! Sanrio Japan Tuxedo Sam Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 05/06/2009 Great communication, excellent game, exactly as described. Thanks! Playstation Atlus Thousand Arms RPG Video Game wit 05/03/2009 excellent selection Q-Lia Japan Paint Tubes Gumi Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 04/23/2009 !!OMG!! BEST SELLER EVER! NICEST PACKAGING I EVER GOT! ITEMS PERFECT! CUTE BONUS. WILL COME AGAIN:) Kamio Japan Happy Japanese Food Loose Memo Sheets , etc. 04/19/2009 Top-rate seller - fast service and good quality products. San-X Japan Palette&apos;s Sweet Street Letter Set Kawa, etc. 04/18/2009 Great. Thank you Crux Kamio Q-Lia San-X Sanrio Loose Stickers Lot o, etc. 04/17/2009 Love the product and tracking on it. Thanks!!!!! Pool Cool Japan Horoscopy Children Loose Letter Se, etc. 04/16/2009 great as always!! I love the stickers you picked out for me!! Sanrio Japan Charmmy Kitty Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 04/16/2009 pkg rec&apos;d quickly--4/16/09. This seller is a pleasure to buy from. She ships very fast! Thanks Crux Japan Thief Kitten Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 04/16/2009 VERY fast shipping! Even cuter in person! Will purchase from again! Thanks! San-X Japan Nyanko Burger Series Nyanko Cat Ice Cr 04/14/2009 Lovely seller, my favorite on ecrater! Thanks for the extra memo sheets! xoxo Sanrio Japan Pom Pom Muffin Hamster Variety Sticke, etc. 04/10/2009 Got it today... Thanks! Japan Sanrio Charmmy Kitty Block Erasers Set of 2 , etc. 04/08/2009 Everything was perfect. Game Boy Color Dragon Warrior III RPG Video Game b, etc. 04/08/2009 Very fast service and I&apos;m happy with what I ordered. Sun-Star Japan Disney Alice In Wonderland Letter S, etc. 04/02/2009 Loved my purchase; fast ship; highly recommend this Seller; will buy again; THANK YOU!!! Kamio Japan Baby Crown Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 04/01/2009 pkg rec&apos;d quickly once again--4/1/09. very nice seller, awesome product selection Kamio Japan Sweet Usa Chan Origami Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 04/01/2009 LOVE Kawaiibobo sooo much! Perfect! Crux Funny Punch Angel Pony Sticker Sheet, etc. 03/30/2009 Great seller, had problems with shipping but was corrected Immediately. Would buy from again!! A+++ Crux Japan Moko Moko San Loose Memo Sheets (B), etc. 03/30/2009 seemed very personal and attentive; would order from them again! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Year of the Cow 2009 Stic, etc. 03/29/2009 Incredible! Fast shipping! Will shop here again! Japan Iwako Sea Animals Collection Penguin 3D Eras, etc. 03/26/2009 very fast, just as described Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Sushi Limited Edition Mem 03/26/2009 Excellent Sanrio Japan Spottie Dottie Block Eraser 2000 03/24/2009 everything was smooth - a good transaction San-X Japan Cinderella Diecut Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 03/23/2009 superb seller! very generous, helpful. pkg rec&apos;d 3/23/09--very fast! Thanks for all gifts. Kamio Japan Sweet Pudding Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii, etc. 03/23/2009 Perfect Thank you Media Factory Japan Usarusan Memo Pad (B) Kawaii, etc. 03/22/2009 Great prices and great products! Have bought from twice now and probably will again! Japan Sanrio Hello Kitty Mini Letter Set with Stic, etc. 03/19/2009 Super fast shipping and adorable memo! Simply awesome seller! Thanks :) San-X Japan Oxygen Memo Pad with Stickers Limited 03/16/2009 One of my fave kawaii shops! will be back very soon! Q-Lia Japan Pineapple Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 03/14/2009 awesome seller! very good communications. very nice free gifts enclosed! Mind Wave Japan Animal Circus Memo Pad with Sticke, etc. 03/12/2009 Everything is so kawaii! She shipped everything very fast and included cute extras! Very happy!!!!!! Mind Wave Japan Fairy Tale World Memo Pad with Sti, etc. 03/11/2009 She is awesome! And has great prices! Kamio Japan Nakayoshi Kinoko Mushroom Loose Memo S, etc. 03/11/2009 Wow, what a great transaction. Very speedy shipping and even threw in some extras. I&apos;ll be BACK! San-X Japan Nyanko Cat Summer Festival Loose Memo , etc. 03/09/2009 Wonderful selection, fast shipping. Thanks! Japan Q-Lia Picnic Bear Letter Set with Sticker Sh, etc. 03/06/2009 another great order. Thank you so much Sanrio Japan Sugarbunnies 2-Part Memo Pad with Sti, etc. 03/01/2009 another PERFECT transaction! GREAT items! THANK YOU! A+++ (^_^)/ San-X Japan Nyanko Burger Series Nyanko Cat Ice Cr, etc. 02/27/2009 Sent very quickly! Game in perfect shape! Playstation Beyond The Beyond RPG Video Game 02/26/2009 Loved everything, great seller! Kamio Japan Cherry Pandas Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii, etc. 02/24/2009 Quick shipment! Awesome! Will shop here again! Pool Cool Japan School Friends Block Eraser Kawaii, etc. 02/22/2009 thank you so much. I recieved my stamps wrapped all nicely! Crux Japan Happy Gumballs Stamp Set Kawaii 02/20/2009 Arrived in good condition Crux Japan Friend Town Christmas Water-Filled Bubb, etc. 02/16/2009 very fast service thank you very much. Japan Crux Happy Usagi Eraser with Roller, etc. 02/15/2009 FAST shipping! CUTE items! PERFECT transaction! THANK YOU! (^_^)/ Sanrio Japan Cinnamoroll Puffy Sticker Sack Rare K, etc. 02/13/2009 Awesome! Will shop here again! Iwako Japan Noodle Soup Eraser, etc. 02/13/2009 Cute, Thanks! Crux Skull Rock Sticker Sack Kawaii 02/02/2009 Everything was perfect. Thank you so much Q-Lia Japan Happy Potatoes Loose Memo Sheets Kawai, etc. 02/02/2009 Absolutely wonderful, fast shipping, wonderful products, will recommend and do business again. =) Sanrio Japan Japan Only Hello Kitty Cute Model Min, etc. 02/01/2009 fantastic transaction as always!! super fast shipping&amp;friendly service. Kamio Japan Stroll of Sheep Stroll of Hedgehog Let, etc. 01/22/2009 Fantastic . One of my favorite kawaii shops Crux Japan Happy Parfait Puffy Sticker Sheet Kawai 01/21/2009 love the item fast service!!!! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty PVC Golf Strap Kawaii 01/18/2009 Lightning fast delivery; very happy with purchase; will buy again; awesome service; THANK YOU!!!!!!! Q-Lia Japan Happy Drop Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 01/16/2009 This seller is better than perfect! So quick, so nice. Really nice surprises included, too! Thanks! Crux Japan Happy Clover Puppy Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 01/10/2009 Great Seller! Quick Shipment! AAA+++ Kamio Japan Ninjas Epoxy Sticker Sheet Kawaii 01/02/2009 Always a great seller! Item was well-wrapped and shipped quickly. Thank you! Q-Lia Japan Sweet Friends Memo Stationery Set in B 12/30/2008 seller was excellent. product arrive timely and in great condition. would but again. Mind Wave Japan Hedgehog Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 12/30/2008 adorable items and fast shipping!! San-X Japan License Nyan Nyan Nyanko Mechanical Pe, etc. 12/22/2008 Amazing! The shipping, items and everything was wonderful. I will be shopping here again! Sanrio Japan Kerokerokeroppi Notebook 1997 Kawaii, etc. 12/18/2008 thanks! Japan Q-Lia Sakura Mail Mini Memo Pad 12/18/2008 thankyoushismush:) AGAIN! I love your storeぬぬぬ San-X Japan Mossa Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #96, etc. 12/18/2008 I was very happy with my purchase. Delivery was very quick. Thank you very much! Sanrio License Japan Hello Kitty Pancake Cafe Lett, etc. 12/17/2008 Super fast shipping! Friendly and responsive! Would love to order from you again! ^_^ Q-Lia Japan Suikasan Watermelon Letter Set with St, etc. 12/15/2008 Great selection, reasonable prices, and fast shipping. Thanks! Daiso Japan Happy Nyanko Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 12/11/2008 Very fast shipping; reasonable prices, and great communication :) Thanks!! Sanrio Japan Bunny Plush New with Tag 2000 Rare Ka, etc. 12/08/2008 awesome seller! would highly recommend for kawaii collectors. pkg rec&apos;d 12/4/08 Kamio Japan Colorful Dog Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 12/04/2008 More desc on memo sheets - size of sheets. Would have ordered more if I had known how small they are Mind Wave Japan I Love Kurumi Squirrel Letter Set , etc. 12/01/2008 excellent! Crux Japan Happy Pudding Memo Pad with Stickers Ka 11/30/2008 thankyoushismush:) Kamio Japan Cell Phone Messages Mini Memo Pad 11/25/2008 fast shipping Japan Kamio Shabon Usachan Letter Set, etc. 11/24/2008 smooth, easy transaction. fast shipping. thanks! Sanrio Japan Bad Badtz Maru Cool Sticker Sheet 200 11/24/2008 Awesome item, prompt shipping, excellent seller as always! ^_^ Crux Japan Natto Chan Memo Pad with Stickers Kawai 11/21/2008 Everything was lovely as always! Thanks!! Q-Lia Japan Mayo Tube San Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii, etc. 11/18/2008 As always a fantastic transaction. Delivered super fast and in perfect condition. Kamio Japan Stitiched Bunny Doctor Loose Memo Shee, etc. 11/17/2008 love it thanks Q-Lia Japan Panda Food Loose Memo Sheets Kawaii #2, etc. 11/17/2008 Fast shipping and excellent service! Will come back again. ^__^ Crux Japan Takoyaki Panda Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 11/14/2008 recommended seller! Kamio Japan Soda Drinks Origami Memo Pad Kawaii 11/10/2008 I can&apos;t believe how fast my order arrived! So sweet to include a nice surprise! Thanks much! :-) Japan San-X Wanwanwanco Chihuahua Pencil Caps (Set, etc. 11/06/2008 great seller! Q-Lia Japan Sweet Land Origami Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 11/04/2008 Very cute! Quick to ship! Very reasonable prices! Would do business with again in the future! Japan Sanrio Chococat Momoberry Sticker Sheet Rare, etc. 11/03/2008 I received the goods on time San-X Japan Cherry Berry Scented Putty Eraser 11/02/2008 I LOVE my little bunny, and the free gifts are so sweet! Fast shipping and excellent seller! Thanks! Lavendar Pets Lavendar-Scented Stress Relief Plush 10/30/2008 Always a pleasure! Great prices! Very reasonable shipping rates! Great products! Japan Sanrio Pochacco Sailing Letter Set with Stic 10/28/2008 Fast shipping! Thanks! Sanrio Japan Tuxedo Sam Plush New with Tag 2000 Ra 10/28/2008 Fast shipping! Thanks! Japan Sanrio Tuxedo Sam Small Container 10/28/2008 Very good seller, she is very fast to send her products Japan Sanrio Little Twin Stars Letter Set with Sti, etc. 10/25/2008 a very pleasnt transaction.Fast to response and recieved item in very good condition. Crux Japan Milk Chocolate Friends Memo Pad Kawaii 10/25/2008 Adorable item, fast shipping, excellent service as always! Thanks! ^_^ Lavendar Pets Lavendar-Scented Stress Relief Plush 10/23/2008 super seller, fast delivery, very well packaged. would highly recommend Q-Lia Japan Strawberry Love Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 10/23/2008 Great products! Arrived quickly. Japan Sanrio Hello Kitty Japan Style Origami Craft, etc. 10/19/2008 Fast shipping! Thank you! Gakken Japan Year of the Rat Sticker Sheet Kawaii 10/19/2008 shopping experience was perfect. San-X Japan Kogepan Cafe Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 10/14/2008 Thank you for the quick shipping and pretty deco tapes Japan Disney Stitch Deco Tape Pack of 3 Kawaii 10/09/2008 Adorable memo, fast shipping, excellent service as always! Thanks! ^_^ San-X Japan Chiikaba Osanpo Mini Hippo Memo Pad wi 10/06/2008 Awesome Seller, Would Buy From Again!!! Kamio Japan Special Message Loose Letter Set Pink , etc. 10/04/2008 Sorry for the late feedback! Youre a FANTASTIC seller. I love all your items! Crux Japan Bunny and Squirrel Amusement Park Loose, etc. 10/02/2008 Cute memo pad! Fast shipping. Highly recommended seller. San-X Japan Penguin Breads Memo Pad with Stickers 09/28/2008 No problems - thank you. Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Scented Diecut Erasers in, etc. 09/26/2008 Thank you SO much! I love everything!! **** Q-Lia Japan Stand By Me Pancakes Loose Letter Set , etc. 09/15/2008 excellent shipper and was a pleasure to work with. Highly recommended. Kamio Japan Pudding Chan Origami Memo Pad 09/14/2008 Kept me informed of when it was sent, product was just as described. Thanks!! Sun-Star Japan Nightmare Before Christmas Sticker , etc. 09/12/2008 very pleasant and quick transaction overall! Crux Japan Happy Melody Miu Loose Letter Set (A) K, etc. 09/08/2008 Perfect as usual, arrived quickly and thank you for the freebie deco tape. You&apos;re the best San-X Japan Kogepan Stickers with Collectible Tin , etc. 09/07/2008 wonderful seller!! shipped items out very fast :) items are super cute&amp;in perfect condition! Kamio Japan Have A Rest Donuts Loose Letter Set Ka, etc. 09/06/2008 Oh so cute. Can&apos;t stop buying things from your site. :3 Sanrio Japan Pankunchi Mini Letter Set (A) Kawaii 09/06/2008 i received everything in excellent condition; shipping is fast; and great communication too :D Crux Japan Koala Mart Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 09/04/2008 Item as described, mailed promptly. Recommended! Game Boy Advance GBA Advance Wars 2 Black Hole Ris 09/03/2008 Great A+! Sanrio Japan Hello Kitty Lavender Scented Letter S 08/31/2008 Extremely cute. :3 Japan Sanrio Pankunchi Mini Memo Pad (A) 08/30/2008 Goods came as described Game Boy Advance Yu-Gi-Oh Reshef of Destruction Vi 08/18/2008 Yanna is always a super seller :) Very fast shipping and I love the letter sets! San-X Japan Vegetables Family Orange Loose Letter , etc. 08/14/2008 i got my stuff in a quick professional manner, everything was nice quality, and the seller was A Japan Bears and Flowers Large Deco Tape Pack of 3 08/14/2008 Excellent! I have already received my product. Thank you. Sanrio Japan Pankunchi Keychain Made by Ban Dai Ka 08/12/2008 Arrived in perfect condition. Thank you so much. I love your shop. San-X Japan Kogepan Bakery Loose Letter Set Kawaii, etc. 08/06/2008 Thank you! I love your selection :D Crux Japan Panda and Friends Rainbow Sticker Sheet, etc. 08/06/2008 Everything was great as always! Thanks for the goodies! Crux Japan Natto Chan Loose Memo Sheets, etc. 08/03/2008 Loved all I got and that it was trackable. So kawaii!!! Kamio Japan That Made Me Happy Loose Memo Sheets, etc. 08/02/2008 Love this seller!!! Kamio Japan Twinkle Magic Stickers w/Case Kawaii, etc. 08/01/2008 Smooth transaction. Good seller. Crux Japan Rocking Melodies Loose Memo Sheets, etc. 08/01/2008 Wonderful as always :) Thank you so much! Crux Japan Panda and Hamster in the Park Sticker S, etc. 07/30/2008 Fast shipping and excellent service! Will come back again. ^__^ Prom Japan Seal Fairy Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 07/23/2008 Shipping prices incredibly reasonable! And very quick to receive items! Sanrio My Melody Stickers with Collectible Tin Kaw, etc. 07/22/2008 perfect! thank you!! Q-Lia Japan Cool Punk Mini Memo Pad Kawaii, etc. 07/20/2008 fantastic seller!! Always ships so fast =) San-X Japan Kinokoron Mushroom Plush Cell Phone St 07/18/2008 Thank you :D Crux Japan Sweet Shop Stamp Set Kawaii, etc. 07/17/2008 Lovely Seller, Awesome Items, Always Mint, thanks!! Kamio Strawberry Friends Puffy Sticker Sheet Rare, etc. 07/13/2008 awesome as always! Kamio Japan Nakayoshi Kinoko Mushroom Loose Memo S, etc. 07/05/2008 Love everything! 100% happy! will be back! Crux Japan Smile Friends Sticker Sheet Kawaii, etc. 07/03/2008 Fast shipping. Items are as described. Japan Origami Cakes Origami Craft Paper Kawaii, etc. 06/28/2008 Great communication, fast shipping, and overall great experience. I love my new kinokoron, thanks =) San-X Japan Kinokoron Mushroom Plush Cell Phone St 06/28/2008 Seller was quick to respond to questions and even quicker to ship - excellent transaction! Kamio Japan Alice in Wonderland Sticker Sheet, etc. 06/20/2008 Even cuter than I thought! Crux Japan Hope Music Mushroom Mini Memo Pad 06/13/2008 Fast Shipping-Seller kept in touch between order and shipping date. Japan Iwako Sea Animals Collection Penguin 3D Eras 06/01/2008 thanks for sending it so promptly Sanrio Bad Badtz-Maru Sticker Sheet, etc. 05/31/2008 Thanks so much! Love them! FAST shipping!! A+++++ Japan Crux Snow Friends Mini Memo Pad, etc. 05/30/2008 Super cute! Fast shipping. Thanks so much! Will check back...love kawaii skull stuff! Q-Lia Japan Skull Diecut Mini Memo Pad Kawaii 05/30/2008 Delivered super fast and was perfectly packaged. I will buy here again. Perfect Crux Kamio Q-Lia San-X Sanrio Loose Stickers Lot o, etc. 05/26/2008 perfect! thanks so much!! Japan Kamio Dental Paradise Sticker Sack Kawaii, etc. 05/15/2008 perfect! thanks so much! Japan San-X Kinokoron Mascot Mechanical Pencil 05/13/2008 AWESOME SELLER!! SUPER FAST SHIPPING&amp;GREAT PRODUCTS! WILL BUY AGAIN! MAHALO! Sanrio License Pom Pom Purin Dog Block Eraser (B), etc. 05/11/2008 Fast shipping and excellent service! Crux Japan Happy Charm Tropical Mini Memo Pad, etc. 05/10/2008 Very fast shipping, wonderful packaging, nice seller ^^ Crux Japan Happy Parfait Memo Pad 04/29/2008 I love the sticker sheet, thanks! Japan Q-Lia Junk Sweets Burger Sticker Sheet 04/27/2008 Adorable stickers and memos, excellent seller! Wonderful service as always! :) Crux Japan Chestnut Pig Loose Memo Sheets, etc. 04/26/2008 thanks! Japan Crux Happy Mail Friends Sticker Sack Rare, etc. 04/26/2008 Arrived promptly. Product exactly as stated. Japan Sanrio Pandapple Apple&amp;Grapefruit Scented , etc. 04/20/2008 Fast shipping and great products! San-X Japan Nyanko Cat Food Mini Memo Pad (A) Rare, etc. 04/16/2008 As always, great items and fast shipping! Thanks so much :) Crux Kamio Q-Lia San-X Loose Memo Sheets Lot of 60, etc. 04/08/2008 Thank you! Kamio Hamster P.E. Class Sticker Sheet, etc. 04/08/2008 EXCELLENT Merchandise, Well Packaged, I love everything, thank you! Japan San-X Mamegoma Sanrio Charmmy Kitty Kamio St, etc. 04/07/2008 great seller! Thank you! Crux Kira Kira Angel Kittens Sticker Sheet, etc. 03/28/2008 Perfect! Thank you very much! Crux Hamster Ghosts Sticker Sheet, etc. 03/27/2008 Thank you!! Japan Lemon Cats and Sakura Mini Letter Set with S, etc. 03/21/2008 Easy to order, I got the order in about a week, and everything was exactly as described. Cool. Japan Q-Lia Forever Clover Letter Set with Sticker, etc. 03/21/2008 
 
 
 Last Updated: 7 Jul 2012 20:27:50 PDT home  |  about  |  terms  |  dmca  |  contact  |  news Copyright © 2012 eCRATER. Get your  free online store
	</body>
</document>
