<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005010" url="http://www.activediner.com/old-custom-house/restaurant/avila-beach/ca/us/reviews/392192" time="2012-07-12-21:32" support="1" score="0.0025586346706060574" bingtitle="Old Custom House Restaurant Reviews, 324 Front St, Avila Beach, CA ..." webtitle="Old Custom House Restaurant Reviews, 324 Front St, Avila Beach, CA, 93424, (805) 595-7555 - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>- American, Seafood, Cafe, Fast Food Restaurant in ... Avg Rating: Number of Reviews: 4 ... My food was cold when it finally arrived. You would ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 
 more... 
 American Barbecue Breakfast Cafe Catering Children&apos;s Menu Deli/Sandwich/Subs Dinner Fast Food Kids Friendly Lunch Outdoor Seating Scenic View Seafood Take Out/Carry Out 
 
 


Nearby Cities
 San Luis Obispo 
 Morro Bay 
 Atascadero 
 Paso Robles 
 Pismo Beach 
 
 more... 
 Cayucos Creston Oceano San Miguel San Simeon Santa Margarita Shandon Templeton 
 
 



 
 
 


 
 United States &gt; California &gt; Avila Beach Restaurant Guide (4 ratings) 
Old Custom House
 (805) 595-7555 
 324 Front St, Avila Beach, CA 93424 | MAP 
   | Share | Features 
 Barbecue , Fast Food , Catering 

 
 Overview 
   
 Reviews (4) 
   
 Map 
   
 



 UPDATE THIS LISTING 

Old Custom House Reviews
 
Avg Rating:     Number of Reviews: 4
 A diner 
 from pismo beach california gave an overall rating of on May 21, 2007 @ 4:52 PM

  As a lifelong local to the area we LOVE Avila ! Our dissapointment is with the management at Mr Ricks. The bar was full of underage drinkers. Chito needs to watch his door people. They were drinking on the job as well. We watched several teenagers allowed in and served. The band was awesome that night but in talking with their girlfriends they admittted to being underage. Whats up with that? A diner 
 from Richland, Washington gave an overall rating of on March 10, 2007 @ 2:10 PM

  I was at the above reviewers event and know those to be the facts. I have been to The Old Custom House several times while spending time at the wonderful Inn at Avila Beach but I will never dine there again. The food for the group was delivered sporadically by the overworked wait persons, the seating they did provide suited saradines. Very unsatisfactory and upsetting. A diner 
 from Columbus, Ohio said...

on March 10, 2007 @ 12:23 PM

  I also attended the same event the reviewer from Atascadero reviewed. I wish I could rate less than one star for the service. It wasn&apos;t the servers&apos; fault, though. My food was cold when it finally arrived. You would think that knowing that a group of nearly 40 people was coming, more than two servers would be scheduled. I was embarrassed for the establishment. Even though I can heartily recommend Avila Beach as a community to my friends who travel often to the California coast, I will also tell them to NEVER go the Old Custom House restaurant. A diner 
 from Atascadero, CA gave an overall rating of on March 9, 2007 @ 6:18 PM

  I live locally and have gone to this restaurant several times. I recently planned a large event that included author Sue Grafton. Sue wanted to buy all of us (about 40 people) dinner and I made plans with Chito, the manager of the Old Custom House. We agreed on a price, Sue sent in a deposit and all was set. When we arrived, he doubled the price and even added another couple of hundred dollars for a bartender. Do you need a bartender to serve wine with dinner? He only had two wait people for 40 people. For you Grafton fans, U is for Unexpected Disappointment. I never expected this kind of bait and switch at one our local restaurants. 

   »  Read More:   Avila Beach Restaurant Reviews Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
