<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005972" url="http://www.sodahead.com/united-states/public-opinion-fast-food-ads-in-america-can-stay/question-2535295/" time="2012-07-12-22:39" support="1" score="0.00025660695263690105" bingtitle="PUBLIC OPINION &gt; Fast Food Ads in America Can Stay" webtitle="PUBLIC OPINION &gt; Fast Food Ads in America Can Stay">
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="226"/>
	<description>In most of the world people wish they could receive that many calories in ... have much of an income or a means of transporting yourself to a fast food restaurant. Yeah, you ...</description>
	<body>
		SodaHeadlines Entertainment Living Fun&amp;Humor games sports music fashion News&amp;Politics Leaderboard 
PUBLIC OPINION&gt;Fast Food Ads in America Can Stay
 by SodaHead News Posted March 23, 2012 13:00:00 Related Topics: watershed , Fast Food , Fast food ad ban , Obesity , Health , Scotland , Public Opinion , America , Kids , Ads , Commercials , Children , Liberals , Conservative , Progressive , Model , Conservatives , Food , Public Health 
 +12 Rave 3 Share 
 
 Read all 129 opinions 
 The U.K. has already banned fast food commercials from being aired during kids&apos; shows, but now Scotland&apos;s public health minister is pushing for a watershed ban . That means no junk food ads before 9 p.m., period. The push was made after research revealed kids -- hold on to your haggis, this might come as a shock -- &quot;do not just watch children&apos;s programmes.&quot; Fancy that! Now, America doesn&apos;t even have a ban on fast food ads during kids&apos; shows, but we wanted to see how the public would react to a watershed proposal like the one made in Scotland.

 

 There was some support scattered throughout the demographics, but it wasn&apos;t a particularly close call. Just over a third of respondents think America should adopt a watershed ban. We&apos;ve separated the international votes below, but in general, the main reason the ban proved so unpopular in the States is the idea of freedom. Any ban is going to come up against strong opposition from freedom-minded Americans -- and rightly so, even if there&apos;s some merit to the ban. It&apos;s what the country was built on, so it&apos;s worth keeping an eye on any potential breaches. One proud respondent wrote, &quot;They can take our lives, but they will never take our Taco Bell!&quot; 
 International Support 
 There were, of course, a number of non-U.S. votes, so we made sure to filter them out and examine those separately. Without the international votes, U.S. support only dropped a few percent to exactly one third. However, looking at just the international votes, we found that nearly three out of four non-Americans support the idea! Clearly, Americans have different ideals.

 Rebuked by the Right

 As usual (with the exception of that underweight model thing), the mere utterance of the word &quot;ban&quot; has created a vast political divide. Liberals where relatively moderate on the issue (48%), but progressives were in love with the idea (80%) and both conservatives and libertarians were practically offended (10%). Do we really have to explain?

 Weight-Neutral

 We thought maybe weight class would correlate with support, seeing as the idea is to combat obesity, but nope. The skinniest voters only showed 8% more support for a watershed ban than the heaviest voters. The lowest levels of support actually came from athletes and the average weight class.

 If you&apos;d like to vote on this question, dig deeper into the demographics, or engage in existing discussion about the topic, visit our poll about the fast food watershed . We&apos;d love to hear from you! +12 You! Add Photos&amp;Videos 
More polls by SodaHead News

 Girl Swims With Sharks: Bad Parenting? Was Dr. Drew Paid to Talk Up Drug? Public: Don&apos;t Allow Child Circumcision Should Child Circumcision Be Allowed? 
 
Top Opinion

 Jay Theyme March 23, 2012 17:10:55 +11 A Big Mac and large fries is something called &apos;food&apos; and it keeps you alive. The fat does. The salt does. The sugar does. The Protein, minerals and vitamins, oils and fiber keeps you from dying.
In most of the world people wish they could receive that many calories in a meal and would live off it for a full day.
Food is &apos;good&apos;. It helps you &apos;not die&apos;.

Now.. if you are eating Big Macs 2 times a day + fish and chips + cookies + sitting around + coffee + ordering the giant milkshake or pepsi?
THEN THAT IS YOUR FAULT NOT THE ADVERT.

And btw: Sangsters or Tesco has adverts. So... ban those! Because you can just as easily buy chicken burgers there. Or chocolates.
And ban those adverts for the organic market. Because if you EAT TOO MUCH ORGANIC FOOD YOU GET FAT AND ILL,
and,
ban the tandoori restaurant too. Because if you go there twice a day and order the fattiest, saltiest food and double the desserts then you ALSO GET FAT AND ILL.

Geez.. I&apos;m so sick of this crap. And I have to live in Scotland and have family there and just sick to death of the PC nanny-state crap over there ugh! &gt;&gt;See Replies 
 
 Sort By 
 Most Raves Least Raves Oldest Newest 
 text size Opinions
 
 antiregressivism April 09, 2012 23:03:06 +1 If you&apos;re too young to have the self control to not buy the first thing you see on TV, you probably don&apos;t have much of an income or a means of transporting yourself to a fast food restaurant. Yeah, you can whine and cry to mommy and daddy, but they have a choice as to whether or not they&apos;re going to buy you a happy meal. This is a patently idiotic idea that is devoid of any principle whatsoever. If you want to effectively &quot;combat childhood obesity&quot;, it would make more sense to have a minimum age limit on the purchase and consumption of fast food. Of course, that would still be an utterly toothless law, as parents can and will just buy it and bring it home to their kids. Let&apos;s not also forget that if they can&apos;t access fatty foods from fast food restaurants, they&apos;ll just get it elsewhere. Think of prohibition and the drug war and how harmful yet ineffective it is; or when cigarettes were banned from commercials. People still smoke; they still do drugs. It&apos;s just another step towards authoritarianism with no tangible benefit and is an exercise in futility. Even if it did work, it&apos;s not my concern that fatty eats himself to death on Big Macs, and it shouldn&apos;t be yours, either. You&apos;re genuinely stupid if you support this. reply antireg... to antireg... April 09, 2012 23:05:48 (edited) Also, as much as progressives love to resist the idea, people have free will. They are not single-celled organisms that respond predictably and unquestioningly to stimuli. You have a choice in whether or not you want to eat yourself to death. If you can&apos;t handle the fact that people demand at least a small amount of individual liberty, kindly ship yourself off to North Korea--I hear they&apos;ll like you there. reply Willy March 28, 2012 18:12:54 No, the government has no right sticking it&apos;s ass in this. reply Just me being me March 28, 2012 00:33:40 Kinda reminds me when the US banned alcohol commercials reply Mark March 26, 2012 17:03:37 +1 The best way to put people off of fast food is to put out adverts on how its made. reply R Maserati March 26, 2012 15:46:55 GVMNT is not the answer to anything! reply R Maserati March 26, 2012 15:44:10 With pink slime on hamburgers does anyone trust a slaughterhouse, anywhere, anymore? &quot;Fast Food&quot; always means a faster path to one&apos;s death date! reply richwright March 26, 2012 13:12:48 +1 Europeans are concerned that they are getting fat and unhealthy just like Americans. As well they should. Big Government needs to exist to tax people and corporations to promote the kind of behavior needed for the public good. Nothing wrong with that. No one wants to pay or has the ability to pay for healthcare for instance. Replace fast food with salad joints and much of the problem would be solved. reply Willy to richwright March 28, 2012 18:16:47 +1 Except they wouldn&apos;t have enough customers to survive. The government has no right to tell us what to eat and anyone that thinks they do, is an ignorant fool. reply richwright to Willy March 29, 2012 01:44:35 Sure they would. Burger joints wouldn&apos;t have enough customers either if they didn&apos;t have marketing to ram it down your throat. Wake up. reply Willy to richwright March 29, 2012 02:37:08 No they wouldn&apos;t because most would not want an all salad diet and they don&apos;t need advertising to know that cheeseburgers and fries are delicious. The gullible, easily influenced might think they would like a rabbit food diet, but most people would prefer the rabbit, Fried. reply richwright to Willy April 04, 2012 17:02:09 You are more brainwashed than you think if you believe the fast food industry spends billions for their health. reply Willy to richwright April 04, 2012 18:54:57 I&apos;m not gullible and commercials have no effect on me, I know what I like and eat what I like whenever I like. I guess gullible people can watch an add for a tofu and spinach sandwich and then say, wow, I must run out and get me a delicious spinach and tofu sandwich. reply richwright to Willy April 05, 2012 15:40:16 There are no commercials for spinach and tofu sandwhiches. Those people are smart and you&apos;re obviosly NOT. reply Willy to richwright April 05, 2012 19:45:21 But if there was such an add, gullible lefties like you, would run right out and buy 2 or 3 of them. reply richwright to Willy April 06, 2012 03:13:30 Yes, and be healthier for it. Lefties are stupid. They eat salad and you eat fat. Your cardioligist thanks you. reply antireg... to Willy April 09, 2012 23:45:30 But then we could just give them bailouts and subsidies! Think about the children! lol reply The_Chouko March 26, 2012 02:29:34 It&apos;s not the commercials that are making Americans fat... it&apos;s when they eat it on a constant basis and make unhealthy lifestyle choices. reply savages... to The_Chouko March 26, 2012 20:42:10 The commercials don,t help for sure... hahaha reply betsy March 25, 2012 23:02:58 +1 Why would the US ban advertisements? This is ludicrous! Raise your children with proper diets, just because they ask for it does not mean they should receive! reply cupcakes March 25, 2012 20:17:46 +1 lol lets blames someone else for our problems reply Margaret Jacobson March 25, 2012 19:11:02 IT SHOULD BE UP TO THE PARENTS TO SET LIMITS ON WHAT THEY ALLOW THEIR CHILDREN EAT!!! NOT THE FEDERAL GOVERNMENT!! WHEN ADULTS GIVE UP FAST FOOD CHOICES...........THE CHILDREN &quot;DO NOT EAT FAST FOOD&quot;.........GET THE DRIFT.............LESS FUNK FOOD CHOICES...........BETTER IDEA THAN &quot;CENSORSHIP&quot;...........WORKS EVERY TIME!!!! NO!!! reply Swampdog March 25, 2012 15:35:47 +1 As a vegetarian I don&apos;t care, don&apos;t watch that much T.V. In as much as parents should control what and how much their children eat, what does it matter? reply QueenAline March 25, 2012 13:00:24 +1 i&apos;m surprised michelle obama hasn&apos;t already banned fast food ads.....but wait, it might be in the works reply Willy to QueenAline March 28, 2012 18:18:36 (edited) While her fat ass scarfs down triple cheeseburgers and fries.

 

 reply Dionne March 25, 2012 12:21:37 SherriWishard-Mikeska March 25, 2012 05:19:18 +1 Its sad we spend so much gov&apos;t time and money trying to curtail Americans&apos; living habits. I am a fairly small person and could probably eat fast food every day and not gain much weight but even if I blew up like a blimp I don&apos;t like some power over me every day telling me what I should and should not do with personal decisions...stay out of my kitchen, my car, my bedroom and I&apos;m not crazy about the gov&apos;t in schools look what that has gotten us.... as human beings we should be able to respect each other when we discuss things anrefrain from vile names, ect but...dang I could use a few extra pounds and I have to keep digging at the grocery store to find the the whipped cream, ice cream, butter, milk that isn&apos;t lite, non-fat, healthy alternative.
We are supposed to grow up and leave home and make our own decisions NOT grow up leave home and pax taxes so that some politician or gov&apos;t program can tell me what to do. (outside of those laws which are common sense like you can&apos;t kill your neighbor for knocking over your trash can..lol) I am the only one who feels like they are 10 again with the gov&apos;t waggin its finger in my face going no, no, no... and for the record I still eat my spinach, :) reply gregaj7 March 25, 2012 04:32:06 Subway&apos;s! reply QueenAline to gregaj7 March 25, 2012 13:00:59 +1 the only half way decent fast food out there today reply Willy to gregaj7 March 29, 2012 02:39:55 +1 I have never ate there. A submarine sandwich just doesn&apos;t appeal to me like a triple cheeseburger. reply gregaj7 to Willy March 29, 2012 05:06:49 Try the Philly-cheesesteak. reply Soundstorm March 25, 2012 03:18:15 And I say yea even if some of those disgusting Carl&apos;s Jr. ads are pushing it. reply Karl March 24, 2012 23:56:49 +4 Only a politician would think that you can make kids thinner by banning ads. reply intolerantrwj March 24, 2012 22:57:18 +1 ..... I&apos;m impressed .... with their Stupidity that is reply Bibliophilic March 24, 2012 16:37:25 Does the government exist to save us from our stupidity? If people want to consume processed mush and call it food- let them! I agree that these ads should not be targeted towards children though. Children are rarely capable of making responsible decisions about food. reply ATM March 24, 2012 15:49:22 CABLE TV USE TO ALLOW US TO VIEW WITHOUT INTERRUPTIONS BECAUSE YOU PAID EXTRA. NOW ADVERTISING IS EVEN ON THE APPS YOU DOWNLOAD...I HOPE THEY DONT GO WITH ADVERTISING ON THE NFL UNIFORMS LIKE THEY WERE CONTEMPLATING... reply zbacku March 24, 2012 15:09:55 +3 reply cate March 24, 2012 13:35:08 +2 What some fast food ads don&apos;t realize, is that a commercial about their food can turn the consumer off. Case in point. The KFC mashed potato bowl. Yack! reply Stef an... to cate March 24, 2012 21:27:51 +1 KFC is good at that. What does that shredded cheese add to that dish? It doesn&apos;t even belong in there.
 reply cate to Stef an... March 24, 2012 22:33:55 It gives me a heart attack just looking at it!!! reply 
 1 2 3 4 Next» Last» 
 News&amp;Politics

 July 12, 2012 15:55:59 

 
 Hot Questions on SodaHead 

 Facebook Showing 10 Ads Per Page: Would You Pay for an Ad-Free Internet? 91% voted I would N... Do you agree? Public Opinion Should College Be a Constitutional Right? 66% voted No Do you agree? politics Do You Think Booing Is Appropriate at a Political Event? 55% voted Yes Do you agree? politics Facebook Groups Show Exactly Who Read Your Post: Cool or Creepy? 85% voted Creepy Do you agree? tech Obama Pushing for Tax Hike on Top Earners: If You Make $250K+ a Year, Should You Have to Pay More? 51% voted No Do you agree? politics California Restaurants Defy Foie Gras Ban: Does California Have Too Many Laws? 84% voted Yes Do you agree? news UN Chooses Iran to Negotiate a Global Arms Control Deal: Crazy or Makes Sense? 76% voted Crazy Do you agree? news Is the World Economy Heading Into a&apos;Perfect Storm&apos;? 76% voted Yes, the ... Do you agree? news 


 More Community More Originals 
 
 
Slideshow
 Who&apos;s Your Fave Hollywood Rock&apos;Star&apos;? 
Slideshow
 Ugliest Celeb Mother-Daughter Battle? 
Slideshow
 Who Should Replace J-Lo on&apos;Idol&apos;? View more slideshows» 
 
 Login Register 

 Ask 
 Ask a Question Create a Poll Widget 
 Answer 
 Hot Questions Recent Questions 
 Discover 
 Find People Groups Slideshows 
 
 Hot Topics Weird News Barack Obama more… Topics: Weird News Controversy 2012 Election Barack Obama more… Site Links 
 Ask a Question Create a Poll Widget Hot Questions Slideshows Topics 

 News&amp;Politics Opinions Entertainment Opinions Living Opinions Fun&amp;Humor Sitemap 
 Help 
 FAQs Help Find Friends Contact Us 

 Report Abuse Terms of Use Privacy Code of Conduct 
 About SodaHead 
 About Us Advertise with us Poll Widget Samples 

 Polling Solutions @SodaHead on Twitter Like us on Facebook 
 © 2012
 SodaHead.com All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
