<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005508" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/20/243697/restaurant/OC/Lucilles-Smokehouse-BBQ-Orange" time="2012-07-12-22:04" support="3" score="0.006186165108523333" bingtitle="Lucille&apos;s Smokehouse BBQ - Orange | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Lucille&apos;s Smokehouse BBQ - Orange | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="10"/>
	<description>Lucille&apos;s Rib Shack-Best Bar-B-Que in Orange County ... at Lucille&apos;s Rib Shack by ordering at their counter. ... A nice change from the overpriced Disney food. A ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Orange County » North County » Orange » Lucille&apos;s Smokehouse... 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Fresno Las Vegas Los Angeles New York Phoenix San Diego Santa Barbara More... 
 
Lucille&apos;s Smokehouse BBQ
 
(714) 634-1227
 Orange 4050 W Chapman Ave 
 Orange , CA 92868 
 lucillesbbq.com 
 See all 5 reviews Cuisine Barbecue , Southern/Soul Features Kid Friendly , Outdoor Dining Menu $$ $10-15 per entree View menu | Add menu photo 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   44 people have voted 81 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Mr. Stox 83% $$$$ Anaheim - Seafood, European, Steakhouse 1105 E Katella Ave 
 
 Olive Garden 84% $$ Santa Ana - Italian, Pizza 2800 N Main St 
 
Critic reviews

 June 1, 2011 OC Register The 18th Annual Best of Orange County 2011 Winners - Best Barbecue - Winner:1st Place! More from OC Register 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Diner reviews are sorted by relevance

 July 1, 2010 Likes it good bbq served quick by Johnny Automatic ( 308 reviews ) BBQ is pretty sad in the OC. Certainly up on the north end. Except for Beachwood which I love, I haven&apos;t really found a stand alone place that I think makes good BBQ - all have their quirks. But Beachwood is both far away and would turn me into an alcoholic if I regularly went there with all their great beer choices. So that leaves the new chain in town. Every time I have had Lucille&apos;s I have really enjoyed it. It would probably be very middle-of-the-road in a real BBQ heavy area but for here it is pretty damned good. So I was happy to discover this new quick casual version of the chain that is in building that once housed the old Hof&apos;s Hut next to Crystal Cathedral. They have done a great job of remodeling this to look like part of the Lucille&apos;s family. As we entered there was a sign offering table service in the lounge (which looks well stocked and has happy hours during about half the time they are open) or counter service and seat yourself. We opted for counter... more» BBQ is pretty sad in the OC. Certainly up on the north end. Except for Beachwood which I love, I haven&apos;t really found a stand alone place that I think makes good BBQ - all have their quirks. But Beachwood is both far away and would turn me into an alcoholic if I regularly went there with all their great beer choices. So that leaves the new chain in town. Every time I have had Lucille&apos;s I have really enjoyed it. It would probably be very middle-of-the-road in a real BBQ heavy area but for here it is pretty damned good. So I was happy to discover this new quick casual version of the chain that is in building that once housed the old Hof&apos;s Hut next to Crystal Cathedral. They have done a great job of remodeling this to look like part of the Lucille&apos;s family. As we entered there was a sign offering table service in the lounge (which looks well stocked and has happy hours during about half the time they are open) or counter service and seat yourself. We opted for counter service and since I had a 2 fer coupon we went with the big daddy assortment of meats - ribs, pulled pork and brisket. It comes with one side, corn bread and a pickle. Way too much lunch but I wanted to taste as many meats as I could. I love their ribs, only quibble is I&apos;d like a slightly less sweet glaze but it is probably to the popular taste. But the crust and tender meat inside is perfect. The pulled pork and brisket were also classic BBQ with a noticeable smoke ring on the brisket. Nice amount of smokiness. I sense this is a test store for a new concept for them. If so I heartily approve. April 8, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Wellington ( 12 reviews ) I am so glad I found this place on urbanspoon. They had delicious BBQ sandwiches and wonderful sides. The prices were very reasonable and the restuarant was very clean and well organized. The service was lightning quick. My kids both loved their meals too. A nice change from the overpriced Disney food. A very close drive from the park. We will be back on our next trip to Disneyland. April 2, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Pam ( 21 reviews ) I love this place! Order at the counter like fast food, grab a table and they being it out, fast! The only thing not like a fast food place is the taste. The portions are generous, enought to share, and the price is reasonable, even better because you don&apos;t tip. Same great BbQ and salads as the larger Lucille&apos;s, August 19, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Just okay by PeaZazz ( 2 reviews ) Just moved from Virginia so was looking for a good BBQ place. This is not it. The food is very pricey for not so great BBQ. In addition, they had advertisements all over saying they now have sweet potato fries, but when we ordered this, they did not have it. If you have not eaten southern BBQ, then I guess you might think this place is okay. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Johnny Automatic ribs and hot... by Johnny Automatic Southern Cobb... 
 All 9 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Hong Kong Express $ Orange - Chinese, Asian, Fast Food Taco Bell $ Orange - Tacos, Fast Food, Mexican Subway $ Orange - Sandwiches/Subs, Fast Food, Soups 3 Palms $$ Orange - American, California Country Side Inn Orange 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 AMC 30 at the Block -
20 City Blvd W 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 lucille&apos;s chapman lucilles on chapman bbq orange county how much are ribs at lucilles luciles chapman 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
