<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005058" url="http://www.happi.com/news/2011/09/14/carbon_dioxide_blamed_for_death_at_fast-food_restaurant" time="2012-07-12-21:35" support="7" score="0.02210441414443992" bingtitle="Carbon Dioxide Blamed for Death at Fast-Food Restaurant - HAPPI" webtitle="Carbon Dioxide Blamed for Death at Fast-Food Restaurant - HAPPI">
			<query id="000088" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000091" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000063" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000079" bing-rank="112"/>
	<description>Carbon Dioxide Blamed for Death at Fast-Food Restaurant ... determined that a &quot;bleed line&quot; on the tank used to carbonate beverages in the McDonald&apos;s drink dispenser was ...</description>
	<body>
		Subscribe to: Magazine Email Newsletter RSS Feed LinkedIn Twitter Facebook 
 
 
IN THE NEWS    Print     
 
Carbon Dioxide Blamed for Death at Fast-Food Restaurant

2011-09-14 | 03:43
 An 80-year-old woman who died after being found unconscious in a restroom at an eastern Georgia McDonald&apos;s was killed by a lethal dose of carbon dioxide, authorities said Wednesday. In early reports, observers suggested that there was a link between the death and cleaning product fumes.

 An investigation determined that a&quot;bleed line&quot;on the tank used to carbonate beverages in the McDonald&apos;s drink dispenser was&quot;improperly disconnected within the wall cavity,&quot;Pooler, Georgia, Police Chief Mark Revenew said.
 This caused carbon dioxide to build up in the restroom, which was in close proximity to the tank,&quot;in a potentially lethal concentration,&quot;he said. 
 Anne Felton, of Ponte Vedra, Florida, was one of two people found in the ladies&apos; restroom September 7. Authorities arriving on the scene were also stricken by&quot;an odor,&quot;Revenew said at the time.
 A total of nine people, including three firefighters, were transported to a local hospital, where Felton died.
 At certain levels, Pooler Fire Chief Wade Simmons told reporters Wednesday, carbon dioxide can&quot;render you unconscious in a very short period of time.&quot;
 Authorities are still investigating how the incident occurred, Revenew said, adding that it involved&quot;more than one error, I believe.&quot;The franchise&apos;s owners, he said, are&quot;grief-stricken&quot;and have been very cooperative. The findings so far are considered preliminary, he said.
 Investigators did not discover the issue until Tuesday night, after receiving a call from a police department in Phoenix, Arizona, advising them of a similar incident there, Simmons said. That call&quot;sped us up and moved us in the right direction,&quot;he said.
 The restaurant re-opened after the incident when it was deemed safe. Authorities said it was closed Tuesday night for testing and the carbon dioxide issue was found. Revenew said the wall cavity had to be opened during the testing. 
 
News Calendar
 
 &lt; September &gt; S M T W T F S         1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30   Back to latest news 
 
 Buyer&apos;s Guide 
 
Search the Buyer&apos;s Guide for a company:
 
Search the Buyer&apos;s Guide for a category:
 Abrasives Absolutes Absorbents Allantoin Aloe Vera Aluminum Compounds Amino Acids Ammonium Compounds Antacids Anti-Acne Agents Anti-Aging Agents Anti-Cellulite Agents Anti-Dandruff Anti-Inflammatories Anti-Irritants Anti-Pruritics Antibacterials Anticaries Agents Antifungal Agents Antimicrobials Antioxidants Antiperspirants Antiseptics Aromatic Extracts Astringents Bactericides Biological Extracts Biological Polymers Biological Products Biotechnology Bleaching Agents Botanicals Bromides Calming Agents Carbon, Activated Ceramides Chitin Cholesterol Collagen Cooling Agents D-Limonene Deodorants Depilatories Disinfectants Enzymes Essential Oils Exfoliants Fluorescent Whitening Agents Fungicide Glycolic Acid Glycosaminoglycans Hair Conditioners Henna Herbal Extracts Hexachlorophene Hyaluronic Acid Hydrogen Peroxide Hydroxy Acids Insect Repellents Insecticides Jojoba Lactic Acid Lanolin Lecithin Lutein Magnesium Sulfate Marine Extracts Moisture Barriers Oat Extracts Oil Absorbants Oral Care Additives Panthenol Peptides Plant Extracts Protein PVPs Quats Reducing Agents Seaweed Extracts Sensory Modifiers Skin Healing Agents Skin Lighteners Skin Protectants Skin Soothers Skin Treatments Sodium Hyaluronate Sunblocks Sunless Tanning Agents Sunscreens Tan Accelerators Tea Tree Oil Thioglycolic Acid Titanium Dioxide UV Light Absorbers Vegetable Extracts Vegetable Proteins Vitamins Waxes Whitening Agents Wound Healing Agents Zinc Lactate Zinc Oxide Zinc Pyridinethione Absorption Bases Acids Acidulants Activators Alcohol, Ethyl Alcohol, Fatty Alcohol, Stearyl Alkanolamides Alpha Olefins, Normal Amides Amine Oxides Amphoterics Anti-Caking Agents Anti-Foam Agents Antistatic Agents Aroma Chemicals Benzene Betaines Binders Bittering Agents Black Acetylene Boron Nitride Capsules Carboxymethylcellulose Carrageenan Carriers Castor Oil Caustic Soda Chelating&amp;Sequestering Agents Citrates Clay Cleansing Particles Co-Emulsifiers Co-Solvents Colors Controlled Release/Encapsulation Cosmetic Patch Film Coupling Agents Cyclodextrins Defoamers Delivery Systems Denaturants Detergent Alcohols Detergent Intermediates Detergents, Alkali Detergents, Amphoterics Detergents, Anionic Detergents, Cationic Detergents, Nonionic Diethylphthalate Dispersing Agents Emollients Emulsifiers Emulsion Stabilizers Esters Ethanolamines Ethoxylates Fats&amp;Oils Fatty Acids Fatty Alcohols Film Formers Fixatives Flavors Foam Stabilizers Foaming Agents Fragrance Encapsulation Fragrance Raw Materials Fragrances Gellants Glycerine Glycols Gum Humectants Hydrides Hydrogenated PAOs Hydrotropes Imidurea Iodophor Compounds Iron Oxides Isopropyl Fatty Esters Isopropyl Myristate Isopropyl Palmitate Lauryl Sulfate Liposomes Liquid Crystals Lubricants Macroencapsulation Mica Microencapsulation Microspheres Mineral Oil Minerals Moisturizers Molecular Sieves Musk Nail Enamel Nail Enamel Resins NTA Odor-Masking Agents Oils, Non-Vegetable Oils, Vegetable Ointment Bases Oleic Acid Opacifying Agents Palm Oil Paraffin Pearlescent Pigments Petrolatum Phosphates Phospholipids Phosphoric Acid Pigments Poly Alpha Olefins Polybutene Polydecene, PAOs Polyethylene Glycols Polymers Potassium Compounds Powder Bases Preservatives Propellants Propylene Glycol Puffed Borax Resins Rheology Modifiers Scrub Agents Silicas Silicates Silicones Skin Assessment Products Skin Clarifiers Skin Cleansers Skin Conditioners Skin Moisturizers Soda Ash Sodium Bicarbonate Sodium Chloride Sodium Metasilicate Sodium Perborate Sodium Percarbonate Sodium Sulfate Solubilizers Solvents SPF Boosters Squalene Starch Stearates Sulfonates Sulfosuccinates Surface Modifiers Surface-Treated Pigments Surfactants Surfactants, Amphoterics Surfactants, Anionic Surfactants, Cationic Surfactants, Hydrotropes Surfactants, Nonionics Suspending Agents Suspension Aids Sweeteners Talc Tall Oil Fatty Acids Tallow Test Skin Thickening Agents Topic Microspheres Vegetable Oils Viscosity Agents Water Soluble Polymers Water Treatment Chemicals Water-Proofing Agents Wetting Agents White Oils Zeolites Aerosol Can Disposal Aerosol Packaging Machinery Agitators Aluminum Coil Antimicrobial Testing Equipment Applicators Assembly Bag in Box Packaging Barrier Packs Blowmolding Equipment Bottles, General Bottles, Perfume Bows/Ribbons Boxes Brushes Cappers Caps Carton Machines Cartons Case Trays Centrifuges Child-Resistant Closures Coders Colorants for Plastic Compacts Computer Control Computer Software Containers, Aluminum Containers, Composite Containers, Glass Containers, Plastic Containers, Specialty Metal Containers, Tin Plate Converting Machines Conveyors Cosmetic Samplers Custom Decorating Cutting&amp;Folding Machines Decorating Equipment Detergent-Making Machinery Dip Tubes Discs Dispensers Droppers Emulsifying Equipment Filaments Filling Machines Filters Fluid Surface Tension Instruments Form, Fill&amp;Seal Machines Fragrance Samplers Fragrance Sampling Heating Elements Homogenizers Hot-Filling Equipment Hot-Melt Equipment Intermediate Bulk Containers Jars Kettles Lab Equipment Labeling Machines Labels Liners Lipstick Containers Lipstick Molding Machines Machinery, Used Metal&amp;Plastic Specialty Stamping Metallizers Metered Pumps Metered Valves Meters Milling&amp;Grinding Equipment Mixing Machinery Nonwoven Fabric Overcaps Palletizers Paperboard Patch Technologies Perfume Stoppers POP Displays Pouches Powder Boxes Powder Presses Pumps, Sprayers Purfication Equipment Recovery Filters Refurbishing Shrink Packaging Sleeve Labels Soap-Making Equipment Sponges Stick Packaging Surplus Components Tamper-Evident Packaging Tanks Testing Equipment Tube Fillers Tubes Tubs Unit Packaging Unscramblers Valves Valves, Aerosols Vats Vials Wrapping Equipment In Vitro Test Methods Insurance Professional Services Testing Services Wipes 
Search the Buyer&apos;s Guide for a term:

This will search both companies and categories
 
News from our Sister Sites:
 

 The Power of One Drop Disc Connection Acquired Sustainable Summit Goes to Latin America 
 

 AstraZeneca Acquires Link’s Neuroscience Program Verastem, Eisai in Small Molecule Pact Bosch Packaging Enhances Process Portfolio\n 
 

 Pfizer Discontinues Claims for Certain Centrum Products Campbell’s Acquires Bolthouse for $1.5 Billion New Study Shows Higher Levels of Antioxidants in Organic Tomatoes 
 

 Ceresana analyzes the adhesives market Heubach opens a production plant for pigments Hempel acquires Blome International 
 

 Bemis Selects Thin Film Electronics to Develop Intelligent Packaging Platform Applied Materials Solves Critical Interconnect Challenge with Breakthrough Flowable Copper Technology 
 

 Nilpeter to launch new presses at Labelexpo Manroland is new MPS distributor Harper supports USO with new promotion 
 

 Massachusetts Makes Significant Changes to Gift Ban Law MiCardia Announces New Funding and Spin-off Company OxySure Ventures Into Brazil 
 

 Heubach Opens Production Plant for Pigments Squid Ink Introduces Database Linked Message Software Package Eastern Coatings Show Scheduled for April 29-May 2, 2013 
 

 WOW agenda announced Huggies, Diaper Bank donate diapers to Red Cross Fibertex Nonwovens raises prices 
 

 President Obama Signs FDA Bill into Law Wright Medical to Release Updated Bone Plating System FDA to Release Plan for Device Identification System 
 

 Suntron Opens New Clean Room in Phoenix Polygon Solutions Joins Southwest Regional Manufacturer’s Association Metro Mold and Design Opens New Headquarters 
 About Us | Current Issue | Breaking News | Events | Webinars | Archives | Subscribe Now | Advertising | Contact Us 
 Please visit our Sister Sites: 
 BeautyPackaging.com CoatingsWorld.com ContractPharma.com 

 Happi.com InkWorldMagazine.com LabelAndNarrowWeb.com 

 medicaldevicenow.com MPO-mag.com Nonwovens-Industry.com 

 NutraceuticalsWorld.com ODTmag.com PrintedElectronicsNow.com 

 
 

 Subscribe to a magazine: Beauty Packaging Magazine Coatings World Magazine Contract Pharma Magazine Happi Magazine Ink World Magazine Magazine Label And Narrow Web Magazine MPO-mag Magazine Nutraceuticals World Magazine ODT Magazine      Subscribe to eNewsletter: Beauty Packaging Magazine Coatings World Magazine Contract Pharma Magazine Happi Magazine Ink World Magazine Magazine Label And Narrow Web Magazine MPO-mag Magazine Nutraceuticals World Magazine ODT Magazine Printed Electronics Now 
 
Copyright©2012 Rodman Publishing / HAPPI. All Rights Reserved. All rights reserved. Use of this constitutes acceptance of our Privacy Policy 
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of Rodman Publishing / HAPPI.
	</body>
</document>
