<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005052" url="http://legalnews.findlaw.com/article/04TU8qmgYp1FD?q=%22business+law%22+OR+%22commercial+law%22+OR+%22tax+law%22+OR+%22insurance+law%22+OR+%22tax+return%22+OR+%22tax+liability%22+OR+%22tax+fraud%22+OR+%22tax+break%22+OR+%22tax+cut%22+OR+%22tax+increase%22+OR+%22tax+shelter%22+OR+antitrust+OR+%22insider+trading%22+OR+%22sarbanes-oxley%22++OR+%22department+of+the+treasury%22+OR+%22treasury+secretary%22+OR+%28%28%22small+business%22+OR+business+OR+commercial%29+AND+%28law+OR+legislation+OR+legalize%29%29+OR+%28%28incorporation+OR+merger+OR+SEC+OR+FTC+OR+securities+OR+shareholder+OR+stock+OR+commodities+OR+%22Wall+Street%22+OR+investment+OR+privately-held+OR+%22publicly+traded%22+OR+VC+OR+%22venture+capital%22+OR+%22investment+firm%22+OR+Funding%29+AND+%28company+OR+startup+OR+founder+OR+investor+OR+investors+OR+members+OR+chairman+OR+CEO+OR+IPO+OR+board+OR+chairman+OR+president%29%29+OR+%22employment+law%22+OR+%22labor+law%22+OR+%28business+AND+%28contract+OR+lawsuit+OR+dispute%29%29" time="2012-07-12-21:34" support="1" score="0.0007621248545330076" bingtitle="Coca-Cola ends ties to conservative law writers" webtitle="Coca-Cola ends ties to conservative law writers">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Fast food restaurant sued by former employee 3 ... ticket at a Baltimore County 7-Eleven has not come forward. Double-check your ticket before tossing it in the trash, said ...</description>
	<body>
		Are you a legal professional? 
 Visit Our Professional Site Law firm marketing Search 
 Learn About the Law Find a Lawyer FindLaw Answers Legal Forms News Blogs 
 
 FindLaw Legal Pulse Story 
 FindLaw: AP News 3 months ago 
Coca-Cola ends ties to conservative law writers
 
The decision to &quot;discontinue its membership&quot; came Wednesday, just a few hours after the black online advocacy group ColorofChange began a campaign against the company&apos;s support of ALEC. Coca-Cola declined to respond to additional questions, including... Full Article at FindLaw: AP News 
 
 Related Articles from FindLaw 
 
There are no results for this module. Edit the module to change the search term used to query related articles.
 
 Related Articles from Attorneys 
 
There are no results for this module. Edit the module to change the search term used to query related articles.
 
 Related Articles from the web 
 
There are no results for this module. Edit the module to change the search term used to query related articles.
 
 Share this page 
 
 Share 
 Delicious Myspace Yahoo! Buzz StumbleUpon Mixx Reddit Digg Newsvine 
 Share on Facebook Email Your Name* Your Email* Recipient&apos;s Email* (separated by commas) Message I want to share&quot;Coca-Cola ends ties to conservative law writers&quot;via FindLaw Legal Pulse with you. Send Done Share on Twitter 
 
 Search FindLaw News 
 
 All Content Articles Quotes Photos Topics 
 
 Related Photos 
 

 
 Cast of Characters 
 
There are no results for this module. You may be filtering results with a topic filter, or else there are no results. Edit the module to change the filter options or the search term used to query related topics.
 
 Related Quotes 
 
 Our message has been clear, these corporations can&apos;t come to black folks for our money by day and support laws that try to take our vote or potentially our lives by night SOURCE: FindLaw: AP News 3 months ago Our message has been clear, these corporations can&apos;t come to black folks for our money by day and support laws that try to take our vote or potentially our lives by night SOURCE: WTSP-TV St. Petersburgh 3 months ago Our message has been clear, these corporations can&apos;t come to black folks for our money by day and support laws that try to take our vote or potentially our lives by night SOURCE: 10Connects.com 3 months ago Our message has been clear, these corporations can&apos;t come to black folks for our money by day and support laws that try to take our vote or potentially our lives by night SOURCE: Pocono Record 3 months ago 
 View all Related Quotes » 

Learn More About
 Legal Topics / State Laws / Bookshelf / Blogs / FindLaw RSS Feeds / Sitemap /
 Geography Sitemap / FindLaw En Español / LawBrain / FindLaw UK / FindLaw Mobile 


Find a Lawyer
 Browse by Location / Browse by Legal Issue / Search by Name 


Find Answers
 FindLaw Answers / Community Guidelines 


Get Legal Forms
 Visit our Legal Forms site 


For Lawyers
 Visit our professional site / Edit your legal profile / Website development / Advertise on our site 


About Us
 Company History / Media / Contact Us / Privacy / Terms / Disclaimer / Advertising / Jobs 


Local Lawyers
 Atlanta Lawyers / Boston Lawyers / Chicago Lawyers / Dallas Lawyers / Houston Lawyers /
 Los Angeles Lawyers / Miami Lawyers / New York City Lawyers / Phoenix Lawyers /
 San Diego Lawyers / UK-based Lawyers / More... 


Find Us On
           
 Copyright©2012 FindLaw, a Thomson Reuters business. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
