<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005194" url="http://nutrition.about.com/od/calories/qt/1200calmenus.htm" time="2012-07-12-21:43" support="7" score="0.00776186419244945" bingtitle="Example Menu for 1200 Calorie Per Day Diet" webtitle="Example Menu for 1200 Calorie Per Day Diet">
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000869" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="146"/>
	<description>Eat Right; Weight Management; Diet and Health; Share ... You&apos;ll also need to have a good set of measuring cups ... What&apos;s In Your Food; Nutrition and Weight Loss; Nutrition ...</description>
	<body>
		Health 
 Nutrition Search 
 Nutrition Eat Right Weight Management Diet and Health 

 Share 
 Free Nutrition Newsletter! Sign Up 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 Two Menus for a 1,200 Calorie Per Day Diet 

By Shereen Jegtvig , About.com Guide

Updated July 06, 2012

About.com Health&apos;s Disease and Condition content is reviewed by our Medical Review Board 
 See More About: 
 low-calorie weight loss calorie restriction diets 
 
Use an online program like Calorie Count to help you plan and follow your low-calorie diet.
 Joshua Hodge Photography Following a low-calorie diet isn&apos;t difficult if you&apos;re prepared with all the nutrient dense foods you need. Plan all your meals and snacks for a few days or a week at a time. Choose plenty of low-calorie, high fiber fruits and vegetables, whole grains and low-fat protein sources. You&apos;ll also need to have a good set of measuring cups and measuring spoons, plus a kitchen scale until you get used to estimating your serving sizes.
Before starting a low-calorie diet, you should see your doctor. Here are two 1,200 calorie-per day menus to get you started:

1,215 Calorie Menu With No Non-Nutritive Sweeteners
 Breakfast 
 One cup oatmeal One-half cup non-fat milk One tablespoon honey One-half cup blueberries One cup plain coffee or tea as a beverage 
 Lunch 
 Two slices 100-percent whole-grain bread, deli sliced turkey breast, tomato slice, lettuce and one tablespoon mustard One-half cup sliced carrots Water as a beverage 
 Dinner 
 Three ounces baked salmon One cup green beans Salad with one cup raw spinach, five cherry tomatoes and one-half cup broccoli florets with lemon juice as a dressing Water with a slice of lemon as a beverage 
 Snacks 
 One apple with 12 almonds Several glasses of water One cup non-fat milk One-half cup plain yogurt with one tablespoon honey One cup strawberries. 
 Nutrition Information 
 Total Calories - 1,215 Total Fat - 17.7 percent (25 grams) Total Protein - 23 percent (72 grams) Total Carbohydrates - 59.3 percent (185 grams) Sodium - 1402 milligrams Sugar - 107 grams Cholesterol - 94 milligrams Saturated Fat - 5.0 grams Fiber - 28 grams 


1,218 Calorie Menu With Non-Nutritive Sweeteners
 Breakfast 
 One cup whole grain corn cereal One packet sucralose One-half cup non-fat milk One cup 100-percent orange juice as a beverage 
 Lunch 
 A salad made with two cups field greens, two ounces albacore tuna (packed in water), one-half cup cherry tomatoes with two tablespoons balsamic vinegar as a dressing. Diet soda as a beverage 
 Dinner 
 One three-ounce pork chop One baked sweet potato One cup steamed asparagus One tablespoon olive oil One small glass of white wine 
 Snacks 
 One small pita bread with two tablespoons hummus One pear One serving low-fat, sugar-free fruit-flavored yogurt One cup blueberries Two-thirds cup baby carrots with one ounce fat-free vegetable dip Several glasses of water with slices of lemon or lime 
 Nutrition Information 
 Total Calories - 1,218 Total Fat - 14.6 percent (20 grams) Total Protein - 22.6 percent (70 grams) Total Carbohydrates - 56.8 percent (176 grams) Sodium - 1,615 milligrams Sugar - 86 grams Cholesterol - 116 milligrams Saturated Fat - 5.0 grams Fiber - 24 grams 

I created these menus by using Calorie Count , where you can track your calories, find friendship and support with other dieters and even analyze your own recipes.
 Related Articles 
 1500 Calorie Sample Menu - Daily Menu for 1500 Calorie Per Day Diet 1700 Calorie Sample Menu - Daily Menu for 1700 Calorie Per Day Diet Low Carb Menu #8 - High Fiber Low Carb Menu suitable for Atkins, Protein Po... Low Carb Menu #10 - Low Carb, High Fiber, All Essential Nutrients Carbohydrates - Basic Nutrition Lesson One - Carbohydrates 
 
 Shereen Jegtvig 
Nutrition Guide

 Sign up for My Newsletter 

 Headlines Forum 
 Explore Nutrition Must Reads 
 Calorie Calculators Hydration Calculator Healthy Diet Quiz Gain Weight Anti-Inflammatory Foods 
 Most Popular 
 Hydration Calculator - Know How Much Water To Drink? Women&apos;s Caloric Intake Calculator How Do I Gain Weight? Hydration Calculator Results Men&apos;s Daily Caloric Need 
 See More About: 
 low-calorie weight loss calorie restriction diets 
 By Category 
 Start With The Basics of Nutrition Help for Healthy Weight Loss How To Gain Weight Lifetime Nutrition Disease Management and Prevention Healthy Foods Help for Eating at Restaurants and Parties Dietary Supplements Learn About Food Additives Share Your Stories and Tips Shopping and Meal Planning Nutrition Quizzes Water and Beverages 
 Nutrition 
 About.com Health Nutrition Help for Healthy Weight Loss Getting Started Example Menu for 1200 Calorie Per Day Diet 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 Also from About.com: 
 Calorie Count - Nutrition Database 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
 We comply with the HONcode standard
for trustworthy health information: verify here .
	</body>
</document>
