<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005889" url="http://www.alleewillis.com/awmok/kitschenette/2009/09/23/wendys-restaurant-tabletop/" time="2012-07-12-22:33" support="1" score="0.0017940218353100002" bingtitle="The Allee Willis Museum of Kitsch» Blog Archive » Wendy’s ..." webtitle="The Allee Willis Museum of KitschBlog ArchiveWendys Restaurant Tabletop">
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>This is a vintage tabletop from a Wendy’s fast food restaurant. ... displayed on the laminate. I use it as an end table ... rock” cups – Edgar Winter 7/11 Slurpee Cup ...</description>
	<body>
		«Previous Next» 
 
 
Wendy’s Restaurant Tabletop
 
 Submitted by jack 
September 23rd, 2009 
 

 
 
 
 
 

This is a vintage tabletop from a Wendy’s fast food restaurant. I always liked these when I was young and always wanted to take one home with me. I am sad the restaurant doesn’t use them anymore, but I was elated when I finally found one for my own. For those that don’t remember them or never saw one they have have images of old catalog ads displayed on the laminate. I use it as an end table now.
 
Categories: Brands , Certifikitsch Winners , Ephemera , Food , Furniture and Lamps , Submissions 



Allee Willis Museum of Kitsch
 
4 Responses to“Wendy’s Restaurant Tabletop”
 
 Allee Willis says: September 23, 2009 at 2:30 pm 
Although I’m a card-carrying junk food addict, Wendy’s was never my cup of tea. And this old catalog ad pattern that popped up as wallpaper in so many bathrooms starting in the late 1960s always made it hard for me to pee. But the fact that you have the actual tabletop is most impressive. Of course, what advertisements for things like liniment, shoelaces, fireplaces and toilets had to do with Wendy’s–well, I guess the last one makes sense–is anyone’s guess. Which makes it excellent Kitsch.
 Log in to Reply Gilles Snowcat says: September 23, 2009 at 10:48 pm 
Superb. My childhood’s room had a similar wallpaper.
 Log in to Reply Mark Blackwell says: September 26, 2009 at 2:27 pm 
now THIS brings back some memories…i was such a fan of wendy’s way back in day…here’s to dave thomas!
 Log in to Reply djtopcat says: September 15, 2010 at 9:52 pm 
Hey my friend has a vintage Wendy’s table just like this in her basement. She was thinking of selling it but she has no clue what it’s value might be? If anyone is interested or has more info on it feel free to shoot me an email.
This was the only reference I could find on Google. Nothing on Ebay, Craigslist etc Thanks
TC
Seattle WA
email billyblackwood@hotmail.com 
 Log in to Reply 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
 
 


 Share this page.   Subscribe to the blog.   

 
 Protected under a Creative Commons license 
 
 
 Monster Cereal Records   
 one of those“rock”cups–Edgar Winter 7/11 Slurpee Cup   
    
 
   

 
 
     
 
 
To submit something to The AWMOK or to leave a comment you have to REGISTER for an account.

Having
 your own account means you can have a Profile, Bio, Profile Photo,
 submit as much Kitsch as you want, comment on other people&apos;s Kitsch and
 have them comment on yours.
 


 
 See All aKitschionados »

   Allee Willis 
   denny 
   snappyp 
   Nessa 
   kookykitsch 
   MyFunCloset 
   Douglas Wood 
   Mark Milligan 
   shirlie williams 
   Michael Ely 
   windupkitty 
 
 See All aKitschionados »
 
 

 Get the Allee Willis Blog widget and many other great free widgets at Widgetbox ! 

 
 
 Facebook Twitter Press Contact 
 
    
 Subscribe via email: 
 
 Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
 
 
 Login » Register » 
 


 
 Denny’s Adventures In Allee’s“Willis Wonderland”–July 2011–Part 305 Slipper Floor or Dance Exercises Homemade String Holder THE Dr. FART Denny’s Adventures In Allee’s“Willis Wonderland”–July 2011–Part 302 you can say that again…….and again….. and again Allee Willis disguise Bobbi Jean White with the Ballew Sisters&amp;Smitty Gatlin Trio Snapple Iced Tea pin Denny’s Adventures In Allee Willis’“Willis Wonderland”–July 2011–Part 322 Color’s–vintage advert EGG LOVE, 14×11 (a painting by Denny) Long Time No See My new Kitchenette set Sharp Suit….. I mean Shark Suit 
     MORE» 


 
 365 Days Of September Advertising/Promotion Allee performance Allee Posts Allee Related Amusement Park Animals&amp;Birds Appliance Architecture Art Artists Ask Allee Autograph Awards Bad Translations Bathroom Beatnik Bedroom Books Brands Bubbles the artist Celebrities Certifikitsch Winners Children Classique d&apos;Camembert Clowns Clubs Collections Comic Book/Strip/Animation Comics Competitions Construction Contest Entries Contests 
 Love Is in the Hair Valentine&apos;s Day Contest 
 Costumes Cowboy Crafts Creative Process Dance Denny&apos;s Paintings Detroit Disco Drink and Bar Accessories Empowerment Ephemera Event Everything Else Exercise Families Fashion Fauna Film Financial Floral Food Furniture and Lamps Gadgets Games Go-go Green Greeting Cards Hair Hats Health&amp;Beauty High school photos Hippie Holiday Household Accessories Household Products Human Rights IconoKitschoclasts Instructional Invention Jewelry Jungle Animal Petting Zoo Keychain Kitchen Legal Love Is in the Hair Award Winners LPs&amp;Singles Machines Magazine/Newspaper Magic Medical Monster Mural Music Music–Kitsch Versions of Allee&apos;s Songs Nudity Office related Outdoors Outer Space Paintings Parade Party People Photographs Pigmy Will Pin Places Poetry Political/Patriotic Pomplamoose Postcards Poster R.I.P. Reality TV Rebellious Recipes Relaxation Religion Romantic School Seaworthy Self Help Signs Songwriting Soul Spiritual Sports Statuary/Sculptural Store display Submissions Super Ball Bounce Back Review live show Technology The Color Purple Theater Tiki Toys Transportation Travel Travel souvenir TV&amp;Radio Uniforms Video 
 


 
 Certifikitsch Of Authenkitschity Winners! 
 Classique d&apos; Camembert Winners! 
 Jungle Animal Petting Zoo 
 Love Is In The Hair Winners! 
 IconoKitschoclasts 
 


 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009
	</body>
</document>
