<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005396" url="http://popsop.com/51187" time="2012-07-12-21:56" support="1" score="0.0014746304413273197" bingtitle="McDonald’s Redesigns Its Restaurants in France to Underline the ..." webtitle="McDonald’s Redesigns Its Restaurants in France to Underline the Family Dining ConceptPOPSOP.COM. Brand news. Brand design. Package design. Branding agencies. Brand experts">
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="239"/>
	<description>... of its restaurants since 1998 when a Croatian studio njiric+njiric arhitekti has transformed a traditional fast food restaurant into ... to make a counter ... Enter your email ...</description>
	<body>
		Вернуться к стандартному виду Search Advanced Search 
 
 Popsop.ru The fastest brand news online RU EN 
 Global Brands Industry News Case Studies Opinion Expert Board Brand Insiders SBA’12 Events Agencies Archive 
 
 Global Brands 
 
 McDonald’s Redesigns Its Restaurants in France to Underline the Family Dining Concept 

21 November 2011 | By Anna Sanina

 McDonald’s is redesigning several restaurants in France. The pilot location in Villefranche Ouraga 40 km from Toulouse has already been completed by Paris-based designer Patrick Norguet .

 

 
 Photos: McDonald’s interior by Patrick Norguet, from www.psfk.com 

The fast food giant has been developing various regional architecture and interiors of its restaurants since 1998 when a Croatian studio njiric+njiric arhitekti has transformed a traditional fast food restaurant into a regional location with giant panels of chain link fence. One of the famous recent redesigns includes an urban London location by SHH which won over half a dozen design awards. Just in time as the Olympics approach and McDonald’s is the official restaurant of the Games.

Norguet was tasked to make a radical step out of a traditional McDonald’s concept that presents the chain as a family fast food dining. The foundation of the new interior design is the so called ‘root’ or a floor to ceiling high space divider that is made of birch plywood, says PSFK .

Grey and white colors of the root are diluted with colorful panels relating to McDonald’s brand color. There are also digital kiosks which allow customers to make orders without leaving their tables.

McDonalds seems to unite more and more people as the layout of the new interior provides seating for larger groups, while other current urban prototypes have seating for smaller groups and individuals.

New interior features several furniture pieces and materials by Norguet designed for other companies. The designer has altered his chair ‘STILL’ for Lapalma to make a counter stool version specially for McDonald’s. The ceramic floor tile also designed by Norguet for Lea Ceramiche covers the floor of the restaurant.

 

 

 
 Photos: McDonald’s interior by Patrick Norguet, from www.psfk.com 
 
 
 
 Popsop.com 
Tags: fast food , France , interior design , McDonald’s 
 
 Tweet 

 Send to e-mail Print 
 
Related News

 
 McDonald&apos;s to Highlight Suppliers in the New Promotion 

On the heels of Frito-Lay’s...

 15 December 2011
 
 Lacoste Will Launch Its Lab with New Products for Active Life 

Lacoste with help trendsetting Paris boutique colette will promote its new...

 29 November 2011
 
 McDonald’s Announces Commitment to Certified Sustainable Sources; Releases 2010 Corporate Responsibility Report 

McDonald&apos;s Corporation on March 9 announced its Sustainable Land Management...

 10 March 2011
 
 IKEA Created an Apartment in a Parisian Metro Station 

IKEA believes that its stores are not the only space where the brand’s houseware goods can be showcased and often takes them to city streets, opera...

 11 January 2012
 
 
Our Partners
 
Interview
 
Chris Oates, Brisk Iced Tea brand manager, USA:

 “Art is a key brand pillar for Brisk” 
 
Research
 
Interbrand&apos;s Best Global Green Brands report 2012:

 Toyota, Johnson&amp;Johnson and Honda are among the Top 3 &apos;greenest&apos; brands 
 
Opinion
 
Recent M&amp;A;:

 why digital agencies are the hottest commodity for media holdings? 
 
Jobs on Popsop.com

 News editor/Feature editor/Reporter 
 
Expert Columns
 David Rogers 
 We Are Pure 
 
 Why Good Branding is Priceless 

David Rogers, owner of packaging and brand design consultancy We Are Pure, tells Popsop why he believes it should become more common in the vocabulary of agency owners and what he is doing to lead by example.
 Jonathan Ford 
 Pearlfisher 
 
 The Brand Union and Digit Announce Exclusive Partnership 

As it was a day of celebration of Independence in the US recently and as I read more reports of...
 Greg Taylor 
 Elmwood 
 
 Urbania 

With the UN predicting that 70% of the world’s population will be living in cities by 2050, this urban pilgrimage shows no sign of letting up. The result is the growth of the megacity.
 Renée Whitworth 
 Flood Creative 
 
 Trend: “Super” Themes 

Keep your eyes peeled this summer for the “super” undertones in all types of communication. As multi-tasking becomes a permanent and ubiquitous part of the new life experience, marketers are following suit with products that likewise do more in an effort to help us be more.
 Gaston van de Laar 
 CARTILS 
 
 Limited Edition Designs: the Rule of Trinity 

Only three aspects are essential in driving a successful limited edition: brand recognition, brand story, and brand inspiration. At CARTILS, we call this the Limited Edition Trinity® that, when well balanced and executed, should bring great and inspiring design to the brand.
 
Subscribe to our daily rss-to-email
 
 
 
Subscribe to our newsletter
 
 

 
 
 
 About Us Popsop Russia Privacy Policy Terms of Use Advertising Jobs Contact Us 
 

 Copyright©2012 Popsop Ltd. All rights reserved. Brand news. Brand design. Package design. Branding agencies. Brand experts | media@popsop.com
	</body>
</document>
