<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005865" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g155042-d774190-Reviews-Burger_Baron_Drive_In-Regina_Saskatchewan.html" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="1" score="0.0016409949763078894" bingtitle="Burger Baron Drive In, Regina - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor" webtitle="Burger Baron Drive In, Regina - 21 Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>Would always pick BB over the other multi ... This is the worst fast food restaurant in Regina I have eating ... hour work day...the girl at the cash got my order ...</description>
	<body>
		Burger Baron Drive In, Regina
 
 Home Regina 
 Regina Tourism Regina Hotels Flights to Regina Regina Restaurants Things to Do in Regina Regina Travel Forum Regina Photos Regina Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; Canada &gt; Saskatchewan &gt; Regina &gt; Regina Restaurants &gt; Burger Baron Drive In 
 
 All 257 Regina Restaurants» 
Burger Baron Drive In
 681 Albert St , Regina , Saskatchewan S4R 2P4 , Canada (306) 522-0323 Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #80 of 257 restaurants in Regina 21 Reviews Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
21 reviews from our community
 55% Recommend 
 Excellent 6 Very good 6 Average 1 Poor 1 Terrible 7 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 21 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any PLAYA155043 Saskatoon, Canada Contributor 16 reviews Reviews in 5 cities 4 helpful votes “Best burger!” Reviewed July 10, 2012 NEW 
Burger baron has the best burger anywhere for a fast-food chain! Mushroom burger is my fav and keeps me coming back!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 11 more reviews by PLAYA155043 for Regina Judith S Regina, Canada Senior Contributor 37 reviews Reviews in 4 cities 2 helpful votes “Always Great!” Reviewed July 5, 2012 
Service is excellent, food is hot and fresh, friendly staff, a place to return to again and again
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 27 more reviews by Judith S for Regina 40years1970 Regina, Canada Contributor 15 reviews Reviews in 4 cities 5 helpful votes “Great burger!” Reviewed May 29, 2012 
One of the go to places in Regina for a great hamburger. Prefer the location on Albert, but the eastend one is good also. Have been going to Burger Baron for 45 years. Introduced numerous family members to this great burger.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by 40years1970 for Regina Elliott T Vancouver, Canada Top Contributor 60 reviews Reviews in 16 cities 39 helpful votes “A Regina must!” Reviewed May 29, 2012 
Try and eat at Burger Baron when in Regina if you can. As far as I know they&apos;re a Saskatchewan only chain of burger shops and they serve great food. They are a little slow, but definitely worth the wait.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by Elliott T for Regina Bill R Vancouver Senior Contributor 46 reviews Reviews in 22 cities 5 helpful votes “Nice change from BK and McD” Reviewed May 21, 2012 
The burger combo had fried onion on a charbroiled burger, the bun was white but fresh and large. I took the Yam fries option over reg fries or salad - no extra charge for yam fries!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? MFamilyTraveller Edmonton, Canada Top Contributor 79 reviews Reviews in 37 cities 22 helpful votes “Not sure why it&apos;s so&quot;legendary&quot;” Reviewed May 13, 2012 
Although many locals may rave about the burgers at Burger Baron, we just couldn&apos;t see why.
We thought we&apos;d try it as because of its purported reputation for a quick bite to eat and a great burger. We&apos;re sorry to say we were greatly disappointed (which is an understatement!) The food just tasted fake to us - no&quot;wow&quot;and... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by MFamilyTraveller for Regina AmalfiRegina Regina, Canada Senior Contributor 38 reviews Reviews in 13 cities 12 helpful votes “Its a burger legend in Regina.” Reviewed March 27, 2012 
Typical burger joint. Locally owned. Burgers have a great sauce.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 15 more reviews by AmalfiRegina for Regina Meegs_RT Regina, Canada Senior Contributor 21 reviews Reviews in 8 cities 15 helpful votes “Not a fan!” Reviewed March 4, 2012 
Some people love Burger Baron, but I just don&apos;t like their burgers.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 7 more reviews by Meegs_RT for Regina coldbearinsk Regina Contributor 15 reviews Reviews in 3 cities 14 helpful votes “Great mushroom burger” Reviewed February 23, 2012 
Awesome place to eat. Has been around longer than me (49 years) LOL
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 8 more reviews by coldbearinsk for Regina Hoot777 Melville, Canada Senior Contributor 23 reviews Reviews in 6 cities 2 helpful votes “Very unique burgers that taste great!” Reviewed February 18, 2012 
Burger Baron has its own style of burgers that are sure to please! Fast service and good food at reasonable prices!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 7 more reviews by Hoot777 for Regina 1-10 of 21 reviews « 1 2 3 » 
Travelers who viewed Burger Baron Drive In also viewed
 Memories Fine Dining 84 Reviews Regina, Saskatchewan Siam Authentic Thai Restaurant 30 Reviews Regina, Saskatchewan   Bushwakker Brewing Co 56 Reviews Regina, Saskatchewan Creek Bistro 37 Reviews Regina, Saskatchewan   All restaurants in Regina (257) 
Been to Burger Baron Drive In? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage Burger Baron Drive In, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 Wingate by Wyndham Regina 77 Reviews Read reviews Regina, Saskatchewan Days Inn Regina 67 Reviews Read reviews Regina, Saskatchewan Delta Regina 89 Reviews Read reviews Regina, Saskatchewan 
 All hotels in Regina (27) 
Browse nearby
 Restaurants (257) | Hotels (27) | Things to Do (17) Burger Baron Drive In 681 Albert St Regina, Saskatchewan S4R 2P4 Canada Get Directions What&apos;s Nearby: Hotels Restaurants Things to Do Click map pins for more information. You are zoomed out too far to see location pins. Please zoom back in. Interactive map 
Free Regina Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Regina restaurants

 Italian Star Deli Milky Way Ice Cream Michi Japanese Restaurant Knotted Thistle Pub Bushwakker Brewing Co Siam Authentic Thai Restaurant Hanabi Japanese Sushi Restaurant Flavours Of India Greenspot Cafe Fresh and Sweet Pasta Prima Orange Izakaya Memories Fine Dining Teppanyaki Japanese House La Bodega Enso Browns Social House Peking House Afghan Restaurant The Willow On Wascana 
 
Hotels around Regina

 Days Inn Regina 3.5 out of 5, 67 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Delta Regina 3.5 out of 5, 89 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Quality Hotel Regina 3.0 out of 5, 28 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Comfort Inn Regina 3.5 out of 5, 28 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 Travelodge Hotel&amp;Conference Centre Regina 4.0 out of 5, 122 reviews Last reviewed Jul 7, 2012 Knights Inn Regina 2.5 out of 5, 17 reviews Last reviewed Jul 6, 2012 Regina Inn Hotel and Conference Centre 3.0 out of 5, 83 reviews Last reviewed Jul 5, 2012 Days Inn - Regina Airport West 4.0 out of 5, 34 reviews Last reviewed Jul 3, 2012 HomeSuites by d3h 4.5 out of 5, 27 reviews Last reviewed Jul 3, 2012 Ramada Hotel&amp;Convention Centre 3.5 out of 5, 129 reviews Last reviewed Jun 29, 2012 Chateau Regina Hotel&amp;Suites 3.5 out of 5, 79 reviews Last reviewed Jun 27, 2012 Sandman Hotel and Suites Regina 3.0 out of 5, 33 reviews Last reviewed May 24, 2012 Sunrise Motel 3.5 out of 5, 12 reviews Last reviewed May 23, 2012 West Harvest Inn 4.0 out of 5, 41 reviews Last reviewed May 20, 2012 Turgeon International Hostel 2.5 out of 5, 11 reviews Last reviewed Apr 16, 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 Swiss Chalet 3.5 out of 5, 6 reviews Duck Deli 4.0 out of 5, 57 reviews Senzairo 3.0 out of 5, 1 review Crown Inn 4.0 out of 5, 19 reviews Sparrow in Montreal 4.5 out of 5, 9 reviews Old Town Mexican Cafe in San Diego 3.5 out of 5, 270 reviews 
 Hotels 
 Oakes Hotel Overlooking the Falls in Niagara Falls 3.5 out of 5, 1,083 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Hotel Grand Teguise Playa 4.0 out of 5, 247 reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 Breakers Hotel Myrtle Beach 4.0 out of 5, 826 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Seaecho Beach Pension 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor®features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, vacation packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Some photos provided by VFM Leonardo. * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
