<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005393" url="http://hypervocal.com/news/2011/yet-another-fast-food-fight-woman-in-bikini-goes-beserker-at-burger-king/" time="2012-07-12-21:56" support="2" score="0.0036361470239541" bingtitle="Fast-Food Fights: Woman in Bikini Goes Beserker at Burger King" webtitle="Fast-Food Fights: Woman in Bikini Goes Beserker at Burger King">
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>... as Kimesia Smith of Montgomery, Ala., jumped up on the counter and threw a charity coin jug at employees, and 3 of Smith’s friends also began throwing napkins, utensils ...</description>
	<body>
		10 Celebrities From the ’90s Who Aught-smarted Us All 
 
 10 Awesome Superhero Mash-ups to Join ‘Breaking Batman’ 
 
 20 Best &apos;Arrested Development&apos; Inside Jokes and Recurring Gags 
 
 Reddit Cracked a Mysterious Cipher That Might Be a Viral Marketing Scam 
 
 MLB Report: 2012&apos;s Top 5 Mid-season Player Surprises 
 
 All This Cow Wants Is a Kiss From Her Dog Friend 
 
 P&amp;G;&apos;s &apos;Kids&apos; 2012 Olympics Ad Saluting Mothers Is Terrific, Familiar 
 
 Watch Gus Fring on &apos;Sesame Street,&apos; and Other Web Goodness 
 
 
 
 
 
 Read It. Like It. Share It. 
 News Politics Music Media LGBT Sx/Culture Entourage 
 search 
 Sinners/Saints Sports Entertainment Vids 
 
HV-Rated
 Back to all stories 
Yet Another Fast-Food Fight: Woman in Bikini Goes Beserker at Burger King
 Posted March 24, 2011 2:03pm by HVculture Tags: Burger King , Denny&apos;s , Fast Food Fights , Florida , Kimesia Smith , Panama City Beach 
 Tweet Email 

 Tweet Email 

We’re fighting at Denny’s . ( Often, it seems .) We’re fighting in taco shops . ( Drag queens, too .) Fast-food joints have become the de facto venue for public fights that end up on YouTube.

And one of the original fast-food joints apparently didn’t want to be left behind. So one Burger King in Panama City Beach, Florida, last weekend played host to an unusual one—a bikini-clad woman throwing, ahem, a whopper of tantrum and nearly inciting a small riot in the King’s court.

Warning: harsh language and video hilarity ensue.

 

 According to WJHG ,“Employees dialed 9-1-1 for help, as one bikini-clad woman, later identified as Kimesia Smith of Montgomery, Ala., jumped up on the counter and threw a charity coin jug at employees, and 3 of Smith’s friends also began throwing napkins, utensils, and trays throughout the location.

The woman in the bikini, who became concerned about the whereabouts of her two children after Panama City Beach Police placed her in handcuffs, was taken to the Bay County Jail on charges of simple battery, in part because of allegations she pulled a Burger King employee’s hair. Beach police contacted a friend of the woman, who told police she would take care of Smith’s children.”

We’re excited to see which fast-food joint will next play host to this growing lack of civility.
 
MOST RECENT BY HVculture:

 Is This the Creepiest &apos;Personal Massager&apos; You&apos;ve Ever Seen? Here&apos;s a Young, Pre-Fame Ryan Reynolds Holding a Puppy Taco Bell 1, Old Spice 0: Twitter Flame War Over Fire Sauce 
 Posted March 24, 2011 2:03pm 


 


 

 
 http://Website Leon 
As a black man, I am truely embarrassed. That does nothing for our race but perpetuate sterotypes in black people. Congrats Ms. Kimesia Smith, you have officially become ghetto trash. Now go spend some food stamps on your half-dozen kids.
 http://Website Lulz 
We should deport that trash back to Africa.
 http://Website Lulz 
Do you think they asked her if she wanted a burger with that shake?
 http://Website Lulz 
What started the fight is that The King gave her the secret sauce and got her pregnant. She is mad that he dont wanna pay no child support now so she can buys her a Louis Viton purse.
 
 http://Website Leon 
It’s Louis Vuitton, sweetheart. Maybe you should join them on that boat back to Africa.
 
 http://Website Lulz 
I guess you would know. Actually I was thinking more of an airdrop instead of a boat. Weren’t you the one in the yellow shirt?
 
 http://Website Leon 
Yes, I would know. I’m educated. Yellow shirt? LOL! That’s funny! Hope it didn’t hurt too much coming up with that one. You know what the difference is between you and those morons? You prolly don’t eat at Burger King. Just sayin’…
 
 http://Website Lulz 
You educated?? I doubt it as your comebacks are weak. My guess is that you are the token black dude on some website that likes to make it seem that you are better then the people in the vid. FTW
 
 
 
 
 http://Website Leon 
Ding, ding, ding….Ur right. U win…
 
Pingback: Stop Us If You&apos;ve Heard This One: A Fight Breaks Out in Denny&apos;s | HyperVocal 
 
Pingback: VIDEO: Brutal McDonald&apos;s Beating in NYC Caught on Tape | HyperVocal 
 
Pingback: Don&apos;t Faze Me, Bro: Man Uninterested in NYC McDonald&apos;s MMA Bout 
 
 Follow @hypervocal Sign up for The Hype e-Newsletter sign-up email address subscribe 
 
 10 Celebrities From the ’90s Who Aught-smarted Us All 
 
 20 Best &apos;Arrested Development&apos; Inside Jokes and Recurring Gags 
 
 20 Weirdest Etsy Items of 2012 
 
 New York City&apos;s Vigilante Soda Police Enforce Bloomberg&apos;s Ban 
 
 
 News Politics Entertainment Media Sx/Culture Vids Sinners/Saints Sports LGBT Music Entourage 
 
 About Us Contact Us Write For Us Advertise Privacy/Terms of Use Partners Jobs/Internships 
 email address sign-up 

 
Join the HyperVocal E-Newsletter to Get The Most Vital&amp;Viral Stories in your Inbox. If you already have, just click the X to the right and go read some more HyperVocal. You deserve it!
 * indicates required Email Address * First Name Last Name Close 
Hypervocal copyright©2012. All Rights Reserved. info@hypervocal.com
	</body>
</document>
