<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005566" url="http://www.times-standard.com/statenews/ci_20377591/march-foreclosure-activity-down-near-5-year-low" time="2012-07-12-22:07" support="5" score="0.017067749035503534" bingtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low - Times ..." webtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low - Times-Standard Online">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>Cars. Place an Ad; Deals on Wheels; Jobs. Place an Ad; Classifieds ... March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low ... Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are ...</description>
	<body>
		Mobile  |  Digital Subscribe  |  e-edition  |  Print Subscribe 

   
 Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH   Site   Web Subscriber Services 

 
 Home News 
 Local News State News On The Record Business Local Gas Prices Earthquakes Web Cams Videos Special Sections 
 Lifestyle Opinion 
 Editorials Guest Opinion Letters Dave Stancliff 
 Sports 
 Prep Sports Humboldt Crabs Fishing the North Coast 
 Entertainment 
 Humboldt Dining Guide TV Listings Horoscopes Lottery Results Photo Galleries 
 Obituaries Announcements 
 Anniversaries Engagements Weddings Announcement Forms 
 

 Shopping Cars 
 Place an Ad Deals on Wheels 
 Jobs 
 Place an Ad 
 Classifieds 
 Garage Sales Business&amp;Service Dir Tri-City Weekly Place an Ad Today&apos;s Ads All Top Listings Legal&amp;Public Notices 
 Real Estate 
 On the Market 
 
 
 

 

 
 
 

 

 
 
 
 
Thank you for visiting Eureka Times Standard .
 We are sorry the article that you requested is no longer available. Please search for this article in our archive search .
 
 
 
 Readers:
• Read our FAQ and let us know what you think of the new commenting system 
•Experiencing any glitches or bugs with the commenting system? Are any of your comments disappearing? Report these instances and note the date, time and article your comment was made. 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Most Viewed Most E-Mailed 
 (From the last 12 hours) 
 Federal raids net 13; Drug Enforcement Agency serves SoHum search... Calling all truckers: Driver shortage could affect Humboldt County Jury finds three people not guilty of violating urgency ordinance;... EPD investigating possible homicide; 48-year-old dies of suspected... Possible assault victim dies of injuries Monday Woman sues doctors after &apos;nightmare&apos; birth; Eureka woman alleges she... Updated: One-way controlled traffic on State Route 299 due to fire Man arrested after trying to hide gun in planter Baseball bat battery leaves one jailed; Briceland man held on... Shell WindEnergy pulls plug on Bear River Ridge wind project; locals... 
 (From the last 12 hours) 
 Federal raids net 13; Drug Enforcement Agency serves SoHum search... Report challenges Mexico&apos;s choices in drug war Calling all truckers: Driver shortage could affect Humboldt County Humboldt says no wage increase for home care workers; fact-finding... Employee rings up $236K on company credit card Blood bank calls for donors; types O, A needed most Time for different direction on Klamath Dam removal Police: Tracy motel owner, 62, killed by naked man 
 
 
 
 
   Job     Home     Car     Rental   
 
   OPTICIAN NEEDED   (Job) CERTIFIED NURSING ASSISTANTS   (Job) District Service Advisor   (Job) OPTICIAN NEEDED   (Job) OPTICIAN NEEDED   (Job) Eureka Campus, Systems Operator   (Job) DIRECTOR OF PATIENT SERVICES   (Job) Lifetouch job fair   (Job) Would you...   (Job) Would you...   (Job) Eureka Campus, Systems Operator   (Job) FISCAL ASSISTANT I   (Job) Lifetouch job fair   (Job) Would you...   (Job) Patient Financial Services Manager   (Job) All Listings 
 
   MOVE TO The Sunshine   (Home) Offices for Lease   (Home) FERNDAL CLOTHING   (Home) REAL ESTATE AUCTION   (Home) Open House   (Home) MOVE TO The Sunshine   (Home) MOVE TO The Sunshine   (Home) All Listings 
 
   &apos;90 FORD 350 Econoline   (Car) Ford Bronco II   (Car) &apos;02 SUBARU FORESTER   (Car) 2003 Montana 5th Wheel   (Car) 2010 Energy Toy Hauler   (Car) 1999 Mercedes Benz   (Car) &apos;03 FORD F250 Tailgate   (Car) All Listings 
 
   STUDIO APT. in Orick   (Rental) Large 3 bd   (Rental) KING SALMON 2 bd   (Rental) EKA, 3/1 Duplex   (Rental) Eka 3bd/2ba   (Rental) EXTENDED STAY   (Rental) Room ($425) Studio (560)   (Rental) Arcata 1bd   (Rental) Fortuna Rental   (Rental) EKA, 3/1 Duplex   (Rental) Room ($425) Studio (560)   (Rental) MCK 4 bd. 2 ba.   (Rental) Home Rentals   (Rental) Homes for Rent   (Rental) MCK Cozy 2 bd 4 plex.   (Rental) All Listings 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 

 Copyright©- Times-Standard

 MediaNews Group - Northern California Network
	</body>
</document>
