<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005632" url="http://www.recipelion.com/Breakfast-Recipes/Quick-and-Easy-Breakfast-Recipes-15-Tasty-Easy-Breakfast-Ideas" time="2012-07-12-22:12" support="8" score="0.023800037945427188" bingtitle="Quick and Easy Breakfast Recipes: 15 Tasty, Easy Breakfast Ideas ..." webtitle="Quick and Easy Breakfast Recipes:  15 Tasty, Easy Breakfast Ideas | RecipeLion.com">
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="82"/>
	<description>Well, don&apos;t bother wasting gas and time going to that fast-food restaurant. Here is a collection of 15 — count &apos;em — 15 quick and easy breakfast recipes to help you ...</description>
	<body>
		Tweet 
Follow Us on Facebook

Get updates from RecipeLion.com posted directly to your News Feed.
 
 
 My Recipe Box My Newsletters Log In Register Now 
 
 Site Map RSS Bookmark 
 
 Blog Casseroles Cheap Meals Copycat Free eCookbooks Printable Grocery Coupons Reviews&amp;Giveaways 
 
 
Categories

 Breakfast Recipes 
 Muffins Pancakes and Waffles Scones Egg Recipes Cereals Breakfast Bread Recipes Omelets and Frittatas Healthy Egg Recipes 
 Appetizers Beans Beef Recipes Bread Budget Friendly Cake Candy Recipes Casserole Recipes Chicken Recipes Cookies&amp;Bars Cooking Tips Dairy Dessert Drink Recipes Dry Mixes Editor&apos;s Picks Ethnic Food Featured Foodies Food Companies Foodie Reviews Fruit Grilling Holidays Meat Recipes Microwave Modified Diet Pasta Pie Recipes Pizza Pork Recipes Preserving Pressure Cooker Restaurant Recipes Rice Salad Sandwiches Sauces Seafood Side Dishes Slow Cooker Snacks Soups, Stews, Chili Substitutions Turkey Vegetables Vegetarian Your Favorite Brands 
 
 Home &gt; Breakfast Recipes &gt; Quick and Easy Breakfast Recipes: 15 Tasty, Easy Breakfast Ideas
 (1) 
 
Quick and Easy Breakfast Recipes: 15 Tasty, Easy Breakfast Ideas

By: Nina Hoffman, RecipeLion.com
 
You must be logged in to add a private note. Login | Register 
 
My Notes
 
My Notes

ONLY YOU see your private notes.
 
 Notes Print My Recipe Box Add Rate Comment 
 
We are adding the recipe to your Recipe Box.

This was added to your Recipe Box.

 Click here to view your Recipe Box. 

You must be logged in to add a recipe. Login | Register 
 
 
Rate This Article
 Very Poor Poor OK Good Very Good 
Comment On This Article
 
 
We are adding your Comments&amp;Rating. 

Thank you! Your Comment&amp;Rating have been added and will be posted shortly.

You must be logged in to rate or leave a comment. Login | Register 
 
Share this on:

 Twitter Digg Delicious Facebook Google StumbleUpon MySpace Email 
 
If your day starts out like so many of ours do, it’s something like this: Wake up, hit the snooze, wake up again. Rush to get ready for work, maybe grab a doughnut or mc-sandwich on the way in. If you’re lucky, there’s coffee or Coke with it. While this may seem like a viable option for an easy breakfast, it&apos;s far from ideal. So many of us share this same dilemma. We’re in a hurry and don’t have time to make any breakfast recipes at all, so we just grab a cup of coffee. The thing is, there are so many easy breakfast recipes out there that don’t take a lot of time.

Certainly, lack of time is something we can all relate to. We want to sleep as late as we can, but unfortunately we end up compromising in the area of breakfast because we feel there is no such thing as quick and easy breakfast recipes. More often than not, we do grab that fast food breakfast. Well, don&apos;t bother wasting gas and time going to that fast-food restaurant. Here is a collection of 15—count &apos;em—15 quick and easy breakfast recipes to help you get a better start to your day . 

 

 Table of Contents 

  

 Easy Pancake Recipes 

 

 Easy Waffle Recipes 

 

 Easy Breakfast Casserole Recipes 

 

 Easy Egg Recipes 

 

 Easy Muffin Recipes 

 

 Easy Pancake Recipes 

 Blueberry Buttermilk Pancakes —Everyone loves a fluffy blueberry pancake on a Saturday morning. Try this delicious recipe that uses creamy buttermilk and fresh or frozen blueberries. Try switching out half of the flour for whole-wheat flour for a variation.

 

 Super Simple Pumpkin Pancakes —Pumpkin recipes don&apos;t have to be difficult to be delicious. Try these super simple pumpkin pancakes and you&apos;ll see what we mean. Make a double batch and invite your friends for Sunday brunch.

 
 Whole-Wheat Buttermilk Pancakes —Whole-Wheat Buttermilk Pancakes are a great way to create naturally sweetened pancakes that are healthy. The whole-wheat flour gives the pancakes a thicker consistency and a nuttier flavor that you will love!

 

 Back to Table of Contents 

 

 Easy Waffle Recipes 

 Basic Waffle Recipe with Variations —This is the perfect easy waffle recipe, especially if you&apos;ve never made them before. It&apos;s simple to make and has practically endless variations. There are some listed here, but you can come up with your own as well. Eat &apos;em up!

 

 Buttermilk Waffles —If you&apos;ve been on the lookout for a nice easy basic waffle recipe, your search is over! These buttermilk waffles are simple and delicious, so whip up a batch today and enjoy a tasty breakfast.

 

 Pumpkin Nut Waffles —Pumpkin Nut Waffles Waffles are a delicious way to start your day, and pumpkin recipes are always yummy. Why not combine the two? Make these tasty pumpkin nut waffles and enjoy them for breakfast soon. You can even make them ahead and freeze them...just defrost any time.

 

 Back to Table of Contents 

 

 Easy Breakfast Casserole Recipes 

 Cheesy Brunch Casserole —This breakfast casserole has been a favorite for ages! Rather than using just whole eggs, we use egg whites for a portion, and the fat-free and low-fat cheese combination gives it a really rich flavor.

 

 Semi-Homemade Breakfast Casserole —This Semi-Homemade Breakfast Casserole only requires 6 ingredients, and chances are you have them in your kitchen. Using seasoned croutons will cut back your time without cutting back on flavor.

 

 Velveeta Breakfast Casserole —Who doesn&apos;t love Velveeta cheese, and what better way to eat it than for breakfast? This casserole have everything you love about breakfast: eggs, cheese, hash browns and sausage!

 

 Back to Table of Contents 

 

 Easy Egg Recipes 

 Easy Eggs Bernaise —This eggs Bernaise recipe (or do you say Bearnaise?) is so simple, it practically makes itself! Just take a look and you&apos;ll see what an easy breakfast recipe this really is.

 

 Saucy BBQ Omelet —If you are a breakfast-lover who also loves barbecue, this omelet is for you. Made with part eggs and part egg whites, it&apos;s a lower fat alternative, too. Plenty of flavor here!

 

 Scrambled Eggs with Cream Cheese —A scrambled egg breakfast doesn&apos;t get much easier than this! The surprise is the wonderful flavor imparted by the cream cheese. You have to experience it for yourself - make this easy breakfast recipe today!

 

 Back to Table of Contents 

 

 Easy Muffin Recipes 

 6-Week Bran Muffins —This bran muffin batter is quick and easy. Mix up a bowl of batter and leave it in the fridge for up to six weeks, baking fresh muffins for a healthy breakfast or snack as you like.

 

 Almond Peach Muffins —These Almond Peach Muffins are a quick and easy recipe you can make any day. All you need to do is mix ingredients and put in the oven. These are great breakfast foods or can be eaten as a snack.

 

 Quick Cheese and Bacon Muffins —These quick cheese and bacon muffins are the perfect breakfast! Where else can you get eggs, cheese, and bacon all in one handy take-along meal? Make a double batch and watch them disappear.

 

 Back to Table of Contents 

 
 
Related Recipes
 
 325 Favorite Christmas Recipes 

 &quot;Celebrate Mom: 26 Terrific Mothers Day Recipes&quot; Free eCookbook 

 17 Excellent Easter Recipes Free eCookbook 
 
 Notes Print My Recipe Box Add Rate Comment 
 
Newsletter Signup
 
Free Newsletter!

Subscribe to our free recipe newsletter and we will send you delicious recipes and special offers to your inbox. Sign up today!
 
Please Wait 

Thanks for signing up

Sorry, we could not sign you up.
 
What&apos;s Hot
 
Top Breakfast Recipes

 All-in-One Breakfast Sandwich 16 Heavenly Cinnamon Roll Recipes&amp;Coffee Cake Recipes 9 Easy Breakfast Casserole Recipes 11 Baked French Toast Recipes, Plus Bonus New Recipe! 18 Recipes for Overnight Christmas Casseroles 10 Easy Breakfast Recipes Best Make Ahead Potato Breakfast Casserole Brunch Egg and Cheese Casserole Island Sticky Puffs Cheesy Bacon&amp;Egg Brunch Casserole 
 My Recipe Box (0) View» 
Something worth saving?

 Register now for FREE to:

 SAVE your favorite recipes ADD personal notes GET fast cooking tips 
 
 Log In 
 
 Join Us Today Forgot Password 
 
 
 
Free eCookbooks
 
 39 Appetizer Recipes and Party Pleasers Must-Have Meatloaf Recipes Simple Mexican Recipes Simple Slow Cooker Suppers Tasty, Easy Breakfast Recipes Top Secret Copycat Restaurant Recipes 
 
Connect with Us

Find us online

 
 
 
 About Us Advertise Contact Us FAQs Keyword Index News Privacy Policy Subscribe Terms of Service Unsubscribe 
 
 
©Copyright 2012 Prime Publishing, LLC. All rights reserved.
 
 
©Copyright 2012 Prime Publishing, LLC. All rights reserved.

www.recipelion.com
 
Log In to Your Account
 
 Register Now! Forgot Password? 
 Email: Password:   Login with Facebook 
Register Now!
 
 Log In Forgot Password? 
 Public/Display Name: Optional: This is the name that will appear alongside any reviews you create on the site. You can use letters, numbers and white space. First Name: Last Name: Email:
	</body>
</document>
