<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005412" url="http://www.naturallyempowered.com/html/h_info/food.html" time="2012-07-12-21:58" support="5" score="0.017393176436670453" bingtitle="Healthy Diet - Naturally Empowered Fantastic Health" webtitle="Healthy Diet">
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000160" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000409" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>A famous fast-food restaurant donates money to a charitable ... canned foods, boxed foods, packaged foods, soups, sauces, condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Healthy Diet

 Let&apos;s Wake Up! Definite Do&apos;s Definite Don&apos;ts Helpful/ Harmful for Some 

Click here to see an example of An Exceptionally Healthy Diet .

Check out the Naturally Empowered Health Shake .  This is the most comprehensive health shake available anywhere, and is part of an exceptionally healthy diet.

 Let&apos;s Wake Up!

As a society, we are collectively sleeping.

 Let&apos;s wake up! Do you really and truly want to be
 healthy?

Right after the LOVE&amp;HAPPINESS component
 of health, the FOOD&amp;NUTRIENTS category has produced the most dramatic changes in
 health
 that I have ever seen. Amazing changes - simply by eating a much more healthy diet. By improving nutrition,
 I have seen improvements in problems and illnesses that were chronic,
 problems that were thought to be&quot;irreversible&quot;, and
 changes toward incredible new life and vitality for those who decided
 they
 wanted
 to take action and do something wonderful for themselves like consuming a healthy diet.

I see irony everywhere: Organizations that fundraise for the Cancer
 Society sell hotdogs and pop - both substances are loaded with cancer-causing
 chemicals.  Let&apos;s wake up! Illness-producing hospital
 foods like jello and puddings are given to the sickest of patients
 in order to&quot;help&quot;them recover.  And what about those
 coffee and pop machines in the hospital that help increase the stress
 load
 on the patient&apos;s family members while they sit by their loved ones
 with concern? Let&apos;s wake up!  A famous fast-food restaurant
 donates money to a charitable foundation for gastrointestinal
 disease, yet the foods they sell contribute to these diseases. Let&apos;s
 wake up! Girl Guide events that promote the learning,
 growth and nurturing of our young girls, ask parents to bring
 cookies,
 cakes, doughnuts and&quot;treats&quot;to these events - foods
 that are devitalizing, promote chronic degenerative diseases and
 are
 anything
 but nurturing
 and growth-producing for our young girls. Let&apos;s wake up! Parents
 that give sugary chemically laced&quot;treats&quot;to their children,
 trying to be helpful, but in the end&quot;treat&quot;their children
 to a whole host of chronic degenerative diseases later in life. Let&apos;s
 wake up! What about treating your children and yourself
 to wonderful health, ease and comfort for a lifetime instead of
 a momentary fix?

 Every single cell in your body is made from the food
 and beverages you consume. It&apos;s really simple: a healthy diet of high quality food
 creates high quality and healthy cells. I also believe and have witnessed
 over and over that poor food choices lead to symptoms, illness, disease
 and relapse from good health.

I believe
 that you are your own best healthcare expert. If you are healthy,
 happy, have boundless energy, no problems or symptoms of any
 kind, are of an excellent body weight, have clear eyes, healthy
 skin, healthy hair and have a vibrant joy for living, then
 the
 diet you are eating is obviously working well for you, whatever
 that diet may be - at least for the present time. However,
 if you cannot attest to the previous statement of incredible health,
 then perhaps you may wish to reconsider that your diet isn&apos;t
 as healthy as you think it is.

The following information comes directly from my clinical experience
 as a naturopathic physician. And for those of you who are wondering
 (I am asked this many times), yes, I walk my talk; - completely.
 I follow what I recommend to patients each and every day. This is because
 I enjoy feeling extraordinarily vital and alive.

I&apos;m not going to beat around the bush. Many healthcare practitioners
 will say:&quot;limit your consumption of _____&quot;. Nope, not I. The patients
 whom I have seen take off with their health and blossom, do not straddle
 any line of semi-commitment.

I also understand that for many of you, the following suggestions may be a 180 degree turn from your present dietary habits. I invite you to change as quickly or as slowly as you desire. Each one of us has our own pace in becoming exceptionally well, as we are the architects of our own health. We are all doing the best we can at any given moment. 

 Let&apos;s all wake up to a wonderful and vibrant world of healthy bodies, healthy minds and a healthy planet!!

My suggestions are clear and to the point. These dietary suggestions dramatically improve immune function, decrease inflammation, regulate hormones more effeciently, support mental and emotional health through optimizing the nervous system, heal digestive problems, and help generate healthy cells instead of diseased ones. My suggestions are based on clinically observing thousands of patients:

 Definite Do&apos;s

 If you eat beef , poultry or lamb , make sure
 it is organic, grass-fed and free-range grown with no antibiotics
 or hormones. This is one area that I never compromise on. Have you
 ever seen how our mass-produced livestock are raised? The living
 conditions of these animals and the poor quality of feed they consume,
 render this meat to be health destroying. If you are eating these
 foods at restaurants, you have a 99.9% chance of ingesting these
 health-destroying meats because most restaurants do not serve organic
 meat. High quality organic red meats (beef, buffalo, lamb and wild
 game) are best consumed not more than once weekly. Poor quality red
 meats and poultry are best avoided entirely.

 Fruits and vegetables .
 At least 8 - 10 servings daily.
 This is a case where more is better when it comes to vegetables.
 30% of people I see do not tolerate potatoes and corn. Many people
 are fine with raw tomatoes, however cooked tomato sauces are not
 tolerated well by many. When it comes to fruits and vegetables, organic
 and fresh are always best, however, for those who are unable
 to hit the 8 - 10 daily servings mark, I recommend Greens
 Formula . 

 Grow your own organic sprouts . In this way you depend on
 yourself year-round for daily organic fresh greens that help prevent
 cancer and increase your vitality. Fresh living sprouts, chuck
 loaded with living enzymes, vitamins and minerals that YOU can grow
 yourself,
 is one of the best healthy diet tips I can give you. A mixed blend
 of sprout
 seeds including broccoli is the most helpful. There are many
 ways to grow sprouts and I&apos;ve tried most of these ways. The cheapest
 way is by using a wide mouth glass jar and the healthiest way of
 growing sprouts by this method can be found on pg. 207 of the book &quot;The
 Complete Natural Medicine Guide to BREAST CANCER&quot; written by
 Dr. Sat Dharam Kaur N.D. However, this method is labour intensive.
 By far, the healthiest and least labour intensive way of growing
 sprouts is by using the EasyGreen Sprouter as these sprouts
 are automatically rinsed and nourished with a constant supply of
 fresh clean water and the old skunky waste water is constantly
 drained from the unit. The result is a cleaner and healthier sprout.
 As well,
 this sprouter ensures varying growing stages of the sprouts so
 you can eat fresh living food on a daily basis. This type of sprouter
 is a bit more expensive than other sprouters and I believe it is
 well worth the cost. 

 Drinking fresh vegetable juice at least
 once per week (if not daily) exponentially maximizes a healthy diet. Juice your
 own concoction. Here&apos;s one idea: use 5 medium carrots, 1/2 beet,
 2 celery
 stalks, handful of spinach, 1/2 cup cabbage, parsley, watercress and a slice of fresh ginger. 
 
 Having a Naturally Empowered Health Shake at
 least 4 - 5 times weekly is wise. It can also be used as a comprehensive nutrient-packed meal replacement for those on the run who usually skip breakfast and want to maintain a healthy diet.

 Eat fish at
 least 3 -4 times per week if
 you are not allergic to it or have not chosen to be vegetarian. High
 quality fish in my
 opinion, is by far the best source of protein available for a healthy diet.
 Wild (north pacific) salmon heads the top of the list. Salmon
 contains every amino acid, an abundant supply of essential fatty
 acids,
 and every vitamin and mineral the body requires for great health.
 Other quality fish include sardines, herring, mackerel, anchovies
 and
 trout.
 Fresh fish is best. However, if you purchase canned fish, ensure
 that it is packed in water with no chemical additives. I do not
 recommend eating tuna due to the increasing heavy metal
 toxicity found in these fish. And for goodness sake, if you are taking
 fish
 oil as a supplement, do not purchase a cheap brand. Most fish
 oils
 that are sold as supplements are not molecularly distilled for
 heavy metals. With the increasing heavy metal accumulation in fish,
 this
 is of great concern regarding toxicity . The best fish
 oils come from the following
 companies: Carlson, Nordic Naturals and Genestra. I personally
 prefer Super
 EFA Liquid because it is made from anchovies and wild salmon
 and has the highest concentration of EPA and DHA that I have
 come across. 

 Ensure that all of your oils are cold pressed and organic.
 The best oils by far are olive oil and coconut oil. People who
 don&apos;t consume fish or fish oils can benefit from using uncooked flax
 oil.

 Determine what your food allergies and sensitivities are
 by any one of the following methods: ELISA blood food allergy testing,
 electrodermal food sensitivity testing, kinesiological testing or
 eliminating foods and reintroducing them (the last method can be
 viewed in Determining food sensitivities/allergies ). In my
 experience, a combination of these various methods is most helpful.
 Most naturopathic physicians offer at least one or more of the
 first three methods; you can do the last method on your own. 

 back to top 

 Definite Don&apos;ts

 Absolutely no coffee . This includes decaffeinated. You
 urinate out so many life-giving minerals as well as stress out
 your stress glands when you consume this beverage. Absolutely none.
 Wean
 off slowly to prevent severe withdrawal headaches. The variety
 of symptoms I have seen improve with the elimination of coffee alone,
 is mind-blowing.

 Absolutely no chemicals, additives, preservatives,
 processed foods . It&apos;s amazing how many people believe they
 eat a healthy diet and consume these products in their diet every day. What are
 these found
 in? Most salad dressings, deli meats, hot dogs, hamburgers, sausages,
 most smoked meats, jerky, canned foods, boxed foods, packaged
 foods, soups, sauces, condiments (ketchup, relish, mustard, barbecue
 sauce,
 etc.), artificial sweeteners, candy bars, Kool-Aid, popsicles,
 freezies, sno-cones, ice cream, jello, most dried fruit, most
 restaurant food, and the list goes on and on. Read your labels.
 Better yet,
 don&apos;t buy packaged foods. These foods are a one-way ticket to
 the degeneration of your health.

 Absolutely no pork or shellfish .
 These foods have great propensity for toxicity. Pork contains very
 poor quality fat and
 protein. My clinical observations are simple: people who eliminate
 pork experience improvement in health and those that do not, experience
 no improvement or a decline in their health.

 Absolutely no sugar .
 Sugar is a one-way ticket to a depleted immune system and the diseases
 that follow its depletion. Fresh fruit
 is great. Everything else is downhill after that. Refined white
 sugar is the worst. Brown sugar is no better. Read your labels for
 glucose,
 dextrose, sucrose, turbinate sugar, cane syrup, invert sugar,
 galactose, maltose and corn syrup. I would also leave out even the&quot;healthy&quot;sugars
 like raw unpasteurized honey, rice syrup, fructose, organic cane
 sugar and pure maple syrup. Some people need to switch to these&quot;healthy&quot;sugars
 as a transition toward a healthy diet before they take the plunge
 toward exceptional health. Dried fruit is best if you make it
 yourself in a dehydrator. If you
 purchase dried fruit, make sure that they are unsulphured and
 organic.

 If sugar
 is a one-way ticket to disease, then artificial sweeteners make
 sugar look like a pleasure cruise. My advice to you is this:
 get off that boat now before there&apos;s no turning back.

 Absolutely
 no alcohol . When people have reached an exceptional
 level of health, this is the most common cause of relapse that
 I see, even when people say:&quot;but I only drink one glass of wine
 per week&quot;. Through repeated testing and observation, I have not seen
 alcohol benefit anyone. There are those that believe they receive
 health benefits by drinking alcohol occasionally, however, when
 I examine their blood work, test their organ function through electrodermal
 screening, and listen to their symptoms, I would respectfully disagree
 with them. This substance does not improve health - not even a
 little bit. It&apos;s time we started relying on our own intuition. It&apos;s time we started becoming more in tune with our bodies, rather than believe in the studies that have been supported by those who have a vested interest in the outcome of these studies.

 Absolutely no margarine - even those labelled&quot;non-hydrogenated&quot;.
 Vegetable or nut/seed oils cannot be solid at room temperature
 without altering their chemical structure in some way. Margarine
 is a one-way
 ticket to accelerated disease as are other hydrogenated oils :
 peanut butter, Crisco, potato chips and French fries.

 Absolutely
 no white flour . This is often found in breads,
 wraps, cookies, pastas, bagels, pastries, desserts, crackers, and
 hidden within many foods that you may not be aware of unless you
 read the label. 70% of patients I see do not tolerate wheat products.
 If you use wheat, use organic whole grain wheat. I strongly recommend
 that anyone with a chronic disease remove wheat and gluten from
 his or her diet. 

 back to top 

 Helpful/Harmful For Some

 No cow&apos;s milk . 80% of patients I see do not tolerate dairy
 products. For those who tolerate dairy well, I recommend organic
 goat&apos;s milk, organic goat&apos;s cheese, organic yoghurt and organic
 butter. I strongly recommend to people who have cancer, heart disease,
 asthma,
 chronic sinusitis and chronic ear infections to avoid dairy products
 completely. (By the way, ice cream initiates a triple threat:
 milk, sugar and chemicals. Why not make your own Frozen Fruit Ice Cream made
 from only fruit?) 

 Legumes (beans, lentils, chickpeas). 50% of people tolerate
 these well. 50% don&apos;t. If you don&apos;t tolerate them (i.e. gas, bloating,
 etc.) don&apos;t eat them. Do not take enzymes just to tolerate them
 well. Leave them alone as they will do you more harm than good. For
 those
 that tolerate them well, they are good sources of protein and complex
 carbohydrates.

 Soy . This is not the wonder food that it is
 touted out to be. Yes, some menopausal women find great relief with
 their
 hot
 flashes by eating soy products, and some people tolerate it well
 and use it as a protein source. I believe it is overused and
 for many people, creates problems. Avoid soy if you have thyroid
 problems
 or are copper toxic (determined via hair analysis). If you consume
 soy, ensure your diet is high in iodine (seaweeds, fish, collards).

 Nuts
 and seeds . 20% of people I see do not tolerate these
 well. If you tolerate them well, buy raw nuts and seeds, as they
 are loaded with vitamins and minerals. Avoid peanuts since these
 nuts are on the top of the list for having the greatest susceptibility
 to molds. (Most patients I see do better eliminating peanuts).
 Do not eat roasted nuts and seeds unless you roast them yourself.
 You
 can do this by lightly browning raw nuts or seeds in the oven or
 on a non-stick frying pan, making sure to stir them up while they
 are browning. After removing them from the pan, drizzle a tsp.
 of cold pressed sunflower oil, olive oil or coconut oil on top then
 add Real Salt or sea salt and stir. Nuts and seeds can be eaten
 raw,
 used in a stir-fry, used to make creamy salad dressings, ground as a flour for cakes, or used for
 great toppings on casseroles.

 Salt. I believe adding salt to
 your food (for the sodium) along with a diet high in vegetable greens
 (for the potassium) is
 very healthy. Our bodies require a balance of both minerals for
 optimal functioning. Use sea salt or Real Salt. Some people cannot
 tolerate
 adding salt to their diet due to water retention and high blood
 pressure. However, salt is not the problem. The problem starts well
 before
 that point and often these people do not drink enough water ,
 do not exercise , and do not eat An
 Exceptionally Healthy Diet . When people become healthier, I often
 observe that they can tolerate salt easily. 

 Gluten (a protein component of grains found in wheat, spelt,
 kamut, barley, oats and rye). 30% of people I see do not tolerate
 gluten well. Gluten intolerance is determined via blood IgG and
 IgA antibody testing, blood IgA antibodies to tissue transglutaminase,
 salivary IgA antigliadin antibody test, or electrodermal food sensitivity
 testing. At times, even these types of testing do not definitively
 diagnose gluten sensitivity and regardless, the elimination of
 gluten
 has produced great improvement in some people. Non-gluten grains
 include rice, quinoa and millet. I strongly recommend that people
 with neurological illnesses, autoimmune diseases, people with intestinal
 disorders, those with mood disorders such as anxiety, depression
 and irritability, or those who have unresolved skin rashes, completely
 remove gluten from their diet and eat only non-gluten grains.

 Eggs .
 A very common food allergen. An excellent source of protein for those
 who can tolerate them. Egg sensitivities/allergies
 are best determined by ELISA blood testing or electrodermal screening
 in my experience. 

Click here to see an example of An
 Exceptionally Healthy Diet .

 back to top 

 Effectively Managing Stress 

 In my clinical experience, I have witnessed
 many people effectively deal with stress and life challenging situations
 utilizing the category of FOOD&amp;NUTRIENTS . 

 The top three ways that I have seen are as follows: 

 Those who completely eliminate alcohol, sugar,
 coffee and food chemicals deal with stress much better. These
 beverages are like gasoline on a fire and create huge stressful burnout.

 Those who eliminate food sensitivities and food allergies
 from their diet, rebound far more easily from stressful
 challenges.

 Taking the following supplements, especially
 during a stressful crisis, helps to support the nervous system
 since many of these nutrients become quickly depleted with high stress: 
 Scorbatate 1/2 tsp 2 times daily
 in juice 

 Orti-B
 1 capsule 2 times daily OR Liquid
 B vitamins 1 tsp 2 times daily 

 Magnesium
 Complex 1 or 2 capsules 2
 times daily 

 Super
 EFA Liquid 1 tsp daily 

 GLA
 130 Primrose Oil 2 capsules 2 times
 daily 

 Greens
 Formula 1 scoop daily in 8 oz.
 of water 
 

 The greatest observable physical improvements
 I have ever seen in people (vitality, optimal weight, eye brightness,
 healthy facial colour, skin, nails and hair) have come about
 after positive nutritional changes. Improved physical health more often
 than not, filters into greatly improved emotional and mental health. 
 
 back to top 
 
 
 

 • Love&amp;Happiness • 
 
 

 • Water,
 Air, Sunlight • 
 
 

 • Natural
 Therapies • 
 
 

 • Food&amp;Nutrients • 
 
 

 • Exercise&amp;Rest • 
 
 

 • Toxin
 Elimination • 
 

   
 Home • About Us • Health
 Info • Health Stories • Products 
 Detoxification Programs • Contact
 Us • Links •Search•Site Map
 Terms
 of Service • Disclaimer • Privacy Policy 

 DISCLAIMER 

The information on this site is not
 meant to diagnose, treat or cure any disease. As well, the FDA
 or any other institution has not evaluated the information on this site
 unless otherwise stated. All the opinions and views expressed on
 this site come from the authors and are presented for educational purposes. You
 are responsible for your own health and for the choices you make regarding
 your health. It is also your responsibility to seek out the advice
 of a licensed healthcare practitioner if you require this.

 
 
 

Copyright©2004
Naturally Empowered Inc.
	</body>
</document>
