<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005616" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/210017-gotmilk.com-Get-The-Glass-For-Cash-(7-29)*" time="2012-07-12-22:11" support="3" score="0.002258003439855108" bingtitle="gotmilk.com - Get The Glass For Cash (7/29)*" webtitle="gotmilk.com - Get The Glass For Cash (7/29)*">
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000683" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>... between contestants are allowed, trash ... winner cannot elect another person to take his/her place). RECEIPT ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Contests - Sweepstakes Expired Contests / Instant Wins gotmilk.com - Get The Glass For Cash (7/29)* 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Results 1 to 2 of 2 
Thread: gotmilk.com - Get The Glass For Cash (7/29)* 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 04-16-2007,  01:03 PM #1 Pearl 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2007 Posts 795 
gotmilk.com - Get The Glass For Cash (7/29)*
 http://www.gotmilk.com/fun/pdf/get_t...test_rules.pdf 

 http://www.gotmilk.com/fun/get_the_glass_contest.html 

--------------------------------------------------
 http://www.gettheglass.com/ 

 http://www.gettheglass.com/legal/rules.html 

* Get The Glass Official Rules

US residents aged 13 or older only. Each qualified person who completes the got milk?&quot;Get The Glass&quot;web game found at www.gettheglass.com will be eligible to receive one got milk?&quot;Get The Glass&quot;Glass. One got milk?&quot;Get The Glass&quot;Glass per person, family or household. 3,000 Glasses are available to be given away while supplies last, but not later than 7/29/07. Got milk?&quot;Get The Glass&quot;Glasses will be sent by U.S. mail to home residences only, allow 6 - 8 weeks for delivery.

Any attempt to manipulate or tamper with the Game, or commit fraud, will make participant ineligible. Sponsor reserves the right to cancel or modify the program in the event of any manipulation, tampering or fraud. Void where prohibited or restricted. Note that the got milk?&quot;Get the Glass&quot;web game may continue without the offering of any got milk?&quot;Get The Glass&quot;premium program.
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

---------------------------------------------------
This appears to have dates of April 20, May 18
---------------------------------------------------

GOT MILK? GET THE GLASS FOR CASH OFFICIAL PROGRAM RULES

WHAT IS THE GOT MILK? GET THE GLASS FOR CASH CONTEST? GET THE GLASS FOR CASH will tap the competitive essence of the GET THE GLASS TV advertising and online game. The contest creates a way for California consumers in Fresno, San Diego and Los Angeles to be a part of the new milk campaign.

WHAT CAN A GET THE GLASS FOR CASH CONTEST CHAMPION WIN? One winner from Fresno and one winner from San Diego will each receive $5000 (Signed W-9 Form Required) as well as gifts emphasizing the ailments milk cures in the TV spots and online game: weak muscles and nails, cavities and PMS. The package includes a year supply of milk, sports activity and manicure certificates, box of chocolates and an electric toothbrush. The Fresno and San Diego winners also win an all expense paid trip to Los Angeles where they will compete with Angelinos for another $5000 and a prize package. GOT MILK? will cover travel, hotel and meals.

WHO CAN ENTER? Potential contestants must be at least 18 years old by the following dates: April 13, 2007 for the Fresno contest, April 20, 2007 for the San Diego contest and May 18, 2007 for the Los Angeles contest. Proof of age through drivers license or picture ID is required. Potential contestants must sign a personal liability agreement and photograph/video/interview release and indemnity agreement. Potential contestants must first play GET THE GLASS online game at the contest site on the day of contest and score 500 points in five minutes to qualify for the GET THE GLASS FOR CASH contest. Online gaming qualification begins at 12 noon in Fresno, San Diego and Los Angeles. The first 30 players to reach 500 points in five minutes qualify for GET THE GLASS FOR CASH contest in all three cities listed. All eligible contestants must wear GET THE GLASS t-shirts throughout the duration of the contest.

CONTESTANTS PREPARATION&amp;CONDUCT The GET THE GLASS FOR CASH contest will take place rain or shine at an outdoor venue for all three cities listed so contestants need to prepare for any weather condition. While GOT MILK? will provide milk and cookies during breaks, contestants need to bring provisions they deem necessary. Consumption of alcohol and or illegal drugs during the competition for all three cities is prohibited and will result in disqualification. Contestants are NOT allowed to sabotage other contestants. No touching, kicking or hitting other participants. While conversations between contestants are allowed, trash talking and the use of profane and offensive words will result in disqualification.

ABOUT THE GOT MILK? JUDGES Before the contest starts in each city, GET THE GLASS FOR CASH Milk judges will be identified to all contestants. The judges will watch all contestants and create a fair and safe environment for all participants. The judges have the right to eliminate any contestant who disobeys any rule listed in this document.

HOW WILL THE CONTEST BE JUDGED? The contest starts with 30 people, 18 years or older. The contestants must place one hand, flat on a Plexiglas surrounding the GET THE GLASS milk encasing. The palm and all five fingers must be placed on the Plexiglas. Lifting even one finger will result in disqualifi-cation. Contestants must stand the entire duration of the contest. Every two hours, contestants will receive a 10-minute milk&amp;cookie/bathroom break. Failure to return within the 10-minute period will result in disqualification. Judges will use a stop watch to time breaks. On the first day, the contestants will compete from 12 noon to 12 midnight. Contestants must return the following day at 6 a.m. Failure to do so will result in disqualification. Day two will last from 6 a.m. to 12 midnight if necessary. Day three will last from 5 a.m. to 12 midnight if necessary. Day four will last from 4 a.m. to 12 midnight if necessary. Day five will last from 4 a.m. to 12 noon. If there is still a tie on the fifth day, contestants must answer a series of GOT MILK? trivia questions. Contestant(s) who fail to give the right answer will be disqualified. The last person standing or the participant who answers the most trivia questions correctly on the fifth day of competition wins.

GET THE GLASS FOR CASH FINAL The GOT MILK? Team will contact the winner from Fresno and the winner from San Diego to encourage them to participate in the GET THE GLASS FOR CASH Contest Final in Los Angeles/Orange County, where they could win another $5000 plus prizes. The GOT MILK? Team will cover travel, meals and lodging expenses. If either winner from Fresno or San Diego cannot participate in the Los Angeles/Orange County competition, he/she forfeits the right to do so. This eligibility is NOT transferable, (i.e. the winner cannot elect another person to take his/her place).

RECEIPT OF PRIZES Before the GET THE GLASS FOR CASH winners could receive their prizes; they must fill-out a W-9 form with their proper information. GOT MILK? will not issue a check unless they do so. The GET THE GLASS Campaign is sponsored by the California Milk Processor Board, 101 S. El Camino Real, Suite 207, San Clemente, CA 92672. Reply With Quote 04-16-2007,  01:05 PM #2 Pearl 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2007 Posts 795 Trade paper write-up
----------------------------------------

The folks who brought us the catchphrase got milk? are serving up a new contest that raises the stakes on the possibility of a world without milk.

The California Milk Processor Board is running a TV and online campaign about the last glass of milk on earth. Seven ads, themed Get the glass, show the goofy Adachi family trying to break into a heavily guarded Fort Fridge, where the last glass of milk is being protected.

Those tongue-in-cheek ads have spawned a tour that will take Fort Fridge to three California cities to let consumers compete for $5,000 and a years supply of milk.

The Get the Glass for Cash contest starts online and finishes up with events in Fresno (April 13), San Diego (April 20) and Los Angeles (May 18). First, contestants play a 3-D game at gotmilk.com, answering trivia questions and battling against physical limitations caused by lack of milk: brittle bones, weak muscles, insomnia and Premenstrual Syndrome.

The first 30 players who score 500 points in five minutes qualify to compete in the real-world events. Those contestants enter a big Fort Fridge and place one hand on a Plexiglas case holding a glass of milk. The player who keeps his hand on the case longest wins $5,000 cash and a slate of other prizes.

The winners in Fresno and San Diego also win a trip to Los Angeles to compete in Fort Fridge there for another $5,000.

Contestants arent allowed to touch each other. They can converse, but trash talking is forbidden, according to the rules. Each contest can go as long as five days; if theres more than one contestant still in on the fifth day, judges will pose a series of got milk? trivia questions to break the tie.

The other items in the prize package allude to the ailments from a lack of milk: sports certificates (for weak muscles), manicures, chocolate (for PMS) and an electric toothbrush (for cavities).
T
he new Get the Glass ads broke in March and will run through yearend via the boards longtime ad agency, Goodby, Silverstein&amp;Partners, San Francisco.

We want people to imagine what it would be like if milk really was that scarce and how that would change the way we think about it, said Steve James, executive director of the California Milk Processor Board, in a statement.

Get the Glass fits the same scarcity strategy that first prompted the boards got milk? ad campaign 14 years ago.

The got milk? print, TV and outdoor ads that show funny moments when the milk runs out have become pop culture standbys. The campaign, which first aired in California, went national in 1995 when the national dairy boards began licensing the tagline and ads from the San Clemente, CA-based board. The campaign gets $150 million in media support each year. Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
