<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005174" url="http://southflorida.menupages.com/restaurants/chef-creole-2/" time="2012-07-12-21:42" support="3" score="0.00803974655672087" bingtitle="Chef Creole - Miami Restaurant - MenuPages Cajun &amp; Creole, Seafood ..." webtitle="Chef Creole - Miami Restaurant - MenuPages CajunCreole, Seafood, Caribbean Restaurant Search">
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>... it received my food in good time considering that it was cooked fresh. I can see if someone wants to compare thier production to a fast food restaurant ... begin to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 5922 Menus for South Florida Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Central Palm Beach East Broward Florida Keys Miami and Miami Beach North Broward North Palm Beach Northeast Dade Northwest Dade South Dade South Palm Beach Southeast Broward Southwest Broward West Broward All Neighborhoods Allapattah / Overtown / Liberty City Atlantis / Florida Gardens Aventura / Sunny Isles Boca Raton Boynton Beach Coconut Grove Coral Gables Coral Ridge Coral Springs / Parkland Cutler Bay / Perrine / Redland Dania Beach Davie / Cooper City Deerfield Beach Delray Beach Downtown / Brickell Downtown / Las Olas Ft Lauderdale Beach Greenacres / Lake Clarke Shores Hallandale / Pembroke Pk Hialeah Hollywood Homestead / Florida City Jupiter / Tequesta Kendall Key Biscayne Key West Lake Worth Lantana / Hypoluxo / Manalapan Lauderdale Lakes / Lauderhill Lauderdale-by-the-Sea Little Havana / Flagami Lower Keys Loxahatchee Margate / Coconut Creek Melrose Park / Airport Miami Gardens / Opa-Locka Miami Lakes / Palm Springs North Miami Springs / Airport Middle Keys Middle River / Lauderdale Manors Miramar North Beach North Miami North Miami Beach North Palm Beach / Juno Beach Oakland Park / Wilton Manors Palm Beach Palm Beach Gardens Pembroke Pines Pinewood Park / Miami Shores Plantation Pompano Beach Riviera Beach / Palm Beach Shores Shenandoah South Beach South Miami / Pinecrest Sunrise Sweetwater / Doral Tamarac / North Lauderdale Upper Keys Wellington / Royal Palm Beach West Boca West Miami / Westchester West Palm Beach Weston Westwood Lakes Wynwood / Design District Cuisines All Cusines African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan New England Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Portuguese Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Steakhouses Sushi Teahouses Thai Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
Chef Creole
 + SHARE 


 $$$ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Cajun&amp;Creole, Seafood, Caribbean 13105 W Dixie Hwy , Miami   FL 33161 25.8960283 -80.1818979 (Btwn NE 8th&amp;NE 9th Ave) 

 
 
 Phone: (305) 893-4246 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/chef-creole-2/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
User Ratings (Based on 4 reviews) 
 3.50 5 
 Food 3.3 Value 3.1 Service 3.6 Atmosphere 4.0 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (305) 893-4246 Website: www.chefcreole.com/chefcreole Notes: Catering Hours: Mon-Sat: 11:30am-11:30pm Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner Features: Catering 
User Reviews
 
 Chef Creole 
 Posted by Ron on 08/30/2011 
 
Damn good Haitian food
 
I loved the this location it had an Island feel to it the service was good although it was busy it received my food in good time considering that it was cooked fresh. I can see if someone wants to compare thier production to a fast food restaurant they would be upset of time it takes, but this is REAL food i love it and would urge everyone to check it out.
 Chef Creole 
 Posted by James on 12/19/2009 
 
chef creole in miami gardens
 
whoever reads this try the chef creole at 441 and 204 st. i liked the food there a lot better then the one on NE 54 st. the conch was not salty or overcooked
 Chef Creole 
 Posted by Malin on 05/24/2009 
 
Not.....
 
Chef Creole was the place to go for the best Haitian and Seafood in my opinion. Now its value and food has gone down, nt the same plp so nt the same food. Just a week ago my boyfriend went there to go buy us some rice and conch, the rice was under cooked and the conch was salty 8-(. Boy, Boy, boy if i wasn&apos;t hungry and it wasn&apos;t raining it wouldn&apos;t be a pretty site if i would of went back there. dnt waste ur time,taste buds, definitely not ur money.
 Chef Creole 
 Posted by Fion on 08/14/2008 
 
I came on on a bad day
 
I always heard their griot was the best. I went in all excited and ordered some after months of driving by. When I got home, that griot must have been at least a day old and refried, it did not taste fresh at all. The rice and banana (plantains) were delicious though. I had some fried chicken of theirs as my first purchase, that was just divine...I would never buy griot from them again.
 
 
 1 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near Chef Creole
 Intracoastal Mall 
3701 NE 163rd St

North Miami Beach
 Savages  (R) The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Magic Mike  (R) Ted  (R) Tyler Perry&apos;s Madea&apos;s Witness Protection  (PG-13) Show More [+] More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages Miami Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
