<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005485" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/82114-weight-watchers-points-lists/" time="2012-07-12-22:03" support="11" score="0.02379604511804528" bingtitle="Weight Watchers Food Points Lists | LIVESTRONG.COM" webtitle="Weight Watchers Food Points Lists | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001132" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001037" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>Some condiments and proteins even accumulate no points ... Take, for example, a meal at the popular fast food restaurant ... How to Calculate the Number of Weight Watchers ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Weight Management Weight Loss Diets M-Z Weight Watchers Food Points Weight Watchers Food Points Lists 
 
 Weight Watchers Food Points Lists 
 Mar 5, 2011 | By Andrea Cespedes Photo Credit hamburger menu image by Xavier MARCHANT from Fotolia.com 
Weight Watchers has persisted since the 1960s because it offers a program that helps people successfully lose weight. Its approaches have changed over the years, and it now focuses on a points system that endeavors to give its members the incentive to eat high-fiber, low-fat foods and to control portion sizes. Participants are assigned a daily point allotment for the day, based on their gender, weight, activity level, age and height. Basically, it comes down to following a low calorie diet---but in a way many people can understand.
 
Zero Points

To encourage you to choose healthy foods, Weight Watchers assigns most nonstarchy vegetables zero points. Artichokes, asparagus, beets, zucchini, eggplant, lettuce and mushrooms all fall into this category. Fruits like kiwis, oranges and peaches also have zero points. Weight Watchers incentivizes you to drink zero-pointed coffee, tea, fat-free creamer and vegetable juice. Some condiments and proteins even accumulate no points---egg whites, salsa and chili sauce are just some in this list. Be sure to pay attention to serving sizes, however. Just because a food has zero points for a certain serving does not mean unlimited servings of it will help you lose weight. Stick to 1 cup of vegetables, 8 ozs. of vegetable juice, a tablespoon of fat-free creamer, a tablespoon of salsa or one egg white.
 
One Point

Some starchy vegetables, like a 4-oz. serving of corn on the cob, or a cup of parsnips and peas, contain one point. Most fruits, including apples, pears, grapes and melons, contain one point when you serve up 1 cup. Dried fruits--a half cup of dried apple or two prunes--or 4 oz. of fruit juice also count as one point. Light carbohydrates like rice cakes, shredded wheat (one biscuit), five saltines or two slices of light whole wheat bread bring one point. A few meats also tally one point: a slice of bacon, skinless chicken drumstick,½cup of crab or an ounce of smoked salmon. You may also enjoy a light, 4-oz. yogurt, fat-free slice of cheese or a tablespoon of full fat cream cheese for one point.
 
Highest Points

Eating out usually racks up the points. Take, for example, a meal at the popular fast food restaurant Chick-fil-A. A classic chicken sandwich at comes in at nine points. Add in a medium fries for eight points and a large vanilla milkshake for 15 points and you&apos;ve probably gone over your point value for the day. Enjoy the chicken parmesan entrée at the Olive Garden and rack up 25 points; if you choose the linguine alla marinara you eat only eight points worth. By budgeting your points, you learn to make healthier choices. Point values are not listed on restaurant menus or packaging, so you are dependent on becoming a paid member of Weight Watchers to obtain a comprehensive list of points.
 
References

 Peer Trainer: The Weight Watchers Point System Exercise for Weightloss: Weight Watchers Points EveryDiet: Weight Watchers 
 
Article reviewed by Renee Peterson Last updated on: Mar 5, 2011
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 List of Foods and Points in Weight Watchers 
 
 List of Food Points for Weight Watchers 
 
 Weight Watchers Winning Points Food List 
 
 Points Information for Weight Watchers 
 
 A List of Weight Watchers Foods&amp;Points 
 
 List of Weight Watchers Points for Food From the Store 
 
 Foods That Have 0 Points on Weight Watchers 
 
 Weight Watchers List of Food Point Values 
 
 Weight Watchers Points System Food List 
 
 List of Foods That Have Zero Weight Watchers Points 
 
 Weight Watchers One Point List of Foods 
 
 A List of Free Points on Weight Watchers 
 
 List of Points for Fruits&amp;Vegetables on Weight Watchers 
 
 List of Weight Watchers Food Points 
 
 Weight Watchers 2 Point Foods 
 
 The Weight Watchers Foods With 0 Points 
 
 Fruit Points List for Weight Watchers 
 
 Weight Watchers Flex Points List 
 
 Foods That Are 1 Point With Weight Watchers 
 
 Weight Watchers Fast Food Points List 
 more Weight Watchers Point List Chick-Fil-A advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 How to Count Weight Watchers Points 
 
 Food With Egg Whites 
 
 Weight Watchers Sandwich Ideas 
 
 Weight Watchers Points List of Food 
 
 Weight Watchers Low Point Foods 
 
 How to Calculate the Number of Weight Watchers Points I Get 
 
 What Foods Can One Eat If Allergic to Egg Whites? 
 
 How to Use the Weight Watchers Calculator 
 
 How to Calculate the Weight Watcher Points for a Horseshoe Sandwich 
 
 Weight Watchers Food: The Value of the Points 
 
 Low Point Foods That Are Filling for the Weight Watcher&apos;s Diet 
 
 How to Make a Weight Watchers Points Sliding Calculator 
 
 Fried Egg White Nutritional Facts 
 
 How to Calculate Weight Watchers Foods 
 
 How to Use Lean Cuisine&amp;Weight Watchers Pre-Packaged Foods to Lose Weight 
 
 List of Zero Points Foods 
 
 How to Figure Out the Weight Watchers Points System 
 
 How Much Vitamins&amp;Protein Does One Egg White Have? 
 
 How to Calculate Weight Watcher Points for Meals 
 
 Weight Watchers Nutrition Products 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
