<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005312" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/46/1572359/restaurant/Suburban-Northside/Italia-Express-Oklahoma-City" time="2012-07-12-21:51" support="1" score="0.0005048041183939272" bingtitle="Italia Express - Suburban Northside - Oklahoma City | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Italia Express - Suburban Northside - Oklahoma City | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>When I finally got my order it was room temp and ... Express&quot; in their name might indicate a fast-food restaurant ... It is now a favorite spot to pick up a home ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Oklahoma City » Oklahoma City » Suburban Northside » Italia Express 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Austin Dallas/Fort Worth Houston Kansas City Los Angeles New York Tulsa More... 
 
Italia Express
 
(405) 917-9995
 Suburban Northside 4621 N May Ave 
 Oklahoma City , OK 73112 
 italiaexpress.us 

Added by Thestreetsarewatchin 
 See all 17 reviews Cuisine Italian , Pizza , Sandwiches/Subs Features Delivery , Kid Friendly , Vegan Friendly Menu $ Under $10 per entree Podoro, Xl pizza 7 toppings $17.99, Bread - light&amp;airy fresh yummy bread... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late 
   103 people have voted 86 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Gopuram Taste of India 82% $$ Inner City Northside - Indian, Buffet, Wine Bar 4559 NW 23rd St 
 
 Olive Garden 70% $$ Belle Isle - Italian 1844 Northwest Expressway 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 March 6, 2011 Likes it Bill Hensley&apos;s Random Blog Service was excellent and attentive. The only thing I could mark the place down for was that the tea, while good, was a little weak. Value was outstanding. The check for nine of us, with... More from Bill Hensley&apos;s Random Blog 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 March 3, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it No more of my money! by DTMOKC ( 18 reviews ) I&apos;m a 4 time loser with these folks. 1st time was dine in, I ordered what was supposedly a $2 loaf of homemade italian bread and a medium pepperoni pizza. The bread was decent but tasted like Mrs. Rhoades frozen bread and the pizza was mediocre at best. The very next evening I gave their delivery a try, I was told there was no one available for delivery. Since I live directly across the street I gave them another try the very next evening. I ordered a small sausage pizza and what was to be their famous calamari. After an hour of waiting I called and they informed me they could not find my address...REALLY! When I finally got my order it was room temp and by that I mean a cold room! There&apos;s to many other good Italian choices for me to waste my time with these guys. I won&apos;t return!!!!! February 21, 2012 Likes it WELL KEPT OKC SECRET! by Foodie Okie ( 138 reviews ) Very good pizza, pasta and salads, and all at very modest prices. We&apos;ll be back again. And again. March 4, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Unionjacklvr76 ( 10 reviews ) Wow! We eat out frequently and I have to say this is by far, hands down the WORST dining experience we have ever known. Our orders were completely wrong and as we were trying to talk to the waitress about what we had actually ordered, another waiter came out and asked us to leave. Pointed to the door and told myself, my husband,&amp;two young children that they didn&apos;t need us there if we didn&apos;t like the food and he would gladly show us all to the door because we were not welcome!! All I could do was laugh, it was as if it were a joke at first, sadly it wasn&apos;t!! Unbelievable!!! August 6, 2011 Likes it Wow Totally Surprised by MagzOK ( 73 reviews ) I was totally blown away by how good the food was for the money. It is home cooked Italian food. The eggplant parmesan was very tasty and my wife&apos;s calzone was top notch. They provide you an endless supply of fresh baked bread. The only think I&apos;d recommend there is perhaps some more seasoning on the bread. The girl who waited on us didn&apos;t tell us there was a special tonight -- I overheard her brother, who was also a cook, out talking to another customer about it. It was a special mahimahi fish that sounded and also looked fabulous. I would have ordered this had I known about it. The authenticity of the place was realized when I overheard what was presumably all family staff, speaking in Italian, teaching one of their family members how to run some aspect of the restaurant. I really enjoyed how the cooks came out and talked to the customers. All around the service was really pretty good. I actually felt like I needed to pay more for my meal. My family was completely stuffed and we walked out of there for under $20. I don&apos;t think you&apos;ll find better Italian food for cheaper. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful March 21, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Jimmy Goukon ( 5 reviews ) I order out from these folks every once in awhile and have never been dissappointed with my food. I have had their subs (the tomato and spinich is good), their pizza (the greek pizza with artichokes and kalamata olives is incredible) and a few of their pasta meals. Their ceasar salad dressing is very good. June 26, 2011 Likes it WOW! by Dr. Matt ( 174 reviews ) I was extremely impressed with my first visit....so much so I am breaking tradition and writing a review (usually I wait until after my 3rd visit to write!) I needed a quick meal. I got the pepperoni and sausage calzone. The server talked me into a small caesar salad, and I am glad he did! It was delicious and only a $1 more. For a little over 7 dollars I had a delightful meal, complete with homemade bread, with the most wonderful crunch to the crust. If the rest of the menu is as delicious and priced right, I have just found an Italian goldmine! March 8, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Ashley Nichole ( 1 review ) Not worth the money!!! I&apos;ve been here twice, first time left toppings off pizza and I let that slide. Second time was today spent $60+, got extreme pepperoni that was NOT extreme! Same as regular pepperoni as other pizza that are $5. Escargot &apos;is how it&apos;s really spelled&apos; 6 tiny overdone snails on top of huge mushrooms. Won&apos;t be wasting money here again. Take note. January 10, 2012 Likes it amazing! by taaaaang ( 8 reviews ) This place is AWESOME. I got the&quot;express&quot;and it took everything in me not to lick the plate clean. Our waiter, I don&apos;t know how he spells his name, but it sounded like&quot;Martine,&quot;was the greatest waiter in the all time history of waiters. He was super friendly and helpful with suggestions, and joked around with us, but stayed totally professional at the same time. Even my six month old son loved him. I want to go back there just for the garlic bread. I didn&apos;t even know bread could be that good. January 1, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Preston ( 1 review ) Awesome! Very delicious and very reasonably priced. I was pleasantly surprised at the quality and freshness of the food. I highly recommend this place! December 10, 2011 Likes it Great Food Great Service by Devon ( 3 reviews ) Hubby and I tried Italia Express on May for the 1st time tonight. LOVED IT! Service was exceptional, friendly and attentive. Garlic bread was hot, fresh and nice and heavy on the garlic. Since we couldn&apos;t decide on 1 appetizer we ordered both the calamari and escargot. Calamari was crispy and hot and the escargot was served on mushrooms which made it very tasty. We opted for the daily special-can&apos;t remember the name, but it had chicken, cheese and Alfredo sauce also excellent dish. Last we had a canoli. All I can say is OMG YUM! We did order a lot of food and it was all very good. Price was also very nice. Our only complaint, the portions were on the small side. Wouldn&apos;t mind paying a few dollars more for a tad more food on the plate. Other than that, I highly recommend Italia Express. I promise you won&apos;t be disappointed. August 10, 2011 Mobile review by Michael Deverey ( 6 reviews ) Good, not great. Well worth the money. June 18, 2011 Great Italian food at cheap prices! by luv2fly6715 ( 1 review ) This is a great new Italian restaurant. The wait staff is very friendly, the portion sizes are generous and the prices are very reasonable. The complimentary garlic bread was home baked and fresh out of the oven. We&apos;ll definitely be going back again. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful August 28, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by hoodchristi ( 2 reviews ) It is delicious! Almost always have the special. So very good. And the staff rocks! March 21, 2011 Likes it One of the best kept secrets in OKC! by TMorelock ( 5 reviews ) We stumbled across this place and couldn&apos;t be more thankful we did! It is now a favorite spot to pick up a home cooked meal before making it home! I can say from experience that the Calzones, the Stromboli, the Pepporoni Rolls, the Tortolini a la Pana, and the Fettuccini Alfredo are all outstanding! The staff is friendly, the restaurant is clean and I can tell you that you can NOT be disappointed by the food! October 3, 2011 Likes it My New Favorite Italian Restaurant by Doris ( 1 review ) Just driving by this building that has been many different restaurants, you might not stop; there is nothing remarkable about it from the outside. However, once you are inside, everything is remarkable. The chef at this Italian restaurant makes everything from scratch, and his marinara sauce is out of this world! The menu is extensive, including all kinds of pasta (the meatballs are very, very good), chicken, salads, and cold-cut sandwiches made on their home-made bread, to name just a few. Don&apos;t miss the house salad dressing, which is a tomato-based vinaigrette. Although the&quot;Express&quot;in their name might indicate a fast-food restaurant, it definitely is not. There are real menus and a wait staff that is at your beck and call. This is a family-owned business and they obviously take pride in their product and their services. The employees are ultra-friendly, and the chef will make a dish to your specifications if at all possible. The prices are very reasonable and mostly lower than other full-service Italian restaurants. Italia Express is open for lunch and dinner seven days a week. Try it; you&apos;ll like it! March 18, 2011 Really likes it by Rebecca Woods Stewart-Ary ( 2 reviews ) Awesome food at moderate prices. Also, very nice wait staff. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by MagzOK Eggplant Parmesan by MagzOK Spinach and... 
 All 9 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Ron&apos;s Hamburger&amp;Chili 89% $ Suburban Northside - Burgers, Hot Dogs/Sausages Khazana 86% $$ Suburban Northside - Indian Brookline Deli $ Suburban Northside - Sandwiches/Subs Popeye&apos;s Louisiana Kitchen 85% $ Suburban Northside - Fast Food, Cajun/Creole, Chicken Chester&apos;s Billiards&amp;Grill $ Suburban Northside - Pub Food, Breakfast/Brunch, Burgers 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Super 8 Fairgrounds NW -
2821 W I 44 Service Rd 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 italia express okc italia express okc may ave italia express italia express okc menu escargot in oklahoma city 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
