<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005985" url="http://www.msgtruth.org/whywe.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:39" support="8" score="0.02953899079482552" bingtitle="American Restaurant Syndrome?" webtitle="American Restaurant Syndrome?">
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001187" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>At Asian restaurants, they know what is in the food because ... protein naturally contains free glutamate to give ... or seafood extracts were added to the rice if you order ...</description>
	<body>
		American Restaurant Syndrome? 
 

 
 MSG Symptom Complex 

For years MSG Symptom Complex has been known in the US by the misnomer Chinese
Restaurant Syndrome. We do not use that term anywhere on this site, except this
page. The reason is quite simple. Calling this health problem Chinese
Restaurant Syndrome not only does a disservice to Chinese Restaurant owners who do not add
MSG, but it also dangerously hides the fact that American processed food is now so loaded
with the flavor enhancer Monosodium Glutamate (MSG) as to be the largest source of MSG in
the average American diet. Most Americans, when told MSG is harmful respond with&quot;I
don&apos;t eat Chinese food, so I don&apos;t need to worry&quot;. 

However, Consider this:

 American Diet Syndrome 

FRIED CHICKEN - What could be more American than Fried Chicken? Chick-fil-A sandwiches have MSG added and KFC chicken actually
contains so much MSG that in one country at least, KFC exceeded the legal limit for adding
MSG to chicken.   

 The absolute worst offender listed on our Foods to Avoid 
page is KFC. The following KFC menu items all contain MSG:
    Roasted Ceasar Salad (WITHOUT dressing and croutons)
   Crispy Ceasar Salad (WITHOUT dressing)
   Roasted BLT Salad (WITHOUT dressing)
   Crispy BLT Salad (WITHOUT dressing
   Hidden Valley - The Original Fat Free Ranch Dressing
   KFC Creamy Parmesan Ceasar Dressing - contains parmesan 
 cheese - very high in MSG naturally
   KFC Garlic Parmesan Croutons Pouch - contains parmesan cheese 
 - very high in MSG naturally
   KFC Famous Bowls - Mashed Potatoes with Gravy
   Gravy
   KFC Famous Bowls - Rice with Gravy
   Rice
   Seasoned Rice
   KFC Snacker - Chicken
   KFC Snacker - Honey BBQ
   Honey BBQ Sandwich
   Double Crunch Sandwich
   Crispy Twister
   Oven Roasted Twister
   Oven Roasted Twister (WITHOUT sauce)
   Tender Roast Sandwich   
   Tender Roast Sandwich(WITHOUT sauce)
   Original Recipe Chicken (its in the marinade - it&apos;s 
 literally soaked in MSG and salt)
   Extra Crispy - MSG is in both the marinade AND the breading
   Colonel&apos;s Crispy Strips
   Popcorn Chicken
   Chicken Pot Pie
   Boneless HBBQ Wings
   Boneless Fiery Buffalo Wings
   Sweet and Spicy Boneless Wings
   Hot Wings
   Green Beans (yeah, this shocked us too)
   Mashed Potatoes with Gravy
   Potato Wedges 

 
The Second Worst offender is Burger King. The following menu items from 
Burger King have MSG added:
    Breaded Chicken Patty
   Spicy Chicken Patty
   Breaded Tendercrisp Chicken
   Chicken Tenders
   BK Chicken Fries
   Garden Veggie Patty - contains hydrolyzed corn, soy and wheat 
 - which contains free glutamate
   Sausage Patty
   Ranch dipping sauce
   Ken&apos;s Fat Free Ranch Dressing 

 Based on the way MSG is used by the American fast food 
industry, the following tips may be helpful for those wishing to avoid MSG when 
they must eat at an American restaurant: 

    AVOID all CHICKEN items
   AVOID all SAUSAGE items
   AVOID all PARMESAN products
   AVOID all Ranch dressings - stick to oil and vinegar Italian
   AVOID Croutons
   AVOID KFC altogether - we&apos;re not kidding
   AVOID Dipping Sauces
   AVOID Gravy
   AVOID Soups - as they often come from an MSG-containing soup 
base
  
The following very American snacks and foods also have MSG added in large 
amounts: 

FLAVORED SNACK CHIPS - Most flavored potato chips and snack chips 
contain MSG.  Doritos , a very popular food among American teens, has at least four
sources of free glutamate - the business end of MSG. 
CANNED AND INSTANT SOUP - Lipton, Knorr, Progresso and ramen noodle, and boullion 
cube manufacturers put MSG in their products. Products most Americans have 
been raised on, and not a few American office workers have stashed in their desk 
for those overtime evenings when a home cooked meal is out of the question , 
and foods poor college students practically live on. 
CANNED TUNA - Most brands of canned tuna in the US have&quot;broth&quot;added or
hydrolyzed vegetable protein added, which can contain up to 20% free glutamate. Manufacturers add this to hide any off flavors.
FRESH TURKEY - Many&quot;self-basting&quot;fresh turkeys and chickens sold in US
supermarkets have solutions injected into them - solutions that contain free glutamate.

This is only a few of the products that have MSG added to them - products most
Americans are unaware have MSG added to them. 

 Difference Between Chinese and American Restaurants 

Chinese food, for the most part consists of fresh vegetables quickly cooked. MSG
is added at the end as a condiment. It can be NOT added at the consumers request. Most Chinese Restaurant owners also know what else on the menu contains natural MSG
- soy sauce for instance is naturally loaded with free glutamate. Wait staff at a
Chinese restaurant will often steer the MSG sensitive patron away from dishes containing
soy sauce as well as MSG. At Asian restaurants, they know what is in
the food because they put it there. 

Most American restaurants today purchase their foods from large US food companies that
have what are called &quot;Food Service&quot;divisions.  In
American restaurants, most wait staff and often the cooks don&apos;t know what is in the food, because the soup base probably came from a can, those cute little jalapeno poppers came
from a brightly colored bag in the freezer, and very little is actually&quot;fresh&quot;. And, unfortunately, most American food scientists use the fact that soy sauce, and
hydrolyzed vegetable protein naturally contains free glutamate to give their free
glutamate containing products what is called&quot;a clean label&quot;. So even
cooks and wait staff don&apos;t even know what they are reading on the labels. The people
who create the foods supplied to American restaurants have absolutely no compunction about
hoping you don&apos;t know that MSG is in your food when you are consciously trying to avoid
it. 

 Who Started It?
 
The truth is, the country where MSG was first isolated (in 1908) and used was Japan. A Japanese company called Ajinomoto - only recently found guilty of price-fixing
MSG on the world market, is today the prime maker of MSG. Japan is also where
taurine and CoQ10 are now used to treat heart disease, and ginger and taurine-rich sushi
are eaten alongside MSG sprinkled food. These foods have protective effects against
an MSG reaction. However, even the Japanese have found recently that MSG fed to mice
can lead to blindness. The Japanese are concerned about the health affects of MSG. Should we not be also?

 Then Why Chinese Restaurant Syndrome?
 
The reason MSG may have been associated with Chinese food, and not Japanese food, may be
the protective effects of raw fish and fresh ginger in Japanese cuisine mentioned above,
but also that taurine is found mostly in animal products, and that Chinese food is often
low in meat. Also, taurine is destroyed by high heat, and foods are often cooked at
high temperatures in Chinese stir frying.

It is interesting to note the joke that after eating MSG in foods at a Chinese
restaurant&quot;you are hungry an hour later&quot;, may have some merit. The
glutamate in MSG acts as an insulin trigger. This will definitely give you a hunger
response about an hour and a half later. This fact has not been lost on American
food manufacturers. They know the value of an addictive food ingredient. If they
keep you hungry for more, they have succeeded. 

 MSG-free Tips on Eating at Asian Restaurants
 
We don&apos;t want to discourage anyone from the pleasures of eating Asian cuisine. MSG
is actually easier to avoid in an Asian restaurant, than in an
American one. 

 
Ask for NO MSG in your food.
 
 Avoid soy sauce 
Avoid soups, and sauces
 
Instead of a sushi roll ask for sashimi - no seaweed 
 NO SEA TANGLE, NO FISH EXTRACT, NO SEAFOOD EXTRACT - 
 these can make an MSG sensitive person very ill. Even Whole Foods adds 
 Tangle extract to their sushi. 
 
Make sure no MSG or seafood extracts were added to the rice if you order Chirashi
 
Use vinegar and wasabi instead of soy sauce to dip your sashimi
 
Think fresh - ask for a quick MSG-free stir fry of fresh vegetables, water chestnuts,
 bamboo shoots, unmarinated meat, plain noodles, fresh ginger , 
 plain sesame oil. 
 
Avoid dishes that look too mixed together and marinated.
 
Avoid saki - sometimes MSG is added to warmed saki to remove the bitterness. In fact, go
 easy on alcohol altogether - your liver is needed in good condition if you should have an
 MSG reaction
 
Avoid those little crunchy appetizers - they often contain MSG. 
Green tea is a good idea to drink with your meal.  
Avoid sauces and dishes like Egg Foo Yung which consist of sauces likely to contain MSG 
 At Dim Sum restaurants, avoid the sauces they deliver 
 on the side, and choose foods not sauced already. 
 
Most Asian restaurants serve very simple desserts which often consist of fresh fruit -
 usually oranges. It is a good idea to eat this, as Vitamin C helps mitigate any MSG
 reaction. 
Korean food is interesting as there are safer dishes like those served in very hot
 bowls, where rice, raw vegetables, and raw egg are added to the bowl, and it cooks right
 in front of you at the table. Sauce is suppied on the side, but you don&apos;t need to
 use it.
 

 
In Korean restaurants steer clear of the Kim Chee, the red pickled cabbage - it often
 contains MSG. 
 

 
Try Thai food - there are many soy-free choices - it has fresh bright flavors - but also
 ask for NO MSG. Thai sauces which are creamy are usually made from coconut milk, an
 interesting flavor.
 

 
Vietnamese food - vietnamese food is also interesting to try, in some dishes, star anise
 gives this cuisine the exotic flavor of licorice. Again, ask for NO MSG.
 

 
Do not drink any aspartame diet drinks with your meal. Aspartame is just as bad
 for you as MSG. Aspartame and MSG have a synergistic effect.
 

 
So - basic rules of thumb-
Always ask for NO MSG 
NO TANGLE, FISH, OR SEAFOOD EXTRACT 
Think fresh - avoid marinaded foods
 No dipping sauce 
Eat your fruit, drink your green tea, eat fresh ginger
No soy sauce, limit alcohol, avoid diet drinks - 
 especially with aspartame 
 

 CONCLUSION 

Asian cuisine should be treasured and enjoyed for the fresh vegetables, and fresh fish
it contains. MSG is considered an avoidable condiment in Asian cooking, not the main
attraction. In fact, our favorite restaurants to eat at are 
Asian because most foods are served with sauces on the side and many restaurants 
now offer NO MSG in anything. So, if you skip the soy sauce and talk to 
the staff ahead of time about your concerns, you can usually have a wonderful, 
fresh meal, without getting ill.  In American Restaurants often MSG is added because the other ingredients may
be inferior or already processed, or out of a can, or not as fresh as you&apos;d like.  Often, if the restaurant is a chain, like McDonalds, or KFC, 
the food is often precooked or prepared at a different location first. (Recently, McDonalds admitted that its french fries are precooked elsewhere with 
a&quot;seasoning&quot;.)  Because of this MSG Symptom Complex could just as easily be called American Diet Syndrome.

Unfortunately, Americans are not looking for MSG in the most important place they
should be: American food. That is why we DON&apos;T call MSG Symptom Complex - Chinese
Restaurant Syndrome.   

 
  
 Home 
 Flow Chart 
 Why MSGTruth? 
 Food For Thought 
 American Restaurant Syndrome? 
 What exactly is MSG? 
 What Makes Me MSG Sensitive? 
 Body Systems Affected by MSG 
 Disease States Affected by MSG 
 Disease Statistics 
 What Foods To Avoid? 
 What To Eat? 
 Remedies 
 MSG in the NEWS 
 Related Research 
 Recommended Reading 
 Recommended Viewing 
 Recommended Products 
 Recommended Links 
 

 
 [  Back  ] [  Home  ] [  Next  ]   FLOW CHART 

 20 11 MSGTruth
	</body>
</document>
