<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005197" url="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2081079/Junk-food-really-DOES-mess-brain-Research-shows-trans-fats-causes-brain-damage.html" time="2012-07-12-21:44" support="3" score="0.0020701131936767536" bingtitle="Junk food really DOES mess with your brain! Research shows trans ..." webtitle="Junk food really DOES mess with your brain! Research shows trans fats causes brain damage  | Mail Online">
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>... now American researchers have discovered that junk ... 4) Your home smells like... well, a fast-food restaurant... ... of scandals Simon Cowell splashes out on a new car ...</description>
	<body>
		Home News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 News Home Arts Headlines Pictures Most read News Board 

 My Profile Logout Login 
 Find a Job M&amp;S;Wine Our Papers Feedback Thursday, Jul 12 2012 9PM  9°C 12AM 10°C 5-Day Forecast 
Junk food really DOES mess with your brain! Research shows trans fats causes brain damage
 
By Daily Mail Reporter 
 UPDATED: 17:30 GMT, 5 January 2012 
 
 Comments ( 65 ) Share 
 
 
 
 Not only does it rot your teeth and add inches to your
waistline, but now researchers have discovered that junk food actually hurts
your brain. 
 
 By consuming trans fats, found often in fried or processed
food, the chemicals send mixed and damaging signals to the brain and lessens
its ability to control appetite. 
 
 Essentially, by eating junk food, your brain becomes less
and less able to tell what you have eaten and continues to make you fee as if
you are hungry so that you proceed to eat more. 
 
Silent killers: French fries have loads of trans fats as well as all fried foods
 
 &apos;It&apos;s clear that trans fats are bad -- both for your heart
and now, we see, for your brain,&apos; Dr Gene Bowman of Oregon Health&amp;Science University told Huffington Post. 
 
 Given the somewhat complicated nature of trans fats, it is
harder for shoppers to spot goods that contain loads of the molecule. Trans fat
is the common name for unsaturated fats which are harder for the body to digest
given its double carbon-carbon bond. 
 
 Brain injury comes as the latest addition to a long list of
health problems that stem from the consumption of unsaturated fat. Coronary
heart disease, high cholesterol, obesity and diabetes. 
 
 The battle against trans fats is not a new one.
 

   
More...

 Have you got change? Man attempts to go shopping at Walmart with a million dollar bill Average American consumes one ton of food a year while equating a gallon of soda a week HuffPo: Trans Fats-Brain Damage Link Suggested By New Study On Nutrient Levels 
 
 
 While restaurants in New York and Switzerland have been
banned from serving dishes that have high levels of trans fats, there are still
plenty of everyday foods that are stealthily hiding the destructive
ingredients. 
 
 Girl Scout cookies, microwavable popcorn, and crackers- like
Saltines and Ritz- are some of the worst offenders, and that&apos;s ignoring the
obvious choices like French fries or fried chicken. 
 
 Though Mr Bowman conducted a relatively limited study among
elderly white Oregonians, his findings have been backed up by countless earlier
studies that highlight the difference between the yummy taste and disgusting
after-effects of junk food. 

 
 
MOST READ NEWS

 Previous 1 2 3 4 Next 
 
 Police hunt dealer who sold Tetra Pak wife Eva Rausing the... Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate... Horrific moment three young tigers attack and eat young cub... &apos;The way you brutally manipulated and exploited them is pure... Doing the logo-motion: From McDonald&apos;s without its big... What a difference a trim makes! Neighbours breath a sigh of... Two hotel workers found NOT GUILTY of murdering a honeymoon... &apos;The girl with this phone is dead, was smiling&apos;: The... Renter&apos;s revenge: Pictures which show the squalid aftermath... O2 hit by nationwide network failure: &apos;Millions of users&apos;... The human right to claim benefits: Jobless could sue for... McDonald&apos;s force Olympics bosses to ban all other... 
   
Share this article:
 
 Facebook Twitter Google+ Messenger LinkedIn Digg it Newsvine Fark Nowpublic Reddit 

 
 
 Print article Email article 
 
Comments ( 65 )
 
Here&apos;s what other readers have said. Why not debate this issue live on our message boards. 

The comments below have not been moderated.
 
 Newest Oldest Best rated Worst rated 
   View all 
Use coconut oil. It is probably the best on Earth. Buy the non-hydrogenated kind. It has plenty of lauric acid, also found in mothers&apos;milk. The fats in coconut oil are predominately medium-chain; they&apos;re good for you. Look up Dr. Mary Newport, and read about her struggle to save her husband from Alzheimer&apos;s disease with coconut oil.

- Umbagog, USA, 04/1/2012 02:15
 Click to rate     Rating   3 
 Report abuse 
 
I am ok. I dont eat curry.

- Robert, Leicestershire, 02/1/2012 20:16
 Click to rate     Rating   (0) 
 Report abuse 
 
If you have a problem with hot, inexpensive food prepared quickly by others, I suggest the following: Buy the ingredients yourself (meat, cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, onions, spices, salt, pepper, potatoes, ketchup, mustard, mayonaise); prepare them yourself at your home or workplace; do not complain when the any of the floowing occur: 1) It seems all you do is buy, prepare and cook food. 2) You lose your job for repeatedly exceeding your lunch hour. 3) Your dishwasher runs 24/7 or dishes pile up to the ceiling. 4) Your home smells like... well, a fast-food restaurant...
- Paevo, USA, 02/1/2012 17:53
--------------
Spoken like someone who has never even gone grocery shopping. You forgot that:
1. It&apos;s still cheaper to cook for yourself.
2. You can make a quick stirfry in 15 minutes.
3. If you bring your own lunch, you don&apos;t have to go out to get your food resulting in MORE time in the office.
4. It is not difficult or time consuming to operate a dishwasher.

- justregistered, Canada, 02/1/2012 19:05
 Click to rate     Rating   23 
 Report abuse 
 
If you have a problem with hot, inexpensive food prepared quickly by others, I suggest the following: Buy the ingredients yourself (meat, cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, onions, spices, salt, pepper, potatoes, ketchup, mustard, mayonaise); prepare them yourself at your home or workplace; do not complain when the any of the floowing occur: 1) It seems all you do is buy, prepare and cook food. 2) You lose your job for repeatedly exceeding your lunch hour. 3) Your dishwasher runs 24/7 or dishes pile up to the ceiling. 4) Your home smells like... well, a fast-food restaurant...

- Paevo, USA, 02/1/2012 17:53
 Click to rate     Rating   24 
 Report abuse 
 
Also be very wary of those sugar&quot;substitutes&quot;like aspartame aka the by product of chemical waste next time you&apos;re necking down those&quot;zero&quot;soft drinks....

- i keep it real, london, 02/1/2012 17:41
 Click to rate     Rating   29 
 Report abuse 
 
The government is not doing enough to improve the health of the nation. It&apos;s a lot worth in Scotland.
- Nadia, Glasgow, 02/1/2012 11:56
_____________________________________________ Yeah, because that&apos;s really going to happen.... When are you all going to learn They DONT CARE ABOUT US....

- i keep it real, london, 02/1/2012 17:37
 Click to rate     Rating   18 
 Report abuse 
 
The article isn&apos;t actually entirely correct. Not all unsaturated fats are bad, infact they are very important biological molecules, particularly in the membranes of cells. Trans fat is not another word for unsaturated fats, it is a form of unsaturated fat that is usually found in processed food. Sis fats are another form of unsaturated fat which are naturally occuring. Unsaturated fats are an important part of cholesterols, and if these fats are sis or trans is the difference between&quot;good&quot;and&quot;bad&quot;cholesterol. The shape and arrangement of molecules is very important in biology, and biological processes can produce molecules that are totally identical, wheras chemical processes produce mixtures of similar but different molecules (isomers), usually rougly evenly split between the possible types. In many cases this can be the difference between a molecule that is essential to life, and one that is highly dangerous.

- Chris Cooper, Loughborough, 02/1/2012 14:45
 Click to rate     Rating   29 
 Report abuse 
 
Explains why the yanks are so thick.

- Smith, UK, 02/1/2012 13:21
 Click to rate     Rating   6 
 Report abuse 
 
KFC and Mc&apos;donalds should be&quot;Class A&quot;under the misuse of foods act. illegal to posses or give away. Maximum prison sentence should be life for intent to supply.

- potter, kent, 02/1/2012 13:10
 Click to rate     Rating   30 
 Report abuse 
 
Leew - wrong! Cellulose is a carbohydrate. Just not one humans can digest. Ruminants like cattle can. Starch is a very similar carbohydrate, but one we can digest easily into sugars (also carbohydrates!) - once these are broken or changed into glucose the body can use them. Then there&apos;s the animal equivalent of plant starch, glycogen - but I&apos;m sure everyone can find wikipedia.

- John Walker, MK, UK, 02/1/2012 12:54
 Click to rate     Rating   10 
 Report abuse 
 
The views expressed in the contents above are those of our users and do not necessarily reflect the views of MailOnline.
 
We are no longer accepting comments on this article.
 Bing Site Web Enter search term: Search     
FEMAIL TODAY

 Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using M&amp;S;virtual technology &apos;This time, Justin messed with the wrong woman&apos;: Triumphant Tulisa settles legal action against ex over sex tape leak &apos;The truth has come out&apos; Gorgeous by day: Kelly Brook shows off her shape in sailor bikini as she enjoys amorous day with beau Thom Evans She&apos;s nautical but nice! Playful by night: Kelly Brook nearly pops out of her dress as she dances at the dinner table Thom&apos;s eyes almost popped out too at restaurant in Italy Divorce leaves Tom feeling flushed: Cruise visits loos THREE times in 20 minutes on Oblivion set Filming in Iceland &apos;Still shocked and saddened&apos;: Tom Cruise plans to see Suri &apos;very soon&apos; as he struggles to get to grip with being dumped by Katie Holmes Former Scientology chief claims church &apos;brainwashed Tom Cruise&apos;s children and turned them against Nicole Kidman&apos; Marty Rathbun left in 2004 Single lady style statement: Katie Holmes dons tight leather trousers for dinner date Younger, sexier image for Ms Holmes Doppelgangers! Joey Essex appears to be taking after Tom Cruise&apos;s style Uncannily similar jacket and shades to Top Gun star Kim and Kanye as you&apos;ve never seen them before! Couple pile on the pounds in frumpy portrait... with the help of a little trickery No nudity, no sex, just cuddles: How one woman is making a living from snuggling - but for 38 an hour, would you pay to hug a stranger? Why This Morning&apos;s penis enlargement feature brought a tear to my eyes (for all the right reasons) PETER LLOYD found him brave Whittle-d down: Ricky becomes a one woman man again as he holds hands with new girlfriend while baring his chest (of course!) Year since Carley Stenson split That&apos;s no demure maxi! Miranda Kerr sexes up her floor-length dress with a plunging neckline and hip-high slit Two maxi dresses in a row The devil wears gym gear: Emily Blunt looks ready for the Olympics as she works up a sweat during gruelling work out session Want a body like Denise? Richards reveals the secret behind her slim frame as she works out in weight loss shorts It&apos;s that simple! Katy Perry in a spin as insurers try to ban her from wearing trademark rotating bra Experts are concerned about the resulting strain on her neck Mother in heart-breaking plea for return of son, three, &apos;missing&apos; in Corfu with Greek father amid tug-of-love custody battle Tom Cruise&apos;s lawyer to sue National Enquirer for &apos;hundreds of millions&apos; over &apos;vicious lies&apos; Branded Tom a &apos;monster&apos; and said he &apos;humiliated his wife&apos; Friends again: Jennifer Aniston and Courteney Cox enjoy reunite on night out after rift rumours They hadn&apos;t been seen together for months The Only Way Is Essex star Gemma Collins in hot water over hair salon tweets Not the only TOWIE star to plug for freebies Gisele Bundchen&apos;s naked ambition is laid bare in daring nude beach shoot for Vogue Paris Stripping back to basics It&apos;s Posh-er and hips! Made In Chelsea&apos;s Hugo Taylor and Natalie Joel sport matching outfits... but hers is cut a little lower Robert Blake launches into bizarre tirade at Piers Morgan in first interview since being sensationally acquitted of wife&apos;s murder Big Brother 2012: Psychiatrist rushed in as &apos;depressed&apos; ex Playboy model Shievonne Robinson makes suicide remark Been &apos;crying hysterically&apos; All by myself: Pregnant Camila Alves does some solo sightseeing in Berlin while her husband Matthew McConaughey promotes his new film She&apos;s learned her lesson! Lydia Bright teams up with Zoe Hardman to encourage the public to stay safe in the sun Been burnt before Getting down and dirty! British women&apos;s football team enjoy muddy bonding session as they prepare to open the Olympic Games Soldiering on: Bikini girl Rihanna lights up a suspicious roll-up cigarette as she unwinds in Barbados after family drama Chris Hemsworth... the human stroller: Thor star carries baby India Rose around on shopping trip - and leaves pram at home Hands on dad! Curse of the Vera Wang wedding gown? How eight celebrities who married wearing her designs have ended up divorced After her own divorce Woman with world&apos;s largest natural breasts claims 102ZZZ-cup assets require security to fend off admirers who &apos;chase her&apos; Annie Hawkins-Turner Fleetwood Mac reuniting for tour next year, reveals Stevie Nicks Play their first shows since 2009, Stevie confirmed Grimace and bear it: Christine Bleakley looks terrified with Frank Lampard at Universal Studios Not flashing those pearly whites What were you inking! The embarrassing matching tattoos that brand couples for life They take saying &apos;I love you&apos;, to a whole new level It&apos;s chest OR legs! Sarah Harding reveals her very thin figure in a cropped top AND low-riding shorts Didn&apos;t get the memo Raffaella Fico shows off her growing bump as she steps out after penning open letter to Mario Balotelli Maintains footballer IS the father Aunty Khloe on duty! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s sister looks after Mason while she spends time with newborn daughter Putting in some practise? A forlorn looking Rihanna goes back to her plaited roots... after returning home for grandmother&apos;s funeral Grieving loss of beloved grandmother Dolly You&apos;re not fooling anyone! Tulisa spends five hours having her hair dyed blonde... then tries to hide it with a wig Next time put the wig on properly Tulisa! Makes a change from tennis whites! Maria Sharapova reveals killer legs in sheer chiffon dress at ESPY awards Caused quite a racket &apos;One doctor suggested I abort her&apos;: Against all odds one of the world&apos;s smallest surviving babies finally goes home Kenna Claire Moore is a little miracle That&apos;s one pricey push-up! The bra dripping in diamonds and gold selling for $1million Contains 750 grams of gold They&apos;re his mini mes! Liam Gallagher&apos;s sons Lennon and Gene are a chip off the old block Perfected that mean and moody scowl Fifty Shades of Grey author&apos;s saucy tale was inspired by her Latin roots, says her mother Alexandra Mitchell has praised her daughter&apos;s erotic trilogy Making the most of her bikini body: Actress Louisa Lytton shows off her slim frame on holiday Before rehearsing for latest theatre show Lesbian sex scene in ballet thriller Black Swan makes it film with most complaints Some viewers described the scene as &apos;pornographic&apos; What would Marilyn say! Karolina Kurkova flashes a bit too much as she takes centre stage in a sexy photoshoot She took it a lot further! Angelina Jolie dresses her brood in angelic white... as Maleficent sticks to the dark side in head to toe black A woman of many talents &apos;Maybe it&apos;s time to go&apos;: Jennifer Lopez hints at American Idol departure as show seeks younger judges to rival Britney and Demi &apos;Duct tape over the camera and a $1,000 a night Presidential Suite&apos;: Inside Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s last weekend together Efforts to hide tension &apos;Look how broken up we look&apos;: Professor Green denies split from Millie Mackintosh Said he made up lesbian rumours &apos;I just can&apos;t function in the morning&apos;: What Nick Grimshaw told BBC boss moments before being offered top breakfast slot On Chris&apos; show today Pudsey goes Stateside! Talented pooch wins over U.S. audiences with an adorable performance on Jay Leno Entranced by their show 
 
CREDIT CARDS: OUR TOP PICKS

   Best balance transfer credit card rates   Best credit cards for cashback and rewards   Best credit cards for overseas use   Best credit cards for spending
	</body>
</document>
