<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005639" url="http://www.bookbrowse.com/excerpts/index.cfm/book_number/1819/Chew-on-This" time="2012-07-12-22:13" support="2" score="0.0019100504709367054" bingtitle="Chew on This by Eric Schlosser, Charles W. Wilson: Read free book ..." webtitle="Chew on This by Eric Schlosser, Charles W. Wilson: Read free book excerpt (page 1 of 2)">
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000761" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>Moments later, grab the plastic tray with your ... The whole experience of eating at a fast-food restaurant has ... In the past but not now: No: Select Any That Apply</description>
	<body>
		Join   |   Gift   |   Member Login   |   Library Login 

 
 Email 
 
 Home Magazine What&apos;s New 
 Members Recommend Featured This Week Recent Hardcovers Recent Paperbacks Publishing Soon Book News 
 Read-Alikes Find a Book 
 Genres Settings Time Periods Themes Favorites Award Winners Book Finder Surprise Me! 
 Authors 
 Interviews Biographies Pronunciation Guide Author Websites 
 Book Clubs 
 Discuss Books Book Club Interviews Reading Guides Advice 
 Blog Free and Fun 
 First Impressions Wordplay Book Giveaway Polls Literary Quotes Personality Quiz 
 About 
 About Us Take a Tour Become a Member Gift Memberships People Say FAQ Meet the Reviewers Contact Us 
 
 
    Book Excerpt 
Read free book excerpt from Chew on This by Eric Schlosser, Charles W. Wilson, plus multiple reviews, author biography&amp;more

 
 
 
 Chew on This 
 Everything You Don&apos;t Want to Know About Fast Food 
by Eric Schlosser , Charles W. Wilson 
 Hardcover: May 2006,
270 pages.
Paperback: Apr 2007,
320 pages.

 Publication information Author Information: 
 Schlosser 
 Wilson 
 Critics&apos; Opinion:    
 Readers&apos; Rating:   
 About BookBrowse Rankings 
 
 Buy This Book 
 please select.... US Bookstores: Amazon Barnes&amp;Noble Indie Bookstore UK Bookstores: Amazon (UK) Waterstones Foyles 
 
 
 
 
 About the Book Reviews Beyond the Book Further Reading 
 Synopsis Excerpt Reading Guide 
Excerpt of Chew on This by Eric Schlosser, Charles W. Wilson
(Page 1 of 2)

   Printer Friendly Excerpt 

Pull open the glass door and feel the rush of cool air. Step inside. Look at the 
backlit color pictures of food above the counter, look at the cardboard ads for 
the latest Disney movie, get in line, and place your order. Hand over some 
money. Put the change back in your pocket. Watch teenagers in blue-and-
gold uniforms busy working in the kitchen. Moments later, grab the plastic 
tray with your food, find an empty table, and sit down. Unwrap the burger, 
squirt ketchup on the fries, stick the plastic straw through the hole in the lid 
of your drink. Pick up the burger and dig in.

The whole experience of eating at a fast-food restaurant has 
become so familiar, so routine, that we take it for granted. It has become just 
another habit, like brushing your teeth before bed. We do it without even 
thinking about itand thats the problem.

Every day about one out of fourteen Americans eats at a 
McDonalds. Every month about nine out of ten American children visit one. 
McDonalds has become the most popular fast-food chain in the worldand 
by far the most powerful.

In 1968 there were about 1,000 McDonalds restaurants, all of them in the 
United States. Now there are more than 31,000 McDonalds, selling Happy 
Meals in 120 countries, from Istanbul, Turkey, to Papeete, Tahiti. In the 
United States, McDonalds buys more processed beef, chicken, pork, 
apples, and potatoes than any other company. It spends more money on 
advertising and marketing than any other company that sells food. As a 
result, it is Americas most famous food brand. The impact of McDonalds on 
the way we live today is truly mind-boggling. The Golden Arches are now 
more widely recognized than the Christian cross.

Despite McDonalds fame and all the money it spends on 
advertising, every day the vast majority of its customers dont plan to eat 
there. Most fast-food visits are impulsive. The decision to buy fast food is 
usually made at the last minute, without much thought. People generally 
dont leave the house in the morning saying,Im going to make sure to eat 
some fast food today.Most of the time, theyre just walking down the 
sidewalk or driving down the road, not thinking about anything in particular. 
Maybe theyre hungry; maybe theyre not. Maybe theyre in a hurry and dont 
have time to cook. And then they see a great big fast-food signthe Golden 
Arches, the red-and-blue of a Dominos pizza box, the picture of Colonel 
Sandersand they suddenly think,Hey, I want some of that.So they stop 
to eat fast food. They do it because they feel like it. They just cant resist the 
impulse.

The point of this book is to take that strong impulse we all feelour hunger for sweet, salty, fatty fast foodsand make you think about it. 
Chew On This will tell you where fast food comes from, who makes it, whats 
in it, and what happens when you eat it. This is a book about fast food and 
the world it has made.

Food is one of the most important things youll ever buy. And yet 
most people never bother to think about their food and where it comes from. 
People spend a lot more time worrying about what kind of blue jeans to wear, 
what kind of video games to play, what kind of computers to buy. They 
compare the different models and styles, they talk to friends about the 
various options, they read as much as they can before making a choice. But 
those purchases dont really matter. When you get tired of old blue jeans, 
video games, and computers, you can just give them away or throw them out.

The food you eat enters your body and literally becomes part of 
you. It helps determine whether youll be short or tall, weak or strong, thin or 
fat. It helps determine whether you will enjoy a long, healthy life or die young. 
Food is of fundamental importance. So why is it that most people dont think 
about fast food and dont know much about it?

 1 2 next  » 
CHEW ON THIS: EVERYTHING YOU DONT WANT TO KNOW ABOUT 
FAST FOOD by Eric Schlosser and Charles Wilson. Copyright (c) 2006 by 
Eric Schlosser. Reprinted by permission of Houghton Mifflin Company. All 
rights reserved. 
 
 
 
 
 Become a Member Join Now! Gift Membership 
 
 
 Editor&apos;s Choice 
 
  Jul 12   Jul 10   Jul 10  
 
 City 
 P.D. Smith 
 
 With erudite prose and carefully chosen illustrations, this unique work of metatourism explores what cities are and how they work. It covers history, customs and language, districts, transport,... 
 
 The Virgin Cure 
 Ami McKay 
 
 From the author of the number one Canadian bestseller The Birth House comes the story of a young girl abandoned to the streets of post-Civil War New York City. 
 
 Tell the Wolves I&apos;m Home 
 Carol Rifka Brunt 
 
 In this striking literary debut, Carol Rifka Brunt unfolds a moving story of love, grief, and renewal as two lonely people become the unlikeliest of friends and find that sometimes you don&apos;t know... 
 
 Darwin&apos;s Ghosts 
 Rebecca Stott 
 
 Darwins Ghosts tells the story of the collective discovery of evolution, from Aristotle to Al-Jahiz, an Arab writer in the first century, from Leonardo da Vinci to Denis Diderot in... 
 
 The Undertow 
 Jo Baker 
 
 The American debut of an enthralling new voice: a vivid, indelibly told work of fiction that follows four generations of a family against the backdrop of a tumultuous century - a novel about... 
 
 
 
     Most Recent Blog Entries 
 The Sanctuary Bookstore&amp;Booklovers&apos; Bed and Breakfast, Lyme Regis, England BookBrowse&apos;s Read-Alikes and Nancy Pearl&apos;s Rule of Four Recommended Reading for Older Men - Best Books for Father&apos;s Day   RSS      subscribe 
 
 
 
   Latest BookBrowse News Project Gutenberg, the granddaddy of all digitization programs, now has 40,000 books available! (Jul 10 2012) 
Project Gutenberg may have long since been surpassed by the Internet Archive and Google Books, but the granddaddy of all digitization programs is still... Full Story 
 RSS feed More... 
 
 
 
 BookBrowse Poll Q: Which 2 of these elements are most important to you when reading fiction? More on this topic 
 Story: Books you can&apos;t put down - page turners Character: You connect to the characters and miss them when the book ends Setting: The setting is so real you feel you&apos;re almost there yourself Language: Books that you read slowly to savour the language Select Any That Apply [ View Poll Results ]
[ Previous Poll Results ] 
 
 
 
 Search: Title or Author 
 
 
 Free Newsletters Read latest issue 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 Online Book Club 
 
 More about
 Heading Out to Wonderful Join the discussion! 
 
 
 
 
 

 Win This Book! Shine Shine Shine 
 
 

 Publishes July 17
&apos;A funny, compelling love story from the freshest voice Ive heard in years.&apos; - Sara Gruen, author of Water for Elephants 

 Enter To Win Now! 

 
 
 
 
 

 First Impressions Members Recommend: The Woman at the Light 
by Joanna Brady
 15 Seconds 
by Andrew Gross
 The Age of Miracles 
by Karen Thompson Walker
 more... 
 
 
 
 BookBrowse Showcase
	</body>
</document>
