<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005130" url="http://chinablog.cc/2009/11/top-eight-most-popular-chinese-food-with-recipes/" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="1" score="0.007394073242066151" bingtitle="Top Eight Most Popular Chinese Food with Recipes | ChinaBlog.cc ..." webtitle="Top Eight Most Popular Chinese Food with Recipes | ChinaBlog.cc - Timeless China Blog">
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>... countryside of this Central America nation, they cannot find any familiar fast food ... Sorry, I should have served some napkins with them. Hope it’s not too late to save ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Library 
 China Travel Chinese Music Chinese Story 
 Archives 
 Polls Archive 
 Links About 
 Privacy policy Copyright 
 
 Home » Featured , Misc 
Top Eight Most Popular Chinese Food with Recipes
 Nov 12, 2009 Jensen Liu Leave a comment Go to comments 
Last Christmas, my friends Mike and Nicole went for a honeymoon trip to Belize. In the poor remote countryside of this Central America nation, they cannot find any familiar fast food restaurant such as McDonald or KFC. However, they are able to find a few Chinese restaurants. They were so amazed by their existence. Just like a proverb has told: There are Chinese people where sun rises; there is Chinese restaurant where Chinese people live.

 
 by the rocketeer @ flickr 
For the early Chinese immigrants to the United States, most of them do not have high educational level or any qualified skills. So it is their only choice to rely on housekeeping cooking skills to open a Chinese restaurant and make a living.

As a Chinese myself, I always say,“The most lucky thing to be a Chinese is to have Chinese food”. Like it or not, Chinese food has apparently become an important image of Chinese culture to the rest of the world. It is loved by hundreds of millions people all around the world. Although at lots of foreign places, the Chinese food is not really“authentic”Chinese food, it does change the food preferences of many people.

Here is the“eight most popular Chinese food for foreigners”selected by a survey with foreigners. Which ones of them have you ever tried? Recipe links are also included.

 CAUTION: don’t drool over your keyboard when viewing these yummy pictures! 

 1. Sweet and Sour Pork 糖醋里脊– recipe 

Not surprising that this is ranked first. With a mixture of sweet and sour flavor as well as bright, colorful appearance, nobody could not resist. One answer in the survey says“Sweet and Sour Chicken (NO PORK)”. It seems to a typical example that good dishes have been improved in foreign countries.

 

 2. Kung Pao Chicken 宫保鸡丁– recipe 

Many respondents from different countries have nominated this one in their answers. In China it is also one of those“must-have dishes”for a lot of people.

 

 3. Mapo Tofu 麻婆豆腐– recipe 

Probably no other cuisine can compete against Sichuan food on complicated use of spice. Current popularity of Sichuan cuisine is majorly because of the“spicy”word. Western cuisines will never give the same taste. Foreigners could only tell us their praise while busy enjoying the food.

 

 4. Wonton Soup 混沌汤– recipe 

Simply no western wheaten food could be as delicate and refreshing as wonton soup!

 

 5. Dumplings 饺子– recipe 

There is a saying in China: Nothing is more delicious than dumplings. It shows the importance of dumplings in Chinese food. It encompasses the essence of Chinese culture. No wonder that in the eyes of foreigners it can best represent Chinese dishes. In addition, fried dumpling is also very popular in foreign countries. Variations in flavor are achieved with changes in the filling. Never be surprised when you put something new in the filling.

 

 6. Spring Rolls 春卷– recipe 

It makes sense that foreign friends elected this dish. From this, we can easily find the influence of Chinese, especially Cantonese-style dim sum snacks in the minds of foreign people.

 

 7. Chow Mein 炒面– recipe 

When foreign friends wrote“Cantonese Chow Mein”, I did not realize what it is. I have to say that Cantonese people have made an outstanding contribution in changing the diet habits of foreign people.

 

 8. Peking Duck 北京烤鸭– recipe 

Every foreigner who comes to China would want to have this dish, because of its reputation and its history.

 

 What other Chinese cuisine do you think should be included in this list? Tell us your favorites! 
 Be Sociable, Share! 
 
 
 
 
 Tweet 
 Categories: Featured , Misc Tags: chinese cuisine , chinese food , top china Be Sociable, Share! 
 
 
 
 
 Tweet 
 Rate this: 
 (No Ratings Yet)
  Loading ... Comments (9) Trackbacks (0) Leave a comment Trackback 
 Magnus November 12th, 2009 at 11:54 | #1 Reply | Quote 
I HATE THIS BLOG! YOU ARE MAKING ME SO HUNGRY! I’VE NOW DROOLED ALL OVER MY KEYBOARD! UGH. Amazing pictures! THANKS!
 Jensen Liu November 12th, 2009 at 15:07 | #2 Reply | Quote 
 @Magnus 
Sorry, I should have served some napkins with them. Hope it’s not too late to save your keyboard 
 Zhu November 12th, 2009 at 21:07 | #3 Reply | Quote 
Mmmm…包子、 茄子、 韭菜饼 are among my favorite.

There are some dishes here that I really don’t see in China…it’s more a Western-Chinese kind of food.

But you are right, there are Chinese restaurants everywhere. Belize, for sure, I had great Chinese food there. But also Argentina, Peru and Bolivia (Chinese restaurants are called chifa by locals), France…really, everywhere.
 Zhu@china November 16th, 2009 at 21:22 | #4 Reply | Quote 
Your pics are so amazing. Where did you get that?
 Jensen Liu November 19th, 2009 at 08:30 | #5 Reply | Quote 
 @Zhu@china 
They are“Creative Commons”licensed images from Flickr.
 Modern Zen December 2nd, 2009 at 04:46 | #6 Reply | Quote 
Kung Pao chicken is my favourite! I can’t get enough chinese food 
 glchina December 11th, 2009 at 06:39 | #7 Reply | Quote 
when I travel to Shenyang last year ， I ate spring rolls the first time . When we went to restaurant ，my friend recommended me eat spring roll. wow, when I roll up on a thin piece of pie a fragrant dishes swallowed , I feel great.But after that time , I never eat again, because there is no spring rolls in the city I live now , I really don’t know it is one of China’s most popular foods.Thank you for your sharing
_________________________________________________
 http://world-culture-research.org/c.asp?d=15370 spring rolls–my favourite
 xtaaxtw December 11th, 2009 at 06:41 | #8 Reply | Quote 
aha!I LOVE Spring Rolls too
 Stage China January 29th, 2011 at 11:12 | #9 Reply | Quote 
Dumplings 饺子 and Peking Duck 北京烤鸭 really are my favourites! Delicious!
 

 No trackbacks yet. 
 Name (required) E-Mail (will not be published) (required) Website Subscribe to comments feed 
 Close 
 
 
 Chinese Music Classics of 20th Century–III/VI: Choir&amp;Opera Taibao Tetrapod: A Delicate Bronze Ware 
Who Am I?
 Yi Liu 
a postdoctoral researcher
living in San Diego, California.
 About Me 
Subscribe to ChinaBlog.cc
 RSS Email Twitter 
A bit Chinese wisdom
 “Rewards and punishment is the lowest form of education.”
 by  Zhuangzi 
Tag cloud
 Snipe and Clam Medan ancient instrument Yunnan BianQue Chinese Music Classics urban district Russian doll yin-yang xinjiang qiang village spring and autumn period temples India Ejin Banner violin tang dynasty Chinese new year Dai people Island forbidden city terra cotta warriors three kingdoms medicine wuqiao architecture audrey hepburn legend chinese food wine culture partable yurt video Mo Li Hua blog carnival flute cosmetic surgery traditional chinese culture kite Bird xi&apos;an pocketcultures index shadow puppetry world culture Southern and Northern Dynasties 
Categories
 open all | close all Amazon.com Widgets 
Recent Posts

 Red Flowers Blooming All Over the Mountain Bianzhong of Marquis Yi of Zeng: Heaviest Instrument in the World His Spear Against His Shield China Carnival #19: Fengshui, Carbon Tax Eight First-Class National Protected Plants in China – II/II 
 
Most Commented

 Why no year of the Cat? Ten Types of Residential Houses Chinese People Live In Top 10 Chinese Classical Music - Part I Top Eight Most Popular Chinese Food with Recipes About 
 
Blog Carnival
 CHINA CARNIVAL 
 Archives | Submit post Have a post about China? Why not share it with the world? Your trip to China, your Chinese culture experience, your opinion about Chinese history, art, music, anything but controvercial politics is welcomed at China Carnival. Join Us~ Log in | Combined theme Arthemia and iNove | Terms&amp;Copyrights
	</body>
</document>
