<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005327" url="http://www.farmerfranksfarmmarket.com/WHATS_COOKING_.php" time="2012-07-12-21:52" support="11" score="0.025149938897814583" bingtitle="WHATS COOKING? - Farmer Frank&apos;s Farm Market" webtitle="WHATS COOKING?">
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000554" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000963" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>If there is a special pie or cake you need, place your order. ... HOMEMADE ICE CREAM WHY PICK UP SUPPER AT A FAST FOOD RESTAURANT WHEN YOU CAN HAVE GOOD HOME COOKED MEALS ...</description>
	<body>
		FARMER FRANK&apos;S FARM MARKET 
 
 
 Home Page ANTIQUES&amp;COLLECTIBLES Jams, Pickles&amp;More Peanuts Flags&amp;Garden Decor Boiled Peanuts Cast Iron Veggies&amp;Fruits WHATS COOKING? CANDIES 
 
 FARMER FRANK&apos;S FARM MARKET 
 
 FARMER FRANK&apos;S
 is the place to come for home cooking.    

 DAILY MEAL SPECIALS INCLUDE:

SUNDAY: CHICKEN
MONDAY: HAMBURGER STEAK
TUESDAY: PORK CHOPS
WEDNESDAY: COOK&apos;S CHOICE
THURSDAY: MEATLOAF
FRIDAY: FISH
SATURDAY: LASAGNA
 If you need catering, give us a call.

 OUR MENU
 
 
 
 Sandwiches including Country Ham, Turkey, Club and Peanut Butter and Jelly, Soups such as Brunswick Stew and Beef Vegetable, BBQ, Chicken and Dumplings, Hamburgers and Hotdogs. 


 

 Our Chicken and Dumplings are homemade! We even make the pastry. Pick up a hot cup or take a large container home to feed the whole family. 


 

 Our jacks might not be the prettiest but they sure do taste good. Homemade! That&apos;s right. Even the filling is made from the sweet potato or the apple. It doesn&apos;t come from a can. 


 

 Try our baked goods. We have pies, cakes and breads.  


 

 

 Try our Homemade Chocolate Covered Peanuts
 

 and Chocolate Covered Peanut Brittle
 

 

 If you are planning an event, give us a call. We do prepare foods in large quantities. If there is a special pie or cake you need, place your order. 

Other items we have available:
 
 POTATO SALAD
CANDY YAMS
COLLARDS
CHICKEN SALAD
BUTTER BEANS&amp; CORN
KALE
CRAB SALAD
OYSTERS
PEACH COBBLER
BANANA PUDDING
ICED TEA
LEMONADE
HOMEMADE ICE CREAM
 
  WHY PICK UP SUPPER AT A FAST FOOD RESTAURANT WHEN YOU CAN HAVE GOOD HOME COOKED MEALS FROM
FARMER FRANK&apos;S? 


  
 
 

 

 




 

 

 10% OFF Take this coupon to the farm market to get 10% discount on your next meal. Discount is for the &quot; meal of the day .&quot;
EXPIRES 11/01/2012 

 

 
 


 

 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

  

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
         
 

 
                                                    
 
                                                    
 

 
     Powered by WebRing . Copyright . Farmer Frank&apos;s Farm Market. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
