<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005501" url="http://www.aceco.org/escape/health/index.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:03" support="1" score="0.0010369776517899696" bingtitle="Health and Wellness Weight loss without loosing any of the ..." webtitle="Health and WellnessWeight loss without loosing any of the 
nutrition that your body needs">
			<query id="000871" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>... value menu at your favorite fast food restaurant. N.R.G. delivers you a complete meal ... with the shake (do not eat at that meal ... available a complete new line of ...</description>
	<body>
		Ace Co 

 Independent Representative of Escape International # 258854 
   Start 
 a business of your own sign up now for FREE! 


 **Use the # below when asked** 
 Rep ID # 258854 
 Watch the Escape International Presentation 

 How to get your business 
 started off right 
&quot;Your first 24 hours&quot; 

 Escape the pounds with the Escape diet plan 



  

 Escape the pounds with the Escape Diet Plan 


 
 
 Health and Wellness 
  Weight loss without loosing any 
of the nutrition that your body needs!
 
 
 /\ Click the banner above to order NRG or the Colon Cleanse /\ 

 
 Escape NRG   Meal Replacement Shake 

 Nutraceutical 
Meal Replacement Shake  
 
 
 Delivers 100% 
 Of The Optimum Nutrition Your Body Needs. Scientifically 
 Formulated Medically 
 Proven 
 Functional Food 
 
 NRG     Is: 
 
 Actual Meal Replacement 
 
  Not just supplement 
 
 
 
 
 Why do I need 
Supplements in the first place? 

 What makes Escape&apos;s N.R.G. better than everything 
else? 

 Why is 
Being Overweight so Bad? 

 Can N.R.G. be used for weight loss? 

 How do I use N.R.G. for weight loss? 

 
 
 24 HOUR message on wellness and what works as well as what doesn&apos;t work 
 YOU WILL BE SURPRISED! 

 Listen and learn how vitamins work vs NRG 

 248 788 7074 
 
 

 Why Do I Need Supplements In the First Place? According to leading medical researchers and 
clinicians, every American should use a daily multinutrient supplement to 
address the health dilemma of nutritionally poor diets. Experts have revealed 
conclusive information that farmland throughout North America is 85% 
micronutrient depleted. &quot;It doesn&apos;t matter how much you eat, and how hard you 
try to eat clean healthy foods, you still can&apos;t consume enough of the essential 
nutrients your body needs everyday&quot;. 

 back to top 

 What Makes Escape N.R.G. Better Than Everything 
Else?   N.R.G. is different from every other nutritional 
supplement found in other MLM companies or on the shelves at the local store 
because it is classified as a NUTRACEUTICAL which means that it has been Scientifically 
formulated , Medically Proven , 
and is recognized as a Functional Food . A NUTRACEUTICAL is any Non-toxic food component that has scientifically 
proven health benefits . The functional component of the food must be 
standardized and manufactured under&quot;Good Management Practices&quot;(GMP).   

 N.R.G. provides your body with OPTIMAL NUTRITION by delivering all of the essential nutrients your body needs in a great tasting shake. N.R.G. furnishes the ingredients, which have 
demonstrated effectiveness for brain tissue and nervous system functioning, and 
for cellular replication in the immune system.  It is 
common knowledge among researchers that the body&apos;s natural defense mechanism 
against disease (immune system) is highly dependent upon the absorption of 
nutrition to fuel its function . Without proper absorption of 
essential nutrients, the immune system is unable to ward off potential disease 
or to effectively battle against existing conditions. N.R.G. is extremely &quot;bio-available&quot; and has an absorption rate 
of up to 90%. This absorption rate demonstrates that the ingredients in our 
product are highly assimilated by the body at the cellular level.    

 N.R.G.&apos;s optimal nutrition allows your body to 
function at PEAK PERFORMANCE and it is more 
economical than the value menu at your favorite fast food restaurant. N.R.G. 
delivers you a complete meal replacement (not just a supplement) for only $1.68 
per meal (wholesale cost including shipping). N.R.G. is the Solution for 
you! 

 View a&quot;nutritional value&quot; comparison between our N.R.G. and other leading shakes. 

 back to top 

 Why is Being Overweight So 
Bad?    

 O BESITY 
HAS PASSED SMOKING AS THE #1 PREVENTABLE CAUSE OF DEATH.    

 An obese person can be a little as 20-30lbs. 
overweight, yet that can dramatically increase your risk of death or your risk 
of getting a life threatening/debilitating disease. 

 Response Risk 
 Increased By Death 
 From Heart Disease 110% Death 
 From Cancer 60% Acquire 
 Type II Diabetes 2600% Acquire 
 High Blood Pressure 260% Acquire 
 Degenerative Arthritis 400% 

 According to the U.S. Surgeon General, Vice Admiral 
Richard H. Carmona,&quot;As a society, we can no longer afford to make poor health 
choices such as being physically inactive and eating an unhealthy diet. These 
choices have led to a tremendous obesity epidemic&quot;.  

 back to top 

 Can N.R.G. Be Used For Weight Loss?   N.R.G . can be used for weight loss because it is 
actually a meal replacement, not just a supplement. The bottom line about 
weight loss is consuming less fuel than you use. Yet, your body needs and 
demands fuel (cravings) throughout the day. So how do we give our body what it 
needs, yet do it with less calories than we are burning throughout the day? 

 To provide you with the OPTIMAL SOLUTION, we must 
first explore a few problems that need to be understood: 

 Problem #1: Today&apos;s food cannot provide the body with what it needs on a daily basis, 
regardless of how well we eat, because of the micronutrient depletion in the 
land (an apple today has less nutritional value than an apple from 20 years 
ago). 

 Problem #2: Most of the nutrients that do remain in the foods, are removed during 
processing, preserving, cooking, etc. 

 Problem #3: If 
your body doesn&apos;t get the Carbohydrates, Proteins, and Fats that it needs, along 
with all of the Vitamins and Minerals, it will crave food intensely, and/or it 
will shut down its energy level or ability to perform (headaches, stress, low 
energy, sickness, etc.). 

 Problem #4: When your body has these cravings (telling you it is in need of certain things, 
e.g.,&quot;thirsty feeling&quot;= needs water) we feed it more food, because we feel&quot;hungry&quot;. Yet we are giving our bodies more empty food in high calorie amounts. 

 Problem #5:  Because we feed our cravings, our bodies receive a lot of food, calories, and&quot;stuff&quot;, but not the necessary vitamins, minerals, and fuel that they need. Cravings continue, weight begins to climb. 

 Problem #6:  Without the body receiving the fuel it needs, we do not have the energy to 
exercise, or even get through the day, without feeling exhausted, lethargic, or 
anxious. Our bodies burn little fuel (calories) but we are consuming a lot, so 
we gain. 

 SOLUTION : Give 
Your body the optimum nutrition that it requires each day by drinking 3 N.R.G. 
shakes per day (only 160 calories each). 

 back to top 

 How Do I Use N.R.G. for 
Weight Loss?   

 3 
Opt ions For Weight Loss With N.R.G. 

 (Note: Consult Your Physician before 
beginning any exercise or diet plan) Also, read the 6 problems listed above for 
a greater understanding of the 3 weight loss options. 

 
 Gradual Weight Loss: Consume 
 a shake at each meal, approximately 30 minutes prior to eating. You will not 
 need to eat as much when your body gets what it needs. DO NOT SKIP A SHAKE. Even if you don&apos;t regularly eat breakfast, have a shake each day. Your body 
 will respond favorably to receiving fuel all day long. You should not 
 experience cravings. If you do, have a shake. 
 Faster Weight Loss:  Consume 
 a shake at each meal, but replace 1 or 2 of your meals with the shake (do not 
 eat at that meal). Your body will receive all of the essential nutrients it 
 needs for optimal performance, yet with only 160 calories/meal. By removing 
 unnecessary foods, your body will feel lighter and you will have higher 
 energy. 
 Fastest Weight Loss: (SOLE 
 SOURCE 4:2:4): Consume 3 shakes per day, every day, for 4 weeks. Do not eat 
 food. Your body will receive all of the protein, carbohydrates, fat, and 
 nutrients that it needs for peak performance, yet at a rate of only 480 
 calories per day. After 4 Weeks, continue the 3 shakes per day, but also 
 consume one meal each day for 2 weeks. After you complete the 2 weeks with a 
 meal added, repeat the first 4 week regimen by&quot;sole sourcing&quot;for an 
 additional 4 weeks (only shakes). You will drop weight quickly and safely! Losing weight fast is the best way, if and only if you are giving your body 
 the nutrition it needs. With N.R.G. you are!  

 &quot;Sole Sourcing is far easier than it 
sounds. I was not hungry and didn&apos;t have cravings, because my body was getting 
what it wanted...good food! The first day is the hardest, but by day 2 you will 
already feel lighter and after 2 days, you won&apos;t want to eat. I didn&apos;t exercise 
a lot during my sole source period but I did take 4 or 5 long walks. If you 
want to lose weight now, and you are sick and tired, make sure all is ok with 
your health and start your sole source schedule right away. My stats are listed 
here for your viewing:&quot;, David Rutz, President of Escape 
International, Inc. 

   Start Week One Week Two Week Three Week Four Weight 306 288 278 273 270 Body Fat % 30.2% 28.2% 26.6% 25% 24.1% Stomach 53 1/4&quot; 50&quot; 46 3/4&quot; 45&quot; 43 1/4&quot; 

 Future Stats to Follow 

 back to top 

 20 Minute Audio Overview 

 
 
 
 
 Important links for you 

 
 Documents on Demand 
 Explore Seminars 
 In the News 
 Contact Corporate Office 
 About Us 
 Wireless Phone Service 
 Business Opportunity 
 Products&amp;Services 
 Back 
 Office Center 
 Modify Your Site 
 Z TEL 
 Websites 
 VoIP 
 Video Phone and hook up Info 
 Long Distance 
 NRG 
 Shakes 
 Talk America   
 VoIP 
 Order Now   
 Colon Cleanse 
 

 
 



 
 
 Colon Cleanse 
 
 Cleanses The Intestinal Tract 
 
 
 
 Key Functions of this product 
 Moistens and Lubricates the Intestines Promotes Bowel Cleansing Intestinal Upset and Inflammation Breaks-up Bowel Obstruction Decongests and Cleanses the Intestinal Tract 
 
 
 Click Here For DOD 
 503
 
 
 Traditional&amp;Current Uses: 

Colon Cleanse is a highly effective herbal combination used to moisten, 
lubricate and cleanse the intestinal tract and promotes bowel movements.

This formulation has broad beneficial potential in the treatment of 
constipation, intestinal toxicity, intestinal upset and inflammation, abdominal 
distension and intestinal gas, purifies the intestines, eliminates food 
stagnation by removing old stuff, and clears intestinal microorganisms and 
toxins. Also promotes bile flow, stimulates the liver and gall bladder.

Used for constipation, irritable bowel, dysentary, colitis, foul breathe, gas 
and bloating, toxemia, cellulite, gallstones, and headaches. Colon Cleanse is 
used to clear toxins from complications of intestinal Candidiasis, parasites and 
all toxic conditions. Bowel cleansing is a vital and important step in the 
treatment of most disease processes.
 
 Our 
Colon Cleanse Contains the Following: 
 
 Bentonite Clay: 

Bentonite, as well as other types of healing clays, have been used by 
indigenous cultures since before recorded history. There is an electrical aspect 
to Bentonite&apos;s ability to bind and absorb toxins. Technically, the clay first &quot;adsorbs&quot; toxins (heavy metals, free radicals, pesticides) attracting them 
to its extensive surface area where they adhere like flies to sticky paper; then 
it &quot;absorbs&quot; the toxins, taking them in a way a sponge mops up a kitchen 
spill.

 Rhamnus Frangula: 

Also known as Alder Buckthorn, its purgative action is said to be similar to 
that of rhubarb. It works without irritating the system and can be used for all 
conditions causing or associated with constipation, including liver and 
gallbladder problems. It produces no constipative backlash after purgation as 
some other remedies do, neither does it become less effective with repeated use.

 Linum Usitatissimum: 

Linum Usitatissimum, also known as Flax seed, has a long history of medicinal 
use. Its main effects being a laxative and expectorant that soothes irritated 
tissues.

 Rhamnus Purshiana: 

Other names: Cascara Sagrada, California Buckthorn, Cascara. It is one of the 
oldest, time proven, and most reliable remedies for chronic constipation. It is 
not habit forming. It is a good intestinal tonic. An excellent remedy for 
gallstones and increases the secretion of bile.

 Menta Piperita: 

More commonly known as Peppermint, it is an excellent carminative, having a 
relaxing effect on the muscles of the digestive system. It combats flatulence 
and stimulates bile and digestive juice flow. It is used to relieve intestinal 
colic, flatulent dyspepsia and associated conditions.

 Senna Alexandrina: 

Senna Alexandrina is a laxitive herb with antibacterial effects. It is a 
safe, stimulating laxitive with a long history of use. It acts as a stool 
softener so is beneficial for hemorrhoids or anal fissures.

 Zingiber officinale: 

Zigiber officinale, commonly known as Ginger, is a classic tonic for the 
digestive tract. Classified as an aromatic bitter, it stimulates digestion. It 
also keeps the intestinal muscles toned. This action eases the transport of 
substances through the digestive tract, lessening irritation to the intestinal 
walls.

 Althaea officinalis: 

The herb Althaea Officinalis, also known as Marshmallow root, has been used 
for centuries as both a food and a medicine. Its botanical name comes from the 
Greek word&quot;altho,&quot;which means&quot;to cure.&quot;It is beneficial for inflammation and 
ulceration of the digestive tract, hiatal hernia, and urinary tract infections.

 back to top 

 
 
 
 /\ Click the banner above to order NRG or the Colon Cleanse /\ 

 

 


 

 

 Now available a complete new 
line of communications products! 

 

 Local Phone Service with 
free unlimited long distance plans starting at $19.95 

 DSL or most any High 
Speed Internet online service 

 

 Nationwide wireless phone 
service with the hottest phones on the market 
 
 
 Want to meet new online friends? 

 Find a date? 

 Chat with other people in your area with the same 
 interests as you! 

 Invite other friends to find a romantic match that they have 
 been looking for! 

 Join Now! 

  
 
 
 
 
 
 

 Nutraceutical and dietary 
supplements that provide 100% of your body&apos;s needs 

 

 Video Phones that you can 
see who you are talking to much better than web cam phones 

   Much 
more will also be launched in the near future!! 

 New products and services 
will be available in a short time so check back often! 

 

 New 
products and services will be available in a short time so check back often! 

 
 
 Gods Help | Lords
Prayer  |  Send me your
links to other religious sites  |  Ace
Co Order Site  |  Home  | XM Satellite Radio | Loose Weight and feel Great   | GET NRG |
 Free Long Distance |  New lead site!    |   video
on home business  |  Ace Co  |  Reason to start business |  Former Excel Reps  |  Escape
Business  |  Local Phone Service  |  Earn
Money from home video |  2way 
 Pagers   | Internet 
 Access   |  Wireless 
 Phones  |  Unlimited
Free Long distance calling! across the USA and Canada | Earn money from home!   |  Websites to put your business online   |  Escape International   |  Online 
 Shopping  |  4Aceco.com  | Mike Peeples  |  Where
are you going in the future? video   |  WT
Powers   |   Message
to Mike  |  The
answer to success  | WT
powers Marketing  |   Search
Engines  | Search Ace Co site | Order
Site | How To? | Search
Engines | Trucking Software | Justice | Speed up your computer  |  Get rid of spyware  |  Performance Pro  | Free Pic Page | Useful Info | Alphabet | X M Radio | Ebay  | 
 Digital Music 
 
 Ebay  | Roxio, Inc. | Wal-Mart.com | Ace Co Stores | Target.com | XM Radio | Escape Sign up Free | 
  
 NRG Nutraceutical Shake 
 Order Now 
 


          

 Contact me!&lt;Click
Here&gt;
	</body>
</document>
