<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005532" url="http://www.henrycountytimes.com/Archives/2012/01.25.12/hey_henry.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:05" support="2" score="0.0017448994064356968" bingtitle="Hey Henry" webtitle="Hey Henry">
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>... from the back to window, take my payment back to the back to get a receipt. ... use disposable styrofoam trays ... more than he makes at a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Proudly 
 celebrating ten years of faithfully serving our readers, the 
 people of Henry County 
  
 
 &quot;Celebrating 
 Henry County&quot; 
 
 
  
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
       
  
  
 
 
 
 
 
 
 We have 12 new 
 Hey Henrys 
 this week! 

 Submit your 
 &quot;Hey Henry&quot; 
 
  
     
    
Hey Henry is our own little vent section. Read others&apos; vents, and post one of your own. 
 You&apos;ll never look at life the same way again.
 
 Disclaimer 

 
 01.25.12

Hey Henry, do you think maybe Newt 
 was including himself when he said we cant get decent people to 
 run for office?

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t believe the teacher that wrote questions about 
 slavery should have to apologize to anyone. White people were slaves 
 too.

Hey Henry, just a reminder to arrogant, ignorant drivers who tend to 
 tailgate on our roadways. Some vehicles are manual transmissions 
 that have acceleration fluctuations to allow for gear changes after 
 stopping at required intersections/red lights. If your level of 
 intelligence causes you to blow your horn and unsafely tailgate as 
 if you are the only tax paying vehicle on the roadway, just do 
 everyone a favor, STAY HOME.

Hey Henry, I&apos;ve heard it all now. I know a college student who went 
 to Burger King to apply for a job and was told they are saving the 
 jobs for people who have kids and really need to work. Is this 
 discrimination?

Hey Henry, you know bartenders aren&apos;t allowed to drink, so it is not 
 like we have hungover assistant principals, but we do have some 
 deadbeat parents!

Hey Henry, the guineas at Old Jackson Road and Laney have saved a 
 number of drivers from getting speeding tickets. Quite a few of the 
 chickens aka guineas have also lost their lives due to the speed 
 demons traveling that road in the daylight hours (none lost their 
 lives between dusk and dawn because they were roosting in the trees 
 next to their home). As for leash laws, I don&apos;t recall ever seeing 
 anyone walk a chicken or a guinea on a leash before, at least not 
 in my lifetime I haven&apos;t. The guineas are just living and coping 
 with life wandering free in the country and crossing county back 
 roads in search of food such as insects and water. Maybe if your 
 readers would take a few moments out of their busy lives they would 
 enjoy watching wildlife living off the land. Just my thoughts for 
 the day. Sincerely, a wildlife watcher

Hey Henry, how is it we can buy an airport and give the 
 commissioners a raise but not increase our police officers pay? I 
 dont mean the high ranking officers, I am talking about the guys 
 that patrol our streets everyday.

Hey Henry, do as I say, not as I do.

Hey Henry, instead of patching Cohen road over and over and over 
 again, wouldn&apos;t it be easier to re-pave it. It needs it anyway! I 
 believe after a couple of months of going down that road, cars will 
 have to start replacing their struts more often. Since SPLOST 
 passed, get busy and pave!

Hey Henry, I went to O&apos;Charleys in Stockbridge for dinner Thursday 
 night at 7:30 and while parking the car I noticed two out-of-state 
 cars in the parking lot with the passenger side windows broken out.

Hey Henry, in regard to the assistant principal bartending, do you 
 think tenure and loyalty mean nothing? Twelve years with one job, be 
 it bartending or not, is job security like no other. Especially when 
 it does not affect elementary school-aged children. They aren&apos;t 
 aware of the ins and outs of a restaurant or bar and most certainly 
 shouldn&apos;t be sitting at a bar (even if it&apos;s in a family restaurant) 
 on a Friday night, so what does it really matter? I am sure he 
 doesn&apos;t walk into a classroom and teach bartending. Good 
 administrators and educators are hard to come by. Consider that 
 before trying to discourage someone honestly supporting a family - 
 bartender or not.
 
01.18.12

Hey Henry, I just want to wish a very 
 special Happy Birthday to the love of my life, Elissa. I hope you 
 have a wonderful birthday and I love you!

Hey Henry, why is it that every time it rains, huge holes form on 
 Jonesboro Street between the Square and railroad tracks? They even 
 form where holes have already been patched. Someone is going to blow 
 a tire on one of these&quot;craters&quot;one day.

Hey Henry, thanks to the two guys holding signs and having a good 
 time at the Tanger intersection in Locust Grove. I always have to 
 smile.

Hey Henry, why doesn&apos;t Henry County have a 55+ community for 
 renters?

Hey Henry, not satisfied with library hours or temperatures? With 
 the county currently millions in the red, you&apos;ll soon have fewer 
 branches to gripe about. In spite of what the media tell you, there 
 is a recession going on.

Hey Henry... To the person saying a Vice Principal is also 
 bartending at night.... How would you know? Why are you hanging out 
 in a bar instead of being at home with your kids? At least the Vice 
 Principal is working!

Hey Henry, guineas/chickens whatever they are...They should not be 
 allowed to go into the road. Leash laws do exists for the safety of 
 these animals and drivers in this county! I do agree the speeds are 
 in excess on Old Jackson but these animals going into the roadway 
 are a hazard also. What are you going to do when you get hit head on 
 because someone is swerving to miss the guineas?

Hey Henry, attending the City Council Meetings in Stockbridge is 
 better than any&quot;reality&quot;show ever made.

Hey Henry, a big thank you to Phil at Moyes Pharmacy in Hampton for 
 saving my day.

Hey Henry, the older I get, the older elderly gets.

Hey Henry, I wish there was a decent place to eat in the Kelleytown 
 area. I really miss the East Lake Diner.

Hey Henry, why are the restrooms at Heritage Park locked with a 
 winterized sign? People do go to the park in the winter and need the 
 restrooms open.

Hey Henry, the City of McDonough did a great job on the Square. The 
 brick walkways, benches and even music are wonderful. However, it&apos;s 
 time to do something about the storefronts that surround it. 
 Improving them would finish the project.

Hey Henry, people who have the means to pay their mortgage, but walk 
 away from that responsibility because the home value is less than 
 the mortgage are predators and have no honor!

Hey Henry, is there some rule against a Vice Principal having a 
 part-time job, or is the problem that you have an alcohol prejudice?

Hey Henry, Stop signs mean stop! Not go when you feel like it, or 
 don&apos;t stop at all. Henry County doesnt seem to know exactly how a 
 stop sign is used!
 
01.11.12

Hey Henry, I want to send a HUGE 
 Thank You to the person who found and turned in my AARP/Visa card to 
 the Lake Dow CVS on Hwy. 81 on or around December 14. It really 
 increased my faith in humankind to know there are still some honest 
 people. It made my Christmas much better. You know who you are and I 
 hope you read The Times. Thanks again!

Hey Henry, I was traveling out 81 East where the new traffic signal 
 is going in at Racetrack Road. I saw they finally got some wire 
 strung from all four poles. The first thing that came to my mind was 
 if the Man in Black, Johnny Cash, was there, he would say Theyre 
 fixing this intersection one piece at a time.

Hey Henry, did anyone know that you can be a Vice Principal for a 
 school by day and a bartender by night in Henry County?

Hey Henry, those guineas (not chickens) near the road at Laney and 
 Old Jackson are a blessing. The way people fly down Old Jackson Rd. 
 at such a busy intersection is just clucking nuts. A truck had to 
 swerve across the road and into the guineas yard not to rear end me 
 while trying to turn onto my road. I think a Pay Attention and Slow 
 Down sign will work.

Hey Henry, for all of you who vote yes to SPLOST, just remember that 
 most of it is LOST.

Hey Henry, I got my vehicle tag bills for 2012 and was shocked to 
 see that the ad valorem tax is the exact same price as it was in 
 2011. The County says my vehicle has not depreciated in the last 12 
 months. How could that be possible?

Hey Henry, I have a suggestion for next year&apos;s Geranium Drop. On the 
 giant pot have ACME in big letters, and have people running around 
 dressed in coyote suits on the sidewalks beneath.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s too bad we can&apos;t enjoy the McDonough library during 
 the few hours they&apos;re open because it&apos;s so cold in there!

Hey Henry, did you know that there&apos;s a new tax we as taxpayers are 
 going to get hit with? It&apos;s to cover the money that Georgia got from 
 the Feds. I don&apos;t recall asking for the money myself. The governor 
 did, but we have to pay for the loan he asked for. Surprise!

Hey Henry, I think Steve Davis is earning every bit of his $17,000. 
 He&apos;s a doer.

Hey Henry, to the person who told the person to quit being lazy and 
 get out of the car to pay the water bill, I know this person and 
 they happen to have an incapacitating injury and is not mobile like 
 you and me. So shame on you for your remark about being lazy.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s a crying shame what they have done to our city 
 Square. We used to have a perfectly good roundabout.

Hey Henry, when will you ever pave Peeksville Rd? We&apos;ve lived here 
 24 years and ruined many a car driving on this poorly maintained 
 dirt road. Every once in a while they sprinkle a few rocks here and 
 there, but never give it a good solid coat of gravel. Peeksville is 
 a main thoroughfare from Ola to Locust Grove with quite a bit of 
 traffic, including the Water Authority trucks and people with boats 
 going to the Tussahaw Reservoir. Why don&apos;t you get the Water 
 Authority to pitch in and help with the cost of paving since they 
 are part of the problem? Thanks for the opportunity to sound off.
 
01.04.12

Hey Henry, thank you Commissioner 
 Warren Holder for being man enough to vote&quot;Yes&quot;so that Sunday 
 sales will be on the ballot in March.

Hey Henry, I want to thank the family on East Mays Rd. off 155 for 
 the beautiful Christmas scene. We loved it, even after Christmas it 
 was still great. Next year I hope more people will leave on their 
 Christmas lights after Christmas. Some of us were just finally 
 getting to get out and see them. Happy New Year to all the Henry 
 County folks!

Hey Henry, okay there are leash laws for dogs and cats, right? Well, 
 what about chickens? I sure do wish someone would do something about 
 the chickens on the corner of Old Jackson and Laney. They just cross 
 the road as if they own it and apparently they are deaf cause the 
 horn doesnt phase them... Come on man, fence in your yard or at 
 least put your chickens in a fence.

Hey Henry, has anyone else noticed that the left turn signal on Bill 
 Gardner when turning onto Tanger Blvd. only lasts for about three 
 seconds. Ive never seen all the cars make it through without 
 running the light. Can this be fixed?

Hey Henry, thanks to the Locust Grove Wal-Mart&quot;Secret Santa&quot;who 
 provided for the children&apos;s Christmas while their mother has been in 
 ICU, Thank you for all of the food and gifts. Your generosity is 
 well appreciated.

Hey Henry, just a reminder that the leash law applies to cats, too.

Hey Henry, a big Thank You to all of those that drove out to our 
 home and watched our Christmas Light Show on East Mays Road in 
 Stockbridge. We do it every year. Come back and see us again in 
 2012. A bigger Thank you to the paper for featuring our home this 
 year. Happy New Year everyone!

Hey Henry, my wife said that I don&apos;t listen...........at least, 
 that&apos;s what I think she said.

Hey Henry, I think Henry County should fix their roads. When you 
 come off 75 going north at Jodeco Rd. you can&apos;t miss the big long 
 hole on the end of the ramp just as you get onto Jodeco Rd.

Hey Henry, the new traffic lights are up on 138 in Stockbridge. We 
 were hoping they would synchronize the lights to help with the 
 traffic flow. Looks like someone got a big check for new lights but 
 we&apos;re stuck with the same old mess!

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t understand why the HCBOE will not press charges 
 against people who are crossing attendance lines from out of the 
 county to attend Henry County Schools. As a taxpayer to the schools 
 and court system it is what my dollars should be used for.

Hey Henry, our tax bill came in the mail on Christmas Eve. Great 
 timing Commissioner Curry and a Merry Christmas to you too!

Hey Henry, in response to&quot;County Probate Judge requested 
 retroactive pay.&quot;The County never paid what was due. A workman is 
 worth his hire. Do you work for less than agreed?

Hey Henry, it is sad when a country considers one race more 
 important than others. One race should not be more important then 
 another race. We all are out here trying to make it. Struggling 
 doesnt have a skin color.
 
12.28.11

Hey Henry, thanks to everyone 
 involved in the decoration on the Square. They made a lovely 
 backdrop for my holiday pictures.

Hey Henry, you dog lovers need to keep your dogs on a leash! There 
 is a leash law in Henry County.

Hey Henry, I would like to say a big thank you to the person who 
 found my sons debit card in the Walmart shopping center and then 
 turned it in to Suntrust. So glad that there are still honest people 
 in this world. You are truly an angel.

Hey Henry, I think you should dedicate one issue to Hey Henry. 
 That way all the vents make the paper, not just a select few. Come 
 on, we all need a little vent every once in a while!

Hey Henry, this community has proven once again why I moved to Henry 
 County. You have all heard about the tragic event that occurred on 
 December 19 to the Butler/Thornton family. The support and love that 
 this community has given to the families of the children that have 
 been left behind and the mothers and grandmothers that mourn their 
 children and grandchildren is amazing. I want to say how proud I am 
 to live in Henry County and how grateful I am for the people who 
 have come together to support and and assist these families. I am 
 sure Dustin, Kelly, Brooke and Braylon are smiling down from Heaven 
 and are thankful that their loved ones have your support.

Hey Henry, people, if the sign says 20 items or fewer, don&apos;t get 
 in line with 30 items and then look furtively at those of us waiting 
 with our 10 items like you&apos;ve cheated the system. All you have 
 succeeded in doing is exposing yourself as the cheat that you really 
 are.

Hey Henry, Happy Holidays to everyone at The Henry County Times! 
 Thanks for all you do all year long. (Ed. note - we love you too!)

Hey Henry, would the media just tell us? Is Kim Jong Il or really 
 dead?

Hey Henry, to the person complaining about paying their water bill 
 at the drive-through window and waiting 12 minutes. Go inside. You 
 always get faster service inside a business, as they tend to wait on 
 the people who are standing in front of them. Quit being lazy and 
 get out of your car!

Hey Henry, must be someone that needs to retire before the Eagles 
 Landing extension can be completed. Sure tired of going over uneven 
 bridge joints.

Hey Henry, we need to remember our men and women who are overseas 
 and away from loved ones this holiday season. Not just the soldiers 
 in Afghanistan. But also in places like France and Germany. I 
 remember when I was in the service in 1971. The Bob Hope Show came 
 and performed for us, and there for a little while we were able to 
 forget about where we were and what we were doing. Ill never forget 
 when Bob Hope sang Silent Night. That was really something. So lets 
 not forget about them and the sacrifices they make for our freedom.

Hey Henry, thank you so much for the person who turned in the 
 McDonald&apos;s gift card at the Kroger at Price Quarters/East Lake. You 
 will be blessed! My faith is restored.
 
12.21.11

Hey Henry, the best Christmas tree in Henry County is on Leguin Mill 
 Rd. just past South Ola Rd.

Hey Henry, we need someone to enforce the noise ordinance over here 
 on Hooten, College, Cleveland and Zack Hinton streets. Somebody 
 needs to do something to quiet down these fools.

Hey Henry, I would like to thank the person who found my Wii game in 
 a cart at Walmart and returned it to the store. You not only saved 
 my grandson&apos;s Christmas gift but reaffirmed my trust that some 
 people do the right thing! May you have the best holiday ever! You 
 will be in my prayers for the rest of my life.

Hey Henry, for the one who is misinformed about SPLOST and&quot;all 
 administrators getting raises&quot;.... uh, not so much! I am the spouse 
 of an administrator and there are no raises on the horizon. There 
 seems to be a lot of criticism from people who have no idea what 
 they are talking about. Merry Christmas!

Hey Henry, can someone tell me why are there so many traffic lights 
 hanging above the intersection of 155 and Lawrenceville St?

Hey Henry, in response to our tax dollars being used to pay inmate 
 work crews from other counties. Check it out. It&apos;s cheaper to 
 contract convict labor than maintain county staff.

Hey Henry, why did it take me 12 minutes to pay the water bill at 
 city hall in the drive thru line? There was not even anyone in front 
 of me! The clerk has to come from the back to window, take my 
 payment back to the back to get a receipt. Along the way stopping 
 and talking to people. They have a computer terminal located at the 
 drive thru window. When I asked the clerk why it couldnt be 
 processed there, she laughed and said none of the equipment at the 
 window worked. Really? First of all, dont laugh about it and 
 secondly, lets get it fixed!

Hey Henry, for those complaining about Sunday alcohol sales. Here is 
 your solution - don&apos;t buy on Sunday! For those of you that want to 
 control others choices, feel free to move elsewhere.

Hey Henry, I believe the taxpayers should be up in arms about the 
 new Campground Road SPLOST project. There is no way that it will 
 improve the traffic problem. This very expensive undertaking is a 
 waste of much needed money. I for one will never vote for another 
 SPLOST penny!

Hey Henry, I am sure I speak for all school bus drivers...we love 
 our job and kids... but will we ever get a raise...we transport 
 precious ones safely and with love everyday...but come on Henry 
 County we need a raise... It&apos;s been long overdue...Please 
 help...Very low pay and higher insurance premiums...It is really sad 
 but over the years I have noticed you get what you pay for.

Merry Christmas to all and to all a Happy and Safe New Year. And 
 remember Jesus is the reason all season long.

Hey Henry, illegal immigrants should not get free education and 
 medical care at our expense. I was born and raised on a farm and we 
 got the work done with Americans. Sorry to offend those who think 
 differently, but we can get it done again. My hard working tax money 
 should not support those who are not legal.
 
12.14.11

Hey Henry, after reading the story 
 about the musical Christmas tree house on East Mays Rd. I went by 
 there this past weekend. It was marvelous and definitely got our 
 carload into the Christmas spirit. I am going back again this 
 weekend!

Hey Henry, we appreciate the lines that were painted on Sandy Ridge 
 Road. But, wouldnt it have made more sense to pave it first.

Hey Henry, I saw a stationery store move.

Hey Henry, to the person who passes through the Square and thinks it 
 is empty, you are really missing out. Four of the best restaurants 
 (Seasons, Chevy&apos;s, Pasta Max, and PJ&apos;s) in the county are all 
 located on the Square. No&quot;big box&quot;restaurant can touch any of 
 them. It&apos;s not Mayberry as you said, but slow down and enjoy the 
 good life the Square has to offer!

Hey Henry, I appreciate the chance to vent.

Hey Henry, to the posts about Henry County Administrators getting 
 raises....its not true, there are no raises for administrators or 
 anyone else. If you actually read the minutes, you&apos;d see that all 
 they did was officially include the new job title of Executive 
 Officer in the already existing salary schedule. No raises for any 
 positions at all.

Hey Henry, to the person who stole the Christmas wreaths off the 
 store front at Clay Plaza. Did you think you were stealing from the 
 city? No, you stole from a private citizen who put them on the store 
 front trying to make the building look less&quot;abandoned.&quot;

Hey Henry, to the young woman with the dancing hat that was pooper 
 scooping behind the horses in the McDonough Christmas parade; bravo! 
 You made what is a really gross job look like fun. Think we enjoyed 
 watching you have such a good time most of all!


Hey Henry, this is for our local middle school. Assigning a very 
 long movie to watch, and fifty questions is not the way that we 
 would like to spend our Christmas break. A break should be a break, 
 right? We would like to spend our break the same way that your 
 faculty does, with our families and friends. Some of us have family 
 that we only get to see, and spend time with a few times a year. We 
 all need a break. Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays everybody!

Hey Henry, a shout out to McDonalds! The tiny fry container in the 
 revamped Happy Meals costs more than the fries it contains! I 
 ordered a Happy Meal the other night, and there were 10 fries in the 
 teeny-tiny fry box. McDonalds should be a treat - if you&apos;re trying 
 to eat healthy, then you probably won&apos;t be going to McDonalds to 
 begin with. I know I don&apos;t go to McDonalds for apple slices.

Hey Henry, please educate yourselves before complaining! SPLOST 
 funds are used solely for capital improvements - new schools, 
 replacements and upgrades to current schools, and technology. SPLOST 
 does not fund salaries of school system employees, nor were 
 administrators given raises. Again, educate yourself! School 
 activities and actions are public record, and as such are available 
 for anyone to review at any time.

Hey Henry, why is Tara Field being called Atlanta Southern Regional 
 Airport? It&apos;s in Henry County, Hampton, why not call it Henry 
 Regional? We are not in Atlanta. Same with Atlanta Motor Speedway.
 
12.07.11

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t understand why 
 there is someone at the Heritage Park museum from 9 to 3 Monday 
 through Friday, but our libraries are closed Friday and Saturday. 
 Friday afternoon and Saturday are the times when working moms can 
 take their kids to the library so they can work on school projects 
 to read. I was a member of the county public gym and now it has 
 limited hours. I would like to know how many people visit that 
 museum in a week compared to visitors to the public library on 
 Fridays. Even if the museum has volunteers, could we not do that to 
 keep our libraries open. Is this how our tax dollars are at work?

Hey Henry,&quot;Leeway in interpreting&quot;is another way of saying we&apos;re 
 going to continue cheating others and acting in our own best 
 interests just like the developer, builders, real estate agents, and 
 HOA management companies did.

Hey Henry, this section needs to be longer!

Hey Henry, if I were an employer I would never hire a smoker. All 
 they have on their mind is the next cigarette.

Hey Henry, I agree with the person who says they would Think Local 
 if the prices were competitive. There is nothing on the Square in 
 McDonough which I need. Most of the stores are empty and the few 
 that are in business, are way overpriced. I pass through the Square 
 on my way to Henry Town Center, or head south to Macon to the 
 Shoppes at River Crossing. Local, homegrown businesses are a thing 
 of the past. This isn&apos;t Mayberry!

Hey Henry, this Henry County cop wishes we did have Sunday sales. 
 That&apos;s when I tend to do my velvet shopping. On the rare occasion 
 when I think some beer might be nice, it&apos;s silly to prohibit the 
 sale. The people who are likely to cause a problem either buy a case 
 to tide them over or go to a bootlegger.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s funny how after SPLOST was passed, Henry County 
 Schools are giving raises to all Administrators and wasting money 
 leasing a warehouse.

Hey Henry, there has been a lot of dirty talk about&quot;rednecks&quot;in 
 the paper recently. Just because you have a four wheel drive, hunt, 
 or chew tobacco, does not make you a redneck. I would take that as 
 offensive. Dont make fun of someone because they have a country 
 accent, they cant help it.

Hey Henry, just a reminder that calling an ambulance should be 
 reserved for&quot;emergencies&quot;only! Not for a runny nose, stubbed toe, 
 toothache, or other minor injury or illness. These are advanced life 
 support trucks that are being used to transport non-emergency 
 patients to hospitals all over Atlanta when people who really need 
 them have to wait! Call a cab, a private ambulance service, a 
 friend, or family member to take you to the hospital if you have a 
 minor problem. Thank you, from a frustrated firefighter!

Hey Henry, did you know that our tax dollars are used to pay inmate 
 work crews from other counties like Spalding. Your tax dollars at 
 work.

Hey Henry, why do I constantly see Henry County police driving so 
 aggressively while patrolling and unnecessarily wasting fuel. Other 
 cities like Griffin are struggling to purchase gas in this economy. 
 They are having to make their officers walk a beat. Maybe we should 
 give them some of our gas since we have plenty to waste.
 
11.30.11

Hey Henry, I want to thank the very 
 nice guy at &apos;QuickTrip&apos; last week who gave me an extra $5 so I could 
 get more gas than my $20 would buy. That was so nice. I hope that 
 you did win some money on the lotto ticket that you got. I will 
 never forget your kindness. I wish that others would do something as 
 nice as you did for me. Thanks again, Melissa. (The lady who had to 
 count all the loose change!)

Hey Henry, I shot my first turkey the day before Thanksgiving! Sorry 
 to the folks in the Kroger frozen foods section if I startled you.

Hey Henry, in response to the person wanting&quot;No Thru Traffic&quot;in 
 McDonough. What does&quot;No Thru Traffic&quot;really mean? Correct me if I 
 am wrong, but these are public roads! If I choose to utilize that 
 road as part of my route, how can you stop me?

Hey Henry, to the person who thinks it&apos;s&quot;no big deal&quot;about Sunday 
 alcohol sales, why dont you ask some local law enforcement officers 
 how they feel about it? Or maybe some of the long time, original 
 Henry County residents? You may find that they, like I, wish that 
 there were no Sunday sales! However, this is just one more reason to 
 prove that our country is going to you-know-where in a handbasket 
 and the ones who care seem to be&quot;outnumbered&quot;by the ones who 
 don&apos;t!

Hey Henry, I made my first visit to Heritage Park last month, and 
 was greatly surprised at how nice and clean it was. The Memorial 
 Wall was very informative and displayed in a very reverent manner. I 
 never knew Henry County had anything so nice. Everyone needs to go 
 out there and see it at least once.

Hey Henry, young people, don&apos;t get in any hurry to get your college 
 education, because I just spent $40K at college. I got my degree 
 with honors and cannot find a job because a lot of companies wont 
 hire unless you have experience. I don&apos;t understand this. In the 
 past, having a degree was all that mattered. Now experience is all 
 they care about. It&apos;s a no-win situation. I believe companies call 
 people and interview people just to make themselves look good. They 
 already know who they are going to hire, believe me. They just do 
 this to cover their own butts. If you are a family member or friend, 
 you wont have a problem.

Hey Henry, I just watched the Henry County Commissioners meeting on 
 the local cable station and was appalled that the County Probate 
 Judge requested retroactive pay for her duties in dealing with Vital 
 Records and Passports. The total of the retroactive pay was over 
 $90,000. I can&apos;t believe that she would request this when the County 
 is in such dire financial shape and many county employees are losing 
 their jobs. I am afraid the Probate Judge just sealed her fate for 
 the next election.

Hey Henry, is there some way to make those&quot;Give gap-Take gap&quot;signs 
 more visible on the McDonough Square? Right now, it&apos;s just a 
 bumper-car free-for-all.

Hey Henry, FYI... It is not true that the faster you go the greater 
 chance of hydroplaning in standing water. The speed at which a car 
 hydroplanes is equal to 8.6 times the square root of the tire 
 pressure....which for most cars is between 45-50 mph.

Hey Henry, in the parking lot at the Walmart on Hwy. 138 a lot of 
 panhandlers are asking for gas to get them to the hospital to see a 
 sick loved one...etc. Isn&apos;t there something that can be done about 
 this?
 
11.23.11

Hey Henry, thank you... for all the 
 news you have and all the problems people are having to write you 
 about. It makes my day out here in Garland, Texas to know what is 
 going on in McDonough and Henry County. I miss not being out there 
 to see Henry County like it has grown in the past 47 years that I 
 have been away.

Hey Henry, about the parking meters, the City could wrap the meters 
 but then the people from the courthouse will park there all day 
 long. What will the merchants do then?

Hey Henry, I would THINK LOCAL for shopping if you could&quot;THINK 
 COMPETITIVE&quot;in your pricing. I don&apos;t have extra money to blow 
 supporting over-priced local business.

Hey Henry, lets all try for more positive attitudes!

Hey Henry, did the principals really just get a raise?

Hey Henry, what would you say if I said you could access questions 
 to ask your child about Math, Science, English, and Social Studies 
 for this week in school, and what would you say if I told you, that 
 these questions are written as conversation starters, requiring your 
 child to discuss with you, what they are learning? Ed note. Id say, 
 Where can I find them?

Hey Henry, sometimes people have to accept a wage that they don&apos;t 
 like because there are no other jobs.

Hey Henry, if the minimum wage rates aren&apos;t cutting it for you then 
 you need to learn a new trade to make better wages. Do not depend on 
 the government to take care of you! The rich are getting richer 
 because they strive for better and work hard.

Hey Henry, what&apos;s the logic of building a multi-million dollar 
 bridge for 10+ lanes of traffic on Hudson Bridge Rd. over I- 75 and 
 leaving room for only 6 lanes on I-75 under the bridge?

Hey Henry, to the Nissan owner with electrical problems. I am sure 
 your car has a huge (MISS) then just quits while driving. Change 
 your fuel pump/filter first. Then, you can check the CAM 
 sensor/crank shaft sensor and distributor. I just went thru this as 
 well. Nissans are notorious for this problem.

Hey Henry, I wish someone would look at adjusting the traffic lights 
 in Stockbridge. Every morning on the way to work, traffic has to 
 wait on North Henry for the light at Flippen Rd to cycle. Turn 
 arrows on with no turning traffic.

Hey Henry, who cares that alcohol can be sold on Sundays now, this 
 isn&apos;t the bible belt anymore. Deal with it, it&apos;s another day where 
 you don&apos;t have to drive to a bar and drink there.

Hey Henry, since the November 8 election, the sun shines brighter 
 and the birds are still here, singing again in Hampton - the Bird 
 Sanctuary. The nest needs further cleaning in the next election, if 
 not sooner.

Hey Henry, I was amused by the person in the gold car last week who 
 said he/she was driving at seventy in the rain, although being 
 careful. Usually driving that fast in the rain is not careful, it is 
 dangerous, and one of the reasons so many accidents happen. I don&apos;t 
 know if an accident happened to gold car, but watching the truck 
 behind it could distract a driver going seventy in the rain. Sorry 
 Gold Car, slow down in the rain. It is easy to hydroplane on a wet 
 street, and seventy is just too fast under those conditions.
 
11.16.11

Hey Henry, courage doesn&apos;t always 
 roar. Sometimes courage is the little voice at the end of the day 
 that says I&apos;ll try again tomorrow.

Hey Henry, for anyone driving an older (1999) Nissan Maxima... can 
 you recommend a local mechanic who can handle a possible electrical 
 problem? Thanks!

Hey Henry, the Mt. Carmel Dog Park is meant for friendly dogs that 
 know how to play well with others. If you have trained your dog to 
 be aggressive and attack other dogs, please do not take them to this 
 park.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s not a company&apos;s responsibility to ensure that their 
 workers make a living wage. They&apos;re responsible for paying you a 
 wage that you accepted.

Hey Henry, to the person who walked off with my 40 dollars cash 
 back from the self-serve checkout at the Kroger on McDonough Rd. 
 this Saturday, with more on my mind than you care to know, I 
 inadvertently walked off without it. I hope you were able to feed 
 your hungry children with it.

Hey Henry, I really wish the Henry County Police Department would 
 sit outside of Luella High School when the students dismiss. The 
 kids drive like maniacs and so do a lot of the parents. I am tired 
 of nearly getting hit everytime I have to go to that school.

Hey Henry, I am the person in the gold car. I was doing 70 and it 
 was raining. I was using caution and the truck was driving 
 wrecklessly, so close to my bumper I could hardly see the lights. 
 They could have gone around but they cut between me and the car 
 behind me. You were either a witness who did not come forward or the 
 person in the truck. I hope HCPD follows up on your post.

Hey Henry, good for Hampton! The people have spoken and now have 
 council members who share our culture and values. Wonder who will be 
 the next to go?

Hey Henry, how come none of my vents ever make the paper?

Hey Henry, it is disgusting to see people willingly vote themselves 
 a tax increase in times like this. I guess the school system needs 
 to build another palatial academy for the children. We are sheep 
 and suckers and deserve exactly what we are getting. Have a little 
 common sense people.

Hey Henry, Rock Quarry Road is closed at the railroad tracks!
How hard is it to comprehend a road closed sign? Not to mention no 
 outlet and dead end? Put your phones down and pay attention to 
 what is going on around you. And don&apos;t be mad at the truckdrivers 
 when we shake our heads at you, we know where we are going. Don&apos;t 
 you wish you could say the same?

Hey Henry, I would like to challenge our local citizens to THINK 
 LOCAL as you do your Christmas shopping! I also would like to 
 challenge City Hall to wrap those parking meters during our holiday 
 season so shoppers can shop without stopping to feed the meters!

Hey Henry, City of McDonough Mayor and Council please fill the City 
 Administrator position with a native of Henry County. The citizens 
 are tired of the out-of-county hires because they could care less 
 about our County or our City.
 
11.09.11

Hey Henry, it&apos;s ridiculous that 
 companies really believe people can make it off of an $8 to $10 per 
 hour salary. This seems to be the going pay for most jobs in this 
 economy when everything is going up, from groceries, to health 
 insurance. The only jobs our government is producing are low paying 
 jobs with no hope of the American dream. The rich get richer and the 
 poor get poorer.

Hey Henry, I would like to know why, we the people of Henry, dont 
 have the privilege of voting to see if we wanted to have (Sunday) 
 alcohol sales in this county? I know we have intelligent people 
 here, so why cant we decide?

Hey Henry, your police department is being destroyed. Police 
 officers are forced to do less every day to stay out of trouble. 
 Without aggressive police, crime will go up and property values will 
 go down. It is time to fix the problem and save the good officers 
 that still work there. 42 have quit.

Hey Henry, I want to say a big&quot;Thank You&quot;to the City of Hampton 
 and the merchants of Main St. and Booth&apos;s Crossing for the Trick or 
 Treat event Monday. My 4-year old and her cousins had a great time. 
 I was happy to have a safe place for my daughter to enjoy the 
 tradition.

Hey Henry, regarding the British taking over our airwaves, maybe 
 it&apos;s because we Americans have lost the proper way of speaking 
 English. It&apos;s nice to hear people on the airwaves speaking good 
 English and not some slang of some sort. It&apos;s refreshing for a 
 change and shows some intelligence.

Hey Henry, to the person in the gold convertible Sebring that got 
 run off the road on I-75. If you CANT go faster than 65 in the fast 
 lane then get out of the way!

Hey Henry, where&apos;s your spell check?

Hey Henry, as an employee of a local school system, I am required to 
 report when children are in danger. I need to file a report. I watch 
 as our precious children are put in danger each day when they must 
 cross over Hwy. 20 at East Lake Road under such precarious 
 conditions. I watch as elementary children on buses, middle school 
 children with their parents and high school children in their own 
 vehicles must cross over an intersection that desperately needs a 
 light. Hey Henry Commissioners - MAKE THIS HAPPEN!

Hey Henry, all of you who park on the curb at the Superior 
 Courthouse in the Square make it very difficult for people with 
 larger cars and SUVs to pull out of their parking spots for fear of 
 hitting your car. There are parking spots to park in, so why can&apos;t 
 you just park there and leave the curb open?

Hey Henry, I know 99.99% of you are law abiding and hunt in a 
 conscientious manner. But to the irresponsible fool who killed a 
 deer on private property and then dumped the carcass on the side of 
 my road: You shouldn&apos;t even be allowed to own a gun. And I would 
 guess you don&apos;t have a hunting license, either.

Hey Henry, there&apos;s going to be 50 more employees laid off at Henry 
 County, but they approved $200,000 for highway landscaping at exit 
 218. So how&apos;s that airport purchase helping keep jobs?

Hey Henry, Did it occur to any of the geniuses who planned the 
 zoning/construction on Eagle&apos;s Landing Pkwy. how an ambulance would 
 get to Henry Medical with Rock Quarry Rd. also closed for over a 
 year. Where are your brains?
 
11.02.11

Hey Henry, Rock Quarry Road at the 
 railroad crossing is closed and will be closed until December 2012. 
 Traffic is being detoured onto Flippen Road to Banks Road.

Hey Henry, what happened to the&quot;cool&quot;in school?

Hey Henry, is there anything the City Of McDonough can do about the 
 racetrack and traffic on Sloan Street and Bryan Street? Both are too 
 narrow for the speeds people insist on traveling. Both should be 
 posted with No Thru Traffic - No Trucks!

Hey Henry, if a word were misspelled in the dictionary, how would we 
 ever know?

Hey Henry, would like to give a BIG shoot-out to the 8U Longhorns 
 and awesome coaches for finishing the season undefeated! Way to go 
 boys!

Hey Henry, where was the train depot located in McDonough?

Hey Henry, I think all the storefronts around the Square should be 
 painted in cheerful colors like the yellow one. It might attract 
 more business; the Square looks boring as it is.

Hey Henry, the color of the new party store on the Square is tacky! 
 Our town square is a reflection of our warm southern charm. Now we 
 have Bozo the Clown sticking out like a neon light. Isn&apos;t there an 
 ordinance to keep the theme of the Square similar? If not I vote to 
 make one ASAP!

Hey Henry, somebody needs to remind the commissioners (especially 
 District 2) that when you say you are getting something&quot;free&quot;for 
 the taxpayers of Henry County because you are paying with federal 
 money, the feds got it by taxing us. Nothing is free, certainly not 
 the $15 million in federal money that went to buy Tara Field, and 
 not the previously-approved operating budget. The voters aren&apos;t 
 nearly as stupid as you assume.

Hey Henry, thank you to the Locust Grove City Council for 
 re-instating Chief Jesse Patton!

Hey Henry, I would like to compliment the kids who were helping out 
 at Noah&apos;s Ark a couple of weekends ago. When I asked whom these 
 extremely well behaved and clean-cut kids were, I was told that they 
 were the ROTC group from Henry County High School. Parents of those 
 children should be very proud of how they look and how they acted.

Hey Henry, why do Hampton residents have to pay the city to pick up 
 trash on the side of the road? It should be included in with the 
 high electric bill.

Hey Henry, I always read all the negative comments from everyone 
 complaining about Henry County. Well I don&apos;t have a complaint; I 
 want to say THANK YOU TO THE CITY OF MCDONOUGH POLICE! I feel safe 
 knowing that I have them watching over me! Mayor Copeland, I know 
 you are pushing for our safety as well. A HUGE THANK YOU TO YOU AND 
 THE MCDONOUGH POLICE FORCE!

Hey Henry, can we PLEASE have the huge bump on the new bridge at 
 Eagle&apos;s Landing smoothed out? I hit it so hard it knocked my car out 
 of gear.

Hey Henry, Ron White had it right. You can&apos;t fix stupid!
 
10.26.11

Hey Henry, I know what happened to the pal in principal: He was my 
 boss, Ted Strickland (passing March 2010). Many of his students 
 would share their fond memories and often used the quote he put the 
 pal in principal. Every day we miss him. Terry Kight, City of 
 Stockbridge.

Hey Henry, bravo to McDonough Arts on their cemetery tour last 
 Saturday! It was well organized and one of the very best events that 
 I have been to in Henry County.

Hey Henry, there was a power outage at Macy&apos;s yesterday. Twenty 
 Atlanta&quot;occupiers&quot;were trapped on the escalators.

Hey Henry, if the citizens of Henry County are lucky, maybe we will 
 be able to have a SPLOST citizens oversight committee like Dekalb, 
 if we really matter.

Hey Henry, we used to have so much fun this time of year with Horror 
 on Heritage Hill. Now the county is too afraid to use its own 
 facilities. I think Henry County Government has consumed too many 
 slices of Stanley Pye.

Hey Henry, FYI: Halloween is on Halloween in my neighborhood. If you 
 come on any other day, you will not receive candy. We do not change 
 the day. It is one night a year folks, you can deal with having your 
 doorbell rung on a school night and work week. People can&apos;t afford 
 to give out candy two and three nights for Halloween.

Hey Henry, we would like a Chick-fil-A and a Tractor Supply Co. in 
 Luella. Sincerely, Occupy Luella.

Hey Henry, has nobody noticed the British are taking over our media. 
 I thought our ancestors came over here to get away from that bunch.

Hey Henry, remember those pretty pumpkins decorating the outside of 
 Bell, Book&amp;Candle up until this past Wednesday? Would the 
 person(s) responsible for&quot;borrowing&quot;every single pumpkin please 
 return them?

Hey Henry, thanks to the Best Buy Geek Squad for your instant 
 diagnosis of my laptop problems, and then checking on-line through 
 your Rewards program to find the faulty part was still under 
 warranty. What a crew!

Hey Henry, if you are thinking about burning leaves, now that it&apos;s 
 fall, it would be a good idea to call and get a burning permit, even 
 for a small burn. I speak from experience...

Hey Henry, is there is anyone out there who saw the maroon 2 door 
 pick up deliberately run me, in my gold convertible Sebring, off the 
 road onto the median. I was in the fast lane on I-75 S, near the 155 
 exit at 5 p.m. Tuesday 10/18/11. If you have any info or got a tag 
 or part of the tag number, please call the Henry County Police Dept. 
 This person has bad road rage and is a danger to everyone. Thank you 
 to the yellow car that let me get back on the highway.

Hey Henry, to the person complaining about administrators and 
 teachers being rude to you. First, I am a teacher and do NOT get a 
 big paycheck and second, please don&apos;t put all teachers and 
 administrators in the same boat. Instead try to confront the person 
 or people who are being rude to you.

Hey Henry, to the person who said go to the higher up people, they 
 are the problem because they don&apos;t get anything done. They are too 
 busy sucking down their coffee in their offices and talking for 
 hours about how their weekend went.
 
10.19.11

Hey Henry, residents on Moseley Road in Stockbridge should observe 
 the leash laws or keep their dogs at home. It is unfair to those of 
 us who live on Moseley Road who do observe the laws.

Hey Henry, someone needs to do an expos on HOA management firms and 
 their self-serving ways.

Hey Henry, does anyone remember when Charles Hancock was Chief of 
 Police in Hampton? I thought it was in the late 1990s or early 
 2000&apos;s.

Hey Henry, this sure is a beautiful county! I wish it were safer for 
 the elderly people that live alone.

Hey Henry, to the person complaining about the McDonough Police 
 parking in the church parking lot and running radar. If you&apos;re 
 complaining you must have been stopped. If you obey the traffic laws 
 you won&apos;t be stopped. Thanks to the police for being out there.

Hey Henry, if the county wants to generate more revenue, why not 
 have the police enforce the handicap parking spots. I see people 
 everyday park in them with and without handicap stickers and there 
 is nothing handicapped about them, they are just sorry and lazy. 
 They just take up the space and the people that need them have to 
 park far away.

Hey Henry, what happened to the&quot;pal&quot;in principal?

Hey Henry, I wish the parents would push for the Board of Education 
 to put more effort in catching and putting the parents of all the 
 kids who are out of county or going to schools out of district in 
 jail. When they catch them they just send them back to their home 
 school. What about punishment to really teach them a lesson?

Hey Henry, I noticed that The Times had recipes for pork chops and 
 ribeyes. I am glad to see that some folks can still eat high on the 
 hog! This week I roasted a whole chicken that was 69 cents a pound, 
 and my daughter asked me why it looked so funny; it didn&apos;t look like 
 the usual chicken. I guess she is used to eating the 99 cent a pound 
 breast. She also told me that my dirty rice with the giblets was 
 weird.

Hey Henry, the GDOT awarded Henry County $435,600 and Henry County 
 matched with $108,900 for a 12-foot-wide paved trail at Nash Farm. I 
 wonder how the people who travel East Lake Road each day feel. The 
 road is nothing but patches and the intersection of East Lake Road 
 and Highway 20 is one of, if not the most dangerous in Henry County. 
 Do the people in this area not have a representative on the Henry 
 County Board of Commissioners?

Hey Henry, to the HCPD officer whom I encountered Sunday 10/09/11 on 
 Miller&apos;s Mill near Hwy 138, you berated me like I was a stupid 
 child. I thought you were on a pullover and that is why I attempted 
 to pull around you. I haven&apos;t had a ticket in 30 years nor have I 
 been arrested. Not everyone you encounter is a criminal!

Hey Henry, if you&apos;re on a side road and would like to turn on a main 
 road, don&apos;t assume someone turning onto your side road is going to 
 let you go. You are going to end up seriously injuring someone 
 because of your impatience!

Hey Henry, if you are the parent of a school bus rider, you might 
 want to teach them what respect and manners are.
 
10.12.11

Hey Henry, thanks so much to the readers for sharing the pictures of 
 the majestic sunset on September 21. We live in an incredible 
 community and I truly appreciate your kindness! Thanks to the 
 Editor, too!

Hey Henry, wanted to thank the SUMC for giving a 23 yr. old female a 
 chance to play some pick-up soccer! Before, there was no place for 
 me! Thanks!

Hey Henry, hyphenating your last name does not make you any more 
 important!

Hey, Henry, let&apos;s try something a little different and all come 
 together instead of tearing each other apart. There is a radio 
 station trying to send a personal thank you letter to ALL MEN AND 
 WOMEN who will be away from home on Thanksgiving. Let&apos;s show them 
 that Henry County has a heart. It must be a handwritten letter, no 
 political views, and can be mailed to them, or turned in at a local 
 Taco Mac. Go to www.thebertshow.com and click the link for Bert&apos;s 
 Big Thank You.

Hey Henry, Atlanta HOT LANES! They will be coming this way sooner 
 than later. Call Gov. Deal and let him know, we don&apos;t need Hot Lanes 
 on I-75.

Hey Henry, a big&quot;Thank You&quot;to Gerri Yoder, Henry County&apos;s Director 
 of Animal Control for all of the good work that she and her staff 
 do. Gerri is a hard worker and really cares for all the animals. 
 She&apos;s a&quot;keeper&quot;in Henry County Government.

Hey Henry, as I am reading these&quot;Hey Henry&apos;s&quot;it looks like all 
 anyone is doing is complaining. Well personally I love Henry County.

Hey Henry, I would like to send out a huge Thank You to the Henry 
 Co. Police Dept. They are sworn to protect and serve and they did 
 just that last Friday when my home alarm went off. They got to my 
 house before me, secured the inside and out, and truly made me feel 
 safe and proud to be a citizen of Henry County. In this day and 
 time, we put sports figures on a pedestal, but let&apos;s pay tribute to 
 the real heroes, our police and firefighters!

Hey Henry, how about having DOT repaint the lines on Clark Rd. in 
 extreme North Henry. It would be nice to be able to stay on the road 
 on a rainy night.

Hey Henry, it is great to see such a wonderful outreach program for 
 kids at the SUMC soccer organization in Stockbridge. 700+ kids every 
 weekend in a family environment having fun! Great job to those who 
 organize it all.

Hey Henry, almost time for burning leaves, I love that smell.

Hey Henry, Al Sharpton, Jessie Jackson, and now Herman Cain are 
 playing the race card against Rick Perry. Never thought I would see 
 this from Herman.

Hey Henry, you should think about all the deer that will be 
 harvested for the homeless by the hunters who have a heart and stop 
 crying about a little noise from the gunshots. But if you would like 
 to go buy about a thousand dollars worth of meat and donate it 
 yourself, go right ahead, I am sure the homeless will accept it and 
 I am sure you will be in the car driving to Krogers right after you 
 read this. Elmer Fudd that.
 
10.05.11

Hey Henry, teachers and adminstators this message is for you: Do you 
 realize how little money the people under you, the secretaries, 
 clerks, cafeteria workers, lunch staff and custodians, make? You 
 make about 10X more than we do. You do have the degree and deserve 
 it, but you count on us to make you look good. How about being a 
 little nicer to us and showing us some respect .... your degree and 
 big pay check doesn&apos;t do it alone. Without your secretaries you 
 would fall apart!

Hey Henry, I love that my child is growing up with so many friends 
 of many different races. I love that I am friends with the parents 
 of these kids and we socialize together outside of work etc. I hate 
 that so many people still are racists, because they are missing out 
 on making many wonderful friends!

Hey Henry, you people who go to Hardee&apos;s please move out of the way 
 when you are fixing you coffee inside the restaurant. It is simple, 
 go to the coffee supplies, get your supplies, and move out of the 
 way and fix your coffee somewhere else in the restaurant so people 
 getting soft drinks can get to the straws and lids.

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t think it&apos;s right for the police to sit in the 
 church parking lot on Griffin Street and use radar to catch 
 speeders. Churches are private property and this is wrong.

Hey Henry, I have to say I don&apos;t like the yellow building on the 
 Square but what I find even more offensive is the gigantic TV screen 
 with glaring colors. It is not in keeping with the Historic 
 District.

Hey Henry, I am so thankful that the commissioners are putting in 
 walking trails at Nash Farms and Panola Park. This is after they 
 just bought an airport, laid off 57 county employees, did not fill 
 30 open county positions, gave out 72 early retirements to county 
 employees, handed out 4 furlough days a year to existing county 
 employees, and cut the library budget to the bare bones. Now there 
 will be something free for us to do with our free time.

Hey Henry, beware of the thieves at Alexander Park. A crook broke 
 into 6 or more cars Monday night and stole purses and other valuable 
 things. The police were called and I heard a suspect was picked up 
 the next day with one of the purses in his hand. Thanks to the 
 observant policeman who arrested him.

Hey Henry, to the Henry County Police officer who came to Mt. Carmel 
 this weekend to watch their childs soccer game and parked their 
 police car beside a fire hydrant and left it running for an hour. 
 Please do the taxpayers a favor and turn off your car when you will 
 be out of it for an extended period of time. Everyone should be 
 looking for ways to save money for ourselves, our employers and the 
 government.

Hey Henry, everyone is commenting on the yellow building on the 
 Square. No one has noticed that they have a different sign than all 
 of the other merchants. No one else has ever been allowed to have a 
 lighted sign. There are businesses that have moved to the Square and 
 weren&apos;t allowed to use their previous signs.

Hey Henry, from someone who knows, if you have a problem with an 
 employee at a county office or public building, please go to 
 higher-ups and complain. We need to get rid of some of these people, 
 and complaining to fellow employees won&apos;t get the job done. Thank 
 you.
 
09.28.11

Hey Henry, with all the talk about the yellow building, I would 
 think someone would point out the negative impact the unkept 
 buildings on the Square have on city image. Clay Plaza is crumbling 
 to the ground, the Chafin Building is coming apart, and the doll 
 store looks dirty and in need of paint and repair.

Hey Henry, why do so many schools use disposable styrofoam trays 
 instead of washing the plastic ones? It seems so wasteful of money 
 and landfill space.

Hey Henry! it&apos;s Albert Roberts, (CPT Army National Guard) giving a 
 shout out from GITMO, Cuba! I miss you all! Make it a great day! 
 ...and God bless America!

Hey Henry, it&apos;s downright ridiculous when the taxpayers have to keep 
 up a prisoner for 22 years and they can&apos;t decide whether or not to 
 execute him. Have they not had long enough to decide this? I guess 
 it&apos;s alright to murder someone because it seems like anyone can get 
 away with it and have 3 meals a day and cable television. What a 
 country!

Hey Henry, the more you complain the longer God lets you live!

Hey Henry, I was shocked when I took my friend to Eagle&apos;s Landing 
 Medical on Hwy 81. We filled out the paper work, waited and he could 
 not be seen because he had no insurance, and we were going to pay.

Hey Henry, who is responsible for taking care of the dirt road, Mt. 
 Olive, connecting Jodeco Rd. to Jonesboro Rd. by the mall? Our van&apos;s 
 tires have had it!

Hey Henry, so Billy Beckett is staying on for a few more months, If 
 you had a position paying approximately $140,000 a year, you can bet 
 your sweet bippy you would stay as long as possible. This city 
 government is out of control people, open your eyes and your mouths, 
 its your tax money supporting these high paying jobs! No matter how 
 they spin it, believe me there is no justification to the salaries 
 of many of the city employees. They have set up a legal Mafia for 
 themselves with no regard to the public.

Hey Henry, did anyone happen to get a picture of the majestic sunset 
 on Wednesday, Sept. 21? It was the evening that a great friend and 
 neighbor passed away. If so, maybe you could send it to the editor.

Hey Henry, if the government legalized all illegal drugs and taxed 
 them really high and set up stores where you could purchase them, 
 then this country would more than likely get out of debt. They could 
 also use the tax money from the sale of drugs to pay those on 
 welfare. Then Social Security would not lose any money and would be 
 there for when we all got old. After time those that are excited to 
 finally purchase these once illegal drugs would lose the allure and 
 eventually get off of them. It&apos;s a win win situation. There will 
 always be addicts so the tax money will always be there, but they 
 could also set up clinics with this money. Just a thought.

Hey Henry, congratulations to the Union Grove JV Fastpitch Softball 
 team for going undefeated this year! Way to go ladies and great job 
 Coaches Johnson and Steel!

Hey Henry, I personally love the yellow building with the cheerful 
 black-and-white awning on the Square. The Square is too drab and has 
 been for a long time. Liven it up!
 
09.21.11

Hey Henry, we drove all the way to 
 the McDonough Square today to see the YELLOW building. Please tell 
 me that it will not stay that way!

Hey Henry, to the person complaining about the yellow building on 
 the Square, go back to the September 7 and 14 issues of the Times to 
 the picture of the Square in the early 1900s. There was a yellow 
 building then. The yellow building now is historic.

Hey Henry, to the person talking about Marta bringing the criminal 
 element in. I rode Marta for 3 years, never saw anyone with a stolen 
 TV on their lap. It&apos;s all about thinking blacks are all crooks. I am 
 a white man (61) that just lost his beautiful black lady (53) last 
 year. Get over it, you redneck! It&apos;s 2011.

Hey Henry, I hate to tell you this but the criminal element has been 
 here in Henry County for a long time already. In fact, they may be 
 sitting near you in church on Sunday.

Hey Henry, this is a big Thank You to Locust Grove city employees. 
 Im a new resident after 40 years in Hampton (whose employees are 
 phenomenal) and Im happy to say that the Locust Grove people are 
 just as friendly and helpful about any inquiry.

Hey Henry is for&quot;quips,&quot;not hurtful, bullying name calling. For 
 many weeks now I&apos;ve read comments that say&quot;go back to where you 
 came from,&quot;and generalizing people as&quot;rednecks&quot;when referencing 
 something or someone you don&apos;t like. I see nasty criticism of our 
 Commissioners, but also see a lot of empty seats at the meetings. I 
 don&apos;t agree with everyone and everything, but I do believe in saying 
 my side or venting my complaints with supporting facts or at least a 
 suggestion to make it better. (Ed. note - Well said!)

Hey Henry, thanks to McDonough citizen Beau Kelley for creating a 
 crime watch page for the community on Facebook. My building was 
 vandalized last week, and I am glad that someone is making an effort 
 to bring awareness and educate our community on some of the recent 
 crime activity. McDonough Crime Watch can be accessed on the web at www.McDCrimeWatch.com .

Hey Henry, to the person who burglarized our house, I want to say 
 that God loves you and I hope that you find the forgiveness He 
 offers to us all through His Son, Jesus.

Hey Henry, the railroad crossing on Rock Quary Rd. is beating up my 
 car, can&apos;t even crawl over the tracks without being tossed about. If 
 we really can&apos;t afford to fix it because of the new bridge going in, 
 then set up a toll box. I&apos;d be glad to contribute every time I 
 cross. You wouldn&apos;t have to stop to drop your money in because you 
 are already going so slow you couldn&apos;t miss it.

Hey Henry, thanks to everyone in the community who helped support 
 the Caring for Ken Fundraiser event last Saturday in Locust Grove.

Hey Henry, the City of Locust Grove 9/11 Remembrance Ceremony at 
 City Hall was GREAT. All of you did a great job. A big Thank You to 
 the firefighters, police, sheriffs department and the people who 
 showed up. I will be there next year to remember all those who have 
 lost their lives.

Hey Henry, SPLOST is not specifically for Union Grove Middle School. 
 Call the Henry County BOE for the facts so you can make a very 
 informed decision.
 
09.14.11

Hey Henry, SPLOST is not specifically for Union Grove Middle School. 
 Call the Henry County BOE for the facts so you can make an informed 
 decision.

Hey Henry, have you seen the new YELLOW building in the Square? Did 
 the city approve this? I thought this was the historic district.

Hey Henry, to the person ignorantly criticizing teachers for sending 
 educational work home for completion: my advice to you is that if 
 you are struggling with homework, perhaps you should have spent more 
 time in the formative years educating your child on some of the 
 basics. Teachers send home work for practice or for remediation when 
 needed. Unfortunately, parents who haven&apos;t spent enough time with 
 their own children early on, later expect teachers to&quot;catch them 
 up&quot;and educate them to a level of those children who had the 
 benefit of being raised by parents who were willing to sacrifice the 
 time to work with their children on building an educational 
 foundation.

Hey Henry, to the parent complaining about the homework, I bet the 
 homework is the only time you might spend time with your child. If 
 they don&apos;t have homework you would sit them in front of the TV and 
 ignore them. How about spending time together learning something 
 new! (and no, I am not a teacher and I have kids in the same 
 situation)

Hey Henry, now that Billy Abbate is incarcerated, who is B.J. going 
 to depend upon to guide her to complete the Tara Field project. 
 Those e-mails are very revealing.

Hey Henry, why don&apos;t you send a reporter to sit in the car rider 
 lines at some of the elementary schools (Woodland Elementary) and 
 question some of these parents with out-of -county tags.

Hey Henry, HCBOE needs to do like Fayette County and bill the 
 parents of those caught crossing attendance lines. Enough is enough! 
 They ran their school system in the ground so now they want to ruin 
 ours. The ones who are crossing attendance lines are the least 
 involved parents and late pick ups in the afternoons and tardy for 
 school. Why ruin our AYP?

Hey Henry, if ya can&apos;t handle the South, get the heck out of here!

Hey Henry, buy my house for my cost and I&apos;ll be happy to move.

Hey Henry, when the going gets rough... Go fishin&apos;!

Hey Henry, at least us chewing tobacco, four wheel drive, gun 
 shooting rednecks know that it&apos;s not deer season, darlin&apos;. It&apos;s dove 
 huntin&apos; time.

Hey Henry, Stockbridge...really? Do we not have anything better to 
 worry about than saggy pants? How about the MANY drug deals going on 
 in the Highlands Neighborhood, off of Hwy 42? Maybe we should focus 
 on more important things, ya think?

Hey Henry, re:&quot;I&apos;m all for allowing MARTA into Henry County&quot;. It 
 would bring more of the criminal element into our community. Think 
 about it.
 
09.07.11

Hey Henry, if you don&apos;t like hunting don&apos;t hunt. If you don&apos;t like 
 rednecks then move back where you came from. We don&apos;t need you 
 telling us what to do. The problem with the south is, it is so 
 wonderful everyone else wants to come live here and make it just 
 like where they came from.

Hey Henry, to the Elmer Fudd hater: when Bambi jumps in front of 
 your car, or eats all your marigolds, don&apos;t complain, embrace Mother 
 Nature!

Hey Henry, My husband doesn&apos;t chew tobacco, and he&apos;s certainly not a 
 redneck, but he most certainly will be hunting this year. It puts 
 meat on the table for my family, and in hard economic times, every 
 little thing helps! So please don&apos;t hope he misses! A country boy 
 can survive.

Hey Henry, the City of Locust Grove needs to place some pedestrian 
 crosswalks in the downtown area! Its pretty dangerous walking 
 across 42 at 4 pm!

Hey Henry, re: the complaint against the Superintendent 
 ....obviously you don&apos;t know him well. He visits schools and has 
 lunch with the kids, even takes his wife with him weekly. He is also 
 rarely behind his desk as he is in the community, attending 
 meetings, and running leadership training. Check your facts.

Hey Henry, all you have to do is sit in the car rider lines at 
 schools and you can see all the DeKalb and Clayton car tags. They 
 can&apos;t all be baby sitters or grandparents.

Hey Henry, I&apos;m for allowing MARTA to come into Henry County. It will 
 get some folks off the road who have used it before. They know how 
 it works. The rest of us can drive.

Hey Henry, do we really need a Tractor Supply Store on Hwy 81? What 
 about a grocery store down past Key&apos;s Ferry area?

Hey Henry, what is up with the Henry County school bus drivers? They 
 drive slower than the posted speed limit on major roads, but speed 
 through neighborhoods full of children.

Hey Henry, a great big thanks to Henry County Transportation (Road 
 Maintenance) for the completion of Lawrenceville Street (in 
 McDonough). It&apos;s a pleasure to drive on it now. Good job!

Hey Henry, to those of you that tailgate and try to intimidate 
 others who are doing the legal speed limit around the roads in our 
 county please stop and remember that some of those drivers are teens 
 learning to drive. Back Off! If you&apos;re in such a hurry leave earlier 
 the next time.

Hey Henry, I would let you walk a mile in my shoes, but I am wearing 
 flip flops, and your toes are ugly!

Hey Henry, it would be nice if teachers would start teaching the 
 kids while they are actually in school, and not sending home 
 material the kids have not learned for the parents to try and teach 
 them. It make homework miserable for everyone, and not to mention 
 the kids grades. That is what the teachers are paid to do, and yet 
 they seem to let it fall on the parents. I work 9 hours a day, and 
 hate having to rack my brain on homework I dont know. I am going to 
 start sending the teachers my work to complete if I have to do their 
 job.
 
08.31.11

Hey Henry, well it&apos;s that time of the year again when all the 
 chewing tobacco, four wheel drive, gun shooting rednecks go looking 
 for Bambi because all I heard this Sunday was a bunch of rednecks 
 target practicing with their shot guns. I hope you Elmer Fudd&apos;s miss 
 every deer you go hunting for.

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t have a horse in this race, but I want to comment 
 on last week&apos;s post about Nash Farm not being a battlefield. I 
 expect that the 400 plus who lost their lives there thought it was a 
 battlefield.

Hey Henry, to the person who posted that crime does not follow rail 
 transit lines such as MARTA. You might want to tell the north lines 
 around Lenox Mall. They had three homicides near the stations within 
 the first three months of opening; not to mention there has been a 
 247% increase in theft cases and a 102% rise in assault cases. If 
 you love the public transit so much, move to north Clayton County.

Hey Henry, this is a comment for the individual who claims that 
 Henry County removes students who aren&apos;t in a schools district. How 
 come half of my neighbors go south to carry their kids to school, 
 and I pass them every morning when I have to go north to carry mine 
 to school. Oh well maybe they have a parent who is a teacher, or 
 maybe a bus driver. Maybe it is time for some redistricting.

Hey Henry, to the school bus driver stating no raises - I police for 
 a local city and have not gotten a raise in 5 years. Everyone is 
 doing with less. With higher pensions, insurance and the cost of 
 living I cannot afford to pay more taxes for a raise every year. 
 Sacrifices have to be made!

Hey Henry, why are there over 2,000 students in Luella High School 
 with empty classrooms in Locust Grove. Some classes at Luella have 
 35 to 40 students. I know, I have a child in one of those classes. 
 School Board do your job. Move some students around to help the 
 teachers and students. Board members make too much money to be 
 sitting on their hands. Help stamp out Government Education.

Hey Henry, big thanks to Stockbridge United Methodist Church for the 
 great soccer program they offer the community. From 36 kids to over 
 700 kids, what a wonderful outreach program.

Hey Henry, this is for Mr. Superintendent. We would love to see you 
 visiting the schools in our community, instead of staying hidden 
 away behind a desk at the county office.

Hey Henry, I just wanted to say&quot;Go Luella Lions&quot;7th grade 
 football.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s amazing that people can jump up and down, yell, and 
 scream like a bunch of Indians when it comes to a man running down a 
 football field in a leotard carrying a piece of raw hide, but when 
 it comes to raising your hands in church and shouting, everyone 
 looks at you like youre crazy.

Hey Henry, I read a great suggestion last night. Politicians and 
 elected officials should have to wear jumpsuits, like NASCAR 
 drivers, with patches naming their&quot;sponsors.&quot;

Hey Henry,&quot;SPLOST&quot;the sound fresh cow manure makes when it hits 
 the ground.
 
08.25.11

Hey Henry, if Standard and Poor&apos;s can get investigated why can&apos;t the 
 Henry County Commissioners?

Hey Henry, to the person donating books to the Locust Grove Library 
 - my heartfelt thanks to you. To the man going through the boxes of 
 books before the library is open - shame on you!

Hey Henry, how much longer do the citizens of Henry County have to 
 put up with Commissioner Mathis and all these underhanded shenanigans 
 going on in this county. I think it is time that she be investigated 
 for this whole airport business. She has danced with the devil and 
 has ruined this county.

Hey Henry, why do we keep calling Nash Farm a battlefield, when it 
 has been proven it was not?

Hey Henry, for the person who said the SPLOST will only go to Union 
 Grove Middle School, have you ever thought that the money could go 
 to many more schools in the county? For example, have you ever been 
 to Luella High where they have 35 trailers and overcrowded 
 classrooms? Why don&apos;t you think about other people who have to deal 
 with that everyday instead of only thinking about yourself? And by 
 the way, the county constantly removes students who are not in 
 district. (Just trying to correct your misinformation.)

Hey Henry, have the folks who re-timed the traffic lights on Hwy 138 
 ever actually driven on 138?

Hey Henry, I&apos;ll be glad to take over your job and take the load of 
 crap you say you have to take daily. Sounds to me like you are not 
 very well suited for dealing with the public. You said it, you get 
 what you give!

Hey Henry, I&apos;m all for commuter rail to Henry County. The solution 
 to traffic problems is fewer cars on the highways, not more 
 highways. If I took the current bus to Atlanta, my commute time 
 would be doubled. Saying that crime will follow is just a scare 
 tactic.

Hey Henry, I hear that the McDonough Community Development Director 
 resigned. Maybe she wanted to work closer to home. Perhaps they 
 should hire someone who is more invested in their own community. 
 Maybe pigs will fly.

Hey Henry, thanks to Jim Houston and Bugles Across America and 
 Bethany Baptist Church choir and orchestra for organizing and 
 performing at the&quot;Keep the Spirit of 45 Alive&quot;rally this past 
 week. All the speakers were great, but especially GM1 Clifford 
 Dunnaway. His accounts of the battles he was involved in were 
 awesome.

Hey Henry, when is the county going to start using King&apos;s Mill Road. 
 Did you put the red light for that road at Lake Dow?

Hey Henry, to the person looking for workers. Where are you? I have 
 a brother that has been looking and everyone is saying they are not 
 hiring? Ed. Note: We havent heard from him/her.

Hey Henry, Im also extremely tired of the schools pushing so much 
 homework on children whose parents spend 2-3 hours per evening 
 helping them do it. It makes me wonder what is being done in the 
 schoolroom? I am from Missouri and they at least give grade 
 appropriate homework. I am all for education, but why are we sending 
 our children to government run schools when most of the teaching and 
 money for the supplies and education are being supplied by the 
 parents. Home schooling is looking much better.
 
08.17.11

Hey Henry, don&apos;t forget...you were once a&quot;twenty something.&quot;

Hey Henry, if the county is so strapped for money why do we send 
 four fire department personnel to pick up two fire engines in 
 Louisiana with hotels, airfare, etc. and pay to fly two of them 
 back?

Hey Henry, the School Board has done it again. No raises for bus 
 drivers or monitors. Monitors aren&apos;t even considered real employees.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s nice to see the Chamber and the City of McDonough 
 pushing for Hampton to get the Rapid Rail. Those who live in Hampton 
 support it coming through McDonough.

Hey Henry, who but the developers want this rail system? It didn&apos;t 
 work in Fla. Why do the commissioners think it will work here? It 
 will just bring more crime into area.

Hey Henry, to the person needing workers....I am out spending all my 
 money on gas looking for you. Post your job in the classifieds and I 
 and a 100 others will contact you. Ed. Note: To the individual 
 who, in last week&apos;s column, said he couldn&apos;t find any workers, the 
 Times has received numerous responses from people who are looking 
 for jobs. Contact the Times at 770-957-6314 or editor@henrycountytimes.com and we will give you their names&amp;numbers. 

Hey Henry, I would rather see a guy in a Speedo or a girl in a 
 bikini than nasty underwear that hasn&apos;t seen the inside of a washing 
 machine in weeks.

Hey Henry, why is it that for every white person that leaves 
 Woodland Middle School they are replaced with two black personnel? 
 Do they not want any white people working there or do they just not 
 apply?

Hey Henry, I just wanted to thank Henry Medical Center. I went in 
 the E.R. on 7-27-11 with a broken ankle and was out in less than an 
 hour. Yes, I said less than an hour! Great job guys!

Hey Henry, and if I see your dog left alone in the car again, I will 
 call the police on you again.

Hey Henry, all that was needed at Racetrack and Hwy. 81 was a left 
 turn lane for westbound traffic to turn onto Racetrack. What they&apos;re 
 doing there is major overkill.

Hey Henry, lets limit one computer per person at the Senior Center. 
 Once you get up and walk out the room that means that computer is 
 available not for you to walk back in and say I was on that 
 computer.

Hey Henry, first, I would like to say there are many citizens County 
 employees deal with each day who are super nice. We appreciate you 
 so very much. Now to the flip side of that; yes, the good, the bad 
 and the rude do pay our salary. Being a Henry County resident 
 myself, technically I help pay my salary. I dont know why I havent 
 given myself a raise in 3 years. Things that make you go... hmmmmmm.

Hey Henry, why would we want to support SPLOST? SPLOST is 
 specifically for Union Grove Middle School, so how is it helping 
 those of us who do not go there or have children that go there? It&apos;s 
 not. Also, why would we pay tax dollars to build more classrooms, 
 etc. in a school that is overcrowded and the only reason it is 
 overcrowded is because of children that are crossing the lines to go 
 there? You should have to go to the school you are zoned for!
 
08.10.11

Hey Henry, where are all you people 
 who say you want to work, I can&apos;t find you.

Hey Henry, I find it amazing that the public can be snippy and nasty 
 and rude to city and county employees with alarming regularity but 
 when one of us snaps back, we have to hear&quot;I pay your salary&quot;and 
 that we were rude. You don&apos;t pay us nearly enough to put up with a 
 lot of the crap we take from the public on a daily basis. To get 
 respect, you give respect.

Hey Henry, hurray for Hampton. Hope the other towns/cities will 
 follow with the citations for sagging pants on the ground and 
 rear-ins showing. So sick of it. Jonesboro is another place that 
 should do the same. The extra money could help the county. Thanks 
 Hampton for showing some common sense.

Hey Henry, as if Henry County wasn&apos;t already the laughingstock of 
 the metro area, now Hampton has to add an ordinance against saggy 
 pants. I don&apos;t like seeing underwear any more than anyone else, but 
 guess what? It&apos;s absolutely legal to walk down Main Street in a 
 bikini....or if you&apos;re a guy, a speedo! You can&apos;t legislate common 
 sense.

Hey Henry, the Henry Varner Band did a great job performing at the 
 concert at Stockbridge City Hall Lawn. It&apos;s nice to see some 
 diversity in the entertainment line-up. That band was top notch!

Hey Henry, who voted in these politicians who make these ridiculous 
 rules and unsensible budgets? Oh, we did!

Hey Henry, giving to charities is a wonderful thing. But I don&apos;t 
 like being asked by grocery stores and retail stores when I&apos;m 
 checking out. It puts people on the spot. We all know these stores 
 then turn around, make the donation in their name, and then get a 
 huge tax break off of our dimes.

Hey Henry, why are illegal aliens allowed to stay in this country if 
 they aren&apos;t legally allowed to be here? Why do employers hiring 
 these people feel justified in breaking the law because they claim 
 they can&apos;t find any American workers? If you can&apos;t find Americans to 
 work for you maybe you should pay better. Send these people home. 
 They come here and tap into our Social Security, and welfare 
 systems, and most of them have been here for years and can&apos;t speak 
 English.

Hey Henry, tonight Im going to my HOA meeting. I expect that it&apos;ll 
 waste 2 hours of my evening but I need to know how the&quot;Advisory&quot;Board is going to mess up my neighborhood even more. Sort of like a 
 root canal without anesthetic.

Hey Henry, dogs are such incredible creatures. Please remember to 
 provide them with plenty of cool water and shade during these hot 
 months. They also need love and attention. Don&apos;t neglect them. 
 They&apos;ll give you much love in return.

Hey Henry, I would love to support local small businesses if they 
 were open when its convenient. How about staying open past five 
 o&apos;clock and opening on Sundays?

Hey Henry, can someone explain why it is only white males who can be 
 made fun of, made to look like idiots, or shown as burglars on 
 television commercials?

Hey Henry, 1% of the people make things happen; 9% watch things 
 happen; and 90% ask,&quot;What happened?&quot;
 
08.03.11

Hey Henry, my Mama told me to try to say good things about people 
 (so here goes). Im convinced politicians always try to do whats 
 best----for themselves. Sorry Mama, I tried!

Hey Henry, way to go Hampton for the Saggy Pants law. I think 
 everyone should follow you. I wish someone would take a picture of 
 these kids from behind so they could see what they look like because 
 they have to walk with their legs apart so their pants wont fall 
 off which looks like my 2 year old when he has done an oops in his 
 diaper.

Hey Henry, government entities don&apos;t pay property taxes, so Henry 
 County did not lose any tax revenue by purchasing Tara Field. 
 Instead, Henry County now has the opportunity to grow the aviation 
 industry around the airport, which will in turn increase the 
 property taxes on those properties while also creating high paying 
 aviation jobs in our community. It is a win-win for Henry County, 
 and kudos to the commissioners for having the vision to purchase it. 
 I also appreciate that they have worked out the financing to spread 
 out the $2.7 million over three years.

Hey Henry, congratulations! We now have poorer fire and police 
 protection because the BOC cut the vacancies in the departments 
 rather than filling them, saving money in the process, and spent 
 that money to buy an airport that hasn&apos;t seen a profit since the day 
 it opened more than 20 years ago! Why worry about the federal 
 government shutting down? The county government is going to bankrupt 
 us!

Hey Henry, have you ever noticed that the people who scream the 
 loudest for higher income taxes on the wealthy are those who pay no 
 income taxes at all?

Hey Henry, commenting on the individual who said it seemed everyone 
 was still eating out and&quot;shopping like nothing ever happened&quot;, when 
 you figure out the secret could you tell me? I&apos;m a small business 
 owner here in McDonough and I don&apos;t see anybody shopping like that! 
 What I do see are businesses closing up and empty storefronts 
 everywhere. Come on friends, support your local small business!

Hey Henry, why is the county sinking millions in the far side of the 
 county? Tara Field, Nash Farm, and a non-centrally located soccer 
 complex.

Hey Henry, Hampton ROCKS! Hampton will cite saggy pants. Yippee! I&apos;m 
 so sick of seeing butt cracks and he&apos;s not even fixing my sink!

Hey Henry, I found out why there&apos;s more political answers than 
 straight and direct ones. OH! What a tangled web we weave when we 
 first practice to deceive.

Hey Henry, you know, 25 years ago we had Ronald Reagan, Johnny Cash 
 and Bob Hope, now we have Obama, no cash and no hope, go figure?

Hey Henry, The purchase price of that airport is just the start. 
 What about staff, maintenance, upgrades galore? Just like Nash Farms 
 had many little projects costing an untold amount of money.

Hey Henry, Why is the county making the Fire Department furlough 
 employees only to pay overtime to fill the same positions because 
 there is not enough staffing to run the department?
 
07.27.11

Hey Henry, I agree with the person 
 tired of people crying about the library and flip-flops; but saving 
 a Civil War battlefield and building a shooting range, which we need 
 badly in the County, are not a waste of money.

Hey Henry, I know plenty of 20-somethings who are dependable and 
 have an incredible work ethic. Don&apos;t judge all by a few bad eggs.

Hey Henry, to the person who said the Locust Grove City Hall 
 employees were rude to the public, I agree with you. Maybe its 
 because they havent had a raise in 2 years but thats not a reason 
 to be rude to the public. If you dont like your job, quit. Theres 
 lots of folks out there who will work for half of what you make. 
 People are hurting.

Hey Henry, the Back to School Event at Stockbridge City Hall on 
 07/22/11 was a catastrophe. People pushing and shoving and taking 
 more supplies than needed was absolutely the worst thing I have 
 seen. It is time for people to treat each other with respect and not 
 to be selfish. Remember - our children learn what they live.

Hey Henry, I would like to commend Hampton for their saggy pants 
 ordinance. Now all the other cities need to follow suit.

Hey Henry, how can you think that the elected officials in 
 Stockbridge can run our city when they can&apos;t and dont know what 
 they are doing? Wonder how much money they have spent on legal fees 
 trying to figure it out? The residents and the employees are the 
 ones coming up on the short end.

Hey Henry, I like our balanced school calendar, but PLEASE teachers, 
 don&apos;t give assignments to be done over the fall break week. That 
 defeats the purpose of the break.

Hey Henry, if Clayton County was making money off Tara Field, why 
 would they sell it to Henry County? Seems to me, Henry County was 
 collecting property taxes from Clayton County. Now we own it, pay 
 taxes to ourselves, DUH. What&apos;s wrong with this picture?

Hey Henry, weeks ago, we were told Henry County was in such dire 
 financial straits that the B.O.C. had to lay off 59 employees. If 
 the average total cost to the county in salary, benefits, SS, etc of 
 those employees is, say, $45,000; and we multiply that by 59; we 
 have a total of $2,655,000. Yet, just weeks later, the B.O.C. 
 finds $2.7 to buy an airport! Is anyone really dumb or naive 
 enough to believe those numbers are not connected? Anyone? (crickets 
 chirping).

Hey Henry, as we all know, the economy is in poor shape. The 
 question is, it seems like it hasn&apos;t affected many people because 
 they still go as much as they did when the cost of gas was low. They 
 still eat out continuously, and shop like nothing has ever happened. 
 Yes, I work full time and so does my wife. Could someone tell me 
 what the secret is?

Hey Henry, to the person who lost their Sam&apos;s Gift card and was 
 angry Sam&apos;s wouldn&apos;t replace it because it had already been used. If 
 you dropped a $100 dollar bill, who are you going to blame? The U.S. 
 Treasury Department? It really stinks that you were dealt that card 
 (no pun intended) but America needs to quit blaming other 
 people/companies for their own mistakes!

Hey Henry, Let&apos;s go to the fair tax. I would pay another one cent 
 sales tax to keep the county running without layoffs. Everybody 
 would pay by adding a one cent sales tax.
 
07.20.11

Hey Henry, whatever happened to giving straight and direct answers? 
 It seems like every question gets a political answer that never 
 answers the question. Maybe these people need real jobs so they stop 
 wasting the time of those of us who do have real jobs! Ed note: 
 Amen!

Hey Henry, kids remember that the month of July is the time to 
 return completed reader&apos;s club folders to whichever Henry County 
 library branch you use.

Hey Henry, if the county wants to balance the budget, check the 
 employees computers and fire all of the deadbeats that spend all 
 day on facebook, or playing games on facebook. We working employees 
 are already doing their jobs anyways.

Hey Henry, I would like to commend the Board of Commis-sioners for 
 their great acting skills. The tears when announcing the layoffs 
 were very touching. But, how many of those jobs could have been 
 saved if the purchase of an UNNEEDED air field had been taken out of 
 the budget? How many more layoffs will we have next year or the year 
 after that because they had to have this airport? When is the 
 senseless buying of unneeded land going to stop?

Hey Henry, I agree with the person who noticed so many&quot;twenty 
 somethings&quot;always being sick and unable to work. I know exactly 
 what you mean! At my place of work, I have never seen as many young 
 people with so many health problems. Do you think they&apos;re really 
 sick, or just don&apos;t want to work.

Hey Henry, I see that the county has paid $17 million to purchase 
 Tara Field - that in addition to the golf club land and the 
 battlefield land. Just one of these millions spent on useless 
 property could support the five county libraries at the level needed 
 to get back all their former hours of operation and all staff. Where 
 are our priorities?

Hey Henry, how many county employees could have kept their jobs had 
 the powers that be not purchased Tara Field?

Hey Henry, a great big thanks for quick response from Henry County 
 road crew for cleaning the brush on South Bay Dr. at Jodeco Rd. Now 
 we can see the stop sign!

Hey Henry, to the person who wants the farmers to hire teens to work 
 on their farms. The teens are too lazy to work hard these days, in 
 fact the majority of adults are too lazy to work on a farm. They 
 would rather sit back and complain about being out of work and want 
 us to give them a hand out.

Hey Henry, taxpayers may want to look into the spending of all board 
 members on all boards for the County. It is all public info that can 
 be requested through the Open Records Act. Frivolous spending for 
 attendance at unnecessary conventions out of town and beachfront 
 accommodations. Receipts turned in for reimbursement for shocking 
 items. Taxpayer money is footing the bill. Who is approving these 
 trips? Who is approving reimbursements? People take an interest in 
 your COUNTY! It is your MONEY!

Hey Henry, the reason that my motorcycle is so loud is so that you 
 will hear me coming! You obviously are not paying attention while 
 you drive because you are talking on your cell phone, texting or 
 fumbling around looking for your Lady Gaga CD. You can&apos;t see me if 
 you are not paying attention so at the very least maybe you will 
 hear me!
 
07.13.11

Hey Henry, Alien T&amp;T, formally known as American Telephone and 
 Telegraph, is charging me for a Caller ID feature. I still get calls 
 from unidentified callers. Why isnt big brother protecting us?

Hey Henry, everyone who volunteered to clean up Nash Farms - how 
 about volunteering to clean up and maintain our children&apos;s schools. 
 Our present day children and county need more support than an old 
 battlefield.

Hey Henry, I agree with the person about a noise ordinance. These 
 people with loud motorcycles sounding like a sick B-52 bomber, 
 thinking that it sounds good, duh. Sounds like crap!

Hey Henry, is it just me, or does every&quot;twenty something&quot;around 
 here have major medical problems so often that they can&apos;t seem to 
 work a 40 hour week. I wonder what they&apos;re going to be like when 
 they&apos;re 50! At least I&apos;ll be retired somewhere else by then, thank 
 goodness.

Hey Henry, apparently the honor of being a public servant has worn 
 off the people at the Locust Grove city hall. The employees there 
 are very rude to the taxpayers in the city. Shame on you.

Hey Henry, after talking with the officer over the HCPD H.E.A.T. 
 officers, I have found that they are funded by and mandated by the 
 state to only deal with seat belt, DUI, and traffic violations. This 
 is a waste of state funds when these officers could be used to 
 patrol neighborhoods and prevent burgularies and A/C thefts. All 
 officers should be able to handle seat belt, DUIs, and patrol 
 neighborhoods as well. Everyone please email Governor Deal as well 
 as your state legislator and ask they either redirect the H.E.A.T. 
 effort or cut funding so these officers are put to better uses.

Hey Henry, wouldn&apos;t it be nice for Henry County to have an Aquatic 
 Center with a public pool like Clayton County has? Sure would be 
 nice with this hot weather we&apos;ve been having lately.

Hey Henry, its interesting to me that our County Government wants 
 to limit a citizens access to our court system by imposing 
 unreasonable and outrageous costs for access to official records. 
 Curious that the costs of going to court has more than doubled the 
 past year. Its very interesting that requesting a redress of made 
 up, ambiguous, indistinct County rules will now cost more than the 
 request for relief is worth. Was it because so many of the Countys 
 citizens won their appeals that reasonable redress of grievances is 
 now cost prohibitive? Where are our County Commissioners on this?

Hey Henry, Florida is the first state that is going to require drug 
 testing for welfare! Some people are crying this is 
 unconstitutional. How is this unconstitutional but it&apos;s completely 
 legal that every other working person had to pass a drug test in 
 order to support those on welfare?

Hey Henry, We lost it, our problem? We returned defective 
 merchandise to Sam&apos;s Club. Despite having the receipt, they refused 
 to replace or fix the merchandise, they refused to give us a refund 
 insisting that all they could do was give us a gift card. They sold 
 us defective merchandise, refused to make it right or give us a 
 refund, and refused to replace the gift card when we reported it 
 lost because someone else used it. Every way, they win. Every way, 
 we lose. That&apos;s still poor customer service no matter how you cut 
 it.
 
07.06.11

Hey Henry, so theres a shortage of immigrant workers in Georgia-why 
 can&apos;t the local farmers hire our young teens that would love to work 
 for $8 an hour? Maybe the teens could sign up through the schools, 
 then the farmers could hire these youngsters that want to make 
 money. My son would love to make more than he makes at a fast food 
 restaurant, who hires so many kids that they don&apos;t even get 10 hours 
 a week.

Hey Henry, we can mind our own business just fine. We need no help 
 from the&quot;neighbors.&quot;

Hey Henry, how is it the Henry County Board of Commissioners are 
 financially able to purchase Tara Field, in Clayton County, but 
 unable to save over 50 jobs in Henry County, not to mention again 
 allowing furlough days to occur?

Hey Henry, to the person who lost the Sam&apos;s Club gift card. First, 
 you lost the card, someone found it and spent the money. That is not 
 Sam&apos;s Clubs fault so why would you expect them to give you your 
 $500 back? You lost the card, it is your problem.

Hey Henry, this is to&quot;I have 1 1/2 acres ...&quot;Your neighbor may 
 have agricultural use, or frozen taxes under agreement not to 
 develop it. Ask him.

Hey Henry, the next time you find yourself picking through the 
 desiccated remains of what was once the thriving, growing Henry 
 County Library System, keep in mind that the county cut their 2011 
 budget by almost $700,000, and the 2012 budget will be cut an 
 additional $268,000. That&apos;s almost a million dollars, resulting in 
 shorter hours and less staff to serve you. Something to think about 
 when local elections take place in 2012!

Hey Henry, heres another good one from Thomas Jefferson&quot;I predict 
 future happiness for Americans if thay can prevent the government 
 from wasting the labors of the people under the pretense of taking 
 care of them.&quot;

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t think the panhandler complaint was against the 
 firefighters, but against the kids and parents for letting them 
 stand on the street corner and road sides; they should offer a 
 service instead of asking for a hand out.

Hey Henry, seriously...to the lady with no patience at the parking 
 lot at Great Escapes. You know sometimes you have to back up a 
 couple of times to get out of your parking spot, especially when you 
 are a new driver. Give the 15-year-olds a break. So, blow your horn 
 and take pictures all you want! I hope I smiled HUGE for your 
 picture and right back at you with your ugly words.

Hey Henry does anyone really want to pay more taxes? I think if the 
 local, state and federal governments would put their heads together, 
 they could finance a transportation plan with the taxes we already 
 pay. Instead they waste so much of our hard earned dollars. JUST SAY 
 NO NEW TAXES!

Hey Henry, did you know that there used to be a street in 
 Stockbridge named Chuck Norris, but it had to be changed because 
 nobody crosses Chuck Norris and lives.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s good manners to say excuse me when someone is 
 standing in your way, for instance, but you need to allow the person 
 a chance to get out of your way. Just saying excuse me does not give 
 you license to run someone over and just because you say excuse me 
 doesn&apos;t mean the person who you are saying excuse me to is even 
 obligated to get out of your way.
 
06.29.11

Hey Henry, my heart just aches for all the lonely pets who are left 
 out in the yards all alone. Yes, children are out of school, but 
 theyd rather be inside playing games, watching TV, staying cool, 
 etc. The sad little dog roves up and down the fence just waiting for 
 a word or a pat from anyone. He is just so starved for love and 
 attention. Why do they have a dog?

Hey Henry, I have 1 1/2 acres in Henry County and my neighbor beside 
 me has 50 acres. His taxes are the same as mine Seems like no one in 
 this county can tell me why.

Hey Henry, thank you Judge Studdard for correcting me on the traffic 
 laws about impeding traffic, but drivers, if youre driving along 
 and theres no one in front of you and you look in your mirror and 
 see a convoy behind you, pull over and let them pass Everyone will 
 thank you!

Hey Henry, to the person that doesn&apos;t like the panhandlers in Henry 
 County. MOVE! My son is a Henry County Firefighter and is proud to 
 be taking up money that will help someone! Thank you so much for 
 caring about others.

Hey Henry, there are lots of of four way stops in McDonough, 
 especially in the Lake Dow neighborhood. Please be considerate of 
 others and drive safely. I&apos;m tired of sitting at four way stops and 
 being afraid of getting hit by someone who thinks a rolling stop is 
 a complete stop or someone who thinks if they are turning right that 
 they do not have to stop. Take turns! Its first-come, first-serve! 
 And remember that that neighborhood is full of children playing in 
 the yards and walkers and joggers on the roads!

Hey Henry, there are plenty of empty apartments and unfinished 
 subdivisions in Henry County. So what&apos;s the point in changing the 
 zoning for the property at Highway 20&amp;Westridge Parkway? 
 Overbuilding is one of the reasons were in this mess in the first 
 place.

Hey Henry! Lets dont forget our support for this wonderful little 
 paper. Hard times are had by The Times too! No, Im not a paid 
 employee of The Times, I just dont want to see this jewel disappear 
 on us. Where could you vent if it did? Spread the word and send in 
 those ads!

Hey Henry, what&apos;s so hard to understand about golf carts not being 
 allowed on the street?

Hey Henry, harassing others is not a contribution to the community.

Hey Henry, in response to the person who was refunded by Wal-Mart 
 for their stolen pre-paid card. We lost a $500+ Sam&apos;s Club gift card 
 in McDonough. When we realized that the card was missing and 
 reported it, we were told that it was spent in Macon and that there 
 was nothing they could do. That&apos;s terrible customer service.

Hey Henry, A big thank-you to John Jackson and his band of merry 
 (persons) for donating the parking-lot striping at the McDonough 
 Library. It looks great!

Hey Henry, get a life, everyone keeps crying over libraries and flip 
 flops, what about the waste of money for a battlefield, golf course 
 and shooting range. This is money that could have saved some jobs 
 and kept people from Henry P.D. from quitting daily to pursue jobs 
 elsewhere.
 
06.22.11

Hey Henry, we did a tour at the fire station for my grandson&apos;s 2nd 
 birthday. Many thanks to AJ and Mr. Pete and all the guys at 
 firestation #10. Youre the best.

Hey Henry, when economic times are tight, budgeters must set 
 priorities. Sometimes we need hospitals, streets, and public safety 
 more than libraries.

Hey Henry, what nice press the commissioners put out about it being 
 so much easier to check out library books by McDonough being open on 
 Sunday afternoons. They didn&apos;t mention that they are closing all the 
 libraries on Fridays now and eliminating all paid holidays. This is 
 equal to 48 furlough days for the remaining staff. Is any other 
 county office losing this much pay? Certainly not the commissioners 
 office!

Hey Henry, are there any others out there disturbed by the 
 panhandlers on our road ways? It started with the Firefighters 
 raising money for Jerry&apos;s Kids, then it was the sports teams selling 
 donuts for their team, now we are dodging both kids and adults with 
 buckets asking for money for who knows what? And by the way, if you 
 do want to donate, please don&apos;t do it when the light turns green and 
 I am behind you.

Hey Henry, as a retired RN who has had experience at both Piedmont 
 and Emory.......I&apos;d go with Piedmont every time! Emory spends a lot 
 of time and energy blowing their own horn while Piedmont goes 
 quietly about its business with docs, nurses and all ancillary 
 personnel giving great patient care. For one, I am delighted with 
 the decision that was made.

Hey Henry, this is Judge Studdard at State Court, and I have to 
 correct what someone wrote in the June 15 Hey Henry column: the 
 Georgia Court of Appeals recently ruled that a person cant be 
 convicted of impeding the flow of traffic for driving the speed 
 limit in the fast lane of the interstate. Sorry, speeders. Yall 
 drive carefully, now.

Hey Henry, theres nothing like putting $600 on a pre-paid money 
 card at Wal-Mart for a trip to New Orleans only to arrive the next 
 day at the hotel to find out that someone in Pakistan and Czech 
 Republic has spent all but 9 cents while the card was still in my 
 purse. Today, I received a refund check for the full amount from 
 Wal-Mart. Now, that&apos;s great customer service.

Hey Henry, how many county jobs (supporting the local economy) could 
 have been saved if the county had not purchased Nash Farms and the 
 Cotton Fields Golf course? What will the airport they want to buy 
 mean in lost jobs?

Hey Henry, when is the city or county going to fix those two giant 
 holes in the ground where the curve of the new section of Lake Dow 
 Road is. Someone is going to drive into those and cause a serious 
 accident if something isn&apos;t done about it.

Hey Henry, I love the feature&quot;As It Was&quot;but I&apos;d love it better if 
 ya&apos;ll would put one from the past 20 or 30 years in every now and 
 then instead of always putting in ones from&quot;the olden days&quot;so I 
 might be able to recognize it!

Hey Henry, I work at a grocery store and I am a friendly person. Why 
 is it that when I say hello to people and I know they hear me, they 
 just go about their shopping and ignore me? Does it take that much 
 effort just to say hi? You may have had a bad day or there&apos;s 
 something on your mind but it&apos;s just good manners to say hello back 
 when someone says hello to you.
 
06.15.11

Hey Henry, happy birthday to my wife, the frugal fashionista! You 
 dress so well, no one would guess that you get most of your clothes 
 from thrift shops. You save us lots of money, have fun and look 
 great. I call your style&quot;Millionairess Casual&quot;. Thank you!

Hey Henry, Normon Vincent Peale said it well -&quot;There was a time when 
 the American people roared like lions for liberty. Now they bleat 
 like sheep for security.&quot;

Hey Henry, the Board of Commissioners just passed a budget that 
 effectively gutted our public libraries. Nothing will change for 
 Henry County libraries until the voters do what they did in Cobb Co. 
 Get out your signs and protest.

Hey Henry, to the person who said that if they were running the 
 speed limit in the left lane they wouldnt move over to the right 
 lane for another car to pass, you would be breaking the law by 
 impeding the flow of traffic. If another car overtakes you in the 
 left lane, regardless of speed, you need to move right to allow them 
 to pass.

Hey Henry, there is nothing wrong with the economy in Henry County. 
 Just go to Tanger Mall on Saturday and Sunday and see how many 
 people are shopping, driving suv&apos;s and brand new cars. To top it 
 off, all the restaurants in Henry County are full as well.

Hey Henry, I still get sick every time I drive by the multi-colored 
 water fountain on North Henry at the new government complex. How 
 many library days would that waste of money have paid for. Is it too 
 late for a refund?

Hey Henry, is spreading rumors about a nonexistent crime wave a 
 distant cousin to yelling Fire in a crowded theatre? Chicken 
 Little, you&apos;re hurting my property resale value!

Hey Henry, in response to&quot;how to pick a good watermelon&quot;... Get one 
 with a green top and a deep yellow color on the bottom. Or just go 
 to Aldi. If it&apos;s bad they replace the bad one.

Hey Henry, when are McDonoughs finest going to start patrolling 
 McGarity Rd. and stop some of this tailgating and speeding. Drivers 
 pass you on the double yellow line in the curve-- speed limit is 
 45mph.

Hey Henry, after hearing of the reported layoffs at Piedmont this 
 past week, I wonder if Henry Medical Center is saying a big UH-OH 
 for choosing to partner with them instead of Emory? Looks like 
 Piedmont might not be in the position for partnering with another 
 facility right now.

Hey Henry, it is illegal for the County to pass an unbalanced 
 budget. The Board of Commissioners has to look at the&quot;bottom line&quot;and I&apos;ll work tirelessly to defeat the first Commissioner who 
 suggests raising taxes!

Hey Henry, I work in one of the public offices in the county. If you 
 need assistance why can&apos;t you say Excuse me or Could you help me 
 instead of tapping on the counter. Also, if I am helping you and you 
 start tapping on the counter I will get slower and slower until you 
 stop. That is so rude and annoying.

Hey Henry, I am disappointed Stockbridge moved the music in the park 
 to the city hall lawn. Memorial park has much better ambience, 
 grills, pavilions and a playground. Please move it back!
 
06.08.11

Hey Henry, let&apos;s talk about something important. How do you pick out 
 a good watermelon?

Hey Henry, I heard of a new Olympic event. It&apos;s called Politicians 
 (NOT) Answering Questions.

Hey Henry, can&apos;t the Henry County Board of Education do away with 
 the pine straw and put that money towards the classrooms! This is 
 ridiculous when people are getting furloughed! The schools will 
 operate fine without pine straw. Wake up Henry County Board of 
 Education, children are more important.

Hey Henry, shame on you, Locust Grove, for not putting 
 congratulations on the sign in front of the municipal building 
 congratulating the seniors of Locust Grove. Farmers needed has 
 been up on the sign too long!

Hey Henry, who in the Fire Department Admin. dropped the ball on 
 recognizing our EMS workers during EMS Appreciation Week? Hey, the 
 public appreciates you even if your Admin. doesn&apos;t. Thank you for 
 all you do!

Hey Henry, I would like to know what is the timetable for completing 
 the highway construction on Fairview Road near Hearn Road? Will it 
 be completed by Christmas 2011 or New Year&apos;s 2012?

Hey Henry, I recently watched the county budget hearing on the local 
 cable station. I want to applaud Commissioner Holder on his 
 passionate comments and his vote against the budget. It is very 
 clear that Commissioner Holders comments came from his heart and 
 that he, unlike the other Commissioners, sees a whole lot more than 
 the bottom line. He sees the impact that the decisions make on 
 employees and families. I have the utmost respect for him as a 
 neighbor, fellow citizen and elected official. His passion and 
 historical knowledge are a tremendous value and asset to the county 
 and its citizens.

Hey Henry, to that Henry County employee who says they are just out 
 for themselves.....why not sign your name to your comment if you&apos;re 
 so proud of looking out for just you? Sure hope you aren&apos;t one of 
 the 57 people who get laid off or the 9 who have a reduction in pay.

Hey Henry, how about offering the local farmer&apos;s market during hours 
 the majority of us are NOT working? Whose idea is 2-6 on a Thursday 
 afternoon. And there&apos;s Hampton, whose 2-6 on Friday doesn&apos;t help, 
 either. At least stay open til 7! And what happened to Saturdays? 
 Looks like I will just have to spend my money out of the county 
 again this summer!

Hey Henry, Im a Henry County umpire and I want to respond to the HH 
 from last week. Each park, age group, and division has their own 
 rules and the umpires follow those rules. The umpire associations 
 have nothing to do with making up the rules. The sport is still fun 
 90% of the time depending on the coaches and parents.

Hey Henry, so if the person wants a bicyclist to pay taxes for using 
 the road, what about extra taxes on running shoes or kids toys that 
 are ridden on subdivision roads? I am confident the bicyclists 
 already pay taxes on their cars!

Hey Henry, please don&apos;t forget about your outdoor pets during this 
 heat wave. Make sure they have a good water supply and somewhere to 
 seek shade. Shame on those of you who have your poor dogs chained up 
 outside with nowhere to go!
 
06.01.11

Hey Henry, the bus drivers for HCS are not the only employees who 
 have not had a raise in three years. None of the HCS employees have, 
 so please quit whining. You are off the same number of days as the 
 students, drive in the mornings and afternoon only, so don&apos;t ask for 
 prayers for more money, just be thankful you have a job unlike many 
 people. Bus drivers are valuable employees but no more so than 
 anyone else at the BOE.

Hey Henry, this is for the Henry County employee who would be 
 willing to take more furlough days. You haven&apos;t talked to me. I am a 
 Henry County employee and I don&apos;t like the 4 we got this year. Step 
 up to the plate! Go to HR and say you want a 20% pay cut. To hell 
 with you, it&apos;s about self preservation. I have bills to pay and 
 family to take care of. I don&apos;t know who you are and don&apos;t really 
 care. The only job I am worried about is mine!

Hey Henry, so Warren Holder, a county commissioner, thinks all 
 county employees should take 12 furlough days to help the people who 
 are going to lose their jobs. Well he is a self-made millonaire, 
 more power to him, but I haven&apos;t heard him say he would give up his 
 commissioner pay. He doesn&apos;t need it. Its not much money, but it&apos;s 
 a start. In fact, none of the commissioners need their pay, they 
 have jobs. Do the job for the county, for the citizens.

Hey Henry, way to go Mrs. Mullis for providing the Locust Grove 
 community with a wonderful inaugural graduation. The GYM was 
 beautifully decorated and the only issues were with a few spectators 
 who obviously do not understand graduation etiquette.

Hey Henry, it is not necessary to shoot off fire works at midnight 
 on a random weeknight. Some of your neighbors are trying to sleep 
 and don&apos;t appreciate the noise!

Hey Henry, I just wanted to say to those who are worried about 
 people in flip flops, men wear sleeveless shirts with their armpits 
 showing, and people smoking cigarettes. If youre worried about that 
 then evidently everything is going pretty well for you because you 
 aint got much serious to worry about.

Hey Henry, am I the only one feeling cheated by Stockbridge cutting 
 trash removal down to 1 day a week? Shouldn&apos;t we pay less if we are 
 getting less service?

Hey Henry, Kelleytown Park is slated to get the county&apos;s first bike 
 trails in the next few months. Volunteers already began marking the 
 trails during Hands on Henry Day. Thanks to all the volunteers!

Hey Henry, when at a stop light, I don&apos;t WANT to hear internal organ 
 rattling, thumping base music coming from your car. If I want music, 
 I&apos;ll turn on my OWN radio.

Hey Henry, saw a young mother today holding a baby, about 6 months 
 old. They were both badly sunburned. If you aren&apos;t smart enough to 
 use a good sunscreen or keep your baby out of the sun, maybe you 
 shouldn&apos;t have the child. Why should the baby suffer for your 
 mistake?

Hey Henry, to the person who wrote about Henry County parks having 
 different playing rules. The rules are the same but the parks are 
 run by different associations for sports, and they all use different 
 umpire groups. The only way to fix it is have the same umpire group 
 calling all parks. You are right, the fun is gone.
 
05.25.11

Hey Henry, I was not surprised to learn, but I had not previously 
 heard that my dentist, Dr. Billy Dellinger, was voted the&quot;2010 TOP 
 DENTIST IN ATLANTA for outstanding recognition from your peers in 
 Atlanta magazine&quot;! He&apos;s way too modest to ever tell anybody or toot 
 his own horn, so that is why I just found out 5 months late. Thought 
 you should know - he&apos;s a great dentist and his office staff is great 
 too!

Hey Henry, I know people say&quot;Happy Memorial Day&quot;without thinking 
 about it, but it&apos;s really not an appropriate sentiment for a holiday 
 meant to honor our war dead. I have no problem with people enjoying 
 their 3-day weekend with cookouts, parties and the like, but please 
 stop and think before you use this misguided phrase.

Hey Henry, sitting at a red light at I-75&amp;Hwy 20/81 and I look 
 over to see a woman smoking inside her van with children inside. 
 Selfish idiot!

Hey Henry, way to go Commissioner Warren Holder for your comments 
 about the budget at the May 17, 2011 BOC meeting! As an employee of 
 Henry County, I would be willing to double or even triple the number 
 of furlough days, if it means that no one will be laid off. Everyone 
 I&apos;ve talked to feels the same way!

Hey Henry, you see road signs saying Share the road with bicycle 
 riders. I want to know why they dont have to pay license fees, ad 
 valorum taxes, and tag fees. I ride a motorcycle and I have to pay 
 them. Shouldnt they share the taxes?

Hey Henry, why am I paying construction workers to stand around? I&apos;m 
 sick of driving by&quot;construction&quot;sites and seeing workers laying 
 down, standing around, and talking. I&apos;m over it. They are paid to 
 work. They should work.

Hey Henry, why doesn&apos;t anyone use their turn signals anymore? Is 
 that just a luxury item they put on vehicles? Hmmm. I even see Henry 
 County Police do the same. What is up?

Hey Henry, residents of Locust Grove who live on the west side of 
 Hwy 42 or anywhere in the vicinity of Tanger Blvd. there&apos;s a PEEPING 
 TOM prowling around our neighborhoods. Let&apos;s all be diligent about 
 watching and listening, so we can be safe. Call Locust Grove Police 
 or 911 if you see or hear anything.

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t mind the flip flops, but please men, no 
 sleeveless shirts! The male armpit is not a thing of beauty.

Hey Henry, please help my friend find her dog. Someone was shooting 
 fireworks on May 5th and this scared her dog and she ran away. She 
 was in the Stonewall Subdivision. She is a black and white Boston 
 terrier, and her name is Lucy.

Hey Henry, can Henry County please provide a place (pay-for-use) 
 where citizens can bring their larger trash pieces. We should not 
 have to drive to Clayton County and pay them. This would help with 
 the dumping issues in Henry County.

Hey Henry, if you are breastfeeding your 2-year-old you need some 
 help, let alone out in public. I am all for breastfeeding infants up 
 to 1 but after that, take it to a private place.

Hey Henry, Walnut Creek Manor would like to thank the Palmertree 
 Family for our 3 new gardens. The residents are enjoying the 
 sprucing up your family volunteered to do for us. We especially 
 would like to thank Suzanne and Zack. Go Scouts!
 
05.18.11

Hey Henry, it is not just Kelley Town with no sidewalks or 
 amenities. Henry County does not care about citizens quality of 
 living. Just keep those good ole boys paving over everything. When 
 they paved Sims Drive, a tiny bit of dirt road, it became the 
 Woodland Express cut through. Now you cannot even go for a walk 
 without speeders running you over. I wish I had moved to another 
 county.

Hey Henry, why is graduation ceremony for the charter class of 
 Locust Grove High being held in the gym and graduates limited to ten 
 tickets? We have a stadium that could easily accomodate many 
 attendees. This should be a memorable time in these students lives, 
 not a time that they are forced to choose who does or does not share 
 this special time.

Hey Henry, thanks Henry for the Rock Roll&amp;Reminisce at the Jason 
 T. Harper on Saturday. I had friends and family come from FL, NC and 
 TN for the event.

Hey Henry, your bright lights are necessary when you leave your 
 driveway on the remote roads of the county, but when you get to the 
 major roads and 75, please have the brains and consideration to turn 
 your high beams off.

Hey Henry, before you purchase ANYTHING, look at the label to see 
 where it was made. If it says&quot;Made in Pakistan,&quot;please put it 
 down. Once you start looking, you will be surprised just how much&quot;stuff&quot;being sold in America is made in Pakistan?

Hey Henry, thanks for putting in everything that the county wastes 
 money on in the vent. Oh wait, you don&apos;t. Is the vent run by queen 
 B.J. herself?

Hey Henry, if you die in an elevator, be sure to push the up button.

Hey Henry, your county school bus drivers thank you for your support 
 and gratitude. Our job has enormous responsibility and liability--a 
 job we do well. Due to pay freezes last year and again this year, we 
 are some of the lowest paid drivers in the metro area. Please keep 
 us in your thoughts and prayers.

Hey Henry, I am one of the dummies who did not research the 
 content of The Producers before attending. I did not take my 
 children, but if I had, I would have left long before it was over. I 
 have been a season ticket holder for several years. I have never had 
 a reason to check any production before attending. If you support 
 this lifestyle, go for it. I have only one request, dont expose 
 your children to this lifestyle. they have enough problems to face.

Hey Henry, please let the County and especially Locust Grove know 
 the Event Center is also the Senior Center. It is a place to have 
 good food and fellowship. They have some programs going on BUT they 
 need more participation. It is on the corner of Bowden St. and Mose 
 Brown Dr.

Hey Henry, I am appalled at Judge Chafin&apos;s decision to let the 
 Muslim, who appeared in court, wear his kufi. We are giving away all 
 our rights here in America. Next time I appear in court I will be 
 wearing a huge cross with a Bible in my hand. I will likely be fined 
 for violating the rights of others.

Hey Henry, thank you Judge Chafin for reversing your earlier 
 decision regarding the man wearing his religious headwear. You are 
 wise and fair--what a judge should be!
 
05.11.11

Hey Henry, it sure would be nice if the McDonough and Henry County 
 police departments would enforce the noise ordinances in our 
 communities.

Hey Henry, it took President Obama so long the release his birth 
 certificate because he shouldn&apos;t have had to release it. No other 
 president has ever had to release one.

Hey Henry, this is a followup to a previous Hey Henry. The writer is 
 correct. Kelleytown has nothing, no sidewalks, no amenities of any 
 kind from the County. We have a 126 acre park with no money to 
 develop. All we get from Henry County is tax bills.

Hey Henry, apparently the reader complaining about the&quot;low bid 
 paving contractor&quot;for the Keys Ferry paving project didn&apos;t read the 
 signs on the trucks. They were Henry County DOT trucks.

Hey Henry, Henry County may not have closed the libraries but they 
 sure did lay a lot of people off that needed their jobs. I just 
 don&apos;t see that as being better than Cobb County. Not one little bit.

Hey Henry, why are all the Henry County ballparks on different game 
 rules? Game rules vary from park to park.....and way too much drama 
 at all the ball parks! We pay good money for our kids to PLAY 
 ...what are we teaching our kids? Lets show some sportsmanship! What 
 happened to FUN?

Hey Henry, the legitimate press covered the issue of our President&apos;s 
 birth certificate during the election process. Perhaps if one would 
 stop watching only one news channel, owned by an Australian, that 
 keeps its viewers by telling half-truths and partially edited video 
 clips, one would see that the press is indeed asking questions good 
 for all of us...questions on more important things like true budget 
 and tax reform and not pandering to the fears of the few.

Hey Henry, I just would like to say how much my family and I have 
 enjoyed living in Henry County these last five years. We moved from 
 Rockdale County in 2006, and the difference has been awesome! I want 
 to thank the Henry County Police Department for being close when 
 people need them.

Hey Henry, why would we need a library in Kelleytown? We&apos;re 10 
 minutes away from the main library on 81.

Hey Henry, Happy Birthday IRS! The IRS started in 1911 and was an 
 $11 flat tax. Like any other government agency it grew and grew to 
 over 21,000 pages of tax laws. Maybe in a hundred years we can look 
 back and say Happy Birthday Obama Care. Ya&apos; think it&apos;ll grow too?

Hey Henry, I just love it that the GADOE has a parent advisory panel 
 and at their website parents are welcome to send suggestions!

Hey, Henry, don&apos;t forget that in your vehicles, the switch on the 
 left is a turn signal, USE IT!

Hey Henry, whats up with the gas stations that charge 7% tax on food 
 items. Tax on food items should only be 3% in Georgia.

Hey Henry, I just want to give a special thank you to the people who 
 played a part in finding my lost pet. He is home and we are all 
 happy and getting back to normal.
 
05.04.11

Hey Henry, in case no one paid attention: Henry County NEVER closed, 
 nor proposed closing a single library branch. We&apos;re much better than 
 Cobb County.

Hey Henry, so you&apos;re offended by the content and anti-Christian 
 sentiments in The Producers, and worried about the effects on 
 children in the audience? Well, I&apos;m offended by parents who take 
 their children to shows without researching the content ahead of 
 time. BTW, the fact that it was in a government building is 
 irrelevant. I&apos;m sure&quot;UnChristian&quot;things are said and done in 
 government buildings on a daily basis.

Hey Henry, I guess the barrels at Hwy 81 and Racetrack road are 
 there for decoration. They have been sitting there well over a 
 month. I guess it will take another 2 years before this gets done as 
 well.

Hey Henry, The real issue behind the birth certificate drama is why 
 our press refused for three years to ask Obama why he wouldn&apos;t 
 release it. The national press had no problems asking REPUBLICANS 
 about it, at every turn. But I never saw the press ask Obama about 
 it. The press is supposed to be looking out for us.

Hey Henry, to the couple who saw The Henry Players show&quot;The 
 Producers.&quot;You are complaining because you did not like the 
 selection? Or maybe because you went to the show and did not know 
 what was being played? lol ! Wake up, it was a Mel Brooks 
 production! And btw, it was GREAT. Maybe next time you should watch 
 one of the childrens shows instead, unless that is offending you on 
 some other issue. Get a grip!

Hey Henry, will anyone in McDonough live long enough to see 
 Lawrenceville Street repaved?

Hey Henry, close your eyes and you can see it. Highway 81 East the 
 new Tara Blvd. ...

Hey Henry, I just want to wish everyone a happy Mothers Day.

Hey Henry, I&apos;d just like to thank Jimmy and Johnny White of Triple J 
 Tree Works for rescuing our cat, after being stranded in the top of 
 a tree for 7 days. Really nice guys and were glad to help.

Hey Henry, I think most of us realize that all handicaps are not 
 visible to the eye. However, when you see a carload of teenagers hop 
 out of their car and race each other to the door, how would you 
 define THAT handicap?

Hey Henry, if this county doesn&apos;t hurry up and fix it&apos;s economic 
 problems this county won&apos;t even exist anymore. With no new jobs and 
 no new money coming in, what&apos;s to become of this county and it&apos;s 
 people.

Hey Henry, to the Hampton resident that wants a county Rec. Center 
 with a full gym inside and a Senior Center: Do you want your taxes 
 raised to pay for it? Tax revenues are down due to the economy. 
 There are commercial gyms you can pay for out of your pocket to go 
 to. There is also a church that offers a&quot;senior center&quot;on certain 
 days in Hampton. It&apos;s not the government&apos;s job to entertain us.

Hey Henry, heres a quote for all you complainers. The tendency to 
 whining and complaining may be taken as the surest sign symptom of 
 little souls and inferior intellects. ~ Lord Jeffrey
 
04.20.11

Hey Henry, in response to the person who complained that non 
 handicapped persons are improperly using anothers handicapped 
 parking permit, many handicapped persons do not have visible 
 handicaps and not all handicapped persons are senior citizens.

Hey Henry, I have 1 1/4 acres and my neighbor down the street has 25 
 acres. Property taxes are the same for both. Somethings wrong here. 
 This is not fair.

Hey Henry, Id like to give a positive thought to some special 
 people. Im in my 70s and disabled and have no one to help me when I 
 grocery shop. Im always surrounded by nice people I like to call my 
 angels and they know who they are.

Hey Henry, everyone who volunteered to clean up Nash Farms - how 
 about volunteering to clean up and maintain our children&apos;s schools. 
 Our present day children and county need more support than an old 
 battlefield.

Hey Henry, have you seen Henry Cork?

Hey Henry, a big thanks for the special needs Easter egg hunt at 
 Nash farm - People First of Henry County deserve your full support. 
 Thanks to all the volunteers and sponsors who made the day special.

He Henry, This is in response to the person complaining about not 
 having a recreation center in Hampton. You have a library, and the 
 folks in Kelleytown don&apos;t. Appreciate what you&apos;ve got.

Hey Henry, you know the best thing about this weekly vent? You will 
 only find it in your weekly, community newspaper! The big newspapers 
 would ignore your complaints, but The Henry County Times will always 
 support the community. Great Job! There is nothing better than a 
 weekly, community newspaper to keep you informed and on top of local 
 happenings and this is one reason when my husband and I return to 
 the area we will live in Henry County!

Hey Henry, would not watering the grass and it dying be a better 
 option? The cost of water to the county, I&apos;m sure, is quite cheap 
 compared to replacing or regrowing the grass in the future. With sub 
 par fields you would not have tournaments like the one a month or 
 two ago that brought quite a bit of money into the county. Anyhow, 
 do you want our kids playing on fields with no grass?

Hey Henry, to the person who wants a recreation center and senior 
 center in Hampton... you realize that costs money to either build or 
 renovate an existing building? Are you prepared to have an increase 
 in taxes to pay for it or is the county just supposed to add more 
 furlough days and possibly cut more jobs so it&apos;ll be less of an 
 inconvenience to you?

Hey Henry, I hope the economy improves soon or there will be 
 squirrel in every pot.

Hey Henry, express bus-coaches from McDonough to Downtown and 
 Midtown Atlanta - Eight departures times in the morning and eight 
 return trips in the evening. Monday-Friday. Stress free ride and 
 major savings on gas. Just Sayin. $7.00 round trip www.xprssga.com.
 
04.13.11

Hey Henry, why is JP Mosely Recreation Park the only one with a full 
 gym, what about the other centers and how about a recreation center 
 for Hampton, we have to drive clear over to Heritage Park or Locust 
 Grove to do anything, there are lots of us here in Hampton who would 
 like our own recreation center and a senior center.

Hey Henry, to the person complaining about job openings at the 
 county, do you realize the number of unemployed people there are? 
 ANY position, if left open for too long, could easily see several 
 hundred applicants. Would you want to sort through 400 applications 
 for each open position? That is why they are closed quicker than in 
 the past when the economy was better. So don&apos;t be mad that you 
 didn&apos;t get the job and blame it on someone else.

Hey Henry, noticed the flags coming and going on 81? YES, YES, YES, 
 We are going to get a light and turn lanes. Gee, I got so excited I 
 forgot to tell you where. Racetrack and 81.

Hey Henry, after participating in Pvt. Jeremy Faulkner&apos;s homecoming 
 yesterday and remembering the homecoming of Staff Sergeant First 
 Class John C. Beale in 2009, I would like to challenge the residents 
 of Henry County to only post positive and inspiring comments to&quot;Hey 
 Henry&quot;for the rest of April. During the homecoming of a fallen 
 soldier, we all came together as a loving community. Let&apos;s do this 
 in MEMORY of all of our fallen soldiers.

Hey Henry, clean up the drugs and trash off the roads!

Hey Henry, each year, only 25% of the EIGHT MILLION dogs in shelters 
 are adopted. Please spay and neuter. There aren&apos;t enough homes for 
 them all.

Hey Henry, I do not understand why Parks and Rec. is watering the 
 ball fields while county employees are being furloughed because 
 there is not enough money in the budget. Money is money no matter 
 where it comes from.

Hey Henry, thank you to the Commissioners and GDOT for getting the 
 traffic light and turn lanes at Lake Dow and Hwy 81. That should 
 help the problem at Race Track Rd. as well.

Hey Henry.&quot;Congressmen who willfully take action during wartime 
 that damages morale and undermine the military are saboteurs and 
 should be arrested, exiled, or hung&quot;Abraham Lincoln

Hey Henry, yesterday I went to the new Wal-Mart in Locust Grove. 
 Traffic was held up (6 cars that I could count) because a car was 
 waiting to get a handicapped space right in front of the door. 
 Finally, this car pulled into the space, hung a handicap tag on the 
 rear view mirror, and out hopped two teenagers! Unforgivable.

Hey Henry, I love the idea of Blue Grass music on the Square. Come 
 on events planner lets do it! A whole bunch of banjo pickers, 
 guitar players, mandolins, fiddles that would be too awesome!

Hey Henry, work hard, don&apos;t buy into this&quot;someone&apos;s out to get me&quot;attitude, and make good choices. Just remember someone out there is 
 doing more with less than you. Please stop the begging and looking 
 for handouts. Go out and make your own life instead of listening to 
 fairy tales.
 
04.06.11

Hey Henry, to the person who wrote about the Henry County Schools 
 and parents doing their job - HOORAY! Someone finally said it out 
 loud. The truth hurts so bad. It&apos;s not all parents, and thank you to 
 those who do their jobs. It shows in the classroom and sorry that 
 your children have to miss out on learning because the teacher has 
 to stop to discipline those that just want to goof off.

Hey Henry, I&apos;d like to give a shout out to the City of Hampton for 
 all the additions they have made to the City Park next to the 
 Elementary School! They added exercise equipment and more playground 
 equipment. I hadn&apos;t been in a while, and was really impressed. 
 Thanks Hampton!

Hey Henry, did former Rep. Lunsford and Rep. Steve Davis ever pay 
 back the money they owed Henry County? Never heard the outcome.

Hey Henry, if you are a pet owner please make sure that your pet has 
 an I.D. tag on it&apos;s collar. In the last few months many pets have 
 been found in my area with collars but no I.D. tags. Even if your 
 pet has a chip, an I.D. tag makes it easy to call the owner. They 
 sell the tags at most pet stores or big box stores for around $4.

Hey Henry, kudos to the Henry Players for a wonderful show (The 
 Producers). We are lucky to have this group adding to the social 
 life of our county!

Hey Henry, if the Parks and Recreation Dept. is funded by taxes, why 
 is there a membership fee to use the gym and track facilities?

Hey Henry, if your reader actually read your paper, they would know 
 that the Friends of the Library recently held it&apos;s annual Roast 
 raising over $9,000, had a 5K race in December raising over $1,000 
 and has several other projects on tap for 2011. Ask the library 
 director if she thinks the Friends do nothing.

Hey Henry, congratulations on the low-bid paving project on Keys 
 Ferry Rd. We certainly got what we paid for.

Hey Henry, when are you going to get this BIG MESS at Rocky Creek Rd 
 and Hampton/LG Rd. done? Get it right the first time and stop 
 wasting my money.

Hey Henry, please don&apos;t call 911 just to have someone come tell your 
 neighbor to stop burning leaves. Our EMS services have much bigger 
 problems than your neighbor burning leaves. If you have a problem 
 with it, go put your big girl panties on and go explain your issue 
 to the burner and it might get resolved without tying up our 
 firemen.

Hey Henry, I am so glad no one said anything about flip flops last 
 week. Did I just say that out loud?

Hey Henry, if you&apos;re so concerned about Charter showing hard liquor 
 programs while your kids watch TV why don&apos;t you sit down and watch 
 TV with them so you can monitor what they&apos;re watching? Don&apos;t let the 
 TV be your babysitter!

Hey Henry, this is to the Mayor or Dept. of Transportation. Why 
 can&apos;t you get a traffic light on Racetrack Rd. at Hwy 81? When you 
 fixed the intersection at Bethany and Hwy 81 you put up a traffic 
 light which is great for the County but the Racetrack Rd. 
 intersection is ridiculous.
 
03.30.11

Hey Henry, whoever plans the events in the Square, lets do a super 
 one. Get a good Blue Grass band and invite everyone who can play a 
 guitar to bring it and play along. That would be great music ... 
 people would love it.

Hey Henry, lets not sweep the gunning down of family pet dogs by 
 police officers under the rug. Meter readers, package delivery 
 employees and mailmen are in peoples yards and doorways hundreds of 
 times more often than police officers. I have never heard of any of 
 these needing to gun down a dog to get their jobs done.

Hey Henry, I wonder how many of my SPLOST tax dollars went towards 
 the soccer complex I will never even see. Not demeaning the ones who 
 will use the facility but how many holes in the road will be endured 
 trying to get to the complex, hum?

Hey Henry, HELP! Cheer gym needed for a fantastic special needs 
 cheer team that just got dumped from CTA!

Hey Henry, It&apos;s inconsiderate, when there is available parking, to 
 hold up traffic so you can get a preferred space. It&apos;s totally wrong 
 to park in a handicap space if you&apos;re not handicapped - even if you 
 do have your grandmothers handicap tag to hang up. Stop being lazy 
 and walk a few more feet!

Hey Henry, the Ola High Academic Team hosted and competed in the GA 
 qualifier for the first National History Bee and Bowl March 5th and 
 qualified a varsity team and a junior varsity team to compete in the 
 National Bowl finals in DC in April and one student qualified for 
 the National Bee. Congratulations and good luck!

Hey Henry, both of my daughters who live next door to each other on 
 Dorsey Road in Hampton were burglarized this year. Both burglaries 
 occurred in broad daylight. Keep your guard up and call 911 if you 
 see folks or vehicles that don&apos;t belong at a neighbor&apos;s house!

Hey Henry, why is the speed limit on Mill Road between Mt. Carmel 
 and Jonesboro Road 45 MPH going north and 35 MPH going south?

Hey Henry, this is to the Locust Grove Citizen, with concerns in the 
 March 23 edition concerning street side pick-up of leaves and trash. 
 The city contracts with an outside vendor to pick-up household 
 garbage weekly. The leaves, trash and limbs are picked up by city 
 employees at no cost to the citizens because the city has no 
 property tax, therefore it is free to all Locust Grove citizens.

Hey Henry, shame on the commissioners or whoever approves current 
 houses for potential residential zoning! No other rezoning needs to 
 be done until ALL of the empty, abandoned, and unused strip malls in 
 and around McDonough get occupied!

Hey Henry, what exactly do the&quot;Friends of the Library&quot;do here? In 
 every other place I have lived, the Friends are highly visible, 
 raising money and awareness for the library. Other than the book 
 sales Henry&apos;s&quot;Friends&quot;seem to do nothing. Hey Friends, how about 
 doing more like participating in the upcoming county garage sale for 
 example. The library needs help...NOW.

Hey Henry, I agree in thanking those businesses that give Military 
 discounts, I also agree on allowing our Marines to show Military 
 I.D. They should be acknowledged also even though they are not 
 allowed to wear their cammies in public. Semper Fi!

Hey Henry, unless youre related to the&quot;higher ups&quot;in Henry County 
 Government, you don&apos;t have a prayer of getting a job since the job 
 postings only last long enough for the&quot;pre-chosen&quot;applicant to 
 submit their application. Sometimes postings last less than one 
 business day.
 
03.23.11

Hey Henry, other counties in the metro area are just now cutting 
 library hours and services and even closing branches altogether. 
 Henry County had to do this a year ago because our library funding 
 was slashed way before any other county&apos;s. I always hoped to see 
 Henry County first in something, but not this.

Hey Henry, First, we need to pray for those over in Japan. Second, 
 we need to commend those in Japan for setting the bar in the face of 
 disaster. They have far surpassed what we here in the good ole USA 
 would do. I have yet to hear of any looting, gunfire, fighting. What 
 an example to set as a nation ... Wake up America, look at Japan. We 
 need to pray, pray, pray for these people.

Hey Henry, I am so glad that someone else has decided to join me in 
 the fight to put out those leaf burners... It is rude, disrespectful 
 and not to mention TOXIC to choke your neighbor. Homes are built on 
 top of each other now, so bag your leaves, compost them, whatever 
 you need to do, but STOP taking my air, smelling up my house, car 
 and animals and destroying these perfect, beautiful days with your 
 choke-smoke.

Hey Henry, can everyone please be kind to each other and focus your 
 energy in a positve way!

Hey Henry, I would like to run for commissioner in Henry County, but 
 I don&apos;t live in your area. How would YOU- Henry County- like this, 
 knowing I live in another county rather than yours. Would this make 
 you uneasy?

Hey Henry, since my mantra of Dont Worry, Be Happy has not caught 
 on ... Just Shut Up!

Hey Henry, why is it when people are elected to public office they 
 pack their logical thinking away in a closet? We have curbside 
 pick-up in Locust Grove, which is great, but I don&apos;t understand why 
 they pick up everything except raked up and bagged leaves. Where is 
 the logic in that? They have to send a special truck around when 
 they have time to do this. That makes for unsightly curb side trash 
 and a total waste of gas and money. Come on Locust Grove elected 
 officials--get with the program.

Hey Henry, to the person who complained about the smell of smoky, 
 burning leaves filling their house even with the doors and windows 
 closed do what I do call the Fire Dept and tell them one of your 
 family members is asthmatic (which is not a lie) and someone is 
 burning leaves and they will come out and find out who is burning 
 and have them put it out. ... hope this helps.

Hey Henry, about our schools in Henry County. If you parents would 
 take more time out with your children, we as a school system and our 
 teachers and staff wouldn&apos;t have so many problems with discipline in 
 the school classrooms ... We are here to help them learn and not 
 have to discipline or babysit your child and have to take all their 
 crap or yours.

Hey Henry, as a mother of a US Military man, I would like to thank 
 all of those who give Military Discounts. Sadly, our Marines don&apos;t 
 receive these discounts because the men and women have to be in 
 uniform and the Marines arent permitted to wear their camis&quot;out 
 and about.&quot;Can some concessions be made for our Marines so they can 
 show the proper military ID and receive these discounts as well?

Hey Henry, I am a 26 year old woman who needs NO HELP changing a 
 flat tire!

Hey Henry, responding to the Hey Henry relating to GA legislature 
 members being stupid, they usually train at the local level. Refer 
 to the purchase of Tara Field, the police shooting range (needed in 
 10 years?), Nash Farms, etc.
 
03.16.11

Hey Henry, all my doors are shut, and yet somehow, the pollution you 
 call one of the top ten smells in the world, Mr. Burning Leaves 
 Dude, is seeping in my house and fouling up my air. Justify it all 
 you want, but if you dispose of those leaves properly, they get 
 composted at the landfill with the other lawn clippings. If you 
 really want to help the Earth, compost those leaves instead of 
 burning them and adding to the air pollution problem.

Hey Henry, women can do anything a man can do...... until the flat 
 tire needs changing.

Hey Henry, I&apos;d like to have a goat and some chickens. I&apos;m in Flippen, 
 with a McDonough address. At one time I saw it was illegal within 
 city limits (which I think I&apos;m in), but now that we all are getting 
 back to nature, are they still being cranky about it?

Hey Henry, instead of the Commissioners using money to buy Tara 
 Field, why can&apos;t they use the money to help out the libraries and 
 other departments that have been cut almost to death? I mean, that 
 would make sense to the taxpayers.

Hey Henry, my daughter&apos;s boyfriend is not coming to see her today 
 because he lost his cellphone. I don&apos;t think my generation had this 
 problem; all we needed was a dime in our pocket, or maybe a quarter.

Hey Henry, so gasoline is sky-high; this is still a beautiful 
 spring. Enjoy it!

Hey Henry, to the person who wrote in about&quot;trashy people&quot;in 
 Walmart, please define&quot;trashy people&quot;so I can be on the lookout 
 for them when I&apos;m there.

Hey Henry, bring back the Easter Parade!

Hey Henry, if you need trash pickup two times a week, you need to 
 recycle. Be part of the solution, not part of the problem.

Hey Henry, have you noticed that the younger generation has replaced&quot;you are welcome&quot;with&quot;no problem&quot;in response to our&quot;Thank You&quot;we offer for services. I never thought of it as a problem in the 
 first place. Parents please teach your children proper manners. My 
 grandchild was saying&quot;you are welcome&quot;before the age of two and 
 continues now at age 25.

Hey Henry, do only stupid people run for the Georgia legislature or 
 do they become stupid after they are elected?

Hey Henry, it wasn&apos;t that long ago that the recycle center on Hwy. 
 81/Hampton Road was essentially a dump. It is now cleanly swept, 
 organized, and the assistants actually assist. I see that a 
 recycling station has been set up for motor oil. I will gladly go 
 back to servicing my own vehicle, especially now that I have a place 
 to properly dispose of the old 10W. If you gave up on this facility 
 some time ago, it&apos;s time for you to return. They&apos;re doing a first 
 rate job!

Hey Henry, I certainly hope you understood that 1984 was a 
 metaphor to represent a total, authoritarian police state. We are 
 controlled from cradle to grave as it is, yet they keep pushing for 
 more. We can&apos;t burn leaves, make a purchase, drive a car, make a 
 phone call, have a parade, assemble in public, add on to a home, 
 etc, without layers of government involvement and regulation.
 
03.09.11

Hey Henry, in regards to the Bark Park just off Jonesboro Road. I 
 would love to take my large breed Pom to a place where he can run 
 and play as much as he wants. (Ed. note: The Bark Park is at North 
 Mt. Carmel Park at 307 N. Mt. Carmel Road. It is part of the Henry 
 County Parks and Recreation Dept.)

Hey Henry, all the money being wasted investigating Atlanta Public 
 Schools cheating on tests needs to be funneled into the HOPE 
 scholarship and Pre-K funds. It is a waste of resources. The lawyers 
 and&quot;special investigators&quot;are the only ones benefiting from this 
 mess. They cheated, get over it, move on, and put all that money to 
 good use somewhere else!

Hey Henry, the City of Stockbridge has reduced trash pickup from two 
 days per week to one day per week. The piles of trash in the cans 
 lining the streets last week was horrible, smelly, and unsightly. 
 This will worsen in the upcoming summer heat. Most importantly, if I 
 am getting half the service, why is my bill not being cut in half?

Hey Henry, what is the best way to get rid of a stray cat? (Ed. 
 note: hang on to your seatbelts, folks. This is going to be 
 interesting.)

Hey Henry, Walmart is not a high-end department store. If you don&apos;t 
 like the people, then shop somewhere else.

Hey Henry, can anyone out there tell me what you have to do to get 
 the handicapped parking law enforced? If the law is not going to be 
 enforced, they may as well take down all the signs, because right 
 now, everyone and anyone are parking in the designated spaces marked 
 off for the handicapped. What does it take to get the attention of 
 our law enforcement folks?

Hey Henry, the Board of Commissioners should learn the difference 
 between wants and needs. They might want to buy Tara Field, but we 
 don&apos;t need to buy Tara Field.

Hey Henry, has anyone else hit the holes in the road on Jonesboro 
 Street between the Square and the railroad tracks? The holes are 
 getting worse and someone is going to blow a tire there.

Hey Henry, parents, please don&apos;t let your kids climb on the MIA 
 military memorial wall in Heritage Park. Teach them to show the 
 respect it deserves.

Hey Henry, bag your leaves and fill up the landfills. Burning leaves 
 are one of the ten top smells in the world... close your windows, 
 Yankee, and get over it.

Hey Henry, I like to take all my kitties out into the street in the 
 moonlight and sing showtunes. Is that odd?

Hey Henry, why don&apos;t you publish all the&quot;Hey Henry&quot;submissions. (Ed. note: Well, Skippy, I guess you just got yours in, didnt you?) 

Hey, Henry, I see the gas prices have not stopped Henry County 
 residents from going places. I believe if the gas goes up to $5.00 a 
 gallon, it will not stop them from eating out and continuing to 
 drive those gas guzzling SUVs.

Hey Henry, I hear that Extreme Makeover - Weight Loss Edition is 
 filming in Henry County. I think 90% of the people in this County 
 should be contestants. Especially you women in those way-too-tight 
 stretchy capri pants. (Ed. note: and we dont want to leave out 
 you beer-belly men.) 
 
03.02.11

Hey Henry, why do I detect so much 
 anger here? Isnt anybody happy anymore?

Hey Henry, I just heard that Southlake Mall is closing. I thought 
 the economy was&quot;getting better?&quot;

Hey Henry, everyone seems to looks down on our school - Henry County 
 High School. But if they only knew how many of the staff really 
 loves our kids, no matter their race or their wealth. I wouldn&apos;t put 
 my kids in any of the Henry County schools other than HCHS because I 
 think kids should be raised to love and respect everyone, 
 regardless.

Hey Henry, wake up! 1984 was 27 years ago.

Hey Henry, if you are driving 45 mph in a 55 mph zone, you obviously 
 have ample time to move over and allow the 15 cars behind you to go 
 by.

Hey Henry, in response to the Ellenwood mom and her doggy. There is 
 a dog friendly park in McDonough off of Jonesboro Road. It is called 
 Bark Park. You will meet friendly people and your dog will have a 
 blast! Come join us!

Hey Henry, what is the deal with all you leaf burners? Dont you 
 know the smoke is choking your neighbor? Bag the leaves and quit 
 taking my air. I would like to go outside and breathe!

Hey Henry, please fix the light at Hwy 81 and Lake Dow Rd. before 
 someone gets killed.

Hey Henry, get the county commissioners off the golf course and get 
 our county cleaned up - it is a pigsty. I am embarrassed to have 
 people from out of state come to see me. I travel all over the state 
 and Henry is by far the worst for trash.

Hey Henry, you are not being watched by the county 24/7. The cameras 
 on I-75 are from the state DOT, to monitor traffic in and out of 
 Atlanta. Go to Ga. DOT web site and you can watch the same traffic 
 if youre worried.

Hey Henry, every time I go to the McDonough Walmart, I feel like I 
 am at the Jerry Springer show. Ive never seen so many trashy people 
 in my life. Hopefully, they wont make their way down to the new 
 Walmart in Locust Grove.

Hey Henry, I know people wonder why I write you since I live so far 
 away but they have no idea how much I enjoy the Henry County Times 
 even though I have it on the computer. I hope McDonough never 
 changes from such a warm, caring city. Many years ago, I worked with 
 a wonderful group at Dr. Fosters office and met so many people and 
 I still remember them. Thanks for keeping me up on all the news. 
 Garland, TX is a long way from McDonough but I still have friends 
 there. I also count you as my friend.

Hey Henry, is it really too hard to reach down and turn on your 
 lights when driving in the rain? It would make it a lot easier to 
 see you, hence making it safer to drive.

Hey Henry, it is illegal to park your car on public streets in the 
 City of Stockbridge. It is dangerous when people park on the street 
 and you can&apos;t pass around the cars in your neighborhood. You can 
 easily hit an oncoming car or worse yet a child. If you have too 
 many cars to park in your driveway buy a bigger house.
 
02.23.11

Hey Henry, my four legged daughter and I are new to the county 
 (Ellenwood). Are there any pet friendly parks around?

Hey Henry, just sayin, I DID wear my flip flops just to show off my 
 beautiful feeties! Didn&apos;t ya&apos;ll love them? Oh, you know you did! 
 Yes, you did! I mean, they were just beautiful!

Hey Henry, that new District 5 Commissioner is a real prize.

Hey Henry, yes it is time for flip flops and I would be the first 
 person to say cover those ugly feet up, but when you take care of 
 them then wear them. It is those with ugly feet who complain to 
 begin with and the ones that do not know how easy it is to wash your 
 feet.

Hey Henry, doesn&apos;t anyone have anything positive to say? Stay 
 positive and love your life.

Hey Henry, if I&apos;m going 45 mph on Hwy. 81 where the speed limit is 
 55 mph and you call the police and report me as a drunk driver, then 
 I say you are the one endangering public safety by making false 
 claims that take up valuable police time. If the speed limit is 55 
 mph that doesn&apos;t mean I must drive 55, it simply means I can&apos;t drive 
 over 55 mph legally. Calm down, or go back up north where I&apos;m sure 
 you&apos;re from.

Hey Henry, lots of folks abuse the Henry Co. 911 system. You are 
 dumb to call 911 about a hang nail or because you stubbed your toe 
 at 3 a.m. Just remember that the gas to get to your house is costing 
 you and the rest of us money.

Hey Henry, please do something about Racetrack Rd. This is one of 
 the most dangerous roads in the county. Yes, another accident, as a 
 mother and her young child were hit. Why not do something before 
 someone dies because of an accident. Be pro-active.

Hey Henry, on behalf of the many working moms who are good parents 
 and helping to support their families, many of us don&apos;t have the 
 choice to stay at home with our children but it doesn&apos;t mean we&apos;re 
 not doing everything we can for our children including entrusting 
 them to wonderful caregivers during the day. Take off your rose 
 colored glasses and realize that sometimes it does take a village.

Hey Henry, so Fairview Athletic Association is now called Bruce 
 Holmes Athletic Association? Is Mr. Holmes paying for this or is it 
 just another politician on an ego trip?

Hey Henry, many thank you&apos;s to the Sacred Journey Staff for what you 
 did during our father&apos;s illness. We will never forget the kindness 
 and love you&apos;ve shown us during his stay. The world needs more 
 places and people like you.

Hey Henry, the election for Governor is over and you lost Ray 
 McBerry, so take down your signs. They are an eyesore. It is also 
 against the law to leave them up.

Hey Henry, a quip is, at most, a sentence or two; anything more is a 
 misplaced editorial. (Well Said! Ed.)

Hey Henry, working for the HCBOE means that I have not had a raise 
 in 3 years and I have had to take 8 days off without pay. Teachers 
 make good money but all the other&quot;little&quot;people would make more 
 working at Walmart.

Hey Henry, What are all those poles with mounted cameras on I-75 in 
 Henry County for? We are being put under surveillance 24/7 in this 
 country. 1984 is here, folks.
 
02.16.11

Hey Henry, it gets on my nerves that 
 people don&apos;t pay attention to simple signs. Like ENTER and EXIT, for 
 instance. At some stores, people look at you like youre crazy for 
 going out or in the correct door. I guess they either can`t read or 
 just dont care. Maybe they need to go back to elementary school to 
 learn something so simple.

Hey Henry, annoy a conservative, live like Jesus!

Hey Henry, we keep hearing about childhood obesity being an 
 epidemic. When I was a child, I spent my afternoons during the week 
 outside. These days homework consumes most of our childrens 
 evenings, and even much of their time on weekends. If in the past 
 you were able to receive a proper education without so much 
 homework, why can&apos;t it happen for our own children today.

Hey Henry, just thought those who have students at Luella High 
 School should know that there obviously IS a tolerance for bullying 
 and threats. My daughter was sexually threatened by a male and 
 NOTHING was done about it. No hearing, no ISS, no OSS. I know this 
 because he is still in classes, roaming halls and no students she 
 mentioned as witnesses were interviewed.

Hey Henry, I saw Girl Scouts selling cookies in front of South Side 
 Steve&apos;s on Industrial on Sunday. Didn&apos;t know they could sell cookies 
 in front of a bar. Must be relaxing their standards.

Hey Henry, just saying I&apos;m wearing my nasty&quot;FLIP FLOPS&quot;and showing 
 my ugly feet.

Hey Henry, to the guy who thinks he should govern the speed on Hwy 
 81, the speed limit is just that, a maximum, not a minimum. This 
 means the public can drive any speed 55 or under without breaking 
 the law when there is no minimum speed posted. If you are in such a 
 hurry, I suggest you leave earlier! Driving under the speed limit is 
 not a crime, but making false accusations is! I think Ill start 
 driving 35 mph on that stretch, just for you.

Hey Henry, in reference to last week&apos;s Hey Henry: Bruce Holmes has 
 various athletic leagues he sponsors for kids. The name of the 
 recreation center in Fairview is the Fairview Recreation Center. It 
 doesn&apos;t have Bruce Holmes in the title.

Hey Henry, why don&apos;t cops issue warnings for speeding anymore? I can 
 understand the need for speeding tickets every now and again. But my 
 gosh, it&apos;s getting crazy around here. (Ed. note: Those days are 
 gone).

Hey Henry, Re: the&quot;Take gap, Give Gap&quot;on the Square, It works 
 great for me, Don&apos;t Worry, Be Happy; Re:&quot;No Red Light&quot;at Lake Dow 
 and 81 East, there&apos;s one now. Don&apos;t Worry, Be Happy; Re:&quot;All the 
 People on Welfare&quot;, I feel so blessed I am not one of them and have 
 the good fortune and ability to assist those in need... Dont Worry, 
 Be Happy; Re:&quot;All the Rookie Cops&quot;I&apos;m glad there are young people 
 willing to go into this underpaid and underappreciated line of work 
 to protect and serve. Don&apos;t Worry, Be Happy!

Hey Henry, welfare was made to be a hand up not a handout or way of 
 life. If you continue to have kids while on welfare then yes, you 
 should be forced to use birth control until you can get your life in 
 order.

Hey Henry, can someone ask that cop who thought it was okay to hold 
 up traffic on Thurmond Rd. at 11:30 a.m. on January 19 to have a 
 conversation with someone, lights flashing to make us stop for him 
 and all, if that is common practice.
 
02.09.11

Hey Henry, thank you Henry County for taking over the recycling 
 center! On our visit today we found the drop off area clean, 
 well-organized and helpful staff in attendance. What a change! The 
 center had gotten so bad (trashy area, overflowing dumpsters, surly 
 staff) that we had almost decided to forego recycling rather than 
 deal with it.

Hey Henry, I commend the person who stated that schools are not 
 daycare centers and totally agree that if you can&apos;t afford daycare - 
 don&apos;t have kids. I don&apos;t understand why people want to have 3, 4, or 
 more children then stick them in daycare for the for the first five 
 years of their lives. What&apos;s the point? You miss all the&quot;firsts&quot;, 
 and someone else is teaching them THEIR beliefs, core values, and 
 outlook on life. How can you even have the nerve to suggest that 
 schools be open 7/24/365? It DOES NOT take a village to raise a 
 child. Stay home and raise your own kids and stop putting that 
 responsibility on everyone else.

Hey Henry, as a response to the Hey Henry about welfare recipients 
 being drug tested, I agree. If they have money to buy drugs they 
 don&apos;t need welfare.

Hey Henry, maybe we should quit worrying about what others are 
 wearing on their feet and instead worry about what comes out of our 
 mouths. Which one effects others the most?

Hey Henry, to all of you self-appointed Traffic Safety Officials, 
 the speed limit on 81 between Publix and 212 is 55 mph. Those of you 
 who think you are being safe by driving between 30 and 45 mph are 
 not. You are a nuisance and a danger to the public. Get in front of 
 me going that slow, and I will report you to the police as a drunk 
 driver. Happy driving.

Hey Henry, we now have a new Rec. Center in the Fairview area, which 
 is great, but it is named Bruce Holmes Athletic Association, why not 
 Fairview Athletic Association?

Hey Henry, just noticed the proposed strategic plan for Henry County 
 Schools on their website. Does it take a culture and climate focus 
 team to handle problems in our schools? All we need are 
 administrators and teachers that are able to uphold their moral 
 obligations to our children, and if they can&apos;t, they should be held 
 accountable for their actions.

Hey Henry, Yay! We hereby declare February 14th Henry County Flip 
 Flop Day! Lets start the season early this year for all of our 
 local admirers.

Hey Henry, to the people that constantly complain and disrespect the 
 Law Enforcement Officers - I am sure the majority of you make way 
 more than they do. If you ever wonder about how little they are 
 paid to risk their lives to keep you and your families safe, just 
 check out your Countys Board of Commissioners website. They are 
 not making a killing to risk getting killed for you.

Hey Henry, why were the new firing range plans for Stroud Rd. kept 
 so quiet? Doesn&apos;t look like anyone cares about the homeowners that 
 will have to deal with the noise, and believe me, the sounds will 
 carry.

Hey Henry, to the person that owns a truck and is responding in 
 reference to the gas guzzling SUV&apos;s, I do have a job and so does my 
 spouse. You must be one of those people that got a good job because 
 you are related to someone or you are a good friend. That is how it 
 works nowadays. Look at the Board of Education. There are people 
 that got hired on in maintenance because of the buddy system and are 
 making top dollar just to cut grass.
 
02.02.11

Hey Henry, it&apos;s getting close to that 
 time of year where everybody will start wearing their nasty flip 
 flops. I bet they can&apos;t wait! If you people only knew how many germs 
 your feet get on them wearing those trashy things.

Hey Henry, why not drug test all people who want or are on Welfare? 
 If you can&apos;t pass the test then you don&apos;t get the Welfare, because 
 if you have drugs in your system then where did you get the money 
 for them? If you have money for drugs then you have money to pay 
 your bills. Welfare was not put in place to be a life style - it was 
 put in place to help you between jobs and better yourself by getting 
 an education so you can get a job. No sympathy here.

Hey Henry, this is a special thank you to the HCPD and Sheriff&apos;s 
 Department and everyone that helped transport staff to Sacred 
 Journey Hospice during the recent snowstorm. Thank you to all who 
 helped us take care of our special patients.

Hey Henry, to the poster wondering if taxpayers were footing some of 
 the bill to send the Marching Mustangs to London. I can say 
 definitively that the answer is NO. Students are paying their own 
 way, and many students will not be going on the trip simply because 
 of the cost. Marching Band is an extracurricular activity that is 
 paid for by the students and parents, not the School Board. But, if 
 you are offering, I&apos;m sure the band would be happy to accept your 
 donation toward the trip.

Hey Henry, do we not have enough oil change places and gas stations 
 and for god sakes not another drug store down 81. We need something 
 good like a Chick-fil-A.

Hey Henry, I don&apos;t know who invented the car lights that are bright 
 blue and looks like someone has their brights on, but they need to 
 have a good kick in the ____.

Hey Henry, to the uneducated-about-crime person who made the comment 
 about HCPD rookie cops - you are clueless. We live in metro Atlanta. 
 Check out the crime stats. I sure hope that the widow of the 
 recently slain Georgia State Patrolman doesn&apos;t read the unfeeling 
 Hey Henry submission by you. You should hope that all police 
 officers, regardless of their time with the department, are using 
 every safety precaution necessary, including suspecting everyone of 
 being a criminal.

Hey Henry, did you see the police stopping all the traffic on the 
 Square so four people could cross from the courthouse. Who were 
 those people?

Hey Henry, please tell me I didn&apos;t read it right. On the Henry 
 County website did I read that the county is considering an&quot;adult 
 entertainment&quot;establishment?

Hey Henry, saw a posting at the 4th floor nurses station at Henry 
 Medical. It read,&quot;Focus for the month. Patient Care.&quot;

Hey Henry, this weather stinks!

Hey Henry, the&quot;give gap, take gap&quot;sign on the McDonough Square is 
 non-standard and goes against the AASHTO Highway Safety Manual, and 
 the most common interpretation of this mess violates at least two 
 state laws (three if you count unnecessary horn use). Unless you 
 have a trailer or are driving a bus, turn into your own lane (the 
 closest one, for those who slept through driver training) like the 
 pictorial sign and state law indicate, and merge in the remaining 
 240 feet of road before the next light. It&apos;s much more efficient, 
 especially if people have the courtesy to let you move over.
 
01.26.11

Hey Henry, all the news about Sonny Purdue and Mr. Deal just shows 
 that the state will be in worse shape than it has been in the past. 
 They are padding their pockets and the pockets of their buddies. I 
 hope all that voted for them and the crooked Republican party will 
 be happy. The kids and school system will suffer from the crooks 
 that have been elected. Furloughs and budget cuts. Please take care 
 of the school systems. Teachers and employees have taken the cuts to 
 pad their pockets.

Hey Henry, what about people who paid big money for their homes on 
 Rodgers Rd. and have to look at a contractors work materials in his 
 yard facing the street.

Hey Henry, to the person who said that the schools should be open 
 24/7/365, because you can&apos;t afford daycare. First of all, if you 
 cannot afford daycare you should have not had children. Second of 
 all, we are a school system not your personal daycare.... that is 
 why the children act the way they do, because the have no parental 
 supervision going on.

Hey Henry, regarding the 55 mph speed limit on Hwy 81, the traffic 
 has become more congested closer into town due to the increase in 
 population and businesses out that way. The 55 mph limit has become 
 outdated. The common sense approach would be to lower the busier 
 section of it to 45 mph.

Hey Henry, I am almost positive the City of McDonough&apos;s Mayor, 
 Council and Administration have been brain washed.

Hey Henry, Is it true that now that the OHS Marching Mustangs trip 
 was approved that us taxpayers are having to foot some of the bill?

Hey Henry, on Saturday the 22nd I was walking around the Square and 
 noticed that Christmas music is still playing. What&apos;s with that?

Hey Henry, I just want to say kudos to the person who commented on 
 the SUV gas guzzler. I personally drive a truck, (chevy 4x4), and 
 love it! I pay for the tag, insurance, and GAS. That being said, 
 maybe if the person complaining would spend more time and energy on 
 finding a job, they wouldn&apos;t care about how people with a job spend 
 their hard earned money.

Hey Henry, Mary Jane Owen can write anything she wants. That&apos;s why 
 it is called an Opinion Page!

Hey Henry, where is the American flag that was at Jonesboro Road 
 exit on I-75?

Hey Henry, There are many avid runners and cyclists in and around 
 the county. Please be respectful and courteous and slow down and/or 
 move over a bit for those people.

Hey Henry, Christmas is over. Please take your decorations down. If 
 you are unable to take them down, please stop turning them on! This 
 includes the City of Stockbridge!

Hey Henry, To the person who rarely gets sick and doesn&apos;t believe 
 you need health insurance, when you get a cold and it turns into 
 pneumonia and you end up in the hospital or you fall off your roof 
 cleaning your gutters and break your back don&apos;t go to the hospital 
 without insurance. Your bill will be astronomical. It only takes one 
 trip to run up a huge bill. If you aren&apos;t responsible enough to pay 
 for health insurance the rest of us shouldn&apos;t have to pay your 
 hospital bill.
 
01.19.11

Hey Henry, stop using the library system&apos;s woes as a whipping boy 
 for the whole financial picture in this current economic situation. 
 Your generalized anger should not be directed to people who are 
 doing their best under very dire circumstances.

Hey Henry, coming into the Square from Jonesboro Road, it would 
 resolve some of the traffic issues if you could make that right turn 
 and both lanes on Griffin Street were made left turn lanes at 
 Hampton Street?

Hey Henry, just thinking about a recent&quot;Hey Henry.&quot;If I have to 
 work to collect an&quot;unemployment check,&quot;it isn&apos;t an unemployment 
 check is it? Good idea though.

Hey Henry, shame on the Times for the&quot;slap&quot;for the people who made 
 the decision to close libraries and furlough staff. The slap should 
 have been delivered to the politicians who cut library funding. Why 
 is it so hard to understand that to be open, libraries must be 
 funded?

Hey Henry, for all of you folks who (like me) love your $19.95 per 
 year Magic Jack phone you should know that if you have to call 911 
 your call does not go to Henry County 911. It goes to a national&quot;call center&quot;and precious time will be wasted ... I learned this 
 the hard way when I thought there was a prowler in my yard at 3 a.m. 
 and called 911 for police. I had to hang up and dial directly to HC. 
 I suggest everyone have the direct line&apos;s number posted somewhere 
 near your phone. Direct line to HC 911 is 770-957-9121.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s happened already, several times. Accident after 
 accident on Hwy. 81 and Lake Dow Road. ... who thought it wise not 
 to install a traffic light there before opening the road? ... That 
 was a no-brainer right from the beginning. Duh! and I hate that 
 term.

Hey Henry, I do believe every Mustang in Henry County and every 
 pickup truck with dual mufflers live near Airline Road and 
 Kelleytown Road. Be considerate of the old folks that live around 
 that area. That is not a place for burnouts! There are four stop 
 signs there - please stop.

Hey Henry, crime in City Square Subdivision? Ten dwellings per acre? 
 Hey, build it and they will come!

Hey Henry, anyone of any age can use a library computer. Those under 
 16 have to be accompanied by a parent or guardian. The fact that 
 that&apos;s too much trouble for some people doesn&apos;t mean the libraries 
 should allow kids unfettered access to expensive equipment.

Hey Henry, you are&quot;slower traffic&quot;if someone wants to go faster 
 than you. Be courteous and get over!

Hey Henry, to the ignorant horses&quot;ice&quot;who stated,&quot;why don&apos;t we 
 look at cutting back on welfare and all those other programs that 
 give freebies to so many undeserving individuals... and Govt. forced 
 sterilization, etc ... I have so much significant and valid rebuttal 
 I don&apos;t know where to start. Every time I try to type I just find 
 myself frozen in utter disbelief that such self-righteous ignorance 
 still exists.

Hey Henry, last time I checked a Charter Cable subscription was not 
 compulsory. If you have a problem with them showing liquor 
 commercials call and CANCEL! Duh.

Hey Henry, it is really nice to have a new connection for Lake Dow 
 Road to Hwy. 81 E, but D.O.T should know it needs a light. I see 
 many traffic accidents for the near future.

 (Ed. Note) Below are our Hey Henry Snowmageddon specials
 
Hey Henry, for the past week most of us were fortunate to be home 
 with our families, cooking, watching movies, playing games, etc. We 
 see many Thank Yous to our Fire and Police as well as medical 
 staffers and they do deserve much more, but my hat is off to Ga 
 Power and EMC not only because they were all on call, but also 
 because very few lost power in our area. This is because of the work 
 they do all year not just during the storms when they are not home 
 with their families. So the next time you see one of these special 
 people, say thank you.

Hey Henry, McDonough Dialysis Center is extremely grateful to Henry 
 County Transit who opened their services on a snowy, icy day to get 
 patients to their lifesaving treatments. Their spirit of going above 
 and beyond was so deeply appreciated. And to the volunteers from the 
 McDonough United Methodist Church who filled in the transportation 
 gaps, you showed love in a tangible way in what felt like a helpless 
 situation. The people of Henry County take good care of needs in 
 their community.

Hey Henry, one good thing about the snow storm...everything comes to 
 a complete standstill and it&apos;s kind of nice to have to go back to 
 the way it once was ... neighbors coming outside to play in the 
 snow, talking to each other ... being forced to walk to where you 
 need to go, saying hello as you pass by. It was really nice seeing 
 people outside and visiting with each other and checking on each 
 other and helping out where needed, and so very nice not to hear 
 those loud mufflers. Enjoyed the four wheelers out and about - wish 
 everyone had snowmobiles! God Bless America.

Hey Henry, thank you, Luella Middle School teachers, for helping 
 your students stay on track with schoolwork during the snow/ice 
 storm. I appreciate the phone calls and emails.

Hey Henry, thank you Georgia DOT for sanding and salting the roads 
 and scraping the ice after the snowstorm. I don&apos;t know about 
 everyone else, but I am very appreciative of the hard work that you 
 did!

Hey Henry, I am appalled at the way Henry County and Clayton County 
 handled this snow/ice week. Monroe and Lamar Counties are rural 
 counties and they are back in school already. Has your departments 
 ever heard of salt and sand on the road before the ice/snow storm. 
 Enough warning was given from all the news stations. It&apos;s ridiculous 
 that these students are out of school 5 days because maintenance 
 can&apos;t get out in their dump trucks and dump salt, gravel and sand on 
 these roads. You ought to be ashamed of yourselves and we are paying 
 taxes on these roads for what reason?

Hey Henry, I loved all this snow and ice, hope it happens again 
 soon.

Hey Henry, to all who complain about the roads, whatever, all you 
 people were told to stay off the streets, but decided not to listen. 
 So all accidents are your problem, think insurance shouldn&apos;t pay for 
 anything. Peace Out.

&quot;Idiots to the right of me! Idiots to the left of me! Onto the 
 highway of death I drove from 400!&quot;Had to drive from Sandy Springs 
 Sunday night. The snow and sleet were no problem. It was all the 
 idiots the asylum let out onto the interstate. Driving 5 mph with 
 their flashers on, skidding sideways by Ga. Tech, and piling up 
 below the Braves Stadium. Once I got past the idiots, I clipped 
 along at 40 mph with no problem. Geez! I wonder what it would have 
 been like had there been 2&quot;of snow?
 
01.12.11

Hey Henry, Jack Webb on Dragnet always said,&quot;Just the facts, sir, 
 just the facts.&quot;Fact: Payroll taxes including unemployment is paid 
 by the library system, NOT the county.

Hey Henry, why has McDonough gotten to the point that they even need 
 protective glass at city hall. Think about it! I have. It really is 
 getting that bad.

Hey Henry, for the woman who is looking for the single men, what age 
 man are you looking for?

Hey Henry, to everyone complaining about the library hours, give it 
 a break. These services are a convenience to us, not a necessity. Be 
 thankful our emergency services and water are still being provided. 
 I frequent our local library, and have had to make some changes to 
 the times I go, but it&apos;s just part of the current economic 
 situation. Not everyone has a computer at home (or sometimes it&apos;s 
 not working) and it&apos;s great that we (and our school kids) have a 
 place to go to do what needs to be done. To those who work for our 
 library system, Thanks!

Hey Henry, I&apos;m not bashing HCPD, but some of these rookie cops are 
 ... disrespectful. Perhaps they can&apos;t see the forest for the trees 
 and everyone must be a criminal, even the ones who failed to signal, 
 didn&apos;t wear a seatbelt that one time, the occasional speeder. C&apos;mon, 
 you don&apos;t have to be ugly about it. Maybe we&apos;re not like Mayberry 
 anymore, but we ain&apos;t Jersey Shore either.

Hey Henry, because of the sleet and snow I can&apos;t get to work but the 
 WalMart employees better be at work. I can&apos;t drive 6 miles to work, 
 but I can make the 8 miles to Walmart with no problem! I just hope 
 the boss doesn&apos;t see me as I pass work!

Hey Henry, one has to be 18 to use the library computers, even on 
 Saturdays and Sundays. Most of the children in poor households would 
 already have graduated by the time they could use them. (Ed. note: 
 The policy states that with a signed parental waiver, children age 
 16 may use computers.)

Hey Henry, according to the current Georgia Driver&apos;s Manual&quot;A 
 yellow flashing light means you must slow down and exercise caution 
 before proceeding through the intersection. If I feel I need to 
 come to a complete stop in order to&quot;exercise caution&quot;then you&apos;ll 
 just have to live with it. And on a similar note when it comes to&quot;slower traffic keep right, if I&apos;m going the speed limit - I&apos;m not 
 slower traffic.

Hey Henry, why not make those collecting unemployment checks do 
 community service to EARN the paycheck they get. If they had to get 
 out and work for it then maybe they would look a little harder. I 
 have personally heard 3 people that are on unemployment say they can 
 make more staying home than getting a minimum wage job--shame on 
 you! I am a single mom working 2 jobs and I am tired of paying for 
 you to sit at home on your butt.

Hey Henry, the pictures of the nursing home visit on Woodland Middle 
 School&apos;s website were quite impressive. The elderly and the kids 
 both seemed to thoroughly enjoy one anothers company. The manicures 
 were awesome. Way to go WOLFPACK!

Hey Henry, I think the person who said,&quot;As you plan your parties, 
 dinners, etc. remember there are a lot of lonely, hurting people out 
 there that just need to know they are loved. Reach out and make 
 someone feel cared for. It truly is better to give than receive.&quot;Yes, it is, that was a really sweet vent. Nice to know some really 
 care!
 
01.05.11

Hey Henry, The Night Before Christmas poem about shelter dogs that 
 was printed in the Times Christmas edition brought tears to my eyes. 
 I am proud to live in a community where the animal shelter really 
 cares about animals. I visited the shelter for the first time today 
 and it was a great experience.

Hey Henry, I want to send a big thank you to all the people who 
 helped make the McDonough Square look so beautiful at Christmas. I 
 loved driving past there every day and seeing the beautiful lights 
 and decorations. This&quot;Yankee&quot;appreciates all your hard work!

Hey Henry, for those of you who do not like to look at feet that 
 probably means you have ugly feet. My wife takes very good care of 
 her feet, so her wearing flip-flops does not bother me at all. 
 Telling someone not to wear flip-flops is like telling someone to 
 not wear short sleeves during winter or long sleeves during summer. 
 It is called&quot;Human Rights.&quot;

Hey Henry, I think it is terrible that someone stole a van in the 
 parking lot at the Stockbridge Wal-Mart. The van is for a 
 handicapped person. Now, they have nothing. You should be ashamed.

Hey Henry, it would be nice and safe if Peach Drive werent like the 
 autobahn. Slow down, please. There&apos;s a school, hospice and a lot of 
 nice people who live there. A little police radar might also be a 
 good idea, especially around 7:30 a.m.

Hey Henry, all I&apos;ve got to say is that stop signs are for stopping, 
 open freeways are for driving, and yellow lights are for caution.

Hey Henry, is there any truth to the rumor that in order to start a 
 business in McDonough, one must pay an&quot;impact fee&quot;of around 
 $5,000? People, we need the economy to rebound, not stifle it!

Hey Henry, where are all the hot, single men in Henry County? It&apos;s 
 cold and I&apos;m lonely!

Hey Henry, kudos to the Henry County Police and Sheriff&apos;s Department 
 on all the work they did to take $1.6 M of drugs and weapons off the 
 streets of Henry County. Good Job!

Hey Henry, where is the recession in Henry County? I sure haven&apos;t 
 seen it. Folks shop til they drop and eat out constantly. When 
 exactly do they work?

Hey Henry, to those who enjoy smashing our mailboxes, please use 
 that energy and time to volunteer to help those less fortunate.

Hey Henry, you say to stay at home when I have a bad cough, 
 congestion, or chills; but my boss says if I do not come to work to 
 teach your children I will be fired (of course, I wouldn&apos;t be sick 
 at all, if your kids would stay home when sick, would I?).

Hey Henry, congratulations to the students and alumni of Ola High 
 School who are now members of Spirit of Atlanta drum and bugle 
 corps! This is an amazing opportunity for these kids, and I wish 
 them well.

Hey Henry, what is going on at Lake Dow Rd. and Hwy. 81 East? It is 
 another accident waiting to happen, since there have already been 
 accidents there. Where is the light?

Hey Henry, just how many geese are crossing the new East Lake 
 Extension? Seems the county could easily save a few dollars by not 
 posting unnecessary signs.
 
12.29.10

Hey Henry, from Butts County. I want you to know how much I enjoy 
 reading The Times. I am always glad to see the writings by Jimmy 
 Cochran and Brenda DeLauder. Keep telling how great God is!

Hey Henry, has the City of Stockbridge stopped enforcing the sign 
 law on the right-of-way in front of businesses on Hwy. 42 and 138? 
 It looks like we have been annexed into Clayton County.

Hey Henry, a special thank you to the honest lady who found my 
 wallet in the parking lot at the station on E. Atlanta Road and 
 brought it to my door.

Hey Henry, thank you so much for the house on Bridges Drive with the 
 beautiful light display. But mainly, thank you for putting up the 
 birthday cake for Jesus. It shows the reason for Christmas and 
 brightens up our street.

Hey Henry, thank you to the Henry County and Hampton police for 
 doing such a good job catching the two men who robbed the BP in 
 Hampton two weeks ago. Thank you guys for a job well done. We 
 wouldnt know what we would do without you.

Hey Henry, its a new year! Time to clean up every aspect of your 
 life, including intellectually. Have a mental yard sale; you won&apos;t 
 make much, but you&apos;ll feel better!

Hey Henry, instead of cutting back on our social security, why don&apos;t 
 we look at cutting back on welfare and all those other programs that 
 give freebie&apos;s to so many undeserving individuals. If women and men 
 want to stay on welfare, they should be allowed one child, at the 
 most, two. If they are not at a point of self sufficiency by the 
 second pregnancy, then after the child is born the mothers tubes 
 should be tied. Then the government needs to go after their own and 
 start cutting their overpaid incomes and outlandish expenses.

Hey Henry, while we are on the subject of dangerous intersections, 
 how about addressing Hwy. 81 and Racetrack Road that everybody south 
 of the Square seems to turn down every morning backing traffic up 
 for 10 miles. Can&apos;t you people find an alternate route?

Hey Henry, why is it that you never see a skinny person riding 
 around in a hoverround? Because the hoverround was designed for 
 those who lounged around so much they got too fat to move 
 themselves. No, this is NOT for those of you who have a medical 
 reason for using a hoverround; it IS, however, directed at those of 
 you who are lazy, overweight and a contributor to our obesity issue 
 in this country.

Hey Henry, 8U LG Lady Dawgs - we love you and you are the best. What 
 a first class softball team! Be proud of who you are and what you 
 represent. You are loved by many.

Hey Henry, green means go!

Hey Henry, those poor dogwood trees on Jonesboro Rd need to come 
 down - it&apos;s tree planting time, can we get some new ones?

Hey Henry, is anything going to be done about the crime in City 
 Square Subdivision? There have been two separate shootings in my 
 neighborhood in the last two months. These shootings apparently 
 don&apos;t make the news, and as a homeowner I am appalled. If it is 
 happening here, it wont be long till it spreads over the county. I 
 paid $115,000 to live in McDonough, and the city should be doing 
 something about this. And trust me, if we could sell our house, we 
 would be out of here as quick as possible!
 
12.22.10

Hey Henry, kudos to the Atlanta Festival Ballet for their 
 outstanding production of The Nutcracker! It was magical.

Hey Henry, we really don&apos;t need a gas station or development at 
 every intersection.

Hey Henry, I really love the vintage looking, singing snowmen on 
 Sloan Street. I wave every morning as I pass them.

Hey Henry, has the state passed a law that turn signals and lane 
 change signals are not allowed anymore?

Hey Henry, Mary Jane Owen can write anything she wants. That&apos;s why 
 it is called an Opinion page.

Hey Henry, does anyone else have the feeling that the wealth of this 
 country is being swiped right before our eyes?

Hey Henry, and we wonder why we get sick... people licking their 
 fingers when passing papers? Uh-huh, there&apos;s your answer.

Hey Henry, to all you Yankees - if you want to live in Henry County 
 in peace, you need to learn not to tell people where you are from 
 and learn a country accent. Ha-ha-ha, Imma go now, see ya later!

Hey Henry, I&apos;ll be glad when they finish working on the intersection 
 of Hudson Bridge and Flippen Road.
\
Hey Henry, it is cold now, so put up your nasty flip flops so people 
 don&apos;t have to look at your ugly feet!

Hey Henry, let&apos;s thank our Henry County teachers for the job that 
 they do teaching our children. Show them the respect and kindness 
 they deserve.

Hey Henry, way to go City of McDonough! You work on bringing adult 
 entertainment to the city while at the same time doing all you can 
 to push a church out of the Square. At least youve got your 
 priorities straight.

Hey Henry, thanks to all the good people of the county who are 
 engaged in charitable work. I am not always able to participate 
 first hand, as I&apos;d like to, so I give donations. I want to thank all 
 of you who are out there doing the actual work.

Hey Henry, every house between McDonough to Jonesboro to Lovejoy is 
 sitting on a battlefield. The whole area was a battlefield. Look at 
 your historic town maps and get educated.

Hey Henry, what has happened to the Santas around the community? 
 They are short on hair and beard. Santa should have long hair and 
 beard. Happy Holidays, all!

Hey Henry, Our water rates are going up? During the Great Recession? 
 Are you kidding me?

Hey Henry, for those who feel the McDonough City Hall&apos;s new image is 
 bothersome, then do everyone a favor and mail your payment in, or 
 drop it off in the drop box. I am not sure which world you are 
 living in, but the world in which everyone else lives agrees that 
 preventive measures are necessary. By the way, there are more than 
 two employees behind that protective glass.

Hey Henry, I walk into my den and my children are watching a program 
 on Charter Cable about liquor and wine with a commercial showing 
 hard liquor. Thanks Charter. You&apos;re providing a real community 
 service for our children.
 
12.15.10

Hey Henry, give a great gift to your library! Visit the&quot;wishing 
 trees&quot;at any Henry County library and purchase a book off the tree. 
 Your donation can be made in honor of someone you love.

Hey Henry, could the Board of Education give math textbooks back to 
 the students? Taking their books is not helping them achieve.

Hey Henry, a special thanks to the taxpayers of Clayton and Fayette 
 Counties for keeping their libraries open. This Henry County person 
 sure appreciates being able to use them at convenient hours.

Hey Henry, let&apos;s go back to&quot;old school&quot;and remember what our 
 momma&apos;s and grandmomma&apos;s taught us about manners. If it&apos;s not yours 
 - don&apos;t touch it; ask for permission, not forgiveness;&quot;yes, 
 please&quot;-&quot;no thank you&quot;; hold the door open for those behind you; 
 treat others as you wish to be treated... it&apos;s not that hard, 
 really.

Hey Henry, Mary Jane Owen is obviously an old scrooge to make such 
 disparaging comments about Christmas letters in her latest column. I 
 love to receive Christmas letters and appreciate that friends take 
 the time to write about the happenings in their lives and send it in 
 a Christmas card.

Hey Henry, I rarely ride a motorcycle so why should I buy motorcycle 
 insurance? I rarely drive a boat so why should I buy boat insurance? 
 I rarely get sick so why should I buy health insurance?

Hey Henry, Christmas is a time for giving. A Salvation Army employee 
 said over 150 churches in the Southern Crescent were contacted and 
 asked if they could send volunteers to ring the bells around town 
 for the Salvation Army. One church replied no, one replied yes and 
 the others didn&apos;t reply. Please don&apos;t pass by those red kettles 
 without dropping in something and saying&quot;Thank You&quot;for taking care 
 of those in need this year!

Hey Henry, I hope we have a white Christmas! I just love snow, don&apos;t 
 ya&apos;ll?

Hey Henry, tell Georgia Power to quit spending millions of dollars 
 each year on meaningless TV and print ads, then perhaps it wont 
 need so many rate hikes. It&apos;s not like their customers have a choice 
 in where they get their electric service. Don&apos;t wait until the hikes 
 go into effect, voice your objections to the PSC now.

Hey Henry, to the person commenting about people who drive large gas 
 sucking SUV&apos;s, who did not understand how people can afford them. 
 There are still a few people who get up every morning and go to work 
 to earn an honest living instead of waiting for a government hand 
 out.

Hey Henry, I would like to thank the firemen of Station 13 for 
 coming to my house and providing and installing a smoke detector for 
 me. Henry County Firemen are the best!

Hey Henry, if you need help and dial 9-1-1, don&apos;t be rude to the 
 operator. Make YOUR emergency and OUR job easier by listening to us 
 and answering our questions. Also, when we ask you to hold on...you 
 are not actually on hold. The operator may be in the process of 
 dispatching fire, EMS, or police to another call. We do several 
 things at once; please be patient. Your cooperation will be greatly 
 appreciated.
 
12.08.10

Hey Henry, the speed limit on Hwy 81 is 55 mph from the Newton 
 county line until just beyond McDonald&apos;s near town. I know that most 
 of the time you can&apos;t drive that fast due to traffic congestion, but 
 at 4:30 a.m. there just isn&apos;t that much traffic and it&apos;s a pain to 
 follow a string of traffic behind someone going 45 mph. Have a heart 
 and speed up. Some of us are trying to get to work in Atlanta. All 
 I&apos;m asking is to do close to the speed limit. Thanks!

Hey Henry, for those who feel City Hall&apos;s new image is bothersome 
 then do everyone a favor and mail your payment in or drop it off in 
 the drop off box. I am not sure which world you are living in but 
 the world in which everyone else lives in agrees that preventive 
 measures are necessary. By the way, there are more than two 
 employees behind that protective glass.

Hey Henry, stop ragging on Nash Farm. Every house between McDonough 
 to Jonesboro to Lovejoy is sitting on a battlefield. The whole area 
 was a battlefield. Look at your historic town maps, get educated. 
 Just because someone wants to preserve a piece of it does not make 
 it any less than what it is. At least its not covered with houses 3 
 feet apart. And by the way, I am a Nash.

Hey Henry, interesting that the TEA Party, that supposedly&quot;racist&quot;organization, has now put more blacks in Congress than have been 
 there in recent history.

Hey Henry, it is not only the teachers who have furlough days, the 
 custodians, office workers, parapros etc. all have 8 days off 
 without pay. Most people do not realize they have not had a raise in 
 3 years and make about 1/4 the money teachers make.

Hey Henry, I wonder how much McDonough clears off the parking meters 
 after they pay the meter man&apos;s salary.

Hey Henry, I know first hand that the lap band really works because 
 my daughter participates in Dr. Gorgalas lap band program.

Hey Henry, I would just like to know why some people have to always&quot;be a hatin on people. Is it necessary? Think about it.

Hey Henry, I would like to know if our votes are counted here or are 
 outsourced to another country and who counts them. I don&apos;t think 
 anybody has ever thought of that. We vote at electronic ballot 
 boxes, but we don&apos;t know where the vote goes. I just wonder if our 
 votes stay in America?

Hey Henry, I am a Henry County Senior Citizen. I lost my purse on 
 Jonesboro Road near McDonough. A wonderful young man returned it to 
 my home and in the stress of losing it and the excitement of having 
 it returned I did not get his complete name. I want to thank him 
 from the bottom of my heart and I know that his honesty will prove 
 to be a great thing for him in the future. Thanks so much to a fine 
 young man!

Hey Henry, to the lady in the black truck at the pediatrician&apos;s 
 office on Tuesday who signed in 4 kids for one appintment, parked in 
 the handicap parking spot and then left your children there to go 
 get food to eat while you wait, I just want to say it must be nice 
 to not have to follow the rules.

Hey Henry, let&apos;s thank our Henry County Teachers for the job that 
 they do teaching our Children. Let&apos;s show them the respect and 
 kindness they deserve!

Hey Henry, The protective glass in City Hall is there to protect the 
 employees so get over it!
 
12.01.10

Hey Henry, you have no idea how much I enjoy reading on the computer 
 what is going on in Henry County. You have so many things that I 
 look forward to reading about out here in Garland, Texas. I get 
 homesick every time I think about McDonough. Please keep doing what 
 you are doing...Mary Ann Barnette

Hey Henry, let&apos;s keep the schools open 24/7/365. A lot of households 
 can&apos;t afford babysitters.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s interesting how you say,&quot;Hey Henry is our own 
 little vent section. Read others&apos; vents, and post one of your own. 
 You&apos;ll never look at life the same way again.&quot;The reason we may 
 never look at life the same way again is because some people are 
 being rude. For example, a few weeks ago, someone posted a vent 
 saying that we shouldn&apos;t breathe aka die. Yeah, that&apos;s really nice. 
 Not!

Hey Henry, *big girl panties up* ahh... better.

Hey Henry, Henry County Police Department, you are the greatest! 
 What a great job you do. Thanks to all of you, including the support 
 staff. I love Henry County.

Hey Henry, I was shocked when I went to our nice McDonough City Hall 
 and found that ugly glass cage to protect the office that has two 
 people out front. It reminds me of a liquor store on Stewart Ave. 
 Looks to me like someone is paranoid. Our little town image is gone.

Hey Henry, I appreciate learning that&quot;Mack Donna&quot;came before&quot;Mick 
 Dunna&quot;. Since language is a living thing, the changing pronunciation 
 may simply mean we are living and growing. Thank goodness! I&apos;ll be 
 sure to use&quot;Mick Dunna&quot;from now on.

Hey Henry, true that to the different types of restaurants! Love 
 the idea!

Hey Henry, admittedly, it hasn&apos;t been a major concern, but in the 18 
 years I&apos;ve lived in Henry County I can&apos;t remember the libraries 
 being open on Sundays.

Hey Henry, so Georgia Power is about to get yet another rate 
 increase. I think our Public Service Commission should say&quot;NO&quot;every time. Georgia Power can make salary cuts and benefit cuts like 
 every other corporation in this country. Folks, it is time to get 
 mad and start letting elected officials hear from us. When you see 
 this increase on your power bills in Jan. or Feb. let the Public 
 Service Commission know how you feel.

Hey Henry, to the person who is taking the&quot;Mack Donna&quot;comment to 
 be framed at Michaels. Why not take it to Scandinavian Custom 
 Framing on the Square instead? You&apos;d be supporting a local business 
 and you&apos;d save money. Guaranteed!

Hey Henry,&quot;We moved from [fill in the blank] to get away from noise 
 and traffic. Now we want to keep our neighborhood quiet. We don&apos;t 
 want any more development near us.&quot;I hear this sentiment quite 
 often -- ironically, from the very people who brought the 
 development along with them.&quot;Retail follows rooftops.&quot;May I 
 suggest we work to improve development, not prevent it?

Hey Henry, to the lady who said we needed more types of restaurants 
 and different cultures. She must be a shut-in, because right around 
 here in the city limits we have Japanese, Chinese, Caribbean, 
 Italian, Greek and Mexican.

Hey Henry, I want the city to turn the lights off in the new parking 
 deck on the weekends and pave the roads with the money saved. The 
 lights are on 24/7 and I only see one car in there.
 
11.24.10

Hey Henry, just because you have a family member who has a 
 handicapped parking permit, it doesn&apos;t give you the right to use it 
 when the person is not with you.

Hey Henry, I just want to thank the police officer who pulled me 
 over and told me I had no brake or tail lights last Friday. We would 
 have been traveling at night the next day in that car, which could 
 have been very dangerous. There are police who are really there to 
 protect and serve regardless of what many think.

Hey Henry, kudos and bravo to the mastermind behind the&quot;Henry 
 County FAIL Parking&quot;page on Facebook. All you people who are 
 totally inconsiderate when you park your cars beware, as your 
 inconsiderate parking may show up in a photo on the Internet for the 
 whole world to see.

Hey Henry, just want to say how much fun it was seeing the huge cow 
 in our front yard on November 21. Thank you to our neighbors who 
 pulled into the driveway and enjoyed this anomaly with us. Sorry we 
 failed to introduce ourselves; we were just so excited about that 
 beautiful cow.

Hey Henry, for those who get ticketed while shopping on the Square, 
 why not have an appeal procedure in which the ticketed person can 
 show their store and/or restaurant receipts with date and time? Who 
 wouldn&apos;t want to park and shop in our town if they had such recourse 
 in case the time in the parking meter runs out? The City could even 
 set a grace period (30, 45 minutes?) past the time of the ticket if 
 the receipts submitted proved patronage in the Square.

Hey Henry, Luella High School has top notch Fine Arts classes, 
 teachers, and activities. The theatre department&apos;s production of&quot;OrphanTrains&quot;was outstanding. I was moved by the stories and actually learned 
 something about the history of our nation.

Hey Henry, someone at a local restaurant took the liberty of filling 
 in the tip space for us after we left. The tip was almost as much as 
 the bill was. I didn&apos;t think to mark through the tip space with a 
 pen and we left them a big tip in cash. I&apos;m thankful I kept the 
 receipt. Be aware.

Hey Henry, the Thanksgiving and Christmas holidays are upon us. As 
 you plan your parties, dinners, etc. remember there are a lot of 
 lonely, hurting people out there that just need to know they are 
 loved. Reach out and make someone feel cared for. It truly is better 
 to give than receive.

Hey Henry, I say we take all of the computers out of public 
 libraries, period. We don&apos;t have an obligation to pay for anybody&apos;s 
 internet connections. These libraries are starting to look like 
 internet cafes instead of places to check out books. No wonder we 
 can&apos;t afford to keep libraries open anymore!

Hey Henry, well, the cold weather&apos;s here and to all those that 
 wanted it to come...guess what? No more home grown tomatoes! Thanks 
 to the tomato man out on Turner Church Road for those delicious 
 tomatoes he grows. They&apos;re the best I&apos;ve ever tasted and I can&apos;t 
 wait to buy some more from you next summer....awww, that seems so 
 far away.

Hey, Henry, all you hear these days is furloughs and job cuts. I 
 would like to know, where is all this stimulus money that the 
 counties are supposed to get. Is it going into the pockets of the 
 high paid crooks?
 
11.17.10

Hey Henry, where was this tough-talking, no-nonsense President Bush 
 during the eight years he was in office?

Hey Henry, thank you, John, for saying so eloquently those things 
 that we want our politicians to understand.

Hey Henry, we desperately need a traffic light on 42 and Locust 
 Road.....cars come over that hill like race cars. We have precious 
 kids on our school buses that make a left from Locust Road onto 42.

Hey Henry, so proud of my alma mater for the love and tribute the HC 
 Warhawk football players extended to Coach Gralls family at his 
 funeral. They are a fine group of young men Coach Grall would be 
 proud.

Hey Henry, McDonough City Council elections happen in 2011. 
 Positions pending election are: 1 - CM at large; 1 CM District 3 and 
 1 CM District 4. Now is the time to watch the process and pay 
 attention to issues that will come to vote. The Council is 
 developing the 2011 Budget and will discuss if a tax increase is 
 appropriate. Everything voted on effects your home, business, your 
 economic growth or your health and welfare. Get involved.

Hey Henry, can we borrow Gwinnett county D.A. Danny Porter and his 
 grand jury to look into some of our county transactions?

Hey Henry, this is to all of you haters. At least some people care 
 enough about their community to want to help improve it.

Hey Henry, from the 2009 deer dad to the two ladies who did not 
 check on my daughter last year after she savagely attacked a deer 
 with her car on Crumbley Road, all is well. The car had a lot of 
 damage but was fixable, However, it is that season again...so, deer, 
 beware. Next time ladies, check on the human.

Hey Henry, the Veterans Day ceremony at the Veterans Wall of Honor 
 in Heritage Park was a wonderful tribute to all who have served, are 
 currently serving, and those who have died to protect the freedoms 
 we enjoy each and every day in this wonderful country. Thanks to 
 everyone involved in making the day so special and thanks again to 
 all of the men and women of our Armed Forces. GOD BLESS AMERICA, 
 LAND THAT I LOVE!

Hey Henry, to the reader who says&quot;let&apos;s leave the corner of Hwy 155 
 and Millers Mill Road alone,&quot;I&apos;ll bet you don&apos;t own that property. 
 And I&apos;m willing to bet the families that own it have paid property 
 taxes on it for generations. I don&apos;t understand why people think 
 they have the right to tell others what to do with their land.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s just awful to think that our county is turning into 
 trash like the neighboring counties. McDonough has been on the news 
 almost everyday this past week for recent crimes in the city! Is it 
 too late to take back what has been a quiet peaceful place to live 
 in the past? I hope not. However I will be getting a permit to carry 
 and wont be a victim next time!

Hey Henry, restaurants of different cultures? Yes, how nice would 
 that be? But, YOU have to SUPPORT them, and that does not mean only 
 going in once a year. People in Henry county don&apos;t even seem to 
 appreciate live music, how can you expect them to appreciate 
 different foods.
 
11.10.10

 Hey Henry, I 
 challenge you to commit a random act of kindness.

 Hey Henry, kudos 
 to the person who wrote that our town&apos;s name is pronounced&quot;Mack 
 Donna,&quot;not&quot;Mick Dunna.&quot;I am actually going to cut out the Hey 
 Henry section, highlight that comment, and take it to Michael&apos;s to 
 be framed.

 Hey Henry, I 
 think we should have a few different types of restaurants in Henry 
 County that reflect different cultures from other countries; like 
 German and Indian. You may be surprised and actually like it. In 
 Henry County, we mainly just have plain old American fast food.... 
 not that there is anything wrong with that.

 Hey Henry, please 
 let the reader who lives off Jackson Lake Road and who wishes to 
 thank me for picking up trash along that road know that receiving a 
 fresh clean orange jumpsuit from the county each morning is thanks 
 enough.

 Hey Henry, don&apos;t 
 you think it is time to give us our libraries back on Sat. and Sun.? 
 Not every child&apos;s household is able to afford a computer and pay for 
 internet services. In this day and age our children need computers 
 for much of their schoolwork.

 Hey Henry, the 
 elections are over, please clean up all of the campaign signs!

 Hey Henry, to the 
 woman at the Lake Dow Publix, when you are walking behind a car that 
 is backing up, and the car is in between two SUVs, it is also your 
 responsibility to make sure the driver sees you. Next time, instead 
 of screaming obscenities, why not try helping them to back out.

 Hey Henry, I&apos;ll 
 be glad when this road construction around Flippen and Hudson Bridge 
 is over.

 Hey Henry, ever 
 stop and think,&quot;is it really that big of a deal?&quot;How blessed are 
 we that we have the opportunity to bicker back and forth with one 
 another over such insignificant topics. Have a wonderful week.

 Hey Henry, it is 
 sad that I can&apos;t go to the McDonough Walmart without being 
 approached by someone asking for money, fundraising, or just plain 
 begging. It is really affecting our quality of life here.

 Hey Henry, the 
 closer you ride my bumper, the slower I tend to go. If you are going 
 to run into the back of my car, I want to be going slow enough to 
 make sure I don&apos;t die.

 Hey Henry, this 
 past weekend, I witnessed what people are supposed to be like when I 
 attended the Team Maddie Softball/Baseball Tournament at Warren 
 Holder Park. Maddie is 7 years old with Stage 4 Neuroblastoma and 
 lives in Ola. Many people braved the cold to spend all weekend at 
 the ballpark raising money for her and raised over $20,000. To 
 witness people working together for a common good cause is so rare 
 these days and although I don&apos;t personally know Maddie Briscoe and 
 her family, I LOVED what we all did.

 Hey Henry, all 
 I&apos;ve got to say is bada-boom, baby!

 Hey Henry, some 
 people really do need to pull their&quot;big girl panties&quot;up... I&apos;m 
 just saying.

Hey Henry, Do we 
 really need a gas station or development at every intersection in 
 the county? Let&apos;s leave Miller&apos;s Mill and Hwy. 155 alone.
 
11.03.10

Hey Henry, the 
 well-meaning Future Land Use Map and related zoning restrictions are 
 very frustrating to local property owners, are keeping a lot of 
 local people unemployed, and are suppressing tax revenues in the 
 County. If you believe a property should be&quot;preserved as a rural 
 area,&quot;then save your money, buy the property; preserve it as a 
 rural area, and your private property rights will be respected 
 accordingly. 

Hey Henry, if you 
 are sick and coughing and sneezing, I really feel for you. I hope 
 you get better soon. But stay home.

Hey Henry, Mary 
 Jane Owen - Your article was right on! Oh, if only the young folks 
 of today had the training you and I had. Honesty and respect for 
 each and every one of us is mandatory.

Hey Henry, just 
 because the southbound lane of Hwy. 42 turns into 2 lanes after you 
 get out of Locust Grove towards Butts County doesn&apos;t mean you need 
 to speed up and go 70 mph. It is extremely dangerous just to pull 
 out of Barnes Station subdivision.

Hey Henry, yellow 
 flashing traffic lights ALWAYS mean proceed with caution, NEVER 
 stop.

Hey Henry, a friend 
 of mine put $2 in the Squares parking meter; She ate at Gritz 
 (spent money) she then went to one of the shops that sells the 
 handbags (spent money). Most people like to browse and take their 
 time when shopping and the meters are unforgiving. We need a city 
 ordinance that states $2.00 max and if your time expires you must 
 show a receipt from one of the local shops to be forgiven by the 
 Greed Monkey who thought it was a good idea to install these useless 
 meters. Or we can run on down to the big box stores and let the 
 Square remain as a ghost town.

Hey Henry, I live 
 off Jackson Lake Road and want to thank the person who always walks 
 down that road picking up trash everyday. If you see him next time, 
 thank him for keeping our road clean.

Hey Henry for the 
 last 2 weeks someone has had something to say about our teachers. To 
 the one who said they needed to pull up their big girl panties, that 
 was not a nice thing to say. The reason they say anything about the 
 furlough days is because that is money they can use for the kids in 
 their classes. I don&apos;t know where the parents think that money comes 
 from... You might be shocked if you knew what was spent to make 
 sure the children had what they needed in class and for special 
 occasions. I will say that I can&apos;t believe that, at a school that 
 has over 600 students, the teachers all had to work the Fall 
 Festival because they couldn&apos;t get enough parents to help.

Hey Henry, I wish 
 folks would quit licking their fingers before picking something up, 
 and then handing it to me. Im just saying....

Hey Henry, I hate 
 to disappoint the people who think you can fake a moon landing, kill 
 a president or a princess, or bring down two skyscrapers without 
 anyone finding out. Henry Countys conspiracy nuts can always 
 explain away mountains of evidence, (that disproves their own 
 theories). It&apos;s funny now how their actions have exposed them as 
 being the actual conspiracy.

 Hey 
 Henry, this&quot;whiney&quot;teacher would also be ok with 2 furlough days 
 but the 8 we&apos;ll actually have are a lot. I&apos;d like the writer to 
 spend a day in my classroom and then tell me I&apos;m paid too much. 
 
10.27.10

Hey Henry, I think the Henry Players should do the Rocky Horror 
 Picture Show as one of their next musicals.

Hey Henry, those of us who grew up here know that our town&apos;s name is 
 pronounced&quot;Mack Donna,&quot;not&quot;Mick Dunna.&quot;

Hey Henry, we at the Veterans Wall of Honor Preservation Committee 
 would like to thank everyone who set up and came out to shop at the 
 Huge Yard Sale at Heritage Park. It made the day a success for the 
 upkeep of the Wall.

Hey Henry, I was saddened to hear the &apos;not guilty&apos; verdict by the 
 jurors in Henry County regarding the death of young Ryan Gilliam 
 last year. Did our DA lose the case, or is no one held responsible 
 for their actions anymore. Ryan was buried, and the man on trial 
 went home to his family. What happened?

Hey Henry, why do you change your baby&apos;s diaper and throw it down in 
 the parking lot? I can&apos;t believe you are that lazy.

Hey Henry, I&apos;m so sick of hearing teachers complain about furlough 
 days. Do they think they are the only ones affected by today&apos;s 
 economy? We are all being hit hard! You don&apos;t hear other people 
 complaining all the time about taking pay cuts and no pay increases 
 for the past three years. I&apos;d be glad to take a day or two without 
 pay. Put on your big girl pants and deal with it.

Hey Henry, it could be worse, you could live in Clayton County.

Hey Henry, let&apos;s keep Kelleytown and the rest of Henry County clean 
 and beautiful.

Hey Henry, kudos to the motorists who got out of their cars after a 
 big storm and removed a tree that had fallen across Jonesboro Road, 
 opening the road again. I&apos;m a senior was not able to help. That&apos;s 
 citizenship in action.

Hey Henry, the word SPLOST has a&quot;T&quot;on the end. Not an&quot;H&quot;. Quit 
 saying SPLOSH! You&apos;re driving me crazy.

Hey Henry, the house on Jonesboro Road in McDonough looks awesome. 
 The person who isn&apos;t in the Halloween spirit should drive another 
 way if he doesnt like it. There are lots of us who do!

Hey Henry, I found a seashell in my yard. According to&quot;Nash Farm 
 Logic,&quot;that makes my yard a beach, right?

Hey Henry, what a beautiful day on the McDonough Square for the 
 chili cook off. However, I was very hurt when someone stole my 
 Minolta Digital Camera. It had a card full of pictures that cannot 
 be replaced. I am praying that the person who took the camera would 
 find it in their heart to return the card from the camera to The 
 Next Level Church. You can just mail the card without a return 
 address to The Next Level Church 4030 East Lake Parkway McDonough, 
 GA 30253.

Hey Henry, I have the utmost respect for our senior citizens, 
 however, just being over the age of 65 does not give you the right 
 to park in the handicapped spot.

Hey Henry, I want to thank the lady who feeds the cats at the 
 Provisions BP station off of Highway 20. We need more people in the 
 world like her. She takes time out of her day and money out of her 
 pocket to feed animals in need.

Hey Henry, in response to the&quot;transplanted northerners&quot;who can go 
 back to where they came from. Why would we want to? We are 
 considered geniuses here.
 
10.20.10

Hey Henry, we are so glad the dangerous and, dare I say, moronic, 
 intersection at Hwy. 81 and Lake Dow Rd. is FINALLY being addressed.

Hey Henry, yep, I sure am proud of my gas-guzzling SUV. Ain&apos;t it 
 pretty?

Hey Henry, we need to rid our beautiful city of all of the&quot;panhandlers&quot;asking for money at every intersection by our retail 
 stores. Although many are good causes.....many are not...

Hey Henry, Son of a Greek Pizza has good honest people working 
 there. If you have a chance stop by. They returned a very special 
 ring that I thought I had lost forever. Thank you!

Hey Henry, as a teacher I was offended when asked to put ourselves 
 in the students&apos; shoes. Put yourself in our shoes; we spend our own 
 money for supplies, absorb furlough days which shorten the school 
 year, pay increased insurance costs, deal with larger class sizes, 
 all with little or no support from parents. Try looking in the 
 mirror and see what you can do. Provide supplies for your child. Do 
 homework and study WITH them. Address discipline at home--don&apos;t put 
 it off on others. Teachers work many hours before and after the 
 school day to provide the best education possible for each student. 
 I, personally, teach 140 students and it is unrealistic to expect us 
 to develop individual lessons for each student.

Hey Henry, the code enforcement in this county needs to get their 
 act together. I put up my yard sale signs, only to be told they 
 couldn&apos;t be put within so many feet of the road, yet they are all 
 over every road in the county. I put my signs up after you passed 
 thru my area, and guess what- I took mine down in a timely manner. 
 If you want to give out citations, give it to the owners of the 
 signs that are up 3 days after their yard sale is over. Don&apos;t 
 penalize the responsible residents who are just trying to make a 
 little extra money.

Hey Henry, if someone told you to jump off a bridge, would you? No! 
 So, breathe in, breathe out, and repeat.

Hey Henry, maybe if all you&quot;Hey Henry&quot;haters quit knocking people, 
 we could have a more peaceful community, a community where people 
 want others to breathe.

Hey Henry, why do my kids have to be terrified every time we drive 
 past 92 Jonesboro Road just outside of the Square? When did 
 Halloween become about decorating your yard with zombies, severed 
 limbs, and decapitated heads. Have some consideration for the small 
 children who have to drive by your house every day.

Hey Henry, you know what really aggravates me? When someone doesn&apos;t 
 take up their&quot;yard/garage sale&quot;signs. I have driven many miles 
 following signs only to reach a dead end - either they have already 
 closed for the day or the sale was the previous weekend. Please be 
 considerate to others.

Hey Henry, if the Henry County Board of Education is not really 
 awarding kids at their monthly meetings for going to state level or 
 beyond on their projects they should take it off of their webpage.

Hey Henry, to all the transplanted Northerners down here who think 
 the South is slow, stupid, etc. - the road that brought you down 
 from that&quot;great&quot;place you came from is still open for you to 
 return back up there! Goodbye.

Hey Henry, thanks to all the employees, patrons, and Henry County 
 EMS who helped my husband when he became ill at the South Point JC 
 Penney. It really showed that there are still caring people in our 
 world. My husband is doing fine.
 
10.13.10

 Hey, Henry, does everyone in Henry County own a gas sucker 
 (SUV)? Everytime I turn around or park somewhere, there is a SUV 
 right beside me. I can&apos;t even see to back out of the parking lot. 
 They say that the economy is bad, but you could have fooled me 
 because everyone owns these expensive vehicles and how people afford 
 to put gas in these gas suckers is beyond my comprehension.

Hey Henry, those of us zoned for Luella High School are tired of all 
 the bad assumptions about our school. Before you throw your stones, 
 how about talking to some parents and students and find out about 
 all the GOOD things that are happening. The administration, faculty, 
 and staff are top notch and the student body rocks!

Hey Henry, how about those restaurant health inspectors. I 
 understand the importance of keeping a healthy, clean restaurant, 
 but most of the point deductions aren&apos;t even food related. A crack 
 under the back door, the cashier&apos;s bangs are too long, an employee 
 has a drink sitting on a table without a top on it, and so on. It&apos;s 
 gotten out of hand. And the bad thing is that the public doesn&apos;t see 
 this, they just see the score. I wonder how many Health Inspectors 
 we will need when there are no more restaurants in Henry County.

Hey Henry, if you&apos;re a politician, and make a four-year commitment 
 to the voters, then quit after two years because a better offer came 
 along, don&apos;t expect me to vote for you again.

Hey Henry, the best reasons to vote no to the ballot question about 
 the Redevelopment Powers Act: bigger government and more debt. It&apos;s 
 borrowing money and someone else dodges taxes to pay it back. Debt 
 is not wealth or recovery!

Hey Henry, I would like for the coaches at Dutchtown High School to 
 use some discretion. Coaches should set the standard for their 
 players. This coach used language inappropriate for twenty-five 
 Color Guard girls to hear as they sat on the field waiting for 
 halftime. Get it together guys.

Hey Henry, please remember the families of the two Henry County 
 School students whose lives were lost last week. One was a freshman 
 from HCHS and one was a senior from LGHS. Remember their peers who 
 are going to school daily missing their friends.

Hey Henry, I love the new light at Bethany and Highway 81; I just 
 don&apos;t understand why turn lights were not installed. What&apos;s up with 
 that?

Hey Henry, maybe if all you Hey Henry complaining people stopped 
 breathing for a little bit all your problems will just go away. (Ed. 
 note: now, thats just a bit harsh, dont you think?)

Hey Henry, today, when my children came home from school, I asked 
 them what they learned and they told me apparently not enough, 
 because they told them they had to come back tomorrow.

Hey Henry, speak for yourself when you say we don&apos;t want a Kroger on 
 81. I do want the Kroger and can&apos;t wait until they build.

Hey Henry, what is it with people these days? Sir or Maam, just 
 because you have a big belly does not make you eligible for the 
 pregnant/ new mother parking spot at the grocery store.

Hey Henry, I dont mean to offend anyone; but, teachers, it would 
 help greatly if you could put yourself in each of your students 
 places and see if you think that you are providing an environment 
 that is conducive to maximum individual learning. You may be 
 surprised at what you find. Thank you.
 
10.06.10

Hey Henry, I am 13 years old and I live in Clayton County. Id just 
 like to say that I love your newspaper, it interests me and I 
 appreciate what you guys post on there. Keep up the good work, and 
 remember, write Hey Henry, because Clayton County doesn&apos;t!

Hey Henry, this is to folks turning from Wynn Drive onto Hwy 81: 
 Please stop at the stop sign! I almost rear-ended someone on a rainy 
 day because a white car didn&apos;t even slow down for the stop sign when 
 he turned in front of me. I&apos;ve watched the past 2 weeks and I 
 personally haven&apos;t seen one person stop at that sign. Stop signs are 
 there to protect everyone!

Hey Henry, it seems like every room in the County buildings are 
 painted a different color! What I want to know is that for every 
 color there must be a partially filled bucket laying around... seems 
 like a waste to me. Why not use a few colors that can be used up 
 instead of wasting the taxpayer dollars on each persons likes? Who 
 is paying the bill anyway? Oh, thats right.... I am!

Hey Henry, it is truly amazing to me that a shy child is not allowed 
 to read in class, because their voice is not loud enough!

Hey, Henry, if you think the economy is that bad, go to Tanger 
 Outlet Mall on Saturday and Sunday. You cannot find a parking place 
 and people are driving brand new cars and coming out of the stores 
 with four or five bags full of merchandise.

Hey Henry, how ya doin&apos;? (Ed. - were fine, thanks. And you?)

Hey Henry, why is the Board of Commissioners so against updating and 
 adding more content to a code of ethics? What are they afraid of? I 
 have read the document presented by the citizens group and there is 
 nothing in there that any of the BOC should be concerned with - 
 unless they have been breaking the code!!

Hey Henry, while I understand some might not want to read anything 
 negative...this is a&quot;vent&quot;and sometimes it does us good to do just 
 that. Sorry, you sound like a very nice person and we still love 
 you!

Hey Henry, I just need to express how much inconsiderate and lazy 
 people upset me. If you don&apos;t own it, don&apos;t use it - or at least ask 
 before you do so. If you live in a house with a lawn, cut it!

Hey Henry, why don&apos;t they go ahead and repave Lawrenceville Street 
 in McDonough. Curbs are in, digging up the street has been completed 
 and the street is in horrible condition.

Hey Henry, it&apos;s really a shame that over the years we have lost so 
 much of our county&apos;s historic resources. But in June, Nash Farm was 
 recognized by the American Battlefield Protection Program of the 
 National Park Service as being in the&quot;core&quot;part of the 
 battlefield. Thank you, Henry County for unselfishly preserving a 
 significant part of our history for future generations!

Hey Henry, the no call list should include politicians. When I 
 signed up for it, it meant I did not want to be called by anybody! 
 For the politicians that have called my number constantly for weeks, 
 I wouldn&apos;t vote for you now if my life depended on it!

Hey Henry, for some reason it just rubs me the wrong way to see the 
 metermaid/man parking in the McDonough Square for free while he 
 issues tickets to the other violators. Why can&apos;t he park behind the 
 courthouse? Looks like a revenue opportunity missed.
 
09.29.10

Hey Henry, Sandra Vincent wields a powerful pen. In her article, 
 REMEMBER on September 15, she said all the things all of us should 
 have said. Thank you, Ms. Vincent, for saying it so well and so 
 beautifully. Well done!

Hey Henry, I have lived on Hwy 155 North right outside the City 
 limits since I was twelve years old. The traffic is so bad I can 
 hardly get out of my driveway. I have come close to being hit two or 
 three times. You people that have to go out 155, please dont speed 
 up after you pass the City limits and dont throw your trash in my 
 ditch.

Hey Henry, a big thank you to Mr. Eugene Gibbs for bringing 
 attention to a much needed council meeting about utility fuel 
 adjustment charges in the city of Hampton. The meeting on Sept. 21 
 had a great turn out and the community of Hampton had a lot of 
 questions, concerns. Hopefully the City Council members and Mayor 
 will work with the community to find a solution to some of the 
 problems brought up at the meeting.

Hey Henry, No Deal! That&apos;s all I&apos;ve got to say.

Hey Henry, I absolutely love the&quot;crazy schedule&quot;the schools are 
 on. Vacation spots are not nearly as crowded in September, and it&apos;s 
 still warm enough to swim! The balanced calendar is the best thing 
 for our family.

Hey Henry, where are all the people who need jobs? I have called 
 five places to get shrubs pruned in the yard and no one has returned 
 my calls.

Hey Henry, to the reader who is too cheap to pay parking fees to 
 patronize local merchants on the Square - the Grinch really has 
 stolen your Christmas! By the way - there is a free lot one block 
 from the Square and a free parking structure about two blocks from 
 the Square.

Hey Henry, rain is a rarity, not an emergency. Don&apos;t turn on your 
 emergency flashers just because it&apos;s raining, but DO turn on your 
 headlights. It&apos;s the law.

Hey Henry, I love you! (Ed. note - Right back at you and keep 
 them coming.) 

Hey Henry, why isn&apos;t the new road between Jonesboro Road and Highway 
 42 open? The road and stop lights are finished, so what are you 
 waiting for? We need to use it NOW!

Hey Henry, thank you to everyone so far who have donated one dollar 
 for the upkeep of the Veterans Wall of Honor at Heritage Park. This 
 will continue till Nov. 11, Veterans Day.

Hey Henry, does anyone know a good time to take my recycle stuff to 
 the Henry County Recycle Center? The last three times I have gone, 
 every container is overflowing and I have brought mine back home. I 
 would save myself gas money if I just threw it all away!

Hey Henry, to the person who Henryed about loose cats - Henry 
 County&apos;s&quot;leash law&quot;DOES cover cats as well as dogs! If you have a 
 problem with cats coming into your yard, call the Animal Care and 
 Control Department.

Hey Henry, if you want to see outstanding young adults you should 
 attend a Henry County School Cross Country event. The meet at Nash 
 Farm was attended by a couple of hundred healthy, well-disciplined 
 students from the mid-Georgia area.
 
09.22.10

Hey Henry, I know the Downtown McDonough merchants want our 
 business, but why should I pay for parking and risk getting a ticket 
 when I can park for free at the big box store? Sorry McDonough 
 Merchants, looks like it&apos;s going to be another Wally World 
 Christmas!

Hey Henry, The residents voted no to SPLOST? No, we did not. We 
 overwhelmingly voted against a $256 million bond issue to build ten 
 new schools. Get your facts before begging for another tax increase.

Hey Henry, why is it that our hard-core prisoners get free legal 
 help, free education, free gyms etc. when our military can&apos;t get 
 tents in Afghanistan after being there 2 months? Why not send those 
 hard-core prisoners over there and bring our soldiers home where 
 they will be safe?

Hey Henry, To The Times: thanks for bringing some humor to us all. 
 Some Hey Henry Venters are dumber than rocks about whatever it is 
 making them Vent, and they call you a joke?

Hey Henry, to the cast, crew and everyone associated with this past 
 weekend&apos;s production of&quot;Jesus Christ Superstar&quot;by the Henry 
 Players - BRAVO! To those of you who did not have the opportunity to 
 see the play, you missed a wonderful show. Having seen the Broadway 
 production years ago, all of you involved with the show would have 
 made the original cast members proud. Thank you for a great couple 
 of hours of entertainment!

Hey Henry, why, since we built the new City Hall in Stockbridge, 
 (hideous by the way) are they adding on to the old one? I thought 
 they had to build the new one because they ran out of room. There 
 cannot possibly be that many employees in the City of Stockbridge. 
 What is the old building going to be used for? I just feel there are 
 so many other things that our taxes can pay for.

Hey Henry, when will people realize that the proposed community 
 center/mosque in NYC is NOT being built at Ground Zero nor the site 
 of the 9/11 tragedy, but a few blocks away in a commercial area 
 already containing a deli, an off-track betting site, several strip 
 joints, an &apos;adult&apos; lingerie store, and a book store devoted to 
 &apos;mysteries&apos; among others? Let&apos;s stop the fear-mongering, ok?

Hey Henry, we dont want a Kroger on 81. Prices are ridiculous even 
 more than Publix.

Hey Henry, NOBAMA......Thats all I gotta say.

Hey Henry, to the thugs that broke into our pasture and stole the 
 motorcycle and 4-wheeler out of our barn; the least you could have 
 done is close the pasture gate when you left so we didn&apos;t have to 
 spend the next morning chasing our horses up and down the road.

Hey Henry, maybe I&apos;m in the minority, but I strongly dislike the 
 music piped onto the Square. It&apos;s too loud and if you&apos;re trying to 
 have a quiet conversation on the benches, you can&apos;t hear the person 
 next to you. Anyway, with the traffic noises, it&apos;s loud enough!

Hey Henry, the pine oil truck fire occurred at the Clorox facility 
 that is transferring that facilities&apos; operation to Henry less than 
 500 feet from the front doors of homes. Sorry, Lil Lamb, while you 
 are correct in that it could happen anywhere, its more likely to 
 happen at the facility. Enjoy the millions.

Hey, Henry, I know there is no leash law for cats, but I surely do 
 wish folks would keep theirs at home and away from my bird feeders! 
 I feel like were providing a baited field for cats. Can we shoot 
 em?
 
09.15.10

Hey Henry! To the parent complaining about the lack of textbooks. NO 
 - the budget DOESN&apos;T contain enough money for them. But don&apos;t 
 worry--we won&apos;t raise your taxes to pay for new ones!

Hey Henry, how about widening the road on South Laney Road. This is 
 ridiculous. Horse and buggy days have been over for years!

Hey Henry, what do the folks that drive in Henry County around the 
 Square in McDonough don&apos;t understand about Take Gap-Give Gap? Its 
 pretty simple, don&apos;t you think?

Hey Henry, elementary schools can&apos;t pay for anything, even 
 textbooks, because leaders in Georgia think getting kickbacks from 
 developers is more important than properly funding the public school 
 system. They laid tons of people off, and you have the nerve to ask 
 for textbooks. They increased class sizes. They cut programs. The 
 residents voted no to SPLOST. What else can they do? If you don&apos;t 
 care enough to call out the leaders for cutting these funds, then 
 don&apos;t expect anything to get better.

Hey Henry, that was not a fire at the Clorox plant. It was a fire on 
 the pine oil truck. That could have happened anywhere!

Hey Henry, the person complaining about our new school 
 superintendent knows little about him. Too bad - he&apos;s a great 
 choice. And the&quot;crazy schedule?&quot;We who teach- LOVE it, and we love 
 the first sane decision the BOE has made in years!

Hey Henry, I pay county taxes which I thought went to parks, 
 recreation facilities, etc. If this is true then why are the Henry 
 County homeowners along with the rest of Henry county&apos;s residents 
 charged such a high fee to use these facilities? I would like to 
 hear what our elected officials have to say about this.

Hey Henry, Thanks to Commissioner Holder for standing up for the 
 southern end of the county in the recent Commission Meeting. It is 
 time for us to reap some benefits like the north part of the county. 
 We are still eating dust south of the prestigious Eagles Landing 
 Parkway.

Hey Henry, If you think Hey Henry is too negative, you should see 
 the vents I send in that they refuse to print! It is&quot;our own little 
 place to vent&quot;for a reason. Go read the funnies if you want to 
 laugh!

Hey Henry, where has Bonnie Bergman been? Miss her columns. They are 
 so light and funny.

Hey Henry, why am I being charged a fuel adjustment fee on my 
 utilities bill each month? While I love living in Hampton, I feel 
 the City Of Hampton doesn&apos;t love me. No matter how I try to conserve 
 my energy usage each month, the City adds almost half on to my bill 
 (fuel adj fee) and then taxes it too! Anyone know what this fuel 
 adjustment charge is for?

Hey Henry, I need help finding my lost cat. Her name is Julianne, 13 
 years old, declawed, tortoise shell in color, green eyes and wearing 
 a green collar. She is an indoor cat that got out in the area of 
 Iris Lake Road between Racetrack and King Mill roads. If you find 
 her please care for her and post a&quot;Hey Henry&quot;back to me please.

Hey Henry, If you are running for school board you should have some 
 real life experiences to offer and not rely only on your daddy&apos;s 
 experiences. (Henry Co. Times, is that vague enough for you? I have 
 tried to submit this three times, but I guess since it had your 
 beloved Steve Davis&apos; name in it you would not print it.) This is why 
 you are a joke of a newspaper! Ed. note - Thanks. Were just glad 
 we can bring some humor into your life.
  
 
09.08.10

Hey Henry, why has this become such a negative column? Why can&apos;t we 
 be positive and love what we have instead of complaining about what 
 we don&apos;t have or think is wrong? I want to challenge you. For at 
 least one week lets post nothing but good things to Hey Henry! 
 Who&apos;s with me?

Hey Henry, why does the Special Needs people of this county have to 
 practice softball on Sunday afternoon because there are no fields 
 available to practice on during the week. Who had the brilliant idea 
 to tear up all the fields at Windy Hill Park so a bunch of good ole 
 boys can race their lawnmowers? Who is the big brain behind this 
 decision?

Hey Henry, I was wandering if they could have moved the parking deck 
 a little bit farther away from the square? I have to admit it was a 
 good idea !

Hey Henry, to the dude looking at the statue in the square.....why 
 does everything have to do with&quot;us poor black people.&quot;Get over it. 
 I&apos;m black and that just doesn&apos;t cut it anymore!

Hey Henry, would you oppose a Christian church at Ground Zero? I 
 didn&apos;t think so. Any religion looking to capitalize on 9/11 is 
 motivated by the devil, not God.

Hey Henry, show Decatur and their book fair and Suwanee and theirs 
 that Henry County can stand up and be counted. We are as literate as 
 they are, and more.

Hey Henry, just wanted to say I love the music on the 
 square.....great idea!

Hey Henry, first we&apos;re told&quot;New County e-ticketing program will 
 save us money&quot;and that it reduces the ticketing process way, way 
 down from ten minutes for a carbon ticket and THEN we&apos;re told&quot;The 
 State Court of Henry County will assess a 50 cent convenience fee&quot;for each traffic citation processed. Which is it - are we paying to 
 save money? Where do the rest of the savings go?

Hey Henry, my husband and I would like to thank the Henry County 
 Sheriff officer who stopped to offer his help on Oak Street. He 
 thought our vehicle was broken down at the side of the road, but, we 
 were trying to rescue a small dog who had been missing. The officer 
 was kind enough to monitor traffic while we tried to round up the 
 very dehydrated and scared dog. Thank you so much for stopping and 
 caring.

Hey Henry, what happened to the days when the leaders of youth 
 groups such as scouts, football, baseball, school teams, churches 
 etc. taught kids self-reliance and service by organizing fund 
 raising activities that offered a service to the community or a 
 seasonal commodity for sale. Nowadays the leaders load up the 
 children, head to the nearest Wal-Mart and encourage them to 
 panhandle the public for the monies they desire.

Hey Henry, this is not your grandfather&apos;s school system! We have 
 moved past relying on textbooks to teach students. We now use more 
 creative and innovative ways to teach students today. You will find 
 teachers using a variety of different methods to make learning fun 
 and relevant for our kids today.

Hey Henry, the Board of Commissioners wanted to cut the cost of take 
 home cars. No one lost their cars, but four people in the Fire 
 Department did. Is that fair?

Hey Henry, I believe in miracles! Thank you to Gina, Susan, and Pam 
 for finding one of my most treasured items that was temporarily 
 lost....my wedding ring. God truly does answer prayer!
 
09.01.10

Hey Henry, someone needs to seriously check into what that smell is 
 in the library in Stockbridge.

Hey Henry, hope all the commissioners that voted for the warehouse 
 on King Mill Rd. got a chance to see the Clorox plant fire on TV. 
 Welcome to your future.

Hey Henry, to the person who is misinformed regarding the newly 
 appointed school superintendent. Check your facts, as previously 
 recorded in this paper. Dr. Hildreth&apos;s children are not home 
 schooled. While they were at one time, they were sufficiently 
 prepared such that his son graduated from ELHS last year and is 
 currently attending Georgia Tech. We should all hope to raise such 
 bright children! Way to go, BOE for your wise decision.

Hey Henry, hate to break it to you, but that chicken biscuit you 
 ordered is not pure chicken any more than that bologna you bad 
 mouthed is a pork chop!

Hey Henry, ethics regulations for the BOC? Rules only reinforce an 
 honest person&apos;s behavior. Like locks keep honest people honest. The 
 problem with our BOC is living and acting by the principles they 
 preach. Tar&amp;feathers may serve as a good reminder.

Hey Henry, why do the elementary schools no longer use textbooks to 
 teach grammar and math along with other subjects? Are we that broke 
 that we have to buy the schools supplies, but they cant splurge a 
 dime to buy textbooks to teach my child? It would be much simpler to 
 help study with my child if I knew what the teacher was teaching in 
 class.

Hey Henry, Facebook may cost some Henry County employees their jobs. 
 They have been warned but they did not listen.

Hey Henry, fried bologna biscuits are something many of us grew up 
 with. Spam can also be fried or served right out of the can. Neither 
 may suit the palate of folks who only eat the choice cuts.

Hey Henry, what&apos;s going on at the BOC? One set of minutes said&quot;physical year&quot;rather than&quot;fiscal year&quot;and also&quot;the dog was 
 rabbitt&quot;rather than&quot;the dog was rabid&quot;. Someone needs to proof 
 those minutes before they are put in the County record.

Hey Henry, to the guy in line at Hardees. I was raised eating fried 
 bologna sandwiches and biscuits. They are delicious. Anyway, who 
 decided that chicken was a breakfast food?

Hey Henry, I was on the Square tonight and heard the music on the 
 Square. Job, well done. It was very relaxing and loved watching my 
 little kids dance and sing. Thanks, City Council and Tourism Board.

Hey Henry, what&apos;s it going to take to have something done about the 
 horrid septic smell in the library in Stockbridge. It&apos;s getting 
 worse every day! Can&apos;t be healthy for patrons or employees.

Hey Henry, to the person who flew past my son&apos;s bus as he was 
 getting off on Coan Dr. (on 8/16), if you can&apos;t see those lights you 
 shouldn&apos;t be driving, and if you hit a child, you&apos;ll never forgive 
 yourself. Stop for the buses folks!

Hey Henry, you should not wait until 9/11 to show your appreciation 
 for your local fire department. During this horrible time of budget 
 cuts and downsizing, the fire department is often hit the hardest. 
 These men and women are there 24/7 to protect you, your family, and 
 your belongings. A furlough day for you might be 8 hours but for 
 them it is 24 hours of pay when they are already paid very little. 
 Stop by your local fire department and let them know how much you 
 appreciate them. A kind word can mean the world.
 
08.25.10

Hey Henry, this morning I thanked my hens for not having their eggs 
 recalled.

Hey Henry, the new superintendent of schools appointee in Henry 
 County home schooled his children and were supposed to trust him to 
 educate ours? Another brilliant move from our school board whose 
 chairman lives in Florida and gave us this crazy schedule we now 
 operate on.

Hey Henry, I would like to point out that while everyone is 
 complaining about jobs and so forth., how about us seniors on social 
 security and living alone. We dont get raises anymore and our food, 
 taxes, gas and everything have gone up. It is really getting hard to 
 live from one month to the next. Just a concerned senior.

Hey Henry, to the person in the August 11 issue of the Times who was 
 sitting on the Square staring at the statue and complaining about 
 it. Maybe, instead of looking at the statue you should try looking 
 for a job. Good Luck.

Hey Henry, it was so nice to see two young men being gentlemen and 
 letting two young ladies get onto bus #62-1 first today at the stop 
 on Hwy 81 and Mayo Road. I hope they keep up this fine example and, 
 even though the parents may not have seen this kind act, I did. You 
 can never tell when someone is watching.

Hey Henry, I know what&apos;s wrong with the world today. Nobody wants to 
 get up and go to work. Nobody has any volition anymore.

Hey Henry, I would like to say thank you to Scott, the gentleman who 
 stopped to help me when I ran out of gas Thursday on Eagles Landing 
 Parkway. He very kindly pushed my car out of the street and happened 
 to have some gas on his van. I truly appreciate this act of 
 kindness.

Hey Henry, we would enjoy a bridge or decking (with rules) over the 
 preserves on Hudson Bridge Road. A sidewalk leading to already 
 established parking would also be nice. The ecology would give the 
 schools a great local and creative learning outlet, not to mention 
 using it for family time.

Hey Henry, yes, school has started back and of course there is more 
 traffic. Everyone please take a couple of extra seconds and be 
 careful. So glad Officer George wasn&apos;t hurt more seriously yesterday 
 in an accident that could have been tragic. He&apos;s a great friend and 
 a great cop and we love him! So glad the other person wasn&apos;t hurt 
 either. Get well soon, George!

Hey Henry, I have lived on Hwy 155N right outside the city limits 
 since I was twelve years old. The traffic is so bad I can hardly get 
 out of my driveway. I have come close to being hit 2 or 3 times. 
 Please dont speed up after you pass the city limits and dont throw 
 your trash in my ditch.

Hey Henry, to the woman in the black Yukon XL in the Ola Elementary 
 car rider line, if you want to be first in line why don&apos;t you try 
 getting there the earliest. The rest of us were there thirty minutes 
 before you shoved your way to the front. You should have been taught 
 in kindergarten to take your turn.

Hey Henry, a guy in front of me in the Hardees drive-thru this 
 morning asked if they had fried bologna biscuits. I threw up in my 
 mouth a little bit when I heard that. Dude, its 7 a.m.! Get a 
 chicken biscuit or something normal!
 
08.18.10

Hey Henry, the article by Melissa Robinson,&quot;Threads of Love was 
 wonderful. We are especially thankful for having the opportunity to 
 read the article since our very dear friend, Susan Bowers, is a 
 charter member of Threads of Love.

Hey Henry, I think the ethics regulations for the Board Of 
 Commissioners are way overdue...

Hey Henry, I am sure everyone is wondering why we don&apos;t have the 
 Kroger on Hwy. 81. It is because the county hasn&apos;t fixed Racetrack 
 Rd. like they said they would. There has to be a stop light there 
 before the store can come in. Come on Henry County, this is a&quot;horrible&quot;intersection 
 with or without a grocery store!

Hey Henry, to the person who found the Confederate Monument so tacky 
 and distasteful, I feel it only worthwhile to remind them that 
 Highway 42 runs both North and South, and that Delta is ready 
 whenever you are! A monument can mean most good or bad to anyone. 
 It&apos;s our right to free speech that we all fight for everyday.

Hey Henry, to the parents that have to drop off and pick up their 
 kids at school, please show a little common courtesy to the crossing 
 guards. They are there to do a job that helps keep our kids safe. It 
 makes no sense to verbally abuse these men and women, this only sets 
 a bad example for everyone&apos;s children.

Hey Henry, if you&apos;re so disgusted and insulted by the history of the 
 state/area, that you chose to live in, then please feel free to 
 move.

Hey Henry, to the person who said they&quot;loathe and detest it&quot;(the 
 Confederate statue on the square); May I suggest that you stop 
 sitting in the park and looking at it? Maybe you will feel better. 
 You are not likely to change the fact that the statue is there and 
 will more than likely remain there. Your rantings will probably only 
 cause more answers like the one I am giving to your poorly described 
 reasons for&quot;loathing it.&quot;

Hey Henry, a very special thank you to Officer P. Pressly and 
 Detective Stotts for the fine work you did this week. My good 
 friend&apos;s granddaughter stole her car and bank card. These two 
 policemen were very concerned for my friend&apos;s well being and the 
 safety issue for her granddaughter as well. They kindly kept my 
 friend informed and were swift and relentless in following all 
 leads. Sad she had to go to jail, but she is out of harm&apos;s way. 
 Thank you Henry County Police for a job well done!

Hey Henry, ever since you said it, I can&apos;t un-see the ugliness of 
 that statue on the square. Jebediah Springfield it ain&apos;t!

Hey Henry, it&apos;s an insult to all police, fire, EMS and military 
 personnel to construct that Mosque at the site of the 9/11 incident. 
 I know politicians allow some stupid things to go through at times, 
 but did all of the ones who approved that smoke crack that morning? 
 Come on folks, realize who put you in office and start thinking for 
 us instead of against us ! Look at the polls---we&apos;re slowly but 
 surely voting all of you out. And there is a reason!

Hey Henry, the eighth annual Mr. and Miss Special Henry County 
 Pageant was an awesome experience! A lot of tears and smiling faces! 
 Congrats to all the winners.

Hey Henry, I wish the city council of Stockbridge would get over 
 their buddy losing his Mayorship by the people voting him out. Get 
 on with business and work with the new Mayor or the people will 
 speak again next election for city council. The people of 
 Stockbridge deserve better than this.
 
08.11.10

Hey Henry, I believe it was Mark Twain who commented, There is 
 nothing as irritating as a good example. That must explain why I 
 like the Hey Henry so much!

Kudos to officer W. Barnett of the McDonough PD. My truck was stolen 
 at 1:23 a.m. I reported it at 1:29 a.m. and within 15 minutes he had 
 the truck at my door and the perps in hand. He did it single handed. 
 Hes got to be the best officer in McDonough and possibly the best 
 in the world.

Hey Henry, I have been running (jogging) Hwy. 42 between Eagles 
 Landing and the Square since 2002. There is a car that passes me 
 almost every morning between 3:40 a.m. and 4 a.m. Its a black SUV 
 and as he/she passes me he/ she gives me a gentle two honks of the 
 horn. I know this is a sign he/ she is saying hey to me and sending 
 me encouragement. Thanks to this person for being so kind to do 
 this, it makes my day! Even with head phones on I know the sound of 
 this car. Would love to know this kind person.

Hey Henry, whats the deal with Peeksville Road? Did we run out of 
 money for asphalt? I wonder if these tax-paying residents enjoy 
 eating all that dust?

Hey Henry, you know the little White house on 81 - the one there by 
 the feed store. It added a whole bunch of parking places. Well, its 
 going to be a used car lot - not what we need here.

Hey Henry, thank you Henry County Library System for the fun magic 
 show to start off the summer reading program! But please use the 
 big, new, spacious room and don&apos;t try to fit the whole county in 
 that little room in the front. Isn&apos;t that why we have the addition?

Hey Henry, Amen to the person that wrote in to get Mt. Bethel Road 
 off Hwy 81 paved. While they are paving down there..could they 
 please pave the upper end of Sandy Ridge Road? You have to ride in 
 the residents yards just to keep cars going in the opposite 
 directions from colliding.

Hey Henry, the parking meters around McDonough Square are a 
 detriment to encouraging shoppers to have lunch and stroll around. 
 It&apos;s hurting the businesses that are trying to be successful. If 
 nothing else, they should put a 4 hour limit on them (presently 2 
 hours). Some of my customers have complained that they can&apos;t even 
 sit down for a leisurely meal without running out to the meter! I&apos;ve 
 had others tell me that they have quit shopping the Square because 
 of the aggravation of the meters.

Hey Henry, in light of the AMS announcement that there will be only 
 one NASCAR race yearly beginning 2011, I hope that the Henry County 
 BOC passes a unanimous resolution at the next meeting to change the 
 name of Bruton Smith Parkway to Thanks for Nothing Parkway since 
 he has turned his back on us, and done away with a lot of jobs and 
 tax revenue for Henry County.

Hey Henry, after sitting on a bench on the Square and studying the 
 Confederate statue, I&apos;ve decided that I loathe and detest it and 
 everything it stands for. My reasons are that it&apos;s ugly, obviously 
 made assembly-line ... it looks like a molded-concrete lawn 
 ornament; it&apos;s not even accurate, except for the rifle-musket, all 
 the figure&apos;s clothes and equipment are from the Spanish-American 
 War; and it glorifies as bad a cause as has ever been, a disastrous, 
 futile war we should have been smart enough to avoid, fought to 
 preserve a hideous system which still poisons our society; and it&apos;s 
 a continuing insult to our black population. ... a more realistic 
 statue would show a slave being whipped or a freedman being burned 
 at the stake.
 
08.04.10

Hey Henry, the evil, sadistic man who 
 privately humiliates his employees every Friday morning stooped so 
 low to publicly humiliate one last week. It&apos;s time he knew that 
 Karma comes for all!

Hey Henry, forget about trying to get the OHS Marching Mustangs sent 
 to London. Tonight after their practice the band found out that THE 
 TRIP GOT APPROVED! So every Friday night go watch them and go to 
 their competitions especially October 30th at the Georgia Dome for 
 the Bands Of America competition! Congrats OHS for all your hard 
 work it pays off in the end.

Hey Henry, I just wanted to give a great big THANK YOU to my husband 
 Ben, who is always there for me no matter how much of a pain I am 
 (sometimes).... Luv you, Tu Gorda

Hey Henry, to the lady that saw me stop for the Geese. I stop for 
 the Geese for two reasons: 1. If I hit them it will damage my 
 vehicle. 2. It&apos;s against the law to intentionally kill the nasty 
 stinking things. If you don&apos;t think they are nasty and stinking, 
 just wait until 50 of them take up residency in your backyard!

Hey Henry, just a quick lesson in life - when you&apos;re loyal to an 
 employer and are dismissed, it&apos;s an extra slap in the face when they 
 try to keep you from collecting your rightfully earned unemployments 
 benefits until a new job can be secured. Be nice and play fair. It 
 could be you or your family member who is unemployed. Just try to 
 respect your fellow man. Even if you think you&apos;re smarter than they 
 are.

Hey Henry, to the person complaining about a Realtor not driving you 
 around in their car to look at homes. It&apos;s a safety precaution that 
 must be taken in the world we live in now. You may be a very 
 trustworthy person but, not everyone is and it is one of the ways we 
 can protect ourselves. We already have to take precautions when 
 showing homes. People have been known to set up showings with agents 
 just to get them out to a house while the other person will be there 
 waiting on them to get there and rob, rape or kill them or the 
 homeowner(s)... or all of the above! Please try to see it from our 
 point of view. It&apos;s unfortunate that we can&apos;t trust people as much 
 as we used to.

Hey Henry, I thought people were doing&quot;staycations,&quot;guess not, 
 everyone I call is on vacation out of state, seems folks still have 
 plenty of the green stuff.

Hey Henry, The blame for the kids not passing the CCRTs is shared - 
 budget cuts, crowded classrooms, uncaring teachers, and parents who 
 aren&apos;t helping their child at home. The kids deserve better.

Hey Henry, PARENTS, PLEASE put a little sun hat on your 
 babies/toddlers head when you&apos;re out during the day. Do you not 
 realize how harmful the strong sun can be to them?

Hey Henry, would someone please tell me when people work. I am 
 retired and everytime I go into a store or restaurant in the daytime 
 they are full. I find it difficult to shop for basic needs these 
 days.

Hey Henry, It is a shame that the people who are working in the 
 Square and trying to make it a better place are finding it harder 
 and harder to find parking. The space between the Welcome Center and 
 the Chafin Building is now being rented for $30.00 a month.
 
07.28.10

Hey Henry, we just spent a week at 
 Shingleroof Campground (off Campground Road in McDonough) for the 
 annual&quot;camp meeting.&quot;We want to offer our sincere gratitude to the 
 Henry County Sheriff&apos;s Reserve officers who so patiently and 
 thoroughly patrolled the area during this time. We walked our three 
 dogs as late as 11:00 at night and always felt safe. Thanks, again, 
 Henry County.

Hey Henry, realtors need to learn to give some customer service, it 
 has been years since one has actually taken me in their vehicle to 
 look at a home.

Hey Henry, please let me know the identity of the local official who 
 wants to demolish Toby Springs so that I can vote for him in any and 
 all coming elections!

Hey Henry, please ask the Board of Education why they won&apos;t approve 
 a trip to London by the Ola High School Marching Band. The band has 
 been invited to march in the New Years Day parade in 2012. The 
 entire trip would be paid for by the students-not cost the school 
 board or the taxpayers a dime-yet the BOE thinks it will make the 
 county school system look bad. How can one of our schools being 
 invited to participate in such a prestigious event make the county 
 look bad?

Hey Henry, Im so tired of hearing about Obama&apos;s golf outings, 
 basketball games, and vacations! Another one scheduled for August on 
 the Gulf Coast. Good photo op I guess. No wonder our country is not 
 improving. He never works!

Hey Henry, it does my heart good to see drivers stopping to let a 
 family of geese cross a four-lane road.

Hey Henry, just because I leave my job for lunch......it does not 
 mean that I want to stop by a fast food place and get your lunch. Go 
 get it yourself...why should I spend up to 15 minutes of my time in 
 a drive through while you are kicked back resting on your lunch 
 break. At least offer to get me a coke or something.

Hey Henry, I just want to make a comment about how some people leave 
 their goods out front at the Salvation Army Store on Racetrack Road 
 after it is closed. Whoever you are, you should be ashamed. This 
 store does not deserve this kind of treatment. There are a lot of 
 people, including myself, that shop there and when this happens, its 
 as if you are just throwing your leftovers to the dogs. Have more 
 pride for the American person. Remember this is America, not some 
 third world country.

Hey Henry, if you can&apos;t contact your commissioners, then who can you 
 contact?

Hey Henry, to the wonderful person who found my mobile phone (Sony 
 Ericsson, western boot on back) at the McDonough library and turned 
 it in, MANY thanks! My budget is too tight to buy another one.

Hey Henry, 38% of Henrys schools did not make AYP. However, by 
 September that number should go down due to retakes and appeals. If 
 you want to blame someone, look in the mirror, not at the schools, 
 and especially not the teachers.

Hey Henry, why does the county keep raising the starting pay on some 
 jobs but does nothing for the people that have been there for a 
 while? Keep compressing the pay scale...real smart.
 
07.21.10

Hey Henry, who is in charge of 
 furlough days for the County? Apparently no one. What a mess.

Hey Henry, we need an indoor pistol/ rifle range in Henry co. We 
 should not have to drive to Clayton Co. to be able to enjoy shooting 
 our guns. My wife and I wanted to go shoot last Friday and of course 
 traffic north on 75 was stopped, and it took us an hour to get to 
 the range in Forest Park. When we got there at 7:08 they told us the 
 range closes an hour before the store at 8. Needless to say we 
 weren&apos;t happy. It would be great to have one closer to home. I know 
 a lot of people who would use it.

Hey Henry, since counties are making many cutbacks perhaps the Henry 
 County Water Authority could cut out its one week stay each year to 
 Savannah while we the taxpayers pay for them to bring their wives 
 and stay in luxury.

Hey Henry, most citizens know the four lane Jonesboro Road is 
 nothing but a&quot;honey hole&quot;for the local police to collect revenue. 
 The ridiculous 45 m.p.h. speed limit is strictly enforced. Set your 
 cruise control when you hit that road and don&apos;t give them your 
 money.

Hey Henry, I think the bring-your-dog-to-dinner outside at PJ&apos;s is a 
 great idea! Finally the Square has something new.

Hey Henry, someone recently asked why the residents of Toby Springs 
 can&apos;t get some safe way to walk to town or the shopping center. 
 Well, here&apos;s why--A local official sitting across a conference table 
 from me said that he&apos;d like to have all the housing there demolished 
 because it&apos;s&quot;blighted.&quot;This was the third or fourth housing area 
 for which he used that word; they all just happen to be full of 
 non-whites.

Hey Henry, as back to school season starts, how about helping out 
 all of us furloughed school teachers by sending in the kleenex, hand 
 sanitizer, and other donations we ask for, so we don&apos;t have to use 
 our furloughed paychecks to buy it ourselves. Because that is 
 exactly what all of us do!

Hey Henry, save our tax dollars and disregard the suggestion sent in 
 last week to put out signs reminding drivers to &apos;stop for 
 pedestrians in marked crosswalks&apos; as, it&apos;s pretty much common 
 knowledge, the majority of Henry County residents can&apos;t read.

Hey Henry, is the take gap give gap just too hard for some of you to 
 figure out when traveling through the square? or are many of you 
 like some of the Henry Co Police when coming through there, it just 
 doesn&apos;t apply to you! Pay attention people and TAKE and GIVE the 
 gap. As for the police, if you&apos;re on a call, turn your lights on.

Hey Henry, thank you Henry County Times and People First. The 
 Special Pagent is a big part of what makes Henry County special! 
 Melissa Dodgen thank you for daring to believe and dream big dreams! 
 This year my granddaughter Sherrie is living her dream because of 
 special people like you and your mom.

Hey Henry, The Henry BOE Maintenance Department lost one of its 
 workers (electrician) by the name of Darin McGahey last week in 
 Florida. He saved some children from drowning in an undertow and 
 lost his own life. The maintenance department and close co-workers 
 will be praying for his family through these tough times. Even 
 though Darin is not with us anymore, we will always be turning our 
 heads towards that white county van with the big H on the side, 
 Darin and his partner rode in and wondering why? God Bless the 
 McGahey family.
 

Disclaimer 
*The Henry County Times is not responsible for views expressed in&quot;Hey, Henry!&quot;We will not print any libelous material nor any personal insults. We reserve the right to edit any submission. Submissions posted through our website will not post immediately, as they are first scrutinized by our editorial staff. Thank you, come again.
 
 
 
  
 Henry County Times, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
