<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005311" url="http://www.hotfrog.com.au/Products/Pizza/SA/RENMARK" time="2012-07-12-21:51" support="1" score="0.0005708409990944422" bingtitle="Pizza in SA - Hot Frog - Your Australian Business Directory" webtitle="Pizza in SA">
			<query id="000950" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>We are increasing the number of restaurants ... Pizza Restaurant Fast Food Restaurant Italian Restaurant Fast ... fresh, quality pizzas every time. Order your pizza online. Pick ...</description>
	<body>
		Login Login using 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Pizza in SA
 Pizza   South Australia (320) 1 - 40 of 320 businesses results Sponsored links Eagle Boys Pizza Online 
 www.eagleboys.com.au/ Order Online&amp;Save Everyday All Major Credit Cards Now Accepted 
 Order Pizza Online   Find Your Nearest Store Pizza Catering Orders   Stores In&amp;Around Sydney 
 Pizzaria Adelaide 
 www.ask.com/ Get Pizzaria Adelaide Find Pizzaria Adelaide Pizza Recipes 
 www.momsrecipefinder.com/ Get Pizza 1000&apos;s of Great Recipes Instantly Pizzas for low price 
 au.price-selector.com/ Pizzas Compare Pizzas prices now! Save money on Pizzas bargains. 
Related information
 PICK-UP&amp;SAVE!! 
Pizza Palace - 29-Sep-2010
  Pizza Palace offers piping hot quality PIZZAS! We only use the best, fresh quality ingredients to make our Pizza&apos;s. Pick-up your Pizzas&amp;save $$ Pizza Palace 
Mitchell Park, SA
 (08) 8177 2211 
We have been in the Pizza Business for over 25 years. That&apos;s a lot of delicious, piping hot PIZZAS! We only use the best, fresh quality ingredients to make our Pizza&apos;s. Our pizzas are great value offering something for…
 
 Pizza Restaurant Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza Hot Pizza 
 Eatout-Adelaide.com.au 
Adelaide, SA
 04 03495726 
Do yourself a flavour :) See Online Menus, Photos, Map, Specials, and more at .  We are increasing the number of restaurants, cafes, etc... listed all the time so visit us soon to see 15 great photos, etc... Have a grea…
 
 Pizzareia Pizza Restaurant Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza 
   Cudgee Bar 
Woomera, SA
 08 86 737 800 
…a fire is supplied to keep you warm and increase the atmoshere of the &quot;bush&quot; (on selected nights). Village Pizza s are available in the park during selected tourist periods.  Drop in for a coldie&amp;chat.  Proprietor…
 
 Fast Food alcoholic drinks 
 Billy&apos;s Pizza 
Largs Bay, SA
 08 82424545 
Call 8242 4545 for pick-up or delivery. Located at 195 Victoria Road, Largs Bay. Business Hours: Monday       4-10pm Tuesday      4-10pm Wednesday 4-10pm Thursday     4-10pm Friday         4-11pm Saturday     4-11pm Su…
 
 Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza 
 Crompton Pizza&apos;s 
Lyndoch, SA
 08 85244150 
&quot;The Chef and The Cook &quot; As a Husband (Cook) and Wife (Chef) team we are dedicated to providing a Quality pizza and Take away foods to Lyndoch and the surrounding towns.  Using Fresh Produce from local growers and the f…
 
 Pizza Restaurant Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza Hot Pizza 
 Valley Lake Pizza 
Mount Gambier, SA
 08 87255551 
Valley Lake Pizza is a new business owned by a husband and wife team, Valley Lake Pizza has experienced and friendly staff.We make our own Pizza dough on the premises and will make Pizzas to customers requirements websi…
 
 Pizza Delivery Take Away Food 
 paula&apos;s pizza 
Flinders Park, SA
 08-83541235 
&quot;Taste The Difference&quot; Ordering from Paula&apos;s Pizza is always a special treat. It’s just the right combination of high quality fresh food served in a quick, friendly atmosphere.
 
 Pizza Restaurant Italian Restaurant Restaurant 
 The Orchard 
Aldinga, SA
 (08) 8557 6997 
Between the hills of McLaren Vale and Port Willunga beach,
the Orchard is the best new venue on the Fleurieu. The Orchard has fantastic coffee, fresh regional cuisine, gourmet wood-fired pizza , a stylish wine bar, beaut…
 
 wood fired pizza Restaurant 
 Wicked Pizza 
Highgate, SA
 (08) 8172 2022 
Wicked Pizza represents a refreshingly new approach for pizzas in Australia. The business offers fast, fresh pizzas at events throughout the country using its unique mobile delivery model. Our business is based on the…
 
 Oven mobile catering 
 Jamestown Cafe 
Jamestown, SA
 (08) 8664 1818 
…Takeaway we offer the finest foods prepared with the freshest of local produce, including fish&amp;chips, pizza s, juicy steaks, hamburgers, bakery lines&amp;great Breakfast fare. Our Coffee is second to none…
 
 Takeaway fresh salads dinner lunch 
 Pizzas&apos;N&apos;More 
West Lakes, SA
 (08) 8347 0030 
A bright and friendly pizza bar which also sells ribs, pastas, baked potatoes, seafood&amp;meat dishes.  Seats up to 15 people.  Come and try our mouth-watering experiences!!  Within walking distance to AAMI Stadium.
 
 Pizza Restaurant Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza Quality Pizzas 
 Monto Cafe - Italian Pizza Restaurant A… 
Norwood, SA
 (08) 8331 0900 
…lunch, dinner and supper while you watch the world go by on busy
Norwood Parade. From traditional Italian Cuisine, authentic traditional Italian
style pizza s, a sensational wine list, Manto is a place to meet and
eat.
 
 Pizzareia Pizza&amp;Restaurant Pizza Restaurant italian pizza 
 PARK TERRACE PIZZA 
Salisbury, SA
 (08) 8281 1191 
 PIZZA AND PASTA IN THE HEART OF SALISBURY!! SALISBURY PIZZA BAR DEDICATED TO MAKING THE FRESHEST PIZZAS POSSIBLE. SHOP 2, 101 PARK TERRACE SALISBURY. NEXT TO THE B.P  OPEN FROM 4PM 7DAYS
 
 Pizza Restaurant Pizza And Pasta Take Away Pizza Hot Pizza 
 Dominos Pizza Murray Bridge 
MURRAY BRIDGE, SA
 08 85357400 
Dominos Pizza Murray Bridge are passionate about pizza. Try Dominos online ordering today and get your favourite pizza faster!
 
 Crispy Turkey Rissoles Oregano Ciabatta Pizza Dominos Pizza Fresh Tomato 
 Dominos Pizza Largs Bay 
LARGS BAY, SA
 08 83415811 
Love fresh hot quality pizza s? Order online for speedy delivery from Dominos Pizza Woodville Park, the Pizza Delivery Experts
 
 Crispy Turkey Rissoles Oregano Ciabatta Pizza Dominos Pizza Fresh Tomato 
 Dominos Pizza Golden Grove 
GOLDEN GROVE, SA
 08 82517136 
Godfather, Simply Cheese, Toni Pepperoni, Chicken Monaco or create your own. Order Dominos pizza online.
 
 Crispy Turkey Rissoles Oregano Ciabatta Pizza Dominos Pizza Fresh Tomato 
 Dominos Pizza Plympton 
PLYMPTON PARK, SA
 08 83096010 
Meatasaurus, BBQ Chicken&amp;Bacon, Vegorama, Hawaiian or create your own. Order Dominos pizza online.
 
 Crispy Turkey Rissoles Oregano Ciabatta Pizza Dominos Pizza Fresh Tomato 
 Dominos Pizza Newton 
NEWTON, SA
 08 83659777 
Dominos Pizza Newton are passionate about pizza. Try Dominos online ordering today and get your favourite pizza faster!
 
 Crispy Turkey Rissoles Oregano Ciabatta Pizza Dominos Pizza Fresh Tomato 
 Dominos Pizza Malvern 
MALVERN, SA
 08 83066800 
Let Dominos Pizza Kings Langley, the pizza delivery experts bring your favourite pizza to your door.
 
 Crispy Turkey Rissoles Oregano Ciabatta Pizza Dominos Pizza Fresh Tomato 
 Caffe Sorelles 
Renmark, SA
 (08) 85864888 
…We bring a &quot;Little bit of the City to the Country&quot;, but with country hospitality. We now serve gourmet Pizza s which are made from only the best ingredients. Indoor/outdoor alfresco dining We serve from Tuesday to…
 
 Pizza Restaurant Fast Food Restaurant Italian Restaurant Fast Food 
 Starfire Pizza 
Salisbury North, SA
 08 8281 5022 
Our mission is to provide you the best Pizza service possible. For further details please checkout our website: www,starfirepizza.webs.com
 
 Pizza Delivery Quality Pizzas Pizza Bar Take Away Food 
 Ferellis At North Haven Pizza Delivery 
North Haven, SA
 1300 665 364 
DELIVERY SPECIAL JUST $24 Two Large Pizza s (12 inch) PLUS Garlic Bread&amp;1.25L Pepsi            [Conditions Apply: 5km Radius:Daily5pm-10pm]
 
 Pizzareia Pizza Restaurant Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza 
 Marcellina Pizza Bar Restaurant 
Adelaide, SA
 (08) 82117560, 13 1967 
Now thatza pizzza! Dine in, take-away, Home delivery and functions. Marcellina Pizza can satisfy your hunger
 
 Pizza Restaurant Pizza Delivery Fast Food Restaurant Fast Food Restaurants 
 Cafe B 
Modbury, SA
 (08) 83962333 
Enjoy the Best Italian Cuisine at Adelaide - Modbury. Cafe Buongiorno = Great food + great service + great coffee + FREE Internet Access
 
 Pasta traditional italian food Italian Cuisine Restaurant 
 Stella Restaurant Henley Beach 
Henley Beach, SA
 08 8356 4315 
Stella Restaurant - the perfect location for a foreshore wedding or seafront function on the foreshore at Henley Square, Adelaide
 
 Pasta Restaurant Menus Restaurant 
 Adelaide Hills Gourmet Foods 
Woodside, SA
 0416 049 188 
Deana Tilker , a chef and Barista with over 25 years experience in the hospitality industry is behind Adelaide&apos;s award-winning pizza chefs and makers of delicious gourmet food
 
 Pizzas gluten-free 
 Sportivo Cafe 
West Lakes, SA
 08 8353 7766 
With an Italian influence, Sportivo is known for its traditional thin based wood oven pizza s and alfresco lake view dining
 
 Pizzeria Pasta risotto italian dining 
 Pizzarellos 
Port Adelaide, SA
 +61 419714199 
 Pizza rellos - where ever you go. Delivering fresh, quality pizzas every time. Order your pizza online. Pick from a range of toppings
 
 Pizza Delivery Quality Pizzas Pizzeria Pizzas 
 Morphett Vale Pizza And Pasta 
MORPHETT VALE, SA
 (08) 8384 2477 
Morphett Vale Pizza &amp;Pasta. Located on Doctors Road and Main South Road, Morphett Vale. Morphett Vale Pizza&amp;Pasta offer a wide range of Pizza’s and Pasta’s that the whole family will love
 
 traditional pizza Pizza And Pasta pizza&amp;pasta Pizza Pasta 
 Cafe B 
Modbury, SA
 08 8396 2333 
Enjoy the Best Italian Cuisine at Adelaide - Modbury. Cafe Buongiorno = Great food + great service + great coffee + FREE Internet Access
 
 Pasta traditional italian food Italian Cuisine Restaurant 
 F P Christies Beach 
CHRISTIES BEACH, SA
 08 81863688 
At Fasta Pasta, the freshness of all our ingredients is paramount, but none more so than our pasta. We use farm fresh eggs to make our pasta fresh. The soft texture and tenderness of fresh pasta absorbs the full flavour…
 
 Pasta Farm Fresh Eggs Restaurant Fresh Pasta 
 Restaurant Bella 
Kangaroo Island, SA
 +61 8 8553 0400 
Taste our fresh culinary delights from the lunch or dinner menu’s offering a lovely selection of seasonal food including the infamous King George Whiting
 
 Restaurant 
 Woodcroft Pizza&amp;Ribs 
WOODCROFT, SA
 (08) 8322 4788 
On top of this we have launched a new arm to our business, providing our top of the line ingredients in fresh sealed packages for you to make your own pizza ’s at home, especially targeting those of you with a home…
 
 Pizza Oven Ribs 
 Savellis Take And Bake 
North Adelaide, SA
 +61 8 8361 8666 
Savellis Take and Bake Menu Savelli&apos;s take and bake actively seeks business partners who share our passion for quality food and excellent customer service to become part of the Savelli&apos;s family
 
 
 Caffe Buongiorno 
Adelaide, SA
 08 8381 1744 
We aim to provide the highest standards of customer satisfaction possible, together with a dash of creativity and passion to fulfil our motto: The Cafe with a Difference We provided a fresh blend of authentic t…
 
 Italian Restaurant Pasta Italian Food Restaurant 
 Lilla&apos;s Cafe 
Yankalilla, SA
 08 8558 2525 
Lillas Cafe is a unique dining experience in the Fleurieu Peninsula, located in the small country town of Yankalilla. Lillas provides a tantalising gourmet menu with local food and wine produce. Each meal is prepared …
 
 Restaurant Dining Experience 
 All Fired Up Pizzas 
McLaren Vale, SA
 0410 477 763 
Rich, sweet&amp;smoky with a hint of spice, fantastic pizza base like our Ed La Dou chicken&amp;Cleaver meat pizzas
 
 Pizzas sauce 
 Oscars 
Mclaren Vale, SA
 08 8323 8707 
No trip to the Fleurieu Peninsula is complete without a visit to the charming Oscars Restaurant, in the heart of the picturesque McLaren Vale
 
 Pizza And Pasta Takeaway Pizza Pizza Pasta Fast Food 
 Beer And Burger 
Parkside, SA
 08 8362 4657 
 Cheese Burgers christmas lunch Bread Rolls 
 Bellissimo Pizza&amp;pasta 
Adelaide, SA
 81865991 
 pizza&amp;pasta Pasta Home Delivery 
 First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (320) 
 Related keywords 
 Fast Food Restaurants Restaurant Pizza Restaurant Fast Food Restaurant Italian Restaurant Pizzareia Pizza Delivery Take Away Pizza Home Delivery 
 Pizza by region 
 Northern Adelaide Eastern Adelaide Western Beachside Suburbs Western Adelaide South Adelaide Adelaide Eastern Suburbs Fleurieu Peninsula Far South East SA Outer Adelaide Adelaide Hills South East SA Mt Lofty Ranges Limestone Coast 
 Pizza by suburb 
 ADELAIDE, SA SALISBURY, SA GLENELG, SA MODBURY, SA SEMAPHORE, SA MOUNT GAMBIER, SA HENLEY BEACH, SA MCLAREN VALE, SA ELIZABETH, SA MOUNT BARKER, SA MORPHETT VALE, SA ATHELSTONE, SA WOODCROFT, SA Daw Park, SA Blackwood, SA RIDGEHAVEN, SA COLLINSWOOD, SA ST PETERS, SA WEST LAKES, SA PROSPECT, SA PLYMPTON, SA CAMPBELLTOWN, SA MILE END, SA MURRAY BRIDGE, SA GLYNDE, SA CHRISTIES BEACH, SA Westbourne Park, SA ALLENBY GARDENS, SA PARA HILLS, SA GOODWOOD, SA PORT ADELAIDE, SA PARALOWIE, SA BRIGHTON, SA MARION, SA SEATON, SA NORTHFIELD, SA GREENACRES, SA KILKENNY, SA SALISBURY DOWNS, SA WHYALLA, SA Barker, SA ALDINGA, SA ABERFOYLE PARK, SA TAPEROO, SA DERNANCOURT, SA NEWTON, SA HOLDEN HILL, SA GILLES PLAINS, SA LARGS BAY, SA NORWOOD, SA WOODVILLE, SA GOOLWA, SA PARKSIDE, SA GLENSIDE, SA ELIZABETH SOUTH, SA FLINDERS PARK, SA HACKHAM, SA HIGHGATE, SA CRAFERS, SA ELIZABETH WEST, SA FELIXSTOW, SA KLEMZIG, SA PARA VISTA, SA PLYMPTON PARK, SA GLENUNGA, SA WARRADALE, SA FINDON, SA GRANGE, SA EDWARDSTOWN, SA GAWLER, SA 
 Sponsored links Pizza Sale 
 Save Massive!
Sales,Vouchers, Discounts and Deals 
 www.thebargainavenue.com.au/ Pizza Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
 Cudgee Bar 

 Bellissimo Pizza&amp;pasta 
 Coupons (1) 
 
 
 Bellissimo Pizza&amp;pasta 
 Coupons (1) 
 Cudgee Bar 
 Products (1) 
 Pizza Palace 
 Products (1) 
 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 Billy&apos;s Pizza 14-Apr-2011 Crompton Pizza&apos;s 27-Mar-2011 Pizza Palace 29-Sep-2010 Valley Lake Pizza 09-Aug-2010 Ferellis Pizza and Chickens 26-May-2010 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search enquiry 
Most popular
 
 Dominos Pizza Noarlunga Dominos Pizza Gilles Plains Dominos Pizza Murray Bridge The Pizza Round - mobile wood… Pizzas&apos;N&apos;More Dominos Pizza Mount Gambier 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business.
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of use Privacy policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.8.004 )
	</body>
</document>
