<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005783" url="http://www.snagajob.com/restaurant-jobs/casual-dining/" time="2012-07-12-22:25" support="3" score="0.005221431319902328" bingtitle="Casual Dining Jobs | Restaurant Job Applications | Restaurant Job ..." webtitle="Casual Dining Jobs | Restaurant Job Applications | Restaurant Job Search on Snagajob">
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>Cashier; Restaurant manager; Shift manager Looking for fast ... We offer three pay raises in your first year, flexible ... And we foot half the bill when you eat during your shift.</description>
	<body>
		Are you an employer? To post jobs or get hiring solutions, please visit our employer website . Hide this message x 
 Browse Jobs Job Tips Join Today Sign In 
 
 FIND LOCAL JOBS 
 Search with keywords BETA 
Casual Dining Jobs

 

 
Popular Casual Dining Jobs

 Assistant manager Cashier Restaurant manager Shift manager   Looking for fast food jobs ? We got &apos;em. Want more options? See all restaurant jobs . 
 
Employers Now Hiring Casual Dining Jobs

The food and atmosphere at these restaurants might be “casual,” but these companies are all business when it comes to providing awesome working environments for their employees. Many casual dining restaurants offer benefits, free meals, free uniforms and great camaraderie. Not sure what qualifies as a casual dining restaurant? These restaurants fall somewhere between drive-thru windows and a fancy maitre d’. They have servers instead of cashiers, and they typically require employees to have some restaurant experience.

 Browse our collection of casual dining employers that are now accepting online job applications.

 Applebee&apos;s 

Thanks for your interest in a career at Applebee&apos;s. We&apos;re currently accepting online job applications for hourly, management, and support center/corporate positions. Explore job opportunities near you .

 Cracker Barrel 

Looking for an hourly job? Cracker Barrel Old Country Store is always looking for grill cooks, back-up cooks, prep cooks, bus/dishwashers, hosts, servers, cashiers, retail personnel, and night maintenance employees. We offer three pay raises in your first year, flexible scheduling, and paid vacations. You don&apos;t share tips and your wage is on-par with the best in the industry. There&apos;s also training, performance-based pay and benefits, and eligibility for 401K savings plans. And we foot half the bill when you eat during your shift. View our job openings and to fill out an online job application today .

 Dave and Buster&apos;s 

You know how fun it is to hang out at Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s? Well, imagine how fun it is to work at Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s.

Dave&amp;Buster&apos;s employs an elite group of men and women who are considered to be among the very best in the hospitality industry. Since our Team Members are the key to the continued success of our Company, we know that every job is essential.

 Check out our latest career opportunities .

 Golden Corral 

With nearly 500 company and franchise restaurants in 40 states, you&apos;ll find opportunity abounds everywhere. From small communities to major metropolitan areas, you&apos;re sure to find a location that suits your lifestyle. It&apos;s all here. Everything you need to determine the best career path for you. Along with lots of valuable information on our culture, our values, and our benefits. Are you ready to get started? View all Golden Corral job opportunities currently available .

 Joe&apos;s Crab Shack 

Landing a gig at Joe&apos;s is pretty sweet. You’ll work in a fun, hang-loose environment, work with cool people, and enjoy some pretty competitive benefits to boot. Not a bad way to pay the bills, huh? To find your next gig, browse our job listings to find a restaurant job at your neighborhood Joe&apos;s.

 Landry&apos;s Restaurants 

Landry&apos;s Restaurants, Inc. is one of the nation&apos;s largest and fastest-growing casual dining, hospitality and entertainment companies.

The Landry&apos;s culture motivates employees to achieve their full potential. They&apos;re challenged to improve through leadership, focus, intensity and persistence - and to create a work environment of pride, honesty, integrity and loyalty. Innovative training programs designed to strengthen the Company&apos;s management foundation also encourage employees toward career growth. Browse all Landry&apos;s Restaurants jobs 

 Lone Star Steakhouse 

Lone Star Steakhouse&amp;Saloon is highly committed to attracting and retaining the highest quality managers and employees in the industry. Our working environment and incentive structure make Lone Star one of the most attractive restaurant opportunities out there. We are always on the look out for qualified, energetic and self motivated people who would like to work in a fun and rewarding atmosphere.

If you want to work in an exciting, competitive, fun environment? Then your job search is over, become a member of the Lone Star Team today! 

 Texas Land&amp;Cattle 

With our dedication to southern hospitality&amp;great food we have been named the # 1 steakhouse in almost every market we are in. We are a privately held&amp;will continue to grow, as we continue our commitment to being the &apos;Employer of Choice&apos;.

If you are interested in an exciting career at Texas Land&amp;Cattle Steak House simply apply online now!

 Texas Steakhouse 

Welcome to Texas Steakhouse&amp;Saloon. You might be hundreds of miles from one of these ranches right now. But soon your taste buds will be deep in the heart of Texas. View our current job opeings. 

 UNO Chicago Grill 

You can have fun and take pride in providing an enjoyable dining experience to our expanding customer base and in building a solid career and hefty paycheck!

We offer training, growth potential, flexible shifts, competitive wages and medical and dental benefits. Apply online now! 
 
Restaurant Job Resource Center
 See all restaurant job articles » 
 
 Waiter / Waitress jobs 
 Want to be a Bartender? 
 Turn your restaurant job into a career 
 
Quick Facts: Fun Food Jobs

 The most popular day to eat out in the U.S. is Saturday. Second is Friday, third is Sunday. Monday is the slowest day for restaurants. According to the U.S. Department of Labor, there are more than 2 million restaurant servers in the U.S. The hamburger was invented in 1900 by Louis Lassen. He ground beef, broiled it, and served it between two pieces of toast. Of the 14 billion hamburgers eaten in the United States yearly, most of them are consumed in the summer months. Americans eat 20 billion hot dogs a year – an average of 70 hot dogs per person. More hot dogs are eaten in July than any other month of the year, which is why it is designated National Hot Dog Month. 
 


 
Sign up for email Job Alerts
 Get local jobs delivered to your inbox. Email Address ZIP Code Submit 
 
 
 Snagajob Job Seeker Security Center Local Jobs Job Tips Job Seeker Blog My Job, My Health Coupons Right-Fit Degrees Help and FAQ Contact Us Employer Solutions Post Jobs Talent Sourcing Hiring Manager Training Manager Scheduling Manager Recruitment Ad Agency Advertise with Us Affiliate Program Contact Sales About Snagajob Careers Our Story Giving Back Life at Snagajob News ©2000-2012 SnagAJob.com, Inc. All rights reserved Privacy Terms of Use Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
