<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005047" url="http://www.joe.org/joe/2003february/rb1.php" time="2012-07-12-21:34" support="2" score="0.0019498956316477303" bingtitle="Employees and Food Safety: Is Training Important to Food Service ..." webtitle="Employees and Food Safety: Is Training Important to Food Service Managers?">
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>As an alternative, it was decided to add a one-dollar bill ... Similarly, 42% of full-service restaurant managers indicated willingness to pay at least $26 for food ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME JOURNAL GUIDELINES ABOUT JOE CONTACT NATIONAL JOB BANK 
 
 Current Issue Back Issues Search Subscribe 
 
 
February 2003 // Volume 41 // Number 1 // Research in Brief // 1RIB1

 
 
Employees and Food Safety: Is Training Important to Food Service Managers?
 
 Abstract 
A sample of food service managers were surveyed regarding 
 the value they placed on food safety training: whether 
 they would provide higher pay or bonuses for trained 
 new workers or pay a fixed amount for current employee 
 training. They were also asked how important public 
 image was to their business. Approximately 72% indicated 
 they would be more likely to hire food safety trained 
 workers, and 50% would be willing to pay higher wages 
 to those trained. Finally, given tight labor supplies 
 for this sector, 93% were willing to hire trained 
 Welfare-to-Work participants. However, other barriers 
 to hiring these participants remain.

 
 Susan Hine
 Assistant Professor
Internet Address: suehine@lamar.colostate.edu 

 Dawn Thilmany
 Associate Professor
Internet Address: thilmany@lamar.colostate.edu 

 Pat Kendall
 Professor
InternetAddress: pkendall@lamar.colostate.edu 

 Ken Smith
 Associate Professor
Internet address: kdsmith@cahs.colostate.edu 

Colorado State University
Fort Collins, Colorado
 
 
Introduction

In 1998, Cooperative Extension specialists in Colorado, 
 Wyoming, and Montana conducted focus groups with restaurant 
 workers and managers to help identify motivators and 
 barriers to safe food handling practices in restaurant 
 settings. A recurrent theme was the shortage of workers 
 trained in safe food handling procedures and an overall 
 high turnover rate among restaurant employees. Discussions 
 with food service managers indicated a strong preference 
 to hire workers with training in safe food handling 
 procedures (Kendall, Melcher, Pelican,&amp;Paul 
 1998).

The CSREES-USDA Food Safety and Quality National 
 Initiative, which funded the study discussed in this 
 article, seeks to target food handler education programs 
 for high-risk and hard-to-reach clientele. One such 
 group includes former welfare assistance recipients 
 who are now required to seek job training and are 
 uncertain as to what skills will improve their value 
 to employers. The goals of the study were to assess:

 Importance managers placed on safe food handling 
 skills Importance of public image for food service managers Interest in integrating food safety training into 
 welfare-to-work job training programs Labor market implications of food safety training 
 for these food service managers Extension personnel&apos;s role in this effort 

Background

The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) 
 estimate that approximately 76 million cases of foodborne 
 illness result in 325,000 hospitalizations and 5,000 
 deaths annually (Mead et al., 1999). The yearly cost 
 of lost productivity alone is estimated at between 
 $20 and $40 billion in the U.S. (FDA, 1997).

Barriers to safe food handling practices for food 
 service establishments are of increasing concern as 
 Americans eat away from home more often. According 
 to the National Restaurant Association (2000), half 
 of all adults are restaurant patrons on a typical 
 day. Moreover, public health officials have predicted 
 that foodborne illness may become even more of a problem 
 in the years to come (US-DHHS, 2000).

The FDA&apos;s report, FDA Retail Food Program Database 
 of Foodborne Illness Risk Factors (2000), presents 
 data to establish a national baseline of foodborne 
 illness risk factors and for measuring the current 
 status of occurrence of these factors. Among the establishments 
 studied were fast food and full-service restaurants. 
 The baseline data collected reflected the Food Code 
 provisions on the occurrence of five risk factors:

 Food from unsafe sources Inadequate cooking Improper holding temperature Contaminated equipment Poor personal hygiene 

Each of these issues is addressed in this study&apos;s 
 survey. Further, within each of these categories, 
 the FDA recorded&quot;out of compliance&quot;observations 
 of more than 40% in both fast-food and full-service 
 restaurants:

 Cold holding at 41 degrees F or below Ready-to-eat foods held cold at 41 degrees F 
 or below Commercially processed foods date-marked Surfaces, utensils cleaned and sanitized Proper hand washing 

These statistics pointed to a need for more employees 
 trained in proper food handling techniques. In 1995, 
 ServSafe Training (the National Restaurant Association&apos;s 
 food safety training program) was adopted as a training 
 tool for Colorado, Wyoming, and Montana. It was expanded 
 in l997 and l998 with a train the trainer program. 
 Over the 3 years ending in 2000, over 1,157 food handlers 
 in Colorado had participated in the program.

Labor Management Challenges: Welfare-to-Work

Labor management challenges for the restaurant industry 
 go far beyond the need for food safety training. The 
 Colorado Restaurant Association (CRA) reports labor 
 shortages throughout the late 1990&apos;s were due to a 
 2.6% unemployment rate while restaurant sales in the 
 state increased 6.1% annually (Husted, 2000). This 
 led to short-staffed food service establishments, 
 and managers suggest this is a barrier to safe food 
 handling (Kendall et. al, 1998). The study focused 
 on one potential pool of foodservice workers, those 
 individuals on welfare or taking part in federal assistance 
 programs.

The Colorado welfare-to-work program offers potential 
 employers subsidies and tax credits, and seeks to 
 provide training and skills that are in high demand 
 among Colorado employers (Colorado Welfare Reform, 
 2000). Our Extension personnel have been active in 
 attending sessions with the Colorado program directors 
 to better assess the need for food safety training 
 among this potential labor source.

One assumption motivating the study was that employers 
 may be reluctant to hire persons on welfare because 
 they fear:

 The person will not have the requisite skills 
 needed to prepare and/or serve food to customers 
 in a safe and efficient manner and They (the employers) will not have the time needed 
 to adequately train the person. 

Thus, it was felt to be important for Extension agents 
 to be able to provide a food safety education certificate 
 program for welfare-to-work participants that showed 
 that these workers had acquired the necessary knowledge 
 and skills. This would be of benefit both to those 
 needing jobs and those in the food service industry 
 needing trained workers.

Methodology

An important component of the project was to establish 
 the potential value of food safety training for both 
 the employer and the employee, information Extension 
 agents would be able to use in promoting the value 
 of food safety training and its implied benefits to 
 food service managers. The survey was used to indirectly 
 determine the value of food safety programs and specific 
 skills or knowledge associated with the training.

The survey asked questions with respect to the company&apos;s 
 operations and food safety training practices, including 
 basic description of the type of food service, use 
 of external and internal training programs, financial 
 incentives to employees trained in food safety, and 
 overall happiness with training received on several 
 food safety issues. Kendall et al (2001) focus on 
 the overall satisfaction with food safety training 
 while the findings presented here focus on the following 
 topics:

 The relative importance of food safety issues 
 to managers Management&apos;s willingness to pay for safety training 
 in the form of wages, pay raises, promotion, and 
 actual training programs The level of importance placed on public image 
 by managers 

Focus groups with several food service managers were 
 used to test the survey and increase the readability 
 of survey question. When asked about methods to increase 
 response rate, several participants noted that phone 
 calls and other follow-up measures commonly used for 
 consumer surveys may not be appropriate or effective. 
 As an alternative, it was decided to add a one-dollar 
 bill to the survey to show appreciation to respondents.

In early 2000, 500 surveys were mailed to restaurant 
 managers in Colorado, Wyoming, and Montana. The sample 
 was drawn from former ServSafe participants (because 
 there was interest in how past participants rated 
 that program), restaurant association mailing lists, 
 and yellow pages. The resulting response rate was 
 28%, which is comparatively low, but as high as one 
 can expect for a sector that has relatively significant 
 time constraints, little office staff, and less formal 
 organizational structure.

Results

The restaurant managers who responded to the survey 
 were not fully representative of restaurant demographics, 
 likely due to the fact that corporate-based restaurants 
 were less likely to respond to surveys if most correspondence 
 is referred to a national corporate office. Among 
 respondents, 43% managed full-service restaurants, 
 33% managed limited service restaurants, and the rest 
 worked with a variety of types of establishments, 
 including cafeterias, catering, and bars/taverns.

On average, respondents&apos; businesses served 408 guests 
 per day and employed 18.8 full and 15.3 part-time 
 employees at their locations. Approximately 45% of 
 the meals were served at lunch, 32% at dinner, and 
 the rest at breakfast and other times.

 Food Safety Issues and Hiring Practices 

Respondents were asked to rank the level of attention 
 and time spent on the following food safety issues:

 Personal hygiene Avoiding cross-contamination Adequate cooking Time-temperature control Avoiding food from unsafe sources Pest control management Time 

A ranking scale of 1 to 5 was used, with 5 representing 
 the most attention or time spent on any one factor. 
 As expected, food service managers ranked all food 
 safety skills as high (See Figure 1). In particular, 
 however, close to 60% of the managers ranked cross-contamination 
 highest. Pest control training received the lowest 
 ranking, with only about 31% of respondents rating 
 this factor a 5 and 5% assigning pest control training 
 an importance value of 1.

 Figure 1.
 Ranking of Food Safety Issues

 

Next, managers were asked how satisfied they were 
 with the training that they received for these issues 
 from ServSafe or other sources. Many were very satisfied, 
 with 56% (using a Likert scale of 1-5) believing that 
 the training had actually decreased food safety concerns 
 for their business, 20% giving raises to workers who 
 attended the training, and 20% promoting employees 
 based on their participation in food safety training. 
 See Table 1.

 Table 1.
 Training Satisfaction and Willingness to Pay

 
 Variable 
 
 Yes 
 
Willing to Hire 
 Welfare-to-Work Trainees
 
93%
 
Likely to Hire 
 Previously Trained Workers
 
72%
 
 Decrease of 
 Safety Concerns 
 
 56% 
 
Bring in Trained 
 Worker at Higher Level
 
54%
 
Pay a Higher Beginning 
 Salary
 
39%
 
 Give Pay Raise 
 for Attending a Training 
 
 20% 
 
 Promote Worker 
 after Attending a Training 
 
 20% 
 
Pay a Signing Bonus
 
14%
 

 Willingness to Pay for Safety Training 

How does this translate into a willingness to pay 
 for programs and/or offer higher wage premiums, promotions, 
 or even bonuses? When asked what they would 
 be willing to pay for training programs, 79% of managers 
 said that they would be willing to pay some dollar 
 amount ranging anywhere from $5 to $150, with the 
 largest percentage (29%) willing to pay between $11-$25. 
 The breakdown of premiums shows that 20% of these 
 managers were willing to pay at least $.51 to $1.00 
 in additional hourly wages. See Table 2.

 Table 2.
 Willingness to Pay Fees for Training Programs

 
 Fee for Training Program 
 
 Percent 
 
 Hourly Wage Premium 
 
 Percent 
 
$0
 
21%
 
$0
 
34%
 
$5-10
 
14%
 
$0.05-0.25
 
9%
 
$11-15
 
29%
 
$0.26-0.50
 
27%
 
$26-50
 
17%
 
$0.51-1.00
 
20%
 
$51-100
 
12%
 
$1.01-1.50
 
3%
 
$101-150
 
7%
 
$1.51-2.00
 
4%
     
Over $2.00
 
3%
 

Managers were also asked if they were willing to 
 pay signing bonuses to trained workers but only 14% 
 said yes. In addition, 54% of managers say they might 
 hire those trained in food safety at a higher level, 
 and 72% were more likely hire those individuals with 
 previous training. See Figure 2.

 Figure 2. 
Value of Training

 

It was thought that full-service restaurants may 
 have more concern about image, leading to a higher 
 willingness to pay for food safety training programs 
 and willingness to pay a higher wage to workers trained 
 in food safety compared to limited service restaurants. 
 In fact, managers of full-service restaurants indicated 
 greater willingness to pay a higher starting salary 
 to workers with previous food safety training than 
 did managers of limited service restaurants (75% vs. 
 54%).

Further, 40% of managers from full-service restaurants 
 were willing to pay at least $0.50 more per hour, 
 compared to only 20% of managers of limited service 
 restaurants. Not surprisingly, 80% of managers of 
 full-service restaurants indicated some willingness 
 to pay for food safety training, compared to 69% of 
 limited service restaurant managers. Similarly, 42% 
 of full-service restaurant managers indicated willingness 
 to pay at least $26 for food safety training, compared 
 to 21% of limited service restaurant managers.

Although not presented here, these restaurant types 
 were almost indistinguishable in their ratings on 
 the importance of food safety issues and satisfaction 
 with past food safety training. These findings would 
 indicate that while the importance of food safety 
 issues and satisfaction with food safety training 
 do not vary by location and type of restaurant, willingness 
 on the part of restaurants to pay both directly and 
 indirectly for food safety training does vary.

It was interesting to note, however, that many managers 
 unwilling to pay bonuses to workers with training 
 were still willing to pay for the training sessions. 
 See Table 3.

 Table 3.
 Managers Not Willing to Pay a Hiring Bonus but 
 Willing to Pay for Training Session

 
 Amount of Fee Willing to 
 Pay 
 
 Percent 
 
$0
 
22%
 
$5-10
 
16%
 
$11-15
 
31%
 
$26-50
 
14%
 
$51-100
 
12%
 
$101-150
 
5%
 

 Importance of Public Image 

We next asked managers to rate the importance of 
 different factors that affected the public image of 
 their business. These included:

 Health inspection scores Bad publicity Clean and sanitary image Customer satisfaction Promoting food safety record to customers Promoting food safety training to customers Word-of-mouth referrals 

As shown in Figure 3, respondents ranked all factors 
 relatively high. The highest ranked concerns across 
 the sample were customer satisfaction, the desire 
 to be known for a clean and sanitary image, concern 
 about bad publicity, word-of-mouth referrals, and 
 health inspection scores. The need to promote food 
 safety records and training seemed the least important, 
 which would make sense, for, if the restaurant promotes 
 a clean image and customer satisfaction, the training 
 and safety records would speak for themselves.

 Figure 3.
 Importance of Various Factors on Public Image 
 of Business: Ranked from 1 to 5, with 5 Being the 
 Most Important

 

Food Safety, Labor Market, and Extension Implications

Employers understand the positive and necessary value 
 of safety training programs and emphasize training 
 as important employment qualification, but few have 
 hired trained workers. However, these same employers 
 are at least willing to do so and would even be more 
 willing to bring these individuals in at a higher 
 level than pay to for training themselves. If given 
 the choice, most managers would choose training incentives 
 that require no ready outlays of cash payments.

The study discussed sought to better understand both 
 potential problems by enumerating and publicizing 
 the value of specific skills and the overall value 
 of food safety training to the food service industry. 
 The findings provide some support that managers do 
 value food safety training to private managers, in 
 addition to the public benefits defined in the introduction. 
 Our Extension specialists developed a display and 
 brochure with these findings for distribution at job 
 service offices to assist in recruiting trainees. 
 It is important that they and other Extension personnel 
 continue to have a presence at the statewide meetings 
 where this kind of information can be disseminated 
 to public Workforce personnel.

Based on interviews with workforce centers around 
 the state, however, hiring activity among food managers 
 has been minimal, showing a discrepancy between what 
 employers say and what they may do. This may be explained 
 by the challenges presented by shift work in this 
 industry. Research shows that single mothers have 
 been most likely to take advantage of increased minimum 
 wages and welfare reform (Turner, 2000). Yet, childcare 
 constraints make their availability for food service 
 shifts problematic.

Alternatively, concerns about reliability and&quot;soft 
 work skills&quot;may prevent food service managers 
 from hiring welfare recipients. A National Restaurant 
 Association policy brief (1997) noted that state welfare-reform 
 agencies had only begun to address such key issues 
 as the lack of available childcare, health care, and 
 transportation. Government agencies may be working 
 to match welfare recipients with employers, but those 
 who study welfare reform say government help has traditionally 
 been in short supply once a company actually puts 
 welfare workers on the payroll.

Of more direct relevance to this project, few welfare 
 recipients saw food service as an attractive employment 
 option to aspire to, as evidenced by the lack of interest 
 in food safety training offered through Colorado workforce 
 offices through this project. There was anecdotal 
 evidence that training in hard skills that were perceived 
 to have greater value in the labor market were more 
 likely to draw trainees than food safety skills.

Indirectly, this study found that pre-employment 
 food safety training may not be valued by labor market 
 participants and, instead, that value will be created 
 once a worker is on the job and managers communicate 
 the need for stronger food handling skills. Thus, 
 these findings should motivate Extension personnel 
 to promote the implicit value of food safety training 
 and to find more ways to encourage employers to directly 
 support food safety training through training fees 
 or the pay incentives that they say they are willing 
 to provide.

References

Cochran-Yantis, D., Belo, P., Giampaoli, J., McProud, 
 L., Everly, V.,&amp;Gans, J. (1996). Attitudes and 
 knowledge of food safety among Santa Clara County, 
 California restaurant operators. Journal of Foodservice 
 Systems , 9, 117-28.

Colorado Welfare Reform (2000). Available at: http://carbon.cudenver.edu/public/cwr/ 

FDA (Food and Drug Administration) Retail Food Program 
 Steering Committee (2000). Report of the FDA Retail 
 Food Program Database of Foodborne Illness Risk Factors. 
 Washington, D.C.: FDA Center for Food Safety and Applied 
 Nutrition. Available at: http://www.cfsan.fda.gov/~dms/retrsk.html 

FDA/USDA/EPA (Food and Drug Administration, U.S. 
 Department of Agriculture and Environmental Protection 
 Agency) (1997). Food safety from farm to table: 
 A national food safety initiative . Report to the 
 President. Washington, DC: FDA, USDA, EPA.

Husted, B. (2000). Fat economy leaves city&apos;s eateries 
 hungry for workers. Denver Post , April 2, A-2.

Kendall, P., Smith, K., Thilmany, D., Hine, S., Melcher, 
 L.&amp;Paul, L. (2001) Value of and satisfaction 
 with food safety training in the intermountain West. Foodservice Research International, 13 (October): 
 1-16. 

Kendall, P, Melcher, L., Pelican, S.,&amp;Paul, 
 L. (1998). Motivators and barriers to safe food 
 handling practices among food service workers and 
 managers in restaurants . Society for Nutrition 
 Education Annual Meeting, Albuquerque, NM, July 21.

Mean, P.S., Slutsker, L., Dietz, V., McCaig, L.F., 
 Bresee, J.S., Shapiro, C. Griffin, P.M.,&amp;Tauxe, 
 R.V. (1999). Food-related illness and death in the 
 United States. Emerging infectious disease. Journal 
 of Food Protection , 5, 607-625.

National Restaurant Association (NRA) (2000). National 
 restaurant fact book . Chicago, IL.

National Restaurant Association. (1997) People-to-work 
 initiatives: Nurturing the American dream . Available 
 at: http://www.restaurant.org/rusa/magArticle.cfm?ArticleID=589 

Turner, M.D. (2000). The effect of minimum wage 
 on TANF caseloads . Joint Center for Poverty Research 
 Working Paper. http://www.jcpr.org/ 

US-DHHS (U.S. Department of Health and Human Services) 
 (2000). Healthy people 2010: Understanding and 
 improving health . Washington, D.C.: DHHS, Public 
 Health Service, Office of Disease Prevention and Health 
 Promotion. Available at: http://www.health.gov/healthypeople/ 
 
 Copyright © by Extension
 Journal, Inc. ISSN 1077-5315. Articles appearing in the Journal
 become the property of the Journal. Single copies of articles may be
 reproduced in electronic or print form for use in educational or training
 activities. Inclusion of articles in other publications, electronic sources,
 or systematic large-scale distribution may be done only with prior electronic
 or written permission of the Journal
 Editorial Office , joe-ed@joe.org .

If you have difficulties viewing or printing this page, please contact JOE Technical
 Support 
 
©Copyright by Extension Journal, Inc. ISSN 1077-5315. Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
