<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005328" url="http://www.goodhousekeeping.com/health/diet-plans/diet-cruise-fastfood-0806" time="2012-07-12-21:52" support="6" score="0.01582153732886052" bingtitle="Jorge Cruise - Fast Food Diet - Good Housekeeping" webtitle="Jorge Cruise - Fast Food Diet - Good Housekeeping">
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000145" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="138"/>
	<description>The caveats: Yes, you can eat some fast food -- but forget hitting the drive-through seven days a week. ... This quick St. Paddy’s Day table update doesn’t ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement
 
 Give a Gift Customer Service 

 Games Win Promotions Video 


 Search 
 Try: Summer Books • Travel Mugs • Quick Dinners 
 
 Food&amp;Recipes 
Bobby Flay&apos;s Summer Party Recipes
 Read More! 
 Recipe Finder Quick&amp;Easy Recipes Healthy Recipes Everyday Meals Dessert Recipes Cooking Tips Entertaining&amp;Table Settings &quot;Inside the Test Kitchen&quot; Blog 
 Home&amp;Organizing 
Home Decor Made in the USA
 Read More! 
 Cleaning&amp;Organizing Craft Ideas&amp;DIY Projects Home Decorating Ideas Repair&amp;Renovation Gardening&amp;Plants Green Living Hints from Heloise Home Style Blog 
 Diet&amp;Health 
Which Diet Will Work for You?
 Read More! 
 Diet Plans&amp;Tips Nutrition Fitness&amp;Exercise Health Wellness Diet&amp;Health Tools 
 Beauty&amp;Anti-Aging 
What to Wear This Summer
 Read More! 
 Makeovers Hairstyle, Color, and Haircut Ideas Anti-Aging&amp;Skincare Makeup Tips Fashion Trends Nail Care Virtual Anti-Aging Tool Virtual Makeover Tool 
 Family&amp;Relationships 
Best Beach Reads
 Read More! 
 Marriage&amp;Sex Advice Parenting Tips Money&amp;Budgeting Family Travel&amp;Activities Pet Advice Peggy Post Etiquette Celebrity Interviews&amp;Quotes Books&amp;Blogs 
 Holidays 
10 Things to Do Before Labor Day
 Read More! 
 Valentine&apos;s Day Easter&amp;Passover Mother&apos;s Day Father&apos;s Day 4th of July Halloween Thanksgiving Christmas&amp;Hanukkah Gift Ideas 
 Product Reviews 
Stellar Paper Shredders
 Read More! 
 Appliances Beauty&amp;Makeup Cars&amp;Travel Products Children&apos;s Items&amp;Toys Clothing&amp;Shoes Cooking Tools Eco-Friendly Products Electronics&amp;Computers Food&amp;Drink Health&amp;Fitness Home&amp;Garden Inside the Institute Blog 
 
 Homepage &gt; Diet&amp;Health &gt; Diet Plans&amp;Tips 
Jorge Cruise&apos;s Fast-Food Diet

Craving burgers and pizza? How to eat the takeout you love -- and still lose big.

By Jorge Cruise 
 Email Print Share 
Special Offers
 • • 
Hooray! No more Whopper guilt. With this guide, you can order fast food as often as once a day without sabotaging your diet. The secret is choosing the right menu items -- and that can be tricky. A salad, for example, can seem superhealthy but be packed with calories. Your safest bet: Stick with the low-cal, tasty options I&apos;ve chosen for you here.
 The plan: To lose weight, you should consume about 1,400 calories a day. So I&apos;ve suggested breakfast, lunch, and dinner foods that are around 400 calories each. I&apos;ve also listed 100-cal snacks, which you may eat twice daily. Follow this plan and you can lose up to two pounds a week.

 The caveats: Yes, you can eat some fast food -- but forget hitting the drive-through seven days a week. My picks are good for weight loss, but they are not as nutritionally balanced as a meal you might cook at home. So if you eat, say, a Subway breakfast, load up on fruits and veggies at your other two meals. And don&apos;t forget: Drink plenty of water and take a daily multivitamin. Ready to start? Just print out this guide and stash it in your car.
 Email Print Share Next 
Latest Stories
 

 
 Food
&amp;Recipes 
Bobby Flay&apos;s Summer Party Recipes
 
Chef Flay&apos;s crowd-friendly menu
 Home
&amp;Organizing 
Home Decor Made in the USA
 
Fabulous home decor finds, all made in the USA
 Diet
&amp;Health 
Which Diet Will Work for You?
 
Take this quiz to find out
 Beauty
&amp;Anti-Aging 
What to Wear This Summer
 
Tropical-toned looks for $75 and under
 Family
&amp;Relationships 
Best Beach Reads
 
Books to tote on vacation
	</body>
</document>
