<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005699" url="http://2012predictions.org/see-the-number-everywhere-t1731.html" time="2012-07-12-22:17" support="14" score="0.028952668126999034" bingtitle="I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE : Numerology - Psychics Predictions ..." webtitle="I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE : Numerology - 2012 Predictions - End of the World?">
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>-going to fast food restaurant and total comes out to 11 ... Try it with a random number, or simply make sure you take note of all the ... Count from Jan 11 back 111 days, ok? I ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content 
 
 Advanced search 
 Board index ‹ Astrology ‹ Numerology Change font size E-mail friend Print view 

 FAQ Register Login 
 
 I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 
 Numerology is the art of using numbers to make predictions. Patterns in numbers like always seeing 1:11 on the clock or 11:11. Adding, subtracting and dividing certain numbers could have significant meanings.
 
 Loading... 
 
 Post a reply First unread post •168 posts• Page 1 of 17 • 1 , 2 , 3 , 4 , 5 ... 17 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by Card Storm »Tue Jan 19, 2010 1:11 am
 Hello. My name is 11 letters long. For years I have been seeing the number everywhere. I believe this started happening a couple years after 911, so I know it wasn&apos;t a direct result of knowing that 911 happened. It all started when I would turn my head and the clock would read 11:11. I didn&apos;t think much on it, however the four ones in a row did seem pretty odd. Then I started seeing the clocks read 1:11, 2:11, 3:11 and so on. I still passed it off as coincidence until it just became too much. I told a couple of my friends and surprisingly they didn&apos;t think I was crazy. One of my friends said that their lucky number was 117. So then I started seeing the numbers on receipts.

Here are a list of instances

-going to fast food restaurant and total comes out to 11:11

-Going to a grocery store and halfway through check out line you glance above your head and notice it&apos;s line 11.

-teachers in class lecturing a topic then saying Eleven, as a number significant and relevant to whatever they were lecturing about.

-gas pump stopping at 11:11 various times, and actually just today it stopped at 11:22.

-driving with my friends who know I see 11, and the big truck in front of us says 11.

-when i worked at kroger in 2004 I would come across boxes that would just be marked with the number 11

-got a confirmation email from verizon and they used &apos;1111&apos; to confirm that I got the email on my blackberry

-I was born in the 11th state in alphabetical order, Hawaii.

-all of my closest friends had 11 letters in their name.

-expiration dates reading 11/11 for November.

-my first cellphone bill was due every 11th of the month, this was in 2004 around the time I first starting seeing 11 and realizing it&apos;s significance.

-every 11th of the month were the oddest days ever, and my friends were witnesses of it.

-I actually FOUND 11 dollars exactly in a basket cart when I worked at kroger in 2005. That&apos;s the only time I&apos;ve ever found money.

-One day me and two friends went to this man made lake behind a church everyone calls&quot;blue lagoon&quot;There are lots of sandy hills we walked around those and I looked down and saw a white sock. On top of the white sock was a dime and a penny. 11 cents. Also, one of those times where friends witnessed it so it was hard for them not to believe me.

-two folks walking past me and their soccer jerseys read 11

-oh boy. here&apos;s a scary one. There&apos;s this old abandoned castle in Austin, Texas. i was with a friend and his aunt and uncle. I had heard of a castle in Austin, so I asked them did they know of any castles. As I said that we saw a castle top sticking up from some trees on the side of the road on a hill. We drove up the hill and just so happened to be on 11th street. then when we pulled up to the castle style house the address read 1111. If you don&apos;t believe me this place actually exists and that moment made me know this was real. I got lead to the number, I didn&apos;t look for it. If you don&apos;t believe me go to this link. http://www.austinexplorer.com/Locations/ShowLocation.aspx?LocationID=1973 

there are so many more instances, but i never knew what any of this meant. finally i have come across information regarding 2012 and 11:11. After praying many times for god to stop letting me see this number if it doesn&apos;t mean anything, yet I see it stronger afterwards. I know that it means something, so for anyone else may happen to experience this too, please post your experience, maybe we can come to some type of similarity between us all and work together to do what it is we are meant to do and prepare for.

I played trumpet,
I like the keyboard, kinda natural at it
i like architecture
film
nature
sci/fi Last edited by Card Storm on Wed Jan 19, 2011 1:39 am, edited 1 time in total. Card Storm   Posts: 24 Joined: Tue Jan 19, 2010 12:46 am Top 

 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by ddd »Tue Jan 19, 2010 5:02 am
 I think this is the same as looking at the clock. You go out into the world with certain numbers on your mind and pick those numbers out. Once again, focus on say 23 for a few months and see what happens. If you read back through the other thread you&apos;ll see examples of all different numbers. With me, its usually 9:11, and it really does seem like I see it all the time, but when i think about it without bias I am quick to realize that the only reason it seems that way is because of the significance I place on those numbers. You don&apos;t remember all the times you see 5:41 or 7:17 because you don&apos;t place significance in those numbers, also because it&apos;s less of a pattern as 11, or 33, 44.

Try it with a random number, or simply make sure you take note of all the numbers you see. You&apos;ll notice 11 doesn&apos;t crop up nearly as often as you seem to think. 
 ddd   Posts: 226 Joined: Tue May 12, 2009 12:20 am Location: The Land Of Oz Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by Card Storm »Tue Jan 19, 2010 11:35 pm
 I thank you so much for your response and I do agree that there are things that stick out to us. However, how do you explain me not seeing the number for over 3 months, then suddenly on January 11th I start seeing it really really strong, everywhere I turn my head. Then an Earthquake happens in Haiti. Now I have been seeing it incredibly strong again. So it&apos;s not something that happens every minute, but certain times in my life the number will pop up, then go on for a continuous amount of time, then decrease again. Before I never paid attention to what it might mean because I was what 16? None of the crap made sense. Why is it that for years I prayed to stop seeing it, then it would come stronger. Do you believe in God? Doesn&apos;t have to be the God of other religions, but do you believe in a higher being? Card Storm   Posts: 24 Joined: Tue Jan 19, 2010 12:46 am Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by indigoprincess33 »Wed Jan 20, 2010 6:21 pm
 Hi Chad,

I started seeing 11:11 over a year ago. It was happening at least once a day every day for a week. Then the following week I started to see 1:11 as well. I stared to get annoyed and wondered why I kept seeing all these 1&apos;s. Sometimes I wouldn&apos;t even want to look at the time but my eyes would just go there and sure enough 11:11 and 1:11. I started to do some research and came across a few websites. Soon I started seeing 3:33 (still everyday) and then 4:44, 5:55, 12:34, 1:23, and 9:11. I don&apos;t just see it on clocks. Everything from receipts, change given, house numbers, kms on my car, etc. I told my dad about this and he said he&apos;s seen the number 7:47 on the clock almost everyday since he was younger. I see 7:47 all the time now too. I&apos;m not sure what it all means, but I&apos;ll pass along a few websites. I used to be annoyed and thought I was going crazy but now I find it amusing. I don&apos;t think it&apos;s a mere coincidence. My life has definitely changed in a positive way since I started seeing these numbers, which I continue to see all the time. They have guided in some way. I would embrace it. I think it&apos;s a positive thing.

I found it amusing that when I finished reading your forum and wondered if I should reply. I looked at the clock and it was 1:23. That was my answer. I&apos;m not sure if you noticed but you posted your forum at 1:11. A coincidence... maybe?

 http://www.1111angels.net/content/view/11/25/ 

 


 indigoprincess33   Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by ddd »Wed Jan 20, 2010 10:19 pm
 Card Storm wrote: I thank you so much for your response and I do agree that there are things that stick out to us. However, how do you explain me not seeing the number for over 3 months, then suddenly on January 11th I start seeing it really really strong, everywhere I turn my head. 

The perfect example! You noticed that it was Jan 11, which got the gears going again and low and behold, you began seeing it everywhere again. Seriously, even now, take note of every number you see. Make a list, and see how often the number is 11. I&apos;m not knocking you, I know the feeling you&apos;ve got myself as do most of us at one time or another, but try, as an experiment to yourself, to look upon this in an unbiased way. Try making this list and see what happens.
I did this once, and it quickly became apparent that i was not seeing the same number all the time. I was only remembering the times that i did.

 Do you believe in God? Doesn&apos;t have to be the God of other religions, but do you believe in a higher being? 

I don&apos;t know. I consider myself an atheist - at least where earthly notion of religion is concerned. I&apos;m more of a believer in the evidence for natural cause and effect rather than intelligent motivation, but ultimately, like everyone else, I guess I have to say &apos;I don&apos;t know&quot;. 
 ddd   Posts: 226 Joined: Tue May 12, 2009 12:20 am Location: The Land Of Oz Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by ddd »Wed Jan 20, 2010 10:24 pm
 indigoprincess33 wrote: Sometimes I wouldn&apos;t even want to look at the time but my eyes would just go there and sure enough 11:11 and 1:11. I started to do some research and came across a few websites. Soon I started seeing 3:33 (still everyday) and then 4:44, 5:55, 12:34, 1:23, and 9:11. I don&apos;t just see it on clocks. Everything from receipts, change given, house numbers, kms on my car, etc. I told my dad about this and he said he&apos;s seen the number 7:47 on the clock almost everyday since he was younger. I see 7:47 all the time now too. 

See what I mean chad, look at these numbers. Patterns. All of them! What the cognitive areas of our brain are best at. The way you can see the most complex picture, complete with fine details, sometimes when looking at the clouds. Pulling patterns out of chaos. 
 ddd   Posts: 226 Joined: Tue May 12, 2009 12:20 am Location: The Land Of Oz Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by Card Storm »Wed Jan 20, 2010 11:23 pm
 Thanks a lot for sharing this fellow Elevener. 

something else happened tonight during my late night class. Today was my first day back but most of the people in my class I already knew because it was a continuation of part one of last semesters class. One of the classmates had a tape recorder and I asked him why, he said to record his ideas (it&apos;s a film class)

so I caught a glimpse of the screen and swore I saw 11, quickly before he changed anything I go hey let me see the screen again, and he showed it to me and sure enough the screen had a big digital 11 on it. I asked him why does it say 11? He goes, that&apos;s how many things I&apos;ve recorded so far. I just said oh....and continued.

Then I realized including the teacher we have 11 people in the class. Card Storm   Posts: 24 Joined: Tue Jan 19, 2010 12:46 am Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by mitch »Thu Jan 21, 2010 10:56 pm
 Don&apos;t feel like you are alone, you&apos;re not. I have seen patterns in numbers all my life. You are one of the few with a gift that few understand. Pay no attention to those who would ridicule you. Just remain mindful of what you see, document it and move on. Whatever you do don&apos;t let it consume you it can be a curse as well as a gift. Don&apos;t ignore it and don&apos;t lose any sleep over it. Work on the numbers when you have rested. For me it&apos;s 3 and 11, it took me a while to accept the fact that I wasn&apos;t crazy. As to why this happens, well I think it will eventually be revealed to all of us but to me it almost seems as if it&apos;s some sort of precognitive countdown. So just relax, and know your not alone. mitch   Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by Card Storm »Fri Jan 22, 2010 12:36 am
 ddd wrote: Card Storm wrote: I thank you so much for your response and I do agree that there are things that stick out to us. However, how do you explain me not seeing the number for over 3 months, then suddenly on January 11th I start seeing it really really strong, everywhere I turn my head. 

The perfect example! You noticed that it was Jan 11, which got the gears going again and low and behold, you began seeing it everywhere again. Seriously, even now, take note of every number you see. Make a list, and see how often the number is 11. I&apos;m not knocking you, I know the feeling you&apos;ve got myself as do most of us at one time or another, but try, as an experiment to yourself, to look upon this in an unbiased way. Try making this list and see what happens.
I did this once, and it quickly became apparent that i was not seeing the same number all the time. I was only remembering the times that i did.

 Do you believe in God? Doesn&apos;t have to be the God of other religions, but do you believe in a higher being? 

I don&apos;t know. I consider myself an atheist - at least where earthly notion of religion is concerned. I&apos;m more of a believer in the evidence for natural cause and effect rather than intelligent motivation, but ultimately, like everyone else, I guess I have to say &apos;I don&apos;t know&quot;. 

Here&apos;s why I don&apos;t agree with you. I didn&apos;t realize it was the 11th until I after i started seeing 11 everywhere, after parking on the 11th floor in the garage at work, and after getting many orders that totaled to be 111.00 in the same day so then when I actually realized it was the 11th I let actually said&quot;that&apos;s why I&apos;m seeing 11 everywhere it&apos;s the 11th&quot;. When the earthquake happened the next day I had no idea until 2 days later, and during those two days I saw 11 11 a lot and even took pictures of the instances. Then I found out about the earth quake and it made since. Card Storm   Posts: 24 Joined: Tue Jan 19, 2010 12:46 am Top 
 Report this post Reply with quote 

 Re: I see the number 11 EVERYWHERE 

 by mitchellhawk »Fri Jan 22, 2010 3:19 pm
 You said it was over 3 months since you saw the 11s again. Count from Jan 11 back 111 days, ok? I came up with Sept. 24, 2009,----&gt;9/24/2009----&gt;9+24+09= 44. 44/4=11. These periodic breaks in the sight of the number 11 may be a warning of things to come, now who sounds crazy? Of course I&apos;m only saying 111 days back because it would not surprise me. That is why I document dates and times. FOR you it may have been 92 days or 99 days. just saying! mitchellhawk   Top Next Display posts from previous: All posts 1 day 7 days 2 weeks 1 month 3 months 6 months 1 year Sort by Author Post time Subject Ascending Descending Post a reply 168 posts• Page 1 of 17 • 1 , 2 , 3 , 4 , 5 ... 17 


 Return to Numerology 
 Jump to: Select a forum ------------------ 2012   End of the World   Doomsday   Nibiru   World War 3   Polar Shift   Mayans Predictions   Nostradamus   Edgar Cayce   Hopi Prophecy   Bible Codes   Web bot   I Ching   Consciousness Shift   Conspiracy Theories   Pandemic   Bizarre Astrology   Numerology   Dreams   Psychics Religion   God   Antichrist   NDE   New Age   Evolution Ufos   Ufo Sightings   Alien Abductions Disasters   Earthquakes   Floods   Man Made Disasters   Wildfires   Hurricanes   Survival   Riots   Tsunami   Volcanoes   Economic Collapse Astronomy   Solar Flare   Asteroids and Comets   Black Holes Introduce Yourself   Chat   Apologies   

 
 Related topics Replies Views Last post 

 The NUMBER of the TOPICS 
 1 , 2 by isomer13 »Fri Apr 09, 2010 9:16 am 12 Replies 1827 Views Last post by isomer13 
Sat May 19, 2012 8:52 am
 Numerology 
 
Who is online

Users browsing this forum: No registered users and 0 guests
 
 Board index The team • Delete all board cookies •All times are UTC - 5 hours [ DST ] 

  News  Site map  SitemapIndex  RSS Feed  Channel list 
 Operated by Computer Repair Palm Coast 

 Advertisements by Advertisement Management
	</body>
</document>
