<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005894" url="http://www.delish.com/food-fun/quizzes/fast-food-slogans-quiz" time="2012-07-12-22:34" support="11" score="0.03753609869353373" bingtitle="Are You a Master of Fast-Food Slogans? - Recipes, Party Food ..." webtitle="Fast-Food Slogans ID Quiz - Delish.com">
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001026" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>... Freshness Guide Flower Arranging Table Settings Napkin ... dining and lounge areas are the perfect places to get ... the Globe; 12 Weird Bacon Products; World&apos;s Oddest Restaurants</description>
	<body>
		Cocktails • Grilling • Summery Bites MSN Search: Search recipes Search this site Search the web Recipes&amp;Menus Popular Recipes Cookies Chicken Pasta Desserts Drinks Appetizers Lunch Dinner Under 30 Minutes Low Calorie Kids Comfort Food Chinese Mexican Special Features Recipe Finder My Recipebook Delish Cooking School Delish Cupcakes by Color The Essential Wine Guide Martha Stewart&apos;s Recipes Appetite for Life Summer Treats Grilling Guide Celebrate the Olympics Healthy Summer Meals Bold Flavors Poolside Snacks Kitchen Savings Easy Entertaining Guide Hints&amp;Help Recipe Videos Measurement Equivalents Ingredient Equivalents Substitution Ideas Metric Conversions Freshness Guide Flower Arranging Table Settings Napkin Folding Food in the News Blogs Food in the News Best of the Food Blogs News&amp;Events Award-Winning Recipes Chefs&amp;Shows Taste of Place Kitchen Cookoff World&apos;s Best Chefs Dinner&amp;a DVD Chefs at Home Parties&amp;Holidays Holidays Labor Day Halloween Thanksgiving Hanukkah Christmas New Year&apos;s Valentine&apos;s Day Easter Cinco de Mayo Mother&apos;s Day Memorial Day Father&apos;s Day Fourth of July Parties Baby Showers Bridal Showers Cocktail Parties Dinner Parties Graduation Grilling and Barbecue Kids&apos; Parties Picnics Weddings Super Bowl Parties Special Features Invitations&amp;eCards Coupons&amp;Deals Coupons Fun&amp;Games Quizzes Games Recipe Contests My Recipebook My Recipebook Create a Recipe My Shopping Lists My CookChat ™ Edit Profile 
 Home » Fun&amp;Games » Quizzes » Are You a Master of Fast-Food Slogans? 
 
Are You a Master of Fast-Food Slogans?


A well-placed jingle here and a catchy slogan there, and we&apos;re craving fast food before we know what hit us! Marketing geniuses at fast-food chains around the country have spent countless hours figuring out what we want and how to entice us. Case in point: During the &apos;80s, it was not a coincidence that many of us were craving &quot;two all-beef patties, special sauce, lettuce, cheese, pickles, onions on a sesame seed bun.&quot; Think you remember all those ads? Then take this quiz and prove your fast-food slogan smarts.


By Sara Schwartz 
 Text Size: A | A | A Email Print Comments Share Previous Quiz How Much Do You Really Know About Hunger in America? Think you know the facts about hunger in America? Spend a few minutes taking the Hunger Quiz from Feeding America, and you might have to think again! Next Quiz Halloween Candy Calorie Showdown Which treat is the smarter choice? 
 Text Size: A | A | A Email Print Comments Share 
» More from Quizzes 
 
Post a Comment

When using Facebook Connect your image and name may display on Delish. All privacy settings are controlled by Facebook.
 
Top Features in Fun&amp;Games :

» See More Fun&amp;Games 
 
 America&apos;s Best Boardwalks »

There are over 60 boardwalks running along America&apos;s beaches. These boardwalks are serving notable foods, according to Food&amp;Wine .
 
 Vodka Drinks »

Vodka is known for being the most versatile of alcohols, pairing and mixing well with almost anything. However, the flavorings for these 16 vodkas literally come straight off of supermarket shelves.
 
 The Best Cruises for Foodies »

These relaxing, enjoyable cruises cater to food lovers.
 
 Fast Food and Restaurant News »

Lawsuits, menu changes, customer backlashwe rounded up the latest restaurant and fast food news that&apos;s making headlines.
 
 Advertisement 
 
 
 
 Video: 
 
July 12, 2012

 Gluten-Free Goodness » 

Everyone will enjoy these gluten-free main dishes that are ready in 30 minutes or less
 
 Latest: Rice Recipes

 Quick and Easy Fried Rice 17 Rice Recipes Pantry Picks 
 Answer Questions | Ask | Hot Topics Ask Your Question In a nutshell, what would you like to ask? You have 100 characters remaining Most popular questions&amp;answers » Search CookChat! TRY: Weeknight dinners |
	</body>
</document>
