<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005082" url="http://www.ciao.co.uk/sr/q-kfc+uk,tc-5291600" time="2012-07-12-21:36" support="1" score="0.00825799034297581" bingtitle="KFC UK - Manchester - Prices, Offers &amp; Tests of KFC UK" webtitle="KFC UK - Manchester - Prices, Offers&amp;Tests of KFC UK">
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>...KFC is most certainly my favourite fast food restaurant, I just ... so Its about a 15 minutes journey in the car for ... cuts may vary), 4 chips and normally two side orders.</description>
	<body>
		Join Ciao | Login | Help | Mobile 
 
 Browse by category 
 Appliances 

 Books 

 Cameras 

 Cars 

 Computers 

 Electronics 

 DVDs 

 Music 

 Phones 

 Travel 

 More 
 
Ciao - for people with opinions

 
 Latest reviews Write a review 
 
 Latest questions Latest videos 
 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS Shopping Offers Reviews FILTER BY CATEGORY 
 Travel (79) 
 Europe (79) 
 United Kingdom (79) 
 Birmingham (16) 
 Birmingham Restaurants (16) 
 Glasgow (15) 
 Glasgow Restaurants (15) 
 Manchester (14) 
 Manchester Restaurants (14) 
 Belfast (11) 
 Belfast Restaurants (11) 
 Other Destinations in United Kingdom (9) 
 United Kingdom Restaurants (9) 
 Leeds (8) 
 Leeds Restaurants (8) 
 Edinburgh (5) 
 Edinburgh Restaurants (5) 
 London (1) 
 London Restaurants (1) 
 
 
 
 Internet (1) 
 Food&amp;Drink (1) 
 
 ALL RESULTS &gt; Shopping &gt; Results for &quot;KFC UK&quot; 
Shopping»
 
 
 Results on ciao.co.uk Results in online shops Special Offers 
 

 1 - 14 of 14 results for &quot;KFC UK&quot; sort by: Popularity | Price | Rating | Date 
 
Active filters
 Category: Manchester Remove filter 
 
 KFC , Urmston, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Neary Way, Manchester, Greater ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Neary Way, Manchester, Greater Manchester M41 7FP (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC Drive Thru, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Ellesmere Centre, Manchester ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Ellesmere Centre, Manchester Road, Walkden, Manchester, Greater Manchester M28 3ZD (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , Piccadilly Station, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Piccadilly Station, Manchester, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Piccadilly Station, Manchester, Greater Manchester M1 2PB (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , Hyde Road, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Hyde Road, Manchester, Greater ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Hyde Road, Manchester, Greater Manchester M18 7AA (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , Market Street, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Market Street, Manchester, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Market Street, Manchester, Greater Manchester M4 2HU (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , The Trafford Centre, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: The Orient, Manchester, Greater ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: The Orient, Manchester, Greater Manchester M17 8EH (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC Heaton Chapel MCR, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Manchester, Greater Manchester ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Manchester, Greater Manchester M19 (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , 433 Barlow Moor Road, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 433 Barlow Moor Road, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 433 Barlow Moor Road, Manchester, Greater Manchester M21 8AU (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , 27 Bury New Road, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 27 Bury New Road, Manchester, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 27 Bury New Road, Manchester, Greater Manchester M25 9JY (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , 898 Stockport Road, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 898 Stockport Road, Manchester, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 898 Stockport Road, Manchester, Greater Manchester M19 3AD (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , 338 Palatine Road, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 338 Palatine Road, Manchester, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 338 Palatine Road, Manchester, Greater Manchester M22 4HE (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , Unit 1 Monarch Leisure Park, Manchester 
 
Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Unit 1 Monarch Leisure Park, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: Unit 1 Monarch Leisure Park, Manchester, Greater Manchester M19 2RF (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , Unit K6 Voyager Food Court, Manchester 
 
Take-away, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Unit K6 Voyager Food Court, ... more 
 Take-away, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Unit K6 Voyager Food Court, Arndale Centre, Manchester, Greater Manchester M4 3AQ (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 KFC , Cattermore Retail Park, Manchester 
 
Take-away, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Cattermore Retail Park, ... more 
 Take-away, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Cattermore Retail Park, Manchester, Greater Manchester M16 0SN (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members
 
 1 




 
Offers»

 1 - 3 of 3 results for&quot;KFC UK&quot; sorted by: Popularity | Price 

 
 Kenwood KFC -S703P 17cm 2 Way Component System. 
Kenwood KFC -S703P 17cm 2 Way Component System.
 
 
25mm tetron soft dome tweeter.Swivel tweeter.120 watts RMS.280 watts peak output.ISO connection.Size 17cm.Screws/cables supplied.EAN/MPN/UPC/ISBN:...... more 
 25mm tetron soft dome tweeter.Swivel tweeter.120 watts RMS.280 watts peak output.ISO connection.Size 17cm.Screws/cables supplied.EAN/MPN/UPC/ISBN: 0019048187567.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  YES £ 89.99 Visit Shop  &gt; Argos.co.uk 
 Kenwood 10 cm 3Way Speakers KFC E1062 
Kenwood 10 cm 3Way Speakers KFC E1062
 
 
120w peak input power. 40w maximum input power. 20w rated input power. Speaker size 100mm. Injection P.P. Cone speaker design. Speaker size: 10 cm. Magnet type:...... more 
 120w peak input power. 40w maximum input power. 20w rated input power. Speaker size 100mm. Injection P.P. Cone speaker design. Speaker size: 10 cm. Magnet type: Ferrit. Terminals: Slide type. Tweeter height 0.77 cm.Dimensions: H 13.6 W 13.3 D 6.96 cm.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £0.00 
 Availability :  refer to website £ 29.00 Visit Shop  &gt; very.co.uk 
 California Soul - Riot Act 
California Soul - Riot Act
 
 
JJ STOCKHOLM / PAUL RINCON As featured on the famous kfc tv Advert!! This is the wicked &quot;california Soul&quot;, track complete with new mixes from jj...... more 
 JJ STOCKHOLM / PAUL RINCON As featured on the famous kfc tv Advert!! This is the wicked &quot;california Soul&quot;, track complete with new mixes from jj Stockholm and Raul Rincon
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  Free! 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 24 hours... £ 14.38 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon.co.uk 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members


 
Related tags for KFC UK»
 kfc 800 hamburger kfc kfc kfc kenwood kfc france uk the uk kfc shop kfc paris kfc germany 
Reviews»

 
 KFC! 

 Advantages: the tastiest chicken ever
 Disadvantages: not the healthiest option


...KFC is most certainly my favourite fast food restaurant, I just love the original recipe chicken with its amazing secret spice mix coating. 

My favourite meal has to be the variety meal with its two or three pieces of chicken, two hot wings, fries and a drink. I do like the burgers especially the fillet burger but I am always drawn to the original recipe chicken. 

KFC does tend to be a little more expensive than its rival fast food outlets such as McDonalds and Burger King but at least you know you are getting whole pieces of chicken and not mechanically reformed meat as with most burgers brought elsewhere. The average meal now in KFC tends to be around the 5 mark but they do offer cheaper options such as the mini fillet burger and the snack box. 

The variety of food on the menu as increased so much over the last few years. It...

 star3683 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of KFC 
 
 Finger licking good (KFC) 

 Advantages: Cheap and extremely tasty
 Disadvantages: My experience with poorly manned restaurants and manhanded food


...~~~KFC~~~
Kentucky Fried Chicken for those of you that have not heard of it is an American fast food chain that primarily sells chicken.

Near to where I live we have two KFC&apos;s that I often visit however during the last year I have to admit I have not visited them as often as I used to, hear is my thoughts on KFC:


~Location:
The nearest KFC to me is about 6.5 miles away or if I travel in the opposite direction there is another which is about 7.2 miles away. Unfortunately for me (as Im lazy at times) KFC does not deliver so Its about a 15 minutes journey in the car for me to get there.


~Ordering your food:
My nearest KFC has a drive thru so I have always visited this one apart from on one occasion.

Normally I join the queue for the drive thru because it less hassle and generally you get served quite quickly however after visiting...

 clumsy221 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of KFC 
 
 KFC - Finger looking good, or is it? 

 Advantages: Good price, nice chicken.
 Disadvantages: Chips are normally nasty, long queues, dirty tables to sit on.


...the right blend without being too over-powering, it has this delicious taste to it that just makes me want to go back for more time and time again! 

The chips are a real disappointment though and are pretty similar to McDonalds chips in that they are either over-salted, cold or both! But then I am enjoying the chicken and the corn on the cob too much to care about some cold chips! 

Another speciality of KFC is the bargain bucket and this is normally around 10 for which you will receive 8 pieces of chicken (cuts may vary), 4 chips and normally two side orders. There are different variations of the bucket meals and you might also get boneless chicken, popcorn chicken, mini fillet burgers, bottles of drink or even desserts such as vienetta and ice cream etc.

You can sit down or take away your food to eat wherever you feel like it. In my...

 katykicker 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of KFC 
 
 
 About Us - 
 Jobs
 - 
 Advertise with Us
 - 
 Press
 - 
 Become a Partner
 - Ciao Quality Seal Ciao Deutschland - Ciao France - Ciao Italia - Ciao España - Ciao Nederland - Ciao Sverige Site Index - Ciao Charts - Most searched products - Data Protection 
 ©2012 Shopping Guide GmbH
	</body>
</document>
