<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005417" url="http://www.womenshealthmag.com/nutrition/fast-food-diet" time="2012-07-12-21:58" support="24" score="0.11620412513713974" bingtitle="How to Find Healthy Fast Food | Women&apos;s Health Magazine" webtitle="How to Find Healthy Fast Food  | Women&apos;s Health Magazine">
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000381" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000853" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>But you don&apos;t have to trash your diet just because your meal comes in a disposable bag. Most fast-food restaurants now offer healthy items on their menus, and even the ...</description>
	<body>
		Follow @WomensHealthMag Register for free and win prizes! | Log In Hi, | Member Center | Log Out 
 Fitness Sex&amp;Love Food Weight Loss Spartacus for Women Health Beauty Style 
 Subscribe for 99¢ an issue 

 NEW! Healthy Dish Blog Cooking Eat This Not That The Women&apos;s Health Diet Recipe Finder Videos 

 How to Find Healthy Fast Food 
 By Jill Waldbieser 
 The Fast-Food Places 
 
Photography By ©iStockphoto.com/Brian Powell
 
 
 

Drive-through dining is as much a part of summer road trips as your GPS and the Black Eyed Peas. But you don&apos;t have to trash your diet just because your meal comes in a disposable bag. Most fast-food restaurants now offer healthy items on their menus, and even the ones that don&apos;t advertise stay-slim meals will usually prepare them for you anyway. Follow our handy cheat sheet to satisfy your fast-food craving for just a fraction of the fat and calories
 

More from Women&apos;s Health: 350 Quick And Delicious Recipes! Slower Cooker Favorites! 

 
 
 
 
 
 Share it! Tweet How to Find Healthy Fast Food A healthy diet doesn&apos;t have to stop just because you&apos;re in a rush. Use these ordering strategies to safely navigate fast-food drive-throughs ADVERTISEMENT ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 See More Videos ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
 
 
Yosi Samra flats
 
 We&apos;re giving away a pair of blue Yosi Samra foldable flats, worth $85! 
 
 

 
 
Categories:

 Fitness Sex&amp;Love Food Weight Loss Spartacus for Women Health Beauty Style 

Help:

 About Women&apos;s Health FAQ&apos;s Customer Service Contact Us 
 
Services:

 Manage Your Subscription Magazine Subscriptions Gift Subscriptions 

Favorite Articles:

 Best Beers Best Sex Positions Abs Workouts for Women 
 
A sprinkle of cinnamon may boost weight loss. The spice&apos;s polyphenols help regulate blood sugar, keeping hunger pangs at bay. 52 minutes ago · reply · retweet · favorite 
 
Follow @WomensHealthMag 

Follow @WinTodaySweeps 
 
Women&apos;s Health
 
WH International:

 Argentina Australia Brazil Germany South Africa Thailand Turkey 
 
Other Rodale Sites:

 Rodale Rodale Grow Runner&apos;s World Running Times Bicycling Mountain Bike Prevention Men&apos;s Health Organic Gardening 

Corporate

 Media Kit Your Privacy Rights 
 ©2012 Rodale Inc. All Rights Reserved. Your Privacy Rights
	</body>
</document>
