<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005627" url="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=5056886" time="2012-07-12-22:11" support="1" score="0.0008259279365624579" bingtitle="Liquor Stores and Low-Income Shoppers : NPR" webtitle="Liquor Stores and Low-Income Shoppers : NPR">
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>... They say besides all the trash, the type of people the liquor store ... U.S. Foreclosure Activity Near 5-Year ... Scandal Deepens; 11 Placed On Leave ...</description>
	<body>
		NPR Shop | NPR Social Media | Login | Register 
 
 Find a Station 
 Search close   
 home news arts&amp;life music programs listen 
 
news

 Morning Edition All Things Considered Fresh Air The Diane Rehm Show On The Media On Point Talk of the Nation 

 Talk of the Nation Science Friday Tell Me More Weekend Edition Saturday Weekend Edition Sunday Also heard on NPR stations: Marketplace APM 
 
arts&amp;life

 Ask Me Another Car Talk Radiolab Snap Judgment TED Radio Hour Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Also heard on NPR stations: This American Life PRI A Prairie Home Companion APM 
 
music

 All Songs Considered Alt.Latino Favorite Sessions First Listen From The Top Live In Concert 

 Mountain Stage NPR Music Essentials Piano Jazz Song Travels The Thistle&amp;Shamrock World Cafe 
 
special series

 StoryCorps Planet Money Picture Show Krulwich Wonders... Cabinet of Wonders 
 PUBLIC RADIO PROGRAMS A-Z | close 
hear continuous streams
 
 24-Hour Program Stream 

NPR News and Shows
 View Schedule 
 Find Stations | Music Streams 
 
hear the latest news
 
 Hourly News Summary 
 [4 min 45 sec] 
Latest NPR Newscast
 Public Radio Programs A-Z | close 
 News &gt; U.S. 
 
 Twitter (0) Facebook (1) Share 
 Stumble Upon Reddit Linkedin Digg 

 What is this? 
 Share Comments 
   
Liquor Stores and Low-Income Shoppers
 
by Kristin Wiederholt 
 
December 16, 2005
 
 Listen 

 Day to Day 
 
 Add to Playlist Download 
   text size A A A December 16, 2005 
Vandalism and arson at Arab-American owned liquor stores in Oakland, Calif., highlight prejudices and resentments. Kristin Wiederholt of member station KALW reports that many resent having to rely on corner liquor stores for groceries.
 
Copyright©2005 National Public Radio. For personal, noncommercial use only. See Terms of Use. For other uses, prior permission required.

ALEX CHADWICK, host:

This is DAY TO DAY. I&apos;m Alex Chadwick.

Coming up, a new documentary where boy meets boy and then girl meets boys, and can the three live happily every after?

First, this. Across the bay from San Francisco in Oakland, in some of the city&apos;s poor neighborhoods, there&apos;s a battle under way between liquor store owners, most of whom are Arab-Americans, and local residents and city officials who complain the liquor stores are contributing to squalor. From member station KALW in San Francisco, Kristin Wiederholt reports.

KRISTIN WIEDERHOLT reporting:

Jax Liquor is typical inner city corner store in East Oakland. It hums with the sound of refrigerators and freezers that line two walls inside. They&apos;re full of soft drinks, juice, water and alcohol. Mohamed Saleh Mohamed is filling in behind the counter today for his brother. He believes Oakland liquor stores are under siege these days and the scapegoat for all inner-city problems.

Mr. MOHAMED SALEH MOHAMED (Store Clerk): If you have a killing down the street a block away, they will blame the liquor store. If you have a car accident, you know, where a man is drunk, you would say, `That&apos;s the liquor store.&apos; I mean, everything relates to the liquor store.

WIEDERHOLT: In the first 20 minutes after opening today, most of the customers are African-American and roughly half of them buy alcohol. Mohamed, who&apos;s president of the Yemeni-American Grocers Association, says merchants are running legitimate businesses and only selling what people want to buy.

Mr. MOHAMED: If you want bananas every day and say, `I want bananas,&apos; I will bring bananas. But if you come in and ask for half pint of liquor or a can of malt liquor, I have to provide you that service. I&apos;m obligated because you&apos;re not going to come back if I don&apos;t have that product. So you dictate what I sell. So the community dictate what I sell.

WIEDERHOLT: At least some in the community agree. African-American resident Calvin Neal(ph) likes the convenience of corner stores.

Mr. CALVIN NEAL (Corner Store Customer): But I don&apos;t see the stores as being a problem. I mean, you know, hey, a lot to times they save us a trip to the grocery store or something. You know what I mean?

WIEDERHOLT: Yet many locals of all ethnicities do see them as a problem. There are 350 liquor stores in Oakland with the highest concentration in low-income neighborhoods where there are a few, if any, grocery stores. Residents claim problem stores cause litter, loitering, prostitution, drug dealing and crime. Some have taken to violence to deal with the issue. Three liquor stores have been vandalized in the last few months and four African-American men have been charged with felony vandalism and hate crimes. Not far away, in a grittier section of East Oakland, the streets are lined with trash.

Mr. LEON PAULOS: Just look around you, and this is a clean day.

WIEDERHOLT: Leon Paulos and his wife have joined with neighbors and are actively trying to get a corner liquor store on their block to clean up.

Mr. PAULOS: On this street, on this wide side of East 15th Street, any time of day, you&apos;ll see a cluster of people just sitting around on old milk crates drinking out of brown paper bags.

WIEDERHOLT: They say besides all the trash, the type of people the liquor store attracts makes the neighborhood feel unsafe. Ignacio de la Fuente, president of the Oakland City Council, says cracking down on problem liquor stores is a priority.

Mr. IGNACIO DE LA FUENTE (President, Oakland City Council): The fact is that Oakland has an unfair number of liquor stores, and I think, at no question about it, it affects people of color disproportionately, all of us. And I think that that&apos;s why we are working so hard to change that.

WIEDERHOLT: Controlling liquor stores is tricky because liquor licenses are issued by the state, not the city. In the past two years, Oakland has begun enforcing an innovative ordinance to put pressure on liquor stores. The ordinance sets a series of operating standards, including having appropriate outside lighting and eliminating trash in the doorway and adjacent sidewalks. Stores that don&apos;t comply face hefty fines that can put them out of business. So far, the city has forced five stores to close or stop selling liquor; dozens of others have changed their business practices. In the meantime, de la Fuente says the vandalism of Arab liquor stores is not helping the city&apos;s campaign. It sends the wrong message about racial tension in the city.

Mr. DE LA FUENTE: Oakland cannot afford this `Is he a black or brown or Middle Eastern&apos; or anything like that. You got a good neighbor? You got a good neighbor. You have a bad neighbor? You have a bad neighbor no matter what color you are.

WIEDERHOLT: Oakland&apos;s official effort to close down or change the practices of liquor stores has been so effective it has caught the attention of other cities in California. In November, a San Francisco supervisor sponsored legislation similar to Oakland&apos;s that would give San Francisco more direct control over the liquor store business. For NPR News, I&apos;m Kristin Wiederholt.

CHADWICK: I&apos;m Alex Chadwick. More coming up on DAY TO DAY from NPR News.

Copyright©2005 National Public Radio. All rights reserved. No quotes from the materials contained herein may be used in any media without attribution to National Public Radio. This transcript is provided for personal, noncommercial use only, pursuant to our Terms of Use. Any other use requires NPR&apos;s prior permission. Visit our permissions page for further information.

NPR transcripts are created on a rush deadline by a contractor for NPR, and accuracy and availability may vary. This text may not be in its final form and may be updated or revised in the future. Please be aware that the authoritative record of NPR&apos;s programming is the audio.
   
 Twitter (0) Facebook (1) Share 
 Stumble Upon Reddit Linkedin Digg 

 What is this? 
 Share Comments 
   
 More U.S. 
 
Podcast + RSS Feeds
 
 Podcast RSS 

 U.S. 
Subscribe to U.S. podcast via:

 

Or use this URL:

 

 close 
     Day to Day 
Subscribe to Day to Day podcast via:

 

Or use this URL:

 

 close 
     
   
 Shots - Health Blog 

 State Legislatures Stay Busy On Abortion Laws 

There were 39 state laws restricting abortion enacted in the first half of this year.
 
 It&apos;s All Politics 

 Three Crucial Years Propel Romney&apos;s Business Career Back To Center Stage 

The outsized role a private equity firm has played in the 2012 presidential race grows larger.
 
 The Picture Show 

 Detroit Lost And Found: Vintage Photos Speak Volumes 

Two Italian photographers on assignment in Detroit kept stumbling across old photos around the city.
     
Comments





 Discussions for this story are now closed. Please see the Community FAQ for more information.
   Recent First Oldest First Most Recommended 
 View all comments » 
 The Two-Way: The Two-Way 
 Nike Announces They Will Take Paterno&apos;s Name Off Child Care Center Wells Fargo Agrees To $175 Million Settlement Over Lending Discrimination No Reason To Get Excited, Dylan Says: PBS Has The Wrong Guitar 

 more 
 
NPR thanks our sponsors

 Become an NPR Sponsor 
 
most popular 
 
 Viewed Recommended Commented 

 Studies Tie Human Bladder Infections To Antibiotics In Chicken No Reason To Get Excited, Dylan Says: PBS Has The Wrong Guitar Nightly Glass Of Wine May Protect Boomer Women&apos;s Bones Paterno, Others Slammed In Report For Failing To Protect Sandusky&apos;s Victims 
 
 Poverty In America: The Struggle To Get Ahead 
 
NPR&apos;s Pam Fessler reports on the tens of millions of Americans still struggling in poverty.
 
 Your Turn 

 Sights And Sounds: The &apos;Heart&apos; Of Your City 
 
All urbanites have a place they think of as the heart of their city. Show us the heart of your city.
 
 Headlines 

From the Associated Press
 
 Penn St. Trustee: Joe Paterno&apos;s Legacy &apos;Marred&apos; Thousands Fall Victim To Utility Payment Scam Lawmakers Furious Over China-Made Olympic Uniform 

 View More Last updated: 
 3:59 pm
 ET 
   
 npr always on 

 Newsletters Podcasts Mobile RSS Feeds Widgets API Radio 
 
 news 

 U.S. World Opinion Politics Business Technology Science Health Sports 
 
 arts&amp;life 

 Books Movies Pop Culture Food Performing Arts Games&amp;Humor 
 
 music 

 Music Articles Music Videos NPR Music Radio Browse Genres Browse Artists A-Z 

 All Songs Considered Alt.Latino First Listen Live In Concert NPR Music Essentials Marian McPartland&apos;s Piano Jazz The Thistle&amp;Shamrock World Cafe 
 
 programs a-z 

 All Things Considered Ask Me Another Cabinet of Wonders Car Talk The Diane Rehm Show Fresh Air Morning Edition On The Media On Point Talk of the Nation TED Radio Hour Tell Me More Wait Wait...Don&apos;t Tell Me! Weekend Edition Saturday Weekend Edition Sunday 
 
listen

 Hourly News NPR Program Stream Schedule Find Station Streams 
 
more

 Multimedia Columns Blogs Analysis Commentary NPR Ombudsman StateImpact 

 about 

 This Is NPR Support and Sponsor Press Room Careers NPR Shop Contact Us 
 
 Copyright NPR Terms of Use Privacy Policy Permissions Corrections Text-Only Site Help Contact Us Donate Our partner in public broadcasting
	</body>
</document>
