<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005054" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/37141452/Frommer-s-Puerto-Rico" time="2012-07-12-21:34" support="20" score="0.029194178199597277" bingtitle="Frommer&apos;s Puerto Rico - Scribd" webtitle="Frommer&apos;s Puerto Rico">
			<query id="000577" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000008" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000451" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000390" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000671" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000797" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000297" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001457" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000633" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000954" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000639" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001268" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001394" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001080" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000014" bing-rank="31"/>
	<description>White sandy beaches and idyllic offshore islands are what put Puerto Rico on tourist maps in the first place. The best beaches are labeled on the “Puerto Rico” map on ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Buy Now You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 10 to 97 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 107 to 162 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 172 to 253 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 263 to 281 are not shown in this preview. You&apos;re Reading a Free Preview 
Pages 291 to 324 are not shown in this preview. of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Frommer&apos;s Puerto Rico
 Much more detailed and complete than its major competitors, Frommer&apos;s Puerto Rico, 10th Edition gives you in-depth, honest reviews of lavish honeymoon resorts, intimate inns, fa... ( More ) Much more detailed and complete than its major competitors, Frommer&apos;s Puerto Rico, 10th Edition gives you in-depth, honest reviews of lavish honeymoon resorts, intimate inns, family-friendly condos, and dirt cheap hostels. This guide was researched and written by a travel writer and city news reporter based in San Juan, this edition has its finger on the pulse of the island, with updates on the latest openings and selections in every price category. We&apos;ll point you to a gorgeous white-sand beach that only locals know about, give you the scoop on both upscale dining and roadside nosh pits, and we list the best places for snorkeling, hiking, golf, sailing, deep-sea fishing.You&apos;ll also get a complete shopper&apos;s guide, and up-to-date coverage of the newest nightlife in the region, from casinos to salsa clubs to lowkey beach bars.  Includes a color fold-out map. ( Less ) 2,134 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 09/09/2010 Copyright: Traditional Copyright: All rights reserved Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
