<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005202" url="http://citizendia.org/Highway_401_(Ontario)" time="2012-07-12-21:44" support="1" score="0.0003075244995220941" bingtitle="Highway 401 (Ontario) - Citizendia" webtitle="Highway 401 (Ontario) - Citizendia">
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>... event which occurs in a particular time and place ... The Park Road exit (Exit 416) is to be replaced by ... Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Your Ad Here bad debt consolidation loan Tramadol HCL 50 mg Side Effects Organic Reactions 

 &quot;Highway 401&quot; redirects here. For other uses, see List of highways numbered 401 . The following highways are numbered 401: Canada Highway 401 (Ontario United States U &quot;Macdonald-Cartier&quot; redirects here. For other uses, see Macdonald-Cartier (disambiguation) . 
 Highway 401 
 Macdonald-Cartier Freeway
Highway of Heroes Length: 825. 1 km [1] [2] (512. The kilometre ( American spelling: kilometer) symbol km is a unit of Length in the Metric system, equal to one thousand 7 mi ) Formed: 1938 (parts as Highway 2A ),
1947 (numbered in 1952) [3] West end: Hwy 3 in Windsor Major
junctions: Hwy 402 in London 
 Hwy 403 in Woodstock 
 Hwy 8 in Kitchener 
 Hwy 407 near Milton, Ontario 
 Hwy 410 in Mississauga 
 Hwy 427 in Toronto 
 Hwy 400 in Toronto 
 Hwy 404 / Don Valley Parkway in Toronto 
 Hwy 35 / Hwy 115 in Clarington 
 Hwy 62 in Belleville 
 Hwy 15 in Kingston 
 Hwy 137 near Gananoque 
 Hwy 416 near Brockville 
 Hwy 138 in Cornwall East end: A-20 towards Montreal, QC 
 Ontario provincial highways &lt; Hwy 400 Hwy 402 &gt; 400-series - County 
 Wikimedia Commons has media related to: Highway 401 

 The King&apos;s Highway 401 (also known as the Macdonald-Cartier Freeway ) is a highway that extends across Southern Ontario , Canada . A mile is a unit of Length, usually used to measure Distance, in a number of different systems including Imperial units United States Highway 2A is a short controlled-access Freeway in Toronto, Ontario that extends from its junction with Kingston Road (formerly part of Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario Highway 8 is a King&apos;s Highway in the Canadian province of Ontario. The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Highway 407, officially called the 407 Express Toll Route (ETR, is a Tollway located in the Greater Toronto Area, southern Ontario, Canada Milton ( 2006 census population 53939 is a town in southern Ontario, Canada, part of the Greater Highway 410 is a 400-Series highway in Ontario, Canada that connects Highways 401 and 403 with Toronto &apos;s western suburbs Mississauga (ˌmɪsɪˈsɑgə) incorporated in 1974 is a City located in the Regional Municipality of Peel The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario Highway 404 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada. It runs from the junction of Highway 401 and the Don Valley Parkway in The Don Valley Parkway (generally referred to as the DVP) is a controlled-access six-lane Freeway in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, so Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario Highway 35 is a provincial highway in Ontario Canada, running from Highway 401 in Clarington to Highway 60 near Dwight (and Algonquin Highway 115 is a provincially maintained highway in Central Ontario, Canada, which runs from the Highway 401 junction west of Newcastle The Municipality of Clarington is a municipality in Ontario, Canada in the Regional Municipality of Durham Highway 62 is a provincially maintained highway in Ontario, Canada, running south-north from Highway 33 at Bloomfield in Prince Edward County Belleville ( 2006 population 48821 metropolitan population 91518 is a city located at the mouth of the Moira River on the Bay of Quinte in southeastern Highway 15 is a provincially-maintained Highway in southeastern Ontario, Canada. Kingston Ontario is a Canadian city located at the eastern end of Lake Ontario, where the lake runs into the St Highway 137 is a short Highway that connects Ontario &apos;s Highway 401 at Exit 661 to the New York Gananoque is a town in Leeds and Grenville County Ontario, located at 44°19′55″ North 76°9′44″ West Highway 416, named the Veterans Memorial Highway, is a 400-Series Highway in eastern Ontario that connects between Highway 417 in Ottawa and Highway 138 is a provincial highway in eastern Ontario which extends in a north-south direction from Highway 417 east of Casselman to the former Highway Cornwall is a City in eastern Ontario, Canada and the seat of the United Counties of Stormont Dundas and Glengarry Ontario. Autoroute 20 (also called Autoroute Jean-Lesage, Autoroute du Souvenir or the Two and Twenty) is an important Autoroute in Quebec Montreal, or Montréal in French ( pronounced in French, in English) is the largest city in the Canadian province of Quebec See also Provincial highways in Ontario This is a list of current and former Provincial highways in the Canadian province of Ontario. The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge The 400-series highways are a network of controlled-access Freeways throughout the southern portion of the province of Ontario, Canada, forming a special This is a list of County Numbered roads in Ontario These roads are found only in Southern and Southwestern Ontario (with the lone exception * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * Before adding any more images to this * * page please do carefully consider * * whether they would be mere decoration * * or actually improve Southern Ontario is the portion of the Canadian province of Ontario lying south of the French River and Algonquin Park. Country to&amp;quotDominion;of Canada&quot;or&amp;quotCanadian;Federation&quot;or anything else please read the Talk Page It is the longest 400-Series Highway in Ontario, and one of the widest and busiest highways in the world. The 400-series highways are a network of controlled-access Freeways throughout the southern portion of the province of Ontario, Canada, forming a special [4] [5] Together with Quebec Autoroute 20 , it is the road transportation backbone of the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor , along which over half of Canada&apos;s population resides. Autoroute 20 (also called Autoroute Jean-Lesage, Autoroute du Souvenir or the Two and Twenty) is an important Autoroute in Quebec Colloquially, the road is known simply as &quot;The 401&quot;, spoken as &quot;four-oh-one&quot;.

On 24 August 2007 the stretch of highway between Toronto (from Highway 404 / Don Valley Parkway ) and Trenton (from Glen Miller Road) was given the additional name Highway of Heroes , in honour of Canadian Forces personnel killed during the War in Afghanistan . Events 49 BC - Julius Caesar &apos;s General Gaius Scribonius Curio is defeated in the Second Battle of the Bagradas River Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario Highway 404 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada. It runs from the junction of Highway 401 and the Don Valley Parkway in The Don Valley Parkway (generally referred to as the DVP) is a controlled-access six-lane Freeway in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, so Trenton Ontario (2001 population 19374 is a community on the Bay of Quinte. The Canadian Forces (CF ( French: Forces canadiennes) are the unified Armed forces of Canada, governed by the National Defence The War in Afghanistan, which began on October 7 2001 as the U 

 
 
Contents
 
 1 History 
 1.1 Highway of Heroes 1.2 Carnage Alley 1.3 Speeding and Tailgating 
 2 Overview 3 Transportation corridor 4 Collector-express sections 
 4.1 Islington Avenue to Brock Road 
 4.1.1 Signage 
 4.2 Highway 403/410 to Highway 427 
 5 Future expansion and upgrades 
 5.1 Windsor-area upgrades and extensions 5.2 Essex County upgrades 
 5.2.1 Highway 3 to Essex County Road 19 5.2.2 County Road 19 to County Road 42 
 5.3 London area upgrades 5.4 Oxford County upgrades 5.5 Mississauga upgrades 5.6 Durham Region area upgrades 
 6 Traffic cameras 7 Volume information (2005) 8 Major cities 9 Trivia 10 Exit list 11 Service centres 12 Lane configuration from west to east 13 See also 14 References 15 External links 
 
 




 

 History 
 A Highway 401 marker shield displaying the M-C Freeway designation. Few of the M-C shields still exist, as they are no longer posted by the province. 
The need for a four-lane bypass of Highway 2 in the Oshawa area was growing in the early 1930s , as the simple two-lane road could no longer handle the growing levels of traffic. Highway 2 was the major east-west provincial highway in Southern Ontario, running from Windsor in the west to the Quebec boundary near Lancaster The 1930s were described as an abrupt shift to more radical and conservative lifestyles as countries were struggling to find a solution to the Great Depression. The idea for a roadway similar to Middle Road in Peel County was lead by Thomas McQueston , then head of the Department of Highways . The Queen Elizabeth Way (commonly referred to as the QEW, Q, QE, or Queen-E) is a vital 400-Series Freeway in Ontario Thomas McQuesten ( June 30, 1882 - January 13, 1948) was an athlete militiaman lawyer politician and government appointee who lived in The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law 

Construction began on two portions of Highway 401 before the beginning of World War II : the new Kingston Road from Highland Creek to Oshawa , (modern day Former Highway 2A ) bypassing the Kingston Road ( Highway 2 ), and the scenic highway from Gananoque to Brockville , also bypassing a portion of Highway 2. World War II, or the Second World War, (often abbreviated WWII) was a global military conflict which involved a majority of the world&apos;s nations, including Kingston Road (originally&amp;quotThe;Kingston Road&quot;was built by American engineer Asa Danforth as a route to connect Toronto (then called York with Kingston Highland Creek is a community in south-east Scarborough in the eastern section of Toronto, Ontario, Canada that lies along the southern portion of the Highway 2A is a short controlled-access Freeway in Toronto, Ontario that extends from its junction with Kingston Road (formerly part of Kingston Road (originally&amp;quotThe;Kingston Road&quot;was built by American engineer Asa Danforth as a route to connect Toronto (then called York with Kingston Highway 2 was the major east-west provincial highway in Southern Ontario, running from Windsor in the west to the Quebec boundary near Lancaster Gananoque is a town in Leeds and Grenville County Ontario, located at 44°19′55″ North 76°9′44″ West The former was built because of heavy traffic between Toronto and Oshawa, and the latter to connect with the Thousand Islands Bridge (opened 1937 ). The Thousand Islands Bridge is an international bridge over the Saint Lawrence River connecting northern New York Year 1937 ( MCMXXXVII) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display the full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. In late 1941 or early 1942 , the scenic highway was opened to local traffic as a gravel road , [6] and numbered Highway 2S , for &quot;Highway 2 Scenic&quot; (as opposed to the popular, but incorrect, idea of &quot;Highway 2 South&quot;, since the road does lie fully south of Highway 2). Year 1941 ( MCMXLI) was a Common year starting on Wednesday (the link will display 1941 calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Year 1942 ( MCMXLII) was a Common year starting on Thursday (the link will display the full 1942 calendar of the Gregorian calendar. A gravel road is a type of unpaved Road surfaced with Gravel that has been brought to the site from a Quarry or Stream bed. Paving of the south side, the future eastbound lanes, was completed several years later. [3] [7] 

Construction of the first segment of the highway (originally designated Highway 2A ) from Highland Creek to Oshawa was initiated in 1938 . Highway 2A is a short controlled-access Freeway in Toronto, Ontario that extends from its junction with Kingston Road (formerly part of Highland Creek is a community in south-east Scarborough in the eastern section of Toronto, Ontario, Canada that lies along the southern portion of the Year 1938 ( MCMXXXVIII) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link will display the full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. The highway was designed to bypass a congested section of nearby Highway 2 . Highway 2 was the major east-west provincial highway in Southern Ontario, running from Windsor in the west to the Quebec boundary near Lancaster Much of the grading and a number of structures were completed before the onset of the Second World War , at which time most of the construction work was suspended. World War II, or the Second World War, (often abbreviated WWII) was a global military conflict which involved a majority of the world&apos;s nations, including This section was finally completed and opened to traffic in 1947 . Year 1947 ( MCMXLVII) was a Common year starting on Wednesday (link will display full 1947 calendar of the Gregorian calendar. 

During the war years , the provincial government undertook a number of surveys and studies to determine the most desirable route for the new limited-access highway. World War II, or the Second World War, (often abbreviated WWII) was a global military conflict which involved a majority of the world&apos;s nations, including 

The highway was redesignated &quot;Highway 401&quot; in 1952 . Year 1952 ( MCMLII) was a Leap year starting on Tuesday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. The last segment, between Gananoque and Brockville , was completed in 1968 to bypass a section along the St. Lawrence River that included at-grade intersections and private entrances, now called the &quot; Thousand Islands Parkway &quot;. Gananoque is a town in Leeds and Grenville County Ontario, located at 44°19′55″ North 76°9′44″ West Year 1968 ( MCMLXVIII) was a Leap year starting on Monday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Saint Lawrence River (in French: fleuve Saint-Laurent; Kahnawáˀkye in Tuscarora, Kaniatarowanenneh meaning big waterway The Thousand Islands Parkway is a Parkway in the Canadian province of Ontario, which extends easterly from an interchange with Highway 401 The last at-grade intersection on the present alignment was at Joyceville Road, east of Kingston, which was converted to an interchange with the final 1968 construction.

Much of the current routing of Highway 401 across Toronto was built in 1954 (when the entire area was north of the city ) as the &quot;Toronto By-Pass&quot;. Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario Year 1954 ( MCMLIV) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display full 1954 Gregorian calendar) Old City of Toronto refers to the City of Toronto, Ontario, Canada, as it existed before the&quot; The road ended temporarily at the Weston Road interchange (now Exit 357), while a bridge across the Humber River was constructed for the road to be extended westwards. Weston Road is a north-south street in west end Toronto, Ontario, Canada. This article is about the river in Toronto Ontario Canada Links to other rivers of the same name can be found here. This bridge was never used, as just a few months later, Hurricane Hazel damaged it so badly that it had to be dynamited and completely rebuilt. Hurricane Hazel was the worst Hurricane of the 1954 Atlantic hurricane season and one of the worst hurricanes of the 20th century Dynamite is an explosive based on the explosive potential of Nitroglycerin, initially using Diatomaceous earth (kieselgur US Spelling kieselguhr This delayed Highway 401&apos;s completion in the Toronto area for nearly a year. [8] 

Through much of the 1950s , motorists were annoyed with the perceived snail&apos;s pace of constructing the freeway, and had pressured the provincial government to speed up the completion of Highway 401, with much of the public supporting turning Highway 401 into a tolled road to accelerate construction. The 1950s Decade refers to the years of 1950 to 1959 inclusive To do this, the provincial government had assigned the &quot;Select Committee on Toll Roads and Highway Financing&quot; in 1955 to consider any benefits or disadvantages from this [9] . Year 1955 ( MCMLV) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link displays the 1955 Gregorian calendar) The resulting report from the committee was in by 1956 , and the result was that tolling the roadway would be extremely detrimental. Year 1956 ( MCMLVI) was a Leap year starting on Sunday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Tolls would appear on the 400-series network, if only temporarily. When the St. Lawrence Seaway was built in the late 1950s, drivers on the Queen Elizabeth Way paid tolls on the newly-built Garden City and Burlington Bay skyways until 1973 , as a way to recover the costs of construction and upgrades. The St Lawrence Seaway is the common name for a system of Canals that permits ocean-going vessels to travel from the Atlantic Ocean to the Great Lakes The Queen Elizabeth Way (commonly referred to as the QEW, Q, QE, or Queen-E) is a vital 400-Series Freeway in Ontario The Garden City Skyway is a major high-level bridge located in St The Burlington Bay James N Allan Skyway, originally called the Burlington Bay Skyway, is a pair of high-level freeway bridges located in Hamilton and Year 1973 ( MCMLXXIII) was a Common year starting on Monday (link will display full calendar of the 1973 Gregorian calendar. 

During the late 1950s, the road was extended from Windsor to London as an at-grade Super 2 , before being twinned in the 1960s (the segment from Windsor to Tilbury was completed as a four-lane freeway), with the eastbound carriageway being built first. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper A super two, super two-lane highway or wide two lane is a two-lane surface road built to high standards typically including partial control of access This is still evident today, as many bridges over creeks and streams in the area have different ages and appearances. A stream is a body of Water with a current, confined within a bed and stream-banks The section from Windsor to Tilbury was among the original sections built, from 1952-1958, with the Tilbury Bypass (from Exit 56 to Exit 63) being constructed in 1961 , with the Tilbury-London section opening in 1963 . Year 1961 ( MCMLXI) was a Common year starting on Sunday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Year 1963 ( MCMLXIII) was a Common year starting on Tuesday (link will display full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. In 1957 , the London- Woodstock section opened, as a four-lane divided freeway from Highway 4 &apos;s interchange (just west of London), to Highway 2 &apos;s interchange (just east of Woodstock). Year 1957 ( MCMLVII) was a Common year starting on Tuesday (link displays the 1957 Gregorian calendar) Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario Highway 4 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Highway 2 was the major east-west provincial highway in Southern Ontario, running from Windsor in the west to the Quebec boundary near Lancaster The road would later be extended to Kitchener in 1961, where it was linked to the Kitchener-Toronto-Oshawa section. The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. 

In 1964 , Highway 401 was diverted from its former alignment in Windsor, Ontario along what is now Dougall Parkway , to its current terminus with Highway 3 , with the overpass carrying Highway 3&apos;s westbound lanes being built in 1956 in anticipation of the extension. Year 1964 ( MCMLXIV) was a Leap year starting on Wednesday (link will display full calendar of the 1964 Gregorian calendar. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. Dougall Parkway is a municipal freeway in Windsor Ontario, acting as an extension of Dougall Avenue to lead traffic heading towards downtown into the city centre and to Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. [3] [10] The former alignment became Highway 401A (a secret designation, much like Highway 400A in Barrie ). Highway 400A was a 400-series highway in Canada. It was the Ontario Ministry of Transportation &apos;s internal designation for the 1 At this time, Highway 401 was also twinned from Windsor (interchange with Highway 98 , now Provincial Road ) to the eastern interchange (Exit 63) with Highway 2 in Tilbury , with two new lanes being constructed north of the existing lanes. This moderately long highway travels through the northern part of Essex County Ontario and through south-central Chatham-Kent Ontario, starting its journey in Windsor County Road 46 is a primary artery in northern Essex County Ontario, linking Windsor Ontario with Tilbury Ontario, serving as a viable alternative to Tilbury ( 2001 population 4534 is a Community in the municipality of Chatham-Kent, Ontario The new carriageway became the westbound lanes, while the original two-lane carriageway became the east-bound lanes. This twinning from Windsor to Tilbury was completed in 1965 . Year 1965 ( MCMLXV) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display full calendar of the 1965 Gregorian calendar. By 1968, all of Highway 401 was twinned to a minimum of four lanes.

In 1965, Premier of Ontario John Robarts designated Highway 401 the &quot;Macdonald-Cartier Freeway&quot;, in honour of Sir John A. Macdonald and Sir George-Étienne Cartier , the Province of Canada &apos;s most important Fathers of Confederation , and in recognition of Canada&apos;s upcoming Centennial Celebrations in 1967 . The Premier of Ontario is the first Minister of the Crown for the Canadian province of Ontario. John Parmenter Robarts, PC, CC, QC ( January 11, 1917 – October 18, 1982) was a Canadian Sir John Alexander Macdonald GCB, KCMG, PC ( January 11, 1815 – June 6, 1891) was the first Prime Minister Sir George-Étienne Cartier, Bart, KCMG, PC ( September 6, 1814–May 20, 1873) was a French-Canadian The Province of Canada or the United Province of Canada was a British colony in North America from 1841 to 1867 Canadian Confederation was the process by which the federal Dominion of Canada was formed beginning 1 July 1867 from the Year 1967 ( MCMLXVII) was a Common year starting on Sunday (link will display full calendar of the 1967 Gregorian calendar. This name is found on maps and official documents, but seldom used in conversation or on modern road signs . Most countries post signage known as traffic signs or road signs, at the side of Roads to A 1961 proposal to name the highway the &quot; Leslie M. Frost Thruway&quot; after the recently retired Premier of Ontario was approved by the provincial cabinet, but was not carried out. Leslie Miscampbell Frost, PC, CC, QC ( September 20 1895–May 4 1973) was a Politician 

 

 Highway of Heroes 

On 24 August 2007 , the Ministry of Transportation announced that the stretch of Highway 401 from Glen Miller Road in Trenton, Ontario to Don Valley Parkway / Highway 404 in Toronto would bear the additional name &quot; Highway of Heroes &quot; in honour of Canada&apos;s fallen soldiers, notably those who have died on duty in Afghanistan . Events 49 BC - Julius Caesar &apos;s General Gaius Scribonius Curio is defeated in the Second Battle of the Bagradas River Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law Trenton Ontario (2001 population 19374 is a community on the Bay of Quinte. The Don Valley Parkway (generally referred to as the DVP) is a controlled-access six-lane Freeway in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, so Highway 404 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada. It runs from the junction of Highway 401 and the Don Valley Parkway in Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario The War in Afghanistan, which began on October 7 2001 as the U This stretch of the freeway is often travelled by a convoy of vehicles carrying a fallen soldier &apos;s body with his or her family from CFB Trenton to the coroner &apos;s office in Toronto, at the Centre for Forensic Sciences. A convoy is a group of Vehicles (of any type but usually motor vehicles or ships traveling together for mutual support Vehicles, derived from the Latin word vehiculum, are non-living Means of transport. A soldier is a general English term that refers to a member of a land component of National Armed forces. Family denotes a group of People affiliated by consanguinity affinity or co-residence Canadian Forces Base Trenton (also CFB Trenton) is a Canadian Forces Base located northeast of Trenton, Ontario. A coroner is an official responsible for investigating deaths particularly some of those happening under unusual circumstances and determining the cause of death 

Since 2002 , when the first of Canada&apos;s fallen soldiers were returned from Afghanistan, crowds from the communities along this stretch of the 401 lined the overpasses to pay their respects as the convoy passes. See also 2002 (disambiguation Year 2002 ( MMII) was a Common year starting on Tuesday of the Gregorian calendar. The highway&apos;s designation as the &quot;Macdonald-Cartier Freeway&quot; will remain throughout the freeway&apos;s length. [11] [12] From the Don Valley Parkway to Trenton, large signs and several smaller reassurance markers with the new designation have been added to this stretch of the 401. Similar to the older and discontinued M-C Freeway shields installed in the 1960s, the King&apos;s Highway shields along with two shields with a poppy symbol (one with 401 designation and two with poppies with text Highway of Heroes and Autoroute des héros ) appear after each on ramp along the route.

 Highway of Heroes Gallery 
Showing the New Highway 401 Highway of Heroes Sign
 
Showing another Highway 401 Highway of Heroes Sign
 

 

 Carnage Alley 

The section of Highway 401 between Windsor and London has become known as &quot;Carnage Alley&quot;, particularly since 1988 , when a long string of particularly violent and deadly accidents occurred in this section. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Year 1988 ( MCMLXXXVIII) was a Leap year starting on Friday (link displays 1988 Gregorian calendar) An accident is a specific identifiable unexpected unusual and unintended external event which occurs in a particular time and place without apparent or deliberate These accidents have occurred because of the road&apos;s initial 1950s design, particularly narrow lanes, soft shoulders , and a narrow grass median which have been insufficient in preventing cross-directional collisions. A hard shoulder, or simply shoulder, is a reserved area by the verge of a Road or Motorway. This stretch of highway is also the busiest truck route in North America . * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * Before adding any more images to this * * page please do carefully consider * * whether they would be mere decoration * * or actually improve A bypass is a Road or Highway that avoids or&amp;quotbypasses;&quot;a built-up area town or village to let through Traffic flow without interference from 

This segment of Highway 401 was the site of Canada&apos;s deadliest automobile pile-up . A multi-vehicle collision (colloquially known as a pile-up) is a Road traffic accident involving many vehicles Generally occurring on Freeways An 87-vehicle crash occurred on the freeway just east of the Manning Road interchange and truck inspection center, during a thick fog on September 3 , 1999 ( Labour Day weekend). This page lists all of the numbered County roads in Essex County Ontario. Events 36 BC - In the Battle of Naulochus, Marcus Vipsanius Agrippa, Admiral of Octavian, defeats Sextus Pompeius Year 1999 ( MCMXCIX) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display full 1999 Gregorian calendar) Labour Day is an annual Holiday celebrated all over the world that resulted from efforts of The MTO immediately added paved shoulders and rumble strips , and provided funding for additional police to be hired to patrol this stretch. Rumble strips (also known as audio tactile profiled markings) are a Road safety feature that alert drivers to potential danger by causing a Tactile The Ontario Provincial Police ( OPP) is the Provincial Police force for the province of Ontario, Canada. The CAA described these steps as a &quot;quick-fix&quot;, as their preferred solution is to replace the grass median with a concrete barrier and an additional lane per direction; this is a long-term plan of the Ministry. The Canadian Automobile Association (commonly known as CAA) is a non-profit federation founded in 1913 of nine clubs across Canada, providing roadside assistance A Jersey barrier or Jersey wall separates lanes of traffic (often opposing lanes of traffic with a goal of minimizing vehicle crossover in the case of accidents For more on this, read below .

One of the more accident-prone parts of the freeway is at Exit 109 (Victoria Road, formerly Highway 21 , now Chatham-Kent Roads 17/21). Highway 21 is a Provincial Highway in Ontario, Canada which begins at Highway 402 (Ontario at the south to Highways 6 and 26 The freeway curves immediately east of the interchange and many people are not used to a curve near an interchange, particularly on the Windsor-London stretch of freeway, which is mainly straight.

As a result of such accidents which can shut down the freeway, there is the implementation of province-wide &quot; Emergency Detour Routes &quot; (labelled &quot;EDR&quot; along freeways and exits). The Emergency Detour Routes are a system of temporary detour routes Paralleling most major highways in Ontario. These EDRs are signed at exits, and along parallel county roads (which may or may not have been downgraded/former provincial highways) or major arterial roads in towns and cities to help motorists detour around an accident and find their way back to the freeway if a stretch of it is closed for any reason. A county highway (also county road or county route; usually abbreviated CH or CR) is a road in the United States and in the Canadian However, this diverts high speed highway traffic on to low speed country roads, creating congestion due to the reduced capacity of the road.

 

 Speeding and Tailgating 

Many of the accidents described earlier are attributed to excessive speeding and following too closely , causing many motorists in Ontario to consider having the MTO raise the speed limit on 400-series highways from 100 km/h (60 mph) to 110-120 km/h (70-75 mph), bringing the network in line with comparable freeway networks in the United States , Europe , and other provinces such as Alberta . For a discussion of the maximum speed possible in the universe see Speed of light and Special relativity. Tailgating is the practice of driving on a road too closely behind another vehicle such as less than the travel distance in two seconds or equivalently one vehicle-length The United States of America —commonly referred to as the Alberta (ælˈbɝtə is one of Canada&apos;s prairie provinces. It became a province on September 1 1905 The speed limit was reduced from 70 mph (pre- metric ) in 1974 by act of Provincial Parliament. The basis for this reduction was improved safety, unlike the reductions in US speed limits at the same time, which were ostensibly to save fuel . Fuel is any material that is burned or altered in order to obtain energy Recently, to combat excessive speeding, the Ontario Provincial Legislature, on the recommendation of the Ministry of Transportation and the Ontario Provincial Police , has passed a law that allows police to immediately suspend the driver’s licence and impound the vehicle involved for seven days in the case of &quot;excessive speeding&quot; (driving 50 km/h over the limit, or over 150 km/h on 400-series highways). The Ontario Provincial Police ( OPP) is the Provincial Police force for the province of Ontario, Canada. Transport trucks are also going to be limited by speed governors to 105 km/h, (65 mph) the same as in nearby Ohio , with mixed public sentiment on the matter. This article is about the semi-truck For the North American use of the word see Pickup truck. A governor is a device used to measure and regulate the Speed of a Machine, such as an Engine. Ohio ( is a Midwestern state of the United States. As part of the Great Lakes region, Ohio has long been a cultural and geographical crossroads In contrast with proposals for raising the speed limit, there has been growing grass roots support for a revival of photo-radar with a twist: the total proceeds from photo-radar fines are diverted to a specific charity such as a local hospital emergency room (where many highway traffic accident victims end up) overcoming previous objections to photo-radar where fines were perceived by the public to be mixed with the government&apos;s general tax revenue. A traffic enforcement camera is a system including a Camera and a Vehicle -monitoring device used to detect and identify vehicles disobeying a Speed limit A hospital is an institution for Health care providing treatment by specialised staff and equipment and often but not always providing for However, the perception that photo-radar will reduce excessive speeding has been shown to be false.

 

 Overview 
 Highway 401 was completed in 1968 
Highway 401 begins at Highway 3 , 13 km (8 mi) from the Detroit River on the outskirts of Windsor (not at the Michigan border as some mistakenly assume, though the exits on the freeway are listed as distances from the Ambassador Bridge [2] ) and ends at the Quebec border, 818 km (508. Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. The Detroit River is a river in the Great Lakes system about 32 miles (51&amp;nbspkm;long and 0 Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. Michigan ( is a Midwestern state of the United States of America. The Ambassador Bridge is a Privately-owned Suspension bridge that connects Detroit, Michigan, in the United States, with Windsor Quebec (kwɨˈbɛk 28 mi) away. There are 18 rest areas or service centres (oases) located along the route, allowing motorists to access services without leaving the highway. A rest area, travel plaza, rest stop, or service area is a public facility located next to a large thoroughfare such as a Highway, Expressway A plaque was erected at the Mallorytown oasis, located on the last section of the freeway to be completed, stating that the 401 was the longest non-toll freeway under a single highway authority in North America. (Today the section of Interstate 10 in Texas holds this record. In the US state of Texas, Interstate 10 is the major east-west Interstate Highway in the Southern United States. )

Major freeway junctions are located at these roads and highways: 402 , Highbury Avenue ( London ), 403 , 8 , 6 , 407 , 410 , 427 , 400 , Allen Road ( Toronto ), 404 and Don Valley Parkway (Toronto), 35 and 115 , 416 . Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge Highbury Avenue is an arterial road/expressway located in London and St London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Highway 8 is a King&apos;s Highway in the Canadian province of Ontario. Highway 6 is one of the King&apos;s Highways in the province of Ontario, Canada. Highway 407, officially called the 407 Express Toll Route (ETR, is a Tollway located in the Greater Toronto Area, southern Ontario, Canada Highway 410 is a 400-Series highway in Ontario, Canada that connects Highways 401 and 403 with Toronto &apos;s western suburbs The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of William R Allen Road, known more commonly as Allen Road, The Allen Expressway or simply The Allen is a short Expressway / Freeway Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario Highway 404 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada. It runs from the junction of Highway 401 and the Don Valley Parkway in The Don Valley Parkway (generally referred to as the DVP) is a controlled-access six-lane Freeway in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, so Highway 35 is a provincial highway in Ontario Canada, running from Highway 401 in Clarington to Highway 60 near Dwight (and Algonquin Highway 115 is a provincially maintained highway in Central Ontario, Canada, which runs from the Highway 401 junction west of Newcastle Highway 416, named the Veterans Memorial Highway, is a 400-Series Highway in eastern Ontario that connects between Highway 417 in Ottawa and Quebec Autoroute 20 continues the highway at its eastern end. Quebec (kwɨˈbɛk Autoroute 20 (also called Autoroute Jean-Lesage, Autoroute du Souvenir or the Two and Twenty) is an important Autoroute in Quebec 

There are no direct interchanges with U. S. Interstate highways , but Interstates 75 and 375 in Detroit, Michigan , and Interstate 81 in New York State are each a short distance away, via Highways 3 , the former 3B , and 137 , leading to the Ambassador Bridge , the Detroit-Windsor Tunnel , and the Thousand Islands Bridge , respectively. The Dwight D Eisenhower National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, commonly called the Interstate Highway System (or simply the Interstate System) Interstate 75 (I-75 is a major north-south Interstate Highway in the midwest and southeastern United States. At only in length Interstate 375 (I-375 in Detroit has the distinction of being the shortest signed Interstate Highway that is up to Interstate Standards Interstate 81 (abbreviated I-81) is an Interstate highway in the eastern part of the United States. New York ( is a state in the Mid-Atlantic and Northeastern regions of the United States and is the nation&apos;s third most populous Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. This road is not to be confused with the Highway 3B that is now Norfolk County highway 51 (Simcoe Street. Highway 137 is a short Highway that connects Ontario &apos;s Highway 401 at Exit 661 to the New York The Ambassador Bridge is a Privately-owned Suspension bridge that connects Detroit, Michigan, in the United States, with Windsor The Detroit–Windsor Tunnel is a partially submerged Highway tunnel connecting Detroit Michigan in the United States, with Windsor Ontario The Thousand Islands Bridge is an international bridge over the Saint Lawrence River connecting northern New York Highway 402 also links Highway 401 to I-69 / I-94 via the Bluewater Bridge in Sarnia, Ontario . Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge Interstate 69 (I-69 is an Interstate Highway in the United States. The Blue Water Bridge is a twin-span bridge that spans the St Sarnia is a City in Southwestern Ontario, Canada (city population 71419 census area population An extension to a potential border crossing with Michigan in the western portion of Windsor may eventually connect to a spur Interstate in Detroit, Michigan , but no routing on the extension has been determined yet. Michigan ( is a Midwestern state of the United States of America. A spur route is a short Road forming a branch from a longer more important route (typically a major road Freeway, Interstate Highway or Motorway The auxiliary Interstate Highways (also called 3-digit Interstate Highways) is an additional network of freeways of the Interstate Highway System. 

 

 Transportation corridor 
 The 401 at Don Mills Road . Don Mills Road is a north-south route in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, passing through the former cities of East York and North York 
The 401 is one of the world&apos;s busiest highways, with an estimated Annual Average Daily Traffic (AADT) of over 500,000 in 2006, between the Weston Road and Highway 400 interchanges in Toronto. Weston Road is a north-south street in west end Toronto, Ontario, Canada. The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of [4] Due to its triple use as the main trade , commuting and recreational corridor in Ontario, 24-hour traffic volumes can exceed the 500,000 level on some days. A trade route is a logistical network identified as a series of pathways and stoppages used for the commercial transport of cargo Recreation or fun is the expenditure of time in a manner designed for therapeutic refreshment of one&apos;s Body or Mind. The just-in-time inventory systems of the highly integrated auto industry in Michigan and Ontario have made the highway the busiest truck route in the world. Just-in-time ( JIT) is an inventory strategy implemented to improve the Return on investment of a Business by reducing in-process Inventory and The automotive industry is the industry involved in the design development manufacture marketing and sale of Motor vehicles In 2007 more than 73 million motor vehicles Michigan ( is a Midwestern state of the United States of America. A bypass is a Road or Highway that avoids or&amp;quotbypasses;&quot;a built-up area town or village to let through Traffic flow without interference from Highway 401 also includes the continent&apos;s busiest multi-structure bridge at Hogg&apos;s Hollow in Toronto (four structures for the highway&apos;s four roadway beds). Hogg&apos;s Hollow Bridge is a set of four separate highway bridges that span the Don River Valley and carries the eastbound and westbound traffic of Highway 401, split The first of these structures served as a bypass for Highway 11 , and was built in 1929), with the three others being built more recently. Highway 11 is one of the longest of Ontario &apos;s King&apos;s Highways with a current length ( As of 2004) of 1780 Kilometres (1106 mi) 

The 401 is a strategically important highway in Canada, as it connects the populous Southern Ontario region with Quebec and Michigan, while also connecting to most other major highways in the province. The 401 also acts as a &apos;short cut&apos; between Detroit and Buffalo, New York (via Queen Elizabeth Way and Highway 403 ), and is used by many American motorists for this reason. Buffalo (ˈbʌfəloʊ is the second largest city in New York State. The Queen Elizabeth Way (commonly referred to as the QEW, Q, QE, or Queen-E) is a vital 400-Series Freeway in Ontario Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 The highway also serves as the principal connection to Montreal and points east, including New England , becoming Autoroute 20 at the Quebec border. Montreal, or Montréal in French ( pronounced in French, in English) is the largest city in the Canadian province of Quebec History See also History of New England New England&apos;s earliest inhabitants were Algonquian -speaking Native Americans including the Autoroute 20 (also called Autoroute Jean-Lesage, Autoroute du Souvenir or the Two and Twenty) is an important Autoroute in Quebec The border crossing at Windsor and Detroit is the busiest trade crossing in the world, and although the 401 itself does not physically extend the last few kilometres into Detroit, [2] it is the only route from Toronto to Windsor and on to Interstate 75 (aside from the Bluewater Bridge in Sarnia via Highway 402 and I-69 / I-94 ). Interstate 75 (I-75 is a major north-south Interstate Highway in the midwest and southeastern United States. The Blue Water Bridge is a twin-span bridge that spans the St Sarnia is a City in Southwestern Ontario, Canada (city population 71419 census area population Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge Interstate 69 (I-69 is an Interstate Highway in the United States. A future expansion of the Windsor-Detroit border crossing, which will include a freeway bypass of the existing Highway 3, may result in Highway 401 having a direct freeway link to the border. The route and type of roadway built is causing much debate in the Windsor area, with the city opting for a partially covered roadway with parks overtop. However, the provincial and federal governments of Canada are seemingly opting for a cheaper less-effective solution, likely to be a simple at-grade highway extending to the new crossing. Some 40% of Canada-U. S. trade travels the highway, representing one-third of Canada&apos;s foreign trade, and 4% of all U. S. foreign trade. However, it is not part of the Trans-Canada Highway . The Trans-Canada Highway is a federal-provincial Highway system that joins all ten provinces of Canada. 

 

 Collector-express sections 

Today the stretch of Highway 401 that passes through the Greater Toronto Area ranges from 6 to 18 lanes. The Greater Toronto Area (locally abbreviated as the GTA) is the most populous Metropolitan area in Canada. 

 

 Islington Avenue to Brock Road 
 Highway 401 west of the Don Valley Parkway/Highway 404 junction, showing the wide 14-lane cross-section 
The section that now runs through Toronto was a rural roadway that was entirely outside of the Toronto city limits when first opened, and was originally referred to as the Toronto Bypass . Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario The new freeway attracted development all along its length. As the city&apos;s suburbs grew, it quickly became an urban commuter road, rather than a long-distance bypass route as was originally planned, leading to extensive traffic jams. South San Jose (cropjpg||thumb|A suburban development in San Jose California. 

This was a problem/opportunity solved and built upon to some extent by implementing separate express and collector lanes , similar to the express/local set-up of the Dan Ryan Expressway in Chicago . Local-express lanes or collector-express lanes are a set of two same-direction one-way multi-lane roadways usually on a Freeway. Dan Ryan Expressway runs from the Circle Interchange with I-290 near downtown Chicago through the south side of the city Chicago (ʃɪˈkɑːgoʊ is the largest City by population in the state of Illinois and the American Midwest of the United States. Transfers, such as The Basketweave allow traffic to move from the express to collector lanes and vice versa. The Basketweave is the name of stretch of Highway 401 in Ontario, Canada, immediately east of the Jane Street underpass in Toronto 

Though Highway 401&apos;s collectors are intended more for urban commuters, they enjoy equal access to intersecting freeways as the express lanes do, such as at the junctions with Highway 404 and somewhat with Highway 400, so their use is not restricted to local traffic. It also facilitates road maintenance, as the MTO can to close off either the express or collector lanes for night repairs or upgrades. By contrast, the collector-express system on Highway 427 separate out two streams of traffic; the express lanes connect the QEW/Gardiner with 401 and exclusively lead to freeway-to-freeway ramps, while the collector lanes link up the arterials Highway 27 and Browns Line and have interchanges with local traffic. The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen 

By 1967 Highway 401 was widened from four lanes to 12 or more through Toronto from Islington Avenue to Warden Avenue . Islington Avenue is a north-south route travelling through the City of Toronto and York Region. Warden Avenue is a major north-south road in Scarborough, Ontario, Canada. In the early 1970s the collector express lanes were extended to Neilson Road and eastward to Brock Road by 1997.

The main collector-express setup with a minimum 12 lane cross-section currently stretches from Islington Avenue to Brock Road. Local-express lanes or collector-express lanes are a set of two same-direction one-way multi-lane roadways usually on a Freeway. Highway 409 which branches off from Highway 401 just west of Islington to Toronto Pearson International Airport has been unsuccessful in diverting traffic volumes; the 10 lane segment between Islington and Highway 427 is highly congested as a result. Highway 409 is an Ontario provincial 400 series Expressway that extends from the Highway 401 in Toronto to Toronto Pearson International Lester B Pearson International Airport is a major International airport serving Toronto, Ontario, Canada, situated 27 kilometres (17 mi northwest The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen The existing 401-427 interchange is considered one of the worst bottlenecks since it only allows eight lanes of traffic (four in each direction) to pass through the interchange. It initially only allowed six lanes of through traffic until a widening project was completed in 2005; a major reconstruction of the junction is needed to meet current demands estimated at five-to-six lanes.

An alternative plan to the collector-express setup was to construct a bypass of Highway 401. This project was revived in 1987 and opened in 1997 as the toll road Highway 407 ETR to parallel Highway 401 in the Greater Toronto Area . Highway 407, officially called the 407 Express Toll Route (ETR, is a Tollway located in the Greater Toronto Area, southern Ontario, Canada The Greater Toronto Area (locally abbreviated as the GTA) is the most populous Metropolitan area in Canada. 

 

 Signage 

In order to make sure drivers are not confused by signs appearing in other lanes, colours have been assigned to both Collector and Express Lanes. Collector lanes (handling traffic merging from and to exits) are blue while Express Lane signs are green. Due to the urban nature of the road, all signs are mounted overhead on gantries. The green signs list up to three upcoming exits (for example: Leslie St, Bayview Ave, Yonge St, 4 km). However, the mileage indicated on the signs do not indicate the actual distance to the next exit, they only indicate the distance to the next transfer to the collectors. Once in the collector lanes, the blue signs direct and inform drivers of the distance until the exit ramp (for example: Leslie Street, 1 km).

 

 Highway 403/410 to Highway 427 
 The four Etobicoke Creek bridges in the background carrying the 18 lanes of Highway 401&apos;s collector-express system. Etobicoke Creek (ɛˈtoʊbɨkoʊ) is one of the many creeks running through Toronto, Ontario and the Toronto Area into Lake Ontario In the foreground is burnt-out wreckage of Air France Flight 358 at Toronto Pearson International Airport . Air France Flight 358, a flight from Paris, France to Toronto, Ontario, Canada using an Airbus A340 airliner departed Lester B Pearson International Airport is a major International airport serving Toronto, Ontario, Canada, situated 27 kilometres (17 mi northwest 
Highway 401 has a separate collector-express system in Mississauga between the junctions with Highways 403 / 410 and Highway 427 . Local-express lanes or collector-express lanes are a set of two same-direction one-way multi-lane roadways usually on a Freeway. Mississauga (ˌmɪsɪˈsɑgə) incorporated in 1974 is a City located in the Regional Municipality of Peel Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Highway 410 is a 400-Series highway in Ontario, Canada that connects Highways 401 and 403 with Toronto &apos;s western suburbs The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen This was completed in 1986, concurrent with the expansion of the 401-403 interchange and the addition of two express flyover ramps and includes an eastbound collector-express transfer known as the &quot;Tunnel. The Basketweave is the name of stretch of Highway 401 in Ontario, Canada, immediately east of the Jane Street underpass in Toronto &quot; At 18 lanes wide this is the widest section of Highway 401, although at the present only nine lanes are designated for 401 through traffic (as express lanes) while the collector lanes serve as direct connections or ramp extensions from 403/410 to 427.

The existing 401/427 interchange remains a bottleneck to possible east expansion of this configuration that would link it up with the Islington-Brock collector-express system. Another choke point is at the 403/410 interchange since the 401 narrows down to eight lanes west of that junction. However, that junction has been designed with westward expansion of the collector-express system in mind; several prerequisite projects to accommodate widening from 403/410 to Mississauga Road were underway in the late 1990s, including a new interchange at Mavis Road and the reconstruction of the Mississauga Road and Derry Road overpasses. Peel Regional Road 18, or locally known as Mavis Road is a street in Peel Region, Ontario, Canada, running in the cities of Mississauga 


 

 Future expansion and upgrades 

In the 1950s, Highway 401 had initially been constructed as a four lane divided highway but the narrow grass median has since proven insufficient in preventing cross-directional collisions. In 1999, the Windsor-London stretch of Highway 401 was infamously dubbed as &quot;Carnage Alley&quot; after several fatal accidents, including an 87 vehicle pileup on Labour Day weekend during thick fog that claimed seven lives just east of the Manning Road interchange and truck inspection center. This page lists all of the numbered County roads in Essex County Ontario. Much work has involved replacing the median strip with an &quot;Ontario tall-wall&quot; concrete barrier and often an extra lane per direction. Due to this pile-up, the Ministry of Transportation began erecting signs that say &quot;Fatigue Kills, Take A Break&quot; and &quot;Tailgating Kills, Leave Some Space&quot; along the route between Windsor and London. These were later applied to other notoriously dangerous stretches of provincial highways across the province. [13] 

Areas currently being upgraded are between Windsor and Tilbury , around the City of Kingston , the London area, from Stevenson Road in Oshawa to Highway 35 / 115 , from Port Hope to Cobourg , and west from Cambridge towards Woodstock . Tilbury ( 2001 population 4534 is a Community in the municipality of Chatham-Kent, Ontario Kingston Ontario is a Canadian city located at the eastern end of Lake Ontario, where the lake runs into the St London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Highway 35 is a provincial highway in Ontario Canada, running from Highway 401 in Clarington to Highway 60 near Dwight (and Algonquin Highway 115 is a provincially maintained highway in Central Ontario, Canada, which runs from the Highway 401 junction west of Newcastle Port Hope is a Municipality in Ontario, Canada, about 109 km east of Toronto and about 159 km west of Kingston. Cobourg (2006 population 18210 is a town in the Canadian province of Ontario, located 110km east of Toronto. Cambridge ( 2006 population 124371 is a city located on the Grand River and Speed River Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario This will be followed later by staged upgrades between Trenton and Belleville , and eventually the remaining sections between Cobourg and Kingston. Trenton Ontario (2001 population 19374 is a community on the Bay of Quinte. Belleville ( 2006 population 48821 metropolitan population 91518 is a city located at the mouth of the Moira River on the Bay of Quinte in southeastern Upgrading the final rural sections between Tilbury, Chatham and London, and from Cornwall to the Quebec Boundary remain beyond the 35-year planning horizon at this time.

 

 Windsor-area upgrades and extensions 

On 14 November 2005 , the joint Canadian-American committee studying the options for expanding the Windsor - Detroit border crossing announced that its preferred option was to directly extend Highway 401 westward, using a new bridge or tunnel to cross the Detroit River and interchange with Interstate 75 somewhere between the existing Ambassador Bridge span and Wyandotte . Events 1533 - Conquistadors from Spain under the leadership of Francisco Pizarro arrive in Cajamarca, Inca Year 2005 ( MMV) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link displays full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. The Detroit River is a river in the Great Lakes system about 32 miles (51&amp;nbspkm;long and 0 Interstate 75 (I-75 is a major north-south Interstate Highway in the midwest and southeastern United States. The Ambassador Bridge is a Privately-owned Suspension bridge that connects Detroit, Michigan, in the United States, with Windsor Wyandotte is a city in Wayne County in the US state of Michigan. The exact route of this new highway connection has not yet been determined [14] .

In the 14 February 2008 issue of The Windsor Star , it was reported that the Ministry of Transportation was buying properties and making offers to buy other properties on the southwest side of Windsor for a potential extension of Highway 401. Events 842 - Charles the Bald and Louis the German swear the Oaths of Strasbourg in the French and German 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common The Windsor Star is the regional newspaper of Windsor Ontario (the only daily newspaper in Windsor and Essex County) and is owned by CanWest Global The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law The area where the MTO is reportedly purchasing property is just south of E.C. Row Expressway , parallel to the existing freeway, where there is light development. The E C Row Expressway is an isolated Freeway serving the central portion of Windsor Ontario, Canada. Currently, the area is mostly rural, with a few newer houses with older ones as well, along with mostly-undeveloped parks and nature preserves (see Neighbourhoods of Windsor, Ontario#West_Side for more information on this neighbourhood). Windsor&apos;s Department of Parks and Recreation maintains 3000 Acres (12 km² of green space 180 parks 40 miles (64 km of trails 22 miles (35 km of sidewalk 60 parking lots Windsor Ontario has a very diverse population and this diversity is shown in its many neighbourhoods Currently, the Ministry of Transportation has stated tenative plans for the extension of Highway 401 by travelling up Highway 3 /Talbot Road/ Huron Church Road , before branching west towards E. Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Huron Church Road is a principal Arterial road in Windsor Ontario and is among the busiest roads in all of Canada serving the world&apos;s busiest border crossing C. Row Expressway, heading towards the river towards a new bridge to Interstate 75 . Interstate 75 (I-75 is a major north-south Interstate Highway in the midwest and southeastern United States. The cost for the access route/extension is estimated to be at $ 1. 5 billion, but does not include expropriating homes and businesses along Highway 3 and in the &quot;Yawkey Bush&quot; neighbourhood. This plan follows the &quot; GreenLink &quot; proposal drafted up by the Detroit River International Crossing and the Windsor City Council . There are over 150 interchanges numbered from west to east on Highway 401 in Ontario. The Windsor City Council is the governing body of Windsor Ontario, Canada 

Home owners along the newly-built Chappus Street subdivision have stated they are worried that their land values will weaken if they are sandwiched between E. C. Row and Highway 401, as their houses (and the extension of Chappus Street) were built around 2003, while area developer Ashraf Botros claims that his plans for a much larger subdivision around Chappus Street now have to be scuttled from this potential extension. [15] .

On March 3 , 2008 , the Michigan Department of Transportation and the Ministry of Transportation of Ontario , (in partnership with Transport Canada and the Federal Highway Administration of the United States, and the Detroit River International Crossing group) completed a joint assessment on the soils along the Detroit River , on both the American and Canadian sides to determine if the ground in the area was strong enough to support the weight of a proposed bridge over the river. Events 1284 - Statute of Rhuddlan incorporated the Principality of Wales into England 1575 - Indian 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common The Michigan Department of Transportation ( MDOT) is a constitutional Government agency in the U The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law Transport Canada is the department within the government of Canada which is responsible for developing Regulations, Policies and services The Federal Highway Administration ( FHWA) is a division of the United States Department of Transportation that specializes in Highway transportation The Detroit River is a river in the Great Lakes system about 32 miles (51&amp;nbspkm;long and 0 The United States of America —commonly referred to as the Country to&amp;quotDominion;of Canada&quot;or&amp;quotCanadian;Federation&quot;or anything else please read the Talk Page The technical analysis had determined the soils along the river can indeed support the weight of a new bridge. This was a grave concern of all parties involved in the bridge construction process, due to the nearby Windsor Salt Mine &apos;s activities only a kilometer (0. The Windsor Salt Mine currently operates two locations in Windsor Ontario, Canada. Mining is the extraction of valuable Minerals or other geological materials from the earth usually (but not always from an Ore body 6 mile) or so away, and the soils in the area being of clay and sandy sediment . Clay is a naturally occurring material composed primarily of fine-grained Minerals which show plasticity through a variable range of Water content, and Sand is a naturally occurring Granular material composed of finely divided rock and Mineral particles Sediment is any particulate matter that can be transported by fluid flow and which eventually is deposited as a layer of solid particles on the bed or bottom of a body of [16] 

On May 1 , 2008 , a new proposed highway called the Windsor-Essex Parkway, will be connected extending Highway 401 to a new inspection plaza and river crossing in West Windsor. Events 305 - Diocletian and Maximian retire from the office of Roman Emperor. 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common This project will cost about $1. 6 billion but the parkway will put heavy trucks off local streets and there will be several tunnels so local residents can cross over the parkway with ease. There will be side roads running parallel along the parkway for local traffic. [17] 

 

 Essex County upgrades 

The vast majority of the Essex County upgrades have been completed and opened to traffic. The only parts remaining to be upgraded are from 3 km west of Manning Road, to Highway 401&apos;s terminus in Windsor at Highway 3, which will be upgraded pending the approval of a new border crossing. This part of freeway has become a widened, concrete-paved 6-lane freeway separated by an Ontario Tall-Wall barrier. Despite having a substantial increase in potential vehicle capacity, this section remains the newest and most lightly-travelled of any six-lane stretch of freeway in Ontario (as most freeways of 6+ lanes are found in major urban areas, such as the GTA , London , Kitchener , and Ottawa ). The Greater Toronto Area (locally abbreviated as the GTA) is the most populous Metropolitan area in Canada. London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Ottawa (ˈɒtəwə or sometimes /ˈɒtəwɑː/ is the Capital of Canada and the country&apos;s fourth largest municipality. 

 

 Highway 3 to Essex County Road 19 

The Windsor Star has reported that the stretch of Highway 401 from Highway 3 (its western terminus ) to where the road widens to three lanes per direction (3 km west of Manning Road) will remain as a four-lane route until a route to a potential new border crossing has been finalized. The Windsor Star is the regional newspaper of Windsor Ontario (the only daily newspaper in Windsor and Essex County) and is owned by CanWest Global Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. The MTO intends on upgrading this section, particularly its dangerous interchange with Highway 3 (sharp curves, poor lines of sight, aging overpass structure) when a new bridge and freeway corridor has been chosen. The road widens from four lanes to six lanes just after approaching the former westbound truck inspection station.

 

 County Road 19 to County Road 42 

Highway 401 is seeing a complete overhaul and expansion between the city of Windsor, Ontario and Tilbury, Ontario , in response to the 87-car pile-up that killed 8 on September 3 , 1999 . Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. Tilbury ( 2001 population 4534 is a Community in the municipality of Chatham-Kent, Ontario Events 36 BC - In the Battle of Naulochus, Marcus Vipsanius Agrippa, Admiral of Octavian, defeats Sextus Pompeius Year 1999 ( MCMXCIX) was a Common year starting on Friday (link will display full 1999 Gregorian calendar) The road is being expanded from two lanes per direction with a narrow grass median to three lanes per direction (with concrete pavement), rumble strips , a concrete divider, and newer overpasses at Highway 77 , French Line Road (St. Rumble strips (also known as audio tactile profiled markings) are a Road safety feature that alert drivers to potential danger by causing a Tactile Highway 77 is the name of a current King&apos;s Highway that travels from Leamington Ontario to Highway 401. Joachim Road), and two are planned for Puce Road, Belle River Road, and Former Rochester Township 3rd Concession Road (Eastern Lakeshore). [18] 

The next phase for upgrading and widening Highway 401 in Essex County is currently under way and will stretch from Belle River Road/Essex Road 27 to Highway 77, widening each carriageway from two to three lanes, with a concrete barrier, and should be completed by November 2007. This construction zone is roughly the same size as the previous two, at 10. 6 km in length. [19] 

 From (west) To (east) Originally Currently Planned 3 km West of Manning Road (County Road 19) to 1 km east of Belle River Road (County Road 27) 2 narrow lanes per direction, dangerously narrow carriageways, dangerously narrow median, bi-directional onramps 3 lanes per direction, tall concrete barrier, separated onramps Completed 1 km east of Belle River Road (CR 27) to 3 km west of Highway 77 interchange (10. This page lists all of the numbered County roads in Essex County Ontario. Highway 77 is the name of a current King&apos;s Highway that travels from Leamington Ontario to Highway 401. 6 km in length) 2 narrow lanes per direction, dangerously narrow carriageways, dangerously narrow median, bi-directional onramps Under Construction/Widening/Upgrades 3 lanes per direction, tall concrete barrier, separated onramps 3 km west of Highway 77 interchange to 1 km east of Queen&apos;s Line (County Road 42) in Tilbury 2 narrow lanes per direction, dangerously narrow carriageways, dangerously narrow median, bi-directional onramps 3 lanes per direction, tall concrete barrier, separated onramps Completed 

Additionally, the Windsor South Truck Inspection Station has been upgraded to a commercial vehicle inspection facility [20] 

 

 London area upgrades 

Highway 401 in London between Wellington Road and Highway 402 is currently being widened to six lanes. Highway 77 is the name of a current King&apos;s Highway that travels from Leamington Ontario to Highway 401. This page lists all of the numbered County roads in Essex County Ontario. Tilbury ( 2001 population 4534 is a Community in the municipality of Chatham-Kent, Ontario London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge The improvements will include high mast lighting, a changeable message sign, advanced drainage systems and paved shoulders on both sides of the roadway. This, with the widening projects between Woodstock and Kitchener , will make Highway 401 at least six lanes wide from Port Hope to the Highway 402 interchange (From London to Toronto). Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Port Hope is a Municipality in Ontario, Canada, about 109 km east of Toronto and about 159 km west of Kingston. 

The very busy Wellington Road interchange will be completely redesigned and rebuilt as a parclo interchange . The parclo interchange (a Portmanteau of partial cloverleaf interchange) is a modification of a Cloverleaf interchange. Construction began in 2006. This project is set to be complete by mid 2008.

By 2009, a parclo interchange with Wonderland Road west of the partial Highway 402 interchange will be completed to provide better connectivity for motorists in London&apos;s southwest end to access Highway 401 west to Windsor. The following highways are numbered 402: Canada Highway 402 (Ontario United States Colorado State 

Long term plans call for eight lanes through the city due to its increased use as a commuter road. However, these improvements are not planned until around 2020 and remain mid-to-long term goals for the Ministry of Transportation.

 Originally Currently Planned Lanes: 4 From Highway 402 to Wellington Road. The following highways are numbered 402: Canada Highway 402 (Ontario United States Colorado State Lanes: 4 From Highway 402 to Wellington Road. The following highways are numbered 402: Canada Highway 402 (Ontario United States Colorado State Lanes: 6 From Highway 402 to Highway 403 . The following highways are numbered 402: Canada Highway 402 (Ontario United States Colorado State The following highways are numbered 403: Canada Highway 403 (Ontario United States New York State Median: Ontario Tall-Wall. Median: Reinforced Ontario Tall-Wall. Median: Reinforced Ontario Tall-Wall with high mast lighting. Paved inner shoulder, gravel outer shoulder. No inner shoulder, paved outer shoulder. Paved inner and outer shoulders with outer drainage system. Rumble strips on outer shoulder Rumble strips on outer shoulder Rumble strips on both inner and outer shoulders 3/4 Cloverleaf interchange with Wellington Road. Overview Cloverleaf interchanges viewed from overhead or on maps resemble the leaves of a Four-leaf clover. 401 Westbound on/off ramps open, eastbound closed. Parclo A4 interchange with Wellington Road. The parclo interchange (a Portmanteau of partial cloverleaf interchange) is a modification of a Cloverleaf interchange. 

 

 Oxford County upgrades 

In the late Fall of 2005, the Ministry of Transportation of Ontario started a construction project to upgrade the current four-lane section of Highway 401 from four to six lanes from west of Oxford County Road 3 to west of Waterloo Regional Road 97 (where the next six-lane concrete-divided road begins) in the County of Oxford and Regional Municipality of Waterloo . The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law Oxford County is a Regional municipality and Census division of the Canadian province of Ontario. 

This is currently part of the last four-lane section between London and Toronto (stretching from Highway 403 Interchange in Woodstock, Ontario to Waterloo Road 97 in Kitchener, Ontario), but is being upgraded to 6 lanes plus an Ontario tall-wall barrier in the median. This is the first stage of upgrades of this final four-lane section.

In fall 2003, the widening of Highway 401 from four to six lanes from the Highway 8 interchange to Waterloo Regional Road 97 was completed. The Y-junctions with Highway 8 and Highway 403, opened in 1987 and 1990, respectively, were designed in mind to accommodate the widening of Highway 401 through Oxford and Waterloo.

 Currently Planned Lanes: 4 Lanes: 6 Median: Grassed Median: Ontario Tall-Wall Rumble strips Rumble strips (new) Interchanges every 5 km or so Interchanges every 5 km,
plus two new emergency ramps One slightly sharp curve north of Oxford Road (Oxford CR 29, Exit 250) slightly re-aligned and straightened (completed and re-opened) 

Aside from the addition of one lane per direction and a tall-wall barrier, two emergency ramp connectors that are intended to be used only during emergency highway closures and similar circumstances to permit traffic to move off the freeway (and emergency vehicles onto it) have been constructed. Built near Oxford Road 3 and Trussler Road, the ramps are an unprecedented addition to the Ontario highway system. onthighways.com source .

Other emergency accesses have been built in Essex County where the road was recently widened from 4 to 6 lanes, but these are gravel, and all are alongside overpasses, for use by ambulances, firetrucks, and police cars in emergencies only.

This is currently in stages, and will eventually close the 4-lane gap between the two 6-lane sections ( London /Wellington Road- Woodstock / Highway 403 and Kitchener /Waterloo Road 97 (Cedar Creek Drive)- Toronto ). London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario 

The first segment in Oxford County to see the upgrades is from Waterloo RR 97 to Oxford CR 3, with further upgrades planned from Oxford CR 3 to Highway 403. Oxford County is a Regional municipality and Census division of the Canadian province of Ontario. Several large upgrades will be carried out here:

 The interchange of Towerline Road and Middletown Line (Exit 236, just north of Highway 403) will be completely rebuilt and redesigned, as its current ramp configuration is extremely dangerous (short ramps with tight curves leading from an intersection just 30 feet/10 meters from the freeway, requiring a driver to &quot;floor it&quot; to get up to speed in time). The aging and sagging overpass structure at Towerline Road will be replaced, making this a long-overdue upgrade. The cloverleaf interchange with Former Highway 2 (Exit 238, which is the final remaining cloverleaf with two divided highways in the province) will be converted to a parclo interchange, as cloverleafs are no longer up to the Ministry of Transportation&apos;s safety standards (mostly from weaving). Overview Cloverleaf interchanges viewed from overhead or on maps resemble the leaves of a Four-leaf clover. Highway 2 was the major east-west provincial highway in Southern Ontario, running from Windsor in the west to the Quebec boundary near Lancaster The parclo interchange (a Portmanteau of partial cloverleaf interchange) is a modification of a Cloverleaf interchange. This will not be a disruptive construction contract, as the traffic volumes at the interchange are actually quite low (which is also why the cloverleaf interchange works smoothly) since former Highway 2 has been all but replaced by Highway 403 in the early 1990s. This will leave the Highway 4/401 interchange in London, Highway 62 /401 interchange in Belleville , and the former Highway 88 / Highway 400 interchange in Bradford as the last cloverleaf interchanges on a 400-series highway. Highway 62 is a provincially maintained highway in Ontario, Canada, running south-north from Highway 33 at Bloomfield in Prince Edward County Belleville ( 2006 population 48821 metropolitan population 91518 is a city located at the mouth of the Moira River on the Bay of Quinte in southeastern Highway 88 was a Provincial highway located in the Town of Bradford West Gwillimbury, which connected the village of Bond Head with the town of Bradford The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of Bradford is the primary country urban area of the Town of Bradford West Gwillimbury Ontario, in Canada. Overview Cloverleaf interchanges viewed from overhead or on maps resemble the leaves of a Four-leaf clover. 

 

 Mississauga upgrades 

There are plans to widen the Mississauga stretch from six lanes to 12 lanes from the 403-410 interchange to the Credit River, and 10 lanes to Mississauga Road; this has recently been a major bottleneck due to the reduced capacity west of the junction. Actual construction on the expansion is slated to start in 2008 at the earliest, but for the last decade, numerous prerequisite projects have been undertaken.

The 403-410 interchange , which was under construction from the 1970s until 1995, is designed in mind for westward expansion of the collector-express system. Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 The Highway 401 collector overpass structures crossing Highway 410 each of which have an additional lane which is currently unused. There is also an available right-of-way for a loop ramp from Highway 403 northbound to Highway 401 west and a direction ramp in the opposite direction, which is designed to improve access from Cawthra Road; this project would make the 403-410 interchange a full four-way interchange. Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 

The Kennedy Road overpass, opened in the early 1990s just west of the 403-410 junction, is wide enough to accommodate expansion of the 12 lane collector-express system. The Derry Road underpass have been widened to accommodate this in the late 1990s. An interchange has been added with Mavis Road in 1999, which has been extended north to Highway 401 and beyond, and the overpass abutments are designed to allow future lengthening so fourteen lanes can pass under. In 2002, the Mississauga Road four-lane overpass was replaced with an eight lane structure that can span fourteen lanes, while the interchange ramps were also realigned to support higher speeds.

The main obstacles to Highway 401 expansion are the aging Second Line, Creditview Road, and Hurontario Street (the bridge structure and ramps were realigned in the 1970s from its original cloverleaf configuration) overpasses , which were completed in the early 1960s and place height restrictions on vehicles passing under. An overpass (called a flyover in the UK and most Commonwealth countries is a Bridge, Road, Railway or They will be demolished and replaced as part of the reconstruction.

Recently, the Ministry of Transportation also has mid-term plans to construct HOV lanes along Highway 401 from Mississauga Road to the 403/410 interchange. The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law In Transportation engineering and Transportation planning, a high-occupancy vehicle lane (or HOV lane) is a lane reserved for Vehicles with They have also announced long-term plans to further extend the HOV lanes further west to Milton. [21] 


 

 Durham Region area upgrades 

Highway 401 in Durham Region between Stevenson Road and Highway 35 / 115 (approximately 23. Highway 35 is a provincial highway in Ontario Canada, running from Highway 401 in Clarington to Highway 60 near Dwight (and Algonquin Highway 115 is a provincially maintained highway in Central Ontario, Canada, which runs from the Highway 401 junction west of Newcastle 4km) has been resurfaced.

As this is the oldest stretch of freeway in use (having been constructed between 1938 and 1942), the road is seeing many upgrades, including the opening of new interchanges with longer ramps and better safety features, while older ones (such as the former Harwood Avenue interchange being replaced by the newly-built Salem Road interchange, 1 km to the east) have been closed off and removed.

The Park Road exit (Exit 416) is to be replaced by a new interchange at Stevenson Road in Oshawa . Construction began September 7, 2005. Currently, ramps from Stevenson Road to the Westbound 401 are open. [22] This project is set to be complete by 2010 at a total cost of $65,097,000. 00. [23] 

Further west in Ajax Highway 401 between Carruthers Creek and Church Street has been widened from four to five lanes. Ajax ( 2008 population 93104 is a town located in the Golden Horseshoe of south central Ontario, Canada. 

 

 Traffic cameras 

To manage traffic, the Ontario Ministry of Transportation (MTO) installed the Freeway Management System - COMPASS , the most advanced of its kind in the world when it was deployed in 1991 by Delcan Corporation . Freeway Management System - COMPASS is a traffic management system used by the Ontario Ministry of Transportation on highways in the Greater Toronto Area and parts Delcan Corporation is a system and infrastructure company based in Markham Ontario. Using a combination of CCTV cameras, vehicle detection loops and LED changeable message signs , the MTO Traffic Operations Centre can obtain a real-time assessment of traffic conditions and alert highway travellers of collisions and construction. Closed-circuit television ( CCTV) is the use of Video cameras to transmit a signal to a specific place limited set of monitors A variable- (also changeable-, electronic-, or dynamic-) message sign, often abbreviated VMS, CMS, or DMS, is The system currently stretches from Highway 403 , Mississauga to Harwood Avenue, Ajax , and is likely to be extended westward and eastward as Highway 401 is reconstructed and upgraded. Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Mississauga (ˌmɪsɪˈsɑgə) incorporated in 1974 is a City located in the Regional Municipality of Peel Ajax ( 2008 population 93104 is a town located in the Golden Horseshoe of south central Ontario, Canada. 

 

 Volume information (2005) 

 Highest Volume: 607,800 AADT from Weston Road (Exit 357) to Highway 400 (Exit 359) compared to 510,000 in 2003. Annual average daily traffic, abbrevated AADT, is a measure used primarily in Transportation planning and transportation engineering. Weston Road is a north-south street in west end Toronto, Ontario, Canada. The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of Lowest Volume: 15,000 AADT from Dougall Parkway (Former Highway 401A / Highway 3B ) (Exit 13) to Highway 3 , &quot; Bridge to U.S.A. &quot; 

 

 Major cities 
 A Highway 401 trailblazer at Kipling Avenue and Dixon Road in Etobicoke. Dougall Parkway is a municipal freeway in Windsor Ontario, acting as an extension of Dougall Avenue to lead traffic heading towards downtown into the city centre and to This road is not to be confused with the Highway 3B that is now Norfolk County highway 51 (Simcoe Street. Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. The Ambassador Bridge is a Privately-owned Suspension bridge that connects Detroit, Michigan, in the United States, with Windsor Kipling Avenue is a street in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. It is a Concession road, 6 concessions (12km from Yonge Street, and is a 
Listed below are notable cities along the route of Highway 401, from west to east. Bolded cities are officially-designated control cities for signs. A control city is a city or locality posted on a Traffic sign indicating forward destinations on a certain route [24] 

 
 Windsor Tilbury Chatham London Ingersoll Woodstock Kitchener-Waterloo Cambridge Guelph Milton Mississauga Toronto Pickering 
 
 Ajax Whitby Oshawa Clarington Port Hope Cobourg Trenton Belleville Greater Napanee Kingston Brockville Cornwall 
 

 

 Trivia 

In the late 1980s to late 1990s, the stretch of Highway 401 eastbound around Milton and westbound around Whitby had chevrons painted in the middle of each lane. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. Tilbury ( 2001 population 4534 is a Community in the municipality of Chatham-Kent, Ontario For the town in England see Chatham Kent. The Municipality of Chatham-Kent ( 2006 London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Ingersoll (2006 population 11760 is a Town in Oxford County on the Thames River in southwestern Ontario Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario Kitchener-Waterloo ( K-W) is an unofficial but ubiquitous name for the area in Ontario, Canada, consisting of the Twin cities of Kitchener Cambridge ( 2006 population 124371 is a city located on the Grand River and Speed River Milton ( 2006 census population 53939 is a town in southern Ontario, Canada, part of the Greater Mississauga (ˌmɪsɪˈsɑgə) incorporated in 1974 is a City located in the Regional Municipality of Peel Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario Pickering is a City located immediately east of Toronto in Durham Region, Ontario, Canada Ajax ( 2008 population 93104 is a town located in the Golden Horseshoe of south central Ontario, Canada. Whitby (2006 population 111184 is a Town in Ontario, Canada. Whitby is located east of Toronto The Municipality of Clarington is a municipality in Ontario, Canada in the Regional Municipality of Durham Port Hope is a Municipality in Ontario, Canada, about 109 km east of Toronto and about 159 km west of Kingston. Cobourg (2006 population 18210 is a town in the Canadian province of Ontario, located 110km east of Toronto. Trenton Ontario (2001 population 19374 is a community on the Bay of Quinte. Belleville ( 2006 population 48821 metropolitan population 91518 is a city located at the mouth of the Moira River on the Bay of Quinte in southeastern Greater Napanee (2001 population 15132 is a Town in Lennox and Addington County in eastern Ontario, Canada and is approximately 40 Kingston Ontario is a Canadian city located at the eastern end of Lake Ontario, where the lake runs into the St Cornwall is a City in eastern Ontario, Canada and the seat of the United Counties of Stormont Dundas and Glengarry Ontario. Milton ( 2006 census population 53939 is a town in southern Ontario, Canada, part of the Greater Whitby (2006 population 111184 is a Town in Ontario, Canada. Whitby is located east of Toronto Signs advised motorists to keep at least two chevrons apart, in essence warning them not to follow too closely. Some of these chevrons remain intact in the lanes in Whitby, although some of the signs stating their use have since been removed.

Highway 401 is the widest highway in the world in a total number of thru lanes with 18 in Mississauga . Mississauga (ˌmɪsɪˈsɑgə) incorporated in 1974 is a City located in the Regional Municipality of Peel 

In 1986, the Canadian writer George Elliot published God&apos;s Big Acre: Life in 401 Country , a series of vignettes and portraits collected along the Windsor-Quebec corridor of the 401.

Until the late 1990s, Highway 401 had blue signs near Windsor and the Greater Toronto Area stating nearby Interstate highways in the United States as &quot;Advantage: I-75 I-80 I-90 &quot;. The Dwight D Eisenhower National System of Interstate and Defense Highways, commonly called the Interstate Highway System (or simply the Interstate System) The United States of America —commonly referred to as the Interstate 75 (I-75 is a major north-south Interstate Highway in the midwest and southeastern United States. Interstate 80 (I-80 is the second-longest Interstate Highway in the United States (after I-90) Interstate 90 (I-90 is the longest interstate highway in the United States at nearly 3100 miles (5000 kilometers Advantage was Mainline Automated Clearance System that processed trucks electronically. Trucks were fitted with transponders that relayed location, date, time, weight and axle information. This allowed trucks to bypass truck inspection stations if they already have been inspected. It also improved processing times at truck inspection stations.

An example of the sign:

 ADVANTAGE
 

 

 Exit list 
 Main article: List of exits on Highway 401 (Ontario) 
The following are a few of the major interchanges:

 Location km [1] # Destinations Windsor 0. There are over 150 interchanges numbered from west to east on Highway 401 in Ontario. An exit number is a number assigned to a Road junction, usually an exit from a Freeway. Windsor is the southernmost city in Canada and lies at the western end of the heavily populated Quebec City-Windsor Corridor. 0 Hwy 3  west – Ambassador Bridge to USA 2. Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. The Ambassador Bridge is a Privately-owned Suspension bridge that connects Detroit, Michigan, in the United States, with Windsor 6 13 Dougall Parkway – Detroit-Windsor Tunnel to USA London 173. Dougall Parkway is a municipal freeway in Windsor Ontario, acting as an extension of Dougall Avenue to lead traffic heading towards downtown into the city centre and to The Detroit–Windsor Tunnel is a partially submerged Highway tunnel connecting Detroit Michigan in the United States, with Windsor Ontario London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper 2 183 Hwy 402  west – Sarnia 179. Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge Sarnia is a City in Southwestern Ontario, Canada (city population 71419 census area population 1 21 Highbury Avenue – St. Thomas Woodstock 225. Highbury Avenue is an arterial road/expressway located in London and St St Thomas is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada. It is the seat for Elgin County and gaining its city Charter on Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario 3 235 Hwy 403  east – Brantford , Hamilton Kitchener , Cambridge 267. Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Brantford is a city located on the Grand River in south-western Ontario, Canada. Hamilton (ˈhæməltən ( 2006 population 504559 UA population 647634 CMA population The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Cambridge ( 2006 population 124371 is a city located on the Grand River and Speed River 9 278 Hwy 8 – Cambridge , Kitchener , Waterloo Toronto 341. Highway 8 is a King&apos;s Highway in the Canadian province of Ontario. Cambridge ( 2006 population 124371 is a city located on the Grand River and Speed River The City of Kitchener (ˈkɪtʃɨnɚ is a City in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Waterloo is a City in Ontario, Canada. It is the smallest of the three cities in the Regional Municipality Toronto (təˈrɒntoʊ colloquially pronounced or) is the largest city in Canada and is the provincial capital of Ontario 1 348
352 Hwy 427 – Toronto Pearson International Airport , Downtown Toronto 348. The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen Lester B Pearson International Airport is a major International airport serving Toronto, Ontario, Canada, situated 27 kilometres (17 mi northwest Downtown Toronto is the heart of the City of Toronto. It is approximately bounded by Bloor Street (including areas slightly north of Bloor around Yonge Street 9 359 Hwy 400 / Black Creek Drive – Barrie 364. The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of 9 375 Hwy 404 / Don Valley Parkway – Downtown Toronto , Newmarket Pickering 399 Brock Road - To connect with the Temporary Eastern Terminus of Highway 407 ETR Clarington 425. Highway 404 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada. It runs from the junction of Highway 401 and the Don Valley Parkway in The Don Valley Parkway (generally referred to as the DVP) is a controlled-access six-lane Freeway in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, so Downtown Toronto is the heart of the City of Toronto. It is approximately bounded by Bloor Street (including areas slightly north of Bloor around Yonge Street Newmarket ( 2006 Population 74295 is a Town located approximately 45 km north of Toronto, Ontario Pickering is a City located immediately east of Toronto in Durham Region, Ontario, Canada Highway 407, officially called the 407 Express Toll Route (ETR, is a Tollway located in the Greater Toronto Area, southern Ontario, Canada The Municipality of Clarington is a municipality in Ontario, Canada in the Regional Municipality of Durham 3 436 Hwy 35 / Hwy 115 – Orono , Lindsay , Peterborough Leeds and the Thousand Islands 649. Highway 35 is a provincial highway in Ontario Canada, running from Highway 401 in Clarington to Highway 60 near Dwight (and Algonquin Highway 115 is a provincially maintained highway in Central Ontario, Canada, which runs from the Highway 401 junction west of Newcastle Orono is a community (population approximately 1800 in the Municipality of Clarington, Ontario, Canada. Lindsay ( 2001 population 16930 is a community on the Scugog River in the Kawartha Lakes region of southern Ontario, Canada, Peterborough is a City on the Otonabee River in central-eastern Ontario, Canada, 125 kilometres Leeds and the Thousand Islands is a township in the Canadian province of Ontario, located within Leeds and Grenville United Counties. 6 661 Hwy 137 – Hill Island, Thousand Islands Bridge to USA Edwardsburgh/Cardinal 708. Highway 137 is a short Highway that connects Ontario &apos;s Highway 401 at Exit 661 to the New York The Thousand Islands Bridge is an international bridge over the Saint Lawrence River connecting northern New York Edwardsburgh/Cardinal is a township in the United Counties of Leeds and Grenville of eastern Ontario. 6 721A Hwy 416  north – Kemptville , Ottawa 

 

 Service centres 

The service centres are located at the following points on Highway 401 and contain the following services * View Map :]

 Location km Direction Fuel Food Other Tilbury 61 Eastbound Shell Tim Hortons , KFC CLOSED MAR. Highway 416, named the Veterans Memorial Highway, is a 400-Series Highway in eastern Ontario that connects between Highway 417 in Ottawa and Kemptville is a town located in the Municipality of North Grenville in Eastern Ontario, Canada in the northernmost part of the United Counties of Leeds Ottawa (ˈɒtəwə or sometimes /ˈɒtəwɑː/ is the Capital of Canada and the country&apos;s fourth largest municipality. Tilbury ( 2001 population 4534 is a Community in the municipality of Chatham-Kent, Ontario Shell Canada Limited is the subsidiary of Europe -based Royal Dutch Shell and one of Canada &apos;s largest integrated oil Companies. Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Kentucky Fried Chicken, usually known as KFC, is a chain of Fast food restaurants based in Louisville Kentucky. 2008 Westbound Petro-Canada Tim Hortons , Mr. Sub closed 31 may 2008 West Lorne 144 Eastbound Shell Tim Hortons unknown 145 Westbound Petro-Canada McDonald&apos;s unknown Ingersoll 223 Westbound Esso Tim Hortons , Wendy&apos;s Nicholby&apos;s Express 225 Eastbound Esso Tim Hortons , Wendy&apos;s Nicholby&apos;s Express Cambridge 289 Eastbound Petro-Canada McDonald&apos;s Picnic Area Westbound Petro-Canada McDonald&apos;s Picnic Area
Ellis Chapel Newcastle 444 Westbound Esso Tim Hortons , Wendy&apos;s Nicholby&apos;s Express Port Hope 453 Eastbound Esso Tim Hortons , Mr. Sub , Wendy&apos;s unknown Trenton 519 Eastbound Petro-Canada McDonald&apos;s unknown Westbound Shell Tim Hortons , Mr. Sub , Wendy&apos;s unknown Camden East 591 Westbound Petro-Canada McDonald&apos;s unknown Odessa 604 Eastbound Esso Tim Hortons , KFC unknown Mallorytown 677 Westbound Esso Tim Hortons , Wendy&apos;s unknown 679 Eastbound Esso Tim Hortons , Wendy&apos;s Nicholby&apos;s Express Morrisburg 756 Eastbound Shell Tim Hortons , KFC CLOSED MARCH 2008 Ingleside 761 Westbound Esso Tim Hortons , KFC unknown Lancaster 827 Westbound Shell Wendy&apos;s 

 

 Lane configuration from west to east 

 Section Lane Configuration Huron Church Road/ Highway 3 to Essex County Road 42 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently under construction Essex County Road 42 to Highway 402 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently planned. Petro-Canada () is a Canadian oil and gas firm Its headquarters are in the Petro-Canada Centre in Calgary, Alberta Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Mr Sub, originally called Mr Submarine before the 1990s is a Submarine sandwich Store Chain in Canada. West Elgin is a municipality and Census subdivision in Elgin County, Ontario, Canada. Shell Canada Limited is the subsidiary of Europe -based Royal Dutch Shell and one of Canada &apos;s largest integrated oil Companies. Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Petro-Canada () is a Canadian oil and gas firm Its headquarters are in the Petro-Canada Centre in Calgary, Alberta Woodstock (2006 population 35480 is a City and the county seat of Oxford County in southwestern Ontario Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Cambridge ( 2006 population 124371 is a city located on the Grand River and Speed River Petro-Canada () is a Canadian oil and gas firm Its headquarters are in the Petro-Canada Centre in Calgary, Alberta Petro-Canada () is a Canadian oil and gas firm Its headquarters are in the Petro-Canada Centre in Calgary, Alberta Newcastle is a community in the Municipality of Clarington in Durham Region, Ontario, Canada. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Port Hope is a Municipality in Ontario, Canada, about 109 km east of Toronto and about 159 km west of Kingston. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Mr Sub, originally called Mr Submarine before the 1990s is a Submarine sandwich Store Chain in Canada. Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Trenton Ontario (2001 population 19374 is a community on the Bay of Quinte. Petro-Canada () is a Canadian oil and gas firm Its headquarters are in the Petro-Canada Centre in Calgary, Alberta Shell Canada Limited is the subsidiary of Europe -based Royal Dutch Shell and one of Canada &apos;s largest integrated oil Companies. Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Mr Sub, originally called Mr Submarine before the 1990s is a Submarine sandwich Store Chain in Canada. Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Loyalist is a township in central eastern Ontario, Canada on Lake Ontario. Petro-Canada () is a Canadian oil and gas firm Its headquarters are in the Petro-Canada Centre in Calgary, Alberta Loyalist is a township in central eastern Ontario, Canada on Lake Ontario. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Kentucky Fried Chicken, usually known as KFC, is a chain of Fast food restaurants based in Louisville Kentucky. Front of Yonge is a township in the Canadian province of Ontario, located within Leeds and Grenville United Counties. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. South Dundas is a township in eastern Ontario, Canada, in the United Counties of Stormont Dundas and Glengarry along the north shore of the St Shell Canada Limited is the subsidiary of Europe -based Royal Dutch Shell and one of Canada &apos;s largest integrated oil Companies. Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Kentucky Fried Chicken, usually known as KFC, is a chain of Fast food restaurants based in Louisville Kentucky. South Stormont is a township in eastern Ontario, Canada in the United Counties of Stormont Dundas and Glengarry. Esso (SO is an international trade name for ExxonMobil and its related companies Tim Hortons Inc is a Coffee -and- Doughnut Fast food restaurant chain Kentucky Fried Chicken, usually known as KFC, is a chain of Fast food restaurants based in Louisville Kentucky. South Glengarry is a township in eastern Ontario, Canada on the St Shell Canada Limited is the subsidiary of Europe -based Royal Dutch Shell and one of Canada &apos;s largest integrated oil Companies. Wendy&apos;s is an international chain of Fast food Restaurants founded by Dave Thomas in 1969 in Columbus Ohio. Highway 3 is a provincially maintained Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada. Essex County is a County and Census division located in Southwestern Ontario and covers an area at the southernmost tip of Canada Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge Highway 402 to Wellington Road ( London ) 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently under construction Wellington Road ( London ) to Highway 403 3 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently planned Highway 403 to Northumberland Street ( Waterloo Regional Road 50) 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently under construction Northhumberland St to Milton, ON 3 lanes in Each Direction Milton, ON to Highway 410 / Highway 403 3 Lanes in Each Direction
 Stretch east of Mississauga Road to 403/410 interchange currently being widened to accommodate a collector/express system 
 1 HOV lane per direction currently under planning Highway 410 / Highway 403 to Toronto Airport Basketweave 9 Lane collector/express system Eastbound
 5 Express, 4 Collector 
9 Lane collector/express system Westbound
 4 Express, 5 Collector Toronto Airport Basketweave to Highway 427 / Eglinton Avenue 9 Lane collector/express system Eastbound
 4 Express, 5 Collector 
9 Lane collector/express system Westbound
 4 Express, 5 Collector Under the Highway 427 Interchange 4 lanes in each direction Highway 427/Carlingview Drive to Highway 409 5 lanes in each direction Highway 409 to Highway 400 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 3 Collector Highway 400 to The Basketweave 9 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 5 Collector The Basketweave to Allen Road 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 3 Collector Allen Road to Don River West Branch Hogg&apos;s Hollow Bridge 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 3 Express, 4 Collector Don River West Branch to Yonge Street 6 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 2 Collector
1 additional collector lane in each direction currently under construction Yonge Street to Bayview Avenue 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 3 Collector Bayview Avenue to Highway 404 / Don Valley Parkway 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 3 Express, 4 Collector Highway 404/Don Valley Parkway to Kennedy Road 8 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 4 Collector Kennedy Road to Markham Road/ Highway 48 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 3 Express, 4 Collector Markham Road/Highway 48 to Neilson Road 6 lane collector/express system in each direction
 3 Express, 3 Collector Neilson Road to Whites Road (Durham Regional Road 38) 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 4 Express, 3 Collector Whites Road to Brock Road (Durham Regional Road 1) 7 lane collector/express system in each direction
 3 Express, 4 Collector Brock Road to Westney Road (Durham Regional Road 31) 6 lanes in each direction Westney Road to Salem Road (Durham Regional Road 41) 5 lanes in each direction Salem Road to Thickson Road 4 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently under construction Thickson Road to Stevenson Road 3 lanes in each direction
 2 additional lanes in each direction currently under construction Stevenson Road to Cobourg 3 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently planned Cobourg to Kingston western city limits 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently planned. Highway 402 is a 400-Series Highway in southwestern Ontario, Canada that runs 103 km (64 mi) from the Blue Water Bridge London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper London is a city in Southwestern Ontario, Canada along the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor with a metropolitan area population of 457720 the city proper Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Milton ( 2006 census population 53939 is a town in southern Ontario, Canada, part of the Greater Milton ( 2006 census population 53939 is a town in southern Ontario, Canada, part of the Greater Highway 410 is a 400-Series highway in Ontario, Canada that connects Highways 401 and 403 with Toronto &apos;s western suburbs Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 In Transportation engineering and Transportation planning, a high-occupancy vehicle lane (or HOV lane) is a lane reserved for Vehicles with Highway 410 is a 400-Series highway in Ontario, Canada that connects Highways 401 and 403 with Toronto &apos;s western suburbs Highway 403 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada that extends 126 km (78 Lester B Pearson International Airport is a major International airport serving Toronto, Ontario, Canada, situated 27 kilometres (17 mi northwest The King&apos;s Highway 427 is a 400-Series Highway in the Greater Toronto Area of Ontario, Canada, that runs from immediately south of the Queen Eglinton Avenue is an east-west thoroughfare in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, and in Mississauga to the west Highway 409 is an Ontario provincial 400 series Expressway that extends from the Highway 401 in Toronto to Toronto Pearson International The King&apos;s Highway 400, more commonly known as Highway 400 or the 400, is a key north-south 400-Series Highway in the Canadian province of The Basketweave is the name of stretch of Highway 401 in Ontario, Canada, immediately east of the Jane Street underpass in Toronto William R Allen Road, known more commonly as Allen Road, The Allen Expressway or simply The Allen is a short Expressway / Freeway This article is about the river in Toronto Canada For other rivers with the same name see Don River (disambiguation. Hogg&apos;s Hollow Bridge is a set of four separate highway bridges that span the Don River Valley and carries the eastbound and westbound traffic of Highway 401, split Yonge Street (pronounced&amp;quotyoung;&quot;is a major arterial street in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, and its northern Suburbs It was formerly Bayview Avenue is a major north-south route in Toronto, Ontario, Canada Highway 404 is a 400-Series Highway in Ontario, Canada. It runs from the junction of Highway 401 and the Don Valley Parkway in The Don Valley Parkway (generally referred to as the DVP) is a controlled-access six-lane Freeway in Toronto, Ontario, Canada, so Highway 48 is a King&apos;s highway in Southern Ontario stretching from Markham Ontario northward to near Beaverton in the township of Brock Ontario Cobourg (2006 population 18210 is a town in the Canadian province of Ontario, located 110km east of Toronto. Kingston Ontario is a Canadian city located at the eastern end of Lake Ontario, where the lake runs into the St Kingston western city limits to Sydenham Road ( Frontenac County Road 9) 3 lanes in each direction Sydenham Road to Montreal Street (Frontenac County Road 11) 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently under construction Montreal Street to Highway 15 2 lanes in each direction
 1 additional lane in each direction currently planned Highway 15 to Quebec Line 2 lanes in each direction 

 

 See also 

 400-series highways List of Ontario provincial highways Hogg&apos;s Hollow Bridge The Basketweave 

 

 References 
 
 ^ a b Ministry of Transportation of Ontario , 2004 Annual Average Daily Traffic ^ a b c Highway 401&apos;s distance measurements are from the foot of the Ambassador Bridge to the Quebec border, while the roadway officially starts at the interchange of Highway 3, a full 13 km shorter. Frontenac County, as defined by Statistics Canada is a Census division of the Canadian province of Ontario. Highway 15 is a provincially-maintained Highway in southeastern Ontario, Canada. Quebec (kwɨˈbɛk The 400-series highways are a network of controlled-access Freeways throughout the southern portion of the province of Ontario, Canada, forming a special See also Provincial highways in Ontario This is a list of current and former Provincial highways in the Canadian province of Ontario. Hogg&apos;s Hollow Bridge is a set of four separate highway bridges that span the Don River Valley and carries the eastbound and westbound traffic of Highway 401, split The Basketweave is the name of stretch of Highway 401 in Ontario, Canada, immediately east of the Jane Street underpass in Toronto The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law The Ambassador Bridge is a Privately-owned Suspension bridge that connects Detroit, Michigan, in the United States, with Windsor Quebec (kwɨˈbɛk Sources: http://www.thekingshighway.ca , Rand McNally Atlases, and the Ministry of Transportation ^ a b c TheKingsHighway ^ a b Ontario government investing $401 million to upgrade Highway 401 . The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law Ministry of Transportation ( 2002 - 08-06 ). The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law See also 2002 (disambiguation Year 2002 ( MMII) was a Common year starting on Tuesday of the Gregorian calendar. Events 1538 - Bogotá, Colombia, is founded by Gonzalo Jiménez de Quesada. Retrieved on 2007 - 03-18 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 37 - The Roman Senate annuls Tiberius &apos; will and proclaims Caligula emperor  “Highway 401 is one of the busiest highways in the world and represents a vital link in Ontario&apos;s transportation infrastructure, carrying more than 400,000 vehicles per day through Toronto. ” ^ Brian Gray ( 2004 - 04-10 ). &amp;quotMMIV;&quot;redirects here For the Modest Mouse album see&quot;Baron von Bullshit Rides Again&quot; Events 879 - Louis III becomes King of the Western Franks. 1407 - the lama GTA Economy Dinged by Every Crash on the 401 - North America&apos;s Busiest Freeway . Toronto Sun , transcribed at Urban Planet. The Toronto Sun is an English language daily tabloid Newspaper published in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Retrieved on 2007 - 03-18 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 37 - The Roman Senate annuls Tiberius &apos; will and proclaims Caligula emperor  “The &quot;phenomenal&quot; number of vehicles on Hwy. 401 as it cuts through Toronto makes it the busiest freeway in North America. . . ” ^ Department of Highways, Ontario , Annual Report for the Fiscal Year Ending March 31st , 1942, p. The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law Events 307 - After divorcing his wife Minervina, Constantine marries Fausta, the daughter of the retired Roman Emperor 9 ^ http://books.google.com/books?id=r0e-8PU_4dsC&amp;dq=%22new+kingston+road%22+oshawa&amp;q=%22highway+2s&amp;pgis=1#search Annual Report By Ontario Dept. of Highways, Ontario Dept. of Agriculture and Food, Ontario Dept. of Public Works, 1940, 1941, 1949 ^ TheKingsHighway.ca - History on Highway 401 ^ Highway 401 - the Story.html ^ TheKingsHighway.ca - History on Highway 401 ^ City News ^ CTV.ca ^ Hwy 401 - Page 3 - Ridgetown to London - Images ^ Jarvis, Anne. &quot; Second span on west side, group urges / Binational committee rejects Schwartz Report truck bypass &quot;, Windsor Star , 15 November 2005 . The Windsor Star is the regional newspaper of Windsor Ontario (the only daily newspaper in Windsor and Essex County) and is owned by CanWest Global Events 655 - Battle of Winwaed: Penda of Mercia is defeated by Oswiu of Northumbria. Year 2005 ( MMV) was a Common year starting on Saturday (link displays full calendar of the Gregorian calendar. Retrieved on 2006 - 11-23 . Year 2006 ( MMVI) was a Common year starting on Sunday of the Gregorian calendar. Events 800 - Charlemagne arrives at Rome to investigate the alleged crimes of (English)   ^ Pearson, Craig. &quot; Ont. buying land for Highway 401 route &quot;, Windsor Star , 14 February 2008 , p. The Windsor Star is the regional newspaper of Windsor Ontario (the only daily newspaper in Windsor and Essex County) and is owned by CanWest Global Events 842 - Charles the Bald and Louis the German swear the Oaths of Strasbourg in the French and German 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common  A1 . Retrieved on 2008 - 02-14 . 2008 ( MMVIII) is the current year in accordance with the Gregorian calendar, a Leap year that started on Tuesday of the Common Events 842 - Charles the Bald and Louis the German swear the Oaths of Strasbourg in the French and German (English)   ^ Border transportation partnership reaches milestone - March 3, 2008 ^ The Detroit River International Crossing Study Team Announces Preferred Access Road ^ Ministry of Transportation Road Construction Information ^ CKLW-AM 800 ^ Government of Ontario, Canada - News ^ Ontario’s High Occupancy Vehicle Lane Network: Summary of the Plan for the 400-Series Highways in the Greater Golden Horseshoe . Ministry of Transportation ( 2007 - 05-24 ). The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 1218 - The Fifth Crusade leaves Acre for Egypt. 1276 - Magnus Ladulås is crowned Retrieved on 2007 - 05-24 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 1218 - The Fifth Crusade leaves Acre for Egypt. 1276 - Magnus Ladulås is crowned  “Figure 2 proposes a vision for “growing the corridors” by building on existing HOV lanes. This involves extending the HOV lanes on Highways 400 and 404 farther north and adding lanes to other key sections such as Highway 401 in Peel Region. ” ^ Stevenson interchange open . Metroland Media Group ( 2007 - 09-14 ). Metroland Media Group (formerly Metroland Printing Publishing&amp;Distributing) is the publisher of daily and weekly community newspapers in Ontario as well as Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 81 - Domitian becomes Emperor of the Roman Empire upon the death of his brother Titus. Retrieved on 2007 - 10-04 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 610 - Heraclius arrives by ship from Africa at Constantinople, overthrows Byzantine Emperor Phocas ^ Ministry of Transportation Contract No. 2005-2014 475930000 . Ministry of Transportation ( 2002 - 06-06 ). The Ministry of Transportation of Ontario (MTO is an Ontario government ministry responsible for Transport Infrastructure and Law See also 2002 (disambiguation Year 2002 ( MMII) was a Common year starting on Tuesday of the Gregorian calendar. Events 1508 - Maximilian I Holy Roman Emperor, is defeated in Friulia by Venetian forces; he is forced to sign a three-year Retrieved on 2007 - 09-19 . Year 2007 ( MMVII) was a Common year starting on Monday of the Gregorian calendar in the 21st century. Events 335 - Dalmatius is raised to the rank of Caesar by his uncle Constantine I. ^ Highway 401 directions from Windsor to Quebec border . Google Maps . Google Maps (for a time named Google Local) is a free Web mapping service application and technology provided by Google that powers many map-based services Retrieved on 2006 - 11-23 . Year 2006 ( MMVI) was a Common year starting on Sunday of the Gregorian calendar. Events 800 - Charlemagne arrives at Rome to investigate the alleged crimes of 
 
 

 External links 

 Ontario Ministry of Transportation Live COMPASS 401 Traffic Cameras through the Greater Toronto Area Photographs of the Macdonald-Cartier Freeway (Highway 401) Highway 401 at OntHighways.com Highway 401 History at thekingshighway.ca Highway 401 - the Story Truck Stops Within Ontario TravelCenters of America (operators of the Woodstock/Ingersoll Service Centers Highway 401 History 
 ©2009 citizendia.org; parts available under the terms of GNU Free Documentation License, from http://en.wikipedia.org
 Dapyx Software network: MP3 Explorer | Ebook Manager | Zenithic
	</body>
</document>
