<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005990" url="http://www.cincinnati.com/health/stories/092200_vegetarian.html" time="2012-07-12-22:40" support="8" score="0.019074624133480392" bingtitle="Being vegetarian in Porkopolis - Health: Cincinnati.Com" webtitle="Being vegetarian in Porkopolis - Health: Cincinnati.Com">
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>For $10 a year in dues, you will receive the group ... I slowly give my order and wait for the usual confusion my presence brings to any fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		HOME 

   
 
 CINCINNATI.COM  
 The Enquirer  
 The Post  
 CiN Weekly  
 
 


 
 HEALTH&amp;WELLNESS  
 Health News  
 AP - Health News  
 Conditions/Treatments  
 
 
 
 
   

 Meatless in Cincinnati 
 Porkopolis becoming more vegetarian-friendly 

 The Cincinnati Vegetarian Resource Group helped sponsor a pig in the Big Pig Gig . &quot;Mr. Meatless&quot; is covered with vegetables and the words &quot;Eat veggies, not me.&quot; V E G G I E R E S O U R C E S 
 Restaurants 
 Area restaurants featuring vegetarian selections.
 Vegetarian Resource Group 
For $10 a year in dues, you will receive the group&apos;s monthly newsletter, which in addition to articles, recipes and other resources lists vegetarian events like sponsored speakers and vegetarian potlucks. H E A L T H T I P S 
 The Vegetarian Resource Group recommends the following to ensure a healthy vegetarian diet:
Eat your vegetables.
Choose whole grains like whole wheat products, rolled oats, brown rice, whole corn meal products, popcorn, buckwheat, millet and unpearled barley. Whole grains still retain their naturally occuring vitamins, minerals and fiber, and are the best source of complex carbohydrates.
Plant food is a good source of protein. Dark leafy vegetables, cabbage-family vegetables, all fresh beans and peas, and all sprouts contain between 15 and 45 percent of their calories in protein. Vegetarian foods highest in protein include legumes, soy products and some nuts.
Eat soy. Research indicates soy protein may help prevent heart disease and cancer.
The key to a healthy vegetarian diet is to eat a wide variety of foods, including fruits, vegetables, leafy greens, whole grains and cereals, nuts, seeds, peas and beans, etc.
 
 By Alisha Woolery 
Cincinnati.Com Contributor 
I trudge up to the greasy counter at a hamburger joint, my husband in tow, and stare the cashier straight in the eye. I slowly give my order and wait for the usual confusion my presence brings to any fast food restaurant.
Yes, I do want my hamburger without the meat. No, I&apos;m not crazy.
It&apos;s not easy being a vegetarian in a city historically known as Porkopolis, where Chilifest is a local holiday and where a good goetta recipe brings a tear to the eye of any respectable cook.
But take heart my fellow vegetarians, vegans and healthy food seekers. Even in the land of the bratwurst, there are places catering to the vegetarian palate and restaurants ready to serve up a dizzying array of non-meat feasts. There&apos;s also the Cincinnati Vegetarian Resource Group, an organization focused on making it easier to be a vegetarian in the Midwest.
Susan Hesken is the editor of the group&apos;s monthly newsletter, &quot;The Flying Carrot,&quot; which is filled with the latest vegetarian events, veggie friendly restaurants, stores, books, cooking classes, recipes and articles on health and nutrition. Hesken has been a vegetarian since 1983, and while she has seen good vegetarian restaurants come and then go, overall she sees the Cincinnati area becoming more veggie-friendly.
&quot;The main improvement I&apos;ve seen is in the grocery stores with the health food sections and the convenience vegetarian food,&quot; she said.
No longer are meat substitute products like veggie hotdogs or soy burgers relegated to the shelves of the natural food store. A good selection of vegetarian products can be found at the grocery, right alongside the packaged meat.
Of course places like the new Wild Oats natural supermarket in Rookwood Commons in Norwood give new meaning to the idea of a health food store. Unlike the traditional and more intimate shops such as Cincinnati Natural Foods or Twin Pines Natural Foods, Wild Oats is a massive conglomeration of organic produce, health food, vitamins, herbs, a deli, a juice bar and general groceries.
I wandered around in this mega-store for quite a while. Although it&apos;s not all vegetarian, it does have such hard-to-find veggie snacks as blackened tempeh and good tabouli. Judging by the rush of customers on a Thursday afternoon, healthy eating must be going mainstream.
There are two completely vegetarian restaurants in the Cincinnati area: New World Foods Vegetarian Cafe and Ulysses Whole World Foods. New World, on Ludlow Avenue, has weekly vegetarian specials, including casseroles, salads, veggie burgers and tofu sandwiches. Ulysses, on West McMillan Avenue, has homemade vegetarian food like soup and sandwiches.
Your best bet in finding good vegetarian fare is going international. Indian food has a lot of vegetarian and vegan dishes, and most Chinese and Thai restaurants have veggie options (although you might have to check to be sure the broth is vegetable based). For more information on nutrition, health and vegetarian cooking, see the following Web sites:
 vegsource.com Vegetarian Times Magazine International Vegetarian Union North American Vegetarian Society World Guide to Vegetarianism Vegetarian Society Local Vegetarian Website - This site lists good local vegetarian restaurants and menus, as well as health food stores and local vegetarian happenings.



 
 
 

 

 
 
 Support Groups Choose a category for a list of groups: 
 
 Choose One Abuse Addictions AIDS Cancer Kids&amp;Family Gay/Lesbian Grief&amp;Loss Illness/Injury Mental Disability Mental Health Phys. Disability Weight Issues Women Add a support group 
 
 
 Seasonal Health 
 
 
 Allergy relief 
Treat your allergy symptoms.
 
 Pollen&apos;s path 
How pollen gets from plant to body.
 
 Water&amp;the body 
How much do you need to drink?
 
 Cooking out 
Tips for safe, nutritious grilling.
 
 Summer skin care 
How and why to protect skin from the sun.
 
 
 
 
 E-mail this story to a friend 
 
 Return to Health front page 

 

 

 
 
Classified Partners: Jobs: CareerBuilder.com Cars: cars.com Apartments: apartments.com 
Your Guide to the City: CincinnatiUSA.com 

 Search | Questions/help | News tips | Letters to the editors | Subscribe 
 To advertise | Place a classified | Circulation 
 
 

 Copyright 1995-2007. The Cincinnati Enquirer , a Gannett Co. Inc. newspaper.
Use of this site signifies your agreement to the Terms of Service (updated
December 19, 2002).
	</body>
</document>
