<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005836" url="http://www.denverpost.com/nationworld/ci_18919817?source=rss_viewed" time="2012-07-12-22:29" support="1" score="0.0006378276952156725" bingtitle="Fast-food restaurant playgrounds under the microscope - The Denver ..." webtitle="Fast-food restaurant playgrounds under the microscope - The Denver Post">
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>Fast-food restaurant playgrounds under the microscope ... Car thief kindly drops off toddler ... European finance chiefs end two-day meeting with ...</description>
	<body>
		Commenting: Sign In   |   Register 
 Home | Media Kit | Sign up for breaking news email alerts | Photo Galleries 
 
 

 
 weekly ad specials from the denver post Site Yahoo 
 

 

 
 
 Home &gt; Nation / World 
 
 
 
 Print    Email    Font Resize nation and world 
Fast-food restaurant playgrounds under the microscope
 By Marc Lacey 
 The New York Times denverpost.com Posted: 09/18/2011 01:00:00 AM MDT September 18, 2011 4:54 PM GMT Updated: 09/18/2011 10:54:47 AM MDT 
 Erin Carr-Jordan takes a sample in Gilbert, Ariz., from a slide at one of the dozens of restaurant playgrounds in 11 states that she&apos;s been checking for cleanliness. Her testing reveals a widespread array of pathogens.(Joshua Lott, The New York Times 
 ) 
GILBERT, Ariz.—One of those who slithered her way through the multihued plastic tubes of a fast-food restaurant playground here one recent morning was not enjoying herself in the least.

&quot;It&apos;s bad,&quot; Erin M. Carr-Jordan said, swab in hand, as she collected samples from a surface that she would later deliver to a lab for microbial testing.

Carr-Jordan, a child development professor and mother of four from Chandler, has visited dozens of restaurant playgrounds in 11 states in recent months to test them for cleanliness.

What the inspections and lab analyses have revealed is the widespread presence of an array of pathogens, from coliform bacteria to staphylococcus, at levels that experts said indicated that restaurants might not be disinfecting their playlands as diligently as they should.

&quot;I&apos;m not shocked or blown out of the water because this is my business,&quot; said Philip M. Tierno Jr., director of clinical microbiology and immunology at NYU Langone Medical Center in New York, who surveyed some of Carr-Jordan&apos;s results.

At the same time, Tierno said, &quot;There are very high counts, and that means these places are not cleaned properly or not cleaned at all.&quot;

Carr-Jordan&apos;s campaign, which has attracted the attention of the fast-food industry, began in April when she stopped at a McDonald&apos;s near her Phoenix-area home. Her children asked whether they could play in the children&apos;s park, which McDonald&apos;s calls a PlayPlace. She assented and accompanied her children to the area.

What she saw was alarming.

&quot;My kids were going, &apos;Yuck!&apos; &quot; she recalled of the scene, which she videotaped with her cellphone and posted on You Tube. &quot;It was gross and sticky. There were curse words and gang graffiti. The windows were black. There was matted hair and an abandoned Band-Aid.&quot;

Despite complaints to the manager and several follow-up visits, the play area was not cleaned, she said. So Carr-Jordan, who has a Ph.D. in developmental psychology, had samples tested. When the results were analyzed, they indicated the presence of potentially harmful bacteria, and she began inspecting and testing the playgrounds at other fast-food restaurants.

The restaurants say they have policies in place that require the regular cleaning of their play areas. Danya Proud, a McDonald&apos;s spokeswoman, said the company had stringent sanitizing procedures but had nonetheless assigned a team to review those procedures in light of Carr-Jordan&apos;s complaints.




 Copyright 2012 The Denver Post. All rights reserved. Print    Email    Font Resize Return to Top    
 
 
 

 
 
 

 
 
 Like this article? Recommend it ()  all reader-recommended news 

 Login | Sign Up | Email Support 
Article Comments

 Is your comment not appearing on the article? Read this .

 
 Note: Our article pages automatically refresh every ten minutes. We cannot change this. If you start writing your comment on this page, please refresh the page before you do so—this will reset the ten-minute counter .

 You must be registered to comment (your comment will be saved for you while you register). It&apos;s quick (it takes about 30 seconds) and we only require your email and name. Comments that include any offensive material are prohibited. By using our site you agree to our terms of use .
 
 
You have javascript turned off. To comment on this article from the article page, javascript must be turned on. Alternately, you can search for this topic thread in our forums .
 
 Comment: 

 Use the &quot;Report Abuse&quot; link when necessary (you don&apos;t have to be a member, or be logged in) Keep it clean and respect others—don&apos;t use language you wouldn&apos;t use with your parents Read the Post&apos;s Article Commenting Ground Rules here (link will open in a new window) 

 
 
 More Nation / World Headlines MORE MORE NATION / WORLD HEADLINES HEADLINES Republicans push through mining deregulation bill Syria defections raise hopes among Assad opponents AP Interview: Moderate Taliban want peace, U.S. says Poll: Russians see drug abuse as a top problem U.S. piles more sanctions on Iran Nike taking Paterno&apos;s name off child care center APNewsBreak: New border drug tunnel discovered Debate over year-round versus traditional schools 9 dead, 2 missing in Mont Blanc summer avalanche Rain causes flooding, mudslides in Japan; 15 dead Obama talks up middle class in video to NAACP At least 95 killed in Nigeria tanker truck fire Bridal gown designer Wang and husband separate 485,000 high chairs recalled after injury reports Pittsburgh paper wants to photograph voter IDing Buffett says general economy slowing this summer Potent form of common child illness deadly in Asia Suit blames Ala. coach Saban&apos;s daughter for fight Clinton to meet with Myanmar&apos;s president Some corn farmers mow fields as drought worsens Jerry Sandusky report: Penn State could have stopped abuse in &apos;98 Small earthquakes felt in California Yahoo confirms theft of 450,000 users&apos; passwords Boeing claws back ground lost to Airbus The cast of characters in the Penn State scandal   
 
 
 
 Blogs Front Page Aurora | Boulder | Denver | Feeds | More 

 Denver&amp;the West 
 
 Some fire restrictions lifted as more hot, dry weather is forecast Denver ICE agents shut down 22 counterfeit shopping websites Denver pedestrian cited in collision on North Federal   
 
 Rockies | Avs | Nuggets | Preps | RSS | More 

 Sports 
 
 Broncos&apos; situation at linebacker looks murky Boulder&apos;s Laura Bennett attempts to medal in triathlon at London Games Mark Kiszla: NBA&apos;s joke of parity is on the Nuggets   
 
 Balance Sheet Blog | Techknow Bytes 

 Business 

 
 
 Stocks slide on Wall Street for sixth straight day Denver Metro Chamber selects chair-elect Wells Fargo to pay $175M in lending settlement   
 
 
 
 Movies | Music | TV | RSS | Video 

 Entertainment 
 
 Video: Christian Louboutin partners with Disney to create Cinderella shoe CU-Boulder grad commits $2 million to theater department for endowed chair KMGH nominated for national investigative reporting Emmy   
 
 Columnists | Letters | Cartoon | RSS 

 Opinion 
 
 Editorial: Penn State failed kids in favor of football Editorial: Hot shots earn health insurance Editorial: Richard B. Scudder, 99   
 
 Arcade | Crossword | Sudoku 

 Watercooler 
 
 Cop accused of stealing driver&apos;s iPhone from wreck Court: Ore. police can seize $1M lottery prize German town designates tricky parking &apos;men only&apos;   
 
 
 
 
 POPULAR TALKERS RECOMMENDED YEAR AGO 
 



 
FRESH DAILY. Subscribe to our
Afternoon Newsletter
 
Email Address
 
» See a sample afternoon newsletter here 
 
 TOP STORIES Aurora transplant patient helps revamp hospital that saved him   
 
 Jerry Sandusky report: Penn State could have stopped abuse in &apos;98 Denver ICE agents shut down 22 counterfeit shopping websites Loose cart injures five during landing of Frontier flight in Phoenix Downed bicyclist hit, killed by Lakewood driver Unemployment hitting black middle class Broncos&apos; situation at linebacker looks murky Strength coach Luke Richesson wants Broncos to finish strong   
 
 Post Poll - Plastic Bag Fee 

Should Denver impose a fee on shoppers who request plastic bags in grocery stores? 
  Absolutely: Those shoppers who use non-biodegradable plastic bags should pay the price for landfill maintenance.  Sure: I&apos;ve used cloth bags for years and am doing my part; why can&apos;t everyone else?  No: It&apos;s just another way for government to try to pick our pockets.  Don&apos;t care: I worry more about air pollution. 
 Voting Requires Javascript 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 
All contents Copyright 2012 The Denver Post or other copyright holders. All rights reserved.
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed for any commercial purpose.

 Advertise / Media Kit | Archives | Careers | Contact Us | Ethics Policy | E-mail Alerts | Mobile | Privacy Policy | Web Feeds | RSS | My Yahoo | Repurposing Denver Post content - Guidelines | Site Map | Home Delivery | Terms of Use 

Our other sites: Viva Colorado | Boulder Daily Camera | Boulder&apos;s Colorado Daily | Broomfield Enterprise | Sterling Colorado Journal-Advocate 
 Estes Park Trail-Gazette | The Lamar Ledger | The Fort Morgan Times | Brush (Colorado) News-Tribune 
 Tweet 

 Privacy Policy   |   Terms of Use   |   MNG Corporate Site Map   |   Copyright
	</body>
</document>
