<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005624" url="http://www.fortkent.org/fkzoneord.php" time="2012-07-12-22:11" support="4" score="0.0015171508943232685" bingtitle="Town of Fort Kent, Maine - Ordinances" webtitle="Town of Fort Kent, Maine - Ordinances">
			<query id="001388" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001199" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>ZONING. ORDINANCE FOR THE. MUNICIPALITY OF. FORT KENT . ENACTED: 3/27/95. Amended: 1/24/11. TABLE OF CONTENTS: Section 1 Legal Status Provisions. 1.1 Purposes. 1.2 ...</description>
	<body>
		The Zoning Ordinance of the Town of Fort Kent 
   

   

   

   

 ZONING 

 ORDINANCE 

 FOR
THE 

 MUNICIPALITY
OF 

 FORT KENT 

   

   

   

   

   

   

 ENACTED: 3/27/95 

 Amended: 1/24/11 
 
 
 TABLE OF CONTENTS: 

 Section
1 Legal Status Provisions. 4 

 1.1
Purposes. 4 

 1.2
Authority. 5 

 1.3
Title. 5 

 1.4
Applicability. 5 

 1.5
Repeal of Prior Ordinances. 5 

 1.6
Effective Date. 5 

 1.7
Conflict with Other Laws. 5 

 1.8
Separability. 5 

 1.9
Availability. 5 

 Section
2 Official Zoning Map. 6 

 2.1
Official Zoning Map. 6 

 2.2
Certification of the Official Zoning Map. 6 

 2.3
Changes on the Official Zoning Map. 6 

 2.4
Replacement of the Official Zoning Map. 6 

 Section
3 Establishment of Districts. 7 

 3.1
Zoning Districts. 7 

 3.2
Rules Governing District Boundaries. 16 

 3.3
Lots Divided by District Boundaries. 16 

 Section
4 District Regulations. 17 

 4.1
Basic Requirement. 17 

 4.2
Land Use Requirements. 17 

 4.3
District Regulations. 17 

 Section
5 Dimensional Requirements. 21 

 Section
6 Non-Conformance. 23 

 6.1
General. 23 

 6.2
Non-Conforming Use. 24 

 6.3
Non-Conforming Structures. 24 

 6.4
Non/Conforming Lots of Record. 25 

 6.5 Vested Rights. 26 

 Section
7 Supplementary Regulations. 26 

 7.1
Bed&amp;Breakfast. 26 

 7.2
Buffers and Screening. 27 

 7.3
Elder Cottage Housing Opportunity (ECHO) Units. 27 

 7.4 Electro-Magnetic
Interference. 28 

 7.5
Exterior Lighting. 28 

 7.6
Glare. 29 

 7.7
Home Occupations. 29 

 7.8
Kennels and Veterinary Hospitals . 30 

 7.9
Landscaping. 31 

 7.10
Manufactured Housing/Mobile Homes. 31 

 7.12
Rear Lots . 35 

 7.13
Satellite Receiving Dish. 36 

 7.14
Signs. 36 

 7.15 Soils. 40 

 7.16 Swimming Pools. 40 

 7.17 Temporary Dwellings. 41 

 Section
8 Site Design Review. 41 

 8.1 Purposes for Site Design Review. 41 

 8.2 Applicability of Site Design Review . 42 

 8.3 Site Design Approval. 42 

 8.4 Site Design Notification. 43 

 8.5 Site Design Fees and Guarantees. 44 

 8.6 Site Design Review Application and
Process. 44 

 8.7 Site Design Review Application
Requirements. 47 

 8.8 Site Design Review Criteria and
Standards. 50 

 8.9 Conditional Approvals for Site Design. 56 

 8.10 Revisions to Approved Site Designs. 56 

 8.11 Post Approval Submissions. 57 

 Section
9 Road Design, Construction, and Acceptance Standards. 57 

 9.9 Off-Street Parking and
Loading................................................................................................57 

 Section
10 Administration and Enforcement. 63 

 10.1 General. 63 

 10.2 Land Use Permit. 63 

 10.3 Certificate of Occupancy. 64 

 10.4 Code Enforcement Officer Shall
Act. 65 

 10.5 Inspection. 65 

 10.6 Code Enforcement Officer. 66 

 10.7 Violations. 66 

 10.8 Fines . 67 

 Section
11 Planning Board. 67 

 11.1 Appointment. 67 

 11.2 Organization and Rules. 67 

 11.3 Duties and Powers. 68 

 11.4 Meeting Organization. 69 

 11.5 Hearings. 71 

 11.6 Decisions. 72 

 11.7 Appeals. 73 

 Section
12 Board of Appeals. 73 

 12.1 Establishment and Administration. 73 

 12.2 Associate Members. 73 

 12.3 Board of Appeals Organization. 74 

 12.4 Appeal Procedure. 74 

 12.5 Decisions of the Board of Appeals. 75 

 12.6 Special Exception. 76 

 12.7 Variances. 76 

 12.8 Notification of Variances and Special
Permits to Town Council and Planning Board. 78 

 Section
13 Amendments. 78 

 13.1 Initiation. 78 

 13.2 Procedure. 78 

 13.3 Adoption. 79 

 Section
14 Definitions. 79 

 14.1 Construction of Language. 79 

 14.2 Definitions. 79 

 The Zoning Ordinance of the Town of Fort Kent 

 Note: The Fort Kent Urban Zoning Map and the Fort Kent Comprehensive Plan - Rural Area Zoning Map
are available at the Fort Kent Town Office. 

 Section 1 Legal
Status Provisions. 

 1.1 Purposes. 

 The purpose of this Ordinance is to: 

 a. Protect the
health, safety, and general welfare of the residents of the Town of Fort Kent; 

 b. Encourage
appropriate use of land throughout the Town; 

 c. Promote traffic
safety; 

 d. Provide safety
from fire and other elements; 

 e. Provide adequate
light and air; 

 f. Prevent
overcrowding of real estate; 

 g. Prevent housing
development in unsuitable areas; 

 h. Provide an
allotment of land area in new developments sufficient for all the requirements of
community life; 

 i . Conserve natural resources and town character; 

 j. Provide for
adequate public services as an integral part of a comprehensive plan for town
development; 

 k. Protect
archaeological and historic resources, freshwater wetlands, fish spawning
grounds, aquatic life, bird and other wildlife habitat, and buildings and lands
from flooding and accelerated erosion; 

 l. Conserve shore
cover, natural beauty and open space, and visual as well as actual points of
access to inland waters; 

 m. Prevent and
control water pollution; and 

 n. Assure new
development meets the goals and conforms to the policies of the Fort Kent
Comprehensive Plan. 

 1.2 Authority. 

 This Ordinance has been adopted in accordance
with the provisions of Article VIII-A of the Maine Constitution; the provisions
of MRSA Title 30-A, Section 3001 (Home Rule); and the State&apos;s Growth Management
Law MRSA Title 30-A, Section 4311 et seq ; as may be
amended. 

 1.3 Title. 

 This Ordinance shall be known and may be
cited to as the&quot;Zoning Ordinance of the Town of Fort Kent.&quot; 

 1.4 Applicability. 

 The provisions of this Ordinance shall govern
all land and all structures within the boundaries of the Town of Fort Kent. 

 1.5 Repeal of Prior
Ordinances. 

 All prior Zoning Ordinances, Site Design
Review Criteria, Road Standards and Acceptance Regulations, and Planning Board
By-Laws for the Town, except for the Shoreland Zoning
Ordinance of Fort Kent, are repealed as of the effective date of this
Ordinance. 

 1.6 Effective Date. 

 This Ordinance shall take effect and be in
force from the date of its adoption. 

 1.7 Conflict with
Other Laws. 

 Whenever the requirements of this Ordinance
are at variance with the requirements of any other lawfully adopted rules,
regulations, ordinances, or resolutions, the most restrictive, or that imposing
the higher standards shall govern. 

 1.8 Separability . 

 Should any section or provision of this
Ordinance be declared by the courts to be unconstitutional or invalid, such
decision shall not affect the validity of the ordinance as a whole or any part
thereof other than the part so declared to be unconstitutional or invalid. 

 1.9 Availability. 

 A certified copy of this Ordinance shall be
filed with the Town Clerk and shall be accessible to any member of the public.
Copies shall be made available to the public at reasonable cost at the expense
of the person making the request. Notice of availability of this Ordinance
shall be posted. 

 Section 2 Official
Zoning Map. 

 2.1 Official Zoning
Map. 

 Districts are located and bounded as shown on
the Official Zoning Map which is a made a part of this Ordinance. There may for
purpose of clarity, necessitate by reasons of scale on the map, be more than
one Official Zoning Map. The minimum scale for the Official Zoning Map shall be
no less than 1 inch = 2000 feet. 

 2.2 Certification of
the Official Zoning Map. 

 A. The Official
Zoning Map shall be identified by the signature of the Chair of the Town
Council, attested by the Town Clerk, and bearing the seal of the Town under the
following words: 

 &quot;This is to
certify that this is the Official Zoning Map referred to in Article I of the
Zoning Ordinance of the Town of Fort Kent, Maine&quot;Date:
__________________________________ 

 B.
The Official Zoning Map shall be located in the office of the Town Clerk. 

 2.3 Changes on the
Official Zoning Map. 

 A. If, in accordance
with the provisions of this Ordinance and Title 30A MRSA 4503, changes are made
in District boundaries or other matter portrayed on the Official Zoning Map,
changes to the map shall be made within 14 days after the amendment has been
approved by the Town Council. No
amendment to this Ordinance which involves matter portrayed on the Official
Zoning Map shall become effective until signed by the Chair of the Town Council
and attested by the Town Clerk. In addition, the following wording shall be
reflected on the Official Zoning Map: 

 &quot;On _____ by
official action of the Town, the following change(s) was (were) made: (insert
brief description of the nature of change).&quot;Immediately beneath the entry
the Town Clerk shall place their signature. 

 B. No changes of any
nature shall be made in the Official Zoning Map or matter shown thereon except
in conformity with the procedures set forth in this Ordinance. Any unauthorized
change shall be considered a violation of this Ordinance and punishable as
provided under section 22?134. 

 2.4 Replacement of
the Official Zoning Map. 

 In the event that the Official Zoning Map
becomes damaged, destroyed, lost, or difficult to interpret because of the
nature or number of changes and additions the Town Council shall adopt a new
Official Zoning Map. Fort Kent Zoning Maps.(Available at the Town Office) 

 Section 3
Establishment of Districts. 

 3.1 Zoning
Districts. 

 A. For the purposes
of this Ordinance, Fort Kent is hereby divided
into the following Zoning Districts: 

 1. R -
Residential District. The Residential
District is established as a zoning District in which the principal use of the
land will be for detached family dwellings at low density with educational,
recreational and religious, fraternal and nonprofit organization of club
facilities. The development of attractive neighborhood living will be
encouraged. Areas where similar residential future growth appear possible are
included in the Residential District. 

 2. RF - Rural
Farm District. The Rural Farm
District is established as a zoning District whereby the principal use of the
land is for agriculture, forestry, rural type residence, and customary
associated uses. Included in this District are certain uses unsuited to the
more densely developed urbanized portions of Town. Other purposes of this
District include conservation of natural resources, reduction of soil erosion,
and encouragement of appropriate recreational land use with limited commercial
uses. Certain commercial and industrial uses may be allowed in the RF
District upon proof by the applicant and approval by the Planning Board that
the use is&quot;Natural Resource Based Use&quot;, as defined herein ( Amd . 3/23/98). 

 3. C -
Commercial District. The Commercial
District is established as a general business and commercial District to which
the public requires frequent and convenient access. It is intended to promote
concentration of commercial development for the mutual advantage of the public
and the merchant. 

 a. On West Main
Street between the western boundary line of Tax Map 15, Lots 87, 86, and 1 and
Tax Map 18 the western boundary line of Lot 21 and the eastern property line of
Lot 34, (Town Office up to railroad tracks on East Main Street) residential
uses are permitted only in levels above the ground floor, provided that all
federal, state, and local laws, regulations, and ordinances are met. 

 b.
Plans for proposed construction shall be reviewed by the Town Council and
Planning Board, and when appropriate by the municipal department heads. 

 4. I -
Industrial District. The Industrial
District is established as a zoning District in which the principal use of the
land is for industrial purposes and for commercial and business uses commonly
supplemental to or associated with industrial uses. The following use shall be
permitted in the Industrial District when authorized by the Board of Appeals: 

 a. Storage of
hazardous fuels (as defined in Title 38, MRSA, Section 1303, as may be
amended), including, but not limited to, gasoline, fuel oil, diesel oil, etc.,
can be stored above or below the ground for future delivery to consumers. 

 b. For the purposes
of this Ordinance, Fort Kent hereby has two
special protection overlay Districts; for the sand and gravel aquifers and for
the Fort Kent Utility District&apos;s wellhead. The overlay Districts are intended
to maintain safe and healthful environmental conditions; prevent and control
water pollution; protect spawning grounds, fish, aquatic life, bird and other
wildlife habitats; control building sites; provide visual and physical points
of access to waters and areas of natural beauty; and to protect and maintain
the quality of surface and ground waters. The overlay Districts shall be
superimposed over underlying Districts and land uses are subject to both the standards in the underlying and the overlay Districts. 

 1 . Sand and Gravel Aquifer Overlay District. 

 a. This District
includes sand and gravel aquifers as identified on the Maine Geological Survey&quot; Hydrogeologic Data for Significant Sand and
Gravel Aquifers&quot;map nos. 84 and 85, as well as, a 250&apos; buffer drawn
around the known boundaries of these aquifers (buffers shall be updated as the
aquifer mapping is updated). 

 b. All future agricultural
land uses, on the aquifer and within a 500&apos; buffer, for chicken farms, cattle
farms, horse farms, egg farms, piggeries, sheep farms, and stables shall be
subject to the approval of the Planning Board. Such approval shall be granted
upon showing that such uses shall not cause groundwater contamination or
contaminate or disturb the normal course of surface water run-off. 

 c. All construction
or activity involving the displacement of soil within the 250&apos; buffer shall
follow soil erosion control measures as outlined in the SCS Best Management
Practices. 

 d. Existing unvegetated openings should be documented by the CEO and
reviewed by the Planning Board for possible revegetation. 

 e. No vehicle
carrying pesticides, fertilizers, or other potentially toxic or hazardous
chemicals shall pump water from the aquifer. Penalties of heavy fines and
suspension of licenses shall be imposed for handling potentially toxic or
hazardous chemicals within the aquifer or for the contamination of any waters
within the aquifer. 

 2. Wellhead Protection Overlay District. 

 a. The Wellhead
Protection District is created to protect the public water supply for the Town
of Fort Kent by preventing contaminants from reaching the well and realizing
that drinking water is essential to the survival of the Town. The Wellhead
Protection District includes the land area within 2500 feet of the Fort Kent
Water Depts wellhead as delineated on the zoning map for the Town of Fort
Kent. All land use activity regulated by this Ordinance within the Wellhead
Protection District shall require a brief application be obtained, completed,
and returned by the applicant at the Fort Kent Water Dept. ( 416 W. Main Street , Fort Kent , ME , 04743-1040 )
prior to the issuance of any permit. 

 b. Wellhead
Protection Overlay District. There shall be no new or expansion of underground
storage fuels allowed in the Wellhead Protection Overlay District. In addition
no new or existing aboveground storage of fuel (except for household heating
fuel), chemical tank or toxic or hazardous materials shall be permitted or
expanded within the Wellhead Protection District, except for water treatment
chemicals or materials of the Fort Kent Water Dept. ( Amd .
3/23/98) 

 c. All construction
activity involving the displacement of soil within the Wellhead Protection
District shall follow soil erosion control measures as outlined in the SCS Best
Management Practices. 

 d. No vehicle
carrying pesticides, fertilizers, or other potentially toxic or hazardous
chemicals shall pump water from the Wellhead Protection District. Penalties of
heavy fines and suspension of licenses shall be imposed for handling
potentially toxic or hazardous chemicals within the District or for the
contamination of any waters within the District. 

 e. Wellhead
Protection Overlay District. Performance Standards for a Wellhead Protection
District (WPD) 

 Performance Standards for a Wellhead
Protection District (WPD) ( Amd . 3/23/98) 

 The following are additional performance
standards to be considered by the Town for the Wellhead Protection District in
order to better protect the Fort Kent drinking water
supply from incompatible development and uses. (Reviewed and approved by the
FKUD.) 

 1. The Town and the
Water Dept shall have the right to install groundwater monitoring wells and shall
further maintain the right to sample such wells on properties within the WPD
when the Town or the Water Dept can clearly show that groundwater monitoring in
the area will serve to protect the public water supply from existing or
potential threats. 

 2. When and where
applicable within the WPD, the CEO shall have the right, upon 24-hour notice,
to enter, inspect, and to determine whether all premises which have groundwater
pollution control devices or management practices are in good condition and
working properly. Such testing shall be at the Town&apos;s and Water Dept. expense.
If such testing indicates that the groundwater has been contaminated above the
State Primary and Secondary Drinking Water Standards, then further testing
shall be at the expense of the landowner in question. Additionally, the owner
shall reimburse the Town and/or the Water Dept for expenses incurred in the
initial well installation and testing. 

 3. All development
to be located in the WPD shall comply with Best Management Practices ( BMPs ) for water quality as defined by the State of Maine . The Planning
Board may adopt, be reference, additional BMPs which
have been published by or in conjunction with the MDEP. In so doing the
Planning Board shall hold a public hearing. 

 4. The collection and
disposal of petroleum products, chemicals, and wastes used in construction
shall conform to the following: 

 a.
Petroleum products, chemicals, and wastes shall be collected and stored in
closed, clearly marked, watertight containers. 

 b. Containers shall
be removed regularly for disposal to prevent spills and leaks which can occur
due to corrosion of containers. A schedule for removal shall be included with
the application and in any construction specifications for the project. 

 c.
Fertilizers and landscape chemicals such as herbicides and pesticides shall be
applied following appropriate BMPs developed by the
MDOA in conjunction with the MDEP. 

 5. Storm water Runoff/Snow and Ice Control ( Amd . 3/23/98) 

 a. Drainage systems,
including detention basins, drainage ways, and storm sewer systems, shall be
maintained in order to insure they function properly. 

 b. Chemicals and
wastes shall be stored in such a manner as to prevent rainfall from contacting
them. 

 c. Runoff from
parking lots should be diverted to storm water drains. 

 d. Snowmelt from
parking lots should be diverted to storm water drains. 

 e. Parking lots
should be maintained on a yearly basis. 

 f. Sand/salt
mixtures with a reduced portion of salt should be used for snow and ice
control. 

 6 . Industrial and Maintenance Operations ( Amd 3/23/98) 

 a. A plan detailing
the reuse, recycling, or proper disposal of waste chemicals shall be kept,
maintained, and updated as needed. Provisions shall be provided for
implementing the plan. 

 b. Buildings, rooms,
and areas where chemical potential pollutants are used, handled, or stored
shall be designed to contain spills and or leaks. 

 1.
Floor drains shall not be used except as required by fire regulations; and 

 2.
A waterproof dike shall be placed around areas to contain accidental spills.
The dike shall have an equivalent volume to the amount of material stored or
used in the room. 

 c. Spill/leakage
prevention and detection programs shall be maintained and updated. 

 1.
Plans shall insure the regular collection and transport of chemicals; and 

 2.
Plans shall provide for inspection of containers and storage areas on a regular
basis. 

 d. A spill clean-up
plan shall be maintained and updated annually. The plan shall: 

 1.
Insure adequate materials and equipment are available; 

 2.
Insure that personnel are trained; and 

 3.
Insure that the local fire department is knowledgeable of clean-up procedures. 

 e. Wash waters and
other diluted wastes shall be adequately treated consistent with State law and
the current pre-treatment ordinances. 

 1.
Wastes shall be discharged to sewer systems where possible; and 

 2.
Grease traps and oil separators shall be installed where necessary and shall be
maintained on a regular basis. 

 7 . Septic/Sewage Disposal. ( Amd .
3/23/98) 

 a. Sewer/septic
systems shall be designed by competent professionals using sound engineering
practices. Onsite sewage disposal shall be according to the State of Maine Subsurface Wastewater Disposal Rules . 

 b. Construction of
sewers and septic systems shall be carefully inspected to insure proper
installation. 

 c. Septic systems
and related piping shall be tested for leakage and certified by the LPI that
they are water tight prior to use. Sewer systems shall be tested for leakage,
according to State standards or municipal ordinance/district regulations. 

 d. Provisions shall
be made to maintain sewer and septic systems. 

 e. Sewers and
drainage systems shall be designed to insure that storm water does not enter
sanitary sewers. 

 f. For cluster
systems, 1000-gallon septic tank capacity shall be provided for each 300
gallons of flow. Design flows for leach fields shall be less than 2500 gallons
per day. 

 g. Chemicals,
industrial wastes, floor drains and storm water drains (I.e. roof drains) shall
not be discharged to septic systems. 

 8. Waste Disposal Handling ( Amd 3/23/98) 

 a. Inert Fill 

 1.
Waste disposal areas shall be setback 75 feet from wetlands as defined in the
Maine Natural Resources Protection Act (NRPA); 

 2. Wastes
shall be placed a minimum of 2 feet above the seasonal high ground water table;
and 

 3.
For wastes other than concrete, stone, and brick, documentation from a
laboratory that wastes are inert shall be provided. 

 b. Transfer
Station/Recycling Facilities. 

 1. All storage
areas shall be located a minimum of 5 feet above the seasonal high ground water
table; 

 2.
Sanitary wastes shall be disposed of into public sewer or in accordance with
the State of Maine Subsurface
 Disposal Rules ; 

 3.
If water clean up of facilities is used, it shall be discharged to a public
sanitary sewer. If no public sanitary sewer is available, dry clean-up
procedures shall be used; 

 4.
Gravel, asphalt, or concrete pads or steel or aluminum containers shall be used
for storage facilities for white goods and tires; 

 5.
Facilities shall not be located in 100-year floodplain; 

 6.
An Operating Manual shall insure that only non-hazardous municipal solid waste
is accepted; 

 7.
For recycling facilities, an Operating Manual shall insure that only clean,
marketable recyclables are collected; are 

 8.
For recycling facilities, storage of residuals shall be accomplished to prevent
spillage and leakage. 

 c. Municipal,
Commercial, Industrial, and Other Special Wastes 

 1.
All handling, storage, and transfer shall comply with Department of
Environmental Protection rules; 

 2.
Storage and transfer areas shall comply with the management practices listed in
7b above. 

 d. Junkyards/Metal
Processing 

 1.
Fluids shall be removed in a secure area and stored for appropriate disposal; 

 2.
Fluids shall be disposed in accordance with state and federal laws; and 

 3.
Records shall be maintained to indicate the quantities of fluids handled. 

 9. Chemical and Petroleum Handling and
Storage. ( Amd 3/23/98) 

 a. Non-hazardous chemicals
shall be substituted for hazardous varieties whenever possible. 

 b. A detailed
inventory shall be maintained. 

 c. Provisions shall
be made to clean up all spills immediately with an absorbent material or other
methods and dispose of them properly. 

 d. Hazardous
materials shall be stored in secure, corrosion, and resistant containers. 

 e. Storage shall be
in aboveground, corrosion resistant tanks. The following provisions shall be
complied with. 

 1.
A diked area shall be provided around tanks to
contain spills. The volume of diked area shall equal
the volume of product stored; 

 2.
A roof shall be provided over commitment areas to prevent collection of rain
water; and 

 3.
Drains shall not be installed in containment areas. 

 f. If underground storage
is necessary, corrosion resistant double walled tanks shall be provided. The
system, including piping, shall be tested prior to use. Underground piping and
transmission lines shall be inspected and tested upon installation and on an
annual basis, thereafter. 

 g. All floors shall
be concrete or an impermeable, hardened material. Sub-floor synthetic
containment liners shall be inspected to contain spills or leaks which occur
inside buildings with earth or gravel floors. 

 h. Non-bulk storage
of chemicals shall be inside. Such storage areas shall comply with the
following: 

 1.
Floor drains shall not be used; 

 2. If floor drains
are required by the fire regulations, they shall be discharged to a holding
tank. Tanks shall be pumped by a licensed oil or hazardous waste hauler, as
appropriate. Tanks shall be equipped with gauges to determine used capacity;
and 

 3.
Storage and handling areas shall have waterproof dikes around perimeter so as
to contain spills. 

 i . Tanks shall be quipped with automatic shutoffs and/or
high level alarms. 

 j. Spill and leak
detection programs shall be maintained and updated annually. 

 k. Oil and water
separators shall not be used to remove dissolved compounds or oil and greases
which had been subjected to detergents. 

 l. Loading areas
shall be covered to prevent the mixing of storm water and spilled chemicals.
Concrete or other impermeable pads shall be provided under transfer and
handling areas. 

 m. Exterior transfer
and handling areas shall be slope as to prevent runoff from other areas from
entering the handling area, but to contain small quantities of spilled product. 

 n. Procedures shall
be established to catch and store chemicals spilled at loading docks and other
transfer areas. 

 o. Provisions shall
be made to periodically inspect and test tanks and lines for leaks. 

 p. The facility and
equipment shall be designed to: 

 1.
Prevent tank overflows; and 

 2.
Prevent line breakage due to collision 

 q. Provisions shall
be made to have: 

 1.
Emergency diking materials available; and 

 2.
Emergency spill cleanup materials available. 

 r. The facility and
equipment shall be designed to: 

 1.
Prevent tank overflows; and 

 2.
Prevent line breakage due to collision 

 s. Exterior transfer
and handling sites shall be graded and sloped to prevent runoff for other areas
from entering the handling areas. 

 t. Residential
storage tanks for home heating fuel shall be located in cellars or on a
concrete slab above the ground if outside. 

 10 . Sand and Gravel Mining. ( Amd 3/23/98)
	</body>
</document>
