<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005663" url="http://www.wyandotonline.com/articles/news/articles/000007/000781.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:15" support="1" score="0.0030161398360752214" bingtitle="Wyandot County, Ohio daily news information guide from Wyandot ..." webtitle="Wyandot County, Ohio daily news information guide from Wyandot Online in Upper Sandusky, Ohio">
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>A story from the AP says, Cowdery was a night manager at the fast food restaurant. ... and the case was presented to a grand jury, which issued an order for DNA evidence ...</description>
	<body>
		Home News 
     Local
News     Weather     Obituaries     Community
Calendar     News
Archive     Lottery 
Numbers     School
Delays     Technology/Space Sports Opinion Entertainment City Guide Business 
 Special Sections 
 Internet/Tech 
 
 

  
 
 
 
 Home : News 
 
 Local
Wyandot News 
Local News Headlines 
 Delaware Man Arrested For 40-Year Old Murder 
 07-29-2005 
 
 Parkersburg police say they cracked a 40-year-old murder case with the arrest of a 58-year-old Ohio man. 

 Toby Michael Johnson of Delaware, Ohio, was charged Thursday with the March 1965 shooting death of Garry Cowdery, 18, at the former Burger Boy Foodarama in Parkersburg. 

 A story from the AP says, Cowdery was a night manager at the fast food restaurant. He was shot during a robbery as he was leaving with the night deposit. Johnson was a former employee and a resident of Vienna at the time. 

 Johnson will be held at the Delaware County Jail until an appearance before a common pleas judge for extradition proceedings, said Parkersburg Police Chief Robert Newell. 

 The case remained opened and police pursued leads through the years. In 2002, the Parkersburg Police Tactical Unit was assigned to re-interview witnesses and re-examine the evidence. Modern techniques revealed improved fingerprint and ballistics evidence that pointed to Cowdery, who was an original suspect in the murder, Newell said. 

 The examination of evidence was completed in January and the case was presented to a grand jury, which issued an order for DNA evidence, Newell said. Since that time, Parkersburg police have been coordinating with Delaware County, Ohio, officials to locate and arrest Johnson. 

 Click here to read more of this story from the AP.
	</body>
</document>
