<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005940" url="http://www.deepfatfryerguide.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:36" support="4" score="0.0067155182560135725" bingtitle="Deep Fat Fryers" webtitle="Deep Fat Fryers">
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000463" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="179"/>
	<description>How many times have you suffered through soggy fries at your local fast food restaurant? ... of busy people that want great tasting food but don&apos;t have time or money to waste.</description>
	<body>
		2012-07-12 
 Home  Top Picks  Ebay Search  
 
 
Deep Fat Fryers

 DeLonghi D677UX Deep Fat Fryer 

The DeLonghi D677UX Deep Fat Fryer is a simple, easy to operate fryer with many safety features built in. If you have young children or elderly parents in the house this fryer could be a good choice. ... more 

 Presto 05462 Digital ProFry Deep Fryer 

The Presto 05462 deep fat fryer has a hefty 1800 watt heating element, large capacity oil chamber and simple to use digital controls. The outside casing is stainless steel and the whole thing disassembles for easy clean-up.... more 

 Waring Pro DF100 Deep Fat Fryer 

If you&apos;re looking for a compact, easy to use and clean deep fryer then the Waring Pro DF100 might be worth considering.... more 

 Presto 05466 ProFry Stainless-Steel Dual-Basket 

The Presto Profry 05466 is a professional-style deep fat fryer that can produce restaurant quality results at home and is both simple to operate and easy to clean.... more 

 DeLonghi D24527DZ Stainless Steel Deep Fat Fryer 

The DeLonghi D24527DZ is a semi-professional stainless steel deep fat fryer that can produce restaurant quality fried foods at home. ... more 

 DeLonghi D895UX Deep Fryer 

The DeLonghi D895UX sets itself apart from the other deep fryers on the market with a unique rotary frying basket. This DeLonghi uses a tilted rotating mechanism that slowly cycles the food into and out of the hot oil.... more 

 DeLonghi D14427DZ Stainless Steel Deep Fat Fryer 

The DeLonghi D14427DZ Dual-Zone Deep Fryer is squarely aimed at the family kitchen, with a generous 3lb frying capacity, simple controls, and a stylish stainless steel exterior.... more 

 Cuisinart CDF-100 Deep Fat Fryer 

The Cuisinart CDF-100 is one of those deep fat fryers that you either love or hate. If you happen to fit the market it was designed for, this little puppy is going to be your best friend.... more 

 T-Fal FR7008002 Ultimate EZ-Clean Pro Fryer 

The biggest problem with deep fat fryers is the clean up. The T-Fal FR7008002 EZ-Clean Pro Fryer lets you drain the oil yourself with its auto drain and filter feature. ... more 

 DeLonghi D14522DZ Stainless Steel Deep Fat Fryer 

Deep fat frying doesn&apos;t get much simpler or convenient than the DeLonghi D14522DZ Stainless Steel Deep Fat Fryer. A simple mechanical twist style temperature control and DeLonghi&apos;s front mounted oil drain valve will appeal to many.... more 

 
 
Introduction

In the past if you wanted to satisfy you craving for deep fried foods you basically had two choices. Find a restaurant that served this specialty or attempt to cook it yourself at home with a saucepan full of hot oil. The first option was frequently expensive and the second decidedly dangerous. In either case the results were usually less than satisfying.

Thankfully these days you can prepare deep fried food at home safely and economically with a deep fat fryer . The modern electric deep fat fryer represents the latest innovation in home cooking and is specifically geared towards the needs of the home consumer.

They are inexpensive to buy, easy to operate and most importantly have a number of safety features built in. The latest models allow virtually anyone to produce mouth watering deep fried chicken, fish, vegetables and of course fries, safely and quickly with push button convenience.


Quality And Health

A home deep fat fryer can also offer a level of control beyond simple convenience. How many times have you suffered through soggy fries at your local fast food restaurant? This familiar problem is caused by incorrect oil temperature and poor cooking technique.

Another common but far more serious problem with eating deep fried foods outside the home is the cooking oil that was used to fry the food. Many restaurants are more concerned with their profits than your health. The fact is prices for deep fat fryer oil vary considerably and some cooking oils are much cheaper than others. This is important because over time cooking oils can have a huge impact on the health of you and your family.

With your own deep fat fryer you can select the healthiest cooking oils available yet still satisfy your family&apos;s deep fried cravings.


Style And Design

In the past deep fat fryers used to be large, ugly and heavy kitchen appliances that were difficult to set up and time consuming to keep clean. Fast forward to today and you will find that many of the shortcomings of those earlier machines have been eliminated.

Utilizing the latest hi-tech materials manufacturers have made today&apos;s deep fat fryer lightweight, compact and dishwasher safe. And with a large selection of models of all sizes, shapes and colors to choose from you are bound to find one that meets both your needs and budget.

Do you have stainless steel kitchen appliances? If so a stainless steel deep fat fryer will beautifully compliment your existing decor and keep looking like new for years to come.

For small families and singles check out the latest developments in the mini deep fat fryer . This unusually small deep fat fryer has been designed specifically to meet the needs of busy people that want great tasting food but don&apos;t have time or money to waste.


Not sure where to start? Check out our deep fat fryer reviews . If you&apos;re on a tight budget there are plenty of bargains to be had by using our exclusive advanced ebay search tool .



 

 Latest 
 • T-Fal Actifry • Waring Pro DF55 • Waring Pro DF250B 
 Popular 
 • Presto 05466 Dual Basket • Cuisinart CDF-100 • Waring Pro DF100 • T-Fal FR7008002 • Aroma ADF-212 • Stainless Steel Deep Fat Fryer • Mini Deep Fat Fryer 
 By Brand 
 • Aroma • Bell-Howell • Bella Cucina • Cuisinart • Dormeyer (discontinued) • DeLonghi • Emerilware • Euro-Pro • Farberware • Gaggenau • GE • George Foreman • Hamilton Beach • Knapp-Monarch (discontinued) • Masterbuilt • Maxi-Matic (Elite) • Nesco (discontinued) • Oster • Presto • Rival • Robot Coupe (discontinued) • Sunbeam (discontinued) • Tefal • Ultrex (discontinued) • Waring • Wearever 
 
 
 About | Terms of Service | Privacy | Contact | Site Map 

Copyright 2009-2010 - DeepFatFryerGuide.com - All Rights Reserved (93/95) (0.0075)
	</body>
</document>
