<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005534" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/is-the-fast-food-industry&apos;s-structure-an-oligopoly-or-monopolistic-competition" time="2012-07-12-22:05" support="1" score="0.0052900795422754655" bingtitle="Is the fast food industry&apos;s structure an oligopoly or monopolistic ..." webtitle="Is the fast food industry&apos;s structure an oligopoly or monopolistic competition? | ChaCha">
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>How to Get Your First Credit Card. Viewed 112 times ... What is Americas favorite fast food restaurant ... Yes, you can eat certain fast food meals on a low fiber diet....</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
Is the fast food industry&apos;s structure an oligopoly or monopolistic competition? 

In: Business › Finance&amp;Economy 
 
Rate This Answer
 
Monopolistic competition. For more information, visit the link below. Thank you for using ChaCha! I hope you have a great day! ChaCha On! 
 Answered

 
 - 403 days ago at 1:44pm on Jun 05 2011 
Related Questions for Finance&amp;Economy 

 
 Is there Ethos in Fast Food Nation? 

Yes. Ethos is the appeal mainly based on the ch...

in Dining Out | 2 hr 14 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What were the 3 themes of fast food nation? 

Theme of Fast Food Nation is the fast food indu...

in Dining Out | 2 hr 16 min ago via web 
 
 What is the movie fast food nation about? 

Fast Food Nation is a 2006 American/British dra...

in Movie Showings | 2 hr 22 min ago via sms text 
 
 What fast food chain makes the best hamburger? 

The fast food chain that makes the best hamburg...

in Dining Out | 2 hr 29 min ago via sms text 
 
 Why doe people prefer fast food over eating at home? 

People buy fast food because it&apos;s cheap and hea...

in Demographics | 2 hr 35 min ago via sms text 
 
 If i eat fast food for the rest of my life what will happen to me? 

It will most likely make you obese and cause ma...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 2 hr 37 min ago via web 
 
 What was the first fast food? 

The White Castle restaurant in Wichita, Kansas ...

in History | 2 hr 39 min ago via sms text 
 
 What fast food chain is the worst for your health? 

Different restaurant have different ratings, de...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 2 hr 40 min ago via web 
 
 What is in a fast food burger? 

There are many additives in fast food: Citric A...

in Dining Out | 2 hr 40 min ago via sms text 
 
 What was the first fast food place ever invented? 

The White Castle in Wichita, Kansas is credited...

in Dining Out | 2 hr 40 min ago via sms text 
 
 Is it better to eat your food slowly or fast? 

It is best for you to eat your food slowly, so ...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 2 hr 41 min ago via web 
 
 What fast food establishment was originally made for midgets? 

Los Panchos Mexican Restaurant developed a sala...

in Dining Out | 2 hr 41 min ago via web 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Related Ads
   
Related Galleries for Finance&amp;Economy 

 
 
 
 Best Memorial Day Deals 
 Viewed 14 times 
 
 
 
 Lottery Winner Horror Stories 
 Viewed 2779 times 
 
 
 
 How to Lower Your Teen&apos;s Car Insurance 
 Viewed 140 times 
 
 
 
 Prices Increase at the Pump 
 Viewed 7 times 
 
 
 
 Foreigner&apos;s Guide to the British Pound 
 Viewed 21 times 
 
 
 
 Young Women Feel Empowered, Want Career Success 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Quizzes for Finance&amp;Economy 

 
 
 
 Which Home Loan is Right for You? 
 Viewed 791 times 
 
 
 
 Are You a Cheapskate? 
 
 
 
 Are You Using Too Much Electricity? 
 Viewed 833 times 
 
 
 
 Can You Really Afford That? 
 Viewed 550 times 
 
 
 
 Should You Buy a Car New, Used, or Leased? 
 Viewed 2158 times 
 
 
 
 When Should You Pick a Major? 
 Viewed 1681 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
Top Trends in Finance&amp;Economy 

 Savings» Personal Check» Car insurance» Home Loan» Budget» Free Credit Report» Roth IRA» IRS» Warren Buffett» Tax Credit» 
 
Top Trends in Business 

 Job Application» Savings» Rent» ATM» Resume» Brands» Work Permit» Visa» Bankruptcy» Interest Rate» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Ford» Hurt» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Business › Finance&amp;Economy 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
