<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005914" url="http://www.yelp.com/user_details?userid=phckF6yy5n6YBa9Eu82w9Q" time="2012-07-12-22:35" support="4" score="0.004378273882597137" bingtitle="William R.&apos;s Reviews | Santa Ana | Yelp" webtitle="William R.&apos;s Reviews | Santa Ana | Yelp">
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001316" bing-rank="13"/>
	<description>William R.&apos;s reviews of local businesses in Brea ... bad value, especially considering that every fast-food restaurant ... more awesomer by the fact that they include a cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk Events 

 Member Search 
   
 Profile Home Lists Reviews Compliments Friends Bookmarks Events 
 


William &quot;Clever Nickname&quot; R.&apos;s Profile
 Search Reviews 
Recent Reviews

 15 Reviews 
 Sort by: Date Filter by: Location   Category 924 E Imperial Hwy
Brea, CA 92821
 (714) 990-2869 
 Campitelli Cookies  

Categories: Bakeries , Desserts 

 11/18/2007 First to Review I&apos;ll echo the question most of you (i.e., the one person reading this) must be asking right now: is there really such a thing as a five-star cookie?

I don&apos;t know.

I mean, yeah, I&apos;ll pay almost $2.00 a cookie (or whatever she charges) at Mrs. Fields when I visit the Brea Mall. And I&apos;ll pay up to a buck at any vending machine that happens to offer Famous Amos&apos;s chocolate chip magic. Admittedly, I spent over $25 at Campitelli&apos;s for two of their standard mixed dozen. So I figure there must be a five-star cookie out there somewhere if I&apos;m willing to consistently pay over $1.00 per delicious baked treat to discover it. I could buy a bag of freakin&apos; Oreos for a lot less.

Maybe I&apos;m just dumb.

But, even if there isn&apos;t some mythical five-star cookie waiting to be eaten, Campitelli comes damn close to making one.

After learning that this place was minutes from my apartment (in the shopping center right before you hit the Jamba Juice near Imperial and State College), I swung by to pick up a couple of cookie boxes for my students, my boss, and the staff where I teach. The standard mixed dozen at Campitelli comes with 2 Chocolate Chip, 2 Peanut Butter, 2 Macadamia Nut w/White Chocolate Chip, 2 Toffee, 2 Oatmeal Raisin, and 2 Chocolate Chocolate Chip.

With the boxes sealed after purchase and my stomach growling (oh cliches, how I rely upon you), I  bought a Chocolate Chip w/Walnuts and some milk for myself. All told, my two dozen cookies and personal snack set me back just under $30. I could have chosen an awesome looking pumpkin cookie with cream cheese on top, but I went for something traditional.

And I still regret that choice today. Tear.

But, on the plus side, the girl working the counter (and, by my count, the only employee there) was incredibly polite and helpful. I almost got her a cookie as a reward, but I figured she simply stole them when she was alone. I know I would.

I enjoyed my Chocolate Chip w/Walnuts on my way to work. It was crispy on the edges and soft in the middle just the way I like it (meant in a purely non-sexual way, I assure you), even if it could have used a few more nuts to make it more exciting (okay, that one had more innuendo to it). But the cookie was tasty, and it disappeared in mere seconds.

The milk was, well, milk: cold, white, and wet. And, oh yeah, you totally know what I meant there. Pervert.

The cookies went over well with my students, my boss, and my staff (man, I gotta knock that off). My boss chose the Toffee cookies: she&apos;s a Heath Bar fan. The sweetness of the cookie pleased her, as did the amount of toffee they&apos;d baked into it. The staff liked the Macadamia Nut w/White Chocolate Chips, paying universal compliments to the cookies&apos; chewiness. My students received free cookies and got to take time out of class to eat them: they liked everything. I think one of them might have even chewed the box (last one, I swear).

Nice guy that I am, I let everyone else have their fill before I sampled more of Campitelli&apos;s goodies: this amounted to one plain Chocolate Chip cookie and one Oatmeal Raisin. The former was exactly what it should have been: addicting in an unnoticeable way. You could sit and eat a dozen of these things without realizing it. But the Oatmeal Raisin  was the real pleasant surprise. I don&apos;t typically prefer this variety of cookie because the texture doesn&apos;t allow it to melt in my mouth (fine, one more). But Campitelli&apos;s version rocked: it was really sweet with bumps in the all the right places, mounds of oatmeal/raisin that crumbled once they entered my gaping maw (is there ever any other kind of &quot;maw?&quot;) but held together nicely otherwise.

Would I go back? Yes. I want to try that Pumpkin cookie assuming it&apos;s still there, and this location is incredibly convenient considering where I live. But does the inevitability of my return make Campitelli&apos;s worthy of five stars?

Well, to varying degrees, I enjoyed each of the 3 varieties I tried. And I impressed the staff with both kindness and deliciousness, a combination that&apos;s yet to fail me in life. Plus, I totally scored points with my boss. I don&apos;t know if any other treats could have done so much for so many for so little. That&apos;s worth five stars in my book.

Perhaps you know of an even better place that sells even tastier desserts. And maybe you&apos;re reading my review and scoffing at my naive enthusiasm and hyperbole in proclaiming Campitelli&apos;s so satisfying. If so, do you want a cookie?

Because I know where you can get one. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (7) Cool (4) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 3601 S Bristol St
Santa Ana, CA 92704
 (714) 540-0020 
 Chick-Fil-A  

Category: Fast Food 

 11/5/2007 Meh.

Some places shouldn&apos;t believe their own hype. Chick-fil-A serves average food at irrational prices. I&apos;m not sure how that&apos;s led to its glowing reputation, but I tried to find out.

Armed with a coupon from the Entertainment Book, I went there for an uncomplicated lunch. The coupon read &quot;Buy 1 Chick-fil-A chicken sandwich, get one of equal or lesser value for free.&quot; I wanted to sample a chicken salad sandwich (huge fan) and an original chicken sandwich, but, no, the manager forced me to get two original chicken sandwiches if I planned to use the coupon. I guess &quot;equal or lesser value&quot; actually means &quot;identical value.&quot; Sigh. At least the girl at the counter tried to make my request happen. It&apos;s the thought that counts.

The food here shouldn&apos;t, at least not as the pinnacle of chicken sandwich preparation. I ended up with 2 original chicken sandwiches (fried fillets, not grilled) and a medium lemonade. Nothing else. When I ordered, I was asked if I wanted them plain or with everything. I try to disdain the ordinary whenever possible, so I asked for everything. Apparently, &quot;everything&quot; meant a piece of lettuce so wilted and soggy that it was an insult to vegetables everywhere and a slice of tomato that was so thin it melted. And for this, I was charged an additional 30 cents per sandwich. If I had known this was going to happen, I would have opted for the chicken and pickles sandwich they&apos;d originally planned on giving me.

The fillets were juicy but bland. I think the pickles hid under them because they were ashamed at the restaurant they were associated with. I splashed on some of Chick-fil-A&apos;s &quot;hot&quot; sauce for flavor; it didn&apos;t add much. Plus, the fillets were oddly-shaped, so much so that I had difficulty holding the sandwich despite my years of practice at Togos and Quiznos.

I ate the sandwiches quickly because I was hungry, not because they were good. They were just okay, and they cost too much. That makes them a bad value, especially considering that every fast-food restaurant in existence (McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Jack-in-the-Box, Wendy&apos;s, Carl&apos;s) now has 99-cent chicken sandwiches on their menus. Even if you think that these only taste half as good, remember that they also cost 1/3 as much: this makes them a much better value.

And that&apos;s really Chick-fil-A&apos;s problem: they think that their food is good enough to overcharge, that they don&apos;t have to offer a value. This works at some places, like The Hat, where the food is delicious and the portions are generous. But Chick-fil-A doesn&apos;t deserve the benefit of such doubt. I&apos;m giving them 2 stars only because I assume their chicken salad sandwich must be really, really good. What else explains their adamant refusal when I asked to order one via my coupon? Of course, the &quot;star&quot; of their menu, their original chicken sandwich, disappointed me so much that I&apos;m not sure I&apos;ll return to try its brethren. I was really hoping for more from this place.

To paraphrase one of their slogans, Chick-fil-A didn&apos;t invent the chicken sandwich; they perfected how to con you into buying it.

But trust me: don&apos;t believe the hype. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (2) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 1231 W Memory Ln
Santa Ana, CA 92706
 (714) 550-0057 
 Juan Pollo  

Category: Mexican 

 11/5/2007 First to Review I know good chicken.

My mom&apos;s chicken cacciatore? That&apos;s good chicken.

The broasted stuff sold at The Chicken Box in La Habra? That&apos;s good chicken.

Driving a &apos;57 Chevy towards the end of a cliff to prove my love for Peggy Sue? That&apos;s good chicken.

The chicken at Juan Pollo?

It&apos;s great chicken.

I drive by this place every week on my way to work at Santa Ana College but finally decided to stop in for two reasons. First, I checked out their menu online. Second, I noticed that no one had written a Yelp review for them. Shameless, I know.

But, as usual, my lack of shame led directly to my happiness. The place is small and simple: basic front counter in one half of the restaurant, a dining area in the other half. I ordered my food to go, so I didn&apos;t have much time to enjoy the uncomplicated ambiance. This Juan Pollo&apos;s in a shopping center with a Starbucks. Parking&apos;s not a problem as most other consumers are busy paying $5 for their coffee.

That&apos;s about what I paid for my chicken.

I went for the lunch special. For $5.49, I received two pieces of chicken, potato salad, rice, salsa (which turned out to be some spicier-than-usual pico de gallo), a medium drink, and 5 flour tortillas, even though they&apos;d originally promised only 3. I requested a leg and a breast, which I received without hassle or additional charge. So, at the very least, you know this place gives better service than most strip clubs.

The potato salad was creamy. Not the best I&apos;ve eaten, but it definitely complimented the meal well in lieu of the beans it had to have replaced. Their &quot;pollo rice&quot; was tasty, mixed with green onion and bits of their chicken (hence the name). I didn&apos;t expect anything special from a hole-in-the-wall&apos;s rice, but I was pleasantly surprised that Juan Pollo dared to be different and succeeded. The flour tortillas were flour tortillas, but there were more of them than originally anticipated. And, as previously mentioned, the pico de gallo/salsa added a needed kick to the meal.

The chicken (because that&apos;s why you&apos;re reading if you&apos;re still reading) was pretty damned delicious. It didn&apos;t fall off the bone, but, really, nothing does. Wouldn&apos;t it be weird if you picked up a rib or a drumstick and the meat literally plopped right to the ground or table or plate? You&apos;d have nothing to hold on to as you ate, nothing to guide you or to keep your meat in place. You&apos;d feel like a lazy eater if the meat just fell into your lap without you doing any work. Where would the fun be in that? Oh sure, you could continue to grasp the naked bone in one hand as you scooped up your meat in the other. But, man, that&apos;d be strange. And sexy.

I digress. The chicken at Juan Pollo didn&apos;t fall off the bone. It came close though. I gave it the gentlest of tugs; it yielded to the greed of my fingers. It was juicy and well-seasoned, with a crispy, non-oily skin that became an impromptu condiment for my potato salad. If you like a restaurant&apos;s chicken so much that you start mixing the skin in with your side dishes, you know something&apos;s gone right. Or that you&apos;ve been raised horribly, horribly wrong if you need chicken skin in your soda. This time, however, it was the former.

The food was filling, too. I have a healthy appetite (well, not healthy in terms of my actual health), and even I had trouble finishing off all the chicken, all the sides, and all the tortillas. I had a satisfying meal where everything tasted good and the main course, the chicken, tasted great. Even my beverage (horchata) didn&apos;t disappoint. All in all, an amazing value for less than $6. I&apos;ve only been once, but I know I&apos;ll be back. And I really mean that: after work tonight, I&apos;m swinging by to try their soft taco platter (3 chicken soft tacos and salsa for $3.49).

There&apos;re no guarantees in life (that&apos;s for sure), but it&apos;s pretty certain that my impending dinner will only reinforce my opinion of Juan Pollo&apos;s taste and value.

Now if I could only get Peggy Sue to go steady. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (5) Funny (4) Cool (5) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 891 Baker St
Costa Mesa, CA 92626
 (714) 708-3290 
 Manpuku Tokyo BBQ Dining  

Categories: Barbeque , Japanese 

 10/22/2007 Life, sadly, is hard. Bad hangovers, boring dates, and that invisible leprechaun who keeps stealing my socks, these things make existence that much more difficult.

Accomplishment is a panacea. Every day I can raise my arms in victory--no matter how high I lift them--is another day worth living. And it doesn&apos;t take much. If Carl&apos;s tosses a free french fry in with my onion rings, that&apos;s victory. If I manage to eat my morning Cheerios and tequila without choking, that&apos;s victory.  And if I can learn to write a Yelp review without making lame jokes, well, that&apos;ll be victory, too.

Obtaining this sense of accomplishment is why people come to places like Manpuku. Yeah, so there&apos;s nothing Herculean about cooking meat. But that&apos;s not the point. It&apos;s the fact you can do it on your own and succeed that matters: &quot;Dude, they gave me a bunch of steak, and I didn&apos;t scorch it--I can barely make toast. Awesome.&quot; What&apos;s more sacrosanct than being entrusted with the meat preparation for a table full of ravenous friends? Prayer? Nope. Marriage? Meh. Sipping 30-year-old Glenfiddich? Well, okay, maybe that.

But meat preparation&apos;s still way, way up there. And I was in charge of it last night when three buddies accompanied me to Manpuku, a restaurant that&apos;s within walking distance of Orange Coast College and in the same parking lot as the liquor store where I bought my first bottle of Herradura Anejo (I bought the Cheerios from Ralph&apos;s).

Being a Sunday night, we didn&apos;t expect much of a crowd. There wasn&apos;t one. Good thing, too, because the restaurant&apos;s &quot;cozy,&quot; with enough room to seat anywhere from 19 to 20 people. We had reservations we didn&apos;t need; we were quickly shown a table. Virgins to the Manpuku experience (sounds kinda sexy, huh?), we perused the menu, intending the whole time to order vast amounts of beef. Instead, we started with their mixed mushroom plate, the cabbage salad, and the wakame salad. Grrr. My stomach yearned for cow. Patience, my pet, patience.

The mushrooms--4 kinds, including shitake--were tastier than typical fungi. Very earthy. I wasn&apos;t impressed with my cabbage salad. Essential ruffage, but nothing spectacular--just greens with some garlicky concoction atop it. Two of my friends thoroughly enjoyed their wakame salads, however, digging the seaweed/lettuce mix and the oiliness of its sesame dressing.

But the consumption of flesh could not be denied (sounds kinda sexy, huh?): out came the meat. We went with scallops, salted prime short rib, barbecue ribeye, and prime outside skirt. The scallops cooked perfectly, remaining firm yet chewy. I&apos;m sure they tasted great, too, but my bastard friends didn&apos;t offer me any because they&apos;re bastards. The salted prime short rib was, as other Yelpers have claimed, the best thing to ever happen to a grill, juicy and full of flavor. I heard the outside skirt was decent from those who ate it (i.e. the bastards), and the ribeye hit the spot, even if it was a little tough. We also tried the garlic rice in a stone pot and, wow, this might have been the tastiest rice ever. It&apos;s one of those things that&apos;s so good you have to eat just a little of it for fear of overdosing on deliciousness (sounds kinda sex...ah, nevermind). I heartily recommend ordering it, but don&apos;t eat it yourself, no matter how many double-dares you have to endure.

We had free hot green tea. We were given pre-moistened towelettes. We received cheerful, patient service. Everything was copacetic....except for the prices (hence the 4 stars). We abandoned the plan of ordering vast amounts of beef and gorging ourselves because the food cost too much. High-quality? Uh-huh. Scrumptious? You bet. But damn pricey, too. Every plate of meat cost at least $8, yet each came with only 8 pieces. It didn&apos;t feel right to pay $1 per morsel of cow regardless of how good the animal tasted. It would have taken at least 6 plates to fill me up and, if I&apos;m going to pay nearly $50 for beef, I better be eating filet and the sign outside the restaurant better read &quot;Morton&apos;s.&quot; My group didn&apos;t try the Kobe medallions because they weighed 4 ounces and cost almost $27.00. I won&apos;t pay that much for 4 ounces of anything unless it&apos;s premium black-tar heroin.

Which, when I asked, they didn&apos;t have. Still, everyone agreed that Manpuku definitely deserved a return visit, and I was applauded as the visionary who brought his friends to this mecca of excellent food and personal accomplishment.

Now if I could just find that fucking leprechaun. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (4) Cool (5) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 746 N Brea Blvd
Brea, CA 92821
 (714) 256-9068 
 Red Lantern Chinese Cuisine  

Category: Chinese 

 10/18/2007 To be honest, I didn&apos;t actually &quot;go&quot; to this restaurant. I had their food delivered to my apartment because their take-out menu has the magical words &quot;free delivery&quot; printed neatly at the bottom. As always, &quot;free&quot; is a relative word: delivery costs nothing only if your meal costs at least $12 and you live within three miles of the restaurant. Since both my girlfriend and myself were eating, we qualified. But, then again, all of the prices for their meat and/or vegetable dishes are in the $8-$10 range, so I probably could have met this criteria on my own. If you want to talk decor, go there yourself. If you want to know about the food, keep reading. And if you can&apos;t wait to take advantage of this place&apos;s free delivery, then you must be one of the 20 people who resides in Brea. If so, what&apos;s up? We should hang out.

I think generic places like Red Lantern ascribe to the Taco Bell method of menu creation. We all know that Taco Bell has managed to sustain an international chain of businesses by combining the same seven ingredients in as many different ways as possible. Same principle applies at Red Lantern. It seems as if every dish follows an identical formula: 1. Choose meat (beef, chicken, pork, shrimp, fish, scallops); 2. Mix with arbitrary collection of vegetables (broccoli, bell pepper, carrots, snow peas, baby corn, water chestnuts, mushrooms); 3. Add ambiguous sauce (sweet and sour, white, special white, brown, brown garlic, spicy brown, black bean); 4. Charge $2-$3 more than expected. Presto! Another menu created.

There&apos;s some interesting stuff in Red Lantern&apos;s. The cheapest--if you ignore the beverages--comes in at $2: a couple of vegetable egg rolls or some ice cream (vanilla, strawberry, mango, and green tea). The most expensive item is the steamed Chilean sea bass in the &quot;Red Lantern Specialties&quot; section. It&apos;s $18. If you ever try it, let me know. I won&apos;t because I refuse to pay that much for formulaic Chinese--it&apos;s the same reason I avoid going to P.F. Chang&apos;s. I ordered the Orange Chicken (hey, I&apos;m half-white, so sue me) and the fried cream cheese won-tons. My girlfriend went with the vegetable chow mein.

My orange chicken cost $8.50. This was about $3 more than I would pay at Panda Express (I already said I&apos;m white, so of course I compare all other Chinese to a ubiquitous fast food place), and I didn&apos;t get a second item. Still, the orange chicken was better than Panda&apos;s. The friend chicken pieces were bigger, crispier, and had more of a kick since the orange Szechwan sauce contained dried red peppers. I opted for this dish partly because it was listed as spicy on the menu--it had the little pepper next to its description to prove it. Although the heat wasn&apos;t anything to shed tears over--I&apos;m also half-Mexican, so I enjoy habaneros in my cereal--I did appreciate the extra warmth of the orange flavor. I would definitely eat this chicken again. I&apos;m not lying: there&apos;s some leftover in my fridge. Plus, they give you a lot of it. Like, $8.50 worth. I filled my plate up twice and still had almost half the chicken sitting there, patiently awaiting its turn in my mouth. Good things are worth waiting for.

The cream cheese won-tons, however, weren&apos;t good things. To borrow from Comic Book Guy (as so many Yelpers do), &quot;Worst cream cheese won-tons ever.&quot; I paid $5 for 6 of them; they gave me 10. Although I appreciated the generosity, giving me more of a bad thing doesn&apos;t make it good. And, yes, I know how long this review is. Shut up. The cream cheese was tasteless and had diced carrots in it. If you need carrots, Nature&apos;s kid-on-the-short-bus, to make your food more flavorful, then you know something&apos;s wrong. The won-tons themselves weren&apos;t crispy but instead made me wince with what I&apos;ll describe as a stale flakiness. I ate the first one plain. Big mistake: it tasted as if I&apos;d eaten a piece of diaper. I ate another one drowned in sweet and sour sauce. This worked to a degree, but I could still taste a lot of bland. I threw away the remaining 8 won-tons; I paid $5 for 2 terrible won-tons and 2 ounces of sweet and sour sauce. Ouch.

My girlfriend, a notoriously picky eater and chooser of mates, liked her vegetable chow mein because she, &quot;didn&apos;t have to pick that much stuff out of it.&quot; She kept the mushrooms, the carrots, the baby corn, the bell pepper, and the broccoli. She removed the bamboo shoots. To me, it tasted exactly like the noodles at Genghis Khan&apos;s Mongolian BBQ in the Brea Mall. If you enjoy their chow mein, you&apos;ll enjoy Red Lantern&apos;s. But you won&apos;t get to see them make it in front of you. You&apos;ll just have to use your imagination.

This all adds up to three stars: orange chicken worth a little overcharging, chow mein that saved me a trip to the mall, a friendly delivery guy who smiled when I tried to steal his pen, and cream cheese won-tons that made the fortune cookies seem gourmet in comparison. Will I eat here again? Probably.

But only &apos;cause I enjoy free delivery so much. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (5) Cool (5) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 2264 S Mountain Ave
Ontario, CA 91762
 (909) 983-2826 
 Casa Sanchez Restaurant  

Category: Mexican 

 10/17/2007 First to Review I spent my childhood in Chino but only started frequenting Casa Sanchez years later after I&apos;d long since moved to Orange County and Chino had replaced its dairies with strip malls. When I was a kid, I didn&apos;t remember the city having anything resembling decent Mexican fare aside from Taco Bell, Del Taco, and the long-since out-of-business Nogales. Taco Bell decent? Shows what I knew. I assumed that my Hispanic brethren simply didn&apos;t find it profitable or prudent to migrate that far east. Plus, the city used to smell like cows and lots of them.

I may not have fond memories of Mexican food in Chino from when I was a kid, but I do have them as an adult. Casa Sanchez is everything you want from Mexican food: delicious, filling, efficient, and cheap. Every time I hand over my money at the end of a meal, I feel as if I&apos;m stealing from them. But they smile profusely, so my thievery&apos;s okay.

The prices really are ridiculous. I generally return for the two-taco combination. For $6, you get a couple of nice-sized shredded beef tacos that aren&apos;t heaps of lettuce and cheese masquerading as food (as they are at, oh, Pepe&apos;s, for instance), a tasty puddle of re-fried beans, and a heap of fluffy, orange rice. The meat, God bless it, is juicy in the middle and just a little crispy on the ends, like Nature intended.

It&apos;s an awesome deal, but it&apos;s made even more awesomer by the fact that they include a cup of soup with your meal even though they&apos;re already filling you up for less than it costs to park at Disneyland (screw you, Mickey). The soup choices aren&apos;t particularly eclectic--Chicken Tortilla or Abondigas--but each tastes great. I&apos;m a fan of both Abondigas (that&apos;s &quot;meatball soup&quot; for the gringos out there) and eating beef in as many different forms as possible during one meal, so I always go with the latter.

You can, of course, find the usual suspects on Casa Sanchez&apos;s menu: burritos, enchiladas, tostadas, carne asada, etc.; pretty much everything comes in combination form.Their wet burritos--especially the carnitas--also have a special place in my heart (I like to call it &quot;my arteries&quot;). The menu doesn&apos;t surprise with its variety; it shocks with its value. Almost nothing costs over $10, and everything comes with soup or salad and commendable service that&apos;s done by committee, with every server keeping track of every table in a sort of communist, we&apos;re-all-here-for-good-tips-so-let&apos;s-try-hard method of serving. And, in this case, communism definitely works.

Casa Sanchez doesn&apos;t get 5 stars because it&apos;s the best Mexican food I&apos;ve ever had. I did, after all, live in Santa Ana for 14 years. All the best Mexicans live and cook there. No, it gets 5 stars because it is the best Mexican food you can get at the prices they charge. Few things taste this good and are this cheap. They refill drinks for free. They even cater. And they do all the basic stuff, like the shredded beef tacos, perfectly, meaning that you never have to stray far from what you know to enjoy yourself.

I didn&apos;t have to: I came back to Chino. And now when I&apos;m there I can eat dead cows instead of smelling live ones thanks to Casa Sanchez. Ah, memories. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (4) Cool (2) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 12911 Main St
Garden Grove, CA 92840
 (714) 638-3790 
 Azteca  

Categories: Mexican , Karaoke , Arts&amp;Entertainment 

 10/12/2007 I&apos;m convinced that the owner of Azteca must be a closet vampire slayer or something. This restaurant, though located on the bright and friendly sidewalks of Garden Grove&apos;s Main Street, is dank and dark and kinda creepy on the inside--all the better to lure vamps in, right?

No, see, &apos;cause the place&apos;s famous for their garlic sauce, a concoction that would send any vampire to its coffin for all of eternity. Hell, after eating way too much of it, I was also ready to spend the rest of my life inside a box, closed away from the rest of the world and those unfortunate souls I might breathe upon.

I mean, c&apos;mon, the sauce is famous. The menu told me so. It wouldn&apos;t lie. Manipulated once again by an inanimate object, I ordered garlic tacos, a salad with garlic dressing, and, yes, even a shot of the garlic sauce as a chaser for my Pepsi.

It burned. It scalded. It brought tears to my eyes. Thank God the place was so dark: no one wants to see me crying into my shredded beef. I, of course, finished my meal. But I don&apos;t remember much of it. The flavor of the garlic sauce overwhelmed everything, including my memory. It was as if I&apos;d came in, sat down, and said, &quot;I&apos;ll have the garlic appetizer, the garlic combo, a garlic shake, and a piece of garlic cheesecake for dessert. By the way, could you toss a bunch of garlic on my chips as well? Thanks.&quot;

True, I did try to order in my crappy, learned-from-watching-The Simpsons-after-I&apos;ve-hit-the-SAP-button-on-my-­remote Spanish, but I&apos;m pretty sure that&apos;s not what I said to the waiter.

Okay, maybe this place would kick ass if you really liked garlic. And I&apos;m talking about loving it so much that you&apos;ve petitioned Starbucks to keep bottles of it next to the cinnamon and nutmeg (&quot;mmm...now my latte&apos;s stinky.&quot;) But I doubt anyone planning to kiss something other than their dog likes it that much. And, believe me, if you eat as much garlic sauce as I did, even your dog will shun you. Sorry about that, Peanut. We&apos;ll play fetch again soon.

So how&apos;s the food without the garlic sauce? Glad I asked.

It&apos;s decent. Solid, though nothing spectacular. I suppose it&apos;s actually pretty good for Garden Grove. The city&apos;s far more concerned with the quality of its pho than it is with the tastiness of its carne asada. So if you need Mexican food and you can&apos;t drive the extra 10 minutes it would take to eat anywhere in Santa Ana (you lazy bastard), then, by all means, eat here and don&apos;t feel too bad about yourself....unless you slather on the garlic sauce like it&apos;s whipped cream during another night of double-dare group sex. If you forgo the sauce, I recommend the chili con carne with some butter-covered corn tortillas. What doesn&apos;t taste better slathered in butter? I know I do.

Oh, and one more thing: what&apos;s with all the Elvis memorabilia? Here you are, eating greasy, heartburn-causing, cholesterol-filled Mexican food, and you&apos;re surrounded by statues and pictures of a man who killed himself by swallowing plate after plate of fried peanut butter-and-banana sandwiches. This is supposed to make you feel better about the food? That&apos;s always a good message to send restaurant patrons: eating this stuff will kill you; enjoy your meal, asshole. Uh, thanks.

At Azteca, I guess anything makes sense if you add enough garlic sauce. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (4) Cool (3) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 1235 E Imperial Hwy
Placentia, CA 92870
 (714) 524-1260 
 Brooklyn Pizza Works  

Categories: Pizza , Italian 

 10/11/2007 I must begin this review by admitting two biases:

1. I&apos;ve been coming to this place for years.

2. I love good pizza.

Notice how closely related my preferences are?

Everyone has different criteria for judging their pizza. There&apos;s no shame in admitting that. For some, it&apos;s amount and dispersal of toppings. For others, it&apos;s the delicate balance of crust and cheese. For me, it&apos;s the sauce. Give me a great sauce, and I&apos;ll order your pizza for my wedding.

I love the sauce at Brooklyn Pizza. I would become best friends with this sauce. I would introduce this sauce to my mother if they hadn&apos;t already met. I would even marry this sauce and have its children if such a thing weren&apos;t an affront to God.

Maybe that&apos;s too much. Suffice it to say that I would put this sauce on anything, even a sundae. Yeah, it&apos;s that good.

So putting it on pizza&apos;s an easy call. Coincidentally, that&apos;s also what it happens to taste best on. Brooklyn Pizza does this extraordinary concoction justice, slathering it over New York Style thin crust pizza that holds up well regardless of topping choice. I usually go with an East Coast Greasy Pizza with pepperoni. Don&apos;t let the name scare you: you&apos;re still in Orange County.

I like the pizza because, aside from the tiny round disks of meat, it enhances the normal cheese by baking in crushed garlic, oregano, Romano cheese, and olive oil. I&apos;ve also been told by a good friend whom I introduced to this restaurant that the white pizza with chicken is awesome as well.

I always get a side salad because I love their Italian dressing. It, like everything else, is homemade--I think the secret ingredient is crack. And, if so, then I&apos;m pretty sure the crack is homemade, too. I typically get a side of garlic bread so that I can transfer some of that wonderful marinara sauce to my mouth while I wait for my pizza. And I often take an order of rigatoni with meatballs home so that I can relive eating the sauce at least one more time.

Man, I love that sauce--I wish I had a big glass of it in front of me right now. I do have a copy of Brooklyn Pizza&apos;s menu in front of me. I think I&apos;ll sit here and chew it while I fantasize about tomorrow&apos;s dinner.

Why the four stars? The service, though friendly, can get a little slow if you don&apos;t maintain constant eye contact and, sometimes, they have a tendency to mess up pizza orders. But, even when I get meatball on my East Coast Greasy instead of pepperoni, I happily eat it anyway.

I am, after all, human. If you want to be too, then I suggest you eat here. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (5) Funny (5) Cool (7) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 2901 Ocean Park Blvd
Santa Monica, CA 90405
 (310) 399-8383 
 The Counter  

Category: Burgers 
Neighborhood: Santa Monica
 10/11/2007 If you&apos;re American, then you have to go to The Counter.

And, no, I don&apos;t mean in that popular flag-waving, children-hugging kind of a way. I mean if you eat red meat. And lots of it. In burger form. &apos;Cause then this place is for you.

You see, burgers are the white person&apos;s answer to the burrito (and, no, like the chicken and the egg, I&apos;m not sure which came first...probably the one on top). You unfold a flour tortilla, put whatever you want in it, refold it, and, presto, you have a burrito. Same principle applies with Caucasians: you toast two buns, put whatever you want in between (though it should include a hunk of premium ground beef), put one bun on either side of your fillings, and, presto, you have a burger.

And this is exactly what The Counter does for you: it lets you put whatever you want between your buns.

Maybe places like Red Robin and Johnny Rocket&apos;s do that, too. But you know you&apos;re always saying, &quot;Man, I could totally build a burger this good myself if I had all these ingredients. It&apos;d probably even taste better, too. Just give me a chance.&quot; And then the people sitting across from you look at you funny and return to their food.

You get that chance at The Counter and, since everyone else is doing it too, no one looks at you weird. Well, at least not for how you order.

You get a clipboard. The clipboard has a plethora of choices on it. You make these choices. You get fed. And then you&apos;re happy. Pretty simply.

First, you choose your burger. As I&apos;m sure all the female customers appreciate, everyone gets to decide how big they want their meat. Sizes range from 1/3 of a pound to a full pound of cow. You get buns: regular, wheat, or English Muffin. You pick temperature; you should all know these (Kelvin, Fahrenheit, Celsius). You pick cheese--they&apos;re, like, 9 choices, but stick with Gruyere, the Swiss cheese that typically goes atop French Onion Soup. And, of course, there are the toppings. Though too many to list, some of my personal favorites include the chili, the roasted red peppers, and the dried cranberries (which, even if you don&apos;t put on your burger, are good for future snackin&apos;).

The drinks almost outdo the meat. Do yourself a favor and order a shake. They&apos;re so good you&apos;ll want them hooked to your veins. I almost always get an apple pie shake as it&apos;s their best and a regular fixture on the menu, but the shakes-of-the-month definitely have their charm. The churro shake&apos;s been the best I&apos;ve had of those; that night, they stopped serving them when they ran out of churros.

Oh, yeah, there&apos;re some vegetarian options, but, c&apos;mon, you&apos;re in a place famous for their burgers. If you aren&apos;t there to eat them, then get the hell out and vacate a table for someone who is.

After that, well, it&apos;s a normal burger place. Don&apos;t get me wrong: the burgers are really, really good. They&apos;re juicy, almost always cooked perfectly, and ridiculously filling. I&apos;ve never left The Counter feeling good about what I did to myself while I was there. If you want a great burger for a reasonable price served to you in place that&apos;ll bring back memories of The Peach Pit from 90210 (the television show, not the actual zip code), then, by all means, go here. But what you&apos;re really paying for, aside from the delicious food, is the chance to create something beautiful and imaginative from out of the depths of your own mind and then, like you used to do with your Play-Doh sculptures, eat it. This should just taste a whole lot better.

Now, you might say that&apos;s not worth the price. But, believe me, if you create it, then you&apos;ll have to love it. Just ask anyone with kids.

Besides, where else can you put apricot sauce, grilled mushrooms, and pepper jack cheese on a 1/2 pound burger before sticking it in between two English muffins? Here, I tell you. Well, and other places, too, probably. But they won&apos;t taste as good.

Hey, you think you can come up with something better than what I just described? I believe you. Now go to The Counter and prove it, you red-meat eating American. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (6) Cool (5) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 6922 Hollywood Blvd
Los Angeles, CA 90028
 (323) 465-9097 
 Céfiore  

Category: Ice Cream&amp;Frozen Yogurt 
Neighborhood: Hollywood
 10/10/2007 The yogurt at Cefiore in Hollywood is the best I&apos;ve had.

I didn&apos;t think I would ever share such a sentiment. For the longest time, the vanilla with fresh peaches at Penguin&apos;s was my frozen soulmate, a creamy treat that completed me in a Jerry Maguireesque way. But no more. I&apos;ve fallen in love with the blackberry yogurt with mangoes and strawberries at this particular Cefiore. It&apos;s younger, it&apos;s prettier, and it tastes better. How could I resist?

I tried, actually. Having just eaten a satisfying lunch following a disappointing movie (that&apos;s a review for a different website), I walked by this Cefiore without a thought of dessert in my mind. But that all changed when a smiling, enthusiastic Asian man with a tray full of yogurt samples offered me some delicious goodness as I passed him. Although I could barely understand his English, I heard the word &quot;free.&quot; I accepted his generosity and took a sample. And then my life changed.

I think I tried the raspberry/pomegranate. It was plain--no fruit, no sprinkles, no nothing. But it was perfect in its simplicity. It was like a party in my mouth where everyone was invited and, believe me, I know what that&apos;s like. Hyperbole aside, I was hooked.

Like a good poker player, I think the man could read my face. He knew I wanted more. Introducing himself as Wilson, he patted me on the back and welcomed me to his store. At first, he was so friendly that I thought he might be coming onto me. But, no, this owner/manager wanted me to try more of his scrumptious product.

And with good reason. I had a hard time deciding what to get once I was inside. I was by myself, but Wilson treated me as if I had come with a dozen of my friends and family. I really appreciated the attention I got although I was a single customer. I asked about the snow ice. Although he admitted that it would probably be too much for me to eat by myself, he was nice and let me have a sample of that, too. It was so good that I almost dismissed his warning and ordered a giant cup of it. Showing some willpower, I opted for a medium blackberry yogurt (one of my favorite fruits) covered with strawberries and mangoes (two more of my favorite fruits).

I sat at a table, watching Wilson gaze with delight as I swallowed. I wish I could describe every bite, but it seems as if it only took one to finish. The yogurt was both tart and creamy, an ideal combination that was enhanced by the sweetness of the fruit. I even enjoyed my surroundings--the location is simply decorated with tables, chairs, and colorful hanging lights. It doesn&apos;t feel cluttered when several other customers are there, and it allows for some leisurely people-watching. This was easily the best part of my day.

Satisfied in every way, I thanked Wilson and promised to return. Of course, like a good friend who&apos;s an even better host, he begged me to stay, offering other tempting samples from his menu. But if I&apos;d stayed, I would have been both broke from buying the best yogurt I&apos;ve ever had and over-stuffed to the point of immobility from eating it.

And I wouldn&apos;t be here to share this experience with you. As I live in Orange County, I don&apos;t often find myself in Hollywood. But, next time I am, I&apos;ll definitely make sure to visit Wilson and his Cefiore store again. If you live closer than I do, I suggest you do the same and do it more often. Support this friendly, hard-working, somewhat gay business owner.

His frozen yogurt totally deserves it.

See you in line. 
Was this review…?

 Useful (12) Funny (15) Cool (13) 
 
 Bookmark      Send To A Friend    Link to this Review 
 

 More» 
 
 23 Friends 
   
 33 friends 96 reviews 

 Maria R. 
   
 Elite &apos;12 412 friends 569 reviews 

 Arnold E. 
   
 14425 friends 212 reviews 

 Walker S. 
   
 318 friends 192 reviews 

 Teresa P. 
 More» 
 20 Compliments 

 Hot Stuff 
Thanks, now I&apos;m drooling over the images of carnitas dancing in my head!… More» 
 Just a Note 
I completely forgot about this place. I used to work in Placentia and would… More» 
 Hot Stuff 
Congrats on your ROTD!
 
 More» 
 No Lists 
 
 

William hasn&apos;t made any lists yet.
 Recent reviews by William R. I want this bling on my blog» 
&quot;Don&apos;t fill up on bread.&quot;

 23 Friends 15 Reviews 3 Firsts 4 Fans 
 
 Rating Distribution 
 Loading... View more graphs» 

 Review votes:
88 Useful, 86 Funny, and 84 Cool
 Compliments Like Your Profile 2 Cute Pic 1 You&apos;re Funny 1 Thank You 1 Good Writer 3 Just a Note 2 Hot Stuff 9 You&apos;re Cool 1 Write More 1 Location 
Santa Ana, CA
 Yelping Since 
October 2007
 Find Me In 
Central Orange County
 My Hometown 
Santa Ana, CA.
 My Blog Or Website 
None
 When I&apos;m Not Yelping... 
Fantasizing about other hot Yelpers
 Why You Should Read My Reviews 
&apos;Cause me can right da words reel good
 My Second Favorite Website 
 http://www.ocweekly.com 
 The Last Great Book I Read 
The Kite Runner by Khaled Hosseini
 My First Concert 
New Model Army
 My Favorite Movie 
Kill Bill, vol. 1
 My Last Meal On Earth 
Filet from Morton&apos;s and the Banana Foster&apos;s at TAPS
 Don&apos;t Tell Anyone Else But... 
I can turn water into wine
 Most Recent Discovery 
The apple-pie milkshake diet (results pending)
 Current Crush 
Every Hooters girl I&apos;ve ever met
 Flag this profile 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
