<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005231" url="http://www.careerjet.com/fast-food-restaurant-jobs.html" time="2012-07-12-21:45" support="5" score="0.010541424669926008" bingtitle="fast food restaurant jobs in USA | careerjet.com" webtitle="fast food restaurant jobs in USA | careerjet.com">
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001012" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001039" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001514" bing-rank="82"/>
	<description>Restaurant Opportunities Company name Pay Rate ... perform duties involving Food Service for meal tray ... We are a healthy fast food restaurant serving fresh salads, wraps, and ...</description>
	<body>
		Job seeker free services : : : Create job alerts | Post your resume Sign up / Log in what : where :       Advanced search 
 Jobs by location 
     Advertisers     Partners     Job Seekers       Locations 
   USA

 Alabama 

 Alaska 

 Arizona 

 Arkansas 

 California 

 Colorado 

 Connecticut 

 Delaware 

 District of Columbia 

 Florida 

 Georgia 

 Hawaii 

 Idaho 

 Illinois 

 Indiana 

 Iowa 

 Kansas 

 Kentucky 

 Louisiana 

 Maine 

 Maryland 

 Massachusetts 

 Michigan 

 Minnesota 

 Mississippi 

 Missouri 

 Montana 

 Nebraska 

 Nevada 

 New Hampshire 

 New Jersey 

 New Mexico 

 New York 

 North Carolina 

 North Dakota 

 Ohio 

 Oklahoma 

 Oregon 

 Pennsylvania 

 Rhode Island 

 South Carolina 

 South Dakota 

 Tennessee 

 Texas 

 Utah 

 Vermont 

 Virginia 

 Washington 

 West Virginia 

 Wisconsin 

 Wyoming 
           Contract type 
   Any

 Part-time 

 Full-time 

 Permanent 

 Contract 

 Temporary 

 Training 

 Voluntary 
           Recent searches 
 fast food restaurant, USA 
         23429   
fast food restaurant jobs in USA
 
 Job search &gt; USA jobs &gt; fast food restaurant jobs 
                   Email 
 Fast Food Crew Member 

 TRAVELCENTERS of America - Elgin, IL 

convenience store, several fast food concepts, and a service repair shop. We offer a great manager training program for those that wish to advance... their career. As a Fast Food Crew Member, you will need to be skilled in serving each guest courteously and efficiently with a pleasant...

 
 
 Fast Food Crew Lead 

 TRAVELCENTERS of America - Elgin, IL 

convenience store, several fast food concepts, and a service repair shop. We offer a great manager training program for those that wish to advance... their career. As a Fast Food Crew Lead, you will need to lead your team members in achieving the shift targets according to franchise standards...

 
 
 Restaurant Shift Manager ? Retail Food Service Supervisor 

 Hardee&apos;s - South Hill, VA 

. in 1962 when Carleton Noell and his two entrepreneurial nephews, Mayo and Nick Boddie, opened one of the first Hardee&apos;s restaurants. Fast ...- food was a relatively new concept back then, but BNE&apos;s commitment to friendly service and great-tasting charbroiled burgers established it...

 
 
 Restaurant Assistant Manager-Fast Food-Quick Serve Restaurant 

 Carrols Restaurant Group - Greensboro, NC 

 RESTAURANT – QUICK SERVE – FAST FOOD – FULL SERVICE – RETAIL – HOSPITALITY – RESTAURANT ASSISTANT MANAGER Carrols Restaurant Group... objectives. At least 6 months experience in an Assistant Management role within the restaurant industry ( fast food , fast casual, or full-service...

 
 
 Restaurant Assistant Manager-Fast Food-Quick Serve Restaurant 

 Carrols Restaurant Group - Greensboro, NC 

 RESTAURANT – QUICK SERVE – FAST FOOD – FULL SERVICE – RETAIL – HOSPITALITY – RESTAURANT ASSISTANT MANAGER Carrols Restaurant Group... realistic yet challenging profit objectives. At least 6 months experience in an Assistant Management role within the restaurant industry ( fast ...

 
 
 General Manager / Restaurant -Fast Food 

 Tadich Sales Recruiters - New Kensington, PA 

of a high volume facility. Will handle P&amp;L;and supervise staff. Must have prior fast food , restaurant or related assistant or manager experience....

 
 
 Area Manager- Fast food 

 Marshall, Scott and Monroe - Atlanta, GA 

Area Manager- Fast food What are your responsibilities:~ supervising 5-10 company-owned restaurants.Your goal is to improve restaurant ... performers-Fostering restaurant environments that are neat, clean and organized...

 
 
 Owner Operator- Fast Casual Restaurant Franchise 

 Cleveland, OH 

Owner Operator- Fast Casual Restaurant Franchise Seeking a motivated, hard working individual who desires to own their own business. The... position requires a background in the food service industry. We also look for people who enjoy living a healthy lifestyle and have a strong desire...

 
 
 Restaurant / Food Service Assistant Manager 

 MMAR Recruiters - Houston, TX 

 Restaurant / Food Service Assistant Manager The Assistant Manager has the overall responsibility for directing the daily operations... of a restaurant in the Restaurant General Manager&apos;s absence, ensuring compliance with company standards in all areas of operation, including product...

 
 
 Quick Serve Restaurant Assistant Manager 

 Travel Centers of America - Seattle, WA 

TravelCenters of America is seeking candidates for a Fast Food Restaurant Assistant General Manager. We are seeking Assistant Manager... not required) Responsibilities of a Fast Food Assistant Restaurant Manager: Hands on management position Ordering, inventory, scheduling, staffing Full P&amp;L...;

 
 
 Quick Serve Restaurant Assistant Manager 

 Travel Centers of America - Foristell, MO 

TravelCenters of America is seeking candidates for a Fast Food Restaurant Assistant General Manager. We are seeking Assistant Manager... not required) Responsibilities of a Fast Food Assistant Restaurant Manager: Hands on management position Ordering, inventory, scheduling, staffing Full P&amp;L...;

 
 
 Quick Serve Restaurant Assistant Manager 

 Travel Centers of America - Cheyenne, WY 

TravelCenters of America is seeking candidates for a Fast Food Restaurant Assistant General Manager. We are seeking Assistant Manager... not required) Responsibilities of a Fast Food Assistant Restaurant Manager: Hands on management position Ordering, inventory, scheduling, staffing Full P&amp;L...;

 
 
 Restaurant Manager *IMMEDIATE INTERVIEWS 

 Abilene, TX 

- TheJobNetwork. Category: Restaurant and Food Service, Keywords: Assistant Restaurant Manager... Restaurant Manager *IMMEDIATE INTERVIEWS* This job posting was provided by JobCentral for WorkInTexas.com. General Details Job Posting ID...

 
 
 Food Service Manager 2 Job 

 Sodexo - San Francisco, CA 

– restaurant or fast food concepts.- Enjoy becoming involved in the campus community, have strengths in relationships with clients, customers... fast paced, high volume restaurant environment.- Have strong employee engagement – developing, mentoring, training as well as scheduling...

 
 
 Food Service Manager 2 Job 

 Sodexo - Fort Worth, TX 

years work experience in food or culinary services including restaurants, fast food , vending, catering services, institutional services, mall... Food Service Manager 2System ID: 16825 Location: US-TX-FORT WORTHPosition Title: Food Service Manager 2 Relocation: YesCategory: Food ...

 
 
 Assistant Managers - Fast Food Restaurant 

 Marshall, Scott and Monroe - Phoenix, AZ 

Assistant Managers - Fast Food Restaurant RESPONSIBILITIES OF POSITION:*Hands on management position*Ordering, inventory, scheduling..., staffing*Full P&amp;L;responsibilities of restaurant *Develop team atmosphere with employees*Provide excellent customer service*Maintain safety...

 
 
 Fast Food Restaurant Management 

 GC Inc. - Tampa, FL 

 Fast Food Restaurant Management Our management team enjoys great benefits, including but not limited to: * Weekly Paychecks * Monthly Bonus... Fast Food managers * Competitive Salaries * Competitive Medical Benefits * Flexible Schedules (We know you have a life outside of work...

 
 
 Fast Food Restaurant Management 

 GC Inc. - Orlando, FL 

 Fast Food Restaurant Management DescriptionIt&apos;s different here...seriously.Who are we? What do we want? That&apos;s how everyone else starts off...

 
 
 Server, Fast Food Restaurants 

 Hospitality&amp;Catering Management Services - Pensacola, FL 

Server, Fast Food Restaurants Server jobs near beaches in Florida, North Carolina, South Carolina, Louisiana, Alabama, Mississippi...

 
 
 Fast Food Worker: Restaurant Manager,Shift Supervisor,Team Member(Brooklyn, Queens, Manhattan) 

 New York City, NY 

 Restaurant Manager, Shift Supervisor, Team Member Brooklyn, Queens, Manhattan Team Member - Prefered KFC experience, if new willing... for examination if not already certified. Restaurant Manager - Require KFC experience, Full time position, requiring input of 55-60hrs. Salary...

 
 
page:   1 | 2 | 3    &gt;&gt; 
 
 About us | Frequent queries | Jobs by keyword | Jobs by location | Jobs by company 


©2012 Careerjet
	</body>
</document>
