<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005809" url="http://www.dailydanny.com/?tag=fast-food" time="2012-07-12-22:27" support="18" score="0.05658942458193613" bingtitle="Daily Danny » fast food - Green Living Expert Danny Seo’s eco ..." webtitle="Daily Dannyfast food - Green Living Expert Danny Seos eco-friendly and crafty ideas for everyday living.">
			<query id="001238" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000513" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000526" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001250" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001222" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001235" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001012" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001246" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>It’s not everyday an Indonesian/Dutch fast food restaurant with ... Cozy enough to throw down a tray and eat a quick ... containers and recyclable beverage containers. On ...</description>
	<body>
		Search for: 
 Home About Contact 
 
Posts Tagged‘fast food’
 
 Thank u, Danku 
 April 30th, 2009 
 

It’s not everyday an Indonesian/Dutch fast food restaurant with an organic/eco slant opens up in your neighborhood.  Actually, it never happens.    So, you can imagine my surprise when I was walking down 57th street in New York City (starving) and stumbled across this place.   Daily Danny readers: I introduce you to Danku , a naturalicious fast food restaurant worth a visit.

 

First thing you notice is that the interior of Danku is fun, inviting and very European.  This is a good thing.   Think Ikea Cafe, but (sorry, Ikea) but with actually good food.    Here, a communal table is upfront made from salvaged wood.   Cozy enough to throw down a tray and eat a quick lunch, but communal enough to not feel like your crashing someone’s table if you join them.

 

The menu is a mix of Indonesian and Dutch specialities.  Yes, you read this right. The menu at Danku is inspired by the popular Indo-Dutch cuisine served all over the Netherlands—Danku’s birthplace. At one time, Indonesia was a Dutch colony and Indonesian ingredients and dishes have left a delicious and lasting impression, becoming an integral part of the Dutch culinary repertoire.   So, you can have stir fried noodles with a spicy sauce and then finish it with apple cinnamon fritters.    It sounds bizarre, but it works.   Almost all of Danku’s ingredients are natural and organic, which means they were not subjected to synthetic fertilizers, pesticides, additives, radiation or genetic modification.

 

Just as fast as a normal fast food restaurant, but better organic ingredients and a true effort to be as green as possible.   PLA biodegradable straws and utensils, recycled paper napkins, compostable containers and recyclable beverage containers.  On-site recycling takes all the packaging—including the compostable containers—and disposes of them properly.    Eat, enjoy and throw nothing away.

 

Clear instructions on what to do with your waste.   I peered into each bin and saw most people followed the rules pretty well.

 

And as I sat there and at my noodle spicy shrimp wrap and iced tea, I took this photo of the wall.   Why?  It just looks colorful and nice.   Seriously, when was the last time you were inspired inside a fast food restaurant?  Thank u, Danku.
 Posted in Food and Drink on April 30th, 2009   |    7 Comments   
 Subscribe: Entries | Comments 
About Danny

America&apos;s leading lifestyle expert on all things green, 
 visit Daily Danny everyday for inspiring how-to projects, 
 ideas, tips and contests. It&apos;s easy to live eco-friendly!
 
Categories

 Beauty Books Contests Current Affairs Events Fashion Film Finds Food and Drink Home Design Magazines Radio shopping Television Travel Uncategorized Web/Tech Weblogs 
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 
 
 ©2012. Daily Danny. All rights reserved. Powered by WordPress &amp; SimpleX theme.
	</body>
</document>
