<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005834" url="http://www.marketplace.org/topics/life/wendys-testing-breakfast-menu" time="2012-07-12-22:29" support="1" score="0.0013681495659726153" bingtitle="Wendy&apos;s testing breakfast menu | Marketplace from American Public ..." webtitle="Wendys testing breakfast menu | Marketplace.org">
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>Marketplace Tech Report; Performance Today; Pipedreams; A Prairie Home Companion; Saint Paul Sunday; The Splendid Table; The Story; SymphonyCast; The Writer&apos;s Almanac</description>
	<body>
		Jump to Navigation Marketplace Latest Listen Morning Report Latest Listen Money Latest Listen Tech Report Latest Listen MID-DAY UPDATE Latest Listen 
 Home Business World Economy Tech Sustainability Your Money Wealth&amp;Poverty Shows 
 Donate 
 About Contact Register Sign in 
 Latest Stories Songs Podcasts Elections 2012 Health Care Law 
Search form
 Search 
 Marketplace.org 
 Life 
 
 
 3 
 
Wendy&apos;s testing breakfast menu
 Spencer Platt/Getty Images 
People eat in a Wendy&apos;s in New York City
 
To view this content, Javascript must be enabled and Adobe Flash Player must be installed.
 
 Subscribe to podcast Download audio Embed player Audio player assistance Pop-Up 
 Marketplace for Tuesday, October 5, 2010 
 Transcript 
 
TEXT OF STORY

 Kai Ryssdal: If you find yourself running late in the mornings and you want to grab a quick bite to eat on the way to work, you&apos;ve got no shortage of choices: Your local coffee shop or a donut place, or, of course, fast food. Sixty percent of that industry&apos;s growth the past five years has come from the morning rush. Notably absent -- up &apos;til now -- from the usual menu of Burger King and McDonald&apos;s, though -- has been Wendy&apos;s.

Peter O&apos;Dowd reports from KJZZ in Phoenix.
 
 Peter O&apos;Dowd: Karen Huff just cracked an egg over a griddle. It spreads out and sizzles while she sprinkles it with sea salt.
 
 Karen Huff: And then we&apos;re going to break the yolk and just kinda let the whites set up.
 
It&apos;s just after 8 o&apos;clock, and cracking an egg at this time is not terribly surprising until you learn that Huff is the manager of a fast food restaurant. No more liquid yolks out of a carton -- Wendy&apos;s has gone upscale.
 
 Ken Calwell: While there&apos;s a lot of people doing breakfast right now, there&apos;s not very many of them who are doing it well.
 
Count the folks at Wendy&apos;s among them, according to Ken Calwell, the company&apos;s chief marketing officer.
 
 Calwell: Wendy&apos;s has tested breakfast twice in our past in major efforts. Both of those failed.
 
Calwell says past efforts failed, because the food took too long to make. And it didn&apos;t taste good enough. This time around, they&apos;ll try a new menu with toasted egg sandwiches, paninis, smoked bacon and fresh orange juice. You can find those items right now in three test cities, including Phoenix. Calwell says all 6,300 Wendy&apos;s nationwide could offer the menu by the end of next year. But he says a big challenge will be convincing Wendy&apos;s owners to open early.
 
 Calwell: That&apos;s a cost to a franchisee, so what you have to show through your test market results is that the sales and profitability make it worth it.
 
Other chains have seen the value in breakfast. Subway has rolled out a morning menu. Even Taco Bell has jumped in with breakfast burritos. Morningstar Analyst Joscelyn MacKay says it&apos;s about time Wendy&apos;s made the move.
 
 Joscelyn MacKay: Being in the breakfast day part for any quick-service restaurant right now is going to be the key to driving your sales forward especially as we&apos;re still languishing in the doldrums of a weak economy.
 
Analysts estimate up to a quarter of all fast food sales come in the breakfast rush. MacKay says Wendy&apos;s will lag behind competitors like McDonald&apos;s if it cannot crack into that morning market.
 
 MacKay: To be successful in this arena, they need to have a very compelling offering. It needs to be different than what&apos;s already out there.
 
 Wendy&apos;s employee: Stir the chili please!
 
Back at the Wendy&apos;s drive-thru in Phoenix, there is some indication the new menu is resonating with customers like Ana Franco.
 
 Ana Franco: I really like it. It&apos;s really good.
 
 O&apos;Dowd: And what did you order today?
 
 Franco: The fire roasted burrito, and then just orange juice.
 
Franco gives the cashier about $4, a bit less than she typical spends on breakfast at Jack in the Box. Before she drives off to work, Franco says she&apos;ll be back later in the week, and that&apos;s exactly what Wendy&apos;s needs to hear.
 
 Wendy&apos;s cashier: There you go. Thank you. You have a good day.
 
 Franco: You too. Bye!
 
In Phoenix, I&apos;m Peter O&apos;Dowd for Marketplace.
 
 Google +1 
 Log in to post comments 3 Comments Janet Schmidt - Oct 22, 2010 
The Wendy&apos;s that serve breakfast need to publish their breakfast hours. Nothing on the signage or coupons. Your only clue is whether the breakfast menue or regular menu is showing at the drive-thru.
 
 Log in or register to post comments 
 Rick M - Oct 7, 2010 
Are the or aren&apos;t they? That&apos;s what I think when I drive by Wendy&apos;s in the morning. I think they will have a challenge communication which stores and where are open for breakfast.
 
 Log in or register to post comments 
 Eleanor thomas - Oct 6, 2010 
I heard the article about Fast Food joints selling, and hoping to make money on, breakfasts. The article mentioned a lady who had spent less than $4 on her breakfast at Wendy&apos;s. I wonder if you are ever going to consider doing a piece on how it is that Fast Food is so cheap - I am sure Marketplace would likely find it interesting to investigate the amount of money in government subsidies that goes to farmers of grain, agro business egg suppliers and meat suppliers, and how those subsidies artificially keep fast food and junk food prices low. We hear a lot about how junk food is making us a nation of obese and unhealthy people, but no-one ever talks about the hidden costs in monetary terms to the consumer who is paying twice for their ultra cheap Fast Food. Perhaps it might be interesting to look into how skewed our agriculture has become, where the subsidies are going and what the real cost of Fast Food would be if not for the subsidies. it would be interesting to compare the real cost of our&quot;cheap&quot;food with, say, organic locally grown produce. Thank you for listening to my suggestion.
 
 Log in or register to post comments 
 
 Latest Stories 
 
 
 PODCAST: A pet love hotel, a particle accelerator for your living room 
 
 NBC in talks to buy back Microsoft stake in MSNBC.com 
 
 British Army brought in to fill Olympic security gap 
 
 Weekly unemployment dip due to auto industry 
 
 Tax cuts, candidate wealth: What matters to voters? 
 
 View complete list » 
 Comments 
 
 
 Would an income tax hike hurt hiring? 
 12 
 Letters: Solving problems with the plastic 
 3 
 What is the cost of a House vote? 
 11 
 How TV news and ads affect Americans 
 1 
 Good economy, bad economy: Both candidates are right 
 10 
 View complete list » 
 You Might Also Like... 
 
Explore Stories that share this feature&apos;s tags
 Food 
 Pepsi is getting into the yogurt business Locavorism is not good for you Population growth: The problem of weight What do the dates on food mean? Popcorn subsidy up for debate in Farm Bill 
 View Complete List » 
Get it Here:
 
 Newsletters Mobile Apps Facebook Twitter Podcasts RSS 
 
 Home Shows Business Economy Elections Life Sustainability Tech Wealth&amp;Poverty World Your Money 
 
Marketplace Programs
 
 Marketplace Marketplace Morning Report Marketplace Money Marketplace Tech Report Marketplace Mid-Day Update ReMarket Podcast 
 
Special Sections
 
 Attitude Check BBC on Marketplace Commentary Corner Office Economy 4.0 Education Freakonomics Radio Health Care Euro Debt Crisis Food for 9 Billion 
 
Must Reads
 
 Easy Street The Big Book The Whiteboard 
 
AMERICAN PUBLIC MEDIA

261 S. Figueroa Street, Los Angeles, CA 90012

 
 © | Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy Programs 
 American RadioWorks American Routes On Being Composers Datebook Marketplace Marketplace Money Marketplace Morning Report Marketplace Tech Report Performance Today Pipedreams A Prairie Home Companion Saint Paul Sunday The Splendid Table The Story SymphonyCast The Writer&apos;s Almanac More… 
 Support American Public Media 
American Public Media&apos;s online services are supported by users like you. Contribute now… 
 More from American Public Media 
 APM Podcasts/RSS Feeds APM Newsletters iTunes U Public Radio Tuner APM Careers About APM
	</body>
</document>
