<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005623" url="http://www.yellowpages.com/cedar-rapids-ia/mip/burger-king-2995588" time="2012-07-12-22:11" support="3" score="0.0032266533877710222" bingtitle="Burger King Cedar Rapids, IA, 52404 - YP.com" webtitle="Burger King Cedar Rapids, IA, 52404 - YP.com">
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001402" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="84"/>
	<description>... personalized service I have ever had at a fast food restaurant. ... won&apos;t give you a bigger cup, sadly.We had our receipts ... that, out comes Diane into the lobby with our tray.</description>
	<body>
		Join
 
 Thanks! Click the link in the email sent to activate your account.
 
Check your email at Email Inbox to activate your account. No email? Check your spam/junk folder or Resend It» Resend It» 
 X 
 White Pages Mobile Apps Advertise with Us 
 
 Sign In Join Sign in with Facebook 

 Welcome, User 
 » My Profile » My Locations » My Reviews » My Photos » My Searches and Listings » My Deals 
 Sign Out 
   YP.com What are you looking for? near Where? Home&gt; Cedar Rapids Yellow Pages &gt; Fast Food Restaurants in Cedar Rapids, IA &gt;Burger King 
 Burger King 
 41.944152 -91.673449 3.5 stars 
 3 Ratings 1 Review 
 » 
 Do you love this place? 

Help others by recommending it!
 X Not Now 
 Thanks! 
 Now see what others are saying» 

 
 X 
 » Close 
 Quickly rate your faves! 

Just point at the stars and click. Simple.
 
stars

 1 stars 2 stars 3 stars 4 stars 5 stars 
 
Your Rating
 
 (319) 366-6918 

 395 33rd Ave SW, Cedar Rapids , IA 52404 

Near Southwest Area

 View Menu Visit Website 
 
 Save Email Send to phone Facebook Twitter 
 
Videos&amp;Photos

 Add a Photo 
 


 Be the first to add a photo» 
 
Business Details

 Edit info for this business 
 Hours: Not available Categories: Fast Food Restaurants, American Restaurants, Hamburgers&amp;Hot Dogs ,  Payment: AMEX, DISCOVER, MASTER CARD, VISA Neighborhoods: Southwest Area 
General Info

Since its Florida beginnings more than 45 years ago when a Burger King hamburger cost 18¢ and a WHOPPER sandwich cost 37¢, Burger King Corporation has established restaurants around the world -- from Australia to Venezuela. By 1967, when the Company was acquired by the Minneapolis-based Pillsbury Company, 8,000 employees were working in 274 different restaurant locations. Today, there are more than 361,000 Burger King employees in more than 11,340 locations worldwide.

 ...read more 
 
Reviews&amp;Recommendations

 Write a Review 
 3.5 stars 
3 Ratings
 
stars
 
Your Rating
 
0 recommendations
 
 
 


 

 See all recommendations» 
 
 
 5 stars 

 Patty E. 07/27/2006

Personalized Above and Beyond Fast Food Service at Burger King!

Provided by Judy&apos;s Book 

I went to Burger King on 33rd Avenue SW in Cedar Rapids this morning with my oldest daughter, a friend, and her daughter.We had the ABSOLUTE BEST personalized service I have ever had at a fast food restaurant. The woman that helped us was TERRIFIC! Her name is Diane. She greeted us with a great smile. She then took our order and was very patient while the kids decided what they wanted. She gave us cups for ice water and I asked for a medium size cup and she said sure and gave it to me, still with that great smile. Some restaurants around here won&apos;t give you a bigger cup, sadly.We had our receipts and headed to a booth to set our purses and drinks down, and get the kids settled in. While we were doing that, out comes Diane into the lobby with our tray. She brought it to our table. We asked for sugar, and I followed her up to the counter, she gave me the sugar and only found one spoon and I said that is fine. Little did I know a minute later here comes Diane, she found another spoon to stir our coffees. My friends daughter told her mom she didn&apos;t want juice she wanted chocolate milk, and Diane overheard that when she dropped off the spoon. Not long after Diane is at our table with a chocolate milk, much to the little girl&apos;s delight! About halfway through our breakfast, Diane was wiping off tables and came by us and asked if everything was okay. MOST DEFINITELY! On our way out, I asked Diane her name, and I spoke with her manager and told him how VERY IMPRESSED I was with Diane. You know I don&apos;t think that smile came off of Diane even once! I have NEVER had such excellent, above and beyond service at a fast food restaurant. You know, I don&apos;t even think I have had such friendly service at normal sit down restaurants.Diane deserves a raise in my book. So, if you happen to be in Cedar Rapids , I HIGHLY recommend checking out this Burger King . And if you see Diane, tell her &apos;Hi&apos;.

 Was this helpful? Yes No Respond Flag abuse 
 
 
 YP Mobile Page for Burger King, Cedar Rapids, IA
 » Map&amp;Directions Paid Advertisement 
About

 About YP.com Contact Us Advertise with Us Careers Legal | Terms of Service and Use Privacy Policy Small Business Advertising Advertising Choices 
 
Site Directory

 Home Find a Business Maps&amp;Directions Find a Person White Pages Mobile Apps Reverse Phone Lookup Site Map Mobile YP 
 
City Guides More Cities » 

 Atlanta Austin Baltimore Boston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver 

 Detroit Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Memphis 

 Miami Milwaukee New York Oklahoma City Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Saint Louis 
 
AT&amp;T Family

 AT&amp;T AT&amp;T Wireless AnyWho Ingenio Yellow Pages Keen 
 
 Find Us on Facebook 

©2012 YP Intellectual Property LLC. All rights reserved.
YP, the YP logo and all other YP marks contained herein are trademarks of YP Intellectual Property LLC and/or YP affiliated companies.
AT&amp;T, the AT&amp;T Logo and all AT&amp;T related marks are trademarks of AT&amp;T Inc. or AT&amp;T affiliated companies.
All other marks contained herein are the property of their respective owners.
 Submit
	</body>
</document>
