<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005184" url="http://www.tampabay.com/SearchForwardServlet.do?articleId=1007104" time="2012-07-12-21:43" support="4" score="0.004009032417478159" bingtitle="Joe Redner plunges into the pizza business - Tampa Bay Times" webtitle="Joe Redner plunges into the pizza business - Tampa Bay Times">
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>... ordinary fast-food restaurant building. It has dark red tile floors to hide stains, easy-to-wipe square tables and a front counter ... of chain stores ... ll ever leave ...</description>
	<body>
		Today&apos;s paper | eEdition | Subscribe The Truth-O-Meter Latest print edition 
 Home News 
 Hernando Hillsborough Pasco Pinellas St. Pete Times Stand Your Ground Education Obituaries Health Here&apos;s the Deal Hurricane Guide Video 
 Politics 
 Top Politics News RNC 2012 Elections PolitiFact.com The Buzz Bay Buzz 
 Opinion Sports 
 Top Sports News Sports Stats Rays Lightning Buccaneers Storm Tampa Bay Rowdies High School USF Bulls UF Gators FSU Seminoles Golf Auto Racing Outdoors 
 Things to Do 
 Neighborhoods Kids Food&amp;Dining Events Deals&amp;Shopping Life Times Florida Travel Date Night Movies 
 Money 
 Top Business News Top Places To Work Local Stocks 
 Features 
 Top Features Entertainment News Whoa, Momma! Deal Divas TV Listings Games&amp;Comics 
 Blogs 
 All Eyes (photos) Bay Buzz Bizarre Florida Breaking News Bucs Beat The Buzz Deal Divas Let&apos;s Talk Gadgets&amp;Gizmos The Gradebook The Heater (Rays) Help Wanted High School Sports The Juice Lightning Strikes Pop Life The Feed (TV) Stuck in the &apos;80s USF Bulls Venture (Business) More 
 Weather Traffic Site map 
 
 Classifieds 
 Classifieds Place an Ad 
 BooCoo Auctions Press Releases 
 Submit Press Releases Read Press Releases 
 Jobs 
 Place an Ad Search for Jobs Post a Resume Top Workplaces 
 Real Estate 
 For Sale, Rentals Agent Directory Open House Map Rentals Map New Homes Place an Ad 
 Cars 
 Find New and Used Cars Place an Ad Research ATVs, Go-Carts, Mopeds Parts&amp;Service RVs, Motor Homes, Campers Motorcycles Repair Estimator 
 Shop 
 Deals! Shop Local Special Sections Classifieds BooCoo Auctions 
 Advertise 
 Market Info Media Kit Classified Ads Employers Real Estate BooCoo Auctions More Info 
 
 
 Search Site   Web   Archives - back to 1987 Google Newspaper Archive - back to 1901 
 Top shares 
 Brooksville man among six Americans killed in blast in Afghanistan Tampa soldier dies in Afghanistan attack that claimed 6 MLB commissioner Bud Selig calls Tampa Bay Rays&apos; attendance &apos;inexcusable,&apos; &apos;disappointing&apos; Two teens arrested in connection with mysterious St. Petersburg death FCAT farce just gets worse 
 Most commented 
 MLB commissioner Bud Selig calls Tampa Bay Rays&apos; attendance &apos;inexcusable,&apos; &apos;disappointing&apos; Teen who fell into gap in new John&apos;s Pass Bridge is suing Republicans attack President Barack Obama for Hugo Chávez remark First lady Michelle Obama rallies supporters on campaign stops in Florida Faculty survey shows fear, discontent at Hudson Middle School 
 Business: Retail 
 Horizon Bay Memory Care to open, Salon di Lola strives for Hollywood glam Tampa designers make mark with cool Black&amp;Denim clothing line made in USA 
 
 Joe Redner plunges into the pizza business 

By Justin George , Times Staff Writer
 Justin George Tampa Bay Times In Print: Thursday, June 4, 2009
 
 Bobby Hart, 21, tosses pizza dough Tuesday at Not Your Average Joe’s, next to the Mons Venus on N Dale Mabry Highway. Owner Joe Redner puts exotic toppings near exotic dancing. [WILLIE J. ALLEN JR. | Times] 

 ADVERTISEMENT
 ADVERTISEMENT
 
 Story Tools Print this story Purchase reprints Contact the editor Email Newsletters 
 
 
TAMPA—It is an ordinary fast-food restaurant building. It has dark red tile floors to hide stains, easy-to-wipe square tables and a front counter that could serve tacos as easily as it could burgers.

The small building at 2038 N Dale Mabry Highway along a strip of chain stores, restaurants and strip bars, opened last week serving pizza.

Looks pretty plain Jane.

Except by name:&quot;Not Your Average Joe&apos;s Pizza.&quot;

And the Joe behind it all isn&apos;t an everyman like Joe Six Pack or Joe the Plumber.

This pizza parlor proprietor is Joe Redner, Tampa&apos;s strip club king, the owner of the nationally renowned Mons Venus.

&quot;What we&apos;re really trying to do is give out a superior product like the Mons does,&quot;he said.

Redner, who also owns a gym, a film lighting company, a brewery and real estate, owns the fast-food building, which is next to the Mons and once housed Taco Bell and a Cuban eatery.

When that closed, he batted around opening his own restaurant with his grandson, Kyle Burns, 19.

Burns, a Hillsborough Community College student, wanted to run it. His friend Alex Urrutia, 20, a former sous chef who finished all but three classes for a culinary degree at Johnson&amp;Wales University in Miami, offered to help.

Shannon Adams, 31, a longtime Mons dancer who had also taken culinary classes, wanted in, too.

Redner now had three managers to run an establishment that would stay open until at least 1 a.m. serving suits, blue collars and the late-night lap dance crowd. They came up with pizza.

&quot;Simple and cheap and we have the drive-through,&quot;Adams said.

They know the pizza market is crowded, but they aim for a niche in the middle, offering upscale toppings and gourmet combinations at prices between $10.99 and $15.99 a pizza. They also serve slices.

The menu includes pizzas with tzatziki sauce, cucumbers and feta as well as pies with ricotta cheese, capicola and taco-seasoned beef. The hope is to add more distinctive Tampa ingredients such as ropa v ieja, or shredded beef, as time passes.

Competitors such as 24-year-old Sally O&apos;Neals gourmet pizza in Hyde Park think this isn&apos;t the best time to open up a pizza restaurant.

&quot;If you don&apos;t already have your clientele established, it&apos;s going to be tough for you,&quot;manager Frank Simms said.&quot;If you don&apos;t have a name, you won&apos;t make it.&quot;

If Not Your Average Joe&apos;s has anything going for it early on, it is its name, which is being flashed on the Mons Venus electric sign board along Dale Mabry.

The Joe&apos;s restaurateurs concentrate on consistency and quality. They believe in their imported ingredients and say they spend time making their pizzas visually appealing.&quot;You taste with your eyes first,&quot;Urrutia said.

Redner, a vegan for more than 10 years, cannot taste the pizzas but has told his managers how much looks count.

Adams knows this. She continues to strip at the Mons Venus when she&apos;s not managing Not Your Average Joe&apos;s.

&quot;I don&apos;t know when I&apos;ll ever leave the Mons,&quot;Adams said.&quot;If I ever get too fat or too old, you let me know.&quot;

 Justin George can be reached at (813) 226-3368 or jgeorge@sptimes.com. 

 [Last modified: Jun 03, 2009 10:55 PM] 

 tampa Copyright 2009 Tampa Bay Times 

 

 Join the discussion: Click to view comments, add yours Loading... Subscribe to the Times Click here for convenient home delivery. Want More Breaking News? ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
©2012·All Rights Reserved·Tampa Bay Times · 
490 First Avenue South•St. Petersburg, FL 33701•727-893-8111
 Contact Us | Join Us | Advertise with Us | Subscribe to the Tampa Bay Times | RSS 
 Privacy Policy | Standard of Accuracy | Terms, Conditions&amp;Copyright
	</body>
</document>
