<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005730" url="http://greekfoodcolumbus.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:21" support="1" score="0.00025434312908188356" bingtitle="GreekFoodBlog" webtitle="GreekFoodBlog">
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>The restaurant seats about 38 people comfortably ... supportive and appreciative to be able to give ... in Columbus, OH looks like any other small fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		GreekFoodBlog 
 Just another WordPress.com weblog 
 Home Yanni’s blog 
   
 King Gyros Greek Restaurant Celebrates 19th Anniversary and being Sponsor of Columbus Crew 
 July 7, 2010 
 
Columbus, Ohio–(July 6th, 2010)– King Gyros Greek Restaurant , which was awarded Citysearch’s Best Mediterranean Restaurant in Columbus, is celebrating its 19th year in business at its one, unique location in Whitehall.  Yanni Chalkias, owner and manager of King Gyros Greek Restaurant, first opened King Gyros in 1991, and his business has been growing ever since.  This couldn’t be more evident by the massive menu found both inside King Gyros and at the Drive-thru. 

“I know the menu is pretty large, but I want to make sure I have something for everyone”, said Chalkias, owner of King Gyros.  “Even though most people come here for the gyros and Greek entrees, there are people who just want a sub or a burger, and I want to please them just as much as the Greek lovers.”

With such an extensive variety of food, believe it or not, there are many more delectable Greek dishes that aren’t included on the King Gyros menu, and some of them are the most delicious items in the restaurant.  For starters, there is the Greek Salmon dinner which easily rivals salmon entrees found at up-scale restaurants, in addition to a Greek Salmon salad, and it doesn’t stop there.  King Gyros also has Greek Pasta Salad, a Smelt Dinner, a Penne Pasta with Greek Style Meat Sauce, a Lamb Chops Dinner, numerous combo meals (for $9 or less), and Yanni recently added a Lamb Ribs Dinner, which can’t be found at any other restaurant in Central Ohio.  The ribs are specially prepared only for King Gyros, and they have received rave reviews by local Columbus publications.

 Adding to the celebration of the 19th Anniversary, King Gyros recently became a sponsor of the Columbus Crew by providing meals to the team members and coaches the day before their home games.  “I was thrilled when the Crew approached me about being a sponsor”, said Chalkias.  “It’s a great privilege to be able to feed the home team before their games.”

For more information on King Gyros Greek Restaurant and their 19th Anniversary, please visit them at http://www.kinggyros.com/ .  You can also become a fan of King Gyros Greek Restaurant by finding them on Facebook or follow them on Twitter at @KingGyrosGreek. 

 #  #  # 

 About King Gyros Greek Restaurant : King Gyros Greek Restaurant is an authentic eatery that was established in 1991 in Whitehall, Ohio.  The restaurant is 100% Greek owned and offers a variety of classic Greek dishes.  King Gyros’ menu boasts a wide selection, including spinach pie, hummus, mousaka, stuffed grape leaves, baklava, a variety of traditional and specialty gyros, and most of the dishes do not exceed $9. The restaurant seats about 38 people comfortably and they also have a drive-thru and provide take-out orders, in addition to catering. 

 
– 

 R&amp;S Marketing Consultants 

 Phone: 614-946-7710 

 Email: RandSconsultants@gmail.com 

 www.RandSconsultants.net 

 Twitter: RandSmarketing 
 
 Leave a Comment» | Anniversary | Tagged: columbus authentic greek food , columbus catering , columbus fast casual , columbus greek catering , columbus greek food , columbus greek restaurant , gyro columbus , gyros columbus , king gyros columbus , king gyros greek restaurant , king gyros whitehall , whitehall catering , whitehall greek food | Permalink 
 Posted by gyros2nv
 
 Haiti Relief Fundraiser From King Gyros Greek Restaurant in Columbus, OH 
 February 27, 2010 
 
Yianni and his staff at King Gyros Greek Restaurant in Columbus, OH wanted to contribute to the cause of earthquake relief in Haiti in big way. They all decided to open for a relief event on a Sunday, when King Gyros is usually closed. After discussing it, they decided to open on Sunday, February 21st, and call that day“Gyros for Haiti”. The staff volunteered their time between 12 pm and 6pm and Yianni donated all of the food on behalf of King Gyros.

There were many preparations for that day. First, daily customers and friends were told from two weeks ahead about the fundraiser. Yianni and his staff passed out fliers to everyone visiting for Eat-in, Take-out, or to people going through the Drive-thru. Everyone also visited libraries, schools, and public areas locally to let them know about this event. All of King Gyros’fans were notified and asked to RSVP on Facebook at King Gyros Greek Restaurant, on twitter with KingGyrosGreek, and an email was sent to everyone who is a member or part of the Greek Club.

Finally, it was the day of the event. King Gyros opened from 12 PM to 6 PM to serve and people were lined up right off the bat to get their gyros and donate to the cause. The restaurant stayed busy for most of the day. People were very, very supportive and appreciative to be able to give help for Haiti this way.“We are glad and honored to be able to help the people of Haiti in any way, and this was our way of being able to give to them and help in their time of need”, Yianni said. When giving their money, there were many charities to chose from but the one that clearly stood out to Yianni and his staff at King Gyros was the Lifeline Christian Mission.
	</body>
</document>
