<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005112" url="http://alis.alberta.ca/occinfo/Content/RequestAction.asp?aspAction=GetHTMLProfile&amp;format=html&amp;OCCPRO_ID=71002921" time="2012-07-12-21:39" support="1" score="0.0025230892518544796" bingtitle="OCCinfo - Food and Beverage Server - ALIS - Home" webtitle="OCCinfo - Food and Beverage Server">
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="10"/>
	<description>Food and beverage servers accept and serve customers&apos; food and beverage orders in restaurants and bars.</description>
	<body>
		Food and Beverage Server
 

 
Food and beverage servers accept and serve customers&apos; food and beverage orders in restaurants and bars.
 

 Also Known As: Server, Waiter/Waitress NOC Number(s): 6453 Minimum Education: Education/training requirements vary Employment Outlook: Job openings: turnover plus new jobs due to above average growth in occupation in Alberta 2011-2015 Interests: M S o 

 Duties | Working Conditions | Personal Characteristics | Education | Employment | Salary | Other Information | Related Occupations | Related School Subjects | Related Field of Study 


 Duties 
Food and beverage servers&apos; duties vary considerably from one type of establishment to another. In fast food outlets, they often work behind counters and use computerized systems to take orders and tabulate bills. In coffee shops and cocktail lounges, they provide quick and efficient service for customers seated at tables. In formal dining establishments, they carefully observe established rules of service and etiquette, and pace the meal according to customer preference. In general, however, food and beverage servers:

 prepare tables or counters for meals stock the service area with supplies (for example, coffee, glassware) greet customers, present menus and help customers select menu items inform customers about daily specials record orders and place them with the kitchen and bar pick up and serve orders check that customers are enjoying their meals and correct any problems suggest and serve desserts and beverages clean and reset tables tabulate and present bills for payment. 
 


 Working Conditions 
Working conditions for food and beverage servers vary from one type of food and beverage establishment to another. Servers may be required to lift items weighing up to 10 kilograms.

Shift work and split shifts built around normal meal times are common in the food service industry. At busy times, food and beverage servers are constantly on their feet and under pressure to serve customers quickly. They take their own meal breaks between busy meal serving times.
 


 Personal Characteristics 
Food and beverage servers need the following characteristics:

 the ability to serve customers cheerfully, courteously and efficiently good organization and multi-tasking skills good health good grooming the ability to work as part of a team the ability to work with little supervision good verbal communication skills and sensitivity to customer needs the ability to work calmly under pressure. 

Other requirements depend on the environment in which the server works. For example, serving in a coffee shop or cocktail lounge requires the ability to remember many orders and move very quickly.

Food and beverage servers should enjoy having clear rules and organized methods, working with people, and working with tools and equipment.
 


 Educational Requirements 
There are no standard education or training requirements for food and beverage servers. However, server intervention training, food safety training and food allergy training are definite assets when looking for employment.

Food and beverage servers who serve liquor must be at least 18 years of age. In formal dining rooms, food and beverage servers also must:

 know proper food service etiquette use the correct terminology and be able to answer questions about wines and other beverages be able to prepare tableside dishes (for example, flambe) at the customer&apos;s table if required. 

Many food and beverage servers start as food service helpers or kitchen helpers and develop the necessary skills and knowledge by observing more experienced workers and taking short courses (for example, server intervention and food safety courses). Some employers use self-instructional programs to teach new employees food preparation and service skills.

 ProServe Liquor Staff Training  is a provincial government training program designed to ensure liquor service and sales activities are conducted with integrity and in a socially responsible manner. ProServe is available online, as a self-directed home study using a video and a manual, or by seminar. By January 1, 2010, all staff involved in the sale and service of liquor in licensed premises will be required to have completed ProServe.

In Alberta, food safety courses are offered by:

 post-secondary institutions ( NAIT , SAIT , Red Deer College , Lethbridge College ) Alberta Health Services E-Campus Alberta (online learning from NAIT) the First Nations Inuit Health Branch of Health Canada industry associations such as the Canadian Council of Grocery Distributors , Canadian Restaurant and Foodservices Association , and United States National Restaurant Association private vocational schools and independent trainers. 

Contact the Surveillance and Environmental Health Branch of Alberta Health at (780) 427-4518 for a listing of approved food safety training options.

Alberta Health awards a Food Sanitation and Hygiene Certification to those who complete approved training and achieve at least 70 per cent on a provincial exam. Where six or more people are working on site, at least one person present must be certified. Where fewer people are employed, at least one person in the organization must be certified.

The Alberta Hotel and Lodging Association offers emerit certification, seminars and resources. Emerit certification is recognized throughout the tourism and hospitality industry in Canada.

Continuing education programs may be offered on an as needed basis by post-secondary institutions that offer hospitality-related programs. For more information, see the Restaurant Manager occupational profile.
 Section revised May 2012 


 Employment and Advancement 
Food and beverage servers are employed in restaurants, coffee shops, bars, clubs, hotels and other retail eating and drinking establishments. There are more part-time positions in this occupation than there are in most occupations, and most food and beverage servers are young.

Experienced food and beverage servers can move to better paying jobs in larger and more formal food establishments. They may advance to lead hand positions (for example, captain or head waiter/waitress, maitre d&apos; hotel) or other supervisory positions. Although some larger organizations provide management training programs or training on the job for dependable workers who have leadership ability, related post-secondary education and emerit certification are definite assets for advancement.

In Alberta, 95 per cent of people employed as food and beverage servers work in the Accommodation and Food Services  industry.

The employment outlook in this occupation will be influenced by a wide variety of factors including:

 trends and events affecting overall employment (especially in the Accommodation and Food Services industry) location in Alberta employment turnover  (work opportunities generated by people leaving existing positions) occupational growth (work opportunities resulting from the creation of new positions that never existed before) size of the occupation. 

Over 21,500 Albertans are employed in the Food and Beverage Servers occupational group which is expected to have an annual above average growth of 3.5 per cent from 2011 to 2015 in Alberta. It is forecasted that about 753 new positions will be created each year in addition to job openings created by employment turnover.

There is a relatively high employment turnover rate (particularly in lower priced restaurants) so job openings occur quite frequently. However, competition is keen for positions that offer the opportunity to earn more money in tips.
 Section revised November 2011 


 Salary 
Food and beverage servers often are paid just above minimum wage plus tips . (As of September 1, 2011, the minimum wage in Alberta increased to $9.40 per hour.) Servers&apos; incomes from tips are generally higher during peak periods such as summer or holiday seasons than they are in January and February. In many restaurants, food and beverage servers contribute a portion of their tips to a tip pool which is distributed among all servers, food service helpers, hosts/hostesses and bartenders.

Servers who provide superior customer service, particularly in restaurants where meal prices are higher, generally earn most of their income from tips.

According to the 2011 Alberta Wage and Salary Survey , Albertans in the Food and Beverage Servers occupational group earned on average from $9.27 to $10.89 an hour. The mean wage for this group was $9.75 an hour.

For more detailed information, see WAGEinfo .
 Section revised February 2012 


 Other Sources of Information 
Post-secondary institution calendars and websites (see Educational Requirements above)

EDinfo website: www.alis.alberta.ca/edinfo 

Alberta Hotel and Lodging Association website: www.ahla.ca 

Canadian Association of Foodservice Professionals website: www.cafp.com 

Canadian Tourism Human Resource Council website: www.cthrc.ca 

emerit website: www.emerit.ca 

National Restaurant Association website: www.restaurant.org 

ProServe Liquor Staff Training website: www.proserve.aglc.ca 
 


 Related Occupational Profiles Bartender Casino Dealer Flight Attendant Food and Beverage Service Supervisor In Formal Dining Rooms Food Service Helper Kitchen Helper and Food Assembler 


 Related High School Subjects Community Health; Foods; Language Arts; Mathematics; Physical Education; and Tourism Studies 


 Related Post-Secondary Field of Study Personal and Food Services 

 
 Produced May 2009 Top of Profile 

 
For more information on career planning, occupations and educational programs, visit the Alberta Learning Information Service (ALIS) website at alis.alberta.ca , call the Alberta Career Information Hotline toll-free at 1-800-661-3753 or 780-422-4266 in Edmonton or visit an Alberta Works Centre near you. 

The information contained in this profile was current as of the dates shown. Salaries, employment outlook and educational programs may change. Please check the information before making any career decisions.
 

 
Government of Alberta, Human Services
	</body>
</document>
