<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005930" url="http://www.trulia.com/property/3075924115-5-Lennys-Way-West-Springfield-MA-01089" time="2012-07-12-22:35" support="2" score="0.004276045069110115" bingtitle="5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA | MLS# 71335935 - Trulia" webtitle="5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA - Trulia">
			<query id="000513" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000530" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>Formal dining room w/ tray ceiling. Fst floor bdrm or ... List view Table view ... Communities near 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield | MLS ...</description>
	<body>
		Homes ▼
 Homes Rentals Local Info Advice Professionals Mortgages Advanced Search 
 Buy 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Rent 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Advice 
 California Q&amp;A California Blogs California Advice Q&amp;A Advice Blogs Guides Ask a Question Write a Blog Post 
 Mortgage 
 Home Loans Mortgage Refinance Mortgage Trends Mortgage Advice Mortgage Calculators 
 Local Info 
 Local Home Foreclosure Center Directory 
 Find a Pro 
 Real Estate Agents Brokers Mortgage Brokers or Lenders Builders/Developers Property Managers 
 
 Help Log in Sign up 
 
 Trulia Mobile For Professionals 
It looks like Javascript is disabled in your browser.
 Trulia requires Javascript to be enabled in order to use our site.
 Please follow these instructions to enable Javascript. 
 for sale resale $475,000 
5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA 01089
 Gracious custom built five bedroom colonial plus addt&apos;l 1900+/-sq ft fin bsmnt. Open floor plan features kitchen with granite counters, cherry cabinets, center island, pantry, stainless steel appliances,eat-in area-opens to magnificent family room. Formal dining room w/ tray ceiling. Fst floor bdrm or office with full bath and laundry room. Elegant master bedroom and mster bath w/ jacuzzi, dble vanity, walk in closet, dressing area and built-ins. Fin basmnt w/ game room and full bath. New Deck. housing 42.116653 -72.657425 Home Facts Photos 25 Map&amp;Nearby Mortgage Comparables Sales Trends Schools 
 Photos of 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA 
 View large photos (25) Watch virtual tour 
 
 
 Price: $475,000   •Mortgage payments •Rent vs Buy Est. payment: $2,312 /mo Your Credit Score Bedrooms: 5 151 days on Trulia Bathrooms: 4 474 people have viewed Property type: Single-Family Home Size: 3,472 sqft Lot: 0.84 acres Price/sqft: $137 /sqft Year built: 2004 MLS/ID: 71335935 Zip: 01089 Provided by: newenglandmoves.com This info was not provided by this listing source. Ask an agent for more details about this home. Listing agent: Lori Cotter Broker: Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage 
 Contact agent Follow home Share 
 Send email Share on Facebook 
 Check your credit Report error Get Prequalified More 
 Print this page Ask a question Write a note Report an error 
 Gracious custom built five bedroom colonial plus addt&apos;l 1900+/-sq ft fin bsmnt . Open floor plan features kitchen with granite counters, cherry cabinets, center island, pantry, stainless steel appliances,eat-in area-opens to magnificent family room. Formal dining room w/ tray ceiling. Fst floor bdrm or office with full bath and laundry room. Elegant master bedroom and mster bath w/ jacuzzi, dble vanity, walk in closet, dressing area and built-ins. Fin basmnt w/ game room and full bath. New Deck. Write a personal note about this listing 
My Notes
 Edit  |  Clear List view Table view 
Listing Info for 5 Lennys Way 
 Most recent information provided by newenglandmoves.com on 07/12/2012 04:32 AM: 
 Price: $475,000 Status: For Sale MLS/Source ID: 71335935 5 Bedrooms 4 Bathrooms 3,472 sqft Single-Family Home Built In 2004 Lot Size: 0.84 acres Fireplace Style: Colonial Deck Patio Sprinkler System Garage 
 
Public Records for 5 Lennys Way 
 Official property, sales, and tax information from county (public) records as of 09/2011: 
 Single Family Residential 4 Bedrooms 2 Bathrooms 1 Partial Bathroom 3,076 sqft Lot Size: 0.84 acres Built In 2004 Stories: 2 story A/C Heating: Forced air unit Exterior Walls: Siding (Alum/Vinyl) Roof: Asphalt 9 Rooms 1 Building Style: Colonial County: Hampden 
 
Property Taxes for 5 Lennys Way 
 
 Year Value Land   Improvements   Total Tax 2011 Assessed $139,800 + $294,300 = $434,100 $7,258   
 Source: Public Records This property may be overassessed. Find Out Now» 
Price History for 5 Lennys Way 
 Alert 
 Date Event Price Source 11/22/2004 Sold view details $445,000 Public records Public records   Recording Date 11/22/2004   Sale Price $445,000   Price Type Full amount stated on Document.   Transaction Type Purchase/Resale Arm&apos;s Length Residential Transaction   Document Type Deed 
 
Location Information near 5 Lennys Way 
 
 Comparables Schools Estimates Crimes Amenities Transit 
 Comparables Estimates Schools Crimes Amenities Transit $1,099,500 4 br / 2 ba Single-Family Home OPEN HOUSE Sun Oct 16, 2pm to 4pm West Springfield local info 
 Sold Homes near 5 Lennys Way 
 
 Address Distance Property Type Sold price Sold date Bed Bath Sqft 56 Trotters Walk, West Springfield MA 0.61 mi Single-Family Home $430,000 3/01/12 4 2½ 2,696 64 Appaloosa Ln, West Springfield MA 1.06 mi Single-Family Home $480,000 10/20/11 4 4½ 2,472 85 Therese Marie Ln, West Springfield MA 1.08 mi Single-Family Home $600,000 1/06/12 4 4½ 4,449 82 Devon Ter, Westfield MA 2.65 mi Single-Family Home $350,000 12/16/11 4 2½ 2,080 19 Rachael Ter, Westfield MA 2.72 mi Single-Family Home $395,000 11/28/11 4 2½ 2,780 
 View all homes similar to 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA» 
 Elementary Schools Middle Schools High Schools Type GreatSchools Rating Distance Nearby Schools No public schools where found for this property and grade level. John Fausey Elementary School View Homes Public 7 0.6 mi Tatham Elementary School View Homes Public 7 1.0 mi Mittineague Elementary School View Homes Public 4 1.3 mi Phillip Coburn School View Homes Public 4 1.9 mi Robinson Park Elementary School View Homes Public 8 2.0 mi West Springfield Middle School View Homes Public 5 0.8 mi Chestnut Accelerated Middle School View Homes Public 1 2.3 mi Roberta G Doering School View Homes Public 5 2.6 mi Agawam Junior High School View Homes Public 5 3.5 mi Mcmahon Elementary School View Homes Public 2 4.7 mi West Springfield High School View Homes Public 4 0.9 mi Agawam Senior High School View Homes Public 7 3.0 mi Safe - Recovery School View Homes Public - 3.5 mi William J Dean Tech High School View Homes Public 1 4.5 mi Safe Early College High School View Homes Public - 5.4 mi Private Schools No private schools where found for this property and grade level. Iqra Academy View Homes Private - 0.7 mi St Thomas The Apostle School View Homes Catholic - 1.1 mi Holy Name Elementary School View Homes Catholic - 3.3 mi St Stanislaus School View Homes Catholic - 3.8 mi Academy Hill School View Homes Private - 3.8 mi Iqra Academy View Homes Private - 0.7 mi St Thomas The Apostle School View Homes Catholic - 1.1 mi Holy Name Elementary School View Homes Catholic - 3.3 mi St Stanislaus School View Homes Catholic - 3.8 mi Academy Hill School View Homes Private - 3.8 mi Iqra Academy View Homes Private - 0.7 mi Holyoke Catholic High School View Homes Catholic - 3.3 mi Cathedral High School View Homes Catholic - 6.0 mi Pioneer Valley Chrn School View Homes Private - 7.2 mi Suffield Academy View Homes Private - 9.1 mi 
 indicates schools assigned
 to this home. School data provided by OnBoard Informatics.
 Boundaries provided by Maponics. 
Home Estimates near 5 Lennys Way 
 Loading data 
Individual Crimes near 5 Lennys Way 
 Loading data 
Nearby Restaurants, Banks, and Grocery Stores
 Loading data 
Transit Stops near 5 Lennys Way 
 Loading data 
Price Comparison of 5 Lennys Way 
 This Home $475,000 VS Sold Price Price/Sqft Zip 01089 $154,000 West Springfield $154,000 10yr 5yr 1yr 
Real Estate Trends in 01089 
 
 Sale price for 5 Lennys Way $475,000   Average listing price for similar homes $453,211 5% below sale price Median sale price for similar homes $414,500 13% below sale price Average listing price for all homes in 01089 $227,947 52% below sale price Median sale price for all homes in 01089 $154,000 68% below sale price 
 View more Sales Trends for 01089 » 
What Trulia users think of this area
 Overall area rating: 

 Excellent We need more ratings to calculate an average. Top rated categories: 

 Parks&amp;Recreation 

 Schools 

 Walkability 

 Safety We need more ratings to calculate top categories. Total ratings: 307 | View all ratings Last updated 13 hours ago Rate this area: Rate it Rate these categories: 
 Safety Rate it Pet-friendly Rate it Walkability Rate it Restaurants&amp;Shopping Rate it 
 Rate and Review Read 3 reviews » 
Contact Info for 5 Lennys Way 
 
 Agent: Lori Cotter (413) 348-9259 Broker: Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage Listing website 
 Inquire about this property Name : Email : Phone : Message : I was searching on Trulia and found this listing. Please send me more information about 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA 01089. Thank you. Contact the agent 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 «See similar homes Prev Next Request more information Lori Cotter Tel: (413) 348-9259 Real Estate Agent Single-Family Home 01089 5 Lennys Way West Springfield,MA Coldwell Banker Residential Brokerage Name : Email : Phone : Message : I was searching on Trulia and found this listing. Please send me more information about 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA 01089. Thank you. Contact the agent 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Homes you might like... Alert 
 237 Bear Hole Rd, West Springfield MA 20 photos 
 $397,500 

5 br / 

3,000 sqft

Unspecified
 254 Rogers Ave, West Springfield MA 30 photos 
 $495,900 

5 br / 3 full, 3 partial ba

4,014 sqft

Single-Family Home
 8 Bretton Rd, West Springfield MA 25 photos 
 $369,900 

5 br / 3 full, 1 partial ba

4,044 sqft

Single-Family Home
 102 Harbey Rd, West Springfield MA 20 photos 
 $308,900 

4 br / 2 full, 1 partial ba

2,576 sqft

Single-Family Home
 126 High Meadow Dr, West Springfield MA 30 photos 
 $539,900 

4 br / 3 ba

4,300 sqft

Single-Family Home
 
 View all homes near 5 Lennys Way» 168b41168690b0188ea36707b5acdfeb Sponsored Resource Center Buying a Home? Check your Credit Score today for - $0 This property may be overpaying their property taxes. Check For Free Discussions in West Springfield, MA 232 followers 1 recent questions Ask Question Recent Activity What about drug crimes??? none at all?? 2 answers Getting a loan when self employed 3 answers Is this property still available? Answer first Is it a good idea to go to the Chicopee City Hall to verify if there are any liens on a property before one signs a sales agreement? 2 answers I&apos;ve owned a duplex for the last yr and a half with a Farmers Home loan. And I&apos;m looking to purchase a 2nd duplex. 2 answers My Husband&apos;s Middle Credit Score is 630.. He Makes About 45-50k a year.. We do not have Much saved due to high Rent ect.. Are we able to purchase? 4 answers My fiancé has good credit, mine is poor. We make /- 32k a year each. Is there a mortgage for us? 8 answers View 1 recent question More local advice More Advice: 
 Recent Q&amp;A in West Springfield, MA Recent blog posts in West Springfield, MA Find a real estate professional West Springfield, MA 
 
 Send this property to a friend 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA $475,000 5 br , 4 ba , Single-Family Home Friend&apos;s email: [+] Add another friend&apos;s email Your email: Your name:
 (optional) Message:
 (optional) Cancel Send 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Done       

 My Notes Done Save a personal note that only you can view. Clear Save my note       

 Report Listing Error 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA Error Type: Please select... Property Sold/Withdrawn Price has changed Incorrect Agent/Broker Link Doesn&apos;t Work Incorrect Photo Incorrect Property Details Incorrect Map Other   Current Revised Price: $475,000 $ Property Type: Single-Family Home Select One Single-Family Home Condo Townhouse Coop Apartment Loft TIC Apartment/Condo/Townhouse Mobile/Manufactured Farm/Ranch Lot/Land Multi-Family Income/Investment Houseboat Unknown Listing Type: -- Select One Resale New Home Beds: 5 Baths: 4 Sqft: 3,472 Lot size:
 (acres) 0.84 acres Year Built: 2004     Please remove this listing
until this issue is resolved Details: Your name Your email
 (optional): 
 Cancel Send 
 Done       

 Ask a question about this property Sorry, we couldn’t find contact information for this agent. Try asking your question on Trulia Voices below. 
 Did you know? You can ask the Trulia Voices community about this property to get information and advice from real estate experts and locals .
 150 characters left Question Ask real estate experts,locals, and friends... 1000 characters left More Details (Optional) Optional details about your question This question is about this property: http://www.trulia.com/property/3075924115-5-Lennys-Way-West-Springfield-MA-01089   Get email alerts as people answer my question ASK!       

 Success! DONE       
 Nearby homes 
 31 Lennys Way West Springfield, MA 18 Lennys Way West Springfield, MA 120 Lennys Way West Springfield, MA 142 Lennys Way West Springfield, MA 5 Lennys Way West Springfield, MA 32 Bascom St West Springfield, MA 235 Rogers Ave West Springfield, MA 806 Dewey St West Springfield, MA 13 Maple Hts West Springfield, MA 389 Gooseberry Rd West Springfield, MA 
 Show more You might also be interested in... Similar Homes New Listings Price Reductions View all» Previous 
 25 photos 96 Valley View Cir 
 $275,000 

on

 6 br  2 ba   3,500 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 24 photos 76 Norman St 
 $119,900 

$30,000 on 06/24/12

 4 br  1 ba   1,728 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 19 photos 137 Greystone Ave 
 $243,900 

$5,000 on 06/03/12

 3 br    1,700 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 9 photos 93 Kings Hwy 
 $89,900 

on

 4 br  1 ba   1,170 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 19 photos 134 Greystone Ave 
 $228,900 

on

 3 br  1 ba   1,328 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 22 photos 49 Timber Ridge Rd 
 $398,500 

$15,951 on 04/25/12

 5 br    3,093 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 24 photos 26 Neptune Ave 
 $218,000 

on

 3 br  1 full, 2 partial ba   1,843 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 12 photos 164 Windsor St 
 $119,900 

on

 3 br  2 ba   1,356 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 263 Upper Virginia 
 $243,900 

on

 4 br  1 full, 1 partial ba   1,460 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 5 Lennys Way 
 $475,000 

on

 5 br  4 ba   3,472 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 21 photos 115 Bretton Rd 
 $339,900 

on

 4 br  3 ba   3,294 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 25 photos 737 Piper Rd 
 $224,900 

on

 3 br  1 full, 1 partial ba   1,200 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 10 photos 46 Hampden St 
 $144,000 

$5,000 on 05/27/12

 3 br  1 ba   1,020 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 7 photos 74 Albert St 
 $140,000 

on

 3 br  1 ba   1,375 sqft 

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 17 photos 480 Birnie Ave 
 $169,900 

on

 3 br    

Single-Family Home

 OPEN: 


 
 Next 168b41168690b0188ea36707b5acdfeb 168b41168690b0188ea36707b5acdfeb 
 What do you think of this area? 
Thanks! Your review has been submitted

Thanks! Both your review and ratings have been submitted
 
Thanks! Your changes have been saved
 Done We are collecting ratings for the surrounding area, not for this or any other specific property or listing.       
 
 Communities near 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield | MLS# 71335935 
 West Springfield Real Estate West Springfield Real Estate West Springfield Foreclosures West Springfield Single-Family Homes 01089 Real Estate 01089 Single-Family Homes 01089 Apartments for Rent West Springfield Apartments for Rent 
 
 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Springfield Homes for Sale Brightwood Homes for Sale Willimansett Homes for Sale Chicopee Homes for Sale Feeding Hills Homes for Sale Agawam Homes for Sale See All Nearby Cities 
 
 Real Estate and Mortgage Guides West Springfield Real Estate Guide West Springfield Schools Hampden County Home Prices Heat Map Massachusetts Home Prices Heat Map West Springfield Mortgage West Springfield Refinance West Springfield Home Loan 
 
 Compare 5 Lennys Way With... Similar homes to 5 Lennys Way Recently sold West Springfield homes Recently sold 01089 homes Compare to 5 Lennys Way 
 

 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Springfield Homes for Sale Brightwood Homes for Sale Willimansett Homes for Sale Chicopee Homes for Sale Feeding Hills Homes for Sale Agawam Homes for Sale Halyoke Homes for Sale Holyoke Homes for Sale Westfield Homes for Sale Longmeadow Homes for Sale       

Residential Real Estate

 San Francisco real estate  |  New York real estate  |  Los Angeles real estate  |  Orlando real estate  |  Miami real estate  |  Philadelphia real estate  |  Phoenix real estate  |  San Diego real estate  |  San Jose real estate  |  Chicago real estate  |  Arizona real estate  |  California real estate  |  Florida real estate  |  Illinois real estate  |  Massachusetts real estate  |  New Jersey real estate  |  Pennsylvania real estate  |  Texas real estate  |  Other local real estate  |  California apartments  |  New York apartments  |  Texas apartments  |  Apartments for rent  |  Home price maps  |  Real estate community  |  U.S. Property records 
 
Explore Trulia

 Homes for Sale  |  Homes for Rent  |  Stats&amp;Trends  |  Real Estate Advice  |  Real Estate Apps  |  Trulia Labs  |  Trulia API  |  Trulia Estimates 
 
For Professionals

 Agents  |  Brokers  |  MLS  |  Advertisers&amp;Partners  |  Tools&amp;Widgets  |  Submit Your Listings  |  Real Estate Leads 
 
Corporate

 About Trulia  |  News Room  |  Trulia Blog  |  Careers  |  Privacy  |  Terms of Use  |  Subscription Terms of Use  |  Community Guidelines 
 This Single-Family Home located at 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA, 01089 is currently for sale and has been listed on Trulia for 151 days. This property is listed by newenglandmoves.com for $475,000. 5 Lennys Way has 5 beds, 4 baths, and approximately 3,472 square feet. The property has a lot size of 0.84 acres and was built in 2004. 5 Lennys Way is in West Springfield and in ZIP Code 01089 . The list price of $475,000 is 108% higher than the average list price of $227,947 for 01089 real estate and 108% higher than the average list price of $227,947 for West Springfield, MA real estate . The price for this property is 188% higher than the average sales price of $165,190 for 01089 and 188% higher than the average sales price of $165,190 for West Springfield. The price per square foot for this property is $137, which is 22% higher than the average of $112 for 01089, and 22% higher than the average of $112 for West Springfield. Copyright©2012
 Trulia, Inc. All rights reserved. |  Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity Have a question? Visit our Help Center to find the answer 
 
 $475,000 5 Lennys Way, West Springfield MA
 Follow Share Contact agent
	</body>
</document>
