<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005926" url="http://www.franchisedirect.com/foodfranchises/themarketinggeniusbehindmcdonaldsfranchisesuccess/14/25" time="2012-07-12-22:35" support="9" score="0.03527462695406186" bingtitle="McDonalds Franchise Success - The Best Franchise Opportunities ..." webtitle="McDonalds Franchise Success">
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000306" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="71"/>
	<description>... chain grow from a single store to the most popular fast food ... largest franchise store featuring more than 700 seats ... in the Cincinnati area for Catholics who did not eat ...</description>
	<body>
		Follow Franchise Direct
 
 
McDonalds Fast Food Franchise Success

Do you know why or how fast food franchise giant McDonald&apos;s is the world&apos;s most successful fast food franchise concept? View the following article on the history of McDonalds franchise success and be inspired to invest in a profitable and successful fast food franchise opportunity.
 
 Home › 
 
 Ireland Canada UK France Germany Europe Spain Mexico South Africa 
 
 Home ›  Food Franchises › The Marketing Genius behind McDonalds Franchise Success
 View all Food Franchises 
 

When people think about the franchising concept, McDonalds usually comes up first as a prime example. And though McDonalds was not the first franchise business–Isaac Singer, the inventor of the sewing machine gets credit for originating the franchise idea -- the hamburger chain certainly exemplifies franchising success.

The first“McDonalds”restaurant was opened by brothers Dick and Mac McDonald in 1940 on Route 66 in San Bernadino, California. The menu had about 25 offerings, and“carhops”brought the food out to patrons (usually teenagers) waiting in their cars.

Today, McDonalds franchise network is the world’s leading food service retailer, with more than 30,000 franchise restaurants serving 52 million people in more than 100 countries. Of those stores, more than 70 percent are owned by independent operator franchisees.

 

How did the chain grow from a single store to the most popular fast food restaurant and successful franchise operation in the world?

 

Raymond Kroc gets the credit as the driving force behind McDonald’s successful franchise growth . He did not start out as a restaurant owner, but as an equipment supplier to restaurants after mortgaging his home and investing all his savings in an exclusive distributorship for a milk shake maker called“Multimixer.”

In 1954, the McDonalds restaurant caught Kroc’s attention because it was using eight Multimixers . Kroc went to visit the restaurant and was amazed at the speedy business operation that served so many people at once. The McDonald brothers had already begun to franchise their restaurant concept and had four locations going by the time of Kroc’s visit.

Kroc recognized the opportunity to sell lots of Multimixers and made a proposal to the brothers to let him franchise restaurants outside of their home base in California. (Ray Kroc was not the only one impressed by the McDonalds restaurant, which was also visited by James McLamore, founder of Burger King, and Glen Bell, founder of Taco Bell.)

In 1955, Kroc launched“ McDonalds Systems, Inc .”as a legal structure to run his franchises, and by 1958 McDonalds had sold 100 million hamburgers. In 1961, the McDonald brothers agreed to sell all the business rights to Kroc for $2.7 million. The company went public in 1965, and 100 shares purchased then for about $2,250 would have grown to 74,360 shares now worth over $3 million.

The first McDonalds franchise opened outside the US in British Columbia, Canada in 1967. Since then, McDonalds has spread all over the world, with its largest franchise store featuring more than 700 seats opening in Beijing, China in 1992.

One essential factor that contributes to franchise success is a consistent commitment to standards. McDonalds franchise restaurants became well-known for the inspired and defining vision created by Kroc for his restaurant business.“Quality, Service, Cleanliness and Value”was the company’s motto, and customers knew that no matter where they travelled, they could rely on those qualities at every McDonalds they visited.

Kroc’s brilliant marketing insights produced many winning strategies. He launched“Hamburger University”in 1961 in Elk Grove, Illinois, to train all franchisees in every aspect of McDonald’s management. Kroc also targeted families as his best market share. This resulted in the debut of the“Ronald McDonald”clown character on television in 1963, first played by Willard Scott.

 

McDonald’s success thrives on adapting to consumer demands…

 

But the franchise chain’s success also rests on another key component, which at first glance might seem contrary to franchising principles–continual innovation and adaptation to market conditions.

First started as a simple hamburger, french fries and milkshake restaurant, McDonalds franchise operation experimented and expanded its menu to cater to changing tastes and consumer demand.

 In 1963, McDonalds introduced the“ Filet-of-Fish ”sandwich in the Cincinnati area for Catholics who did not eat meat on Friday. This was the first new offering added to the standard menu and went national the following year. 

It is interesting to note that many of the new products added to McDonald’s menu over the decades were developed by franchisees.

 For instance, the“Big Mac”introduced in 1968 was the brainchild of Jim Delligatti, one of the earliest McDonalds Systems franchisees. The“Egg McMuffin”was developed in 1973 by McDonald’s franchisee Herb Peterson. A Canadian franchisee invented The McFlurry in 1997. In 2005, another adaptation to the times and consumer demand was the provision of WiFi with Nintendo in select locations; and delivery service in Singapore, where customers can phone in their order and have it delivered 24 hours a day, seven days a week. The company has also departed from its standard free-standing units, and installed quick service kiosks in busy places, like malls and airports.
 
 

McDonalds franchise business has not only survived but thrived through boom times and recessions and has successfully reacted to consumer trends. It was one of the first franchise restaurants to post nutritional information about its menu, and now offers salads and other healthy options in recent years.

If you would like to get your bite of the profitable franchise restaurant industry why not find out more about well-known and some up-and-coming  fast food franchises, which have been influences by the world’s most successful franchise business - McDonald’s.
 
Food Franchises...
 
 
 
 Candy Bouquet Combine fun and profit with a low investment and no royalty fees! Fabulous candy gift franchise, a sweet... Minimum Cash Required: $7,500. 
 
 

 YoFresh Yogurt Café Own a YoFresh Yogurt Café! No royalty fees and no experience necessary for this frozen yogurt franchise! Minimum Cash Required: $70,000. 
 
 

 JAKE&apos;s Wayback Burgers JAKE&apos;s - the right time, the right food franchise opportunity. JAKE&apos;s is growing nationwide! Minimum Cash Required: $100,000. 
 
 
 

 Mugs ‘N Jugs Sports Bar&amp;Grill Join a Sports Bar&amp;Grill franchise that&apos;s been wowing customers for over 25 years! Great food, great... Minimum Cash Required: $500,000. 
 
 

 Yogen Fruz Yogen Fruz is the largest frozen yogurt franchise, voted #1 Franchise in the World by Entrepreneur Magazine, with... Minimum Cash Required: $125,000. 
 
 

 Jimmy John&apos;s ...sandwich franchise is offering you a proven business model, expert training, excellent revenue potential&amp;... Minimum Cash Required: $80,000. 
 
 
 View all Food Franchises 
 Tweet 
 

 Focus on...
   Food Franchises 
 Asian Food Franchises Bakery&amp;Donut Franchises Bar&amp;Pub Franchises Barbeque Franchises Burger Franchises Candy Franchises Catering Franchises Chicken Franchises Cupcake Franchises Deli Franchises Drive Thru Franchises Fast Food Franchises Frozen Yogurt Franchises Gourmet Food Franchises Health Food Franchises Ice Cream Franchises Italian Food Franchises Mexican Food Franchises Pizza Franchises Sandwich&amp;Bagel Franchises Seafood Franchises Smoothie Franchises Water Franchises 
 Industry 
 Accounting&amp;Financial Franchises Advertising&amp;Marketing Franchises ATM Franchises Automotive Franchises Business Opportunities Business Services Franchise Children&apos;s Franchises Cleaning Franchises Coffee Franchises Computer&amp;Internet Franchises Consultant&amp;Business Broker Franchises Courier Franchises DVD&amp;Video Franchises Employment&amp;Staffing Franchises Entertainment Franchises Fitness Franchises Food Franchises Health&amp;Beauty Franchises Healthcare&amp;Senior Care Franchises Home Services Franchises Home-based Franchises Industrial Franchises Mailing&amp;Shipping Franchises Moving&amp;Storage Franchises Pet Franchises Printer, Copying&amp;Sign Franchises Real Estate Franchises Restaurant Franchises Retail Franchises Security Franchises Sports Franchises Tax Franchises Training Franchises Travel Franchises Vending Franchise Opportunities 
 Location 
 US Franchises International Franchises 
 Investment 
 Less Than $15,000 $15,000 to $50,000 $50,000 to $75,000 $75,000 to $150,000 $150,000 to $300,000 More Than $300,000 
 More Franchise Lists 
 New Franchises Top Franchises Master Franchises Franchise Resales Franchises for Women Franchises for Veterans Special Financing Offers Green Franchises Mobile Franchises Small Business Administration Approved Multi-unit Franchises Discovery Days Cheap Franchises International Businesses Franchise Directory 
 Franchise Advice 
 Franchise Consultants 
 Franchise Direct Top 100 Global Franchises 
 Top 100 Global Franchises Report Top 100 Global Franchises Rankings 
 Franchise Portfolio 
 Franchise News Testimonials Franchise Videos Franchise Direct Blog Franchise Success Stories Franchise Information Center Franchise Expos and Events 
 
 
Franchise Direct is a member of the IFA
 
 
 Franchise Opportunities Site Map RSS Directory Terms&amp;Disclaimer Privacy Policy About Us Advertise 


 Copyright © 2003-2012 Franchise Direct. All Rights Reserved. 
 Te encuentras en México? Visita nuestro portal www.FranquiciaDirecta.com.mx! Te encuentras en España? Visita nuestro portal www.FranquiciaDirecta.com! In Deutschland? Besuchen Sie www.FranchiseDirekt.com! Vous cherchez une franchise en France ? Visitez le site www.FranchiseDirecte.fr. In South Africa? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.co.za! In Canada? Visit www.FranchiseDirectCanada.com! In Ireland? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.ie! In the UK? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.co.uk! In the USA? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.com! 
 
 
 
 
 
YOUR REQUEST LIST
 
 WHAT IS THIS? 
 
 Your Request List

You can add items by clicking the &quot;Add to Request List&quot; button or checkbox when you find something you&apos;re interested in.

You may add up to 15 items to your Request List

Your request list will follow you around the site.

When you are ready to complete your request for free information, click&quot;Submit&quot; in your Request List.

Why not get started by browsing our New Franchise Opportunities or Low Cost Franchise Directory ?
 
You may only enter 15 items in your Request List.

 Would you like to submit your request now? Click&quot;Yes&quot;to submit your request or&quot;No&quot;to continue browsing.

 Yes | No 
 
 VIEW / SUBMIT 

 HIDE LIST 
 
I would like more information from the following franchises:

   
 
Contact Information
 
Full Name * 
   Mr Mrs Ms 
Email Address * 
 
Telephone Number * 
 
Mailing Information
 
Street * 
 
City * 
 
State/Province * 
 
Zip/Postal Code * 
 
Country * 
 --Select-- Afghanistan Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antigua Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Barbuda Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia Botswana Brazil Brunei Darussalam Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Caicos Island Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Cook Islands Coral Sea Islands Costa Rica Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic East Timor Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Faeroe Islands Falkland Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia Futuna Island Gabon Gambia Gaza Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Grenadines Guadaloupe Guam Guatemala Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Herzegovina Honduras Hong-Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Israel Italy Ivory Coast Jamaica Japan Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Kosovo Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libyan Arab Jamahiri Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Malvinas Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles Nevis New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island North Korea Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Island Poland Portugal Principe Puerto Rico Qatar Republic of Serbia Reunion Romania Russian Federation Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts Saint Lucia Saint Pierre and Miquelon Saint Vincent Samoa San Marino Sao Tome Saudi Arabia Senegal Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa South Korea Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syrian Arab Republic Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Tobago Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks Island Tuvalu Uganda UK - England UK - Northern Ireland UK - Scotland UK - Wales Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom United States of America Uruguay US Outlying Islands Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Viet Nam Virgin Islands (British) Virgin Islands (US) Wake Islands Wallis Island West Bank Western Sahara Yemen Yugoslavia Zaire Zambia Zimbabwe 
Investment Interest
 
Desired Investment * 
 --Select-- Less than $25,000 $25,000 to $50,000 $50,000 to $75,000 $75,000 to $100,000 $100,000 to $150,000 $150,000 to $200,000 $200,000 to $250,000 $250,000 to $500,000 $500,000 to $1,000,000 More than $1,000,000 
Desired Location * 
 --Select-- US - Alabama US - Alaska US - Arizona US - Arkansas US - California US - Colorado US - Connecticut US - Delaware US - District of Columbia US - Florida US - Georgia US - Hawaii US - Idaho US - Illinois US - Indiana US - Iowa US - Kansas US - Kentucky US - Louisiana US - Maine US - Maryland US - Massachusetts US - Michigan US - Minnesota US - Mississippi US - Missouri US - Montana US - Nebraska US - Nevada US - New Hampshire US - New Jersey US - New Mexico US - New York US - North Carolina US - North Dakota US - Ohio US - Oklahoma US - Oregon US - Pennsylvania US - Rhode Island US - South Carolina US - South Dakota US - Tennessee US - Texas US - Utah US - Vermont US - Virginia US - Washington US - West Virginia US - Wisconsin US - Wyoming   CA - Yukon Territory CA - Nunavut CA - Northwest Territories CA - Saskatchewan CA - Quebec CA - Prince Edward Island CA - Ontario CA - Nova Scotia CA - Newfoundland and Labrador CA - New Brunswick CA - Manitoba CA - British Columbia CA - Alberta   Afghanistan Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antigua Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Barbuda Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia Botswana Brazil Brunei Darussalam Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Caicos Island Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Cook Islands Coral Sea Islands Costa Rica Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic East Timor Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Faeroe Islands Falkland Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia Futuna Island Gabon Gambia Gaza Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Grenadines Guadaloupe Guam Guatemala Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Herzegovina Honduras Hong-Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Israel Italy Ivory Coast Jamaica Japan Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Kosovo Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libyan Arab Jamahiri Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Malvinas Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles Nevis New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island North Korea Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Island Poland Portugal Principe Puerto Rico Qatar Republic of Serbia Reunion Romania Russian Federation Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts Saint Lucia Saint Pierre and Miquelon Saint Vincent Samoa San Marino Sao Tome Saudi Arabia Senegal Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa South Korea Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syrian Arab Republic Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Tobago Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks Island Tuvalu Uganda UK - England UK - Northern Ireland UK - Scotland UK - Wales Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom Uruguay US Outlying Islands Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Viet Nam Virgin Islands (British) Virgin Islands (US) Wake Islands Wallis Island West Bank Western Sahara Yemen Yugoslavia Zaire Zambia Zimbabwe 
Additional Information (Optional) 
 
Timeframe to Invest
 --Select-- Within 3 Months Within 6 Months Within 12 Months Just Making an Inquiry 
Preferred Method of Contact
 --Select-- Telephone Email 
Best Time to Call
 --Select-- Morning Afternoon Evening 
Alternate Telephone Number
 
Comments? Questions?
 * required field. 
  Yes, send me updates on new franchise opportunities!
 
This advertisement does not constitute a franchise offering. Please read our terms and conditions for full details.
	</body>
</document>
