<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005748" url="http://www.wikinvest.com/stock/Buffalo_Wild_Wings_(BWLD)" time="2012-07-12-22:22" support="2" score="0.0048554827009463135" bingtitle="Stock:Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) - See your portfolio in a whole ..." webtitle="Stock:Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD)">
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>Potential Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) Trade Targets 41.19% Return ... The bulk of their revenues come from restaurant sales at their company-owned restaurants ...</description>
	<body>
		New! Portfolio     Login / Sign Up Search 
 
 Industries 
 
 Technology Energy Media Finance Green Issues China All Concepts 
 
 Metals Energy Meats Grains Softs 
 
 ETFs Indices 
 
 Currencies Geographies Exchanges Rates 
 
 How To Invest Personal Finance Options 101 Definitions 
 
 
     

 close close close close 
 Send us Feedback 
 
Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD)
 
 
 SUMMARY 
 
 BULLS 

 BEARS 
 
 TOPICS 
 
 DATA CENTRAL 
 
 STOCK CHART 
 
 SEC FILINGS 
 
 BALANCE 

 INCOME 

 CASH FLOW 
 QUOTE AND NEWS 
     
 
 Day 52 Wk 

 Vol Avg Vol 

 P/E Mkt Cap 
 Oops! Unable to complete your request. Please refresh your browser. See more recent news Buffalo Wild Wings, Inc. to Conduct a Webcast of its Second Quarter 2012 Results Globe Newswire   Jul 11   Comment  
 MINNEAPOLIS, July 11, 2012 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Buffalo Wild Wings, Inc. (Nasdaq:BWLD), today announced that the Company will conduct a conference call to discuss its second quarter 2012 results on Tuesday, July 24, 2012 at 4:00 p.m. Central Daylight New Look for Buffalo Wild Wings Unveiled This Week Business Wire   Jul 11   Comment  
 As it enters its 30th year, Buffalo Wild Wings® is refreshing its look, restaurants and its commitment to the Guest experience. The restaurant – with roots on college campuses – has become a destination for sports fans over the years. While the Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) Showing Bearish Technicals With Support At $81.12 Market Intelligence Center   Jun 22   Comment  
 Buffalo Wild Wings (NASDAQ:BWLD) closed Thursday&apos;s unfavorable trading session at $83.02. In the past year, the stock has hit a 52-week low of $52.37 and 52-week high of $94.81. Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) stock has been showing support around... Buffalo Wild Wings, Inc. to Present at Consumer Conference Globe Newswire   Jun 20   Comment  
 MINNEAPOLIS, June 20, 2012 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) -- Buffalo Wild Wings, Inc. (Nasdaq:BWLD) today announced that the Company will present at an upcoming consumer conference. On Tuesday, June 26, 2012, the Company will present at the Oppenheimer 12th Annual Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) Could Fall Through $79.85 Support Level Market Intelligence Center   Jun 11   Comment  
 Buffalo Wild Wings (NASDAQ:BWLD) closed Friday&apos;s bullish trading session at $82.64. In the past year, the stock has hit a 52-week low of $52.37 and 52-week high of $94.81. Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) stock has been showing support around $79.85 and... Potential Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) Trade Has $79.12 Breakeven Market Intelligence Center   May 22   Comment  
 Buffalo Wild Wings (NASDAQ:BWLD) closed Monday&apos;s dramatic trading session at $84.02. In the past year, the stock has hit a 52-week low of $52.37 and 52-week high of $94.81. Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) stock has been showing support around $80.70 and... What Do Fans Think About Baseball’s Biggest Questions? Business Wire   May 18   Comment  
 Sports fans are known for their passion, loyalty, superstitions – but most of all – opinions. From the broadcast booth and sideline reporters to sports radio and blogs, the “experts” debate issues in every sport. But where do the fans stand Half-Off Night on Spicy Wings: Buffalo Wild Wings Stock Compared to Chipotle Forbes   May 7   Comment  
 Share prices for restaurateur Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) have more than doubled in the past couple of years, a feat that has gone under-appreciated perhaps because Chipotle Mexican Grill’s (CMG) was chalking up a 200% gain. But while Chipotle’s... Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) Showing Bearish Technicals With Resistance At $85.86 Market Intelligence Center   May 7   Comment  
 Buffalo Wild Wings Inc (NASDAQ: BWLD) closed Friday&apos;s trading session at $83.97. In the past year, the stock has hit a 52-week low of $52.37 and 52-week high of $94.81. Buffalo Wild Wings (BWLD) stock has been showing support around $82.92 and... UPDATE: DA Davidson Terminates Coverage on Buffalo Wild Wings Benzinga   May 1   Comment  
 DA Davidson says it is dropping its rating on Buffalo Wild Wings (NASDAQ: BWLD) due to the departure of the analyst that covered the company. 



DA Davidson notes, &quot;Due to the departure of our analyst we are dropping coverage of BWLD shares... Oops! Unable to complete your request. Please refresh your browser. See earlier news Suggest other news sources for this topic 
 Topic 
 

 Top news source/blog that we&apos;re missing 
 

 Why do you recommend this news source? 
 
 RELATED WIKI ARTICLES 
Related Articles

 Casual&amp;Upscale Restaurants Ruby Tuesday (RT) Darden Restaurants (DRI) California Pizza Kitchen (CPKI) BJ&apos;s Restaurants (BJRI) 
 more▼ 
 Discussion History Bookmark Print 
 WIKI ANALYSIS   TOP CONTRIBUTORS Alexander Nicolau Alan Ibrahim 
 Buffalo Wild Wings, Inc. ( NASDAQ :BWLD) operates a series of sports bar restaurants across the U.S., but with heavy concentration in Ohio. The company is best known for its chicken wings, which customers can customize with 14 different flavors to choose from. In 2009, the company generated $539 million in revenue and $30.7 million in net income. [1] 

Chicken prices are rising because corn , which is a major ingredient in chicken feed, has become more expensive. Buffalo Wild Wings is sensitive to the price of chicken feed - in 2009, the price for chicken wings increased from $1.22 per pound to $1.70 per pound, leading to a 30.4% increase in cost of sales for the year.

Additionally as a sports bar, Buffalo Wild Wing&apos;s sales are tied to professional athletics&apos; calendar - the company&apos;s earnings have generally been lower during the second quarter, when there are few big sports events.
 
 Company Overview 

Buffalo Wild Wings operates 232 company owned restaurants and 420 franchised restaurants in 42 states. The firm&apos;s principal business is the casual restaurant business. The bulk of their revenues come from restaurant sales at their company-owned restaurants (91%). Food and nonalcoholic beverages accounted for 76% of restaurant sales, with the remaining 24% coming from alcoholic beverages. The menu item with the highest sales volume is chicken wings at 21% of total restaurant sales. Franchise fees and royalties are 9.3% of revenues. [2] 
 
 Business Growth 
 
 FY 2009 (ended December 27, 2009) [1] 
 
 
Contents
 
 1 Company Overview 2 Business Growth 
 2.1 FY 2009 (ended December 27, 2009)[1] 
 3 Trends and Factors 
 3.1 Chicken Wing Prices Are Highly Volatile Which Leads To Uncertain Operating Earnings 3.2 With Low Market Penetration, Growth Opportunities Are Abundant 3.3 Seasonality of the Business Affects Revenues 
 4 Competition 5 References 
 
 
 Total revenue increased 27.6% to $539 million. $97.9 million was generated from the opening of 36 new company-owned franchises and 52 restaurants that did not meet the criteria for same-store sales. Same-store sales for the period increased 3.4% . Net income grew 25.5% to $30.7 million. Cost of sales grew 30.4% primarily due to more restaurants being open. Chicken wing costs rose to $1.70 per pound, up from $1.22 per pound in the prior year. 
 
 Trends and Factors 
 
 Chicken Wing Prices Are Highly Volatile Which Leads To Uncertain Operating Earnings 

Since chicken wings are the largest selling item on Buffalo Wild Wing&apos;s menu, accounting for 21% of restaurant sales, any changes in chicken wing prices have dramatic implications for the company&apos;s cost of goods sold . In 2009, the price of chicken wings increased to $1.70 per pound, up from $1.22 per pound in the previous year. [1] This 48 cent increase multiplied by the hundreds of thousands of pounds of chicken wings the company needs to operates means substantially higher costs and reduced profits. As a result, cost of sales increased 30.4% in 2009.
 
 With Low Market Penetration, Growth Opportunities Are Abundant 

The company operates 652 Buffalo Wild Wings restaurants in 42 states, 88 of which are located in Ohio. This leaves the opportunity for nationwide growth. The company hopes to expand its operations to over 1,000 restaurants nationwide. The company also wants to increase the number of company-owned restaurants -- in 2009 just over 30% of the restaurants were company owned. The company opened 36 restaurants in 2009 and plans to open 88 in 2010.
 
 Seasonality of the Business Affects Revenues 

Operating as a sports bar, Buffalo Wild Wings is largely sensitive to seasonal factors, most notably, the number of big sports events. It is for this reason that second quarter sales have generally been lower than other quarters&apos;. In addition, this sensitivity to sports seasons leaves them susceptible to slower business when, for example, the teams in the Super Bowl are of little interest to the customers of Buffalo Wild Wings restaurants.
 
 Competition 

Buffalo Wild Wings competes primarily with local and regional sports bars and casual dining and quick casual establishments, as well as with quick service restaurants such as wing-based take-out concepts. Many of the company&apos;s direct and indirect competitors are well-established national, regional or local chains.

Main competitors include:
 
 Brinker International (EAT) - Operates casual dining restaurants such as, Chili&apos;s Grill&amp;Bar, Romano&apos;s Macaroni Grill, On The Border Mexican Grill&amp;Cantina, and Maggiano&apos;s Little Italy, in 49 US states and several countries. Ruby Tuesday (RT) - Operates casual dining restaurants under the Ruby Tuesday brand name in the U.S. and internationally. BJ&apos;s Restaurants (BJRI) - Operates casual dining restaurants in the U.S. under the names, BJ&apos;s Restaurant and Brewery, BJ&apos;s Restaurant and Brewhouse, and BJ&apos;s Pizza and Grill. Cheesecake Factory (CAKE) - Operates full service and casual dining restaurants in the U.S. under the names, The Cheesecake Factory, Grand Lux Cafe, and The Cheesecake Factory Express. California Pizza Kitchen (CPKI) - Operates casual dining restaurants in the U.S. and internationally under the names, California Pizza Kitchen, California Pizza Kitchen ASAP, and L.A. Food Show. Applebee&apos;s International (APPB) - Operates the largest casual dining restaurant chain under the name Applebee&apos;s Neighborhood Bar and Grill in the U.S. and internationally. Darden Restaurants (DRI) - Operates restaurants under the names Red Lobster, Olive Garden, Bahama Breeze, Smokey Bones, and Seasons 52 in the U.S. and Canada. Hooters Restaurants (privately-held) - Operates casual dining restaurants in the U.S. and internationally. It is known by many for it&apos;s chicken wings. 
 
 References 

 ↑ 1.0 1.1 1.2 BWLD 2009 10-K &quot;Selected Financial Data&quot; pg. 22 ↑ BWLD 2009 10-K &quot;Overview&quot; pg. 23--24 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.wikinvest.com/stock/Buffalo_Wild_Wings_(BWLD) &quot; 
 Categories : Food&amp;Beverage | Fast Food Restaurants (QSR) | Casual&amp;Upscale Restaurants | Mature | Casual&amp;Upscale Dining | Fast Food Restaurants 
 Reduce your cost of investing in seconds—for free! Introducing SigFig—from the creators of Take Tour 
 
 
 
 Wikinvest©2006, 2007, 2008, 2009, 2010, 2011, 2012. Use of this site is subject to express Terms of Service , Privacy Policy , and Disclaimer . By continuing past this page, you agree to abide by these terms. Any information provided by Wikinvest, including but not limited to company data, competitors, business analysis, market share, sales revenues and other operating metrics, earnings call analysis, conference call transcripts, industry information, or price targets should not be construed as research, trading tips or recommendations, or investment advice and is provided with no warrants as to its accuracy. Stock market data, including US and International equity symbols, stock quotes, share prices, earnings ratios, and other fundamental data is provided by data partners. Stock market quotes delayed at least 15 minutes for NASDAQ, 20 mins for NYSE and AMEX. Market data by Xignite . See data providers for more details. Company names, products, services and branding cited herein may be trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective owners. The use of trademarks or service marks of another is not a representation that the other is affiliated with, sponsors, is sponsored by, endorses, or is endorsed by Wikinvest. About | Blog | Press | Feedback | Help | Get involved Mobile | Advertise | Licensing&amp;Partnerships | Blogger Tools | Jobs
	</body>
</document>
