<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005563" url="http://mycustomerservicereviews.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:07" support="3" score="0.004340407304863912" bingtitle="My Customer Service Reviews" webtitle="My Customer Service Reviews">
			<query id="000914" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="83"/>
	<description>Sauce is a cross between a fast food restaurant and sit-down ... with my friend to tell her that I want to leave this store ... exhausting if I didn’t care each time a cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		Search: 
 My Customer Service Reviews 

Customer Service: the Good, the Bad and the Ugly
 
 About Me 
 
 Fun Customer Service Posts 

July 8, 2012 § Leave a Comment 
 
Here are a few fun things I found and thought I’d share 
 
Source: lolroflmao.com via Racquel on Pinterest 
 Source: justlittlethings.net via Lori on Pinterest 
Source: bluntcard.com via Krystal on Pintrest
 
Source: Uploaded by user via Grantland on Pinterest 
 
 iLove Apple 

March 25, 2012 § Leave a Comment 
 
 Let me just start by saying that since the first time I sat down at a Mac, about 11 years ago, I have loved everything Apple. So to me, anything with an i in front of it is amazing…iPhone, iPad, iMac, you name it, it is a-ma-zing .

So to the reason I am writing this blog post: My husband cracked his iPhone screen when it just happened to jump out of his hand and land on our tile floor. I remembered my friend telling me about how the Apple store had replaced not just one, but two of her iPads when the screens had cracked due to her own fault. Since my husband did not have insurance on his phone, I made an appointment at the Apple store to see what could be done. I was a bit irked when I first entered the store apparently checked into the wrong Genius Bar, the one that only served customers with computer problems. So I ventured across the store the to the other Genius Bar to wait my turn. While I waited, I noticed that their was only one poor guy helping all of us pouty-faced patrons (some waiting more patiently than others), while there were more than enough sales associates on the floor. My mood was beginning to sour, but I only had to wait about 15 minutes from my actual appointment time til I was greeted by the associate behind the counter. My mood instantly brightened. He was new, but very knowledgeable and extremely friendly. He explained to me that he could replace the phone for free, once, as a courtesy. I was more than happy with that offer! He clicked away on his computer and magically transferred all of my husband’s data from his old phone to the new phone. And that was it. Done. Approximately 5 minutes later, I walked out of the store with a NEW, FREE iPhone. Yes, new and free.  I would say waiting 15 minutes was well worth the wait to get something replaced free of charge when it was technically our fault the device was cracked in the first place. But what made it even better was the great customer service from the sales associate. He did not give me a hard time, he just explained the deal, transferred data, and viola! Just another reason to love Apple!

Since then, I have heard of many other people with similar positive experiences. I have also recommended to some of my friends to call Apple when something goes wrong with their electronics instead of going to any other repair locations. As a side note, I had a HORRIBLE experience at a major chain that sells Apple, so I highly recommend not only buying Apple products, but buying from an actual Apple retailer or Apple.com. iLove Apple and I hope you do too 
 
 Super A+ for Starbucks (again)! 

March 11, 2012 § Leave a Comment 
 
 Another great day started with amazing Starbucks customer service! What more do I need to say? And no….only one of the drinks and the oatmeal are mine 

 By the way, if you haven’t read it yet, you should read my very first blog review which was about Starbucks. I just can’t say enough about what great customer service they have! http://mycustomerservicereviews.com/2011/01/08/good-starbucks/ 
 
 
 Great – Arrogant Butcher style! 

February 22, 2012 § 6 Comments 
 
 

One of my favorite places to eat is Sauce. If you have been there, you know that they have d-licous food, a nice clean atmosphere, and great customer service. Sauce is a cross between a fast food restaurant and sit-down dining. You order at the counter, take a number to your table and someone brings out your food. When I ended up at another restaurant, the Arrogant Butcher, and had a great experience, I was not surprised to find out that it was part of the Sauce family, a FOX Restaurant Concept.

Upon entering the restaurant, we were promptly greeted and seated, just ahead the downtown Phoenix lunch rush.  Our waiter, Kyle, was very friendly and patient with us while we waited for another friend to arrive. While we waited, we decided to order the pretzel bites. I know the quality of the food does not equal the quality of service, but these pretzel bites deserve a minute in the spotlight. They were light and fluffy, more like pretzel pillows. They were served with a white fondue cheese. In short, they were amazing . I have a lovely picture, taken by the Mrs. Rebecca Campbell, shown here. I suggest going to Arrogant Butcher just for this amazing app. OK, so back to the service, Kyle was very knowledgeable of the menu and helped four hungry gals ready to eat, choose just the right meals. We were picky, we were hungry. The food was outstanding and the service was even more so.

Back to my point about realizing that Arrogant Butcher was part of FOX Restaurant Concepts. I was happy to know that this new favorite restaurant of mine and Sauce were related. I decided to do some research on FOX and found out that they not only highly value food, but the whole dining experience just as equally – just my kind of place. The FOX mission statement is: Great Hospitality, Every Time. I now am going to try and seek out as many of the FOX restaurants as I can – and I can’t wait!
 
 Perfection– Paradise 

November 19, 2011 § 2 Comments 
 
To conclude my eventful evening at the mall, I was hungry. And I was not expecting exceptional service. My friend and I headed to the food court and decided on Paradise Bakery. After choosing what I wanted to eat, I stepped up to the counter where a nice young lady smiled , greeted me, and took my order. She did everything right from the pleasant-happy-to-be-at-work, but not overbearing greeting, to answering my questions on the food, to offering me a free pastry sample that turned out to be a full-size sample. I wish I had gotten her name because I would like to give her credit for turning my whole night and shopping experience around. What more can I say, the bakery lived up to it’s name. And oh yeah, the food was good too 
 
 Bad–Shop Til You Drop 

October 3, 2011 § Leave a Comment 
 
So after the awesome shoe saleslady experience, my friend and I went to one of my all time favorite clothing stores. Upon entering the store, I received the typical greeting: hi, what brings you in, here are our sales, etc. As a former retail worker I know this is necessary, every manager pushes this and is listening from some back room just waiting for these words to come out of your mouth. As a customer, I welcome the acknowledgment that I am in the store and it’s a bonus if there is an great sale going on that is not plastered all over every surface. So I start to look around for about two seconds before the sales girl gets it out of me that I’m on a mission for skinny jeans. She just happens to be wearing some that they sell in the store, so yes please, I’d like a pair in my size to try on. As I’m looking around, I see the girl rummaging through some tops. For a second, I think, Oh she forgot to grab my jeans or misunderstood me. Then, the thought crosses my mind that she pulling tops to go with the jeans which I know is a sales technique, but I am really not in the mood nor do I have the time to try on ugly , expensive shirts that someone else thinks I might like. I am finally ready to try on my jeans and ONE top I pulled from the floor. I go into my fitting room and I think, I have the wrong dressing room, before my brain kicks into high-gear and realizes that not only did the sales girl pull my skinny jeans and some clownish-looking top she thought I’d like, she also pulled not one, but FOUR more complete outfits all the way down to belts and scarves. Alright, I get it, it’s a slow night (did I mention she also gave the the spill about opening a store credit card?). So I try on the skinny jeans and the top I chose. The gal knocks at my door, had I tried on an“outfit”yet? Why yes, the one I chose . I open the door for her opinion since my friend had wondered on to another shop. I feel like the pants are a bit tight. Of course she tells me perfect they look, yada, yada. She then tells me to try on another outfit, they will look great also! I am still looking at the jeans on me in the mirror, deciding if I should take the leap or not (a leap into a fashion trend that a friend would tell me two days after I actually do buy skinny jeans that that look is so“out”this season). No, I say, not yet. So I peal the pants off my legs, barely escaping a pulled muscle from the contortion move it takes me to get out of them. I go back and start looking at more clothes while still deciding. The sales girl asks me if I like any of the tops? No, I say (I MUST stay strong), I am really only wanting to buy skinny jeans tonight. I see a flicker of irritation on her face right before she rushes back to the fitting room. I’m a bit perplexed by this, but I just keep looking. After a few minutes, I see her frantically putting back of the the clothes she had pulled for me, even though there is no one else in the store. Good, I think, at least I’m alone to shop for a few moments. I find a few more things and head back to the dressing room that is now empty. I try on the other clothes as I try to text my friend to come rescue me, but darn AT&amp;T just won’t have it. In a moment, she’s back at my door, knocking, can she see what I’m trying on? I reluctantly open the door and she throws a belt around my waist, it will look wonderful on me! Ugh…….fine, I try it on and act like I actually care. My friend finally comes back and starts to agree with the sales lady about the crazy belt. I’m not spending money on any stupid belt, I want to say. What I want is a second alone with my friend to tell her that I want to leave this store and this annoying sales lady NOW. No luck, the lady is on us like a dog on a bone. I shut the door to my dressing room, defeated, once again peeling off the jeans I can’t decide on. I sit in there a while wondering if and how I will ever escape psycho-saleslady. Finally I emerge and to my relief, she is in the back, putting away clothes. For an instant, I think about putting down the jeans I’m holding and running, fast. But finally I decide to do the right thing – I lie. I give the jeans to the lady and ask her to hold them for me for an hour, I have to go meet my friend, but I’ll be back to buy them…..
 
 Bad – Shoes, shoes, shoes 

September 26, 2011 § Leave a Comment 
 
I know it’s been a long time since my last post, but besides being a bit lazy, nothing too noteworthy has really been happening (to my surprise!). But the past few weeks sure have given me a lot to write about! I’ll write separate posts about each in chronological order, just in case I get too lazy to finish the whole story.

First off, a friend and I went to the mall and entered a large department store with huge shoe sale. After I looked around a bit, I found my friend trying on two pairs of shoes with a shoe saleswoman next to her. You could tell my friend was mulling over the shoes, walking around trying them on. The sales lady would. not. budge. She was just standing there. Not helping, not moving, just stuck there like white on rice. OK, so no biggie, this happens, salespeople like to stick by their sales. I asked my friend if she liked the shoes and she decided to buy one pair and hold off on the other while we walked the mall and visited the other shoe stores. My friend looked right up at the sales lady and asked if she could hold the shoes for a while until we came back through the store on the way to our car. I looked at the lady expecting the normal,“Sure!”, but no……the lady was not looking back at either one of us, in fact she looked like she didn’t even know my friend asked her a question or that she was even there. I thought she was just off in her own world, distracted. But alas, her lips started moving and without looking at us, she said“she didn’t think she could hold the shoes”……”she was going to be working in another department for the next thirty minutes”……..”they work on commission”. She then reluctantly said she’s have to check with her manager. It took my brain a few minutes to connect the dots. At first, I thought they didn’t allow holds on sale shoes or something to that matter, but the added,“we work on commission”, tipped my mind off to realizing she was afraid that if we came back, we’d have another sales associate ring up the sale, resulting in her losing out on the precious commission. I was shocked to say the least. I was ready to pick up the shoes myself, walk to the manager and ask them to please hold the darn shoes for an hour or so. Call me crazy, but in the retail world, I thought the main goal was to SELL product, not sell product only if it’s conducive to the associate’s needs. And what really irritated me was the lady’s attitude. She could have said,“Sure, and would you mind telling them I helped you, I’ll be in another section for a while and might not be here when you return”; that, I would have been completely happy with. But no, this lady could not crack a smile and was very curt in her speaking. One thing that is so important about customer service is how the service makes you feel . I left that store feeling like I wanted to shove a stiletto heal right up that lady’s….
 
 «Older Entries 


 
 
Search this site
 Search: 
Authors

 mycustomerservicereviews 
 
 Subscribe to this blog 
 
Sign up to get the Good, the Bad and the UGLY.

Join 11 other followers

 

 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 March 2012 February 2012 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 January 2011 December 2010 
Blogroll

 Discuss Get Inspired Get Polling Get Support Learn WordPress.com WordPress Planet WordPress.com News 
 
 My Customer Service Reviews Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Oulipo . 
 Blog at WordPress.com .

Theme: Oulipo by A. Mignolo .
 Follow 
 Follow“My Customer Service Reviews” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel
	</body>
</document>
