<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005677" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2012/02/ch-ch-ch-chia_superfood_and_si.php" time="2012-07-12-22:15" support="1" score="0.00011987478079388079" bingtitle="Change Your Diet With Chia: Superfood, Pet-Shaped Houseplant, and ..." webtitle="Change Your Diet With Chia: Superfood, Pet-Shaped Houseplant, and Awesome Dessert (Recipe) - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>Ch-ch-ch-cheers! Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order. ... Available at Eater Miami; The Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Beet Reporter 
Change Your Diet With Chia: Superfood, Pet-Shaped Houseplant, and Awesome Dessert (Recipe)
 By Camille Lamb Mon., Feb. 13 2012 at 9:07 AM Categories: Beet Reporter 
 Pin It 
 
 
​ ​The commercials were easily mistaken for Saturday Night Live skits, with their exaggerated enthusiasm, catchy jingle, and seemingly arbitrary products. Believe it or not, Chia Pets still exist, and the line has been expanded to include donkey, puppy, Shrek, and even President Obama planters.

Who knew that while waiting for our president&apos;s leafy green Afro to sprout, we had just slathered our Chia Pet pottery with a perfectly edible superfood?

Chia is a desert plant and a member of the mint family. Its seeds were a major food source for the Mayans and were the main sustenance of Aztec warriors. It&apos;s great as a vegetarian replacement for fish as a source of omega-3 fatty acids (which help reduce bad cholesterol, maintain the health of cell walls, reduce inflammation, alleviate depression and ADHD, and prevent cancer cell growth, among other benefits). Like flax, chia can be used in baking or added to cereals, salads, and smoothies. But I think chia is even cooler than flaxseed because of its higher density of omega-3s, its longer shelf life, and the fact that its nutrients are bio-available even when the seeds are consumed whole. I also like its (negligible) taste better, plus its cool gelling properties, which I&apos;ll talk more about later.

Chia is rich in antioxidants, fiber, calcium, magnesium, phosphorus, manganese, copper, niacin, and zinc, among other nutrients. It&apos;s also a good source of complete protein and omega-6 fatty acids. In fact, it naturally has what WebMD suggests as a perfect balance of omega-3 and -6 fatty acids.
 
 
 Chia seeds in fresh organic vegetable and fruit juice make for a powerhouse pick-me-up drink. 
​ Its ability to sprout on clay surfaces is not chia&apos;s only cool physical property. Put a few tablespoons in a short glass of water, wait 30 minutes, and you&apos;ll have a glass of chia jelly that kind of looks like frog eggs. This satisfyingly textured liquid can be added to freshly made organic juice or slurped down on its own. The gelling property of the seed &quot;sprouted&quot; a line of chia beverages called Mamma Chia , sweetened with organic agave, in flavors such as blackberry hibiscus and cherry lime, available at Whole Foods and other health-food stores.

The gelling action is to thank for another awesome thing about chia: Research shows that a bellyful of chia gel slows the digestion of carbohydrates so that they&apos;re released more evenly into the bloodstream, preventing blood sugar spikes and crashes.

Local health-food educator and &quot;plant love&quot; chef Jordan Wolfe knows about chia&apos;s long list of health benefits, but he uses the seeds for a different reason.

&quot;I do it more for the jelly-like consistency that it gives to the drinks or the pudding. It makes it a unique experience,&quot; Wolfe says. &quot;I put it in homemade lemonade or iced tea. You could even put it in wine, which would be kind of weird.&quot;

Try his cheeky chia-based raw-foods dessert to begin ch-ch-ch-changing your diet deliciously:

 
 Camille Lamb Raw cacao and chia make this a healthful, easy-to-make chocolate indulgence. 
​ Jordan&apos;s &quot;Ch-Ch-Ch-Chunky Monkey&quot; Chia Pudding 

2 1/2 cups unsweetened almond milk
2/3 cup chia seeds
3 tbsp raw honey (or organic agave)
1/2 tsp sea salt
1/3 cup raw cacao powder
½ cup raw walnuts
¼ cup cacao nibs
1 banana

 Directions: 
Whisk honey, cacao powder, and sea salt into almond milk. (You can also use a blender for this step.)
Add chia and whisk until consistent.
Cover and refrigerate overnight.
Add chopped banana, walnuts, and raw cacao nibs and serve.

Ch-ch-ch-cheers!

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Chia Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Wow . The pics make me crave for sweet . It is really delicious I can sense . LOL . Hope to taste one someday . Thanks for the share . :D
 
Put a few tablespoons of short glass of water, wait 30 minutes, you&apos;ll have a glass, looks a bit like frog eggs. Satisfactory texture of the liquid can be added to the fresh organic fruit juice, or grunt on their own.
 
Camille....great piece on the healthy benefits of adding CHIA to your diet. When we created our organic blue corn Torchia Chips we choose  CHIA for all the healthy reasons as&quot;whale&quot;. ....&quot;Chia is rich in antioxidants, fiber, calcium, magnesium, phosphorus, manganese, copper, niacin, and zinc, among other nutrients. It&apos;s also a good source of complete protein and omega-6 fatty acids. In fact, it naturally has a perfect balance of omega-3 and -6 fatty acids.&quot;
 
Thank you Camille for more needed info on Healthy options in the community , Mark
 

TotalComments: 4
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Flip Burger Bar
 View Ad | View Site 
Tobacco Road
 View Ad | View Site 
Montes de Oca Original Pizza Cubana
 View Ad | View Site 
Salsa Fiesta Urban Mexican Grill
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Reviews for Whisk, Villa Azur and Tap 42 Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
