<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005892" url="http://www.reddit.com/r/AskReddit/comments/gsxlx/i_just_paid_421_for_gas_the_fast_food_restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-22:34" support="25" score="0.019333475278633154" bingtitle="I just paid 4.21 for gas. The fast food restaurant I usually go to ..." webtitle="I just paid 4.21 for gas. The fast food restaurant I usually go to raised their price close to $7. Average cereal price is getting close to $4. At work there no salary increase, they just tell me I am lucky to have a job. What is going on? I am not happy. : AskReddit">
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000301" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>The fast food restaurant I usually go to raised their price close to $7. ... It took a long time for my pay in tech to catch up with what I was making ...</description>
	<body>
		jump to content my reddits AdviceAnimals announcements AskReddit atheism aww bestof blog funny gaming IAmA movies Music pics politics science technology todayilearned videos worldnews WTF edit subscriptions 
 front - all - random 
  |  
 pics - funny - politics - gaming - AskReddit - worldnews - videos - IAmA - todayilearned - WTF - aww - atheism - technology - AdviceAnimals - science - Music - movies - bestof - trees - fffffffuuuuuuuuuuuu - gifs - pokemon - Minecraft - leagueoflegends - 4chan - mylittlepony - TheLastAirbender - starcraft - skyrim - circlejerk - reactiongifs - gentlemanboners - facepalm - LadyBoners - gameofthrones - doctorwho - tf2 - nba - LifeProTips - Android - Diablo - cats - dayz - zelda - FoodPorn - DotA2 - news - soccer - baseball - food 
 more»   AskReddit 
 comments related 
 want to join? login or register in seconds | 
 English 
 limit my search to /r/AskReddit 
use the following search parameters to narrow your results:
 reddit:{name} find things posted in {name} only author:{username} return things submitted by {username} only site:{domain} get links to pages on {domain} only url:{text} search for {text} in url selftext:{text} search for {text} in self post contents self:{yes|no} include or exclude self posts nsfw:{yes|no} include or exclude nsfw results 
e.g. reddit:pics site:imgur.com dog 

 see the search faq for details. 
 
 advanced search: by author, community... 
 this post was submitted on 18 Apr 2011 2,048 points (55% like it) 10,453 up votes 8,405 down votes shortlink: 

 remember me reset password login 
 AskReddit 
 unsubscribe subscribe 1,884,887 readers 
Spoiler Code

 [text here](/spoiler) 

Hover over to read .
 
 
You must post the question in your title. Post your own reply in the comments, not in the title if you have one also.
 
AskReddit is for thought-provoking, discussion-inspiring questions. If your question can be answered by google, or in one word, it isn&apos;t right for AskReddit.
 
Please use the search in the sidebar. Somebody may have already posted your question!
 
You are able to post self-posts only! (For other types of questions, see&quot;other reddits&quot;below.)
 
Please don&apos;t post poll-type questions.
 
No yes/no answer questions. DAEs are yes/no answer questions. They don&apos;t belong on AskReddit.
 
If you see spam, report it!
 
 Posting any personal information will result in a ban. This includes linking to pictures hosted on Facebook as they can be linked back to an account.
 
If you think your post has disappeared, do not hesitate to contact one of the mods , we&apos;re happy to help.
 
 This sub reddit is not a replacement for local emergency services, legal consultation, medical consultation, missing persons inquiries, charity drives, or homework help. These types of posts will be removed. 
 
Soliciting for money is NOT ALLOWED. For this, please go to /r/Assistance 
 
 
 Other reddits you may like 

 &gt;Related Subreddits answers Relationships Ask Science Self ExplainLikeI&apos;mFive IAmA IdeasForTheAdmins Does Anybody Else Favors samplesize Techsupport Travel IRC TipOfMyTongue YouShouldKnow Assistance PoliticalDiscussion Askedreddit Today I Fucked Up Misc 
 
 Ever read the reddiquette ? Take a peek! 
 
 Join us in the AskReddit IRC! 

 Before posting, please read the subreddit rules in the sidebar. Also, you are advised to use the search feature to see if your question has already been asked. Remember that AskReddit is for thought-provoking, discussion-inspiring questions. The button is under the search bar. There are some great subreddits in the sidebar that may be more appropriate for your question. Non-compliance with the rules when posting a question, especially with the posting of any personal information, can and will result in a ban. 
 a community for 4 years Submit a link to anything interesting: news article, blog entry, video, picture... message the moderators 
MODERATORS
 
 noname99 qgyh2 spez kn0thing chromakode krispykrackers Poromenos BritishEnglishPolice waxpoet PhilxBefore ...and 19 more» 
 
reddit is a source for what&apos;s new and popular online. vote on links that you like or dislike and help decide what&apos;s popular, or submit your own! learn more› 
 

 1 2047 2048 2049 
 I just paid 4.21 for gas. The fast food restaurant I usually go to raised their price close to $7. Average cereal price is getting close to $4. At work there no salary increase, they just tell me I am lucky to have a job. What is going on? I am not happy. ( self.AskReddit ) 

submitted 1 year ago by llways 
 sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 6821 comments share cancel 
 top 200 comments show 500 sorted by: best hot new controversial top old best 
 
 [+] CushBowl 219 points 220 points 221 points 1 year ago  (7 children) 
 [–] CushBowl 219 points 220 points 221 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Its almost as if your country has been financing a decade long war on the other side of the planet by printing money.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] its_sea-man 853 points 854 points 855 points 1 year ago  (485 children) 
 [–] its_sea-man 853 points 854 points 855 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
wow, this post really hit home. i&apos;m a regional sales manager making 50,000 with zero benefits. no health care, no bonus, no 401k, no nothing. it pisses me off when i see my friends, family, and other people in general in much worse situations and it&apos;s pathetic that i feel extremely lucky where i&apos;m at. especially considering just a few years ago someone in my position would have made 80-100k with full benefits.

i recently put some part time job postings on craigslist and got an unbelievable amount of replies. most from people who are waayyyy over qualified for the simple position i&apos;m offering.

it&apos;s unbelievably sad and incredibly frustrating to see where this nation is going.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] CptnBatman 369 points 370 points 371 points 1 year ago  (134 children) 
 [–] CptnBatman 369 points 370 points 371 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Not only your nation. I&apos;m Canadian and about one year ago I was more-or-less the assistant manager at a retail store in a mall.

We put up an ad to hire a part-time sales associate on one job website, and in the mall flyer. The job was about 10-15 hours a week, and paid minimum wage.

The response was pretty great at first. After five hours, we just took the posting down because our inbox couldn&apos;t take it. I&apos;m talking well over 100 applications in a couple hours, for a part-time job in a mall. My city has a population of about 100 000 people.

The worst part? The people applying were WAY too qualified. Everyone had at least a BA, quite a few had long experience in offices etc., some had multiple degrees, and two even had their Masters. One was in education, and the other was something science related I think.

Some of them even came into the store hoping it would increase their chances, but they were mostly just sad. More than a couple were on the brink of tears, talking about how desperate they&apos;ve been for work. They were willing to do anything just to get even a small amount of income coming in. That whole day, and subsequent interview process, bummed me out for weeks.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Andaru 92 points 93 points 94 points 1 year ago  (20 children) 
 [–] Andaru 92 points 93 points 94 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Same goes in Italy. We have hordes of people with degrees, masters and all sorts of specialization and they can&apos;t find jobs. Most companies only hire temp workers dodging all regulations using loopholes, and use the fact that they can avoid renewing your contract as blackmail.

State jobs are so coveted that it&apos;s ridiculous: at the selection test for 100 jobs at the tax agency over 7000 people showed up, and people of course try every possible connection to jump ahead. There&apos;s also an excess of teachers compared to what the state can afford, so most of them are called just for subtitutions and cannot plan ahead for more than a few months at a time.

I have friends who are 35+ and still live with their parents because they cannot afford to rent a home even if they have a job.

The only jobs that -so far- are holding a bit better are IT jobs, but if things don&apos;t get better soon lots of people will be very very unhappy.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (20 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 150 points 151 points 152 points 1 year ago  (61 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 150 points 151 points 152 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
As one of those with a degree applying for minimum wage jobs: PLEASE STOP SAYING WE ARE OVERQUALIFIED! If you truly feel sympathetic to us, do not turn us down because we have an education and experience far above the minimum required for the position. And yes, we will leave when we get a better job. But you know what, there will ALWAYS be minimum wage workers to replace us in the long-run. So please. Please. Just hire the one that you think will do the best job. Period.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] truesound 159 points 160 points 161 points 1 year ago *   (30 children) 
 [–] truesound 159 points 160 points 161 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
&quot;Overqualification,&quot;is just a cop out. These jobs have high turnover rates in the first place, so worrying that the person will quit for a better gig is a distraction. The truth is that people with educations know how to properly value labor. They know to question hierarchies and how to valuate the performance of their superiors. What they are really worried about is educated people negotiating for better pay, organizing collective bargaining, proving the incompetance of management and threatening the complacency that goes with it or outperforming and advancing beyond them.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] stifin 102 points 103 points 104 points 1 year ago  (19 children) 
 [–] stifin 102 points 103 points 104 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
As someone who has worked a job I&apos;m overqualified for, I can understand the employer&apos;s position, and I can tell you you&apos;re wrong. I was the worst employee and I knew it. Not the worst performing mind you, but the worst to have from the employer&apos;s perspective.

I knew exactly how much work I had to do to be in the middle of the group. Not underperforming, but not exerting myself by any means. I had no interest in the job, and there&apos;s no room for advancement in retail unless you want to be a manager, and I certainly don&apos;t. So there&apos;s no reason to spend any extra effort.

That by itself would be fine, but the other thing is that you WILL leave the instant you get a better offer. Because you&quot;value labor&quot;as you say. And everyone values their own higher than others. So you&apos;re going to get that better offer, say&quot;I&apos;m worth it&quot;and move on. And why shouldn&apos;t you? But then, why would they hire you? The turnover rate isn&apos;t that high, especially in a shitty economy where people really need that minimum wage paycheck. But the other big thing is that you&apos;re more qualified, which means you&apos;re much more likely to actually get a better offer, hence more likely to leave.

And seriously, are you going to start organizing collective barganing for GameStop employees, or are you going to be online every night looking for a job suitable for college graduate with several years work experience?

Nobody is trying to keep you out of minimum wage jobs to maintain the status quo. The real reasons are far simpler than that.

And if you really want or need a minimum wage job, and you have a master&apos;s degree, you should be smart enough to not put that on your resume, knowing it&apos;s going to show you&apos;re overqualified. Plenty of people lie about being more qualified than they are. It should be much easier to leave your qualifications off a resume. And if you go in to a retail store telling a sob story about how you have a masters and you really need this job, well sorry, that&apos;s just the wrong way to go about applying for that job.

It sucks and it&apos;s unfair and the world would be much better if it was different. But it isn&apos;t. Ignoring reality doesn&apos;t change it.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (19 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (10 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (30 replies) 

 
 
 [+] FuturePastNow 137 points 138 points 139 points 1 year ago  (22 children) 
 [–] FuturePastNow 137 points 138 points 139 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I&apos;m Canadian
 
Yeah, well, at least you (and they) get health care. I&apos;ve never had a job that provided insurance.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (22 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (27 replies) 

 
 
 [+] gsamov2 150 points 151 points 152 points 1 year ago  (15 children) 
 [–] gsamov2 150 points 151 points 152 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
 Put Perfectly 

We know who to blame, but how do we fix it?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] belfastga 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] belfastga 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I just love how the entire 3 minutes, he doesn&apos;t even tell one joke. Just the goddamn truth.&lt;3 Carlin.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] frexistential 13 points 14 points 15 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] frexistential 13 points 14 points 15 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I really miss Carlin, bittersweet that all the darker aspects of his comedy ring truer and truer with the passage of each day.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 
 
 [+] neunen 475 points 476 points 477 points 1 year ago  (205 children) 
 [–] neunen 475 points 476 points 477 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
dude, i would kill to make 50k a year right now.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] skinneej 473 points 474 points 475 points 1 year ago  (29 children) 
 [–] skinneej 473 points 474 points 475 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
i think that&apos;s his point.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] solidwhetstone 160 points 161 points 162 points 1 year ago  (25 children) 
 [–] solidwhetstone 160 points 161 points 162 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
50k as a hitman hmmm?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] cdude 149 points 150 points 151 points 1 year ago  (23 children) 
 [–] cdude 149 points 150 points 151 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
50k per year as a hitman? What are you doing? Killing them softly with your words?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] naturalcauzes 106 points 107 points 108 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] naturalcauzes 106 points 107 points 108 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
No, he uses song.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] CaddyStrophic 22 points 23 points 24 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] CaddyStrophic 22 points 23 points 24 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Two times.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (13 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 267 points 268 points 269 points 1 year ago *   (142 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 267 points 268 points 269 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Ditto. Went to school for an Aerospace Engineering degree, which usually has starting salaries around 50K. I was unemployed after college for a while, found a temp job doing tech support for $12/hr for a while, and just now feel extremely lucky to have gotten a job as a lab tech for $30K/year. The job market is just totally fucked right now.

We&apos;re going to lose an entire generation (MY generation!) of engineers and scientists, because no one is hiring. Whenever the economy recovers, who are they going to hire:

A) Experienced professionals

B) Fresh graduates bursting with knowledge and enthusiasm

C) Disgruntled guys in their late 20s/early 30s who&apos;ve been working dead end jobs for 5 years and whatever skills or knowledge they learned has gone stale.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Poultry_Sashimi 228 points 229 points 230 points 1 year ago  (60 children) 
 [–] Poultry_Sashimi 228 points 229 points 230 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
D) Chinese post docs.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (60 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (81 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (31 replies) 

 
 
 [+] FoppishDandy 50 points 51 points 52 points 1 year ago  (16 children) 
 [–] FoppishDandy 50 points 51 points 52 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
The economy is very strange right now. I&apos;ve seen two mid-level execs who lost their jobs, never to find a new one in that industry. Your post made me think, because one was the&quot;regional sales manager&quot;role you mentioned. He had a medical issue, lost his job and that was that. He&apos;s better, but now he&apos;s middle-aged with a medical problem in his past, which is like code for&quot;DO NOT HIRE&quot;to HR types. The other person now short-sells homes for people after being a VP at a Fortune 500.

I&apos;m fortunate for now, because I&apos;m in software, which apparently has high talent demand right now, but everything is relative. In 2001 I was laid off as a high paid contractor. I was very lucky to land a job with a 42% pay cut. My wages haven&apos;t gone back to 2001 levels a decade later.

ECONOMY Y U NO HAVE GOOD JOBS?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] StabbyPants 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] StabbyPants 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It occurs to me that if we had socialized health care, then employers wouldn&apos;t have that incentive not to hire the guy with health problems.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago  (6 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It doesn&apos;t make any sense at all for health insurance to be tied to your employment. This was my biggest disappointment with Obama&apos;s health care plan - it didn&apos;t break this link.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] mrpeabody208 44 points 45 points 46 points 1 year ago  (19 children) 
 [–] mrpeabody208 44 points 45 points 46 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I find the crushing depression of our economic situation to be quite liberating. I quit school to work an office job a few years ago. I got promoted and given a raise rather early. Then the October 2008 and onwards mess made the business overprotective of its bottom line. No more wage increases despite increasing business equaled a sputtering career for me. I finally left recently to go back to college.

I had once been profoundly offended by the university debt machine and vowed to make my own way in life. Finding&quot;my own way&quot;to now be barricaded, I decided crippling debt and no prospects is at least a change in pace from numbing sameness and no prospects. Think of it this way:&quot;What better time to completely change my life? I&apos;m fucked either way, right?&quot;The shittiest decision you could make is now roughly equivalent to the best decision you could make. The only movement we&apos;re allowed to make now is horizontal.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (19 replies) 

 
 
 [+] veverkap 33 points 34 points 35 points 1 year ago  (24 children) 
 [–] veverkap 33 points 34 points 35 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Which region are you making 50k in though? That&apos;s decent in the midwest, bad in the northeast.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (24 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (66 replies) 

 
 
 [+] titanicx 149 points 150 points 151 points 1 year ago  (51 children) 
 [–] titanicx 149 points 150 points 151 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Wages have not risen in something like 13 years, yet the cost of living has gone way up. The job that we do paid similar a decade ago. Sad, I know, but hey good news, CEO&apos;s are making more!
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] lundah 76 points 77 points 78 points 1 year ago  (32 children) 
 [–] lundah 76 points 77 points 78 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
This is true, I&apos;m making the same now as I did in 2001. Tell me the price of ANYTHING that&apos;s the same now as it was 10 years ago.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] gameshot911 252 points 253 points 254 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] gameshot911 252 points 253 points 254 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
TI-83 calculator?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] OMouse 44 points 45 points 46 points 1 year ago  (7 children) 
 [–] OMouse 44 points 45 points 46 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
We should use those as currency, at least they don&apos;t suffer from inflation ;p
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Patriark 67 points 68 points 69 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] Patriark 67 points 68 points 69 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Also you can use it to calculate inflation
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (23 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (18 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Komrad33 607 points 608 points 609 points 1 year ago  (34 children) 
 [–] Komrad33 607 points 608 points 609 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
the fecal matter has hit the oscillating unit.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] iamnotatroll 180 points 181 points 182 points 1 year ago  (12 children) 
 [–] iamnotatroll 180 points 181 points 182 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
lucky rich bastard. my unit doesn&apos;t oscillate.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (20 replies) 

 
 
 [+] be81827 272 points 273 points 274 points 1 year ago  (31 children) 
 [–] be81827 272 points 273 points 274 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Welcome to the recovery. Same as the recession.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] The_Egg_Man 100 points 101 points 102 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] The_Egg_Man 100 points 101 points 102 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Meet the new boss, same as the old boss
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Taze_T_Schnitzel 138 points 139 points 140 points 1 year ago  (19 children) 
 [–] Taze_T_Schnitzel 138 points 139 points 140 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Is it just me, or is the&quot;recovery&quot;a political propaganda line? Nothing has changed.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Nyax-A 259 points 260 points 261 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] Nyax-A 259 points 260 points 261 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Recovery is code for&quot;we got away with it&quot;.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 
 
 [+] korvanos 7 points 8 points 9 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] korvanos 7 points 8 points 9 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It recovered for the rich. Let&apos;s give them another tax break so they can recover some more.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (13 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 
 
 [+] reallybigshark 503 points 504 points 505 points 1 year ago  (351 children) 
 [–] reallybigshark 503 points 504 points 505 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I fucking hate that&quot;You&apos;re lucky to have job line&quot;that wore out about 2 years ago. I also have had no salary increases in the last 3 years and the pricing of things is getting ridiculous. It&apos;s really bad when you are at the supermarket and you are wondering if you can afford this or that.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] DoctorAtreides 93 points 94 points 95 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] DoctorAtreides 93 points 94 points 95 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Right after I graduated from university (2009), I was working very part time in a retail job--the same retail job I&apos;d had for almost 3 years and I kept getting&quot;you&apos;re so lucky to even have a job.&quot;I finally snapped and started telling people&quot;You think this is lucky? I&apos;ve had this job for 3 years because I&apos;m a good employee and I&apos;m good at it. In fact, I&apos;ve lost hours recently, plus I have a degree now. There&apos;s nothing fucking lucky about it!&quot;It still kind of makes me angry, obviously.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Detached09 346 points 347 points 348 points 1 year ago  (280 children) 
 [–] Detached09 346 points 347 points 348 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It&apos;s even worse when you can&apos;t afford to go to the supermarket.

Between my rent, car payment, and Uncle Sam taking out his cut, I&apos;m lucky to have gas to get to and from work every day. I can&apos;t afford groceries, and if it weren&apos;t for getting free meals at work I wouldn&apos;t be able to eat.

But, I&apos;ve applied for government assistance. And been told that even though I don&apos;t make enough money to afford groceries, I make too much money for any sort of welfare assistance.

And this is after getting a 50% raise in February. Before that, I was lucky to make ends meet.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] rancid_squirts 209 points 210 points 211 points 1 year ago  (35 children) 
 [–] rancid_squirts 209 points 210 points 211 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
how uniquely american!
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 197 points 198 points 199 points 1 year ago *   (33 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 197 points 198 points 199 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
how uniquely american!
 
Just a bit of context. 

George Bush fields a question from a woman who states that she works three jobs. Bush says&quot;Uniquely American, isn&apos;t it? That&apos;s just great that you do that.&quot;
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] ErnieErmps 96 points 97 points 98 points 1 year ago  (13 children) 
 [–] ErnieErmps 96 points 97 points 98 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Bush pretty much summed up the GOP position on all of this: if you have trouble living on your two jobs, simply go out and get a third one! Also, if you want to be rich, that&apos;s simple: just inherit $50 million or so like Donald Trump.

An important aspect of all of this that some people overlook is that the terrible amount of inflation for about the last ten years can be linked in large part to the tax cuts for the richest Americans. That lost tax revenue drives up the national debt, which means more dollars in circulation&quot;chasing&quot;the same goods... --&gt;inflation.

So... what&apos;s the GOP solution at this point? MORE tax cuts for the rich. (And kill Planned Parenthood... that&apos;ll fix things.)
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] arc13 135 points 136 points 137 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] arc13 135 points 136 points 137 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I am sick of people like you that complain about the wealthy all the time, if you had just worked a little harder at inheriting money instead of being a lazy bum having abortions every other day for fun. Sheesh, the nerve of some peasants people
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] semicolonihasone 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] semicolonihasone 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
And don&apos;t forget that when they have a break between abortions, all they do is listen to NPR and think of ways to hate America.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (18 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 
 
 [+] noreallyimthepope 102 points 103 points 104 points 1 year ago  (165 children) 
 [–] noreallyimthepope 102 points 103 points 104 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
WTH are you doing that pays so little that a 50% increase is even possible?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Detached09 238 points 239 points 240 points 1 year ago  (163 children) 
 [–] Detached09 238 points 239 points 240 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I went from $10 to $15. It involved getting a new job.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] killien 179 points 180 points 181 points 1 year ago  (132 children) 
 [–] killien 179 points 180 points 181 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
your rent and car payments are too high.

downgrade your lifestyle if possible.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] jaunty_jawa 107 points 108 points 109 points 1 year ago  (14 children) 
 [–] jaunty_jawa 107 points 108 points 109 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
The initial cost of downgrading can be an impossibility for some people. For example, having to pay a deposit + first and possibly last months rent on a new, cheaper apartment, as opposed to just one month&apos;s rent at an expensive apartment. Not to mention breaking lease terms, etc.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] CuriousJore 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] CuriousJore 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Downgrade by acquiring roommate?
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (12 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (116 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (30 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (78 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago  (7 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I can&apos;t afford to go to the store. I can&apos;t afford an apartment. I feel like the biggest loser in the world when I work harder than most people I work with and don&apos;t make a living wage. I&apos;m nearing the end of my rope. I have shit job, no money, no friends, no girlfriend, and no potential. Why do I even wake up in the morning? Obviously I don&apos;t WANT to die, but the things I actually want (a nice girl to love and who loves me, some friends, a place to live) seem so impossible for me. I just can&apos;t keep up with this world.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (54 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Zilvreen 866 points 867 points 868 points 1 year ago  (715 children) 
 [–] Zilvreen 866 points 867 points 868 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Grab an american history book and open to the chapter on the 30s/40s. Now add iPods and Hot Pockets. That&apos;s what&apos;s going on.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] i4ybrid 503 points 504 points 505 points 1 year ago  (117 children) 
 [–] i4ybrid 503 points 504 points 505 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Coincidentally, I talked to a friend a few days ago that hot pockets are putting less filling there. THIS IS THE LAST STRAW!
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Zilvreen 322 points 323 points 324 points 1 year ago  (35 children) 
 [–] Zilvreen 322 points 323 points 324 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Welp, looks like it&apos;s time for the uprising.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] solidwhetstone 41 points 42 points 43 points 1 year ago  (10 children) 
 [–] solidwhetstone 41 points 42 points 43 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
What happened to the American dream?

It came true.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Zilvreen 59 points 60 points 61 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] Zilvreen 59 points 60 points 61 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Honestly, I am a firm believer that the American Dream was created to placate the middle class and the immigrants coming to America to make something of themselves. The idea that if you work really hard, pay your taxes, hang out with your buddies down at [local social gathering place] once a week, get a 30-year mortgage on a 3 bedroom 1.5 bathroom house in the suburbs with a white picket fence, marry your highschool sweetheart and have 2.5 kids which she stays home to take care of while you go to work at the same company you worked your way up to the bottom from to the place you are now with the good benefits and decent pension. This job pays enough for you to live comfortably while still putting money away for college for the kids.

In reality, the American Way holds precedence. Take what you can and fuck* the other guy. My oldest brother is basically the biggest conman and hustler I know. He is living very comfortably. I don&apos;t begrudge him it, he earned it, though I may have qualms about how.

Edit: typo
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] AlphaKlams 68 points 69 points 70 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] AlphaKlams 68 points 69 points 70 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I think it was George Carlin who said&quot;It&apos;s called the American Dream because you&apos;d have to be asleep to believe it.&quot;
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (24 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 1 year ago *   (64 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
[deleted]
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] NickBR 508 points 509 points 510 points 1 year ago  (26 children) 
 [–] NickBR 508 points 509 points 510 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I like that you have 3 examples, 2 of which are burritos.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] mrpeabody208 35 points 36 points 37 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] mrpeabody208 35 points 36 points 37 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
The old&quot;guns and butter&quot;economic descriptor has run its course. Kids these days just don&apos;t respond to&quot;guns and butter&quot;. We find the new&quot;pizza-burrito-mysterious other burrito&quot;model has more relevance to today&apos;s youth. We will commence retrofitting our textbooks.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 
 
 [+] warbaby-baby 74 points 75 points 76 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] warbaby-baby 74 points 75 points 76 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Every food example, should by law, include at least one burrito.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] the_ouskull 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] the_ouskull 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Why not just CALL the guy a pothead, geez? =)
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (14 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Xhafzotaj 19 points 20 points 21 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] Xhafzotaj 19 points 20 points 21 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
 cough El Monterey cough 

Yeah, I noticed that too.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (35 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (16 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (597 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Moridyn 1741 points 1742 points 1743 points 1 year ago *   (2345 children) 
 [–] Moridyn 1741 points 1742 points 1743 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
To put it very simply, wages are not rising even though cost of living is.

Cost of living has been rising for the past hundred years, so that&apos;s nothing new. But also for the past hundred years, wages have been rising faster than cost of living (even including inflation in both cases). In the last generation (the baby boomers), employers figured out that they didn&apos;t have to keep increasing wages . Massive deregulation followed suit.

Wages have been flat or falling for the past several years. Americans have tried to compensate by working more, taking on more jobs, or having both parents in a household work (ever think about how it was possible in the 40s for just the father to support a family, yet now it&apos;s very difficult?).

Productivity, due to this, has been skyrocketing. But instead of this productivity creating increased wages, it has been creating ungodly large profits for corporate bosses, CEOs, and other people who happened to be at the top of the financial sector 30 years ago or so.

So TL;DR: you&apos;re getting fucked over by rich guys. And Zilvreen is right, something very similar happened near the turn of the century preceding and during the Great Depression. Rich people wanted to get richer.

PS: as an aside, the entire idea of the&quot;american dream&quot;has been fueled by the fact that wages historically have risen faster than cost of living. So in the past, if you worked hard enough you actually could advance your station in life. Nowadays that&apos;s not the case anymore unless you&apos;re a very lucky and driven enterpreneur.

Edit: oh jesus I caught the hivemind&apos;s attention. I&apos;ll try to answer your questions as best I can, but it helps best to educate yourself on these matters. To hear a real economist speak about the above phenomenon, google Richard Wolff&apos;s talk:&quot;Capitalism Hits the Fan&quot;. And remember that I&apos;m talking about a simplified version of his simplified version.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] stealthmodeactive 615 points 616 points 617 points 1 year ago  (1499 children) 
 [–] stealthmodeactive 615 points 616 points 617 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
In Canada I see spit-in-your-face job postings, people wanting to hire an IT tech for $12/hr with a diploma.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] shanealeslie 836 points 837 points 838 points 1 year ago  (129 children) 
 [–] shanealeslie 836 points 837 points 838 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I make that cleaning up bars all day - but I also get free food, drinks and to see live bands whenever I want. A year and I half ago I was in IT.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] cutlerchris 185 points 186 points 187 points 1 year ago  (6 children) 
 [–] cutlerchris 185 points 186 points 187 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
After being unemployed for 6 months, I got a gig doing IT that&apos;s actually paying pretty well. Where? It&apos;s a foreclosure law firm.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] SuburbanRedneck 29 points 30 points 31 points 1 year ago *   (4 children) 
 [–] SuburbanRedneck 29 points 30 points 31 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I sold out too and went into the financial industry. I just hope they give my soul back when I leave.

Edit: Too many toos.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] mst3kcrow 31 points 32 points 33 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] mst3kcrow 31 points 32 points 33 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
The only way to get your soul back when you leave is to give Anon root access to the servers.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] jamie1414 24 points 25 points 26 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] jamie1414 24 points 25 points 26 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Doing the lords work one network at a time.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 
 
 [+] mattseg 253 points 254 points 255 points 1 year ago  (6 children) 
 [–] mattseg 253 points 254 points 255 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Among the most interesting and telling posts in this mess.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] beholdtruth 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] beholdtruth 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I have a degree in nothing, and I do the same thing!
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 8 points 9 points 10 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 8 points 9 points 10 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Bad economy -&gt;Greater patronage of bars
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] randybingo 60 points 61 points 62 points 1 year ago  (52 children) 
 [–] randybingo 60 points 61 points 62 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I make $14.10 at a grocery store. Kind of free food, and I get to go to work stoned out of my mind.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (52 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (62 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Byaaah 145 points 146 points 147 points 1 year ago  (214 children) 
 [–] Byaaah 145 points 146 points 147 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
This is in America too. Graduate great university and with quite a bit of student loan debt. Get offered $15/hr jobs. There are so many of us young people graduating each year and so many people with 4 year degrees out there, they can just keep offering these low paying jobs knowing (over)qualified people will take them because they need the money.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] nauree 316 points 317 points 318 points 1 year ago  (144 children) 
 [–] nauree 316 points 317 points 318 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Wait for the student loan bubble to burst.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] HunterSThompson_says 136 points 137 points 138 points 1 year ago  (16 children) 
 [–] HunterSThompson_says 136 points 137 points 138 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Been waiting on this one myself. It&apos;s going to be a doozy - most people I know who are 20-something are coming out of school 50 or 100 grand in debt, and they&apos;re finding shit for jobs.

It&apos;s going to be a bloodbath.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] babycheeses 25 points 26 points 27 points 1 year ago  (7 children) 
 [–] babycheeses 25 points 26 points 27 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Dont worry, the boomers are all done school, so it doesnt matter.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] jackmaninov 28 points 29 points 30 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] jackmaninov 28 points 29 points 30 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I&apos;m excited for when the boomers figure out there&apos;s no one to sell their houses to... :P
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] platypuscandy 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] platypuscandy 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Seriously. In less than 15-20 years America is FUCKED.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (8 replies) 

 
 
 [+] fluxity 52 points 53 points 54 points 1 year ago  (99 children) 
 [–] fluxity 52 points 53 points 54 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
What does this mean? I&apos;d like to hear more, as I am about to graduate with an obscene amount of loans into a career field that&apos;s not hiring. It keeps me up at night, thinking about those payments....
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] HunterSThompson_says 88 points 89 points 90 points 1 year ago  (65 children) 
 [–] HunterSThompson_says 88 points 89 points 90 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It means that you are one of many, many, many people in the same boat, and a lot of those loans are going to people who won&apos;t be able to pay them back.

Those loans aren&apos;t the sort that you can lose via bankruptcy, and some of the students are going to be underwater for life. These sorts of loans allow wage garnishment, same as if you had childcare obligations, so the bank gets paid back even if you have to starve to death.

Frankly, I would leave the USA in that situation, but most Americans don&apos;t know how to survive, and thus that isn&apos;t an option.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] fluxity 84 points 85 points 86 points 1 year ago  (51 children) 
 [–] fluxity 84 points 85 points 86 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I just don&apos;t understand the system, I guess.

Why do they spend every moment of our childhood drilling us with this&quot;go to college or you won&apos;t become anything&quot;mantra, when none of us can actually afford to pay for it?

But we do as we&apos;re told, and we go to school - doing whatever it takes to pay for it, only to graduate into a world with less than nothing - less than I had when I started school! And to add insult to injury, that world can&apos;t (won&apos;t?) pay me what I&apos;m worth, much less what I need to make in order to pay my astronomical debt back. Rage rage rage.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] smemily 42 points 43 points 44 points 1 year ago  (32 children) 
 [–] smemily 42 points 43 points 44 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Because you&apos;re even more fucked without school.

They have repayment plan that&apos;s based on your income, you know. After 25 years whatever&apos;s left is forgiven. And like taxes, your spouse and kids are deductions on your income.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] fluxity 11 points 12 points 13 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] fluxity 11 points 12 points 13 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I didn&apos;t know about the deductions! I don&apos;t have kids or a spouse, but it&apos;s nice to know that they&apos;ll take it into consideration if I ever do. Thanks.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (27 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (18 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (13 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Retanaru 29 points 30 points 31 points 1 year ago *   (8 children) 
 [–] Retanaru 29 points 30 points 31 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Well, the housing bubble was loaning people money they couldn&apos;t afford to pay back. Now the student loan bubble will be the same thing, except they will be foreclosing on peoples lives instead.

Edit: spelling
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] fluxity 17 points 18 points 19 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] fluxity 17 points 18 points 19 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
they will be foreclosing on peoples lives instead.
 
Well put.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] nauree 21 points 22 points 23 points 1 year ago  (11 children) 
 [–] nauree 21 points 22 points 23 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It keeps me up at night, thinking about those payments....
 
Start planning a life in another country. Easiest way to escape the loans.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Edison_Was_Scum 42 points 43 points 44 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] Edison_Was_Scum 42 points 43 points 44 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
 Only way to escape them.

Unless you can pay them back. I put every spare penny from a pretty good job into them when I graduated and finished them years early. Everyone thought I was paranoid, but being laid off is a lot less stressful when you don&apos;t have to find a way to make those payments every month.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (8 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (12 replies) 

 
 
 [+] crxgames 67 points 68 points 69 points 1 year ago  (10 children) 
 [–] crxgames 67 points 68 points 69 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
So few people even see this yet. Upvote for you.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] mcotostl 72 points 73 points 74 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] mcotostl 72 points 73 points 74 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It&apos;s only a matter of time. Interesting point of note: Whenever available Federal education loan funding rises there is a parallel increase in average tuition costs.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (16 replies) 

 
 
 [+] parafrog 60 points 61 points 62 points 1 year ago  (32 children) 
 [–] parafrog 60 points 61 points 62 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
My boss refuses to hire anyone overqualified. He doesn&apos;t like the idea of spending time and money training someone that will leave as soon as something better comes along. Sadly, I know many other employers like this.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] x-lurker 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] x-lurker 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
No Rule that says you need to list your B.A./B.S. degree on your resume, especially if you are overqualified for the job you are applying for.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] techmaster242 8 points 9 points 10 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] techmaster242 8 points 9 points 10 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
That was a rule of applying jobs long before this depression we&apos;re in. Always tailor your resume to the job you are applying for. Take out irrelevant work experience or education. Granted, that&apos;s a bit harder to do if your resume is short on actual experience and you&apos;re fresh out of college with a fancy piece of paper. Even if you have a degree, you often need to start at the bottom of any field and start learning the actual industry/job.

For example, I can&apos;t believe the number of people with CS degrees who then try to get into IT, thinking they know everything about computers. Sorry, but in IT a CS degree is almost worthless, and you&apos;re probably going to have to start as a desktop tech like everyone else does. In IT, real-world experience and wisdom are your most valuable assets, period.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (23 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (35 replies) 

 
 
 [+] dent308 249 points 250 points 251 points 1 year ago  (39 children) 
 [–] dent308 249 points 250 points 251 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
No shit. I did the math on a programming job here and I can make more money as a farm laborer. Thinking of getting back into farming. At least that way I am producing food, and not bullshit.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] contextISeverything 277 points 278 points 279 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] contextISeverything 277 points 278 points 279 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
In fact, you&apos;ll be using bullshit to produce food! Well, cowshit, same dif.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 39 points 40 points 41 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 39 points 40 points 41 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Yeah, but at least that way I don&apos;t have to make the bullshit.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 22 points 23 points 24 points 1 year ago  (3 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 22 points 23 points 24 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Depends on the area of the farm you&apos;re getting your shit from, but it&apos;s probably a mix of cowshit, bullshit, and steershit.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (29 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 1 year ago  (223 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
[deleted]
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Sabin10 152 points 153 points 154 points 1 year ago  (198 children) 
 [–] Sabin10 152 points 153 points 154 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Even better, in Ontario our minimum wage is $10.25 so $12 is completely retarded.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] gr3enman 132 points 133 points 134 points 1 year ago  (146 children) 
 [–] gr3enman 132 points 133 points 134 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
in michgan, the minimum wage is only $7.40
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] honda27 243 points 244 points 245 points 1 year ago  (132 children) 
 [–] honda27 243 points 244 points 245 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Woohoo, makin&apos;$7.25 in Texas! Well what do you mean? Of course that&apos;s enough to live on, don&apos;t your boots have straps?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Tokeli 224 points 225 points 226 points 1 year ago  (79 children) 
 [–] Tokeli 224 points 225 points 226 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Pst, $7.25 is the Federal minimum wage. If Texas could have it any lower, they probably would.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 153 points 154 points 155 points 1 year ago  (12 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 153 points 154 points 155 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
hell yeah we would!
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (12 replies) 

 
 
 [+] jellyfish101 71 points 72 points 73 points 1 year ago  (54 children) 
 [–] jellyfish101 71 points 72 points 73 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
20 dollars per hour working in McDonald&apos;s in Australia.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (52 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (52 replies) 

 
 
 [+] eyeforgotmyname 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] eyeforgotmyname 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
 http://www.dol.gov/whd/minwage/america.htm 
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (50 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (24 replies) 

 
 
 [+] mayoriguana 52 points 53 points 54 points 1 year ago  (32 children) 
 [–] mayoriguana 52 points 53 points 54 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I currently work for $12/hr as a biomedical engineer. There are too many students graduating and few seem willing to give benefits to anyone without a decade or two of experience.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 1 year ago  (10 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
[deleted]
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (10 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (21 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Rivent 158 points 159 points 160 points 1 year ago  (391 children) 
 [–] Rivent 158 points 159 points 160 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
U.S.-based computer tech here, with diploma, earning $12 an hour... a spit in my face indeed, but it&apos;s all I can find...
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Aikidi 75 points 76 points 77 points 1 year ago  (47 children) 
 [–] Aikidi 75 points 76 points 77 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
You&apos;d make more money waiting tables. That fucking sucks man.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] polyrhythmic 97 points 98 points 99 points 1 year ago  (34 children) 
 [–] polyrhythmic 97 points 98 points 99 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Waiting tables is actually pretty difficult to do really well. It took a long time for my pay in tech to catch up with what I was making serving/bartending. Everyone wants a job in tech because they hear it&apos;s hot, whereas few people want to work late into the night while getting yelled at and eat dinner at midnight.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] omnilynx 118 points 119 points 120 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] omnilynx 118 points 119 points 120 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
few people want to work late into the night while getting yelled at and eat dinner at midnight.
 
Well then they definitely shouldn&apos;t go into tech.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (33 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Rivent 23 points 24 points 25 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] Rivent 23 points 24 points 25 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I know... but with this I can at least get some semblance of experience somewhat related to my field.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] hekx 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] hekx 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I work 12 hours a day at the Church and Dwight Warehouse for $11.00 an hour. Its dusty and I spend the first hours wage paying for gas to get out there.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] DoTheDew 14 points 15 points 16 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] DoTheDew 14 points 15 points 16 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Prior to this year, I drove close to 120 miles round trip to work everyday. I did this for about 3 years. I now live about a mile from work, and my rent is about $100/month less. It feels like I got a $600/month raise with the added benefit that I&apos;m not putting 30,000 miles on my car per year anymore.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] MyNameisDucks 51 points 52 points 53 points 1 year ago  (18 children) 
 [–] MyNameisDucks 51 points 52 points 53 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Wow thats terrible. I&apos;m a lifeguard in washington and I make nearly 15/hr with no degree but highschool.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Rivent 15 points 16 points 17 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] Rivent 15 points 16 points 17 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I envy you.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (15 replies) 

 
 
 [+] northbayray 168 points 169 points 170 points 1 year ago  (67 children) 
 [–] northbayray 168 points 169 points 170 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Master&apos;s degree, Clinical Psychology, currently cooking for less than $10 an hour. Very happy to see the US government legally protecting corrupt businessmen on Wall Street every step of their frenzied, greedy way. And talking about going after a Goldman Sach&apos;s exec or two does not count as justice. Regardless of how high it&apos;s possible to go in a career, there&apos;s still something to be said for integrity and a lifestyle that is below one&apos;s means. I love the old saying&quot;live simply so that others may simply live.&quot;I doubt any of the crooks in the government and financial sectors of the US have ever thought about the repercussions of unchecked greed, and those who have seem to be a near-extinct breed.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 104 points 105 points 106 points 1 year ago  (6 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 104 points 105 points 106 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Hate to say it but the politico&apos;s are working hand in hand with big business because they are PART OF big business. The doors swing both ways in government and business. The same people end up taking seats in both. Ie. You work in big business and then end up in government. You work in government and end up in big business.

That&apos;s why things are fucked up.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (60 replies) 

 
 
 [+] your_illegit_dad 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago  (13 children) 
 [–] your_illegit_dad 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It&apos;s not much better in the world of science/academia either. I have a master&apos;s degree in cell/molecular biology, and make $12.45/hr to manage a research lab...granted, the low wages are compensated by the resultant opportunities (ie publications and a recent acceptance into medical school), but wages across the board appear to be dismal, even for employees that have invested the time/effort to get an education.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (13 replies) 

 
 
 [+] ModernTenshi04 56 points 57 points 58 points 1 year ago  (52 children) 
 [–] ModernTenshi04 56 points 57 points 58 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
U.S. based computer tech here, with a bachelor&apos;s degree, earning $55k a year salary babysitting servers and servicing applications for various departments of a mid-sized company. A week or so ago I was getting calls or e-mails every day about jobs in other states and even my own.

I&apos;m not saying your situation isn&apos;t common, but I&apos;d also say you aren&apos;t looking hard enough. Look to get with a hiring firm of some sort. I&apos;ve used several in all my job searches, and they&apos;ve been very handy. They can look for jobs while you&apos;re working. Just don&apos;t work with one that you have to pay, work with one that gets paid by the company that hires you.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Rivent 10 points 11 points 12 points 1 year ago  (18 children) 
 [–] Rivent 10 points 11 points 12 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Fair enough... any suggestions on firms that you know to be particularly good?
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (18 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (33 replies) 

 
 
 [+] BatmanInTheHood 32 points 33 points 34 points 1 year ago  (50 children) 
 [–] BatmanInTheHood 32 points 33 points 34 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
What&apos;s your degree in and experience? My company is hiring at way more than $12 an hour. Could you find a better job if you moved? -- U.S. based system administrator.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] pyrotechie83 25 points 26 points 27 points 1 year ago  (23 children) 
 [–] pyrotechie83 25 points 26 points 27 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Rivent mentions a diploma, but no degree. When I graduated high school and only had a diploma, I was making only about $10 / hr as well. I think that&apos;s to be expected. Diplomas don&apos;t carry much weight anymore.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] 1137 56 points 57 points 58 points 1 year ago  (17 children) 
 [–] 1137 56 points 57 points 58 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Diplomas don&apos;t mean anything anymore thanks to&quot;no child left behind&quot;.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] pyrotechie83 39 points 40 points 41 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] pyrotechie83 39 points 40 points 41 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I graduated before NCLB, and it was still pretty worthless after high school. Bachelor&apos;s degrees are the new diploma. And with so many students going off to get master&apos;s degrees instead of getting entry-level jobs, I&apos;m sure a bachelor&apos;s will be worthless in the future as well. When I hear of someone going back to school for their master&apos;s instead of getting a job post-undergrad, I always urge them to get the job first, then get a master&apos;s at the same time. Having a master&apos;s along with work experience will go MUCH further than just the degree.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (9 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (26 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (138 replies) 

 
 
 [+] angrytroll123 176 points 177 points 178 points 1 year ago  (296 children) 
 [–] angrytroll123 176 points 177 points 178 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
You should take those jobs and do a bad job so those people will hire for more money.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] delirium2k 455 points 456 points 457 points 1 year ago  (288 children) 
 [–] delirium2k 455 points 456 points 457 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Upvotes for this. Every time I start a new job I try to figure out whether good performance is rewarded or taken advantage of. If it is taken advantage of, I figure out who the worst coworker is. I then work slightly harder or more proficiently than this worker.

If companies want good workers, they will pay good wages. If they want to pay me shit wages, I will trade them for shit work.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] 17-40 361 points 362 points 363 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] 17-40 361 points 362 points 363 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
&quot;If you don&apos;t like your job, you don&apos;t strike. You just go in everyday and do it really half-assed. That&apos;s the American way&quot;
 
-Homer Simpson
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 
 
 [+] jdi_nit 460 points 461 points 462 points 1 year ago  (50 children) 
 [–] jdi_nit 460 points 461 points 462 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Best summed up by a guy I bought some smokes from a couple years ago:&quot;They pretend to pay, I pretend to work&quot;
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] TheJollyLlama875 266 points 267 points 268 points 1 year ago  (20 children) 
 [–] TheJollyLlama875 266 points 267 points 268 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I always liked&quot;They get the dollar, and I get the dime; that&apos;s why I shit on company time.&quot;
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 184 points 185 points 186 points 1 year ago  (17 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 184 points 185 points 186 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I always make an effort to hold my shit in, in the mornings so i can take a shit on company time.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (17 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] sixtyfivedays 158 points 159 points 160 points 1 year ago  (16 children) 
 [–] sixtyfivedays 158 points 159 points 160 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Maurice&apos;Maury&apos;Levy: You are feeding off the violence and the despair of the drug trade. You are stealing from those who themselves are stealing the lifeblood from our city. You are a parasite who leeches off the culture of drugs...

Omar Little: Just like you, man.

Maurice&apos;Maury&apos;Levy: Excuse me? What?

Omar Little: I got the shotgun. You got the briefcase. It&apos;s all in the game though, right?
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] drcyclops 7 points 8 points 9 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] drcyclops 7 points 8 points 9 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Omar is the only businessman I trust.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (15 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (12 replies) 

 
 
 [+] ButtonFury 304 points 305 points 306 points 1 year ago  (40 children) 
 [–] ButtonFury 304 points 305 points 306 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I worked for a bank a few years back as a part time employee. It was in a cash vault so everyone&apos;s performance was production based. Customer deposits were received, then processed, then the currency was sorted and bundled, and then finally sent back out in the form of change orders or deposits to the Federal Reserve.

When I first started I really slacked off. Bonus/raise time came around and I got 1.5% increase for 6 months of work. I said to myself:&quot;Let&apos;s see what happens if I TRY &quot;. So for the next year I was the best at everything. I learned the processes IN AND OUT. I rewrote many of them; eliminating unnecessary redundancies. I could substitute in every department for people on vacation or sick leave and I would do the best. I would process the most deposits per hour out of everyone. I would sort and bundle the most currency out of everyone. I would process the most change orders per hour than anyone else. And I was accurate too. I never had outages. They laid off two of my supervisors and gave me their responsibilities. I had no change in job title or pay.

Then came raise/bonus time. For my one year of badassness, learning every department, being the best, I got 3%. I got twice what I got the previous year for twice the amount of time of service. So, I stopped being the best. I stopped volunteering in other departments. My bills per hour went from 22,000/hr to 3,500/hr. In a single shift where I would sort and bundle $13M, I would do $2M. I drove that fucking place&apos;s numbers into the red. And the cool thing was that it didn&apos;t take very long for it to happen. 2 months went by and we went from an average daily cash balance of about $30M to about $160M. I quit that fucking job about 2 months later. It took them 6 months to climb out of the hole I created. Fuckers.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 134 points 135 points 136 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 134 points 135 points 136 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I used to work nights at a factory, 12 hour shifts, 3 days a week, 7 p.m. to 7 a.m. Every couple of weeks they would a new day, until 3 months in I was working 12 hours a day, 6 days a week.

Then they started taking people away, jobs that took 3 were down to two, then just me. They knew they could do this because I was desperate and couldn&apos;t quit.

One day I cut open my hand and the machine operator refused to let me take care of it because he would have to take over my post while I tended it because he was a lazy bastard. I waited and bid my time, saving money so i didn&apos;t need the job, until one night when they had a lot of people had called of and my press was at minimum staff. Then I just walked out. the fore man came and told me to get back to work and told him I quit.

With out me to tend the press they would have to shut it down. The thing cost them $10k an hour when down.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] blancs50 24 points 25 points 26 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] blancs50 24 points 25 points 26 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I would&apos;ve feined nerve damage in my hand and tried to get workman&apos;s comp. Its why these companies pay workman&apos;s comp insurance instead of paying for safe work environments.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] wtfUass 30 points 31 points 32 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] wtfUass 30 points 31 points 32 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
As much as people freak out and hate unions.....for your reason alone that is why they are there. Ever watch the move Norma Ray? Check it out.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 
 
 [+] ruff1234 26 points 27 points 28 points 1 year ago  (5 children) 
 [–] ruff1234 26 points 27 points 28 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Same thing happened to me as a content analyst. I worked my ass off, learned everything I could and wrote nearly twice as many articles per hour as my coworkers. A year and a half later my boss gets fired and guess what happens? They dump her workload on me - no bonus, no raise, no change in job title, even though I was then managing my coworkers. I ask about a promotion and they give me the thumbs up.

But nothing happens. Then they stall for two months and end up hiring someone I had to train.

I couldn&apos;t have quit that job any faster.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] ButtonFury 63 points 64 points 65 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] ButtonFury 63 points 64 points 65 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
If you make yourself irreplaceable, you make yourself unpromotable.

Also, the biggest raise you&apos;ll ever get is from another company.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] megs11237 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] megs11237 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I was offered a promotion with no raise because&quot;we are in a recession&quot;and I turned it down, since it would be way more work with same pay. I was glad I did for 2 reasons-

1.) The woman they hired instead of me was a drunk who peed her pants while nodding off at her desk and she was belligerent. She was fired within weeks. I relished these weeks of craziness since they totally got what they deserved.

2.) The company newsletter came out a week after this&quot;promotion&quot;offer, it was rejoicing in all the big wigs magic powers since their quarterly profits were in the billions. Recession my ass.

They offered me a promotion with a raise after that then reduced the raise right before all the paperwork was to be signed off on. I quit. I work as a manager for a small ice cream shop and get paid less, but I am going back to school and I am much happier.

Bureaucracies aren&apos;t limited to government.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (29 replies) 

 
 
 [+] ragincarnage 68 points 69 points 70 points 1 year ago  (59 children) 
 [–] ragincarnage 68 points 69 points 70 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Exactly. Why should you bust your ass for the same amount of pay as someone who slacks off/comes in late/whatever. 
It&apos;s more about getting the right person at (or near) the top to notice you, if any. Your immediate supervisors don&apos;t give a shit about you.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (59 replies) 

 
 
 [+] GoodGreeen420 127 points 128 points 129 points 1 year ago  (22 children) 
 [–] GoodGreeen420 127 points 128 points 129 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
WORD! Minimum wage = minimal effort
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] RamblingStoner 73 points 74 points 75 points 1 year ago  (14 children) 
 [–] RamblingStoner 73 points 74 points 75 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I&apos;ve always liked David Cross&apos;take on it:

&apos;What are you making now?’ “Minimum wage. Yeah. Lowest amount legally possible. Yeah. That’s where I’m at right now. Oh, they’d like to pay me less. But they can’t. Legally they can’t. I win! I’m the winner!”&apos;
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (14 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Fogge 69 points 70 points 71 points 1 year ago  (21 children) 
 [–] Fogge 69 points 70 points 71 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Had the same policy at my last workplace. They pretend to pay me a decent wage, I pretend to make a decent job.

The old bonus system rewarded people between 2:30 and 6:00 minutes combined call time + after call work (I was in customer service for a power company) in tiers where a lower time meant a bigger bonus. I hovered around three minutes average during the worst months and usually got the full bonus.

Then they changed the system to give a flat sum for anyone getting below six minutes and five seconds. As a result, my average shot to about five minutes fifty five seconds. Totally unexplainable.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] nauree 94 points 95 points 96 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] nauree 94 points 95 points 96 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
At one of my jobs they have implemented a new incentive to get people to clock in on work on time and to not have unauthorized overtime by awarding paid time off. At the end of every month if you were straight on your time you got some paid time off. I figured out how many months it would take to get one full day off. It came out to be like 12 months just to get one full paid day off. I lol&apos;d and continued to come in work late.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] knight666 27 points 28 points 29 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] knight666 27 points 28 points 29 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Here, we had a supermarket where you could put stickers in little notebooks. For every 10 euro&apos;s of groceries, you would get 1 sticker. Then, if you had enough stickers, you could get 5 euro&apos;s off on your purchase.

So you&apos;d have to spend 200 euro&apos;s to get 5 euro&apos;s back. That&apos;s a 2.5% discount, that you have to work for . And people were going bonkers for it.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Lyme 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] Lyme 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Ugh, I feel you. Where I work, they got rid of the paid performance benefit (2-5% raise a year, depending on how far you exceeded the set hourly stats). I am still probably second highest producer in a section with 30+ people and manage to spend a good combined 2-5 hours of a 10 hour shift on the internet fucking off.

I ain&apos;t working any harder than I have to anymore. Especially not after getting fucked out of 2 promotions.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 
 
 [+] KryptKat 37 points 38 points 39 points 1 year ago  (11 children) 
 [–] KryptKat 37 points 38 points 39 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Bosses fucking hate this. They never seem to understand, either! My last boss actually said those exact words once, too, and still didn&apos;t understand how business works.

You get what you pay for. And you are paying minimum wage.

What is minimum wage? It means that your boss is paying you the least amount of money he is legally allowed to. It means that if he could pay you any less, he would.

I don&apos;t understand how employers expect work that is disproportionate to what they pay for it. If I go to WalMart, and pay $200 for a computer, I end up with a Dell that performs almost as well as the shitboxes they had in the high school library. If I go to Fry&apos;s, and buy a $1000 computer, I end up with a kickass, high powered gaming machine with Windows 7 and Photoshop and shit.

If you want quality work, pay your employee a wage that puts some food on his table. I guarantee, if he&apos;s hungry, he&apos;s not happy. And if he&apos;s not happy, he has most likely run out of fucks to give.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 
 
 [+] grinningdeamon 35 points 36 points 37 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] grinningdeamon 35 points 36 points 37 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Minimum wage = Minimum work.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (70 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] [deleted] 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
The problem with this theory is there are people who are so hungry for any little pay, they will bust their broke ass for the company like they were king. Its just survival dynamics.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 
 
 [+] NEWSBOT3 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago  (14 children) 
 [–] NEWSBOT3 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
in the uk this happens a lot now, but they also want you to have CCNA and MCSE certifications too.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (14 replies) 

 
 
 [+] rckid13 10 points 11 points 12 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] rckid13 10 points 11 points 12 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I work for $8 an hour with a diploma and I had to move across the country to take this job because I couldn&apos;t find anything better where I lived.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (150 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Scary_The_Clown 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago  (1 child) 
 [–] Scary_The_Clown 16 points 17 points 18 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Americans have tried to compensate by working more, taking on more jobs, or having both parents in a household work
 
When the job market was better, the best way to increase wages was to switch jobs.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 
 
 [+] HeadbangsToMahler 57 points 58 points 59 points 1 year ago  (28 children) 
 [–] HeadbangsToMahler 57 points 58 points 59 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
 Social mobility has been steadily declining shortly after the&apos;middle class&apos;was first created. 
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] SpinningHead 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago  (27 children) 
 [–] SpinningHead 47 points 48 points 49 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Sadly, its demise is being helped by middle and working class people who have been convinced that they are just inches away from being part of the jet set.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Law_Student 45 points 46 points 47 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] Law_Student 45 points 46 points 47 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I think this idea is overplayed to explain so many people voting for people who oppose their interests. Instead, I think it&apos;s explained by many people being unwilling to do their own research, and therefore believing that the people they vote for actually do represent their interests when in fact they don&apos;t.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (8 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Bob3333 95 points 96 points 97 points 1 year ago  (16 children) 
 [–] Bob3333 95 points 96 points 97 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
The middle class is dying because people got comfortable. There was a huge underclass in the United States which gave rise to labor unions. Once people won the right to radical things like overtime, 5-day work weeks, a 40-hour work week, and retirements, they started getting complacent. They forgot how they got where they were, or they were too young to have been involved in fighting for it. They just assumed it was a given. Now that unions have been systematically disemboweled, you are seeing a return to a large peasant class. History will repeat. The rich had better hope that the next time around there&apos;s a Franklin Roosevelt figure to prevent socialism from taking hold in the United States. It was only the compromises of the New Deal that pacified the public enough to stall any socialist momentum.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (16 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (1 reply) 

 
 
 [+] aeeeee 327 points 328 points 329 points 1 year ago  (170 children) 
 [–] aeeeee 327 points 328 points 329 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
where i agree the cost of living has gone up it also seems like what the luxuries people expect and require to live has gone up as well. It seems like these days most families feel entitled to own more than one car, have a huge house, a $100+ cable bill, cellphones for all the kids,etc.
I also understand there is a bigger temptation to live beyond your means than there was 40 years ago with easy credit, is that the consumer&apos;s fault?

i&apos;m only 30 and I already feel like I got by with a lot less than what kids get by with now. we were lucky to get one big purchase (like a $30 video game) once a year, we didn&apos;t have cable, hell I didn&apos;t even have touch tone. had to dial that thing manually and god help me if i was using the modem when my parents were expecting a call.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] agbortol 408 points 409 points 410 points 1 year ago  (42 children) 
 [–] agbortol 408 points 409 points 410 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Watch this. I know it feels like people are over-consuming, but they simply are not: People are not spending more than they did in the 1970&apos;s 
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] kyzf42 92 points 93 points 94 points 1 year ago  (7 children) 
 [–] kyzf42 92 points 93 points 94 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
This deserves to be seen by more people. Elizabeth Warren is a national treasure.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (34 replies) 

 
 
 [+] shadow1515 199 points 200 points 201 points 1 year ago  (44 children) 
 [–] shadow1515 199 points 200 points 201 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
You make good points, but concerning the multiple cars, let&apos;s be fair and recognize that often the reason for that is the necessity to have two wage-earners in the household instead of just one. The extra monthly cost of another car is far outpaced by the extra earning potential, even at only $8/hr.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (44 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Stormflux 82 points 83 points 84 points 1 year ago *   (17 children) 
 [–] Stormflux 82 points 83 points 84 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It seems like these days most families feel entitled to own more than one car
 
Well, back in the&apos;50&apos;s only one spouse was working, hence, only one car...

I could be wrong, but I thought the link to the Harvard professor above showed that families are actually spending less (proportionally) on clothes, cars, tv&apos;s, and other fun stuff. The problem is, this is offset by how much they&apos;re paying into mortgage, insurance, etc.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (17 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (64 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (643 replies) 

 
 
 [+] stimbus 165 points 166 points 167 points 1 year ago *   (20 children) 
 [–] stimbus 165 points 166 points 167 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I expressed this same gripe a few months ago on reddit. Most people called me a whiny bastard and a couple threatened to kill me.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] jakersbossman 330 points 331 points 332 points 1 year ago  (11 children) 
 [–] jakersbossman 330 points 331 points 332 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It all depends on the first comment. If the first comment is thoughtful and intelligent, everyone tries to sound like an intellectual. If the first comment is rash and stupid, all the mindless jackasses here go apeshit.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] stimbus 84 points 85 points 86 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] stimbus 84 points 85 points 86 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I&apos;ve witnessed that and know it to be true.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 
 
 [+] phidel_kashflow 14 points 15 points 16 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] phidel_kashflow 14 points 15 points 16 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Probably the most important insight I can think of to be added to reddiquette in bold letters.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (7 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (8 replies) 

 
 
 [+] BenHuge 67 points 68 points 69 points 1 year ago  (7 children) 
 [–] BenHuge 67 points 68 points 69 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
However, and this is just one way to look at it, the&quot;Gay 90s(1890s), the excess of the 1920s, the happiness of the 50s, the amazing excess of the 80s...all of these&quot;Golden Times&quot;in American history came about because of an attitude of celebration because we all made it through this rough time together.

And whether it was the Civil War, WWI, WWII, The Great Depression, or The Great Recession...we&apos;re all due for a BIG pizza party in about 5-10 years. We just have to make it...
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] thereisnogodbutyou 23 points 24 points 25 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] thereisnogodbutyou 23 points 24 points 25 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I like this attitude.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] rez0k 63 points 64 points 65 points 1 year ago  (3 children) 
 [–] rez0k 63 points 64 points 65 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Welcome to stagflation.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 
 
 [+] ruizscar 232 points 233 points 234 points 1 year ago  (32 children) 
 [–] ruizscar 232 points 233 points 234 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
See

 http://www.reddit.com/r/collapse/ http://www.collapsenet.com/ http://www.theoildrum.com/ http://cryptogon.com/ http://www.energybulletin.net/ 

And then

 http://www.reddit.com/r/Frugal/ http://www.reddit.com/r/Thrifty http://www.reddit.com/r/SelfSufficiency/ http://www.reddit.com/r/gardening/ http://www.reddit.com/r/homestead/ http://www.reddit.com/r/DIY/ http://www.reddit.com/r/Cooking/ http://www.reddit.com/r/Anticonsumption/ http://www.reddit.com/r/simpleliving/ http://www.reddit.com/r/Survival/ http://www.reddit.com/r/Survivalist/ 
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] parafrog 348 points 349 points 350 points 1 year ago  (20 children) 
 [–] parafrog 348 points 349 points 350 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
[1] http://www.reddit.com/r/collapse/ 

[2] http://www.collapsenet.com/ 

[3] http://www.theoildrum.com/ 

[4] http://cryptogon.com/ 

[5] http://www.energybulletin.net/ 

[6] http://www.reddit.com/r/Frugal/ 

[7] http://www.reddit.com/r/Thrifty 

[8] http://www.reddit.com/r/SelfSufficiency/ 

[9] http://www.reddit.com/r/gardening/ 

[10] http://www.reddit.com/r/homestead/ 

[11] http://www.reddit.com/r/DIY/ 

[12] http://www.reddit.com/r/Cooking/ 

[13] http://www.reddit.com/r/Anticonsumption/ 

[14] http://www.reddit.com/r/simpleliving/ 

[15] http://www.reddit.com/r/Survival/ 

[16] http://www.reddit.com/r/Survivalist/ 

I have a mild case of link OCD
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (20 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 
 
 [+] tommytwotats 96 points 97 points 98 points 1 year ago  (53 children) 
 [–] tommytwotats 96 points 97 points 98 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I used to buy pizza for $10. Then it went to $12. then to 14.00 a pizza... then I got flour, yeast and water and made dough in a few minutes, baked it myself and the cost per pizza went down to about .55 cents per pizza and thats with 2 toppings. So, maybe i wasn&apos;t as smart originally as I thought by paying someone to make it for me.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] AGATECH 20 points 21 points 22 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] AGATECH 20 points 21 points 22 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Please explain how you make a pizza for 55 cents. Size? Ingredients and quantities? Thanks.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (9 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (43 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Tezoire666 50 points 51 points 52 points 1 year ago  (6 children) 
 [–] Tezoire666 50 points 51 points 52 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Currently the same in the uk. Employers capitalising on fear, we get less for our money and the people responsible walk away Scott free. All bull shit. Viva la revolution
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 12 points 13 points 14 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Don&apos;t worry guys! That wealth is gonna trickle down any day now!
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] composer77 35 points 36 points 37 points 1 year ago  (3 children) 
 [–] composer77 35 points 36 points 37 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
You&apos;re living through one of the most profitable decades ever (if you&apos;re in the top 1%). There is definitely money, and bonuses, and fat salary increases, but not for you. Also, I wouldn&apos;t take your employers word for it when it comes to the job market. Employers love telling employees that the economy is bad, but if you are good at what you do and they need you, they WILL give you a raise to hang on to you. A friend got offered a 15% raise before he left his last job, during a&quot;salary freeze&quot;.

By all means, look before you leap, but at the same time, don&apos;t believe a word your employer (or even the media) tells you about the job market. Look at quarterly profits, bonuses, etc, to learn what your employer&apos;s bottom line really is. Remember, they will LIE to you to get you to go without a raise.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago  (6 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I don&apos;t know if this will help but I save a TON of money by cooking my own stuff. For example, instead of wasting your money on cereal which is really expensive for 1/2 the size box it used to be, make your own granola and get the ingredients at a bulk store:

*rolled oats

*barley oats

*molasses sugar

*dried currents

*dried cherries or apricots

*chopped walnuts

*sunflower seeds

*Honey

*brown sugar

*coconut

I made 13 pounds of granola for 22.00 and it only took about 1 hour to make. I even make my own lunch meat. Costs a fraction of the price considering lunch meat is upwards of 9.00 per pound (rip-off!) Making stuff like this can save you a TON of money--places like this count on people not cooking
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (6 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Semajal 243 points 244 points 245 points 1 year ago  (170 children) 
 [–] Semajal 243 points 244 points 245 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Obligatory&quot;i am in the UK and pay $8.16 a gallon&quot;
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] smallfried 163 points 164 points 165 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] smallfried 163 points 164 points 165 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Holland: $9.15 a gallon.

But you can almost see the other side of the country when you stand up straight.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] geekzorba 279 points 280 points 281 points 1 year ago  (2 children) 
 [–] geekzorba 279 points 280 points 281 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Yes, that&apos;s because you are all like 7 ft tall.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (2 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (5 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Jeff25rs 224 points 225 points 226 points 1 year ago  (46 children) 
 [–] Jeff25rs 224 points 225 points 226 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Obligatory&quot;You have better public transit and more fuel efficient vehicle options.&quot;
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] hflat 10 points 11 points 12 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] hflat 10 points 11 points 12 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Obligatory&quot;I live in Australia and pay a shitload more than both of you and have to travel further than either of you.&quot;
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (9 replies) 

 
 
 [+] kt00na 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] kt00na 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
If Top Gear has taught me anything, it&apos;s that every single car in the UK is tiny, fun to drive, has a manual transmission, and comes in a diesel variety.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (35 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 85 points 86 points 87 points 1 year ago  (9 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 85 points 86 points 87 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Obligatory: Your government charges a higher tax on gasoline.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (9 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (103 replies) 

 
 
 [+] frankiesayrelax87 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] frankiesayrelax87 9 points 10 points 11 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
My boyfriend (thankfully) just got a job offer for a mechanical engineering job in the states. He has his masters degree and for 2 years was working at Best Buy. And a lot of his fellow classmates are in the exact same position. The salary he was offered is about $20,000 less per year than what his professors said he should be getting upon graduation. Also, very few benefits. It&apos;s crazy though, because he&apos;s considering himself very lucky. He looked at many job postings for $15/hr. For a mechanical fucking engineer with a masters. Seriously, what the fuck is going on.
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] dd99 209 points 210 points 211 points 1 year ago  (38 children) 
 [–] dd99 209 points 210 points 211 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
A lot of people seem to be confused about who is doing this to them . . . just as Keynes predicted. This is not liberals, nor conservatives, not Obama, nor Bush. It is people such as the traders at Goldman Sachs, and the Koch brothers, who understand the process of inflation, understand how to get rich in these times, and have bought members of congress and other politicians (really cheap investment by the way) to make sure that the times are inflationary.

This could all have been easily predicted when Dick Cheney became vice-president. He put his entire fortune into Euros so he would not get hammered when the dollar took a dive (but don&apos;t take this to mean that Bush-Cheney are at fault, this is just a symptom, not the root cause).

A few people, about one in a million, associated with wall street, have realized that they can steal the life savings of everybody in America and put it into their own pockets. To do that, they have to own the government, but it is bought fairly cheaply and they have done that.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (38 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Dax420 199 points 200 points 201 points 1 year ago  (101 children) 
 [–] Dax420 199 points 200 points 201 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Your dollar isn&apos;t as strong as it used to be. When your dollar costs less, things are worth more.

Read this: Do US redditors realize that in 2003 their $100,000 job made them 95,000 euros and today it makes them 70,000 euros? 
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] studlyspudly 103 points 104 points 105 points 1 year ago  (15 children) 
 [–] studlyspudly 103 points 104 points 105 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Dax, when the dollar costs less, things aren&apos;t worth more, they just COST more, right? Is that what you meant? I might need some clarification if it&apos;s not. Thanks.
 
 permalink parent 
 
 
 [+] Dax420 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago  (0 children) 
 [–] Dax420 18 points 19 points 20 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Yes, sorry that was what I meant.
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (14 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (85 replies) 

 
 
 [+] tuna_HP 106 points 107 points 108 points 1 year ago  (19 children) 
 [–] tuna_HP 106 points 107 points 108 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Nope. Maybe middle east instability contributes. Maybe Japan situation contributes. Maybe stagnant wages contribute. But this is 90% of the reason:

 http://www.x-rates.com/d/USD/EUR/graph120.html 

The Federal Reserve has been pumping trillions of dollars into our financial markets in order to prop up banks and investment funds (which disproportionately benefits the wealthiest Americans, of course). As a direct consequence, the US dollar has become much much less valuable relative to foreign currencies, making it much more expensive to buy internationally traded commodities like the oil for your gasoline, the grain for your cereal, steel, beef, everything really.

So for the most part you can thank the Federal Reserve for their policy of making sure that the financial industry is ungodly profitable every year. And you can thank your legislators for supporting that policy. If it wasn&apos;t for this&quot;need&quot;to make sure that the top hedge fund managers make a few billion in income each year, then the dollar would be much stronger and international commodities would be priced much lower in dollars.

Oh, and the billions of dollars in income that the hedge fund managers make each year in performance fees is treated as long term capital gains, so they only pay 15% on it instead of the current top income tax rate of 35%, much less the Clinton era 39.6% tax rate.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (18 replies) 

 
 
 [+] Exce 27 points 28 points 29 points 1 year ago  (11 children) 
 [–] Exce 27 points 28 points 29 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Obviously you need to stop buying gas and cereal. Or start hittin up that malt-o-meal.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (11 replies) 

 
 
 [+] simperingfool 61 points 62 points 63 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] simperingfool 61 points 62 points 63 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Ain&apos;t it great how&quot;core&quot;inflation does not include fuel and food prices? It&apos;s a meaningless metric if it doesn&apos;t include shit you have to buy.
 
At work there no salary increase, they just tell me I am lucky to have a job.
 
Regardless of the economic situation this is a common refrain. You may get more traction if you have a competing offer at a higher wage. You cannot rely on an employer&apos;s sense of fairness to get higher compensation.

Go and search for a new job. You stand a much better chance of getting a better paying job if you hunt while you&apos;re still employed. Alternately, live off lentils and rice for a week: you&apos;ll save a lot and at the end of the experiment you&apos;ll have a much finer appreciation for what fast food costs vs. what it gives you.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (8 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 97 points 98 points 99 points 1 year ago *   (36 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 97 points 98 points 99 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Granola:

1 1/2 cups rolled oats
1/8 cup canola oil
1/8 cup maple syrup

mix

spread evenly in a large dish or cookie sheet and bake at 250 for 1 hour, 15 minutes. stir/turn the granola every 15 minutes for even cooking. serve with yogurt (can also be made for cheap) and honey.

edit: here&apos;s where i got the recipe. AB does it more fancily, but i cut it in half and down to the basics. i tend to do things by eye, but this gets you in the neighborhood. http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/alton-brown/granola-recipe/index.html 
 
 permalink 
 
 
 [+] [deleted] 204 points 205 points 206 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 204 points 205 points 206 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
 OOOH Look who has an oven.
How&apos;s the air in your golden sky castle my King?
 
 permalink parent 
 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (31 replies) 

 
 
 [+] mog_x 7 points 8 points 9 points 1 year ago  (3 children) 
 [–] mog_x 7 points 8 points 9 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
if you are interested in how all of this developed then i heavilly encourage you to watch the BBC Documentary:&quot;THE CENTURY OF THE SELF&quot;\n
about: http://www.bbc.co.uk/bbcfour/documentaries/features/century_of_the_self.shtml 

its a very pschological view on thing. But it is really great. It takes it time (4 episodes a 60 minutes) and starts with industrialisation and ends with today.

You can watch an Google video (in crappy quality of course and is up&apos;till 29th of april)
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 
 
 [+] punkfiveo 32 points 33 points 34 points 1 year ago  (4 children) 
 [–] punkfiveo 32 points 33 points 34 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Don&apos;t listen to all that supply and demand bullshit out there. There are lots of people getting extremely rich off of the commodities boom right now and the average North

American consumer is beginning to pay for it.
I work as an engineer in the mining industry, and have been appalled at the recent (~5 year) spike in metal prices, and commodities in general. So, I started investigating.

Here is what I have found so far.

1) A Quick History

Where to begin... let&apos;s start with a quick history of the derivatives market in the US. Upon their popularization in 1982, the US decided it was not in the best interest of

the people (you and me) to allow banks, institutions, investment outfits, etc., to make&quot;bets&quot;on the market without directly participating in it. (This is, fundamentally,

what any option is: a&quot;bet&quot;on the future price of something. Hmmm, guess why this is not good?) So, if you want to invest in gold, your choices were to either invest in gold

mining companies or buy raw bullion.

2) History Repealing Itself

Enter, stage right, The Commodities Futures Modernization Act (CFMA). In 2001, right before Clinton left office, he signed a rather innocuous bill that was effectively un-

banned derivatives (since markets around the world traded them with not much ado), and designated a governing body to regulate them. The act also (indirectly) opened up

futures markets to business entities that were previously forbidden from trading, since futures contracts used to require participation (delivery of goods stated in the

contract).

So... derivatives were legal, but regulated, right? Wrong.

The CFMA broadly excluded from regulation any type of derivative that was non-agricultural in nature. Furthermore, participants in these types of contracts were excluded from

the market fraud and manipulation provisions set forth in previous acts (specifically, the CEA of 1982). This effectively barred any oversight or monitoring of a company&apos;s

&quot;interest&quot;in any market (i.e. company&apos;s don&apos;t have to show what options they hold in their official books).

So, why is this bad? Well, it creates what is called a&quot;Moral Hazard&quot;.

I&apos;ll give a quick example of a moral hazard: Helmets, knee, and arm pads for kids going rollerblading. You buy these items because you think that the extra equipment will keep

the kids safe from injury, but what really happens is the kids end up taking greater risks, which eventually leads to greater injury.

You can draw a lot parallels from here, But to keep this close to the point of the thread, I will continue to the next section, and then hopefully you will see how it all

comes together.

3) Hedge Funds, Insurance, and Risk

So, all at the same time, a whirlwind of new types of financial derivatives come out that allow you to make a bet on almost anything and everything (This now includes things

like the weather and political outcomes). This is allowed because the derivative is marketed as&quot;insurance&quot;. So if you&apos;re a farmer and want to insure against, say, a hailstorm

ruining your crop, you can do so. However, there must always be a counterparty to provide that insurance should the hailstorm come. Historically, this used to be insurance

firms. Now, however, almost anyone with an interest in the weather can take these kinds of bets off the insurers hands (by buying the counterparty portion of the derivatives

contract).

Do you see where the moral hazard is coming in?

Basically, an insurance company no longer needs to spend so much time on calculating its risk, because it can just sell the counterparty risk to (more than willing) investors.

This is when an insurance company becomes primarily interested in VOLUME of insurance as opposed to QUALITY of insurance. -The profits come from underwriting mass amounts of

&quot;insurance&quot;derivatives, without actually taking on any risks.

So that is one moral hazard in the system, and it has a significant impact on the original subject of your post that will be explained later. For now, let&apos;s get into something

else. Something that everyone is talking about: China.

4) The Chinese Feedback Loop

You&apos;ve probably heard a lot about&apos;China this, China that..&apos;in your newspapers (or even on reddit), and obviously China very closely tied to the US Economy, and the

commodities markets in general. The world&apos;s relationship with China is simple: China buys our raw materials, makes it into something, and sells it back to us for a higher

price. They have become good at this, and have made a lot of money in recent years because of it. This is causing the Chinese population to develop economically. More Chinese

people with more money means more things they want to buy which means more raw materials required. Even without America spending its pants off, it seems China is prospering.

This is one thing that is driving the price of commodities: physical demand. But there is another unseen layer that is diving the price: Market Speculation.

Broadly, market speculation is a reactive force. If speculation is abundant in a market, It makes the highs really high, and the lows really low (i.e. increases market

volatility). Since the Chinese economy has proven itself strong despite a worldwide crisis, there is massive speculation in almost every commodity that China is (or will

become) a net consumer of (i.e. metals, oil, foods).

There is a&apos;feedback loop&apos;in this system and it is formed by the following fact: In order to ensure the dominance of Chinese manufacturing on the world market (which is its

primary economic resource and motivator), it must do the following:
1) Secure as many raw material resources as possible (as a hedge against the future price of these resources)
2) Fight domestic labour rate hikes (which increase the cost to manufacture goods and thus lowers it&apos;s global competitiveness in manufacturing)
3) Fight exchange rate hikes (which lowers the BUYING POWER of the chinese economy in general)

There are more items to add to this list but these are seen as the primary objectives of the Chinese economy

Objective 1 is the other part of the fuel that is feeding the&apos;feedback loop&apos;, but the loop will be broken and the speculative bubble will crash if China fails at ANY ONE of

the three aforementioned objectives.

5) Wrapping It Up and Selling It

So how does this all fit together? As explained earlier, the feedback loop is fueled by two things - physical demand and market speculation. We already know how and why

physical demand is a fuel, but how and why is market speculation? How did it become the monster that it currently is? Key word: Leverage, or, in short, people taking greater

risks. (Leverage is the act of borrowing against the value of a security to pay for more securities. Sorta like re-mortgaging your home to buy a cottage or condo somewhere

hot...) Why do they take greater risks? Because they are insured!

Insurance companies are more than willing to insure your holdings in a mining-related company.. I mean, just look at the past performance of China..it&apos;s unstoppable! (Sarcasm)

Hedge funds? Yeah, we&apos;ll just hedge away all of your downside risk associated with your futures contracts (delta, theta, ANND vega!). And on and on and on financial innovation

goes.

But all of these safety nets have done nothing but allow institutions to take on much greater risks, leading to one HUUGE moral hazard where eventually, you WILL fall and

break your leg.

6) Conclusion

So, this feedback effect, fueled by speculation that is enabled by financial innovation, has caused the price of everything you buy to rise. How much of a price increase are

you willing to put up with? because as soon as you stop buying (out of anger, anguish, or whatever), China starts failing (at being an economic powerhouse), speculative bubble

starts to collapse, everyone loses. I&apos;d recommend getting insurance against market bubbles (...you can probably find it out there, somewhere).
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (4 replies) 

 
 
 [+] eric_ja 39 points 40 points 41 points 1 year ago  (8 children) 
 [–] eric_ja 39 points 40 points 41 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
Two words: Quantitative Easing.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (8 replies) 

 
 
 [+] sidianmsjones 15 points 16 points 17 points 1 year ago  (3 children) 
 [–] sidianmsjones 15 points 16 points 17 points 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
I still don&apos;t understand why we don&apos;t just have a massive subreddit dedicated just to posting and getting jobs.

No offense to Reddit but redditjobs.com is not making the cut at all. There are three jobs on it and it costs $300 to post if I remember.

Can you imagine the amount of help we could make for each other if we had a job board subreddit with like 15,000 subscribers? Why the fuck has this not happened yet?!
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (3 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 1 year ago  (35 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 1 year ago sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
[deleted]
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (34 replies) 

 
 
 [+] [deleted] 44 points 45 points 46 points 1 year ago *   (21 children) 
 [–] [deleted] 44 points 45 points 46 points 1 year ago * sorry, this has been archived and can no longer be voted on 
 
It&apos;s called the Sticky Wage theory. As inflation rises consistently throughout the country, the costs of everything start to go up. Since you, and most others, are locked into contracts your real wages go down as everything else becomes relatively more expensive. This comes from the Fed policy which allows inflation to rise in order to hopefully create more jobs. Its extremely difficult to keep inflation down and combat unemployment so the Fed has to settle for one. In the long run this will correct itself slightly at the beginning of each year as wages are adjusted to better fit inflationary policy.

TL;DR- That raise you might get at the end of next year isn&apos;t as much of a raise as you think it is.

Edit- This is just one narrow way to look at it. I&apos;m an economics major who happens to be procrastinating studying this for a midterm on this subject so take this response with a grain of salt, I&apos;m sure there are a lot of Redditor&apos;s more knowledgeable on the subject.
 
 permalink 
 

 

 load more comments  (21 replies) 

 

 

 load more comments  (2530 replies) 

 
 about blog about team source code advertise 
 
 help help FAQ reddiquette subreddits contact us 
 
 tools mobile firefox extension chrome extension buttons widget 
 
 &lt;3 reddit gold store redditgifts reddit.tv radio reddit 
 
Use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy .©2012 reddit inc. All rights reserved.

REDDIT and the ALIEN Logo are registered trademarks of reddit inc.

 π   Rendered by PID 7973 on app-133 running 77fb142. 
 
you&apos;ll need to login or register to do that
 
create a new account

all it takes is a username and password
 
 username: email:  (optional) password: verify password: 
 
 remember me 

 create account 
 
 is it really that easy? only one way to find out... 
 
login

already have an account and just want to login?
 
 username: password: remember me recover password 

 login 
 close this window 
 interface language English [en] العربية [ar] (*) Беларуская мова [be] (*) български език [bg] (*) català [ca] (*) česky [cs] dansk [da] (*) Deutsch [de] Ελληνικά [el] English (Australia) [en-au] English (Canadian) [en-ca] English (Great Britain) [en-gb] English [en-us] Esperanto [eo] español [es] español [es-ar] eesti keel [et] (*) Euskara [eu] فارسی [fa] (*) suomi [fi] français [fr] עברית [he] (*) hrvatski [hr] Magyar [hu] (*) Հայերեն լեզու [hy] (*) Bahasa Indonesia [id] (*) íslenska [is] (*) italiano [it] italiano (Italy) [it-it] 日本語 [ja] (*) 한국어 [ko] (*) Latin [la] (*) 1337 [leet] LOL [lol] (*) lietuvių kalba [lt] (*) latviešu valoda [lv] (*) Nederlands [nl] Norsk [no] Arrrrrrrr! [pir] (*) polski [pl] português [pt] português [pt-pt] (*) română [ro] (*) русский [ru] slovenčina [sk] (*) slovenščina [sl] (*) српски језик [sr] Srpski [sr-la] (*) Svenska [sv] (*) தமிழ் [ta] (*) ภาษาไทย [th] (*) Türkçe [tr] українська мова [uk] (*) Tiếng Việt [vi] (*) 中文 [zh] (*) (*) incomplete volunteer to translate content language all languages 
 some languages 
 العربية français polski Беларуская мова עברית português български език hrvatski română català Magyar русский česky Հայերեն լեզու slovenčina dansk Bahasa Indonesia slovenščina Deutsch íslenska српски језик Ελληνικά italiano Svenska English 日本語 தமிழ் Esperanto 한국어 ภาษาไทย español Latin Türkçe eesti keel lietuvių kalba українська мова Euskara latviešu valoda Tiếng Việt فارسی Nederlands 中文 suomi Norsk 
 
 close this window
	</body>
</document>
