<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0005882" url="http://www.masslive.com/news/index.ssf/2012/01/cumberland_farms_defends_decis.html" time="2012-07-12-22:32" support="6" score="0.01713090110360125" bingtitle="Cumberland Farms defends decision to fire store clerk Douglas ..." webtitle="Cumberland Farms defends decision to fire store clerk Douglas Moore, who was robbed at gunpoint | 						masslive.com">
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>Cumberland Farms defends decision to fire store ... Remember the fast food restaurant employee that was fired for going ... Birth control activist Bill Baird concerned about ...</description>
	<body>
		MassLive.com 5-day | Satellite 
 


 
 Sign in | Register for free 
 MassLive.com 
 
 Sign in 
 
 News 
 News 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 News Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All News Topics» | All News Forums» 
 
More ...

 Politics Weather U.S. Senate Race Photos Opinion Videos Crime All Towns Casinos All Forums Nation/World CBS 3 Springfield Obituaries 
 Business 
 Business 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Business Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All Business Topics» 
 
More ...

 Business Monday Voices of the Valley Real Estate News Mass. Business Stock Market EDC Energy Prices Reader Raves 
 Sports 
 Sports 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Sports Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All Sports Topics» | All Sports Forums» 
 
More ...

 Patriots Falcons Red Sox Armor Celtics Golf Bruins Auto Racing UMass Basketball Hall of Fame 
 H.S. Sports 
 High School Sports 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 High School Sports Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All High School Topics» 
 All High School Forums» 
 
More ...

 Scoreboard Photos Schedule Videos Find a Player Tournaments Search Teams Recruiting Search Schools Hoophall Classic 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Entertainment Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 Entertainment Topics» | Entertainment Forums» 
 
More ...

 Dining Photo Contests Events Reader Raves Submit an Event Celebrity Galleries Television Comics Music Puzzles&amp;Games Movies 
 Living 
 Living 
 
Follow us:

 Twitter 

 Facebook 

 RSS 
 
 Loading headlines… 

 Living Home» 
 
Featured

 Loading headlines… 

 All Living Topics» | All Living Forums» 
 
More ...

 Prom Outdoors Engagements Girls Just Wanna Have Fun Weddings Fashion History El Pueblo Latino Cries&amp;Whispers Newspaper in Education 
 
 
 Jobs 
 Jobs Home Find a Job Job Seeker Tools Employer Tools Post a Job More» 
 Autos 
 Autos Home Advanced Search New Car Pricing Used Cars Research Motorcycles Classic Cars Find A Dealer Place An Ad More» 
 Real Estate 
 Real Estate Home Homes New Homes Rent Foreclosures Commercial Place An Ad More» 
 Rentals 
 Rentals Home Apartments&amp;Communities Commercial Leases Place An Ad More» 
 Classifieds 
 Classifieds Obits Rentals Pets For Sale Garage Sales Fraud Prevention Manage Your Ad Place An Ad More» 
 Obituaries 
 Obituaries Home 
 Find N Save Local Businesses 
 Local Businesses Home Food&amp;Dining Retail Shopping Health&amp;Medicine Personal Care Entertainment Real Estate Automotive Personal Care Claim Your Business 
 
 Local news the way you want it: 
Sign in to MassLive.com
 Username Password Remember me 
 Forgot your username or password ? 
 
Don’t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 Home &gt; Breaking News - MassLive.com &gt; Crime 
Cumberland Farms defends decision to fire store clerk Douglas Moore, who was robbed at gunpoint

Published: Tuesday, January 10, 2012, 6:00 AM   Updated: Tuesday, January 10, 2012, 10:00 AM 
 By Conor Berry, The Republican The Republican 
 Follow 158 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print Staff photo by Patrick Johnson Douglas Moore, 24, was fired as a clerk at the Cumberland Farms store on West Street in Ludlow following a Dec. 22 gunpoint robbery. Moore was terminated for having too much cash in the drawer, according to the Framingham-based convenience store chain. 
SPRINGFIELD–The Cumberland Farms convenience store chain is defending its decision to fire Douglas Moore, a clerk who was robbed at gunpoint last month, citing the company&apos;s &quot;desire to maintain employee privacy&quot; as the reason for not releasing more details about Moore&apos;s termination.

The story of Moore, who until Dec. 23 had worked as a clerk at a Cumberland Farms store in Ludlow, elicited a strong response from readers of The Republican and MassLive.com . Dozens made online comments supporting the 24-year-old Springfield man and faulting the Framingham-based company for its perceived callous treatment of Moore, who was let go just days before Christmas–and after having a gun stuck in his face.

But the company is firing back, saying Moore was let go because he violated a strict policy governing how much money can be kept in a cash register at any given time.

&quot;The discharge of Mr. Moore is a decision that we do not take lightly nor arrive at easily,&quot; Cumberland Farms spokeswoman Carin Warner told abc40 , media partner of The Republican and MassLive.

&quot;Mr. Moore was absolutely not terminated because he was a victim of a robbery, nor because the company suffered a financial loss due to the robbery,&quot; Warner said in a statement to the TV station.

&quot;Due to a desire to maintain employee privacy, the facts surrounding (Moore&apos;s) termination must remain private,&quot; Warner said. &quot;However, the policy that limits the amount of money that can be held in the register is only there to provide a safer environment, as well as to act as a deterrent to crime.&quot;

On the night of Dec. 22, Moore was robbed at gunpoint as he manned the counter at the Cumberland Farms store on West Street in Ludlow. A man pointed a pistol at his face and ordered him to empty the cash register, Moore told The Republican last week.
 Ludlow Police Department Ludlow police released this surveillance image of the suspected armed robber who held up the Cumberland Farms store on West Street in Ludlow on the night of Dec. 22. 
The following morning, Moore’s boss asked him to come to the store for a talk.

&quot;I thought she was going to see how I was doing,&quot; he said, but instead the conversation quickly veered toward his employment.

&quot;I didn&apos;t think I&apos;d be fired,&quot; he said.

Moore, who spent about 18 months working 40-hour weeks earning less than $9 per hour, said he was fired because more than $75 was in the cash register drawer when the store was robbed.

Police haven&apos;t disclosed how much money was stolen, but Moore said management claims it was more than $200. Company policy only allows a maximum of $75 to be kept in a register, though Moore believes the gunman got away with $100 to $150.

Cumberland Farms reviews each worker violation &quot;to determine if an exception to employee discharge can be made,&quot; Warner said. But company policies must be &quot;close to zero tolerance,&quot; she said, considering &quot;the potentially significant safety risks&quot; to employees and customers.

&quot;Unfortunately, the facts in this case, even after thorough review, could not allow for an exception,&quot; Warner said. &quot;As is always the case in these rare circumstances, crisis counseling was offered to Mr. Moore.&quot;

On the night of the robbery, the store was busy with people buying lottery tickets, gift cards and last-minute Christmas presents, Moore said. When the clerk wasn&apos;t operating the cash register, he was busy restocking coolers and shelves, cleaning up messes, and brewing fresh pots of coffee, he said.

Moore said it&apos;s virtually inevitable that more than $75 will accumulate in the register during the course of a shift, but he didn&apos;t think he&apos;d be fired for accidentally exceeding that limit on the busy night of the robbery.

East Longmeadow resident Nancy Cardaropoli said she and other regular customers of the West Street store were furious when they learned Moore had been fired. Cardaropoli vowed to boycott all Cumberland Farms stores because of the company&apos;s mistreatment of Moore.

&quot;It is appalling what they did to him,&quot; she said. &quot;Doug could have been killed, and all they cared about was the little bit of money in the drawer. That is so wrong on so many levels.&quot;

Moore said he had been chipping away at a college degree, but his sudden unemployment has forced him to suspend his studies. &quot;I can&apos;t sit at home; I&apos;ve got bills to pay,&quot; he said. &quot;Unemployment is not for me.&quot;

 Ludlow Police Lt. Paul Madera described the Dec. 22 robbery suspect as a light-skinned man, possibly Hispanic, who&apos;s around 5½feet tall and was wearing a gray hooded sweatshirt and blue jeans.

Madera said the suspect showed a revolver-style handgun, demanded cash from the register, then fled the scene in a dark Pontiac Grand Prix that was last seen southbound on West Street.

 WATCH an abc40 report on this topic: 

vide 
 Related topics: armed-robbery , crime , cumberland-farms , gun-crimes , ludlow , unemployment , workplace-rules 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in Breaking News - MassLive.com
 Previous story
 Holyoke Community College to host DEP hearing on expanded organic recycling regulations Next story
 Holyoke police arrest man for allegedly assaulting pregnant woman Copyright 2012 masslive.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
More Breaking News - MassLive.com

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 Breaking News - MassLive.com stories with the most comments in the last 7 days. 69 Massachusetts pushes to enroll income eligible residents for food assistance program 58 Romney draws boos from NAACP when he dings Obama 48 Mayor: Scantily clad models using Holyoke fire trucks played part in Deputy Chief Timothy Moran&apos;s early retirement 36 Michelle Obama to make campaign fundraising appearances at Springfield&apos;s Basketball Hall of Fame, Pittsfield&apos;s Colonial Theater 35 Obama pushes extension of middle-class tax cuts 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most masslive.com comments in the last 7 days 54 ZZatright 45 permissionde... 29 Walker45 24 mick99 23 Tigerbangs 
 
Connect with masslive.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
About Us

 About MassLive.com Advertise with us Contact Us 

 Jobs at MassLive.com FAQ Community Rules 
 
Subscriptions

 The Republican Press Pass Email Newsletters Subscriptions&amp;Circulation Contact the Newsroom Searchable archive 
 
MassLive.com Sections

 News Business Sports High School Sports Entertainment Living Travel Opinion 

 Obituaries Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Shopping Good Deals Local Businesses 
 
Your Regional News Pages

 Springfield Holyoke Chicopee 

 Northampton Westfield All Towns 
 
Mobile

 Mobile site | iPhone, Android apps | Tablet Apps 
 
More on MassLive.com

 Forums Videos Photos Interact with us Weather 

 Post a job Post a free classified ad Sell your car Sell/rent your home Sitemap&amp;search 
 
Follow Us

 Twitter | Facebook | Google+ 
 
Partners

 
 
Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 MassLive LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of MassLive LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management. 

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
