<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006043" url="http://m.miami.eater.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:43" support="1" score="0.0009733001740844068" bingtitle="Eater Miami : The Miami Restaurant, Bar, and Nightlife Blog" webtitle="Eater Miami">
			<query id="001280" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>From trash to trashed. It&apos;s a win win. [EaterWire] ... still in development, but featuring a fine selection ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows ·</description>
	<body>
		Miami National Maine Boston New York Philadelphia Washington DC Charleston Miami Atlanta Chicago New Orleans Houston Dallas Austin Denver Las Vegas Los Angeles Seattle San Francisco Portland, OR LATEST STORIES EATER 38 Pull to refresh Obits Developer Gil Dezer To Knock Down a Miami Institution Week in Reviews Reviews for Whisk, Villa Azur and Tap 42 The Gatekeepers Aniece Meinhold of The Federal Manhood Men&apos;s Health has released its 45 nominees for the Manliest Restaurant in America. The restaurants are split into nine categories Calling All Photographers Attention shutterbugs: Eater Miami is looking for photographers. Think you&apos;ve got what it takes? Email the tipline, tell us a Shackin&apos; After entertaining a lucky few last night, Shake Shack will officially launch their Coral Gables sequel Sunday, July 15 at Listage Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting EaterWire Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane Transformations Coral Gables&apos; Mixtura, the second outpost of the casual eatery specializing in Peruvian fare, has completed it&apos;s makeover from La Test Kitchens Eater National takes an in-depth look at ten of the most important test kitchens in the world, from Momofuku to Flashbacks &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Cat Cora Iron Chef and Around the World in 80 Plates co-host Cat Cora was cited for a DUI after causing a Coming Attractions Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Superlatives Wine Spectator&apos;s annual list of best wine restaurants in America, a &quot;selective&quot; group of 3,795, includes eight Miami restaurants awarded Listage Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There Most popular 
 Most read Most commented 
 No more stories. Most popular 
 Most read Most commented 
 LOAD MORE BACK TO TOP Full Eater site
	</body>
</document>
