<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006972" url="http://www.murderpedia.org/male.G/g/godineaux-craig.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="8" score="0.010845233440554113" bingtitle="Craig GODINEAUX - Murderpedia, the encyclopedia of murderers" webtitle="Craig GODINEAUX - Murderpedia, the encyclopedia of murderers">
			<query id="000756" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000521" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>Characteristics: Robbery in a Wendy&apos;s fast-food restaurant ... &quot;He put it in my hands and told me, &apos;Just close ... loud that his ears were ringing, and then the cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		Murderpedia 
  

  

 Juan Ignacio 
 Blanco    
 
   
 home 
 last 
 updates 
 MALE murderers 
 by country by name   A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z     
 FEMALE murderers 
 by country by name   A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 
 
   
 

 
 
 Craig GODINEAUX 
 

   
    
 

 

  
   
 
     Classification: Mass murderer Characteristics:  Robbery in a Wendy&apos;s fast-food restaurant Number of victims:  5 Date of murders: May 24, 2000 Date of arrest: 2 days after Date of birth:  1970 Victims profile:  Jean Auguste, 27; Ali Ibadat, 40; Jeremy Mele, 19; Ramon Nazario, 44; 
 and Anita Smith, 23 (restaurant employees) Method of murder: Shooting Location:  Flushing, Queens, New York 
 city, New York , USA Status: Sentenced 
 to five consecutive life sentences without parole , 
 February 21, 2001         
 The Wendy&apos;s 
 Massacre was a brutal killing that took place in 
 a Wendy&apos;s fast-food restaurant at 40-12 Main Street 
 in Flushing, Queens, New York, on May 24, 2000.

 Robbery and execution of employees 

The killings were carried out by 
 36-year-old John Taylor, a former employee of the 
 restaurant, and his accomplice Craig Godineaux. The 
 robbery was carefully planned, as Taylor had the 
 manager (whom he knew) of the restaurant summon the 
 entire staff to the basement on the pretense of 
 having a meeting.

Once in the basement, Taylor and 
 Godineaux bound and gagged all seven employees at 
 gunpoint and shot each of them in the head at point-blank 
 range with a Bryco-Jennings Model J38 .380 caliber 
 semi-automatic pistol.

All but two of the employees died. 
 One of the survivors dialed 9-1-1, and police 
 arrived to find the victims and discovered $2,400 
 missing from the safe.

 Arrests and trial 

The NYPD arrested Taylor and 
 Godineaux less than 48 hours after the killings. 
 Evidence quickly mounted against the pair, including 
 eyewitness testimony, ballistics, and fingerprints. 
 On January 22, 2001, Godineaux pleaded guilty and 
 was later sentenced to life in prison.

On November 19, 2002, Taylor was 
 convicted on 20 counts of murder and attempted 
 murder. One week later, on November 26, the jury 
 sentenced Taylor to death.

 Post-conviction 

On October 23, 2007, the Court of 
 Appeals of the State of New York, New York&apos;s highest 
 court, vacated the death penalty portion of the 
 verdict.

The Queens prosecutor&apos;s office 
 fought unsuccessfully to have Taylor&apos;s case declared 
 an exception to a 2004 Appeals Court&apos;s decision that 
 found New York&apos;s death penalty law unconstitutional 
 because of a flaw in its mandated instructions to 
 the jury.

On November 29, 2007 Taylor was 
 re-sentenced to life without parole for the five 
 murders. As of 2007, he had been the only inmate on 
 Death Row in New York.

 Victims 

Killed in the massacre were:

 
Jean Auguste, 27 
Ali Ibadat, 40 
Jeremy Mele, 19 
Ramon Nazario, 44 
Anita Smith, 23 

Seriously wounded:

 
Ja Quione Johnson, 18 
Patricio (Patrick) Castro, 23 
 
 Wikipedia.org 
 
 Wendy&apos;s Massacre Revisited: A 
 Killer Speaks Out 

Craig Godineaux Recalls The Horrific Events From 2000

Wcbstv.com

Nov 2, 2007

The Wendy&apos;s Massacre of 2000 was one of the most 
 gruesome mass murders in New York City history. The two men responsible 
 are now both in prison for life. But for the first time, one of them is 
 speaking out, exclusively to CBS 2.

&quot;Everybody looks at me as a criminal, as a monster,&quot;says Craig Godineaux.&quot;I ain&apos;t no monster. I&apos;m a human being.&quot;

But by the age of 30, Godineaux was a multiple 
 murderer. He and his friend John Taylor robbed the Wendy&apos;s in the 
 Flushing section of Queens and shot seven employees execution style.

Five were killed.

&quot;I felt ashamed and disgusted,&quot;Godineaux tells CBS 
 2.

And now, he&apos;s doing the hard time -- five life 
 sentences at the notorious Attica prison upstate, where he says he 
 remains torn and tormented by the events of that gruesome night in May 
 of 2000.

&quot;I&apos;m sorry for what I did. If I could change it, I&apos;d 
 change life period,&quot;he says.

But that night is etched in stone and on videotape. 
 In surveillance footage obtained exclusively by CBS 2, you see both men 
 inside the fast food restaurant. Unsuspecting employees are lured into 
 the basement by the manager.

Once downstairs, the men duct taped the employees and 
 led them to the freezer.

&quot;As he escorted people in, the manager broke free. 
 Once I knocked him down, John stood over him and shot him in the head. 
 So I started screaming,&quot;Godineaux recalls.

Taylor then shoots one other employee before handing 
 the gun over to Godineaux.

&quot;He put it in my hands and told me, &apos;Just close your 
 eyes.&apos; And I closed my eyes. And once I closed my eyes, everything 
 landed,&quot;he says.

Prosecutors went after Taylor with the death penalty, 
 but the court deemed Godineaux to be mentally retarded, so the death 
 penalty was off the table.

Godineaux has a new lawyer now, and she wants a judge 
 to throw out his plea. She says Godineaux didn&apos;t have the capacity to 
 make a plea.

&quot;He has a guardian so he&apos;s essentially a lifelong 
 child, and he was at the time he made the plea,&quot;says his attorney, 
 Susan Betzjitomir.

But Queens District Attorney Richard Brown, who was 
 at the scene and prosecuted the case, disagrees.&quot;There&apos;s no way that 
 neither I or Judge Fischer would have accepted his plea if there were 
 any doubt in our minds he was competent,&quot;Brown says.

And Benjamin Nazario, whose brother Ramon was 
 murdered by Godineaux, isn&apos;t buying it either.&quot;He wasn&apos;t mentally 
 retarded to pull the trigger. He knew what he was doing,&quot;he says.

&quot;I&apos;d like forgiveness, but they&apos;re never gonna 
 forgive me, so I&apos;m not looking for no miracle from nobody,&quot;Godineaux 
 says.

Nazario tells CBS 2 he won&apos;t accept an apology from 
 Godineaux.&quot;Nope. Never! Sorry for what? Sorry he took the life? Sorry 
 doesn&apos;t help anything.&quot;

For those who wondered why Godineaux just didn&apos;t 
 shoot Taylor himself at the time, he says he had never shot a gun before 
 and was afraid that if he missed, he&apos;d end up dead. Godineaux&apos;s attorney 
 says she&apos;ll file the motion to throw away his sentence early next week.

Stay with wcbstv.com and CBS 2 for the latest in this 
 newly unfolding story. 
 
 Craig Godineaux&amp;John B. Taylor 

 Craig Godineaux, 30, and John Taylor,
 36, are accused of entering a Wendy&apos;s in Flushing, Queens, on May 24,
 2000, and ordering seven employees into a basement freezer. 

 There, they
 allegedly bound and gagged their victims with duct tape, placed bags
 over their heads, then shot them one by one in the head during a robbery. 

 &quot;[The victims] were marched
 single file into a big freezer box. They were told to get on their knees,
 and they were each shot by the defendants once in the head,&quot;said
 Lasak Assistant District Attorney Greg Lasak. Two of the employees
 survived the attack, in which $3,200 was stolen from the eatery. Police
 say most of that money was found at Taylor&apos;s home. 

 Craig Godineaux told the cops he
 didn&apos;t wear a mask during the robbery that left five dead and two
 wounded because&quot;nobody was going to be left.&quot;The suspect
 also allegedly told cops that he put a coat on victim Anita Smith to
 keep her warm in the basement freezer before she was murdered on May 24. 

 The new information came out in the Queens courtroom of Supreme Court
 Justice Robert Hanophy as Godineaux and Taylor were arraigned on five
 murder charges. Taylor, a former co-worker of some of the victims, was
 also arraigned on unrelated indictments, charging him with three
 robberies of McDonald&apos;s restaurants in June of last year. 

 After his arrest on Long Island Taylor
 told two detectives while en route back to Queens that they should
 arrest Godineaux.&quot;Please get Craig,&quot;Taylor allegedly said.&quot;Please get Craig because I was the only one who saw him shoot
 those people. I knew three of those people. It was supposed to be a
 robbery.&quot; 

 In reading the charges against
 Godineaux, the suspect made it clear to detectives he did not wear a
 mask because the murders were part of the robbery plan.&quot;This is
 that fat bastard&apos;s [Taylor&apos;s] fault,&quot;Godineaux allegedly said.&quot;I only shot the survivors.&quot;Godineaux later allegedly added.&quot;I shot five of them. I didn&apos;t shoot the girl. That fat bastard
 shot Anita [Smith]. I liked her. I put a coat on her before she went
 into the freezer.&quot; 

 On January 22, 2001, Craig Godineaux
 pleaded guilty to murdering three people and wounding two others.
 According to prosecutors Godineaux, who will be sentenced to five
 consecutive life sentences without parole, was spared from the death
 penalty because he is mentally retarded.&quot;I know my apologies to
 the families will never bring their loved ones back,&quot;he said at
 his sentencing hearing on February 22.&quot;I do deserve what I get. I
 don&apos;t expect nobody to accept my apology.&quot;As for Taylor,
 prosecutors plan to push for the death penalty in his trial. 
 
 Survivor of Wendy&apos;s Massacre Offers 
 Gruesome Details 

 By Sarah Kershaw - The New York Times 

 November 7, 2002

Two and a half years after he survived a massacre 
 at a Wendy&apos;s restaurant in Queens, fainting and then playing dead as 
 five co-workers were executed around him, the star witness against the 
 man on trial in the murders took the stand yesterday and gave the 
 first inside look at a night of crushing violence.

The witness, Patrick Castro, 24, told a Queens jury 
 of waking up in a walk-in refrigerator, his head covered in a plastic 
 garbage bag, his eyes and mouth stuck shut with duct tape and his 
 wrists bound tightly together behind his back, to find himself 
 surrounded by bodies.

&apos;&apos;Is everybody O.K.?&apos;&apos; he recalled saying. &apos;&apos;Is 
 everybody O.K.?&apos;&apos;

There was silence, Mr. Castro testified yesterday.

Mr. Castro&apos;s testimony is considered crucial to the 
 case against John B. Taylor, who could be sentenced to death if he is 
 convicted. Mr. Castro, breaking down in tears as the prosecutor asked 
 him to identify the defendant sitting 10 feet away in a crowded Queens 
 courtroom. Then, he recounted the massacre from beginning to end, 
 speaking publicly about it for the first time yesterday and providing 
 gruesome details of a crime that transfixed the city when it occurred 
 on May 24, 2000.

In doing so, Mr. Castro, an immigrant from Ecuador 
 who had taken a job at the Wendy&apos;s on Main Street in Flushing only two 
 weeks before the robbery and murders, told the story of his unlikely 
 survival.

The first indication of trouble that night came 
 through the speakerphone, Mr. Castro said. He said he noticed two men 
 come into the store and heard one of them, Mr. Taylor, ask to speak to 
 the manager. He said that he thought nothing of that.

A short while later, a voice on the speakerphone 
 said, &apos;&apos;Come downstairs.&apos;&apos;

Mr. Castro said he assumed it was the manager, but 
 he wondered why he would call for a meeting so close to closing time, 
 near midnight.

Mr. Castro and the other employees complied, he 
 said, walking in single file down to the stairs to the basement, where 
 a man that Mr. Castro described throughout his testimony as &apos;&apos;the 
 chunky man,&apos;&apos; and whom he later identified as Mr. Taylor, was holding 
 a gun at his hip.

The most haunting part of Mr. Castro&apos;s testimony 
 came as he recounted what happened after he fainted. When he came to, 
 he said, he knew he was still in the walk-in refrigerator where the 
 employees had been ordered to go after they were bound and gagged.

It was in that basement refrigerator that Mr. 
 Castro had carefully placed a tray of uncooked patties, after cleaning 
 up the hamburger station to get ready for closing, he said. And even 
 though that night was only his fourth day of work, he was familiar 
 with the chill of that air and the scent of the raw meat, the tomatoes 
 and the chopped onions that were stored inside.

As he became more alert, he said, he felt a heavy 
 weight bearing down on his knees, and he began to remember, in vivid 
 flashes of horror.

There was a man with a gun, the &apos;&apos;chunky man.&apos;&apos; 
 Someone said, at one point, &apos;&apos;There are no more bullets.&apos;&apos; There were 
 two gunshots, so loud that his ears were ringing, and then the cashier 
 screamed: &apos;&apos;What happened? What happened?&apos;&apos; Then another shot rang out 
 and the cashier was silent.

As he pieced it all together, he wriggled his 
 wrists free of the tape, peeled away the plastic from his head, ripped 
 the tape off his eyes and mouth and peered out around him. &apos;&apos;Is 
 everybody O.K.?&apos;&apos; he recalled saying, as he saw the bodies on the 
 floor. &apos;&apos;Is everybody O.K.?&apos;&apos;

No one answered, Mr. Castro said, and he soon 
 realized that there was blood dripping from his face.

&apos;&apos;What was the weight on your knees?&apos;&apos; asked Daniel 
 Saunders, an assistant district attorney.

&apos;&apos;Ali,&apos;&apos; Mr. Castro said, referring to Ali Abidat, 
 40, a co-worker who had been killed.

Mr. Castro said he did not know it then, but he had 
 been shot in his right cheek, just below his ear, and left for dead.

Throughout his testimony, relatives of the victims 
 sobbed, particularly as Mr. Castro mentioned the names of the dead. 
 Joan Truman-Smith, whose 22-year-old daughter, Anita C. Smith, was one 
 of the slaying&apos;s victims, burrowed her head in her hands and wept as 
 Mr. Castro recounted Ms. Smith&apos;s screams. Mr. Taylor did not look up 
 from the defense table throughout Mr. Castro&apos;s testimony.

Lawyers for Mr. Taylor, 38, have argued that he is 
 guilty only of killing the Wendy&apos;s manager, Jean Dumel Auguste, 27, 
 and that an accomplice, Craig Godineaux, killed the other four 
 employees. Others shot and killed that night were Jeremy Mele, 18, and 
 Ramon Nazario, 44.

Prosecutors said Mr. Taylor and Mr. Godineaux, now 
 32, got away with $2,400. They said Mr. Castro was left with minor 
 wounds, and another employee, Jaquione Johnson, now 20, was seriously 
 injured.

Mr. Johnson, who is still recovering from being 
 shot in the head, is expected to testify today.

Mr. Godineaux, who is mildly retarded, pleaded 
 guilty to his role in the crime in February 2001 and is serving a life 
 sentence without a chance of parole.

If the jury agrees with the defense&apos;s single murder 
 contention, Mr. Taylor cannot be sentenced to death. Under New York&apos;s 
 capital punishment law, which was reinstated in 1995, Mr. Taylor must 
 be convicted of at least two murders to be eligible for the death 
 penalty.

Mr. Taylor&apos;s lawyer, John Youngblood of the State 
 Capital Defender Office, focused in his cross-examination on the fact 
 that Mr. Castro could not see the killer, because of the plastic bag 
 over his head. Under questioning from the prosecutor, Mr. Castro said 
 that after he freed himself and saw his dead co-workers, he heard a 
 noise and feared the gunmen were still in the restaurant. He said he 
 then put his hands behind his back, slipped the garbage bag over his 
 head again, pulled Mr. Abidat&apos;s body back onto his knees, and laid 
 still.

&apos;&apos;I was thinking this guy was going to come back 
 and finish me off,&apos;&apos; Mr. Castro said.

Mr. Castro said after waiting a few minutes, he 
 heard another noise. This time, he saw that it was Mr. Johnson, also 
 inside the refrigerator, who looked, Mr. Castro said, &apos;&apos;like he&apos;d been 
 punched or beaten&apos;&apos; but was &apos;&apos;trying to smile&apos;&apos; when he saw Mr. Castro 
 was alive.

Mr. Castro said he was able to carry Mr. Johnson 
 out of the refrigerator and prop him up in a chair. He said he crawled 
 &apos;&apos;like a baby&apos;&apos; around the basement, looking for signs of the gunmen, 
 and when he saw none, made his way into the manager&apos;s office to call 
 the police. He carried Mr. Johnson upstairs on his shoulders, he said.

When the police arrived a few minutes later, he 
 said he ran to open the locked door. &apos;&apos;I&apos;ve never been so happy to see 
 the police in my life,&apos;&apos; Mr. Castro said. 
 
 Life Without Parole for Wendy&apos;s 
 Killer 

By Sarah Kershaw - The New York Times

February 22, 2001

A Queens man who pleaded guilty to taking part in 
 the massacre of five workers at a Wendy&apos;s restaurant in Flushing was 
 sentenced to life in prison yesterday, but not before four of the 
 victims&apos; relatives addressed him in court and told him how the 
 shootings had ripped apart their families and their lives.

Some of the relatives yelled at the man, Craig 
 Godineaux; all of them wept along with their loved ones in the crowded 
 courtroom as they explained how the crime haunted them. Many 
 spectators cried along with the relatives. Even the court reporter 
 struggled to maintain her composure as she furiously typed a 
 transcript of the proceeding.

After the emotionally searing scene, and after 
 several minutes during which the relatives and nearly everyone else in 
 the room collected themselves, Justice Steven W. Fisher imposed the 
 maximum penalty of life in prison without parole for Mr. Godineaux, 
 31.

Mr. Godineaux was one of two men accused in the 
 robbery and execution-style slayings at the Wendy&apos;s fast-food 
 restaurant on Main Street last spring. The other man, John B. Taylor, 
 who Mr. Godineaux has said masterminded the crime, is facing capital 
 punishment and is expected to go to trial later this year.

The scene yesterday, in State Supreme Court in 
 Queens, was even more wrenching than the courtroom drama that 
 surrounded Mr. Godineaux&apos;s surprise guilty plea last month. One by one, 
 three relatives of the dead and the mother of one of the two workers 
 who were shot but survived walked up to a lectern in the courtroom in 
 Kew Gardens to address Justice Fisher. Mr. Godineaux sat to the side 
 at the defense table with his back to them, but they addressed him, 
 too.

&apos;&apos;Mr. Godineaux, I don&apos;t know you, but my family 
 will never forget you,&apos;&apos; said Babette Mele, 27, whose younger brother 
 Jeremy, 18, was killed. &apos;&apos;You have deprived the world of the greatest 
 person who I will ever know.&apos;&apos;

Loretta Johnson, whose son, Jaquione Johnson, 18, 
 was shot in the mouth at close range and is still recovering from his 
 injuries, told Mr. Godineaux, &apos;&apos;Craig, the crime that you chose to 
 commit really is a shame before God.&apos;&apos;

She added, &apos;&apos;I don&apos;t have a heaven or a hell to put 
 you in, but God will judge you for what you did.&apos;&apos;

Mr. Godineaux sat with his arms folded, his head 
 hung low, staring down at the table, until Joan Truman-Smith, whose 
 22-year-old daughter, Anita C. Smith, was killed in the massacre, 
 demanded that he look at her.

&apos;&apos;Just look at us,&apos;&apos; Ms. Truman-Smith shouted. &apos;&apos;Turn 
 around and look at us, get up, look at us! It hurt!&apos;&apos;

His face wet with tears, Mr. Godineaux turned for a 
 moment and then turned back and hung his head again. When the victims&apos; 
 relatives were done speaking, Justice Fisher asked Mr. Godineaux if he 
 had anything to say.

&apos;&apos;I know my apology to the families will never 
 bring their loved ones back,&apos;&apos; he said after a long pause. &apos;&apos;I do 
 deserve what I get. I don&apos;t expect nobody to accept my apology. What I 
 did was wrong.&apos;&apos;

Justice Fisher said that Mr. Godineaux had &apos;&apos;condemned 
 himself to spend the rest of his life caged in a prison&apos;&apos; for his role 
 in the massacre, which the judge described as &apos;&apos;a monstrous, vicious 
 and senseless crime.&apos;&apos;

&apos;&apos;He ended the promising lives of five young people,&apos;&apos; 
 Justice Fisher said, &apos;&apos;causing untold sorrow and grief to their 
 families and to all who knew and loved them.&apos;&apos;

It took at least 15 minutes for Justice Fisher to 
 read the sentences for each of the 47 counts against Mr. Godineaux. He 
 concluded by saying: &apos;&apos;The defendant has waived his right to appeal. 
 Take the defendant out.&apos;&apos;

Mr. Godineaux was spared the possibility of a death 
 sentence after prosecutors agreed with his lawyers that he is mentally 
 retarded and therefore could not face capital punishment under state 
 law. The sentence was the maximum penalty for each of the counts of 
 murder and robbery with which he was charged. He waived his right to 
 appeal as a condition of the prosecution&apos;s accepting his guilty plea, 
 according to one of his lawyers.

The Queens district attorney, Richard A. Brown, 
 held a news conference after the sentencing and said he hoped the 
 sentence would bring &apos;&apos;some degree of comfort&apos;&apos; to the victims&apos; 
 families. &apos;&apos;Justice as to Godineaux has been swift and it&apos;s been 
 certain,&apos;&apos; he said. 
 
 Craig Godineaux 

 January 22, 2001 

 One of the two New York Wendy&apos;s
 restaurant killers pleaded guilty to murdering three people and wounding
 two others during a May 24 robbery that left seven dead. According to
 prosecutors 30-year-old Craig Godineaux, who will be sentenced to five
 consecutive life sentences without parole, was spared from the death
 penalty because he is mentally retarded. As for the other suspect, John
 Taylor, 36, prosecutors plan to push for the death penalty in his trial
 which is scheduled to begin next month. 
 
 Forestalling Death Penalty In Wendy&apos;s Massacre 
 Case 

By Sarah Kershaw - The New York Times

November 21, 2000
 
The lawyer for one of the 
 defendants in a massacre that left five 
 people dead at a Wendy&apos;s restaurant in 
 Queens last spring said yesterday that her 
 client is mentally retarded and therefore 
 cannot be put to death if convicted in the 
 case.

The Queens district 
 attorney, Richard A. Brown, was to decide 
 this week whether to seek the death penalty 
 against Craig Godineaux, 30, and John 
 Taylor, 36, who were charged in the 
 execution-style slayings at a Wendy&apos;s in 
 Flushing. But Mr. Brown agreed yesterday to 
 wait another two months while prosecutors 
 investigate the claim that Mr. Godineaux is 
 mentally retarded.

New York is one of 13 
 states that has banned the execution of 
 mentally retarded defendants. The decision 
 yesterday in the Wendy&apos;s case comes at a 
 time when there is a growing national debate 
 over whether mentally retarded criminals 
 should be put to death in states that allow 
 capital punishment.

The two men were 
 arraigned in late July, giving Mr. Brown, 
 who has sought the death penalty in other 
 murder cases, 120 days to decide whether to 
 pursue the death penalty. A 60-day extension 
 was granted yesterday by Justice Steven W. 
 Fisher of State Supreme Court in Queens.

Prosecutors have 
 described Mr. Godineaux as Mr. Taylor&apos;s 
 accomplice in one of the most horrific 
 crimes in the borough&apos;s history. Mr. Taylor 
 worked at the Wendy&apos;s where the killings 
 took place, as well as at a clothing store 
 in Jamaica, where Mr. Godineaux was a 
 security guard.

The lawyer for Mr. 
 Godineaux said yesterday that her client was 
 mentally retarded, but she declined to 
 provide the type of specific information 
 about Mr. Godineaux that is used to 
 determine whether a defendant is mentally 
 retarded, including his I.Q.

&apos;&apos;Craig Godineaux is 
 mentally retarded,&apos;&apos; said his lawyer, 
 Colleen Brady, of the Capital Division of 
 the Legal Aid Society. &apos;&apos;Under New York law, 
 that means that in a case like this, he 
 could not receive the death penalty. We are 
 grateful that the district attorney has 
 extended the time in which to consider this 
 matter and investigate it further.&apos;&apos;

The prosecution must now 
 investigate whether Mr. Godineaux&apos;s mental 
 status meets New York&apos;s legal definition for 
 mental retardation as it applies to death 
 penalty cases.

Experts classify people 
 as mentally retarded if their I.Q.&apos;s are 
 below about 70 and they have an inability to 
 adapt to daily life.

In New York, mental 
 retardation is defined under state criminal 
 law as &apos;&apos;significantly subaverage general 
 intelligence and functioning,&apos;&apos; accompanied 
 by behavioral problems and evident before 
 the defendant turned 18.

In order for Mr. 
 Godineaux, who has served three prison terms 
 in the past decade for robbery and drug 
 offenses, to be deemed mentally retarded, 
 proof of such a condition has to be found in 
 school records, tests or other documents 
 from his childhood.

In addition, 
 psychological evaluations will be conducted 
 by experts for both the defense and the 
 prosecution over the next two months, 
 prosecutors and Ms. Brady said.

&apos;&apos;The defense has offered 
 some information with regard to intellectual 
 functioning in the past,&apos;&apos; said Mary de 
 Bourbon, a spokeswoman for Mr. Brown, 
 referring to Mr. Godineaux&apos;s mental status. 
 But she said evidence that he was mentally 
 retarded before he became an adult would be 
 pivotal in deciding if the defense&apos;s claim 
 has merit.

In criminal cases, 
 defendants deemed mentally retarded are 
 still considered responsible for the crime, 
 unlike defendants who successfully plead not 
 guilty by reason of insanity. In New York, a 
 mentally retarded person can be sentenced to 
 life in prison without parole, but not death.

In the May massacre, five 
 Wendy&apos;s employees were killed after being 
 bound and gagged and forced to march, one by 
 one, into a freezer room. There, they were 
 shot in the head. Two other employees 
 survived.

Dozens of relatives of 
 the victims met privately with Mr. Brown 
 yesterday, Ms. de Bourbon said, as he 
 explained the latest development in the 
 case. The relatives could not be reached 
 yesterday for comment, but several have said 
 at earlier hearings that they are eager to 
 see Mr. Taylor and Mr. Godineaux put to 
 death. 
Benjamin Nazario, the brother of Ramon Nazario, 
 one of those killed, said after the defendants were arraigned in 
 July, &apos;&apos;I want them dead.&apos;&apos;
 
 2 Men Arrested In Killings of 5 At Restaurant 

By Robert D. McFadden - The New York Times

May 27, 2000
 
Two men with criminal 
 histories, one of whom, the police said, 
 staged five terrifying gunpoint robberies at 
 fast-food outlets in New York last year, 
 were arrested yesterday and charged in the 
 execution-style shootings of seven bound-and-gagged 
 workers at a Wendy&apos;s restaurant in Queens.

Less than 48 hours after 
 the grisly massacre in Wendy&apos;s basement walk-in 
 refrigerator, in which five victims were 
 slain with bullets to the head and two were 
 shot in the head and left for dead, the 
 police -- acting on a tip -- seized John B. 
 Taylor, 36, outside a relative&apos;s house in 
 Brentwood, in Suffolk County. They said he 
 had worked at several fast-food restaurants 
 in New York, including the Wendy&apos;s where the 
 massacre occurred.

A short time later, 
 detectives in Queens said they had taken 
 into custody a second man, Craig Godineaux, 
 30, a security guard who lives in South 
 Jamaica. He was seized at the SCR Clothing 
 store at 89-74 165th Street, Jamaica, where 
 he works. The authorities said that he had a 
 record of two convictions for selling drugs 
 and one for robbery, and that he had served 
 three state prison terms -- of 10 months, 
 two years and three years -- in the past 
 decade.

The case against the 
 suspects appeared to be strong. Detectives 
 said Mr. Taylor and Mr. Godineaux made 
 statements implicating each other in the 
 crimes. Each acknowledged that they had 
 robbed the Wendy&apos;s restaurant, but Mr. 
 Taylor said that Mr. Godineaux had shot the 
 employees, and Mr. Godineaux said that Mr. 
 Taylor had done the shooting.

Investigators said Mr. 
 Taylor had a .380-caliber pistol -- the same 
 caliber as the gun used in the shootings -- 
 in a belt pack when he was seized. The 
 weapon was turned over to the Police 
 Department laboratory for ballistics tests 
 to determine if it was the gun used in the 
 killings.

After arresting Mr. 
 Taylor, investigators searched his sister-in-law&apos;s 
 house and found cash, in a canvas bag, that 
 was believed to have been stolen from 
 Wendy&apos;s, and a videotape that had apparently 
 been taken by the assailants from the 
 restaurant&apos;s surveillance camera at the time 
 of the killings. The videotape, officials 
 said, was likely to show the two men in the 
 dining area of Wendy&apos;s, but not the carnage 
 in the basement.

Moreover, the 
 investigators said they had found Mr. 
 Taylor&apos;s palm print on a box in the 
 blood-spattered refrigerator, and they said 
 he had been identified by a witness as one 
 of two men who emerged from the Wendy&apos;s, on 
 Main Street in Flushing, about 11:45 p.m. 
 Wednesday, minutes after the shootings. The 
 witness said one of the suspects was tall 
 and the other was short. Mr. Godineaux is 6 
 feet 4 inches tall, while Mr. Taylor is 5 
 feet 5.

Patrick E. Kelleher, the 
 first deputy police commissioner, said at a 
 news conference last night that Mr. Taylor 
 had been identified by a tip to the Police 
 Department&apos;s Crime Stoppers phone line not 
 long after the shootings.

About $2,400 was taken 
 from an office in the basement, officials 
 said, and the shootings -- which stunned the 
 city and even some law enforcement officers 
 with their brutality -- were apparently 
 carried out to eliminate witnesses to the 
 robbery, some of whom might have recognized 
 one of the assailants.

The suspects were charged 
 last night with armed robbery and other 
 charges, including first-degree murder, 
 which can be punishable by death. The police 
 said it was unclear whether one or two men 
 had fired the shots in what appeared to be 
 an inside job, with the assailants aware of 
 the Wendy&apos;s operations and layout and the 
 manager&apos;s name, which they invoked in a ruse 
 to get in at closing time.

Mr. Taylor jumped $3,500 
 bail in a robbery case last autumn, and a 
 dispute erupted between prosecutors and 
 court administrators yesterday over the 
 amount of the bail and the handling of the 
 case by the Queens district attorney and a 
 Criminal Court judge.

Mr. Taylor was said to 
 have worked at several New York fast-food 
 outlets in recent years, including a 
 McDonald&apos;s in Manhattan that he was 
 convicted of burglarizing in 1996, and as 
 recently as last fall at the Wendy&apos;s in 
 Flushing.

The swift arrests came as 
 more than 100 detectives worked around the 
 clock in pursuit of numerous leads in a case 
 that had drawn expressions of shock from 
 city officials, prosecutors, police 
 officials, employees of fast-food outlets 
 and ordinary New Yorkers.

Wendy&apos;s and Mayor Rudolph 
 W. Giuliani, who had announced rewards 
 totaling $60,000 for information leading to 
 the arrest and conviction of the assailants, 
 said that a relief fund had been established 
 to aid the families of the victims.

Hundreds of people 
 crowded the sidewalk outside the Wendy&apos;s 
 yesterday as a makeshift memorial of flowers, 
 lighted candles and written prayers grew 
 against the wall of the restaurant. Passers-by 
 stopped to pray and some spoke of their 
 sorrow.

&apos;&apos;I feel bad,&apos;&apos; Rinkel 
 Bhasin, 23, said after slipping behind a 
 police barricade to add her bouquet of white 
 daisies to the memorial. She said she had 
 often patronized the Wendy&apos;s.

One of the two survivors, 
 Jaquione Johnson, 18, who lives with an aunt 
 in Jamaica, Queens, underwent six hours of 
 surgery yesterday for his head wound and 
 remained in critical condition in an 
 intensive care unit of the New York Hospital 
 Medical Center of Queens.

The second survivor, 
 Patrick Castro, 22, of Queens, was released 
 from the same hospital late Thursday and was 
 under police protection. Mr. Castro, who had 
 been shot through both cheeks, played dead 
 until the assailants departed, then wriggled 
 free of the duct tape bindings and summoned 
 help with a call to 911.

Five families, meantime, 
 were making arrangements for funerals. Those 
 killed were Anita C. Smith, 22, of South 
 Jamaica; Ramon Nazario, 44, of Flushing; 
 Jeremy Mele, 18, of Neptune, N.J.; Ali 
 Ibadat, 40, of Ridgewood, Queens; and Jean 
 Dumel Auguste, 27, the Wendy&apos;s night 
 manager, who lived in Brooklyn.

Commissioner Kelleher 
 noted last night that Mr. Auguste had 
 dismissed Mr. Taylor from his job at Wendy&apos;s 
 last October, but he did not cite that as a 
 motive for the shootings.

While little was known of 
 Mr. Godineaux last night, two neighbors said 
 he was the father of a 5-year-old girl, 
 attended church and was an aspiring rap 
 artist. A woman who identified herself as Mr. 
 Godineaux&apos;s mother briefly opened the door 
 of her two-story home in South Jamaica and 
 said: &apos;&apos;I&apos;m just overwhelmed.&apos;&apos;

Mr. Taylor was described 
 by acquaintances as the father of two sons 
 and a daughter, who had lived with his 
 children in an apartment in Lefrak City, in 
 Elmhurst, Queens.

&apos;&apos;He was a very secretive 
 guy,&apos;&apos; said George Gross, a neighbor from 
 across the hall who said he also did Mr. 
 Taylor&apos;s tax returns over the past decade. 
 &apos;&apos;He never opened up to anybody.&apos;&apos; He said 
 Mr. Taylor often dressed in a suit and tie, 
 even when he worked in fast-food outlets or 
 as a maintenance man for a Caldor store.

Law enforcement officials 
 said that in 1996, Mr. Taylor worked as an 
 assistant manager at two McDonald&apos;s 
 restaurants in Manhattan, one at 341 Fifth 
 Avenue, and the other at 22 East 42nd 
 Street. On June 24, 1996, the officials 
 said, employees just arriving for work at 4 
 a.m. discovered Mr. Taylor and a second man 
 in a burglary attempt at the Fifth Avenue 
 store.

The two men fled, but Mr. 
 Taylor was recognized, and the police 
 arrested him a day later at the 42nd Street 
 McDonald&apos;s. On July 12, 1996, he pleaded 
 guilty to third-degree burglary. While 
 prosecutors requested a six-month jail term, 
 Mr. Taylor, as a first offender, was 
 sentenced to five years of probation.

Former co-workers at the 
 Fifth Avenue restaurant said Mr. Taylor was 
 involved in several scams, including 
 stealing receipts and placing ghost workers 
 on the payroll and taking their pay for 
 himself.

Law enforcement officials 
 said that Mr. Taylor robbed or tried to rob 
 at least five fast-food restaurants in 
 Queens last year, all within an eight-day 
 period in June.

One June 15, they said, 
 he held up a Burger King at 78-03 Queens 
 Boulevard and got away in a dark green car. 
 Twenty minutes later, they said, he held up 
 a McDonald&apos;s restaurant at 80-03 Queens 
 Boulevard. The authorities said he escaped 
 from the two robberies with an undetermined 
 amount of cash.

Within a 30-minute period 
 on June 19, the police said, Mr. Taylor held 
 up two McDonald&apos;s restaurants, one at 38-02 
 Queens Boulevard and the other at 45-06 
 Greenpoint Boulevard. He got away with 
 $1,192 in the Greenpoint robbery, the police 
 said.

Four days later, on June 
 23, he returned to the McDonald&apos;s on 
 Greenpoint Boulevard about 8 p.m. It was 
 crowded, a manager recalled, and the man 
 flashed a gun stuck in his waistband and 
 demanded money. The clerk at the cash 
 register recognized him from the earlier 
 holdup.

&apos;&apos;Is this the same thing?&apos;&apos; 
 she said, according to court papers.

Mr. Taylor said yes.

Following his 
 instructions, she stuffed a McDonald&apos;s 
 carryout bag with cash -- $427 -- and he 
 walked out. But as he did so, the store 
 manager followed and, spotting Police 
 Officer Michael F. Garcia walking his beat, 
 frantically pointed at Mr. Taylor, who ran.

Officer Garcia, who had 
 talked to the manager about the earlier 
 robbery, caught Mr. Taylor a few blocks 
 away. After he was identified by the 
 victims, Mr. Taylor was charged with 
 first-degree robbery and criminal possession 
 of stolen property. He was not charged with 
 weapons possession because the gun turned 
 out to be a starter&apos;s pistol.

By the time of his 
 arrest, detectives investigating the series 
 of robberies at fast-food restaurants had 
 discovered what they thought was a pattern 
 -- the description of the suspect and his 
 method of operation were the same in each 
 case -- and they matched Mr. Taylor and the 
 robbery for which he was arrested.

He was arraigned the next 
 day before Judge Pauline Mullins in Queens 
 Criminal Court. Prosecutors asked for bail 
 of $100,000, citing the charge of robbery, a 
 violent felony, admissions the suspect had 
 made and the fact that a weapon had been 
 used. Judge Mullins, however, set bail at 
 $3,500, a sum Mr. Taylor was unable to raise 
 until Aug. 10, when a friend obtained a bond 
 to free him.

David Bookstaver, a 
 spokesman for the State Office of Court 
 Administration, yesterday defended the bail 
 decision and said that the fault lay with 
 the office of the Queens district attorney, 
 Richard A. Brown. Mr. Bookstaver said the 
 bail would have been increased if 
 prosecutors had sought an indictment from a 
 grand jury during the weeks when Mr. Taylor 
 was jailed at Rikers Island. That would have 
 carried the case into State Supreme Court.

Mary de Bourbon, a 
 spokeswoman for Mr. Brown, disputed that 
 contention. &apos;&apos;In most instances, the Supreme 
 Court will not disturb the bail set by the 
 Criminal Court,&apos;&apos; she said. She said no 
 indictment was sought because the 
 prosecutors were conducting plea 
 negotiations with Mr. Taylor&apos;s lawyer.

Mr. Taylor, who was still 
 on probation from his 1996 conviction when 
 he was arrested in the Queens robbery, was 
 to appear Jan. 6 at a probation violation 
 hearing. But the plea negotiations broke 
 down in September, and in October he failed 
 to show up for a court appearance. A bench 
 warrant was issued for his arrest on Nov. 5. 
 He has been a fugitive since then.

Mr. Taylor was arrested 
 yesterday at his sister-in-law&apos;s home at 11 
 Dillmont Street in Brentwood, a short time 
 after Mayor Rudolph W. Giuliani and Mr. 
 Kelleher held a news conference to release 
 his name and photograph as a person wanted 
 for questioning in the massacre.

New York City detectives 
 had placed the house -- a shabby, tan, 
 split-level -- under surveillance during the 
 day, unaware that he was already inside. As 
 it happened, a child was involved in a 
 bicycle accident outside the home, and the 
 Brentwood police arrived. During the 
 commotion, Mr. Taylor came out to watch, and 
 was seized on the stoop.
 

 

 
 
 
Graig Godineaux   
 
  
 
 
 
 

 
   
 
   
 
 contact
	</body>
</document>
