<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006431" url="http://ww2.cityofpasadena.net/zoning/P-5.html" time="2012-07-12-23:21" support="14" score="0.007472294870587968" bingtitle="City of Pasadena Zoning Code" webtitle="City of Pasadena Zoning Code">
			<query id="000384" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000165" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001042" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001388" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000539" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000259" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000728" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000414" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>Trash receptacle required. A trash receptacle shall be immediately accessible to ... A fast food or formula fast food restaurant with drive-through service shall not be ...</description>
	<body>
		i
 Table of Contents 
 City Home Article 1  •  Article 2  •  Article 3  •  Article 4 
 Article 5  •  Article 6  •  Article 7  •  Article 8 Glossary 
 Appendix 
 

 
 
Article 5—Standards for Specific Land Uses
 
Chapter 17.50 - Standards for Specific Land Uses 

 Sections :
 17.50.010 - Purpose of Chapter 
17.50.020 - Applicability 
17.50.040 - Alcohol Sales 
17.50.050 - Animal Hospitals 
17.50.060 - Automated Teller Machines (ATMs) and Walk-Up Bank Services 
17.50.065 - Boarding Houses 
17.50.070 - Conversion of a Residential Structure to a Commercial Use 
17.50.080 - Day Care Facilities 
17.50.085 - Donation Collection Facilities 
17.50.090 - Drive-Through Businesses 
17.50.100 - Electronic Game Arcades and Internet Access Studios 
17.50.110 - Home Occupations 
17.50.120 - Life/Care Facilities 
17.50.130 - Live Entertainment 
17.50.140 - Lodging - Bed and Breakfast Inns 
17.50.150 - Lodging - Hotels and Motels 
17.50.155 - Massage Establishments 
17.50.160 - Mixed-Use Projects 
17.50.170 - Office Uses in Designated Historic Resources 
17.50.180 - Outdoor Display, Storage, and Seasonal Sales 
17.50.190 - Personal Property Sales in Residential Zones 
17.50.200 - Personal Services - Restricted and Pawnshops 
17.50.210 - Private Residential Recreational Facilities 
17.50.220 - Recycling Facilities 
17.50.230 - Religious Facilities 
17.50.240 - Research and Development Facilities 
17.50.250 - Residential Uses - Accessory Uses and Structures 
17.50.260 - Restaurants 
17.50.270 - Schools, Private 
17.50.275 - Second Dwelling Units 
17.50.280 - Senior Affordable Housing Regulations 
17.50.290 - Service Stations, Vehicle Washing, and Detailing 
17.50.295 - Sexually Oriented Businesses 
17.50.300 - Single Room Occupancy (SRO) Facilities 
17.50.310 - Telecommunications Facilities 
17.50.320 - Tents 
17.50.330 - Tobacco Retail Sales 
17.50.340 - Transit-Oriented Development (TOD) 
17.50.350 - Urban Housing 
17.50.360 - Vehicle Sales and Repair Services 
17.50.370 - Work/Live Units 
 
17.50.010 - Purpose of Chapter

This
Chapter provides site planning, development , and/or operating standards for
certain land uses that are allowed by Article 2 ( Zoning Districts and Allowable
Land Uses ) within individual or multiple zoning districts , and for activities
that require special standards to mitigate their potential adverse impacts. 
17.50.020 - Applicability

The
land uses and activities covered by this Chapter shall comply with the
provisions of the Sections applicable to the specific use , in addition to all
other applicable provisions of this Zoning Code .

 Where allowed. The uses that are subject to the standards in this
Chapter shall be located in compliance with the requirements of Article 2 ( Zoning Districts and Allowable Land Uses ). Land use permit
requirements. The uses that are
subject to the standards in this Chapter shall be authorized by the land use permit required by Article 2 , except where a land use permit requirement is
established by this Chapter for a specific use . Development standards. The standards for specific uses in this Chapter
supplement, and are required in addition to, those in Articles 2 ( Zoning
Districts and Allowable Land Uses ), 3 ( Specific Plans ), and 4 ( Site Planning
and General Development Standards). In the event of any conflict between the
requirements of this Chapter and those of Articles 2 , 3, or 4, the requirements
of this Chapter shall control.
 
17.50.040 - Alcohol Sales


 Standards for all sales
operations. Proposed on- and off-site alcoholic beverage sales operations shall be designed, constructed,
and operated to:

 Avoid contributing to an undue proliferation
of alcoholic beverage sales businesses in an area where additional ones would
be undesirable, with enhanced consideration given to the area&apos;s function and character, problems of crime and
loitering, and traffic problems and capacity; Avoid any adverse impact on adjacent or
nearby parks (e.g., public parks or recreation centers), playgrounds (e.g.,
public or parochial), religious facilities , or schools (e.g., public,
parochial, or private elementary, junior high, or high schools ); and
 Additional standards for off-site sales. Off-site alcoholic
beverage sales businesses shall comply with the following requirements in
addition to those in Subsection A. above. Locations with off-site alcoholic
beverage sales shall be designed, constructed, and operated to: 

 Not interfere with the movement of people
along any street ; and Supply adequate, appropriately located
litter and recycling receptacles as determined by the Director .

 
17.50.050 - Animal Hospitals 


 Improvements required. All animal hospitals shall be entirely enclosed, soundproofed,
and air conditioned. Incidental uses allowed. Grooming and temporary boarding of animals for a
maximum of 30 days is allowed if incidental to the animal hospital use .
 
17.50.060 - Automated Teller Machines ( ATMs ) and Walk-Up Bank Services


 Where allowed. ATM facilities may be located:

 On public streets ; and At alley entries, but within 50 feet of the
nearest public street .
 Development standards for ATM facilities. ATM facilities shall
be installed and maintained in compliance with the following standards:

 Privacy area required. 

 In order to provide an
appropriate level of privacy and to reduce the potential for blocking the
sidewalk for those users waiting in line, a five-foot deep privacy area shall
be provided in front of the ATM . This would require an ATM to be set back in
an alcove when located adjacent to the public sidewalk; The Director , while conducting
Design Review, or the Zoning Administrator , if no Design Review is required,
may reduce the privacy area down to three feet, while still meeting the intent
identified in Subparagraph a., above.
 Review for impact on pedestrian and traffic
circulation required. The Department of Public Works shall review and approve each proposed location to determine if
on- street parking can be accommodated at the proposed site and if the ATM , or
walk-up bank service window would likely have a major impact on pedestrian and
traffic circulation in the immediate area; Lighting plan required. A lighting plan will be required with the intent to
ensure that adequate lighting is provided;  ATM to be handicap accessible. The ATM shall be handicap accessible; Trash receptacle required. A trash receptacle shall be immediately accessible
to the ATM ; and Appearance following removal. At the time that the ATM is removed, the structure &apos;s facade shall have a finished appearance consistent
with the existing structure , and be subject to the approval of the Zoning
Administrator .


 17.50.065 - Boarding Houses 

 500-foot separation required. A boarding house 
 shall be a minimum of 500 feet from another boarding house. How to measure separation. The distance between any structure 
 used as a boarding house and another structure used as a boarding house 
 shall be measured in a straight line, without regard to intervening 
 structures, from the closest property line of the structure used as a 
 boarding house to the closest property line of another structure used as a 
 boarding house. 

 17.50.070 - Conversion of a Residential Structure to a Commercial Use 


 Applicability. The conversion of a residential structure to an
allowed commercial use shall be in compliance with this Section and the
applicable provisions of this Zoning Code . Location of off- street parking. Off- street parking shall
only be located behind the structure . Maintenance of existing
driveway. The existing driveway
width shall not be widened to accommodate the new commercial use .
 
17.50.080 - Day-Care Facilities

 Large family day-care home. The establishment of a large family day-care home
shall require that an application be filed with and approved by the Zoning
Administrator . The application shall be approved if the Zoning Administrator determines that the application complies with the following regulations .

 Minimum separation between day-care homes. Within a residential district , there shall be no
more than one large family day-care home allowed within 300 feet of another
large family day-care home or child day-care center. If a large family day-care home is within 300 feet of another large family day-care home or child
day-care center, then a Minor Conditional Use Permit shall be required. Plan for loading. The applicant shall submit a plan showing the
location of a loading and unloading area for children. Noise standards. A large family day-care home shall comply with the
noise regulations of Municipal Code Chapter 9.36. Parking. Off- street parking shall be provided at a ratio of one parking space for each employee other than the resident. Parking may be tandem and located
on a driveway that leads to covered parking. Play equipment. Play equipment shall not be located within the front
yard . Signs. Signs shall comply with the requirements of Chapter 17.48 (Signs).
 Child day-care centers. Each child day-care center shall comply with the
following requirements.

 Outdoor play space. A child day-care center shall provide an outdoor
play space as follows.

 Minimum size. The total area of the outdoor play space shall be a
minimum of 75 square feet per child . Location on site . No outdoor play space shall be within 25 feet of a
residential structure on an abutting lot in an RS or RM zoning district . Screening fence. A wall or fence shall surround the outdoor play
area. The minimum height of the wall or fence shall be equivalent to the
maximum height of a wall or fence in the zoning district in which the site is
located or six feet, whichever is less. If a fence with perforations through
more than 50 percent of the surface area is provided, vertical landscaping shall be provided to screen the outdoor play area from adjacent properties.
 Side and rear landscape buffers. Landscaping shall be used to buffer noise in side
and rear setback areas adjacent to RS zoning districts . The following minimum density of plant materials shall be maintained in these areas: For each 100
square feet of yard area or fraction thereof, 0.10 canopy trees (24 inch box or
larger), 0.20 under- story trees (15 gallon or larger), and 2.0 shrubs (five
gallons or larger). Where an existing mature landscape element is retained on
the site , it may be counted as double in meeting these minimum requirements
(e.g., where two canopy trees are required, one existing canopy tree may be used to meet the guideline). Parking. See Chapter 17.46 . Parking shall not be located in an existing front
or corner side setback unless located on a driveway leading to a covered parking space . Loading area. The location and design of passenger loading and
unloading areas shall be reviewed and approved by the Department of Public
Works. Refuse storage. A refuse storage area shall be provided in
compliance with Section 17.40.120 (Refuse Storage Facilities). Outdoor lighting. Outdoor lighting shall comply with Section 17.40.080 (Outdoor Lighting). Hours of operation. 

 
The allowable hours of
operation in residential zoning districts shall be established by the
Conditional Use Permit required for the use . 
Outdoor activities may only be
conducted between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 7:00 p.m. in residential zoning
districts and 6:00 a.m. and 7:00 p.m. in non-residential zoning districts . 



 17.50.085 - Donation Collection Facilities 
 
 
 Applicability. A Zoning Permit shall be required for existing and 
 proposed donation collection facilities. The Zoning Administrator shall 
 review and approve an application if it is in compliance with these 
 standards. 
 Location. Only one facility per site is allowed. The facility shall be located: 

 
 
Only in a commercial, 
 industrial, or PS district; 
Only as an accessory use 
 to a commercial, industrial or public, semi-public use; and 
A minimum of 500 feet 
 from a recycling facility or another donation collection facility. 
 The separation between such facilities shall be measured in a 
 straight line, without regard to intervening structures, from the 
 closest part of one facility to the closest part of the other 
 facility. 
 
 Setbacks.  The 
 facility shall be setback a minimum of 150 feet from a residential 
 district boundary and shall be located at least 25 feet from a street 
 property line. 
 Maintenance.  The site shall be 
 kept clean, maintained in a litter-free condition and checked daily. The property owner shall ensure that any graffiti or materials that are 
 left outside of the facility are removed within 24 hours. 
 Violations.   A facility that does not comply with the 
 ongoing requirements of this section shall be given notice of the 
 violation, and ordered to comply with these standards within 10 days of 
 the notice. If the facility does not come into compliance with these 
 standards within the 10 day period, the Zoning Permit shall be revoked. 
 
17.50.090 - Drive-Through Businesses 


 
 Location requirements for restaurants with drive-through service. A fast food or formula fast food restaurant with drive-through service shall
not be closer than 500 feet from the following uses : a park and recreation
facility; a public or private school; or another fast food or formula fast food
restaurant with drive-through service. The distance requirement shall be
measured from site -to- site . Additional application
materials. In addition to the
standard application requirements for a Conditional Use Permit, an applicant for a restaurant with a drive-through business shall submit a litter clean-up
plan, a parking and circulation plan, and a site plan that includes: driveway
locations, placement of audible equipment (if this type of equipment will be used ), landscaping , light standards, sign locations, and trash enclosures. A
litter clean-up plan shall address litter clean-up on-site and off-site and
shall include, but not be limited to, a litter pick-up schedule and a map of
the clean-up area. Findings
required for approval . The approval of a drive-through business shall require that the review authority first make
all of the following findings, in addition to those required for a Conditional Use Permit by Section 17.61.050 :

 The proposed parking and circulation plan
will provide adequate area for safe queuing and maneuvering of vehicles, and
the site design will provide adequate buffering of the use from adjoining land uses ; and The proposed location of the drive-through
business will not result in adverse impacts upon the vicinity after giving consideration
to a litter clean-up plan, the hours of operation, and the site plan.
 Disposable containers. A fast food or formula fast food restaurant with
drive-through service shall have the name of the business establishment printed
on all disposable containers and napkins. Driveway cuts. The design and construction of the drive-through
facilities shall minimize the number of driveway cuts.
 
17.50.100 - Electronic Game Arcades and Internet Access Studios 


 Separation required. 

 Measurable requirements. Each exterior wall of an electronic game arcade
and/or Internet access studio shall be at least:

 500 feet from all boundaries
of a site occupied by a day-care facility, park, public or private school,
recreation facility, or religious facility that existed before the
establishment of the electronic game arcade and/or Internet access studio; and 1,000 feet from the exterior
walls of another electronic game arcade and/or Internet access studio.
 How to measure separation. The distance between any structure used as an
electronic game arcade and/or Internet access studio and another structure used as a day-care facility, park, public or private school, recreation facility,
religious facility, or an electronic game arcade and/or Internet access studio
shall be measured in a straight line, without regard to intervening structures ,
from the closest property line of the structure used as an electronic game
arcade and/or Internet access studio to the closest property line of another structure used as a day-care facility, park, public or private school,
recreation facility, religious facility, or an electronic game arcade and/or
Internet access studio.
 Waiting areas. 

 An interior waiting area for a minimum of
eight persons shall be provided. Outdoor waiting areas are not allowed. Private rooms with doors or alcove areas are
not allowed.
 No alcohol allowed. No alcohol shall be served. Transparent windows. The front windows shall be transparent. Bathroom for patrons use . The facility shall be equipped with a bathroom that
shall be available to patrons during normal hours the facility is open to the
public. Public telephone. Any public telephone shall be located within the structure . No violation of
gambling/gaming laws. There shall be
no activity that would violate City or State gambling/gaming laws.
 Monitoring of Internet sites . 

 The computer screens shall be located so
that anyone walking around the room(s) can clearly see the computer screens. The full time on-site manager shall monitor
the use of Internet sites .
 No loitering signs. No loitering signs shall be posted on the premises. No live or amplified music. No live or amplified music is allowed; excluding
music coming from the computers. Hours of operation. The hours of operation shall be established through
the Conditional Use Permit, in compliance with Section 17.61.050 .
 
17.50.110 - Home Occupations 


 Purpose. 

 The purpose of this Section is to
allow for a home occupation business from a residential use while ensuring that
the home occupation does not detract from nor is incompatible with the
surrounding residential uses . The uses are intended to be clearly
incidental to a residential use .
 Permit requirement. A Home Occupation Permit shall be required before
the establishment of a home occupation use . After receiving an application, a
permit shall be issued by the Director upon the determination that the proposed
home occupation use complies with this Section . Permit is nontransferable. A Home Occupation Permit shall not be
transferable. Property owner&apos;s authorization required . For rental property, the property owner&apos;s written authorization for the proposed use shall be
obtained and submitted with the application for a Home Occupation Permit. Business
License required. 

 Upon approval of the Home Occupation Permit, a Business License shall be obtained. If a Business License is not renewed, the
Home Occupation Permit shall become void.
 Location and size. A home occupation use shall be conducted entirely
within a structure and shall occupy no more than 500 square feet of floor area.

The maximum floor area shall include on-site storage areas, and any portion of 
the home occupation that is located within an accessory structure. Limitation on activities. 

 There shall be no items other than products
crafted on the premises.

Items manufactured off-site may be sold through mail order or through the 
internet as long as the home occupation use (including storage area) does not 
exceed 500 square feet of floor area. The floor area maximum can be exceeded if 
the storage area is located off-site. Guns and ammunition shall not be sold as
part of a Home Occupation Permit except that a home occupation for a gunsmith
or firearms collector licensed by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms
as a gunsmith or firearm collector is allowed.
 Employees, volunteers or independent contractors. Only a resident of 
the dwelling unit shall be employed in the operation of home occupation use. No 
volunteers, interns or independent contractors shall be part of a home 
occupation permit. Commercial vehicles. 

 
Not more than one truck, equivalent in size
to a truck marketed by the major vehicle manufacturer&apos;s as a 350 or 3500
series, incidental to a home occupation use shall be kept on the site . 
The truck shall not exceed a height of seven
feet nor larger than that able to easily fit within the universal stall
dimension of eight and one-half feet wide by 18 feet long. 
The number of off- street parking spaces accessory to a dwelling unit housing a home occupation shall not be reduced to
less than that required in compliance with Chapter 17.46 (Parking and Loading).
 Client/customer visits. A home occupation use shall not allow any 
clients or customers
without prior appointments. Client/customer appointments are limited to the 
hours of 7 A.M. to 10 P.M., Monday through Friday. Changes to dwelling or
premises prohibited. 

 There shall be no alteration to the residential
character of the premises as a result of the home occupation use . The existence of a home occupation use shall
not be apparent beyond the boundaries of the subject site .
 
 Outdoor uses . No outdoor storage or display of equipment, appliances,
materials, or supplies shall be allowed. 
 Signs and advertising. On-site signs advertising a home occupation use shall not be
allowed.

Paper and electronic advertisements are allowed (including business cards) as 
long as they do not include the address of the home occupation permit. 
 Additional standards. A home 
occupation use shall be in compliance with Section 17.40.090 (Performance Standards), Chapter 9.36 (Noise Restrictions) and Chapter 8.80 
(Handling and Disclosure of Hazardous Materials). Revocation. The Zoning Administrator may revoke a Home
Occupation Permit that is not in compliance with these regulations as provided
by Section 17.78.090 (Permit Revocation or Modification) after 15 days&apos; written notice, unless the home occupation is altered
to comply with these standards.
 
17.50.120 - Life/Care Facilities 


 Purpose. This Section establishes standards for the location, development , and operation of life/care facilities . These requirements are in
addition to any applicable State and/or Federal requirements (for example, the
Americans with Disabilities Act [ADA]). Definitions. Definitions of the technical terms used in this Section are in Article 8 (Glossary of Specialized Terms and Land Use Types)
under&quot; Life/Care Facilities (land use ).&quot; Maximum density . The number of residential dwelling units in a
life/care facility shall not exceed the maximum density allowed by the
applicable zoning district unless a density bonus is granted in compliance with Chapter 17.43 (Density 
Bonus, Waivers and Incentives). The allowable density of a life/care facility shall be determined by the review authority through the Conditional Use Permit process. Minimum number of residential dwelling units required. The minimum
number of residential dwelling units required to be provided within a life/care
facility shall be equal to at least 10 percent of the total number of living
units provided in the facility, or the total square footage of all residential dwelling units shall equal a minimum of 10 percent of the gross square footage
of the structure , whichever option would result in the greatest number of
residential dwelling units . Not allowed in Northwest
Plan area. Life/care facilities are
not allowed in the Northwest Plan area in compliance with the impaction
policies of the General Plan (See Policies 14.5 and 14.6). Site layout and building standards. 

 Setbacks . 

 Except in the PS zoning
district , each proposed structure shall comply with the multi- family development standards for the applicable zoning district (e.g., City of Gardens or Urban Housing .) If the proposed location is
within the PS zoning district , the development standards shall be established
through the Conditional Use Permit, in compliance with Section 17.61.050 .
 Site
coverage . 

 Structures . The total ground floor area of all structures other
than open carports shall comply with the site coverage limitations of the
applicable zoning district . Landscaping and open space . A minimum of 30 percent of the total site shall be
maintained as landscaping and open space .
 General design principles. 

 Each structure shall be
compatible in style, color, materials, height , and scale with the general
character of the neighborhood. The building design and site layout shall define semi-public, semi-private, and private spaces; ensure a
sense of protection and community identity; and minimize barriers to
handicapped or elderly persons .

 Accessory retail and service uses . A life/care facility may
include accessory and retail service uses (e.g., barber and/or beauty shop,
pharmacy, etc.) as determined to be appropriate by the review authority , as
long as the use is limited to the residents of that facility. Common facilities. The life/care facility shall be designed to provide
common facilities (e.g., meeting rooms, recreation rooms and facilities, etc.)
as required by applicable State and Federal regulations and licensing
requirements, and as determined to be appropriate by the review authority . Security lighting plan
required. A security lighting plan
shall be submitted by the applicant and approved by the City . Safety equipment required. Indoor common areas and individual living units
shall provide necessary safety equipment (e.g., safety bars ) as well as
emergency signal and intercom systems, subject to approval by the City . Transit. The following transit facilities and services shall
be provided for the residents as determined to be appropriate by the review
authority .

 A bus turnout and shelter along the street frontage; and/or A private dial‑a‑ride
transportation shuttle.

 
17.50.130 - Live Entertainment 


 Applicability. The following regulations apply to live
entertainment when associated with a commercial entertainment , commercial recreation-indoor , 
or a bar or tavern. Limitation on type of
entertainment. 

 The type of live entertainment provided
shall only be that type approved under the Conditional Use Permit 
or Expressive Use Permit. If another type of entertainment is
proposed, a new Conditional Use Permit 
or Expressive Use Permit shall first be obtained.
 Location of entrances and
exits. No entrance or exit shall
face a residential use . Litter control. Each disposable item provided by the establishment
shall be printed with the name of the establishment. The applicable review
authority may impose a condition requiring a litter cleanup program if it is
determined that the proposed use may create a litter problem.
 
17.50.140 - Lodging - Bed and Breakfast Inns 


 Purpose. The purpose of this Section is to ensure
compatibility between the bed and breakfast inn and nearby residential uses and
provide an incentive for designation as a landmark. Permit requirements. Minor Conditional Use Permit approval , in compliance
with Section 17.61.050 , shall be required to authorize the use of a structure in compliance with this Section . Eligibility criteria. In order for a structure to be eligible for a Minor
Conditional Use Permit for use as a bed and breakfast inn, the following
conditions shall be met:

 The structure shall be located in a RM-16,
RM-16-1, RM-32, or RM-48 multi-family residential or a CO, CL or CD zoning
district ; and The structure shall be designated as a
landmark.
 Exterior appearance. The exterior appearance of the structure housing the bed and breakfast inn in a residential zoning district shall not be altered
from its original residential character except for allowed signs, and any
structural modifications necessary to comply with Title 24 of the California Code of Regulations . Limitation on guest rooms. The bed and breakfast inn shall be limited to a
maximum of five guest rooms. Limitation on services
provided. 

 Service shall be limited to the rental of
bedrooms or suites; and meal/beverage service shall be provided for registered
guests only. Separate/additional kitchens for guests are
not allowed. A bed and breakfast inn within a residential zoning district shall not be used for private parties, receptions, or similar
activities, unless the activities are specifically authorized by the
Conditional Use Permit approval for the bed and breakfast inn, in compliance
with Section 17.61.050 .
 Off- street parking. 

 Off- street parking shall be provided at a
ratio of one space for each guest room, plus two covered spaces for the on-site owner/manager of the bed and breakfast inn. Parking shall not be located in a front
and/or corner side yard setback , including yard areas that may exceed the
minimum setback requirements. Any night lighting for the parking area
shall be limited to the minimum number of fixtures and illumination levels
determined to be necessary for safety, and shall comply with Section 17.40.080 (Outdoor Lighting).
 On-site management. A manager shall be present on the site at all times. Signs. See Chapter 17.48.
 
17.50.150 - Lodging - Hotels and Motels


 Minimum lot size outside the
CD zoning district . The minimum lot size for hotels or motels located in the CG zoning district , the East Pasadena Specific Plan and the East Colorado Specific Plan , shall be 25,000 square feet. Parking in the CD zoning
district . Parking for hotels or
motels located in the CD zoning district shall only be within an underground
facility or parking structure . Maximum number of kitchens allowed. 

 A maximum of 60 percent of the guest rooms
in a hotel or motel may contain a kitchen , as that term is defined in Article 8 (Glossary of Specialized Terms and Land Use Types). A Minor Conditional Use Permit may be
approved to modify this provision in compliance with Section 17.61.050 .
 Minimum stay required. Hotel and motel guest rooms shall not be provided on
less than a daily basis. (See definition of&quot; Lodging (land use )&quot;in Article 8 [Glossary of Specialized Terms and Land Use Types]).

 17.50.155 - Massage 
Establishments 

 500-foot separation required. A massage 
 establishment shall be a minimum of 500 feet from another massage 
 establishment , personal services restricted use, pawnshop or sexually 
 oriented business . 250-foot separation required. A massage 
 establishment shall be a 
 minimum of 250 feet from a residential district. This requirement shall not 
 apply to Planned Development zoning districts.  How to measure separation. The distance separation between 
 the above identified uses shall be measured in a straight line, without 
 regard to intervening structures, from the closest property line of the 
 structure used as a massage 
 establishment s to the closest property line of 
 another structure used as another massage 
 establishment s, personal services restricted use, pawnshop , sexually 
 oriented business or residential 
 district. Other permit requirements. A massage 
 establishment shall comply 
 with the permit requirements of Chapter 5.48 (Massage Establishments). 
 
17.50.160 - Mixed-Use Projects 


 Purpose. The purpose of this Section is to ensure
compatibility between the different land uses (e.g., residential and
commercial) operating within a mixed- use project . Zoning district standards. The density , floor area ratio ( FAR ), height , and street setbacks for a mixed- use development project shall be determined by the
underlying zoning district . Commercial structure required. When the residential units
are located above the commercial uses , the structure shall be treated as a
commercial type of structure for front and corner setbacks and no interior side setbacks shall be required. No rear yard setback is required unless specified
for commercial uses . Hours of operation. Outside the Central District the commercial portion
of projects shall comply with the Limited Hours of Operation requirements
( Section 17.40.070 ), if applicable. Commercial
uses along street frontages. 

 Commercial uses shall be located along street frontages and have a minimum depth of 50 feet. The Zoning Administrator may reduce the commercial uses for a secondary street . On corner lots , the commercial space shall
turn (wrap around) the corner for a minimum depth of 50 feet. The Zoning Administrator shall determine the
primary frontage for purposes of compliance with this Subsection. On double-frontage lots , commercial uses shall be located along both street frontages. Projects within the Central District shall
comply with Figure 3-4 (Ground Floor Concept).
 Ground floor residential
units allowed. Ground floor
residential dwelling units located along secondary streets are allowed only if
the structure is located on a corner lot . Ground floor height . Projects located in the Central District shall comply
with the minimum ground floor height requirements of Table 3-2 . Community space requirements. 

 Community space defined. 

 Community space shall include
both indoor/interior space and outdoor open space . Community space can be in the
form of private open space (e.g., balconies) or common open space (e.g., pool
or side or rear setback areas.) An indoor recreational room of
up to 600 square feet may be credited toward fulfilling this community space
requirement. A utility easement may be
credited toward fulfilling this community space requirement if it is properly
landscaped in compliance with Chapter 17.44 ( Landscaping ).
 Minimum space per unit. Each development project shall provide a minimum of
150 square feet of community space for each dwelling unit . Front and/or corner side setbacks do not
count. Required front and/or corner
side setbacks shall not be credited toward fulfilling this community space
requirement. Private open space . 

 The private open space shall
not exceed 30 percent of the total requirement for community space. Each private open space shall
have a minimum six-foot dimension. This maximum 30 percent
requirement may be modified by not more than five percent if determined to be
necessary during Design Review.
 Community open space . Each community open space shall have at least one
minimum dimension of 15 feet and the other dimensions shall be at least six
feet, except for private open space (e.g., balconies or patios).
 Balconies. 

 
Balconies may project no closer than six
feet to an interior or rear property line and four feet into a front or corner
side setback . 
Balconies shall have a minimum dimension of
six feet in order to count as required open space . 
Balconies that are designed to project over
the public right-of-way shall have prior approval from the Department of Public
Works.
 Inclusionary housing
requirements. Mixed-use projects shall be subject to the inclusionary housing requirements of Section 17.42.040 ( Inclusionary Unit Requirements). Parking. 

 Location. The mixed- use project may have parking located at grade level behind
the ground floor commercial/ residential uses on the street frontage. Number of parking spaces required. For new development projects , parking shall be
provided in compliance with Table 4-6 for both the residential component and
the commercial component. A minimum of one off- street parking space shall be
located on-site for each residential unit in a new project . Guest parking required. Guest parking shall be provided for the residential
units in compliance with Table 4-6 (Off- Street Parking Space Requirements B multi- family dwelling units ). Off-site spaces. All other parking spaces designed to serve the
residential units may be located off-site with a long-term parking lease
agreement in compliance with Subparagraph 17.46.020 I. (Location and
ownership). Distance requirements. Off-site parking for residential units shall meet
the distance requirements for commercial customer/visitor spaces. Conversion of existing structures . Conversions of existing structures (including
additions) may provide parking for the residential units off-site as long as
they meet the distance requirements and there is a long term parking lease
agreement all in compliance with Subparagraph 17.46.020 I. (Location and
ownership). Overnight parking permits not allowed. 

 City Permits for overnight
parking on City streets shall not be issued for residential development projects built in compliance with these regulations . Residential tenants shall be
advised of the unavailability of on- street overnight parking permits.

 Lighting. Lighting for commercial uses shall be appropriately
shielded to not negatively impact the residential units. Noise notification. 

 Residents of a mixed- use development project shall be notified that they are living in an urban area and that the noise
levels may be higher than in a typical residential area. The signature of the residents shall confirm
receipt and understanding of this information.
 Loading .

 Off- street loading. Off- street loading areas shall be located as far as
possible from the residential units and shall be completely screened from view
from the residential portion of the project . Loading and unloading of household goods. If the loading of furniture and household goods for
the residential units is to occur on the street , it shall be limited to the
hours of 9:00 a.m. to 2:00 p.m. and 7:00 p.m. to 10:00 p.m. on weekdays and
9:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m. on weekends.
 Refuse and recycling areas. Areas for the collection and storage of refuse and
recyclable materials shall be located on the site in locations that are
convenient for both the residential and nonresidential uses .
 
17.50.170 - Office Uses in Designated Historic Resources 


 Purpose. The provisions of this Section allow structures of
historical significance that are located in specified residential zoning
districts to be used for business and professional offices . Limitation on use . The reuse of structures in compliance with this Section shall be limited to those uses included under the definition of&quot;Office, Administrative Business Professional (land use )&quot;in Article 8 (Glossary of Specialized Terms and Land Use Types). Permit requirements. Minor Conditional Use Permit approval , in compliance
with Section 17.61.050 , shall be required to authorize the reuse of a structure in compliance with this Section . Eligibility
criteria. In order for a structure to be eligible for a Minor Conditional Use Permit for the reuse of a designated historic resource , the following conditions shall be met:

 The structure shall be located in an
FGSP-RM-12, RM-16, RM-16-1, RM-32, RM-48, WGSP-1 or WGSP-2 zoning
district ; and The structure shall be designated as a
landmark or listed individually on the National Register of Historic Places .
 Conditions
of approval . In granting a Minor
Conditional Use Permit, the review authority shall, at a minimum, adopt the
following conditions of approval .

 Any modifications to the exterior of the structure shall be subject to review and approval by the Historic Preservation Commission for consistency with the Secretary of the Interior&apos;s standards. The hours of operation of any business shall
be limited to 7:00 a.m. through 8:00 p.m. Each structure may have one sign, not to
exceed eight square feet in size. The sign may be freestanding or located on a building wall, and shall not exceed a height of four feet measured from existing grade . Any freestanding sign shall be located within five feet of the structure . The design and materials of any sign shall be compatible with the structure . Exterior lighting shall be designed to
confine emitted light to the property, and the light source shall be visually
screened from surrounding properties and streets in compliance with Section 17.40.080 (Outdoor Lighting). If a proposed use displaces residential
households or tenants, the applicant or successor shall comply with Municipal
Code Sections 16.46.050 and 16.46.060 relating to relocation financial
assistance and counseling. Any structure with over 3,000 square feet of gross floor area shall provide at least one residential unit on the premises. 
Any bungalow court shall retain at least one bungalow as a residential unit.
 Parking. Parking shall be provided as required by Chapter 17.36 (Parking and Loading) except as follows.

 A minimum of 2.5 parking spaces shall be
provided for each 1,000 square feet of gross floor area . Parking shall not be allowed in the front or
corner side setback areas of a corner lot . No loading space shall be required.
 Expansion. The expansion of a use approved in compliance with
this Section shall comply with the development standards of the CO (Commercial
Office) zoning district . 
 
 
17.50.180 - Outdoor Display, Storage, and Seasonal Sales


 Outdoor display and storage. 

 Where allowed. Outdoor display and storage of equipment, materials,
merchandise, and storage bins may be authorized through Conditional Use Permit approval in the OS and PS zoning districts and are allowed by right in the CD,
CG, and CL zoning districts . Standards. Where allowed, outdoor display and storage of equipment, materials,
merchandise, or storage bins shall be in compliance with the following
standards:

 Screening. Except for the land uses listed in Subparagraph d.
(Exceptions to screening requirements), below, outdoor display and storage
(including bins) areas shall be screened from view of public rights-of-way (not
including freeways) and from adjacent residentially zoned property by a solid
masonry wall or concrete fence. The height of the wall or fence shall be the
maximum allowed by the applicable zoning district . Limitation on display and
storage areas. 
(1) An outdoor storage area shall
not exceed 50 percent of the total area of the site except where landscaping is
provided in addition to the required setbacks in compliance with Subparagraph
(2) below.
(2) The additional landscaping shall be equal to at least 10 percent of the area of storage that is over the
50 percent of total site area , and shall be located on the outside of the
required solid masonry screening wall(s).
(3) The Zoning Administrator shall
determine the location and distribution of the additional landscaping in order
to ensure that the landscaping reduces the impact of the solid masonry wall(s).
(4) No outdoor display or storage
of equipment, materials, merchandise, or storage bins shall be located within a parking space or parking lot . Height of stored materials. If visible from the public right-of-way , the height of equipment, materials, merchandise, or storage bins stored or displayed shall
not exceed the height of the screening wall or fence. Exceptions to screening
requirements. Notwithstanding the
provisions of this Subsection, outdoor display and storage shall be allowed
only in conjunction with the following land uses in zoning districts where
these land uses are allowed. 
(1) Nurseries and commercial
growing grounds; provided the outdoor display and storage is limited to plants
only;
(2) Vehicle services - sales and
leasing ; provided the outdoor display and storage is limited to passenger
vehicles offered for sale or rent; and
(3) Farmers&apos; markets . 
 Special standards for the outdoor display of
merchandise. The outdoor display of
merchandise shall be allowed in the CD, CG, CL, and IG zoning districts in
compliance with the following additional standards:

 The merchandise shall: 
(1) Not be located on the public right-of-way (including sidewalks); and
(2) Be brought in only during hours that the business is not open. The sale of the merchandise
shall be associated with a specific business located on the subject site . The outdoor display shall not: 
(1) Be located in the parking lot or in a landscaped area; and
(2) Cover more than 50 percent of the structure &apos;s frontage. No temporary signs (except
price signs) shall be displayed.
 Special standards for the outdoor storage of
materials. The outdoor storage of
materials shall be allowed in the CD, CG, and IG zoning districts in compliance
with the following additional standards:

 The storage area shall be
located to the rear of the lot and shall be screened by a solid masonry wall
with a stucco finish if it faces a street ; The wall shall not exceed six
feet in height and shall be located outside of any required setback areas; and The outdoor storage area shall
not exceed 50 percent of the total area of the site unless additional landscaping is provided in compliance with Subparagraph 2. b., above.

 Storage
of junk materials, goods, wares, or merchandise. 

 Junk materials prohibited. No junk materials, goods, merchandise, or wares
shall be stored or collected in any residential zoning district . Building materials allowed. Building materials to be used in the construction of
any structure in any zoning district may be temporarily stored on the premises
where the structure is to be built or renovated for not to exceed 60 days in
advance of the commencement date of construction. In the event of any failure
to proceed promptly with construction, the City shall serve written notice upon
the owner requiring the removal of the building materials. A site may
temporarily store construction equipment intended for off-site construction for
a 60-day period only. A site may be used more than once or the 60-day limit
may be extended upon approval of a Conditional Use Permit granted in compliance
with Section 17.61.050 . Before issuance of a Certificate of Occupancy , or a temporary Certificate of Occupancy , all building materials shall be removed
from the subject lot .
 Seasonal merchandise sales . Seasonal merchandise sales shall be conducted in
compliance with the following standards.

 Duration. The maximum duration of seasonal merchandise sales shall be 45 days
at one location. Hours of operation. Seasonal merchandise sales shall be allowed on a
daily basis and may operate only between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 10:00 p.m. Parking. Parking at a ratio of one space for each 2,000 square feet of lot
area used for seasonal merchandise sales shall be provided. Temporary structures and signs. Temporary structures and signs shall be subject to
the review and approval of the Zoning Administrator . Site cleanup. After the seasonal merchandise sales event is
completed or after 45 days from the initial occupancy of the site , whichever
first occurs, all associated structures and trash shall be removed from the site within 24 hours. Temporary Use Permit required. A Temporary Use Permit, issued in compliance with Section 17.61.040 , shall be required if any of the above standards are not met.

 
17.50.190 - Personal Property Sales in Residential Zones


 Personal
Property Sales Permit required. 

 No person may sell or dispose of personal
property at a charity bazaar, garage sale, religious assembly use , yard sale,
or similar event in an RS or RM zoning districts without first obtaining a Personal Property Sales Permit.

 The permit shall be obtained
at least 24 hours before the proposed sale. Mailed applications shall be
postmarked at least 72 hours before the proposed sale.
 The permit process is administered by the City &apos;s Code Enforcement Staff.
 Application requirements. An application for a Personal Property Sales Permit
shall be filed in compliance with Chapter 17.60 (Application Filling and
Processing). The application shall be accompanied by the information identified
in the Department handout for Personal Property Sales Permit or as may be
required by the Director . Standards. Personal property sales shall comply with the following standards:

 Personal property only. Items offered for sale for profit shall be limited
to personal property not acquired for resale, owned by the applicant who shall
be the resident of the dwelling where the sale is to be conducted. If nonprofit organization joins in
application. Personal property from
several donors may be sold only if a nonprofit organization joins in the
application and states that it will receive the entire net proceeds from the
sale. Signs. One temporary on-site sign advertising the sale, not exceeding four
square feet in area, is allowed during a sale. Limitation on number and duration of sales. A Personal Property Sales Permit shall be issued for
a maximum of two sales, each not exceeding three consecutive days, for each site within any 12-month period. Display of merchandise. Merchandise shall not be displayed on fences, 
walls or the public right-of-way.

 
17.50.200 - Personal Services - Restricted and Pawnshops 


 500-foot separation required. A personal services restricted use or pawnshop shall be a minimum
of 500 feet from another personal services restricted use , pawnshop 
or massage 
establishment . How to measure separation. The distance between any structure used as a personal services restricted use or pawnshop and another structure used as a personal services restricted use or pawnshop shall be measured in a straight
line, without regard to intervening structures , from the closest property line of the structure used as a personal services restricted use or pawnshop to the
closest property line of another structure used as a personal services restricted use or pawnshop.
 
17.50.210 - Private Residential Recreational Facilities


 Allowed outdoor lighting. Golf facilities, sport courts , and other
recreational facilities in conjunction with a single- family dwelling or residential project may have outdoor lighting only with a Minor Conditional Use Permit approved by the Hearing Officer in compliance with Section 17.61.050 . Compliance with Section 17.40.080 . Any approved lighting
shall comply with the requirements of Section 17.40.080 (Outdoor Lighting). Allowed fences. Fences allowed in conjunction with the recreational
facilities (e.g., tennis court ), shall be reviewed through the 
Minor Conditional Use Permit required for the recreational facility, in compliance with Section 17.61.050 . The Minor Conditional Use Permit shall determine the height , location,
and materials of the fence. 
 
 
17.50.220 - Recycling Facilities


 Small collection facilities. 

 Applicable facilities. The facility shall only be established in
conjunction with a commercial, community, or public facility. Permit requirements. The location and type of the facility on the site shall be subject to the approval of a Minor Conditional Use Permit issued in
compliance with Section 17.61.050 . Location. The facility shall be located on a site that is a minimum 
of two acres.

 As close as possible to the main structure they are intended to serve; and At least 150 feet from the
nearest residential use .
 Limitation on number. There shall be no more than one facility for each
site. Size of facility. The maximum height of the bins, boxes, and/or
containers shall be reviewed through the Minor Conditional Use Permit process. Materials of construction. The facility shall be constructed and maintained
with durable waterproof and rustproof material, and the bins, boxes, or
containers shall be covered and contained in such a manner that they do not
present a danger to the public health, safety or welfare. Site maintenance. The site shall be kept clean and maintained in a
litter-free condition at all times. Identification of allowed materials. The facility shall be clearly marked to identify the
type of materials to be deposited. Signs. Signs shall be reviewed during the Minor Conditional Use 
Permit process and shall comply with Chapter 17.48 (signs).
 Large collection facilities. 

 Permit requirements. The location and type of the facility on the site shall be subject to the approval of a Conditional Use Permit issued in
compliance with Section 17.61.050 . Location. The facility shall be located:

 Within an enclosed structure ;
and At least 100 feet from the
nearest residential use .
 Storage requirements. 

 All storage of material shall be
in sturdy containers or enclosures with tightfitting covers, which are secured
and maintained in good condition, or shall be baled or pelletized. The depositing of materials on
the ground is prohibited. Storage containers for
flammable material shall be constructed of nonflammable material. Oil storage shall be in
containers approved by the Fire and Health Departments .
 Performance standards. The facility shall comply with the environmental performance standards of Section 17.40.090 . Identification and signs. The facility shall be clearly marked with the name
and phone number of the facility operator and the hours of operation. 
Identification and information signs shall meet the sign standards for the zoning district in which the facility is located. Allowable materials. Recyclable materials shall be presorted and shall
include no hazardous materials. Hours of operation. The hours of operation shall be limited to 7:00 a.m.
to 6:00 p.m. Maintenance. The site shall be maintained free of litter and any
other unsanitary materials and shall be cleaned of debris on a daily basis. 
The facility shall be maintained free from rodents at all times.

 
17.50.230 - Religious Facilities 


 Development standards. 

 In residential zoning districts . 

 The development standards for
religious assembly uses located in residential zoning districts shall be as
specified in the Conditional Use Permit, issued in compliance with Section 17.61.050 , except that the interior side setback shall be a minimum of 15 feet
and the rear setback shall be a minimum of 25 feet. The front and corner side setbacks shall be the same as that required for an allowed use .
 In commercial zoning districts . The development standards for religious assembly uses located in commercial zoning districts shall be in compliance with the
subject zoning district .
 Storefront windows and
doors. If the use is proposed to be
located in an existing structure , any storefront windows and doors shall
remain. All windows shall be transparent. Hours of operation for accessory uses . Uses accessory to a
religious assembly use in an R district other than temporary homeless shelters
may only operate between 9:00 a.m. and 9:00 p.m. by right; and between 9:00
p.m. and 9:00 a.m. subject to a Conditional Use Permit issued in compliance
with Section 17.61.050 . Columbariums. A columbarium in conjunction with a religious
facility shall comply with the following requirements.

 Location on site . The columbarium shall not project beyond the front
foot of the building occupancy of the religious facility. Enclosure required within residential zoning
districts . A columbarium within a
residential zoning district shall be located only within in a structure enclosed on all sides. Standards for outdoor facilities. A columbarium located outside of a structure shall
comply with the following requirements.

 The columbarium shall be set
back a minimum of 20 feet from each property line , but shall be set back 100
feet from any property line abutting a residential use or a residential zoning
district . The height of the columbarium
shall not exceed eight feet. A masonry wall with a minimum height of six feet shall screen the columbarium from streets and adjacent lots . Landscaping shall be provided
at a ratio of two square feet of landscaping for each square foot of
columbarium area.
 Parking requirements. The religious facility shall provide the minimum
number of parking spaces required in Chapter 17.46 (Parking and Loading). Contact information. The name, address, and telephone number of the
individual, owner, board of trustees, or designated caretaker responsible for
the maintenance of the columbarium shall be kept on record in the office of the
religious assembly use . Relocation after closure of religious
facility. Upon discontinuance of the
religious assembly use , the columbarium shall be relocated in compliance with
all applicable State laws.
 Temporary homeless shelters. Where allowed by the applicable zoning district , a
religious assembly use may use the site for a temporary homeless shelter
without having to obtain a Conditional Use Permit if the following requirements
are met:

 Within the residential zoning districts and
the CO and PS zoning districts , the religious facility was authorized through
Conditional Use Permit approval ; No rent or fees of any kind are charged for
the service offered to homeless persons ; Except within commercial zoning districts ,
the facility that is used to house homeless persons accommodates a maximum of
10 persons at any one time. Within commercial zoning districts , there is no
limitation on the number of homeless persons that can be accommodated; Homeless persons reside at the facility a
maximum of 60 days; Occupancy by homeless persons at the
facility commences upon the religious facility receiving a Certificate of Occupancy ; and The fee for a Certificate of Occupancy required by Municipal Code Chapters 14.37 and 17.61 shall not be required of a
religious facility that seeks a Certificate of Occupancy for a temporary homeless shelter.

 
17.50.240 - Research and Development Facilities


 Applicability. Research and development facilities, as this land use type may be defined in Article 8 (Glossary of Specialized Terms and Land Use Types) may exceed the height limit and appurtenance roof coverage
provisions identified in this Zoning Code . Height and appurtenance roof
coverage provisions. 

 Height limits. The height limit may be exceeded by a maximum of 10
feet (excluding the appurtenance height ) in order to accommodate additional
mechanical equipment between floors. However, no additional floor area shall
be allowed by this provision. Appurtenance roof coverage encroachments. Section 17.40.060 .D.2.a. specifies that appurtenances covering not more than 25 percent of the roof area may exceed the height limit established by the applicable zoning district by a maximum of 15
feet. However, the allowable appurtenance roof coverage for research and development facilities may exceed the height limit for up to 50 percent of the
roof area.
 Allowed by Minor Conditional Use Permit. The height and/or appurtenance roof coverage provisions may be exceeded to the maximum limits
identified in Subsection B., above through the approval of a Minor Conditional Use Permit, granted in compliance with Section 17.61.050 .
 
17.50.250 - Residential Uses - Accessory Uses and Structures ( See 
Interpretation )

 Limitation on use . Accessory structures shall be limited to uses which
are accessory to the main use , including but not limited to, cabana, garage or carport , gazebo, greenhouse, pergola, pool, or hot tub and related equipment,
or workshop. An accessory structure shall not be used for sleeping quarters.
  Restricted items and
facilities. 

 
 Prohibited facilities. Bathtubs, fireplaces, and kitchens (full or partial)
are prohibited within accessory structures .

( See 
Interpretation ) 
 Allowed, but restricted facilities. Air conditioning, heating, shower, toilet, washtub,
and/or washer and dryer facilities are allowed within accessory structures ;
however:


 
When an accessory structure contains air conditioning, heating, shower, and/or toilet facilities, a
covenant shall be required. 
The covenant shall state that
the structure is an accessory structure and shall be maintained as an accessory
structure and not be used for sleeping quarters or be converted to a residential use . 
The purpose of this covenant is
to ensure that subsequent owners of the property are aware of the restrictions
on the property.
 
 Attic area and stairs. The 
area above the ceiling joists may only be used as a storage area. This storage 
area shall be accessed only by a pull down stairs. 
 Other related items. Other related items not listed above may only be
allowed if first approved by the Zoning Administrator .

( See 
Interpretation )
 Timing of construction. An accessory structure shall not be constructed
before the main structure . Limitation on location. 

 An accessory structure shall not occupy a
required front or corner side setback . An accessory structure may be located in a
required side or rear setback ; provided it is more than 100 feet from the front property line or in the rear 25 feet of the site . A lot abutting on the front 100 feet of a key
lot shall maintain a minimum four-foot rear setback .
 Size, height , and setback requirements. 

 Height limits. 

 Nine-foot limit with
two-foot setback . An accessory
structure shall not exceed a height of nine feet, but only if located
two feet from a property line . Nine-foot top plate . The height of the top plate of an accessory
structure shall not exceed nine feet. Encroachment plane and setback. The overall height of an accessory structure (excluding the top plate height) may rise above the
nine-foot height limit as it steps or slopes away from the two-foot initial setback , but
shall not intercept an encroachment plane sloping inward from a point nine feet
in height (beginning at the two-foot setback ) and rising a maximum of one and
one-half feet for each one foot of distance starting at the two-foot setback . See Figure 5-1 . 15-foot limit .
An accessory structure may
raise to, but shall not exceed, an overall height of 15 feet, but 
only in compliance with Subparagraph c., immediately above. Modification by Minor
Conditional Use Permit. In order to achieve a design that is architecturally compatible with the main 
structure, the maximum height (including the top plate height) may be modified by a Minor Conditional Use Permit, granted in compliance
with Section 17.61.050 . 
 Modification by Historic
Preservation Commission . For
designated landmarks or structures in a designated historic district , the
maximum height (including the top plate height) of an accessory structure may be exceeded without a Minor
Conditional Use Permit, but only if approved by the Historic Preservation Commission , and only upon finding that the greater height is necessary in order
to achieve a design that is architecturally compatible with the main structure .


 Figure 5-1 Encroachment Plane and Setbacks for Accessory Structures 

 

   
 Length of structure walls. 
 
 In order to prevent an
excessive amount of structure located along a property line , the maximum
horizontal length of an accessory structure that can be located 
less than five feet from the property line shall be limited to 22 feet. Any portion of the structure that exceeds 22 feet in length and is less than five feet from the property 
line, shall be required to be set back a minimum of
five feet from the property line .

 Separations between structures . 

 Utility pole. When a utility pole is located on the same site as a proposed accessory structure , a minimum separation of at least four feet shall be 
maintained between the pole and the accessory structure . Other structures . An accessory structure , other than mechanical equipment, a hot tub , or a swimming pool , shall maintain a minimum separation of six feet from any 
other structure (excluding walls and fences) on the site . The separation shall be clear and unobstructed by any encroachments. Pools and hot tubs . Pools, hot tubs , and related equipment, and all
mechanical equipment shall not be closer than five feet from a property line . 
The Zoning Administrator may modify this requirement for pool equipment when
adjacent to an alley .
 Maximum
floor area of accessory structures .
  
 Maximum size. 
 
 Projects using the RS standards. The maximum size of all accessory 
 structures on a site shall not exceed an aggregate of 600 square 
 feet or six percent of the lot size, whichever is greater. Projects using the RM-12 standards. The maximum size of all 
 accessory structures on a site shall not exceed an aggregate of 600 square feet or six percent of the lot size, whichever is greater.

 However, an additional 200 square feet is permitted if used for covered 
 parking. Projects using other multi-family standards. The maximum size 
 of all accessory structures on a site shall not exceed an aggregate of 600 square feet or six percent of the lot size, whichever is greater.
 An accessory structure (or portion of an accessory structure) with a roof that is at least 50 percent open 
 shall not be included in the calculation of the maximum allowable size. All 
 other accessory structures shall be counted in the calculation of the 
 maximum allowable size including carports, gazebos, or covered patio or 
 porches. A basement below an accessory structure or a stand alone 
 subterranean structure shall be included in the calculation of the maximum 
 allowable size.


 Garages and carports . ( See 
Interpretation )

 Attached garages . On a lot 50 feet in width or wider, an attached garage that is visible from the street shall not occupy more than 50 percent of
the structure frontage of the main structure . Carports . A carport shall only be located behind the main structure and not visible from a public right-of-way , and shall not be allowed on a corner lot .

 
17.50.260 - Restaurants and Fast Food Restaurants

 
 Bars and outdoor dining
areas . 

 
 
 Bar areas. Bar areas shall be defined by a barrier approved by the Zoning
Administrator . 
 Outdoor dining areas . Outdoor dining areas shall be defined by landscaping or other barriers approved by the Zoning Administrator .
 
 Disposable containers and napkins. Fast food restaurants with exterior take-out windows shall have the business 
name printed on all disposable containers and napkins. 
 Fast food and formula fast
food restaurants and drive-through. See Section 17.50.090 ( Drive-Through Businesses ).
 
17.50.270 - Schools , Private


 Indoor classroom area. Indoor classroom area (exclusive of bathrooms ,
hallways, kitchens , offices , and other nonclassroom space) shall be 24 square
feet for each child enrolled. Outdoor play area. 

 In residential zoning districts , a minimum
of 125 square feet shall be provided for each child enrolled. In nonresidential zoning districts , a
minimum of 75 square feet shall be provided for each child enrolled. No outdoor play area shall be located within
a required front or corner side setback or within 25 feet of a residential use .
 Traffic control plan. The applicant shall submit a traffic control plan
showing how loading and unloading of school children will occur with minimum
disruption to traffic. Noise. Each school shall be designed and operated to comply
with the noise regulations of Municipal Code Chapter 9.36. 
 
17.50.275 - Second Dwelling Units 


 Applicability. The following standards apply to the construction of second dwelling units . Location and operational
standards. 

 A second dwelling unit may be constructed on
any legal parcel of 15,000 square feet or more in any RS zoning district . Second dwelling units are prohibited on
properties located within the Hillside and Landmark Overlay Districts . Second dwelling units shall only be built
when there is an existing single- family residence (e.g., primary residence) on
the site . If a site is vacant, a second dwelling unit may be constructed at
the same time as the primary residence. There shall be a minimum distance of 500
feet between properties with second dwelling units constructed under these
provisions. This distance shall be measured from the nearest property line of
the parcel on which the second dwelling unit is proposed to the nearest property line of the parcel containing a second dwelling unit . The property owner shall occupy one of the
two units on the site as a primary residence. If thereafter the owner occupies
neither unit, the second dwelling unit shall automatically become a
nonhabitable space, shall not be used as a dwelling, and shall not be rented. A second dwelling unit is only allowed on a lot that is connected to a public sewer system. Existing single- family structures shall not
be demolished to allow the construction of a second dwelling unit . Trailers or prefabricated housing shall not
be allowed to be used as a second dwelling unit . No more than 20 new second dwelling units shall be allowed per calendar year within the City boundaries, with no more
than 200 allowed within a ten-year period. Some flexibility from the standards of this
ordinance is allowed for the relocation of a historic resource onto the front
of a property with an existing single- family residence. Flexibility could
include using the rear house as a second dwelling unit even though it may
exceed the maximum size for a second dwelling unit . Waivers from these
standards to accommodate the relocation of a historic resource shall be subject
to the review and approval of the Director .
 Development standards. 

 Except as identified in this Subsection, second dwelling units shall comply with all of the development standards (e.g., encroachment plane , floor area, height , lot coverage , setbacks , etc.) that
apply to the primary residence. A second dwelling unit shall not be more
than 800 square feet in gross floor area . A second dwelling unit shall be limited to a height of one story , not to exceed 12 feet to the top plate and 17 feet to the
highest ridgeline, and shall not exceed the height of the primary residence. A second dwelling unit shall be located
behind the rear building line of the primary residence, and be clearly
subordinate by location and size. A minimum building separation of six feet
shall be maintained (eave to eave) between the primary residence and a detached
second dwelling unit . A minimum building separation of 10 feet shall be
maintained (eave to eave) from the entrance of a second dwelling unit if it is
facing the wall of another structure on the property. No entry to a second dwelling unit shall be visible from the public right-of-way .
 Parking and circulation
standards. 

 The primary residence shall provide the
required two covered parking spaces on site before allowing a second dwelling
unit on the subject property. An additional two covered parking spaces shall
be provided on-site for the second dwelling unit . No overnight parking permits shall be issued
for a property with a second dwelling unit approved under these provisions. A second dwelling unit shall share the
driveway with the existing primary residence on the site . A second driveway
shall only be allowed from an alley , if there is an alley that serves the
subject site .

 
17.50.280 - Senior Affordable Housing Regulations 


 Density . Density shall be a maximum of 48 units per acre. A
maximum of 50 percent density bonus is allowed. Projects shall meet all other density bonus provisions under 17.43 ( Density Bonus , 
Waivers and Incentive) and are eligible for incentives. Development standards. Development standards including the number of parking spaces shall be prescribed and reviewed as part of the Conditional Use Permit, except that the front setback shall be a minimum of 20 feet, and the
rear, side, and corner side yard setbacks shall be a minimum of 10 feet. 
Parking may be uncovered and located within the rear yard setback . Location. A Senior Affordable Housing project shall be located
within 500 feet of a Medical Office or Medical Services - Hospital use . The Medical Office use or Medical Services - Hospital use shall be located within
the PS district . Occupancy . Each unit shall be occupied by at least one senior
citizen.
 
 17.50.290 - Service Stations , Vehicle Washing , and
Detailing


 Applicability. The following standards apply to the new
construction, remodeling, or expansion of service stations and vehicle washing and detailing businesses. Application requirements. A lighting plan shall be submitted with the
Conditional Use Permit application. Lighting requirements shall comply with
the outdoor lighting requirements of Section 17.40.080 . Minimum site area . A service station , vehicle washing and detailing
business, or combination thereof shall be located on a site of at least 15,000
square feet, with a minimum of 125 feet of frontage on a public street . This
requirement shall not apply to the remodeling or expansion of a preexisting service station or vehicle washing and detailing business. Site layout. 

 Mobile recycling trucks, and temporary ,
nonpermanent structures may not be located on a service station or vehicle
washing and detailing site without Conditional Use Permit approval . Ancillary services (e.g., air, water,
telephone, and vending machines) shall be located in an area that does not
impede vehicular traffic. A cashier kiosk shall be constructed to
provide safe access for patrons. A minimum of three pedestrian queue spaces
for each service station site shall be provided. The site plan/ site layout shall be designed
to ensure maximum security for employees and patrons.
 Planting areas. Perimeter planting areas shall be as required for
parking lots by Chapter 17.46 (Parking and Loading), except where a structure adjoins an interior property line . Required interior planting areas may adjoin
perimeter planting areas. The landscape plan shall comply with Chapter 17.44 ( Landscaping ) and all applicable design guidelines. Storage of materials and
equipment. 

 The provisions of Section 17.50.180 (Outdoor
Display, Storage, and Seasonal Sales) shall apply, except that a display rack
for motor vehicle products may be maintained at each pump island of a service
station . If display racks are not located on pump
islands, they shall be placed within three feet of the main structure , and
shall be limited to one for each street frontage. Storage of inoperative vehicles is
prohibited. The location of display racks and vending
machines shall be specified by the Conditional Use Permit.
 Restrooms. All restroom entrances shall be screened from view
from adjacent properties or street rights-of-way. Screening material may be
partially open or perforated provided the openings or perforations do not
constitute greater than 50 percent of the total screening surface area and are
uniformly distributed throughout the screening material. Dispensing machines. The location of food, cigarette, and/or soft-drink
vending machines and Automated Teller Machines ( ATM&apos;s ) shall be shown on the plans submitted and shall be
reviewed as part of the Conditional Use Permit process. No game machines shall
be allowed on a service station site . Equipment rental. Outdoor storage of, and sale, lease, or rental of
trailers, trucks, or similar equipment shall be reviewed as part of the
Conditional Use Permit process. Vehicle washing and
detailing - Drainage. Each vehicle
washing and detailing business (both large and small scale) shall provide
evidence of compliance with the regulations of the Sanitation District of Los
Angeles County related to drainage. Discharge into the storm drain system is
not allowed without approval from the Los Angeles County Regional Water Quality
Control Board. Vehicle washing and detailing
- small-scale businesses. A small-scale vehicle washing and detailing business shall be located within a
parking structure having a minimum of 500 vehicle parking spaces . Service stations - minimum
number of fueling positions . A
full- service station in the CL zoning district shall have a minimum of eight fueling positions . Site maintenance. All paved areas shall be maintained grease-free.

 17.50.295 Sexually 
Oriented Businesses 

 Definitions. The technical terms and phrases used in this Section are defined in Article 8 (Glossary of Specialized Terms and Land Use Types)
under &quot;Sexually oriented business (land use). 
 Purpose.  It is the purpose of this 
Section to regulate sexually oriented businesses in order to promote the health, 
safety, moral, and general welfare of the citizens of the City, and to establish 
reasonable and uniform regulations to prevent the deleterious secondary effects 
of sexually oriented businesses within the City. The provisions of this Section 
have neither the purpose nor effect of imposing a limitation or restriction on 
the content or reasonable access to any communicative materials, including 
sexually oriented materials. Similarly, it is neither the intent nor effect of 
this Section to restrict or deny access by adults to sexually oriented materials 
protected by the First Amendment, or to deny access by the distributors and 
exhibitors of sexually oriented entertainment to their intended market. Neither 
is it the intent nor effect of this Section to condone or legitimize the 
distribution of obscene material. Findings and rationale supporting this 
purpose are set forth in the uncodified provisions of the ordinance adopted to 
implement this Section. 
 Location requirements.  Sexually oriented businesses shall be permitted in 
only the CG zoning district and shall be subject to the following conditions: 
 
 
 No sexually 
 oriented business is allowed in the Lincoln Corridor (CG-1). No sexually 
 oriented business is allowed within 500 feet of any child day-care center 
 (excluding large and small family day-care homes), park and recreation 
 facility, public or private school, or religious facility (excluding 
 temporary uses), that existed before the establishment of the sexually 
 oriented business. No sexually 
 oriented business is allowed within 250 feet of a RS or RM district.  Measurements shall be made in a straight line in all directions without 
 regard to intervening structures or objects, from the closest point on a 
 lot line of the sexually oriented business premises to the closest point 
 on a lot line of any child day-care center, park and recreation 
 facility, public or private school, religious facility, or parcel in a 
 RS or RM district. No more than two 
 sexually oriented businesses are allowed within a 250 foot radius, drawn 
 around the proposed use. Measurements shall be made in a straight line 
 in all directions without regard to intervening structures or objects, 
 from the closest point on the lot line of the proposed sexually oriented 
 business premises to the closest point on the lot line of any other 
 sexually oriented business. No location in 
 the City shall be disqualified by virtue of its proximity to a land use located 
 outside the jurisdictional boundaries of the City. 
 
 
 Nonconforming sexually oriented businesses.  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in the Pasadena 
Code, any sexually oriented business located within the City of Pasadena on the 
date the foregoing restrictions become effective, which is made a nonconforming 
use by this provision, shall be terminated within 12 months of the date this 
provision becomes effective. A nonconforming sexually oriented business may 
obtain an extension, based upon a showing of financial hardship, of its 
amortization period upon the approval of a written application filed with the 
Department no later than 60 days prior to the end of such 12 month amortization 
period. 

 
 Procedure for 
seeking hardship extension.  An application for a hardship extension shall be filed in writing with the 
Department, and shall include payment of an application fee, evidence of 
purchase and/or lease and improvement costs, income earned and lost, 
depreciation, and costs of relocation. The Department shall determine whether 
the application is complete within ten days. Within thirty days after 
determining that the application is complete, the Department shall schedule a 
hearing on the application before the Hearing Officer, which hearing shall be 
conducted within 30 days after the Departments receipt of the complete 
application.  
 Standards for obtaining hardship extension . The Hearing Officer shall issue a written decision within ten days after the 
hearing on the application for a hardship extension, and the decision shall 
include a statement advising the respondent of the right to appeal such decision 
to a court of competent jurisdiction. A reasonable hardship extension shall be 
granted upon a showing that the nonconforming sexually oriented business is 
unable to recoup its investments, made prior to the effective date of this 
Ordinance, in its current location unless the hardship extension is granted. An 
extension under this Section shall be for a reasonable period of time 
commensurate with the i nvestment 
involved, and shall be approved only if the Hearing Officer makes all of the 
following findings or such other findings as are required by law: 

 
 T he 
 applicant has made, prior to the effective date of this ordinance, a substantial investment, including but not limited to lease obligations 
 incurred in an arms-length transaction, in the property or structure on or 
 in which the nonconforming use is conducted; The applicant will be unable to 
 recoup said investment as of the date established for termination of the 
 use; The applicant has 
 made good faith efforts to recoup its investment, including an attempt to 
 assign the lease, sell or use the property in a manner, and for a use, 
 permitted in the location and has been unsuccessful in his efforts. 


 
17.50.300 - Single Room Occupancy (SRO) Facilities


 Limited Commercial (CL) district . Notwithstanding the
provisions of Section 17.71.080 , existing nonconforming single-room occupancy residential in the Limited Commercial (CL) zoning district may be altered to
comply with the following single-room occupancy residential development standards without obtaining a Conditional Use Permit. Site area per unit. Site area per unit standards shall not apply to single-room occupancy facilities. Unit size and occupancy . The minimum size of a unit shall be 150 square feet
and the maximum size shall be 220 square feet which may include bathroom and/or kitchen facilities. Common area. A minimum of 10 square feet for each unit or 250
square feet, whichever is greater, shall be provided for a common area. All
common area shall be within the structure . Dining rooms, meeting rooms,
recreational rooms, or other similar areas approved by the Zoning Administrator may be considered common areas. Shared bathrooms and kitchens shall not be
considered as common areas. Management. A single-room occupancy management plan shall be
submitted to, reviewed, approved and enforced by the Housing Administrator of
the Housing and Development Department . The management plan shall be approved
before issuance of a Certificate of Occupancy . The management plan shall be
comprehensive and contain management policies and operations, rental procedures
and rates, maintenance plans, residency and guest rules and procedures,
security procedures and staffing needs including job descriptions. The
approved management plan shall be in recordable form as approved by the City Attorney and recorded before issuance of a Certificate of Occupancy . A 24-hour
resident manager shall be provided for any single-room occupancy use with 12 or
more units. Development regulations . Each single-room occupancy facility shall comply
with all applicable commercial development standards for the applicable zoning
district . Parking. See Chapter 17.46 (Parking and Loading). Kitchen facilities. Each unit shall be provided a kitchen sink serviced
with hot and cold water with a garbage disposal and a counter top measuring a
minimum of 18 inches wide by 24 inches deep. A complete kitchen facility
available for residents shall be provided on each floor of the structure , if
each individual unit is not provided with a minimum of a refrigerator and a
microwave oven. Bathroom facilities. For each unit a private toilet in an enclosed
compartment with a door shall be provided. This compartment shall be a minimum
of 15 square feet. If private bathing facilities are not provided for each
unit, shared shower or bathtub facilities shall be provided at a ratio of one
for every seven units or fraction thereof. The shared shower or bathtub
facility shall be on the same floor as the units it is intended to serve and
shall be accessible from a common area or hallway. Each shared shower or
bathtub facility shall be provided with an interior lockable door.
 
17.50.310 - Telecommunications Facilities 


 Applicability. Wireless telecommunications antenna facilities shall
comply with the following requirements. The provisions of this Section do not
apply to satellite earth station antennas due to preemption by Part 25 of Title
47 of the Code of Federal Regulations .

The provisions of this Section also do not apply to wireless telecommunications 
antenna facilities in the public right-of-way, which are governed by Chapter 
12.22 of the Municipal Code. Definitions. The Specialized terms and phrases used in this Section are defined under&quot;Telecommunications Facility Definitions&quot;in Article 8 (Glossary). 
 Special notice. All notices 
required by this Subsection shall be provided in compliance with Chapter 17.76 (Public Hearings).

 
 Notices of public hearings for Wireless Telecommunications Antenna 
Facilities, Major, shall also be mailed to occupants of buildings and registered 
neighborhood associations within 1,000 feet of the primary use site boundary. Notices of public hearings for Wireless Telecommunications Antenna Facilities, 
Minor, shall also be mailed to occupants of buildings and registered 
neighborhood associations within 300 feet of the primary use site boundary. 
Notices of application submittal and 
comment periods for Wireless Telecommunications Antenna Facilities, SCL, shall 
be mailed as follows:

 
 In residential districts, to occupants of buildings and registered 
 neighborhood associations within 300 feet of the primary use site boundary. 
 The comment period is 30 days. In all other zoning districts, to abutting 
 property owners, and posted as set forth in Section 17.76.020.B(2) . The 
 comment period is 30 days.

 
 Requirements for all facilities. 

 
 
 Prohibited fencing materials. The use of chain-link fencing or razor wire in the design of a facility or 
related support facilities is prohibited. Screening required. Support 
facilities housed outside of structures shall be screened from public view by 
fences, landscaping, trellises, walls, and similar treatments. Design Guidelines. Facilities subject to this section shall comply 
with any design guidelines adopted by resolution of the Council. Illumination. Building-mounted facilities and support structures may not be 
illuminated unless specifically required by the Federal Aviation Administration 
or other governmental agencies. Signs. No off-premises or on-premises 
signs may be placed by a wireless telecommunications service provider on a 
building or support structure to which a facility is attached. Each facility 
shall be located a minimum of 25 feet from an existing off-premises sign or an 
on-premises freestanding sign. Site maintenance. The site of the facilities shall be maintained in a 
condition free of debris, refuse, and trash. All graffiti shall be removed 
within 48 hours. Radio Frequency Emissions Compliance. Upon installation of the 
facility, the applicant shall demonstrate that the project will not result in 
levels of radio frequency emissions that exceed Federal Communications 
Commission standards, including FCC Office of Engineering Technology (OET) 
Bulletin 65, Evaluating Compliance with FCC Guidelines for Human Exposure to 
Radiofrequency Electromagnetic Fields, as amended. Additionally, if the Director 
determines the wireless telecommunications facility, as constructed, may emit 
radio frequency emissions that are likely to exceed Federal Communications 
Commission uncontrolled/general population standards in the FCC Office of 
Engineering Technology (OET) Bulletin 65, Evaluating Compliance with FCC 
Guidelines for Human Exposure to Radiofrequency Electromagnetic Fields, as 
amended, in areas accessible by the general population, the Director may require 
post-installation testing to determine whether to require further mitigation of 
radio frequency emissions. The cost of any such testing and mitigation shall be 
borne by the applicant. Applications for amateur radio antennas or antennas 
installed for home entertainment purposes are exempt from this requirement. Posting of removal bond or security. Before the issuance of any permit 
under this section, the applicant shall post with the City a performance bond or 
other security in an amount rationally related to the cost of removal. Citys use of consultant. The Director may require the applicant to provide 
an authorization to permit the City to hire an independent, qualified consultant 
to evaluate any technical aspect of the proposed use, including issues involving 
radio frequency emissions, alternative designs, and alternative sites. Any 
authorization for this purpose shall include an agreement by the applicant to 
reimburse the City for all reasonable costs associated with the consultation. 
Any proprietary information disclosed to the City or the consultant is deemed 
not to be a public record, and shall remain confidential and not to be disclosed 
to any third party without the express consent of the applicant, unless 
otherwise required by law. 
 Inoperable or unused facilities. 

 
 
If a support structure, or an antenna 
array affixed to a building or support structure, becomes inoperable or ceases 
to be used for a period of 180 consecutive days:

 
 
The permittee shall give written 
notice of inoperability or nonuse to the Zoning Administrator; and 
The antenna array and, if applicable, 
the support structure shall be removed within 90 days. 
 
If removal does not occur, the City 
may remove the antenna array and, if applicable, the support structure, at the 
permittee&apos;s expense; provided, however, that if other antenna arrays owned or 
operated by other service providers are affixed to the same support structure 
then only the antenna array that has become inoperable or has ceased to be used 
is required to be removed, and the support structure may remain in place until 
all service providers cease to use it. 
 
 Length of permit and extension. 

 
 
A permit issued under this section 
shall be valid for an initial period of not less than 10 years. 
Upon expiration of the initial 
period, the permit may be extended by a decision by the Director for a period no 
longer than the initial period upon verification of continued compliance with 
the findings and conditions of approval under which the application was 
originally approved, as well as any other provisions provided for in this Code 
which are in effect at the time of the permit renewal request. 
The Director shall provide notice of 
the extension only to the applicant, all persons who have filed a written 
request for notice of the extension, the Planning Commission, and the City 
Council. 
 
 Existing agreements. This 
section does not apply to the terms and conditions of any agreement or permit 
(including an extension) pertaining to telecommunications facilities (issued by 
the City or of which the City is a party) that is already in existence at the 
effective date of this ordinance, provided that the agreement or permit does not 
result in a material change (including changes in size, shape, color, or 
exterior material) of the telecommunications facilities covered by such existing 
agreement.

  
 City-owned real property. Any 
wireless telecommunications antenna facility permitted to be located on 
City-owned real property shall comply with any of the conditions in Section 
12.22.180 of the Municipal Code as determined applicable by the Director, in 
addition to the other requirements of this section. For purposes of this 
Subsection, all references in Section 12. 22.180 to Director shall mean the 
Director of Planning and Development. 

  
 Requirements for new support 
structures. (Wireless Telecommunications Antenna Facilities, Major). 

 
 Projection from roof prohibited. No new support structure may project 
from the roof of a building.
The antenna array on a multiple- use facility
may be approved to extend up to 15 feet above the height of the primary use (e.g., 15 feet above the required height of athletic field lights). Separation from buildings . A new support structure shall be a minimum 
of 10 feet from a building on the same site unless that building houses 
equipment accessory to the support structure. Setback from residential. Where permitted, a new, support structure, 
including any accessory structure, shall be located at a minimum distance equal 
to but not less than 100 feet from the site of any residential use or any 
residentially zoned land. 
 Co-location. The co-location 
of antennas on a single support structure is encouraged. This includes 
co-location with other wireless telecommunications antenna facilities including 
those of public and quasi-public agencies using similar technology unless 
specific technical constraints preclude co-location. 
 Camouflage. A new support 
structure that is designed to look like a faux tree or flag pole shall comply 
with the following requirements:

 
 
 Flag Poles. A flag shall be 
flown and properly maintained at all times, and the base of the pole shall be 
appropriately tapered to maintain the appearance of an actual flag pole. 
 Faux Trees. If a faux tree is 
proposed, it shall be of a type of tree compatible with those existing in the 
immediate areas of the installation. If no trees exist within the immediate 
areas, the applicant shall create a landscape setting that integrates the faux 
tree with added species of a similar height and type. Additional camouflage of 
the faux tree may be required depending on the type and design of faux tree 
proposed. 
 
 Height limit. Where allowed, 
support structures shall not exceed a maximum height of 50 feet above existing 
grade in any zoning district. 
 Justification Study. The 
applicant shall submit a justification study indicating the rationale for 
selecting the proposed use, a detailed explanation of the coverage gap that the 
proposed use would serve, and how the proposed use is the least intrusive means 
for the applicant to provide wireless service. 
 Location. 

 
 
A support structure and any related 
ground-mounted equipment cabinet shall not be located within an area devoted to 
a vehicle/pedestrian circulation area in such a manner that it interferes with 
or impairs the utility of intended function of such area. 
Where feasible, unutilized space 
should be made available for co-location with other wireless telecommunications 
antenna facilities, including space for entities providing competing services. 
Co-location of wireless telecommunications antenna facilities is not required in 
cases where the addition of new service of facilities would cause service 
impairment to an existing facility, or if it became necessary for the host 
facility to go off-line for a significant period of time. 
A support structure shall not be 
located within any designated historic district or landmark district. 
A support structure shall not be 
located within any City-owned library property. 
 
 Distance Requirement. There 
shall be a 500-foot distance requirement between each site containing an 
individual support structure, measured from site to site. 
 Finding required for approval. 

 
 
 Required finding. No new 
support structure will be allowed unless the review authority, in addition to 
the findings required by Section 17.61.050.H , 
first finds that, based upon evidence submitted by the applicant, no existing 
building or support structure can reasonably accommodate the proposed wireless 
telecommunications antenna facility. 
 Evidence to support finding. Evidence supporting the required finding will be reviewed by the Zoning 
Administrator and may consist of any of the following:

 
 
No existing buildings or support 
 structures are located within the geographic area proposed to be served by 
 the applicant&apos;s facility; 
Existing buildings or support 
 structures are not of sufficient height to meet the applicant&apos;s operational 
 or engineering requirements; or 
The applicant&apos;s proposed facility 
 would create radio frequency interference with an existing structure, or the 
 existing structure would create radio frequency interference with the 
 applicant&apos;s proposed facility. 
 
 
 Security. The support 
structure and support facilities shall be constructed so as to prevent 
unauthorized entry into the support facilities or onto the support structure. 
 
 Requirements for co-located 
facilities (Wireless Telecommunications Antenna Facilities, Minor). Unless 
shielded from public view, the antenna array may not extend above the highest 
ridge line of the roof line or parapet of an existing structure. However, whip 
antennas and omni-directional antennas may extend up to 10 feet above the roof 
line or parapet of an existing structure. To the extent feasible, the antenna 
array shall be integrated into the design of the structure it is mounted to and 
be fully screened from public view. ( See 
Interpretation ) 
 
 
 Screening. All 
 screening shall be compatible with the architecture, color, texture, and 
 materials of the building or other structure to which it is mounted. 
 Concealed from public 
 view. All sides of the project shall be concealed from public view. 
 There shall be no visible transition between existing and new surfaces, 
 no exposed cables, mounting apparatus or pipes permitted, and no 
 interruption of horizontal or vertical reveals. 
 Private light poles. If co-locating on a privately-owned light pole, the replacement pole 
 shall match the color, height, and design of existing light poles on the 
 site. 
 
 
 Requirements for 
 building-mounted facilities . Unless shielded from public view, the 
 antenna array of a building-mounted facility may not extend above the 
 highest ridge line of the roof line or parapet of an existing structure. 
 However, whip antennas and omni-directional antennas may extend up to 10 
 feet above the roof line or parapet of an existing structure. 
 Requirements for Wireless 
 Telecommunications Antenna Facilities, Specific Co-Located. 

 
 
 Ministerial permit. The City shall not require a discretionary permit for a Wireless 
 Telecommunications Antenna Facility. SCL, if it satisfies the 
 requirements of California Government Code Section 65850.6(a), as 
 amended. 
 Application requirements. An application for a Wireless Telecommunications Antenna Facility, SCL, 
 shall be filed in compliance with Chapter 17.60 (Application Filing 
 and Processing). The application shall be accompanied by the information 
 identified in the Department handout for Wireless Telecommunications 
 Antenna Facility, SCL, applications and shall include payment of any 
 application fee. 
 Review authority. An 
 application for a Wireless Telecommunications Antenna Facility, SCL, 
 shall be reviewed by the Director. 
 Required findings for 
 approval. 

 

The Director shall approve an 
 application only after finding that:

 
 
The proposed use is 
 allowed within the zoning district and complies with all applicable 
 provisions of this Code. 
The location of the 
 proposed use complies with the special purposes of this Code and the 
 applicable zoning district, and is in conformance with the goals, 
 policies, and objectives of the General Plan. 
The proposed use does not 
 increase the height of the existing wireless telecommunications 
 antenna facility. 
The proposed use complies 
 with all requirements for major wireless telecommunications antenna 
 facilities within this section. 
The proposed use will not 
 be detrimental to the health or general welfare of persons residing 
 or working in the neighborhood of the proposed use. 
The proposed use will be 
 compatible with the existing uses on the site and uses in the 
 vicinity in terms of aesthetic values, character, scale, and view 
 protection and will not interfere with the existing activities at 
 the site. 
 
 Decision. The Director 
 shall prepare a written decision to approve, approve with conditions, or 
 disapprove the application. The Director shall provide notice of the 
 decision to the applicant, all persons who have filed a written request for 
 notice of the decision, the Planning Commission, and the City Council. 
 

 17.50.320 - Tents 


 Exemption from Temporary Use Permit. The use of a tent for a temporary event or other purpose shall require a Temporary Use Permit, unless
all of the following provisions are met:

 Commercial, industrial, public, or
semi-public land uses . The site is
developed with commercial, industrial, public, or semi-public land uses , and:

 Not over 800 square feet. The area covered by tents does not exceed 800 square
feet; Not in street setback . No tent is located in any setback (e.g., front or
corner side) adjacent to a street ; and Not longer than 36 hours. No tent is located on the site for more than 36
hours at a time, and on the site for more than five times within any 30-day
period.
 Residential uses . The site is developed with residential uses , and:

 Not over 800 square feet. The area covered by tents does not exceed 800 square
feet; Not in street setback . No tent is located in any setback (e.g., front or
corner side) adjacent to a street ; and Not longer than 36 hours. No tent is located on the site for more than 36
hours at a time and on the site more than twice in one calendar year.

 Compliance with Section 17.61.040 . If required, the Temporary Use Permit shall be granted in compliance with Section 17.61.040 .
 
17.50.330 - Tobacco Retail Sales 


 1,000-foot separation
required. No significant tobacco
retailer shall be located within 1,000 feet of a sensitive land use (e.g., game
arcade, Internet access studio, library, licensed child day-care facility
[excluding a small or large family day-care use ], park and recreation facility,
public or private school, or theater, as any of those land use types may be
defined in Article 8 (Glossary)). How to measure separation. The distance between any structure used as a
significant tobacco retailer and another structure used as a sensitive land use shall be measured in a straight line, without regard to intervening structures ,
from the closest property line of the structure used as a significant tobacco
retailer to the closest property line of another structure used as a sensitive
land use . Operation standards. 

 The tobacco retailer shall comply with all
applicable local, State, and Federal laws regarding the advertising, display,
or sales of tobacco products. Only store employees shall have immediate
access to the tobacco products and/or tobacco paraphernalia. No person under 18 years of age may
distribute, exchange, or sell tobacco products. Sampling of tobacco products by individuals
less than 18 years of age shall be prohibited.

 
17.50.340 - Transit-Oriented Development ( TOD )


 Applicability. 

 The standards of this Section provide for a
mixture of commercial, high- density residential, mixed- use , public, and
semi-public uses in close proximity to light rail stations, encouraging transit
usage in conjunction with a safe and pleasant pedestrian-oriented environment. These standards emphasize intensification of development and reduced reliance on motor vehicles. These standards shall apply to new development projects located within 1,320 feet (1/4 mile) of a light-rail
station platform. Within the Central District , these standards shall apply to the
area identified on Figure 3-5 - Central District Transit-Oriented Area.
 Prohibited land uses . The following nontransit-oriented land uses , as
these land uses are defined in Article 8 (Glossary of Technical Terms and Land Use Types), are prohibited:

 Drive-through businesses ; Large recycling facilities; Vehicle services - sales and leasing ;
(except for sales and leasing - limited); Vehicle services - service stations ; Vehicle services - washing and detailing;
(except washing and detailing, small-scale); Vehicle storage ; and Wholesaling, distribution, and storage (including commercial and small-scale).
 Permit requirements. A Minor Conditional Use Permit shall be required for
any proposed commercial and industrial development projects with over 15,000
square feet of gross floor area .

 Issues for review. Minor Conditional Use Permit review shall consider
the site plan of the proposed project to ensure that findings can be made that
the use is compatible with transit. Required findings. Minor Conditional Use Permit approval shall require
that the review authority first make the following findings in addition to the
findings required by Section 17.61.050 :

 The project consists of a use ,
or mix of uses , that encourage transit use and is oriented toward the transit
user. The project is designed to
enhance pedestrian access and/or other non-motor vehicle modes of
transportation to public transit. The project encourages
pedestrian activity and/or other non-motor vehicle modes of transportation and
reduces dependency on motor vehicles.

 Parking requirements. ( See 
Interpretation )

 Parking reductions for nonresidential development projects . 

 Office uses . For the uses offices - administrative business
professional and offices - governmental, the minimum amount of required
off- street parking shall be reduced by 25 percent, and this reduction shall be
the maximum allowed number of parking spaces . All other nonresidential uses . For all other nonresidential uses the minimum amount of required off- street parking shall be reduced by 10
percent, and this reduction shall be the maximum allowed number of parking
spaces . Further reduction with
study. The parking requirements may
be further reduced through a parking demand study and approval of a Minor
Conditional Use Permit.
 Exceeding allowable parking requirements. A project site may exceed the maximum allowable
parking requirements in compliance with the following conditions.

 Commercial off-street
parking . If the parking is intended
to serve as commercial off-street parking . Approval of this parking shall
require the granting of a Minor Conditional Use Permit in compliance with Section 17.61.050 . Shared parking. A site may exceed the maximum allowable number of parking spaces if the parking is approved to serve as shared parking in
compliance with Section 17.46.050 . Joint parking. A site may exceed the maximum allowed number of parking spaces if the parking is approved to serve as joint parking. 
(1) Joint parking is a type of
parking that is designed to serve uses on at least two different sites .
(2) The joint parking provided
shall not exceed the maximum required parking for the combined total parking
requirements of the different individual sites . 
 Residential development projects . The following requirements apply to multi-family
residential and mixed- use development projects proposing at least 48 dwelling
units per acre.

 Residential parking shall be a
minimum of: 
(1) 1 space for each unit for units
less than 650 square feet to a maximum of 1.25 spaces per unit; and
(2) 1.5 spaces for each unit for
units 650 square feet or more to a maximum of 1.75 spaces per unit. The parking requirements may be
further reduced through a parking demand study and approval of a Minor
Conditional Use Permit in compliance with Section 17.61.050 . The cap includes the minimum
parking requirement as well as the requirement for guest parking. City Permits for overnight
parking shall not be allowed. 
(1) City Permits for overnight
parking on City streets shall not be issued for residential development projects built in compliance with these regulations .
(2) Residential tenants shall be
advised of the unavailability of on- street overnight parking permits. Guest parking shall be
provided as required by Table 4-6 (Off- Street Parking Space Requirements). The
number of guest parking shall not exceed the minimum required.
 
 Modification.  The Zoning Administrator may modify the 
required parking in a parking garage (including below grade and at or above 
grade garages) by allowing the total parking requirement to exceed or be reduced 
by five percent but not more than 10 spaces. 
 Development projects within
the CG zoning district . 

 1/4 mile of the Allen Street Station. For development projects located within 1/4 mile of
the Allen Street Station, multi- family uses are conditionally permitted , shall
contain a minimum of 50 dwelling units , and shall have a maximum allowable density of 48 units per acre. The Conditional Use Permit shall also establish
the appropriate setbacks . Between 1/4 and 1/2 mile of the Allen Street Station. For development projects that are located between 1/4 of a mile and 1/2 mile of the Allen Street Station, and require a Conditional Use Permit for a project over 25,000 square
feet of gross floor area , the additional findings identified in Subsection C.,
above, shall not be required, but shall be used to guide the review of the project and the development of appropriate conditions. Further reductions. The parking requirements may be further reduced
through a parking demand study and the issuance of a Minor Conditional Use Permit in compliance with Section 17.61.050 .

 
17.50.350 - Urban Housing 


 Applicability. The development standards of this Section shall
apply to the following:

 Residential development projects utilizing a density greater than 48 dwelling units per acre. Development projects located within the CD zoning district . Development projects located outside the CD zoning district , but designated for transit-oriented development around
light-rail stations.
 Density and height standards. The density and height standards for an urban housing development project shall be in compliance with
the underlying zoning district . Setbacks required. In order to provide suitable amounts of air, light,
and open space , the following setbacks shall be required:

 Front and corner side: In compliance with
the underlying zoning district . Side and rear:

 Ten-foot minimum. Through the Design Review
process, the side and rear setbacks may be reduced if the reduction results in
a larger courtyard.

 Street entries required. Residential dwelling units located adjacent to the street shall have direct entries from the street . Open space required: 

 A minimum of 30 percent of the net floor
area of the structure shall be provided as open space . The minimum dimension of any open space shall be six feet in any direction. Private balconies, at- grade patios,
rooftop gardens (including upper level terraces), and the portion of a front or corner side yard setback that is greater than the minimum requirement may be
counted as open space . Not more than 35 percent of the total open
space may be met by counting balconies. Planter balconies that are two feet or less
in width shall not be counted as open space .
 Courtyard requirement. There shall be a ground-floor landscaped courtyard
that shall be a minimum of 20 feet in any direction. Balconies may project up
to four feet into the courtyard. Courtyard opening required. 

 Opening required. For structures with 75 feet of street frontage or
more, the street side of the structure shall have an opening into a landscaped
courtyard. Minimum height of opening. This opening shall be a minimum of 50 percent of the
overall height of the structure but not more than 25 feet. Minimum width of opening. 

 The width of the opening shall
be a minimum of 10 feet. If the depth of the structure opening is more than 30 feet, the minimum width of the opening shall be
increased by one foot for every three feet of depth above 30 feet.
 Multiple frontages. For structures with multiple frontages, the Design
Review process shall determine which frontages shall have an opening in
compliance with Section 17.61.030 . Modification through Design Review. The requirements of this Subsection may be modified
through the Design Review process. Gate transparency. Any gate placed across the courtyard opening shall
have a minimum of 75 percent transparency.
 Parking and Driveways. 

 Location of parking. 

 Parking areas shall be
provided either at grade , semi-subterranean, or subterranean. Parking areas (e.g., provided
at grade or semi-subterranean) shall not abut the front or corner side street elevations. Only completely subterranean parking facilities may be located
within the front or corner side setbacks . All other parking areas shall be
located behind the habitable living space required by Subparagraph c.,
immediately below. Each dwelling unit contiguous
to a front or corner side street elevation shall have a habitable living space
on the ground floor that is a minimum of 12 feet in depth, measured from the
interior wall closest to the street .
 One space per unit on-site . For new development projects , parking shall be
provided in compliance with Table 4-5 (Off- Street Parking Space Requirements B multi- family dwelling units ) and there shall be a
minimum of one off- street parking space for each residential unit located on
the subject site . Guest parking required. Guest parking shall be provided for the residential
units in compliance with Table 4-5 (Off- Street Parking Space Requirements B multi- family dwelling units ). Other spaces may be located off-site . All other parking spaces designed to serve the
residential units may be located off-site with a long-term parking lease
agreement in compliance with Subsection 17.46.020 I. (Location and ownership). Distance requirements. Off-site parking for residential units shall meet
the distance requirements for commercial customer/visitor spaces in compliance
with Subsection 17.46.020 .I (Location and ownership). Conversion of existing structures . Conversions of existing structures (including
additions) may provide parking for residential units off-site as long as they
meet the distance requirements and there is a long term parking lease agreement
all in compliance with Subsection 17.46.020 I.(Location and ownership). Driveway location. Driveways shall be located not more than five feet
from a side property line . The review authority (i.e., Design Commission ,
Planning Director ) may modify the location of a driveway to preserve a street tree or tree located on the site .
 Landscaping required. All areas of the subject site not devoted to lot
coverage , driveways, or walkways shall be properly landscaped and maintained 
in compliance with Chapter 17.44 ( Landscaping ). Balconies. 

 Balconies may project no closer than six
feet to an interior or rear property line and four feet into a front or corner
side setback . Balconies shall have a minimum dimension of
six feet in order to count as required open space . Balconies that are designed to project over
the public right-of-way shall have prior approval from the Department of Public
Works.
 Fences and walls. 

 Fences and walls located along a street frontage are limited to four feet in height . Fences and walls located within rear and
interior side setbacks are limited to six feet in height . Projects with rear and interior side yards located adjacent to commercial uses may have a fence or wall height up to eight
feet. Fences located within front and corner side setbacks shall have a minimum of 50 percent transparency. Fence height shall be measure from the existing grade .
 Overnight parking permits
not allowed. 


 City Permits for overnight parking on City streets shall not be issued for residential development projects built in
compliance with this Section . Residential tenants shall be advised of the
unavailability of on- street overnight parking permits.
 Urban noise levels. 

 Residents of an urban housing development project shall be notified that they are living in an urban area and that the
noise levels may be higher than in a typical residential area. The signature of the residents shall confirm
receipt and understanding of this information.
 Loading and unloading of
household goods. If the loading and
unloading of furniture and household goods for residential dwelling units is to
occur on the street , it shall be limited to the hours of 9:00 a.m. to 2:00 p.m.
and 7:00 p.m. to 10:00 p.m. on weekdays and 9:00 a.m. to 10:00 p.m. on
weekends.
 
17.50.360 - Vehicle Sales and Repair Services


 Applicability. Vehicle repair , when it is accessory to vehicle
sales, shall meet the additional standards identified in this Section . Distance Requirement. In the CG-1 district , vehicle repair shall be located
a minimum of 500 feet from another vehicle repair use . This requirement shall
be measured from property line to property line . Lot size. In the CG-1 district , vehicle repair uses shall have
a minimum lot size of 15,000 square feet. Maximum floor space. The floor space dedicated to vehicle repair shall be
limited to a maximum of 40 percent of the lot area . Servicing of trucks and
industrial equipment prohibited. No
servicing of trucks in excess of one and one-half ton capacity or industrial
equipment of any type or character shall be allowed. All repair activities
located within an enclosed structure . 

 All hydraulic hoists and pits, and all
equipment for greasing, lubrication, and allowed repairs shall be enclosed
entirely within a structure . All areas or structures used for vehicle
repair shall be located or soundproofed to prevent annoyance or detriment to
surrounding properties.
 Limited hours and days of
operation. 

 All vehicle/ equipment repair uses and
related activities shall be limited to between the hours of 7:00 a.m. and 7:00
p.m., Monday through Saturday. The hours of operation or allowed days shall
not be modified through a Conditional Use Permit.
 Allowed on-site for repair only. Damaged or wrecked vehicles shall not be stored on-site for purposes other than repair. On-site parking requirements. 

 In order to ensure that adequate parking is
provided on-site and that the potential for parking in the public right-of-way is
minimized, on-site parking shall be provided at a minimum ratio of four spaces
per 1,000 square feet of gross floor area . Workstation/service bays used for the repair
of vehicles shall not be credited toward meeting the on-site parking
requirement. Queuing lanes to workstation/service bays
shall not be credited toward meeting the on-site parking requirement.
 Parking only allowed on-site . All vehicles that are
repaired and are waiting to be picked up by the owner of the vehicle shall be
parked on-site and not in adjoining streets or alleys . Do not face abutting residential parcels. All new structures constructed for vehicle/ equipment repair shall be constructed so
that the entrances to individual workstation/service bays do not face abutting residential parcels or the public rights-of-way. Discarded vehicles and parts
to be removed. All discarded vehicle
parts or equipment, or permanently disabled, dismantled, or junked vehicles
shall be removed from the premises within 30 days of arrival. Old tires to be stored in
solid wall enclosure. Tires taken in
on trade that have no more than salvage value shall be stored in a solid wall
enclosure.
 
17.50.370 - Work/Live 
Units 


 Applicability. This Section provides standards for work/live and
artists lofts/studios, including the reuse of existing nonresidential structures to accommodate work/live opportunities. Work/live quarters are
especially intended for the use and occupation of artisans, artists, and
individuals practicing similar professions as well as their families. Design standards. 

 Floor area requirement. 

 A work/live unit shall have a
minimum floor area of least 1,250 square feet. The maximum size of the
residential portion of the work/live unit shall be 30 percent of the unit or
400 square feet, whichever is less, in order to ensure that the residential
portion remains an accessory to the primary commercial use . A ground-level work/live unit
with street frontage shall devote the initial 25 feet of floor area depth to
commercial activity. 
 Unit access. Where there are multiple work/ live units within a
single structure , each unit shall be physically separated from other units and uses within the structure , and access to individual units shall be from a
common open space , corridor, hallway, or other common access area. Internal integration of the work/live unit. 

 There shall be direct access
between the working and living spaces within the work/live unit. There shall be no separate
entrance to the living space by a separate door. All access to the living
space shall be from the working space. The working space shall not be
leased separately from the living space; conversely the living space shall not
be leased separately from the working space.

 Occupancy and employees. 

 At least one full-time employee of business
activity occupying the work/live unit shall also reside in the unit; conversely
at least one of the persons living in the live portion shall work in the work
portion. The business activity occupying the
work/live unit may utilize nonresident employees, as necessary.
 Prohibited land uses . The following shall not be allowed in a work/live
unit:

 Sexually oriented businesses ; Motor vehicle maintenance and repair; and Welding and/or machining.
 Hazardous Materials. All uses with hazardous materials shall comply with
the California Fire Codes and other applicable codes . Mix of land uses . An appropriate mix of land uses shall be established
through the Conditional Use Permit process, in compliance with Section 17.61.050 . Compliance with City inspection program required. 

 In order to ensure that a work/live unit
continues to be operated as a bonafide work/live unit, all work/ live units shall be subject to the City &apos;s quadrennial
inspection program, if leased or rented, in compliance with Municipal Code Section 14.16.030. For a work/live unit that is owner-occupied
or has been converted to a condominium, the units would be subject to the City &apos;s inspection program at the time each unit is resold.
 Business License required. The occupants of the work/ live units shall maintain
a valid City Business License in order to ensure that the primary use remains a commercial use . Inclusionary housing
requirements. The construction of
work/ live units shall be subject to the inclusionary housing requirements of Section 17.42.040 ( Inclusionary Unit Requirements). Environmental assessment
required. 

 Reuse of an existing structure shall require environmental assessment of the site . The written assessment report shall be
submitted as part of the Conditional Use Permit application.

 
 
 
 Table of Contents Article 1  •  Article 2  •  Article 3  •  Article 4 
 Article 5  •  Article 6  •  Article 7  •  Article 8 Glossary 
 Appendix
	</body>
</document>
