<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006842" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g34118-d2207974-r117584492-THE_DOG_Bar_Grille-Cape_Coral_Florida.html" time="2012-07-12-23:49" support="1" score="0.0011656620487875068" bingtitle="Inconsistent restaurant - Review of THE DOG Bar &amp; Grille, Cape ..." webtitle="Inconsistent restaurant - Review of THE DOG BarGrille, Cape Coral, FL - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>I switched my order to breaded chicken breast with ... processed chicken like you would see in fast food restaurant ... was so awful I couldn&apos;t force myself to eat ...</description>
	<body>
		THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille reviews
 
 Home Cape Coral 
 Cape Coral Tourism Cape Coral Hotels Cape Coral Vacation Rentals Flights to Cape Coral Cape Coral Restaurants Things to Do in Cape Coral Cape Coral Travel Forum Cape Coral Photos Cape Coral Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Florida (FL) &gt; Southwest Gulf Coast &gt; Cape Coral &gt; Cape Coral Restaurants &gt; THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille 
 
 Back to THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille 
THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille: Restaurant Reviews
 3522 Del Prado Blvd S , Cape Coral , FL 33904 239-541-8304 Website Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #61 of 153 restaurants in Cape Coral 14 Reviews Price range: $4 - $15 Cuisines: American, Hamburgers, Healthy, Seafood, Vegetarian Good for: Families with children, Bar scene, Large groups, Outdoor seating Dining options: Lunch Restaurant details Good for: Families with children, Bar scene, Large groups, Outdoor seating Dining options: Lunch Update restaurant details Write a Review 
14 reviews from our community
 64% Recommend 
 Excellent 3 Very good 6 Average 3 Poor 1 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 14 reviews sorted by Date Rating TerPorrino Cape Coral, Florida Reviewer 4 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 3 helpful votes “Inconsistent restaurant” Reviewed September 2, 2011 
My husband and I used to go to First Round Draft in Cape Coral pretty regularly and really enjoyed it a lot. However, First Round had a fire and they have been closed for several months while repairs were being made. We often see advertisements for the First Round Draft suggesting that customers visit their other restaurant, The Dog, while repairs were underway, so we finally tried it out.

The outside area is very welcoming, and the interior was warm and inviting as well. It is painted and styled in a very modern, adult oriented fashion. The walls are covered with prints of dogs, and the menu, in keeping with the dog theme, is categorized by&quot;tailwaggers&quot;,&quot;ruffage&quot;,&quot;dog gone good sandwiches&quot;, etc.

We ordered wings as an appetizer, and they were quite good. Then our salads came out. My husband was content with his salad, but the lettuce in mine was brown around the edges. Our waitress, Serena, was very knowledgeable about the menu, and when my husband ordered Pork Osso Bucco, she said that was a good choice. I originally asked for the Pot Roast in Brown Gravy and inquired if the carrots and potatoes could be swapped out for mashed potatoes. Serena said she could ask, but the dish ingredients were all cooked together so I wouldn&apos;t be getting the full serving. I switched my order to breaded chicken breast with mashed potatoes&amp;gravy. When we dine at First Round Draft, I always order the Fried Chicken Breast with Mashed Potatoes and Gravy, which I love, and I was expecting the same type of food from The Dog. My entree arrived with two large golden triangles and a scoop of mashed potatoes with gravy in a little bowl. It appeared to be straight out of an elementary school cafeteria. The mashed potatoes were cold, and the chicken looked just like two giant chicken nuggets. I cut one open and it was clearly over-processed chicken like you would see in fast food restaurant nuggets or out of a box of frozen chicken. I took one bite of the chicken and I was done. It was so awful I couldn&apos;t force myself to eat it. My husband&apos;s Pork Osso Bucco, however, was tender and delicious. The meat fell off the bone and was flavored perfectly, and was served on a tasy bed of rice.

It was bizarre that my husband&apos;s meal was so good while mine was so disappointing. I thought maybe I shouldn&apos;t have been surprised, as macaroni and cheese was an optional side dish.....maybe I was served a kid&apos;s meal by mistake? The chicken was nothing like the meals at First Round Draft.

Another waitress took our plates away when we were done, and a few minutes later Serena came out and said she noticed I didn&apos;t eat the chicken and wanted to know if there was a problem. I said it was nasty and I couldn&apos;t eat it. Serena offered to bring me something else from the menu, but I was not interested in trying anything else. She was very apologetic and we assured her it wasn&apos;t her fault. When we received our bill Serena had removed the charge for my entree and said she couldn&apos;t charge us for something we didn&apos;t eat.

When we left, a musical duo was just starting to perform in the lounge, and they sounded great.

The Dog seems like a fun place to go and hang out, have a drink and listen to music... but maybe the menu is targeted for children. I&apos;m not sure. Overall, our waitress and service was good, and one of us had a great meal. We might return there again for the entertainment, but we will never order a chicken dinner again!
 
 Visited August 2011 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask TerPorrino about THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. SWCapeCoral München Top Contributor 189 reviews Reviews in 63 cities 71 helpful votes “Coole Kneipe mit Live Musik” Reviewed December 18, 2011 2 people found this review helpful 

 
 Visited December 2011 
 Value Atmosphere 

 Service Food 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 11 more reviews by SWCapeCoral for Cape Coral Ask SWCapeCoral about THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 13-14 of 14 reviews « 1 ... 3 4 » 
Travelers who viewed THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille also viewed
 Rumrunners 191 Reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast Marker 92 Waterfront Bar&amp;Bistro 135 Reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast   Nauti Mermaid Dockside Bar and Grill 36 Reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast Lobster Lady Seafood Market&amp;Bistro 62 Reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast   All restaurants in Cape Coral (153) 
Been to THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?
 
If you own or manage THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.

 Manage your listing 
 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 Casa Loma Motel on the Waterfront 33 Reviews Read reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast The Resort at MarinaVillage 237 Reviews Read reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast The Sun and the Moon Inn 14 Reviews Read reviews Cape Coral, Southwest Gulf Coast 
 All hotels in Cape Coral (7) 
Browse nearby
 Restaurants (153) | Hotels (7) | Things to Do (17) THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille 3522 Del Prado Blvd S Cape Coral, FL 33904 Get Directions What&apos;s Nearby: Hotels Restaurants Things to Do Click map pins for more information. You are zoomed out too far to see location pins. Please zoom back in. Interactive map 
Free Cape Coral Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Cape Coral restaurants

 Pete&apos;s Fish and Chips Misto Bar and Grill Brew Babies Chef J Bistro Bonefish Grill Maria&apos;s Pizzeria&amp;Restaurant Lobster Lady Seafood Market&amp;Bistro Mel&apos;s Diner Little Sicily Trattoria Siam Hut Ariani Restaurant&amp;Lounge Carrabba&apos;s Italian Grill Ciao Wood Fired Pizza and Trattoria Duke of Germany Moorings Restaurant Fletchers Grill and Spirits Rumrunners Sakura Japanese Steak House Beef O&apos;Brady&apos;s Family Sports Pub Coral Shores The Joint 
 
Hotels around Cape Coral

 Sanibel Harbour Marriott Resort&amp;Spa 4.0 out of 5, 284 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Hampton Inn&amp;Suites Fort Myers Beach / Summerlin Road 3.5 out of 5, 156 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 South Seas Island Resort 4.0 out of 5, 1,076 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Americas Best Value Inn 4.0 out of 5, 54 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 BEST WESTERN Airport Inn 4.5 out of 5, 72 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 BEST WESTERN Fort Myers Waterfront 3.5 out of 5, 89 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Clarion Hotel Fort Myers 3.0 out of 5, 78 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Cape Paradise Resort 2.5 out of 5, 24 reviews Last reviewed Jul 5, 2012 Anchor Inn&amp;Cottages 4.5 out of 5, 57 reviews Last reviewed Jul 2, 2012 Suburban Extended Stay of Fort Myers 3.0 out of 5, 30 reviews Last reviewed Jun 26, 2012 La Quinta Inn Fort Myers Central 3.5 out of 5, 105 reviews Last reviewed Jun 17, 2012 Ramada Inn&amp;Suites at Amtel Marina 3.0 out of 5, 12 reviews Last reviewed May 28, 2012 Rock Lake Resort 4.0 out of 5, 67 reviews Last reviewed May 26, 2012 Harbour House at the Inn 4.5 out of 5, 43 reviews Last reviewed May 25, 2012 Legacy Harbour Hotel&amp;Suites 4.5 out of 5, 12 reviews Last reviewed May 22, 2012 
 Explore the world Hotels 
 Grand Beach Hotel in Miami Beach 4.0 out of 5, 1,226 reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 Hyatt Hill Country Resort 4.0 out of 5, 441 reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 Hampton Inn&amp;Suites Oklahoma City / Bricktown 4.5 out of 5, 142 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 
 Travel Destinations 
 Cedeira hotels 6 hotels, 44 Reviews Avignon hotels 231 hotels, 6,224 Reviews Nashville 185 hotels, 15,725 Reviews Victoria 288 hotels, 13,334 Reviews Soufriere deals 70 hotels, 3,732 Reviews San Francisco deals 603 hotels, 91,934 Reviews 
 Sightseeing 
 Paradise Restaurant Terraza Bar and Beach Club in Acapulco 4.0 out of 5, 6 reviews 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor™ provides traveler reviews of THE DOG Bar&amp;Grille . Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
