<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006509" url="http://voices.washingtonpost.com/checkup/2010/12/cspi_helps_mom_sue_mcds_over_h.html" time="2012-07-12-23:26" support="1" score="0.0005460191847918873" bingtitle="The Checkup - CSPI helps mom sue McDonald&apos;s over Happy Meal toys" webtitle="The Checkup
 - CSPI helps mom sue McDonald&apos;s over Happy Meal toys">
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>... and actually changing what my kids want to eat.&quot; ... This woman is a piece of trash who should be ashamed ... the temptation to let my daughter pick any fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		&gt; The Checkup  
Network News
 X My Profile 
 Friends&apos; Activity 
 View More Activity 
 Column Archive  |  On Twitter: J Huget and MisFits  |  Fitness&amp;Nutrition News  |    RSS Feed About the Bloggers 
 About Jennifer and Rob 
 Search This Blog   
 Recent Posts 
 One embryo good for IVF, study finds Teen birth rate hits record low What&apos;s up with Weight Watchers? GERD and esophageal cancer: 5 things you should know Is that right? Soda taxes would help fight obesity? 
 
 Entries By Category breast cancer ADHD About the Blog Acne Birth Control Cancer Contraception Dentistry Dietary Guidelines Dietary supplements Drug Abuse Economy FDA Family Health First aid and CPR Food labeling General Health Health Policy Hispanics Injury prevention Is That Right? Kids&apos; health Me Minus 10 Minority health Motherhood Nobel Prize Nutrition and Fitness Obesity Parenting Reproductive Health School Nutrition Sodium Strokes Vaccines Vitamins Weight loss Women&apos;s Health Workplace health allergies blood safety death and dying diarrhea digestive tract health drug safety emergency medicine end-of-life care glycemic index heart failure infertility life expectancy medical costs medicare osteoporosis palliative and hospice care prostate cancer red cross stem cells Full Category Archive 
 Entries By Date 
 Full Weekly Archive 
 Subscribe 
 Select ... 
 RSS Feed Close Health Section 

 Blogroll 
 Well Wall Street Journal&apos;s Health Blog Julie&apos;s Health Club Eat Like Me Food Politics FoodThink with Wansink The Nutrition Data Blog Consumer Reports Health Blog Booster Shots 
 Posted at 11:22 AM ET, 12/16/2010 
CSPI helps mom sue McDonald&apos;s over Happy Meal toys
 By 
 
 Jennifer LaRue Huget 
 Forty percent of children ages 2 to 11 ask their parents to take them to McDonald&apos;s at least once a week, and 15 percent of preschoolers ask to go every single day. (Afp/Getty Images/Karen Bleier) 
The D.C.-based nutrition watchdog group Center for Science in the Public Interest has helped a California mother file a class-action suit against McDonald&apos;s , demanding that the burger chain stop marketing toys to children.

The woman, Monet Parham of Sacramento, claims that the marketing of Happy Meal toys has interfered with her ability as a parent to provide her two children with a healthful diet. Here&apos;s a quote:
 
&quot;I am concerned about the health of my children and feel that McDonald&apos;s should be a very limited part of their diet and their childhood experience,&quot; Parham said. &quot;But as other busy, working moms and dads know, we have to say &apos;no&apos; to our young children so many times, and McDonald&apos;s makes it that so much harder to do. I object to the fact that McDonald&apos;s is getting into my kids&apos; heads without my permission and actually changing what my kids want to eat.&quot;
 
CSPI maintains that advertising to people who can&apos;t understand the concept of persuasive advertising amounts to deceptive -- and therefore illegal -- advertising. The CSPI news release announcing the action against McDonald&apos;s says:
 
According to the Institute of Medicine and the American Psychological Association, kids as young as Maya do not have the cognitive maturity to understand the persuasive intent of advertising. Advertising that is not understood to be advertising is inherently deceptive -- an idea that CSPI&apos;s lawsuit points out is well established in law. &quot;Every time McDonald&apos;s markets a Happy Meal directly to a young child, it exploits a child&apos;s developmental vulnerability and violates several states&apos; consumer protection laws, including the California Unfair Competition Law,&quot; said CSPI litigation director Steve Gardner.
 
Seems to me this is at least as much a parenting issue as it is a matter of deceptive marketing.

I have been quite frank about the fact that my own two kids haven&apos;t always, and don&apos;t always, eat as healthfully as they probably should; sometimes I&apos;m surprised and even embarrassed by their food choices.

But I can&apos;t recall a single occasion on which either child saw a McDonald&apos;s ad and begged/nagged/bullied me into taking them to Mickey D&apos;s. And if they had, the answer would as likely as not have been &quot;no.&quot;

Which is not to say that we never have eaten under the Golden Arches. It&apos;s just that we as parents decided when we would and when we wouldn&apos;t. In our family, the kids aren&apos;t in charge.

Your thoughts? Please comment below, and vote in the poll!


 2010 12 16 11 22 
ByJennifer LaRue Huget | December 16, 2010; 11:22 AM ET
Categories:  Childhood obesity , Family Health , Kids&apos; health , Motherhood , Nutrition and Fitness , Obesity , Parenting
	</body>
</document>
