<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006919" url="http://ian-pullen.suite101.com/typical-design-points-of-a-fast-food-logo-a90061" time="2012-07-12-23:54" support="15" score="0.06924094849492828" bingtitle="Typical Design Points of a Fast Food Logo: Sample Logo and Menu ..." webtitle="Typical Design Points of a Fast Food Logo: Sample Logo and Menu Cover for Fast Food Restaurant | Suite101.com">
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000945" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000913" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000441" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001101" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000922" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="88"/>
	<description>... is a look at sample designs for a fictional fast food restaurant ... are looking for well priced food that they can pick ... available space on the menu cover is used in order ...</description>
	<body>
		Typical Design Points of a Fast Food Logo

Sample Logo and Menu Cover for Fast Food Restaurant
 Tweet 
 Jan 14, 2009 Ian Pullen 
 Strong colors are typical of fast food restaurants - Ian Pullen This is a look at sample designs for a fictional fast food restaurant with explanations for some of the Graphic Design choices. 
For this example design, the subject is a fictional fast food restaurant called Newbys.

Newbys is a generic fast food outlet producing the usual types of fast food, including hamburgers and fries.

Target Market

Customers of Newbys are looking for well priced food that they can pick up on the go and consume easily without having to take any more time out of their day than is absolutely necessary to refuel. This is a very basic and no frills segment of the market lacking in any forms of pretence.

Font

In this case, the chosen font is a commercially available font called Dom BT Diagonal Bold. This is a handwriting style font and in the bold diagonal version has a feel reminiscent of chalk writing on a black board.
 
The looseness of the font has a warm and friendly feel and this has been accentuated a little by slightly skewing the font. An oval lozenge device has been placed behind the text to unify the writing and make it more of a stand alone logo. The text was also replicated in black behind the main text and this was offset to give the impression of a drop shadow and so visually push the text forward.

Color Scheme

Bold colors are the order of the day here, with a bright red chosen for the main text color which will stand out. Red&apos;s complementary color, green, is used in two shades to add a double border to the background lozenge. The lozenge has circular gradient of a two shades of yellow. This produces a backdrop that is less harsh than plain white, but is a little more subtle than a solid shade.
 
More on this topic
 
 What are the Basics of Graphic Design? Designing a Brand for a Contemporary Outlet Branding a Private Restaurant 
 
The colors of the logo are echoed in the design of the menu cover. It&apos;s not a sophisticated solution, but then again nor is a hamburger.

Picture

This image of a burger in a bap (courtesy of Robbie Owen-Wahl ) quite quickly and easily sums up what Newbys is all about–good quality fast food. Like the logo, the picture is bold and straightforward and gets the message across quickly.

Layout

With no pretence of sophistication, almost all of the available space on the menu cover is used in order to produce an &apos;in your face&apos; design that grabs the viewer&apos;s attention.

Conclusion

This example demonstrates one approach to producing a logo and menu cover for a fast food outlet and shows how different elements can be combined to produce a visually punchy image that will grab the attention of the audience.

Obviously this is just one solution and it may not be to everyone&apos;s taste, but it covers some important points and should make a Graphic Designer start to think through the process of designing within this market segment.

There are more solutions to fictional Newbys briefs linked to from Suite101&apos;s article on the Essentials of Graphic Design .
 Copyright Ian Pullen . Contact the author to obtain permission for republication. 
 Ian Pullen - Ian Pullen is a Graphic Designer with some 15 years of experience in the industry. His first foot on the ladder, after completing 2 years ... 
 Print Article Tweet Advertisement Advertisement 
More on this topic
 
 Branding Points for an Upmarket Outlet Branding a Whole Food Restaurant How to Increase Restaurant Covers: Tips for Turning Tables Quick 
 more in graphic design theory » 
Related Topics
 
 Fonts/Typography Graphic Design Software Graphic Design Tutorials 
 Advertisement Latest Articles • About Us • Terms&amp;Conditions • Privacy Policy • suite101.de • suite101.fr • suite101.net • Suite101 Blog Graphic Design @ 
 Write for Suite101 Sign In 
 
 Tutorials Graphic Design Software Designing Books/Publications Typography More 

 Theory 
 
 Home Writing&amp;Publishing Graphic Design Graphic Design Theory
	</body>
</document>
