<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006582" url="http://www.mahalo.com/wendys-coupons/" time="2012-07-12-23:30" support="43" score="0.17097777198618933" bingtitle="Wendy&apos;s Coupons - Mahalo.com" webtitle="Wendys Coupons">
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000465" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000682" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000900" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>Are you interested in saving money on your next trip to a Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant? ... These coupons can be used by presenting them at restaurants to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		login | register 
 
 Home How To Courses Answers 
 Search 
Wendy&apos;s Coupons
 Tweet 
Are you interested in saving money on your next trip to a Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant? Wendy&apos;s coupons, deals and specials listed on this page will help you eat your favorite sandwiches, salads, French fries and more, in some of Wendy&apos;s many locations, while at the same time saving money.

According to Zagat&apos;s 2009 Fast Food Survey, Wendy&apos;s is one of the most popular fast food restaurant chains around. In addition to serving up the usual hamburgers and fries one would expect to find at a fast food joint, Wendy&apos;s also offers hot stuffed baked potatoes with toppings such as broccoli and cheese. Also included on the menu are tortilla wraps, four types of salads, chili, and mandarin orange slices. Continue reading for more information and links on coupons and deals for all types of food at Wendy&apos;s.
 
Where to Get Wendy&apos;s Coupons
 
Printable coupons for Wendy&apos;s are common on the Internet, and may be obtained on websites such as Retail Me Not and Deal Locker. These coupons can be used by presenting them at restaurants to receive discounts. Wendy&apos;s coupons are also frequently distributed in newspaper circulars and direct mail marketing campaigns. The Entertainment 2010 book features several Wendy&apos;s coupons.

If you would like to learn about special promotions and savings opportunities at Wendy&apos;s as soon as they become available, you can sign up for Wendy Mail to receive email news and the latest offers. To sign up, visit the official restaurant website, Wendys.com and scroll down to the bottom of the page, where you will see the words Sign Up for Wendy Mail on the lower right corner.
 
How to Get Wendy&apos;s Coupons
 Save Cancel URL | Web Search YouTube 5min Vimeo Flowplayer Ustream 
 YouTube 5min Search 
 
Select a video
 Wendy&apos;s Coupons
	</body>
</document>
