<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006187" url="http://renovatedrachel.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-12-22:52" support="1" score="0.0025685138759601748" bingtitle="Renovated Rachel | Building a better me!" webtitle="Renovated Rachel | Building a better me!">
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>I cannot tell you how to lose weight…I can ... I then snuck the “meat” into my food intake ... to being a food addict than sitting at a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Renovated Rachel 
 Building a better me! Skip to content 
 Home About Me 
 ← Older posts 
 The best way to lose weight is to stop listening to people…now listen to this! 
 Posted on December 16, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
I cannot tell you how to lose weight…I can barely figure this out myself.  I can however tell you what hell I have gone through listening to the“brilliant”advice from other people.

When I was in college I dated a guy who was 50% health nut and 50% lunatic.  He insisted we become vegetarians and thus began my hell.

He filled my head full of crap about the order in which to eat food and portrayed himself as some sort of unofficial nutrionist.  My daily food intake consisted of tufu, lentils, vegetables, fruit, soy beverage, natural cereal, and bread.  I lived like this for over a year and believe me I followed recipes and tried everything to make that tofu taste good.  It didn’t work.

I noticed little things changing in my body.  Okay, maybe not so little.  My skin became dry, my hair started falling out, I was always tired to the point of falling asleep at work and I began gaining weight.  Then I got bit by a spider…a spider that saved my life so to speak.  It bit me on the knee and caused my whole knee to swell and get infected.  My doctor ran blood work and was actually shocked at the results.“I’m not sure how you are even standing”she said as she pointed out that my body was malnourished to the point of starvation.  My body was low in every mineral and vitamin it needed to be healthy.  She asked what I ate on a daily basis and then she gave me this look that I will never forget.  It was the look of pity that I was such a stupid girl to let some uneducated and controlling boyfriend tell me how to feed my body.   She insisted I eat a hamburger immediately or she was going to hospitalize me.  I ate the hamburger, which still remains the best burger I ever ate.  I then snuck the“meat”into my food intake for a month or so until we eventually we broke up for other reasons.

So what’s the point of this sad and pathetic story?  Well I recently bagan a trial of the“raw food diet”…the crazy movement that is sweeping the nation.  I say crazy because again…it is not for everyone.  As I was eating my avacado and coconut salad, I started wondering as I was trying not to throw up…how I got to this place again?  This diet was actually recommeded by a doctor but still…is this for me?  I ate that way for a whole week…no easy task I assure you, before deciding that this was not for me.  And terrified of more damage I would cause my body I decided to focus on what my body tells me rather then what another person thinks my body is saying.

I’m sure there are lots of vegetarians who are living happy, healthy lives but I am not one of them.  My boyfriend’s body seemed to thrive on the vegetarian food while my body was clearly being starved.  Perhaps under proper nutrionist care I may have learned how to get more efficient food intake as a vegetarian but I was already eating a lot of food…it just wasn’t what my body needed.  Perhaps it has to do with enthnic backgrounds, genetics, etc…I am not a doctor and don’t pretend to be one.  What I do know is we all must find our own way, we cannot always take the advice of others.

So as for me.  I walked into the grocery store last week and stared at the beef, confused about what to pick.  I’ve never really been a red meet person but my scientific mind is looking at this like an experiment.  The t-bone steaks were on sale so that seemed as good a choice as any other.  I cooked the steak in olive oil and a bit of butter, with onions and mushrooms and was full after just half of it.  I continue to eat my veggies and fruit and yogurt throughout the day and every night I eat some sort of meat.  It’s been one week and I have lost 5lbs.

And so…my experiment continues:)
 Posted in Diet | Tagged boyfriend , doctor , meat , raw food , vegetarian | Leave a comment 
 Weighting 
 Posted on August 2, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
 It’s been awhile I know.  I have been struggling to lose any weight and frankly that has me feeling blue.

Although weight loss is not my only goal for this self-renovation, I have to admit that I am focussed on it.  For me it seems I am stuck in limbo waiting for my weight to drop before I can begin any other goals.

I haven’t weighed myself in a while as my desire to know my current weight every minute of the day was perhaps bordering on neurosis.

I like good food.  Quality food is more important than convenience and although I was never one to refuse a tasty chocolate bar, it certainly doesn’t give me the same joyous feeling as a slowly prepared and tasteful meal.  Without a doubt I am addicted to food.  The question is how do I change this?  I feel as though I am wandering through some foreign city where I don’t understand anything.  I am lost.

I have my journal which I enter into daily.  I record my food intake as well as my exercise. My exercise is moderate–stairs, walking, situps etc. but this is all stuff I never did before so I would think that I would lose some weight.  I can see how easy it is for people to give up on dieting.  If eating soups and salads and water and smoothies has me weighing the same as cheeseburgers and steaks and coke and chocolate…then really what is the point?  There has to be a benefit to this or I may as well eat the “bad” food.  I don’t feel any healthier and I certainly don’t feel like I am ready to take on the world.  I feel hungry and like a failure.
 Posted in Diet | Tagged Bad Food , Diet , Eating , Exercise , Quality Food , Self-renoovation , Weight | Leave a comment 
 Eating Fat and Losing Weight! 
 Posted on March 16, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
 I’m starting to think there is a diet conspiracy among the masses.  Including, but not limited to…doctors, media, companies, and anyone connected to the health or the weight loss industry.  I have spent most of my adult live thus far decreasing the fat in my diet which ironically has ended up making me fat.

Tired and miserable from not losing any weight, I reduced my sugar intake and had a minimal weight loss of 3lbs and then nothing, despite the fact that I was dragging my haggard body onto my treadmill to exercise daily.  The only thing I managed to accomplish was constipation…which in order to cure my doctor insisted I eat more bran.  I already eat 100% bran cereal daily, eat a good amount of fruits and vegetables and almost no processed food.  But what do I know?  Increasing bran in my diet just made things worse.  I’m sure he assumes that since I’m overweight I probably eat cookies all day but I don’t.  I think I was actually eating far too much bran and my increase in water did nothing to help.  Then I found fat!

I did a lot of research and realized that I was missing a big part of a healthy body–fat!  If every cell in our body is made up of essential fatty acids but our body can’t produce these, then avoiding these foods that contain fatty acids is like starving our body of what it needs.  I’m learning as I go but it would seem that doctors and the media do not tell anyone about this…it’s always“lower fat”and“eat more oatmeal”.  Eating grain, fruits and vegetables are not enough, you need fat to be healthy.  I am not a doctor and know very little about food, health, etc.., but I do know what is not working.  Foods like walnuts, salmon, olive oil and eggs seem to be important staples in a healthy diet so that is what I am going to try.

Eat more good fat, eat less bad sugar and we shall see how things go!  So far I feel better and have lost another 2 lbs!
 Posted in Body , Diet | Tagged Constipation , Diet , Essential Fatty Acids , Fat , Food , Sugar | Leave a comment 
 I have to drink that much water really? 
 Posted on March 10, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
 I hate water and yet it is vital to survival so I drink it.  I chug it quickly hoping that my tastebuds don’t get too much on them.  It should be the purest thing I drink and yet I despise it.  Maybe it’s the flouride, maybe it’s some mineral in there somewhere…but something turns my stomach when I drink water.  This brings me to my latest problem…making sure I am drinking enough water.

The research I did on this topic seems to be all over the place so I had to use my own calculations.  Considering that I eat a lot of high water content foods, but balance that with my high intake of bran as well as adding in that I am exercising more now I have concluded that I should be drinking about 2 litres of water per day.  (I could be totally off here).  On my first day I wasn’t even able to get 1 litre down.  I always thought I drank a lot of water because I seemed to always be drinking a glass here and a glass there.  Turns out there is no way I was drinking this much.  It will be interesting to see in a couple of weeks whether this makes any difference.  There are all sorts of theories on losing weight so now I can see if this one is accurate!

Still only 3 lbs down…sigh.
 Posted in Body , Diet | Tagged Water | Leave a comment 
 Food Addict 
 Posted on March 7, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
 There is more to being a food addict than sitting at a fast food restaurant all day eating.  Food addiction is the continual thought of food.  Whether a person overeats or starves themselves they are always thinking about food…just whether to eat it or avoid it.  And like other addicts I wonder if I will always have this monkey on my back?  Some people find God to help them with their addictions and others find love.  I doubt I will find either of these things which just leaves me!  Food consumes my mind and distractions like work, friends, family and hobbies don’t compare to the joy I get thinking about food.  It is all-consuming but I will have to press on and take it one day at a time.

A few weeks in and I have finally managed to lose 3 lbs.  A small accomplishment but I am thrilled to finally see the scale going down.  Seems kicking the coca-cola habit has made the improvement.  I can’t say I don’t still miss it but each day I miss it less and less.  If anyone has any ideas of what a person is suppsoed to drink I would love to know!  I can’t drink those powdered sugar free drinks, I don’t like coffee or tea and I only drink fruit juices in small portions because of the sugar.  This leaves water…how delicious:(
 Posted in Body , Diet | Tagged Food Addict , Sugar , Water | Leave a comment 
 My Multi Vitamin and Me 
 Posted on March 6, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
 My first day of taking a multi vitamin so we shall see if this helps with my overall feeling of tiredness.  It’s difficult exercising when I feel exhausted but I am moving ahead doing my best.  Aside from sugar I have always been a healthy eater so I am concentrating on portion control.  This morning I had my usual bran flakes but replaced the sugar with honey.  For lunch I had a cucumber salad and for dinner I had a couple peices of pizza.  Not a great choice I know but…baby steps!  I am feeling pretty good without the coke..sigh…but I miss it though.

 
 Posted in Body , Diet | Tagged Portion Control , Sugar , Tiredness , Vitamin | Leave a comment 
 Saying So Long to Soda! 
 Posted on March 5, 2011 by renovatedrachel 
 It is time unfortunately to say so long to soda…in particular coke!  After a few weeks of eating well and exercising I haven’t lost any weight so I am giving up my last sugar fix to see if it makes a difference.

My buddy, my pal, my nemesis!  You are too tasty yet forbidden to me now.  It’s not you…it’s me.  I know that sounds like a line but it’s true.  I want you and yet I must resist you or I will never lose this weight.  You are like no other and leaving you is not simple.  Perhaps one day, down the road when I am in control I will find you again and we can reminisce although our relationship will never truly be the same.  You are one of a kind!

I hope this works!  Frustrated and wondering what’s up with no weight loss!??  But I will keep moving forward on my“sugar free as much as possible”diet!
 Posted in Body , Diet | Tagged Diet , Soda , Sugar Free , Weight | 1 Comment ← Older posts 
 Search for: 
Blog Stats

 294 hits 
 
Recent Posts

 The best way to lose weight is to stop listening to people…now listen to this! Weighting Eating Fat and Losing Weight! I have to drink that much water really? Food Addict 
 
Tags
 Bad Food boyfriend Constipation Diet doctor Eating Essential Fatty Acids Exercise Exercising Fat Food Food Addict Friends meat Portion Control Quality Food raw food Renovating Rachel Self-renoovation Soda Start of a beautiful friendship Sugar Sugar Free Tiredness Treadmill vegetarian Vitamin Water Weight 
Archives

 December 2011 August 2011 March 2011 
 
Categories

 Body Diet Uncategorized 
 
Meta

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.com 
 
 Renovated Rachel Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Twenty Ten . Renovated Rachel Theme: Twenty Ten Blog at WordPress.com . Follow 
 Follow“Renovated Rachel” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel
	</body>
</document>
