<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006124" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/article/358249/zaxbys_a_great_place_to_grab_a_quick.html" time="2012-07-12-22:48" support="2" score="0.0031637880937998254" bingtitle="Zaxby&apos;s - A Great Place to Grab a Quick Meal - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="Zaxby&apos;s - A Great Place to Grab a Quick Meal - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="131"/>
	<description>Zaxby&apos;s is your typical fast food restaurant chain ... or is it? ... You walk to the counter and place your order, and are given ... No matter what you select, it is all good! I am ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
Zaxby&apos;s - A Great Place to Grab a Quick Meal
 quietgirll , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Oct 8, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Zaxby&apos;s 
 Flag Close Zaxby&apos;s is your typical fast food restaurant chain ... or is it? Zaxby&apos;s is a franchised restaurant originally started by two childhood pals in Statesboro, Georgia. Zach McLeroy and Tony Townley. Zaxby&apos;s offers you great choices- as long as you want chicken! But this the best chicken you will find. Chicken wings, chicken fingers, chicken salads, chicken sandwiches, and all with some of the best sides you can imagine. Of course you have your crinkle cut french fries, but you also have your tater chips (deep fried potatoes), onion peels, and Texas toast.
Zaxby&apos;s has great prices, and a great atmosphere. You notice immediately the place has a great decor. Typically, they are filled with local and vintage items so you feel at home from the moment you walk inside. You walk to the counter and place your order, and are given a number. Then you are welcome to fix your drink, seat yourself, and relax while you wait for your food to be cooked fresh. Once your order is ready, they will call your number and you pick it up from the counter. Then you just get to enjoy the food. And you will definitely enjoy the food.

Let me talk about the food for a bit. No matter what you select, it is all good! I am partial myself to the buffalo fingers. They are tender, hot, and saucy. They have quite a selection of sauces for your wings and your strips, so you can have a different experience every time you go! I have tried the salads (or as they call them here, Zalads), and they are good IF you like salads. They have a Blue salad, which is buffalo fingers with bleu cheese crumbles, that is VERY good! If you like wings, and strips, I would definitely recommend the wings and things on the menu. It comes with wings, strips, fries, and Texas toast. It is absolutely fabulous, and allows you to get a little bit of everything!

Zaxby&apos;s is one of my favorite places to go to grab a quick meal. They have a drive-thru, so you can even pick something up on the way home from work. If you don&apos;t want to have to wait for the order once you get there (especially if it is a larger order), you can also call the order in ahead of time. I must say, I wish they would let you pick up call-in orders from the drive-thru!

The prices at Zaxby&apos;s are also great! I like to actually order enough sometimes so that I can have my original meal, and then have enough left to warm up as a second meal. It is actually amazing how well Zaxby&apos;s warms up! Their tater chips are just as crisp after you microwave them as they were originally!!
All in all, Zaxby&apos;s is a great place for a family meal. It is clean, economical, tasty, and quick, Definitely one of my favorite places to go, and I will keep going back again and again!
 
Published by quietgirll 

I am currently working and living with my gf...loving disney and everything about it!  View profile 
 
 Ebay - How to Place a Bid&amp;Tips on Winning the Bid You Want Tips that will help someone new to Ebay place and win their first bid. Slim Fast Meal Bars Review Before buying Slim Fast Meal Bars, as a quick breakfast or lunch, read this review. Barilla Tortellini: Three Cheese Meal Review With Barilla Tortellini you can enjoy a nutritious and healthy pasta meal in only 10 minutes! Romantic Restaurants in Atlanta, Georgia Romantic restaurants cover the city of Atlanta, Georgia. To really make your romantic evening special try one of these great romantic date restaurants, three locations where ambience, food, and music all come together... Romantic Date Restaurants in Miami, Florida Dining in a restaurant is a chance to see and be seen in this paradise. Choosing a romantic restaurant that will blow your date a away is easy. Try any of these great Miami restaurants and your date will have a wonde... 

 One Pan Meal: Sausage and Chicke... How to Properly Place Dishes, Cu... Quick Camera Cozy 
 
 Eat at Your Own Risk Chicken Mozzarella Water Chestnut Dish - Quick, Easy, Taste T... AQ Chicken House: Arkansas Quality Since 1947 Hungry for Pizza? Great Pizza Restaurants in Cortland, New York Is Mudpiles the Ultimate Quick Medical Reference Guide? a Review Gems in a Sea of Taste - Best Mexican Restaurants in Los Angeles Writers&apos; Guide to Finding YOUR Best Place to Submit Great Place for a First Date in Detroit MI, Restaurant CaféCortina 
 
 
 
 Takeaways 
 
 Zaxby&apos;s has great chicken A great family restaurant 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Health and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
