<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006843" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/51087327/STORE-ENVIRONMENT" time="2012-07-12-23:49" support="1" score="0.0007660821850440936" bingtitle="STORE ENVIRONMENT - Scribd" webtitle="STORE ENVIRONMENT">
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="71"/>
	<description>... more they tended to shop at department stores. However, the number ... in a competitive retail environment: a fast food restaurant ... You must be logged in to leave a comment.</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Inﬂuence of retail store environmental cues on consumer patronage behavior across different retail store formats: An empirical analysis of US Hispanic consumers Yoo-Kyoung Seock Department of Textiles, Merchandising and Interiors, The University of Georgia, Athens, GA 30602, USA a r t i c l e i n f o Keywords: Hispanics Retail store formats Store environmental cues Patronage behavior a b s t r a c t This study examined the inﬂuence of Hispanic consumers’ perceived importance of apparel retail store environmental cues and demographic characteristics (i.e., age and the number of years lived in the US) on their apparel store patronage behavio r acro ss vario us retail stor e format s. Three appare l retai l store environmental cue dimensions were identiﬁed. Of the three dimensions, Customer Service appeared as a signiﬁ cant determ inant in Hispa nic consum ers’ decis ion to shop at depar tment stores , specialty store s, and mass merchant stores. Convenience was signiﬁcantly, but negatively, related to the use of specialty stores. Physical Atmosphere appeared as signiﬁcant determinants of Hispanic consumers’ use of Internet websites. The respo nden ts’ shopp ing frequ ency at depar tment stores, Internet websites, and catalo gues was signiﬁcantly different based on the respondents’ age and number of years lived in the US This study offers insights for apparel retailers in building effective retail store environments to attract Hispanic consumers. &amp; 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. 1 . Intro ducti on The US population has experienced remarkable growth over the past half-ce ntury and is becoming more racial ly and ethnically dive rse with faster popu latio n gro wth amon g minor ities than Cau cas ian s ( Shre stha, 2006 ). Th e US Ce ns us Bu re au (2 007 ) repo rted that the natio n’s mino rity pop ulatio n reach ed 100. 7 million in 2006, increased from 98 million in 2005, and Hispanics accou nted for almo st half of the natio n’s minor ity pop ulatio n growth between 2005 and 2006. A more recent report by the US Census Bureau (2008) showed that the US Hispanic population reached 45.5 million on July 1, 2007, which accounts for 15.1% of the est ima ted to tal US pop ula tio n of 30 1 .6 mil lio n. The Pew Hispanic Center report for US population projections revealed that Hispanics will make up 29% of the US population in 2050, making them the nation’s largest and fastest-growing minority population group in the US ( Pew Hispanic Center, 2006 ). Moreover , according to a repo rt rele ased by Hisp anic Tellige nce s , along with such subst antia l pop ulati on incre ases, Hisp anic purch asing pow er surged to nearly $700 billion in 2004, accounting for 8.5% of total US purchasing power that year, and is projected to reach as much as $1 trillion by 2010 ( Broide, 2004 ). Although the median income of Hispanic households is much less than that of non-Hispanic white households ( US Census Bureau, 2007 ), Hispanic households spend a greater percentage of their disposable income on goods and services than do non-Hispanics ( HispanicTrend s.com, March/ Ap ril , 2005 ). Mor e spe ciﬁ cal ly , His pan ic hou seh old s spe nt a greater portion of their income in 2004 on groceries, footwear, men’s and children’s apparel, gasoline and motor oil, and house- hol d te xti les tha n oth er goo ds ( HispanicTr ends.com, January/ February, 2005 ). As the population and purchasing power of this group grows, und ers tan din g His pan ic con sum ers and app eal ing to the m beco mes an incre asing ly impo rtan t oppo rtuni ty for retai lers to cap ita liz e on the pr oje cte d hun dr ed s of bil lio ns of do lla rs of annual sales potential. However , despite the mounting evidence of Hisp anics’ growi ng impa ct and inﬂuence on the retail mar ket, research has lagged behind in this area, and little has been done to investigate this group and their shopping behaviors. Furthermore, US Hispanics were found to exhibit strong ethnic identiﬁcation and att itu din al dif fer enc es tha n oth er eth nic gro up s in the ir shopping behaviors ( Deshpande et a l., 198 6 ; Suro, 2006 ). Retailers sho uld not ass ume tha t mar ket ing pr odu cts to the His pan ic population is no different than marketing to a general population ( Valdez, 2000 ). Marketers should know the preferences of this consumer group compared to other ethnic groups and develop a diffe rent iate d mar ketin g plan. In orde r to shed light on those pre feren ces, the pres ent study focuses on Hisp anic consu mers’ shopping behaviors. Over the past decades , the reta il busine ss envir onme nt has faced aggressive competition with rapid market entry of innova- tiv e sto re con cep ts and for mat s ( Maro nick and Stif f, 1985 ). A company’s success in ﬁnancial performance and market shares AR TIC LE IN PR ESS Contents lists available at ScienceDirect journal homepage: www.elsevier.com/locate/jretconser Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services 0969-6989 /$ - see front matter &amp; 2009 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved. doi: 10.1016/j.jretconser.2009.03.001 E-mail address: yseock@fcs.uga.edu Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services 16 (2009) 329–339   largely depended on the satisﬁed customers who are willing to purchase products or services repeatedly ( Siu and Cheung, 2001 ; Raphe l, 1 999 ; Reichheld and Sasser, 1990 ; Srinivasan et al., 2002 ). In this vein, under stand ing consumers ’ stor e choice s and their patronage beha vior have been ident iﬁed as keys to the success of a particular retail business and have become a premier objective for marketers ( Osman, 1993 ). Therefore, increasing consumers’ loy- alty to the store has been a managerial challenge to marketers, and gaining in-depth understanding and empirical estimation of con sum er loy alt y beh av ior has bee n an imp or tan t iss ue to researchers. In the face of the recent demographic movement of growing minority populations in the US, retailers are recognizing tha t va rio us eth nic gro up s ha ve dif fer en t sto re cho ice and patr onag e beha viors ( Cott on Incor por ated ’s Lifes tyle Monit or , 2005a ). According to the report released by Cotton Incorporated’s Lif est yle Mon ito r , alm ost 25% of His pan ics ten d to sho p at specialty stores and about 22% at chain stores, while Caucasians and African-Americans shop primarily at mass merchants (29% and 27 %) and Asi ans at spe cia lty sto re s (3 3%) . Thu s, re tai ler s should abandon the one-l ook -ﬁts- all stra tegy and try to diffe r- entiate stores that appea l to their target demogr aphic group. More importantly, researchers found that Hispanic consumers tend to patronize the store more frequently once they develop a positive perception of it ( Saegert et al., 1985 ). Much research showed that certain attributes of retail store env ir onm ent inﬂ uen ce sto re cho ice and pat ro nag e beh avi or ( Baker et al., 2002 ; Darden et al., 1983 ; Darley and Lim, 1993 ; Hu and Japer, 2006 ; Pan and Zinkhan, 2006 ; Roy and Tai, 2003 ; Sherman et al., 1997 ; Sirgy et al., 2000 ; Spansenberg et al., 1996 ; Thang and Tan, 2003 ; Thom pson and Chen, 199 8 ; Ward et al., 1992 ). Mor eo ve r, a gro win g bod y of aca dem ic re sea rch als o supports the importance of store environment as a marketing tool to affect shoppers’ approach behaviors ( Fiore et al., 2000 ) as well as a dominant market differentiator ( Reardon et al., 1995 ; Roy and Tai, 2003 ). Thus, effectively managing the retail store environment encountered by customers has been identiﬁed as a viable retail management tactic ( Babin and Darden, 1995 ; Gilboa and Fafaeli, 2003 ) and has gained a growing amount of attention from both industry and academia ( Smith and Burns, 1996 ). Schlosser (1998) noted that, in the face of increased market competition, retailers’ sole reliance on promotional techniques is inadequate; retailers’ efforts must turn from offering just price promotions to creating a pleasant shopping experience. Researchers also asserted that store environments can inﬂuence consumers’ willingness to purchase or entice them to stay in the store for a longer period of time ( McDougall and Fry, 19 7 4–75 ; Mano, 19 99 ). In a survey conducted by Drug Store News , a majority of respondents, almost nine out of ten, revealed that a pleasant store atmosphere was either very or somewhat important when they chose a store in which to shop ( P arks, 1998 ). According to Chain Store Age , retailers reported a posit ive conne ction between improvi ng the retai l stor e atmo - sph er e and inc rea sin g sal es ( ‘‘St ore atmo spher ics,’ ’ 2005 ). As con sum ers oft en inf er ret ail sto re ima ges fro m suc h env ir on- mental cues ( Bloemer and Ruyter, 1998 ), the store environment may rep res ent the mo st imp er ati ve cha nne l thr ou gh whi ch retailers can communicate with their consumers. In fact, retailers have been spending millions of dollars every year for the design, construction, and refurbishing of their stores in order to keep their stores up-to-date and project an image that appeals to their target markets ( Roy and Tai, 2003 ). T o off er an att ra cti ve ret ail sto re env iro nme nt – tha t is, to effectively manage the relationship between the customer and the retail store environment – retailers should know what their target consumers consider important when they chose a store in which to shop, and then design their stores to appeal to those targeted markets, thereby drawing customers into stores and developing cust omer loya lty . Thus, the purpose of the present study is to examine the inﬂuence of Hispanic consumers’ perceived impor- tan ce of re tai l sto re env ir onm ent al cue s on sto re pat ro nag e beha vior across various retail stor e form ats. The study focuses on app ar el ret ail sto re s bec aus e His pan ic con sum ers spe nd a si gn iﬁ ca nt sh ar e of th ei r in co me on cl ot hi ng it em s su ch as foo tw ear and men ’s and chi ldr en’ s app ar el. Acc ord ing to HispanicTr ends.com (January/February , 2005) , His pan ic hou se- holds spent, on average, $2097 for purchasing apparel items in 2004, which accounts for 6% of their annual expenditure based on an annual income of $35k. This statistic is consistent with DRI McGraw-Hill’s projection in that Hispanics are expected to drive sig niﬁ can t gro wth in app ar el and sho e pur cha ses ( Euro RSCG Magnet, 2002 ). Hispanic consumers’ substantial expenditure on appa rel items may transfo rm the existing apparel market and redeﬁne its future. However, the apparel industry is one of the bu si ne ss se ct or s th at in ve st th e le as t am ou nt of mo ne y to His pan ics, acc ord ing to Ass oci ati on of His pan ic Ad ver tis ing Age ncies (2004) . This study inve stiga ting Hisp anic consu mers ’ patronage behaviors will provide practical information for apparel ret ailer s to penet rate this lucra tive consumer market and earn loyal customers. 2. Liter atur e revi ew 2.1 . Hispanic-America n consumers Dis tin cti ven ess the or y pos its tha t a per son ’s eth nic ity is a distinctive and salient trait that differentiates behavior ( Lee et al., 2002 ; Steenkamp et al., 1999 ; Torres and Briggs, 2005 ; Usunier, 2000 ). Bec aus e the memb ers of an eth nic gro up ha ve sha re d norms and beliefs, they conserve the common characteristics of the national culture from which they originate ( Steenkamp et al., 1999 ; Usunier, 2000 ) and each ethnic group constitutes a unique com mun ity wit h the ir ow n cul tur al va lue s ( Le e et al ., 200 2 ). Existing evidence from research lends support to the notion that eth nic ity is an imp ort ant tra it in dif fer ent iat ing con sum er beha vior , espec iall y regar ding appa rel shop ping. Rese arch ers suggested that Hispanics in the United States show strong ethnic identiﬁcation, which results in attitudinal and behavioral differ- enc es fr om ot her eth nic gro ups in the ir sho pp ing beh av ior s ( De shp and e et al. , 1 986 ; Sur o, 2006 ). Ac co rd in g to a re po rt rele ased by Cott on Incor pora ted’ s Lifes tyle Monit or (2005c) , Hispa nic wome n were more part icula r about their appe aranc e than women of other ethnicities. Well over half (57%) of Hispanic fem ale s, acc ord ing to the sam e re por t, op te d for sty le ov er comfort, choosing clothing that looked attractive on them rather than clothing that was comfortable. Only 45% of Caucasians and 46% of African-Americans held the same attitude. Furthermore, whi le onl y 50% of Cau cas ian s and 56% of Afr ica n-A mer ica ns bother to seek help while shopping for clothes, 60% of Hispanic fem ale res po nde nts ten ded to see k som e fri end ly adv ice or a sec ond opi nio n whe n sho pp ing for app are l. His pan ic fem ale consum ers spend signiﬁca ntly more time shopping than their Caucasian and African-American counterparts ( Cotton Incorpor - ated ’s Lifes tyle Monit or , 2005b ). Th ey sp en d an av er ag e of 13 5. 1 min in stor es shop ping for appa rel, while Caucasian and African-American female respondents recorded an average of 89.4 and 109.27 min, respectively . Statistics from the Cotton Incorpor - ated’s Lifestyle Monitor (2005a) also show further evidence that ther e are pur chasin g beha vior differe nces amon g consum ers of different ethnicities. In all, 62% of Asians report that they enjoy wearing denim, followed by Hispanics (56%), Caucasians (54%), and African-Americans (45%). In all, 24.6% of Hispanics tend to buy denim jeans primarily at specialty stores and 21.6% at chain AR TIC LE IN PR ESS Y.-K. Seock / Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services 16 (2009) 329–339 330   stor es, while Cauca sians and Afri can-A meri cans shop prim arily at ma ss me rc ha nt s (2 9% an d 26 .9 %, re sp ec ti ve ly ) ( Cotton Incorporated’s Lifestyle Monitor, 2005a ). Re cog niz ing the pur cha sin g po wer of thi s mar ket , man y retailers have been tapping into this consumer group for years. Sears has advertised in the Hispanic community with customized Span ish-la nguag e adver tisem ents ( Sea rs Pre ss Re lea se, 2005 ). Mor eo ver , in 2005 , Sea rs lau nch ed Lat ina Lif e, a new line of app ar el, foo tw ear , and han dba gs inﬂ uen ced by the sty le of His pan ic wo men , and off er ed the mer cha ndi se in 425 sto re s across the country, offering bilingual store associates and Spanish- lan gua ge sig nag e to ass ist His pa nic cus tom ers ( Sea rs Pre ss Release, 2005 ). Kmart and Kohl’s collaborated on clothing lines wit h Lat ina sup ers tar s suc h as Tha lia Sod i and Dai sy Fue nt es ( Duprey , 20 04 ). In addition, fashion powerhouses such as Carolina Herrera, Oscar de la Renta, Narcisco Rodriguez and Louis Verdad have been taking Hispanic fashions from the street to the runway, ﬁlling the pages of Vogue , W and Elle more than ever before with Hispanic inspired styles ( Cotton Incorporated’s Lifestyle Monitor, 2005b ). Therefore, Hispanic consumers’ distinctive apparel shop- pin g beh av ior s, alo ng wit h a hug e mar ket po ten tia l, de ser ve att en tio n fro m app are l ret ail ers who pla n on re ach ing thi s lucrative and ever-expanding market. Rese arche rs also not ed that demo grap hic and socio -psy cho- graphic background such as age, gender, country of origin, social class and income status are critical to the success of interethnic communications with the Hispanic population ( Suro, 2006 ; Valdez, 2000 ). Mea nw hil e, pr evi ous re sea rch in mar ket ing and soc ial sciences suggests that Hispanic consumers’ degree of assimilation in American society is an important determinant that differentiates their behaviors, indicating that the country of origin is not a key variable in discerning individual differences within this population ( Deshpande et al., 1986 ; Donthu and Cherian, 1994 ; Sabogal et al., 1987 ; Segal and Sosa, 19 83 ; Webster , 1992 ). In addition, Korgaonkar et al. (2000) found that assimilation level is a signiﬁcant factor that diffe renti ates Hispa nic consum ers’ belie fs and attit ude tow ard dire ct mark eting advert ising. One of the factors that inﬂue nces assimilation level might be the number of years lived in the US Acco rdin g to Sur o (200 6) , app ro xim ate ly 70% of the His pan ic po pul ati on con sist s of imm igr ant s and the ir chi ldr en and the numbers of years they lived in the United States vary greatly. Such variation may result in a range of existing perceptual and behavioral tend encie s amon g this group beca use some may prese rve prior learn ing and pre -exi sting attitude s from their own culture mor e than do others. Others may neglect the distinct cultural traits and adopt the new cultural traits and values. In 2008, Seock and Sauls fou nd tha t ag e is an imp ort ant det erm ina nt tha t dif fe ren tia tes Hispa nic consum ers’ shopp ing tend encie s and stor e eval uatio n criteria. Se oc k an d Ba il ey (2 009 ) al so fo un d th at Hi sp an ic consu mers’ use of perso nal and imper sonal informati on sour ces for apparel shopping varied by age. Thus, this study investigates the inﬂ uen ce of such dem ogr aph ic cha ra cte ris tic s as age and the number of years lived in the US. 2.2. Reta il store envi ronme ntal cues Underestimating the importance of the shopping experiences wit hin a ret ail sto re , ret ail er s in the pas t pr efe rre d to ent ice con sum ers int o the ir sto re s by ann oun cin g sal es inc ent ive s ( Kotler, 1973–1 974 ; Saffer, 1996 ). How ever , reta ilers have come to realize the importance of environmental cues and have tried to develop effective retail store atmospherics in order to attract their targ et custo mers and incre ase their proﬁta bilit y ( Sir gy et al. , 20 00 ). Tur ley and Mil lim an (2000 ) asser ted that mark eting researchers have come to realize that the physical store environ- ment experienced at the point of purchase inﬂuences consumers’ sho pp ing beh av ior and , the ref or e, the pra cti ce of cre ati ng inﬂ uen tia l atm osp her es sho uld be an imp or tan t mar ket ing strategy for most exchange environments. Since 197 4 when Kotle r sugg est ed the term atmospherics to refer to the ‘‘intentional control and structuring of environmental cues,’’ marketin g researchers and practitioners in the retailing area hav e paid consi der able att entio n to reta il sto re atmo sphe rics . Lindquist (1974) identiﬁed nine categories of store environmental att ribu tes that cont ribu te to consu mer atti tude tow ard ret ail stores: merchandise, service, clientele, physica l facilities, conve- nien ce, pro mot ion, stor e atm osph ere , inst itut iona l fact ors , and post-transaction satisfaction. Of all these factors, Linquist claimed that the merchandise, service, and locational convenience aspects we re the mos t do min ant en vir onm en tal cue s in for mul ati ng consumers’ attitudes toward retail stores. Mark (1976) concluded th at the ke y fac to rs of st or e att rib ut es we re fas hio nab ili ty , advertisi ng, convenienc e, outside attractiveness, salesmanship, and servi ce. Mazu rsky and Jaco by (1 986 ) disco ver ed that the mer chand ise- rela ted aspe cts (qu alit y, pri ce, and assor tmen t), serv ice- rel ate d aspe cts (qu alit y in gene ral and sale speo ple serv ice), and pleasa ntne ss of shoppin g at the stor e are among the mos t critical components of store image attributes. They also concluded that reta il sto re image has bot h cor e face ts, such as price and mer cha nd ise , and mor e per iph er al fac ets , suc h as po lic y an d service. Bloe mer and Ruyt er (1 998, p. 501 ) proposed that store image can be explained as a function of the salient attributes of a par ticu lar stor e that are eval uat ed and weig hte d agai nst each other; ultimately, they deﬁned store image as ‘‘the complex of a consumer ’s perceptions of a store on different (salient) attribut es.’’ 2.3. Patr onag e behavi or Recognizing the importance of patronage behavior , researchers hav e trie d to deﬁn e consu mers ’ stor e patr onage behavi or and deve lop dime nsion s that meas ure patr onage . Osma n (1 993, p. 1 37) delineated ﬁve variables that measure the degree of loyalty patronage from past studies: ‘‘(1) the percentage of purchases of a speciﬁed product category at a chosen store, (2) the frequency of visits to the store in relation to other stores during a certain period of time, (3) the ratio of ranking between stores, (4) the propensity to sho p at th e st or e in th e fu tu re , an d (5 ) th e ex te nt of th e custome rs’ willingness to recomm end the store to their friends.’’ In his study of patronage behavior, Osman (1993) proposed a more simpliﬁed deﬁnition of patronage behavior: ‘‘the repeat purchase behavior at a particular store for either the same products or any oth er pro duct s’’ (p. 13 5). In a stud y of app arel store patron age behavior, Shim and Kotsiopulos (1992) deﬁned patronage behavior as store choice behavior that represents an individual’s preference for a particular store for purchasing products. More recently, Pan and Zinkhan (2006) iden tiﬁe d reta il patr onag e as havi ng two dimensions: (1) store choice (a consumer’s choice to patronize a particular store) and (2) frequency of visit (how often a shopper pat roni zes that stor e). They also found that reta il imag e was a major predictor for explaining shopping frequencies. As discussed above, the degree of store loyalty or patronage behavior can be measured by using various variables. Past studies on store loyalty or pa tr ona ge beh av io r , ho we ver , ha ve use d eit her one or a combination of several of these variables for this measurement. 2.4. Relationship between r etail store envi ronment and patron age behavior Evi den ce fr om the ex ist ing aca dem ic lit era tur e sug ges ts a the ore tic al and em pir ica l con nec tio n bet wee n ret ail sto re AR TIC LE IN PR ESS Y.-K. Seock / Journal of Retailing and Consumer Services 16 (2009) 329–339 331 of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
STORE ENVIRONMENT
 Download or Print 713 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 03/19/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
