<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006171" url="http://www.jobsare.us/jobs/minnesota/cub-foods/" time="2012-07-12-22:51" support="1" score="0.011372547886623126" bingtitle="Cub Foods Jobs in Minnesota - Jobs Are Us" webtitle="Cub Foods Jobs in Minnesota - Jobs Are Us">
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>A Fast Foods Worker serves customer of fast food restaurant: Requests customer order and ... Presses lids onto beverages and places beverages on serving tray or in takeout ...</description>
	<body>
		Home • Post New Job • 
Cub Foods Job Openings in Minnesota
 
 
Local Job Openings
Hiring Now
 Post Your Job Listing 
 20-day listing only $14.99 
 Job Keywords Location 
 View Jobs From: Email Alert Simply Hired (10) Indeed (6) Career Builder (1) Simply Hired found 10 job openings hiring now in Minnesota Deli Manager - Cub Foods - Twin Cities Market in Minnesota - SUPERVALU Title: Deli Manager
Location: Twin Cities
Reports To: Store Director
Responsibilities: Develop daily and weekly work plans using weekly sales
projections and labor goals, promote deli sales through
promotions and effective... Job found at SUPERVALU Inc in Minnesota Salon Manager Job - Cub Food West Plaza in St Augusta, MN - Great Clips to lift up to 35 pounds. Moving: substantial repetitive movements (motions) of the writs, hands, and/or fingers. Hazards may include, but are not limited to, slipping. Location Information: Cub Food West Plaza 266 33rd Ave. S St. Cloud,... Job found at Great Clips in St Augusta, MN CUB Foods Cake Decorator in Mankato, MN - Cub Foods vided by Bakery Manager or person in charge. Able to work a part-time schedule (approx. 20 hours weekly) 9am-9pm M-F; 9am-6pm Sa/Sun Previous experience preferred. Please apply at cub.com Click Careers/Careers/Cub Retail Positions/Apply... Job found at iHispano.com in Mankato, MN Sales Associate I - Maple Grove Cub in Maple Grove, MN - Sales Associate I - Mn085rbsa1 (cub Foods - Maple Grove) Minimum $9.39 hourly
Aggressively promote, sell and refer TCF products and TCF services to customers. Answer inquiries regarding checking and savings accounts and other bank related products. Open new accounts while providing appropriate... Job found at Direct Talent Exchange in Maple Grove, MN Assistant Store Director, Cub Foods , Duluth MN Market in Duluth, MN - SUPERVALU Purpose
To manage the store in the absence of the Store Director. To organize and direct store activities to ensure total store sales, profit and expense goals. To directly manage the Grocery, Drug and Fresh Departments.
Job... Job found at SUPERVALU Inc in Duluth, MN Stylist Job - Cub Food West Plaza in St Augusta, MN - Great Clips to lift up to 35 pounds. Moving: substantial repetitive movements (motions) of the writs, hands, and/or fingers. Hazards may include, but are not limited to, slipping. Location Information: Cub Food West Plaza 266 33rd Ave. S St. Cloud,... Job found at Great Clips in St Augusta, MN Meat Manager - Cub Foods Twin Cities Market in Minnesota - SUPERVALU Title: Meat Manager - Cub Foods Twin Cities Market Location: Minnesota Other Locations: SUPERVALU is a premier food and ... SUPERVALU Advantage - the key to our continuing success. Cub is recruiting for a Meat Manager position located in the... Job found at SUPERVALU in Minnesota Sales Associate I - Stillwater Cub in Stillwater, MN - Sales Associate I - Mn068rbsa1 (cub Foods - Stillwater) Minimum: $9.39 hourly
Aggressively promote, sell and refer TCF products and TCF services to customers. Answer inquiries regarding checking and savings accounts and other bank related products. Open new accounts while providing appropriate... Job found at Direct Talent Exchange in Stillwater, MN Sales Associate I - Blaine South Cub in Blaine, MN - Sales Associate I - Mn066rbsa1 (cub Foods - Blaine) Minimum $9.39 hourly
Aggressively promote, sell and refer TCF products and TCF services to customers. Answer inquiries regarding checking and savings accounts and other bank related products. Open new accounts while providing appropriate... Job found at Direct Talent Exchange in Blaine, MN Assistant Store Director, Cub Foods Twin Cities Market in Minneapolis, MN - SUPERVALU Purpose To manage the store in the absence of the Store Director. To organize and direct store activities to ensure total store sales, profit and expense goals. To directly manage the Grocery, Drug and Fresh Departments. Job... Job found at Monster in Minneapolis, MN Jobs by Simply Hired Indeed found 6 job openings hiring now in Minnesota Part Time Cake Decorator in Mankato, MN - Cub Foods and product preparation, food safety regulations... experience preferred. Please apply at cub.com Click Careers/Careers/Cub Retail Positions/Apply Now... Job found at Cub Foods in Mankato, MN Meat Manager - Cub Foods Twin Cities Market in , MN - Supervalu SUPERVALU is a premier food and drug retail... Shoppers Food&amp;Pharmacy is just one of the banners in SUPERVALU&apos;s family of stores. As the largest food... Job found at Supervalu in , MN Assistant Store Director, Cub Foods , Duluth MN Market in Duluth, MN - Supervalu Purpose To manage the store in the absence of the Store Director. To organize and direct store activities to ensure total store sales, profit and expense goals... Job found at Supervalu in Duluth, MN Meat Manager - Cub Foods Twin Cities Market in Minneapolis, MN - SUPERVALU Companies SUPERVALU is a premier food and drug retail... Shoppers Food&amp;Pharmacy is just one of the banners in SUPERVALU&apos;s family of stores. As the largest food... Job found at Monster in Minneapolis, MN Stylist Job - Hastings Marketplace in Hastings, MN - Great Clips hands, and/or fingers. Hazards may include, but are not limited to, slipping. Location Information: Hastings Marketplace (Next to Cub Foods ) Hastings, MN, US Job found at Great Clips in Hastings, MN Salon Manager Job - Hastings Marketplace in Hastings, MN - Great Clips hands, and/or fingers. Hazards may include, but are not limited to, slipping. Location Information: Hastings Marketplace (Next to Cub Foods ) Hastings, MN, US Job found at Great Clips in Hastings, MN Jobs by Career Builder found 1 job openings hiring now in Minnesota in MN - Faribault - Pepperidge Farm Distributorships Pepperidge Farm Distributorships is hiring INDEPENDENT DISTRIBUTOR/ROUTE OWNER in MN - Faribault, posted 7/10/2012 Job found at Pepperidge Farm Distributorships in MN - Faribault Didn&apos;t find the job you were looking for? 
Instantly check other job networks by clicking the buttons below! Simply Hired (10) Indeed (6) Career Builder (1) No exact job description was found for &quot;Cub Foods&quot; 
Information for the closest matching occupation in our database has been substituted.
 Fast Foods Worker Job Description 
A Fast Foods Worker serves customer of fast food restaurant: Requests customer
order and depresses keys of multicounting machine to simultaneously record order and compute
bill. Selects requested food items from serving or storage areas and assembles items on serving
tray or in takeout bag. Notifies kitchen personnel of shortages or special orders. Serves cold
drinks, using drink-dispensing machine, or frozen milk drinks or desserts, using milkshake or
frozen custard machine. Makes and serves hot beverages, using automatic water heater or
coffeemaker. Presses lids onto beverages and places beverages on serving tray or in takeout
container. Receives payment. May cook or apportion french fries or perform other minor duties
to prepare food, serve customers, or maintain orderly eating or serving areas. Fast Foods Worker DOL Job Code: 311.472-010 Fast Foods Worker jobs may also be called: 

 Fast Foods
Restaurant Cashier jobs 
 Similar jobs now hiring in Minnesota: 
 Fast Foods Worker 
 Find more jobs in this area: 
 Find more Waiters/waitresses, And Related Food Service
Jobs More Food And Beverage Preparation And Service
Jobs 
 Translate Page: 
 Spanish , French , German , Chinese 
 Jobs By State • Recent Searches • Post New Job • Contact Us JobsAre.us is©2011 Jobs Are Us and Marathon Studios Enterprises
	</body>
</document>
