<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006275" url="http://health.usnews.com/usnews/health/articles/070520/28food.timeline.htm" time="2012-07-12-22:57" support="3" score="0.012320434696818223" bingtitle="Health: Timeline: Deaths and Illnesses Caused by Food ..." webtitle="Health: Timeline: Deaths and Illnesses Caused by Food Contamination - US News and World Report">
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000354" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>Politics &amp; Policy; Health ; Money; Education; Science; Travel; Cars; Rankings ... The scale of the outbreak brought national attention to the issue of food safety and ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, July 12, 2012 
 Subscribe   | Contact Us   | Article Index 
 Search U.S. News 
 Politics&amp;Policy Health Money Education Science Travel Cars Rankings 
 
Health
 
 Article Index Subscribe 
 Home &gt; Health 
 Print   | E-mail   | Subscribe   | +  Share 
 Digg Del.icio.us Facebook Newsvine Reddit 
 

Timeline: Deaths and Illnesses Caused by Food Contamination


 By Jennifer O&apos;Shea Posted 5/20/07 



 Compiled by the U.S. News library staff 
 
Related News

 Food Contamination: Better Safe Than Sorry Eat Like a Peasant and Enjoy! Someday Food May Grow in Skyscrapers Common Food Poisonings: Symptoms&amp;Prevention Foods America Imports From Other Countries Photo Gallery: Where Your Food Comes From Diet and Nutrition Community Video: Health News and Features More From U.S. News Health 
 
 2007 

August 2006February 2007: Salmonella-tainted peanut butter from the Peter Pan and Great Value brands sickened hundreds of people in 44 states. The CDC is still investigating how a Georgia manufacturing plant was contaminated.

 2006 

NovemberDecember: 71 people became sick with E. coli after eating at Taco Bell restaurants in New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, and Delaware. The fast-food chain initially blamed its green onion supply, though investigations by the CDC later suggested that lettuce was the source of the problem.

SeptemberOctober: Prewashed, bagged spinach from Dole was contaminated with E. coli. At least 205 consumers fell ill; three died. Investigators traced the strain back to the field in California and said that in this instance, washing could not have removed the bacteria.

 2002 

Fall: Pilgrim&apos;s Pride recalled over 27 million pounds of frozen and prepared poultry products after listeria was found at one of its Pennsylvania processing plants. Eight people died, and 50 became seriously ill in the ensuing outbreak.

 1998 

The Malt-o-Meal cereal company recalled approximately 3 million pounds of its Toasty-O&apos;s cereal after the product was found to contain salmonella. Nearly 200 people, many of them children, got sick. According to the CDC, this was the first time a manufactured cereal was linked to salmonella transmission.

Hot dogs and lunch meats from Sara Lee became tainted with listeria following mechanical work at the manufacturing plant. At least 15 died, and six miscarriages were attributed to the outbreak. Eighty customers also became seriously ill.

 1997 

August: After 17 people in Colorado contracted E. coli from eating hamburgers, supplier Hudson Foods recalled 25 million pounds of frozen patties. At the time, this was the largest meat recall in U.S. history.

Spring: The CDC noticed something unusual: Hundreds of Michigan children and schoolteachers were diagnosed with hepatitis A. Investigators discovered that a contaminated shipment of strawberries had been imported the previous year and mislabeled as domestic. The strawberries were used in frozen desserts and served with school lunches. Ultimately, over 9,000 students were vaccinated.

 1996 

Shipments of Guatemalan raspberries were contaminated with the intestinal parasite cyclospora. An estimated 1,500 in the U.S. and Canada became infected before the cause was found. Investigators blamed the problem on unhygienic growing conditions. In response, the U.S. halted importation of the Guatemalan fruit. The ban was partially lifted in 1999.

 Mid-1990s 

In the past decade, thousands have become sick with food-borne illnesses like E. coli and salmonella after eating raw sprouts. Over 22,000 illnesses and two deaths have been traced to these outbreaks. The FDA estimates that 20 percent of all produce-related illnesses are from sprouts and recommends that diners avoid eating the vegetable raw.

 1993 

January: Four children died and at least 700 became ill after eating hamburgers from Washington state Jack in the Box fast-food restaurants. The meat was tainted with E. coli, and the burgers had not been cooked to a high-enough temperature to kill the bacteria. The scale of the outbreak brought national attention to the issue of food safety and prompted the development of PulseNet, a program that links data from the CDC and state health departments.

 1985 

In one of the first large-scale listeria outbreaks in the United States, shipments of Jalisco&apos;s Mexican-style soft cheese were found to contain the bacterium. Eighteen people died, and 30 infant deaths and stillbirths were connected to the contamination.

April: Salmonella in milk sickened thousands and killed at least three throughout the Midwest. Investigators cited improper pasteurization at the processing plant.

 1984 

In Oregon, members of a commune led by guru Bhagwan Shree Rajneesh tried to influence a local land-use vote by spreading salmonella to their neighbors. Members of the group produced the bacterium in a lab and poisoned food at 10 local restaurants. No one died, but 751 people became ill.

 1982 

Another large-scale recall of botulism-tainted canned foodsthis time, improperly canned Alaskan salmon. At least one Belgian man died after eating the fish.

 19731974 

Seventy-five million cans of mushroom pieces were pulled from grocery stores following reports that they contained botulism. Some consumers reported seeing swollen cans on store shelves.

 1971 

After a New York man died of botulism from eating Bon Vivant brand vichyssoise, the Food and Drug Administration launched a full investigation, confiscating more than 1 million cans of the company&apos;s products. No one else became sick, but the company filed for bankruptcy one month later.
 
 Print   | E-mail   | Subscribe   | +  Share 
 Digg Del.icio.us Facebook Newsvine Reddit 
 
 Sphere: Related Content 
advertisement
 
advertisement
 
 Health Headlines from USNews.com 
 
HEALTH NEWS FROM HEALTHDAY

 Reused Vials, Unsafe Injections Threatening Patients: CDC Electric Fans May Have No Effect in Extreme Heat: Study Home Elder Care: Buyer, Beware BPA Substitute Lurks in Paper Money, Receipts &apos;Beige&apos; Fat Joins Brown Fat as Potential Weight-Loss Target More Headlines From HealthDay 
 
 Symptom Search 
 
American Hospital Association Symptom Finder

Discover possible causes of your symptoms.
 Pick a symptom Abdominal pain Ankle pain Anxiety Back pain Breathing difficulties Chest pain Constipation Cough Depression Diarrhea Discolored skin patches Dizziness Edema Fatigue Fever Foot pain Frequent urination Gas Hair loss Headache Heartburn Heel pain Hiccups Hip pain Impotence Increase in blood pressure Insomnia Jaundice Joint pain Knee pain Loss of appetite Low back pain Low blood pressure Nausea Neck pain Nosebleed Painful urination Rash Scaling skin Seizure Shin pain Shoulder pain Skin redness Sneezing Snoring Stuffy nose Tinnitus Vaginal discharge Vertigo Vomiting Yawning, excessive 

 
 Health 
 
 Best Hospitals 

The 18th edition ranks 173 medical centers and includes a guide to help navigate any hospital.

 Health Community A-Z Index: Diseases&amp;Conditions Video: Health News&amp;Features Tools: Calculators&amp;Directories Blog: Comarow on Quality Opinion: Dr. Bernadine Healy 
 
 NEWSLETTER 
 
Sign up today for the latest headlines from U.S. News and World Report delivered to you free.

 Learn More 
 
 RSS FEEDS 

Personalize your U.S. News with our feeds of blogs and breaking news headlines.

 Subscribe 
 
 USNews MOBILE 

U.S. News daily briefings are also available on your mobile device.

 Subscribe 
 
 Politics&amp;Policy   | Health   | Money   | Education   | Science   | Travel   | Cars   | Rankings 

Copyright©2012 U.S.News&amp;World Report, L.P. All rights reserved.
 
 Subscriber Services | Site Map | About Us | Contact Us | Newsletters | Marketplace | Store | Advertise With Us | Press Room | Masthead | Widgets | RSS | 

Use of this Web site constitutes acceptance of our Terms and Conditions of Use and Privacy Policy .
	</body>
</document>
