<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006469" url="http://forum.bodybuilding.com/showthread.php?t=910285&amp;page=1" time="2012-07-12-23:24" support="3" score="0.004195542529547953" bingtitle="Dont work fast food, heres why. - Bodybuilding.com Forums" webtitle="Dont work fast food, heres why. - Bodybuilding.com Forums">
			<query id="000446" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001322" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000756" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>Or I need a tray of Reg meat. SO I drop 8 patties on ... When you&apos;re 14 or 15 a fast food restaurant is one of the ... lieing bitch of a manager fired me (said I wasnt picking ...</description>
	<body>
		24/7 Customer Service 1-877-991-3411 Contact Us Need Help? View Cart 
 
 in: Whole Site BodySpace Store SuperSite Reviews BodyGroups BodyBlogs Exercises Videos 
 Free Gift! Any Order Over $ 75 Discounts&amp;Deals - Sign Up! 
 Find A Plan Store BodySpace SuperSite Forum 
 

The Worlds #1 Bodybuilding And Fitness Forum - Save Up To 50% Off Retail Prices In Our Bodybuilding.com Store !

 
 
 
 
 Today&apos;s Posts FAQ Community 
 BodySpace BodyGroups Pictures&amp;Albums Members List BodyBlogs 
 Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 View Forum Leaders Who&apos;s Online 
 
 
 Advanced 
 
 Forum » More General Categories » Misc. » Dont work fast food, heres why. 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 1 to 30 of 77 
Thread: Dont work fast food, heres why. 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Email this Page… Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 09-23-2006, 07:15 PM #1 puppetzz 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Visit Homepage 
 Registered User Join Date: Jun 2005 Location: Michigan Age: 23 Posts: 1,143 BodyPoints: 61 Rep Power: 0 
Dont work fast food, heres why.
 Seriosly, I have worked at Wendys and McDonalds. I worked at Wendy&apos;s for 7 months and quit. I hated every month of it. I was without work for 6 months and really needed money so I got a job at McDonalds through a friends. This is my second week there and Im really hating it. For one, Fast food is extremely repetitive. Today I pretty much spent 7 hours doing the same thing over again. You always have multiple people yelling at you telling you to drop something in the fryer or laydown more meat. They say more nuggests and I run down to the fryer and drop a bag of nuggets. Or I need a tray of Reg meat. SO I drop 8 patties on the grill. Not only is it very repetitive but its very stressfull which is the worse part. I plan on being a pharmacists so I can handle repetitiveness. At fast food though you have to be VERY fast. Everybody is always bumping into each other and yelling and every 10 seconds a timer goes off and you have to hit the button and pull whatever went off. If you run out of meat or something people get mad. There is very little down time. You dont get any rest besides your break. Its constantly cracking eggs for breakfast and working the hot grill which you often burn yourself because you have to work so fast. Also your co-workers are complete retards. All of them pretty much have no future and sing to every fricken song on the radio that plays in the kitchen. There all a bunch of crappy college students. I think it actually helps to be dumb to work in fast food sometimes. Smart people tend to relize that the working envirement degrading. I need to have a job where I can sit down and actually use my head. Not just some boring repetitive job where I have to work my ass off and get minimum wage for it.

If you want a job go to a clothing store, or anything really. I would love to sit and stock or something and relax just a little bit. I think Mnimum wage is going up to 6.95 so I will try and hold out for as long as I can. I think Im going to continue to look for a job and quit when I find one even though Ive only been working for 2 weeks. 09-23-2006, 07:19 PM #2 devildog 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Dec 2001 Posts: 460 Rep Power: 16 That would suck. Although I think working the register would be even worse. Not sure how long I could take some toothless, fat, retard with 6 kids spitting their order in my face before I snapped. 09-23-2006, 07:19 PM #3 sandersonF1 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2006 Posts: 307 Rep Power: 83 It isn&apos;t the most fun thing ever, but I worked at McDonald&apos;s for a year and a half when I was 15 and I have no regrets. The work itself is repetetive and during rushes it got very fast, but it was all people my age, very fun social atmosphere there. Lots of joking around, etc. It was my first job and a great experience.

When you&apos;re 14 or 15 a fast food restaurant is one of the few places where you can quite easily find employment. They won&apos;t hire you at that age at a clothing store or most places.

Sounds like somebody is just bitter and needs to vent. 09-23-2006, 07:20 PM #4 Jeremy-Vincent 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 only in texas baby Join Date: Dec 2005 Location: san antonio Posts: 2,487 BodyPoints: 7105 Rep Power: 2179 yeah your right i work at mcdonalds too and it sux, but i just work one day a week now.

yes one day a week.

my co workers always ask me why do i work one day a week honestly i don&apos;t really know why but i know that when i used to work more it was really ****ty.

i still get the jokes from my co workers.&quot;you work one day a week? how much do you get paid a week 3.50? durrrrrr&quot; Last edited by Jeremy-Vincent; 09-23-2006 at 07:22 PM . We&apos;ve all been
raised on television to believe that one day we&apos;d all be
millionaires, and movie gods, and rock stars. But we won&apos;t. And
we&apos;re slowly learning that fact. And we&apos;re very, very pissed off.
-tyler durden -&quot;fight club&quot;
Misc Pimp # fitty 09-23-2006, 07:21 PM #5 strongsmallkid 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Dat Stringer Bell Join Date: Jan 2005 Location: California, United States Age: 23 Posts: 9,098 BodyPoints: 2609 Rep Power: 15389 are you aware? 09-23-2006, 07:21 PM #6 Coal Man 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 GODERATOR Join Date: Jul 2006 Age: 25 Posts: 19,493 BodyPoints: 30122 Rep Power: 1111290 Originally Posted by puppetzz Seriosly, I have worked at Wendys and McDonalds. I worked at Wendy&apos;s for 7 months and quit. I hated every month of it. I was without work for 6 months and really needed money so I got a job at McDonalds through a friends. This is my second week there and Im really hating it. For one, Fast food is extremely repetitive. Today I pretty much spent 7 hours doing the same thing over again. You always have multiple people yelling at you telling you to drop something in the fryer or laydown more meat. They say more nuggests and I run down to the fryer and drop a bag of nuggets. Or I need a tray of Reg meat. SO I drop 8 patties on the grill. Not only is it very repetitive but its very stressfull which is the worse part. I plan on being a pharmacists so I can handle repetitiveness. At fast food though you have to be VERY fast. Everybody is always bumping into each other and yelling and every 10 seconds a timer goes off and you have to hit the button and pull whatever went off. If you run out of meat or something people get mad. There is very little down time. You dont get any rest besides your break. Its constantly cracking eggs for breakfast and working the hot grill which you often burn yourself because you have to work so fast. Also your co-workers are complete retards. All of them pretty much have no future and sing to every fricken song on the radio that plays in the kitchen. There all a bunch of crappy college students. I think it actually helps to be dumb to work in fast food sometimes. Smart people tend to relize that the working envirement degrading. I need to have a job where I can sit down and actually use my head. Not just some boring repetitive job where I have to work my ass off and get minimum wage for it.

If you want a job go to a clothing store, or anything really. I would love to sit and stock or something and relax just a little bit. I think Mnimum wage is going up to 6.95 so I will try and hold out for as long as I can. I think Im going to continue to look for a job and quit when I find one even though Ive only been working for 2 weeks. 
Cliffnotes? ▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬ஜ۩۞۩ஜ▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬
﻿...............................R.I.P.................................
.............Aziz&quot;Zyzz&quot;Sergeyevich Shavershian.........
.................₪₪₪₪₪₪1989-2011₪₪₪₪₪₪.............
▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬ஜ۩۞۩ஜ▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬▬ 09-23-2006, 07:26 PM #7 out of shape 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Sep 2006 Age: 34 Posts: 192 Rep Power: 23 I got lucky. As a teen and in my early college years, I was a lifeguard at a country club. So lucky. My friends did try the fast food industry. All quit in less than a week. Most ended up working at a restaurant, catering, or caddying, The latter paid the most.

Hang in there. my right arm bicep is bigger than my left! 09-23-2006, 07:28 PM #8 AGS 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Banned Join Date: Mar 2005 Age: 23 Stats: 5&apos;7&quot;, 145 lbs Posts: 4,314 BodyPoints: 155 Rep Power: 0 I worked at Quizno&apos;s for nearly a year ... I don&apos;t know if it falls into the fast food category, as it has more of a restaurant appeal, but we still had our share of fatties come in ... I don&apos;t regret it, although it did hurt my gains eating a sandwich everytime I worked (usually a tuna, with no mayo, but the tuna had mayo inside) 09-23-2006, 07:28 PM #9 Miz-Zou 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 is staying positive! :) Join Date: Jan 2006 Location: Kansas City, Missouri, United States Age: 25 Stats: 6&apos;3&quot;, 244 lbs Posts: 5,806 BodyPoints: 9508 Rep Power: 4118 Cliffnotes: Kid found job at Wendys, didn&apos;t like it, got a job at McDonald&apos;s and is hating every minute of it! the end. 09-23-2006, 07:28 PM #10 BuildUpNow 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nooberator Join Date: Nov 2004 Posts: 13,481 BodyPoints: 30461 Rep Power: 34816 Originally Posted by Coal Man Cliffnotes? im emo i dont wanna work wait wut 09-23-2006, 07:30 PM #11 forgot password 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Living in a vacuum sucks Join Date: Oct 2004 Location: United States Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 201 lbs Posts: 4,903 BodyPoints: 14442 Rep Power: 789 if you want to be a pharmacist y not work as a technician or if under 18 a technician trainee? I drive really slow
In the ultra-fast lane
While people behind me are going insane

Marriage is a great institution, but I&apos;m not ready for an institution yet.

My Karma ran over your dogma.
,___,
[O.o]
/)__)
-&quot;--&quot;- o&apos;Rly 09-23-2006, 07:32 PM #12 muscleman420 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Whatever It Takes Join Date: Jul 2006 Stats: 5&apos;11&quot;, 189 lbs Posts: 12,816 BodyPoints: 37141 Rep Power: 6727 Originally Posted by puppetzz Seriosly, I have worked at Wendys and McDonalds. I worked at Wendy&apos;s for 7 months and quit. I hated every month of it. I was without work for 6 months and really needed money so I got a job at McDonalds through a friends. This is my second week there and Im really hating it. For one, Fast food is extremely repetitive. Today I pretty much spent 7 hours doing the same thing over again. You always have multiple people yelling at you telling you to drop something in the fryer or laydown more meat. They say more nuggests and I run down to the fryer and drop a bag of nuggets. Or I need a tray of Reg meat. SO I drop 8 patties on the grill. Not only is it very repetitive but its very stressfull which is the worse part. I plan on being a pharmacists so I can handle repetitiveness. At fast food though you have to be VERY fast. Everybody is always bumping into each other and yelling and every 10 seconds a timer goes off and you have to hit the button and pull whatever went off. If you run out of meat or something people get mad. There is very little down time. You dont get any rest besides your break. Its constantly cracking eggs for breakfast and working the hot grill which you often burn yourself because you have to work so fast. Also your co-workers are complete retards. All of them pretty much have no future and sing to every fricken song on the radio that plays in the kitchen. There all a bunch of crappy college students. I think it actually helps to be dumb to work in fast food sometimes. Smart people tend to relize that the working envirement degrading. I need to have a job where I can sit down and actually use my head. Not just some boring repetitive job where I have to work my ass off and get minimum wage for it.

If you want a job go to a clothing store, or anything really. I would love to sit and stock or something and relax just a little bit. I think Mnimum wage is going up to 6.95 so I will try and hold out for as long as I can. I think Im going to continue to look for a job and quit when I find one even though Ive only been working for 2 weeks. since you are not enjoying it i would suggest gettingout asap. lifes too short to spend weeks doing somthing you dont want to. best lifts: 500 lb squat @ 181. 585 deadlift @ 185. 625 block pull. 315x3 bench.
best stats: 190 @ 8%

don&apos;t take my misc posts seriously
feel free to pm me about anything lifting related 09-23-2006, 07:46 PM #13 SniperChick 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Resident Female Join Date: Jan 2005 Location: Oh Canada Age: 23 Stats: 5&apos;6&quot;, 115 lbs Posts: 2,499 BodyPoints: 3786 Rep Power: 1630 Originally Posted by sandersonF1 It isn&apos;t the most fun thing ever, but I worked at McDonald&apos;s for a year and a half when I was 15 and I have no regrets. The work itself is repetetive and during rushes it got very fast, but it was all people my age, very fun social atmosphere there. Lots of joking around, etc. It was my first job and a great experience.

When you&apos;re 14 or 15 a fast food restaurant is one of the few places where you can quite easily find employment. They won&apos;t hire you at that age at a clothing store or most places.

Sounds like somebody is just bitter and needs to vent. Yep, I agree. I started working at Wendy&apos;s when I was 14 going on 15 and at the time it was great. The summer before that I sold chocolate bars for some charity and while you actually -could- make good money (like $70 a day) it was the worst. So when I started working there I found the concept great --customers come to YOU wanting something! Lol, after a year of that I took some time off, then worked at The Body Shop for the holidays, and now just recently got hired at Mexx. It&apos;s all what you make of it and yourself (after you&apos;re 16 if you have the personality you can convince fairly good companies to hire you without that much experience). I would definitely be cringing if I had to backtrack. Screw you Wendy&apos;s...screw you. ^_^

 Originally Posted by AGS I worked at Quizno&apos;s for nearly a year ... I don&apos;t know if it falls into the fast food category, as it has more of a restaurant appeal, but we still had our share of fatties come in ... I don&apos;t regret it, although it did hurt my gains eating a sandwich everytime I worked (usually a tuna, with no mayo, but the tuna had mayo inside) Ahah, yea, I&apos;m a vegetarian and as such usually get the veggie sub (no mayo or anything). Anyway, I was trying to figure out what could POSSIBLY be bad in it with only the vegetables, and yet still taste so good. THEN I found it while researching on the net...it&apos;s the bread! 0_0 *Comforts AGS* I know I know... 09-23-2006, 07:52 PM #14 BigDreams21 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Feb 2005 Location: United States Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 158 lbs Posts: 10,779 BodyPoints: 15419 Rep Power: 10679 09-23-2006, 07:55 PM #15 HeroOfTheDay384 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 I live in a giant bucket Join Date: Apr 2005 Location: Beloit, WI Age: 24 Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 185 lbs Posts: 2,048 BodyPoints: 230 Rep Power: 0 I work at McDonalds right now unfortunately. Its not as bad as he is saying. At least at my work. It does get pretty hectic. The only thing keeping me there is my friends. We really dont give a ****. I just hate not being able to get in meals if you work for 7 hours. Its also hard to drink the water I need throughout the day because they dont let you eat during shifts. I think Im gonna bring a frickin milk jug full of water and a sandwich or something to work everyday. Just go to the&quot;crew room&quot;while I go to get something from the freezer, take a bite of my sandwich and chug some water....Im pretty pumped for this. Pain is weakness leaving the body.

I&apos;ll tell you this: In any fight, it&apos;s the guy who&apos;s willing to die who&apos;s gonna win that inch. And I know if I&apos;m gonna have any life anymore, it&apos;s because I&apos;m still willin&apos; to fight and die for that inch.

&quot;People of mediocre ability sometimes achieve outstanding success because they don&apos;t know when to quit.&quot;-George Allen 09-23-2006, 07:58 PM #16 Shiden11 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Apr 2004 Posts: 861 Rep Power: 79 Get a job as a pharmacy tech like someone else said. Or at least as a cashier in a pharmacy. But be warned, they&apos;re going to want you to move your lazy arse too. 09-23-2006, 08:03 PM #17 blood vs. water 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 WHITE MAN IS THE DEVIL Join Date: Oct 2003 Location: Staten Island, New York, United States Age: 29 Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 210 lbs Posts: 9,616 BodyPoints: 14255 Rep Power: 47286 when i was 15-16 i worked at a small grocery store. it was pretty cool. a lot of young people worked there. tons of girls would come in there all the time. i stole so much **** from there and i was friends with everyone in the deli section so i always left with mad food.

when i was 17 and had my first car, i started delivering pizza. that was the best. always out driving around making money, friends always coming in and hanging out, smoking blunts with the mexicans in the back room. the owner was oblivious to everything. free food all the time.

i got fired from there when i was 18 and started working full time for a big shipping company. 5 years later im still at the same place and hating every day of it.

i don&apos;t really know if there&apos;s a moral to my story. but try and get a new job if you don&apos;t like it. Pass me the gun for man&apos;s extinction
I piss in the fountains of youth you drink from
My stomach&apos;s got young dead orphans in it
I eat from trashcans at abortion clinics 09-23-2006, 08:03 PM #18 One Man Army 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Architect of Aggression Join Date: Dec 2005 Posts: 6,824 BodyPoints: 5543 Rep Power: 30128 I like the way the threadstarter says they all have no futures(his coworkers) but then tells us they are all college students. If they are in college then they should be having futures(hence going to college dumbass) He shouldnt be talking...he&apos;s but a high school student 09-23-2006, 08:10 PM #19 puppetzz 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Visit Homepage 
 Registered User Join Date: Jun 2005 Location: Michigan Age: 23 Posts: 1,143 BodyPoints: 61 Rep Power: 0 I said crappy college. I dont see how somebody has a future when they are retarded. 09-23-2006, 08:37 PM #20 Dark Phoenix 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Jun 2004 Location: Ottawa Age: 29 Posts: 5,387 BodyPoints: 14103 Rep Power: 638 Originally Posted by HeroOfTheDay384 I work at McDonalds right now unfortunately. Its not as bad as he is saying. At least at my work. It does get pretty hectic. The only thing keeping me there is my friends. We really dont give a ****. I just hate not being able to get in meals if you work for 7 hours. Its also hard to drink the water I need throughout the day because they dont let you eat during shifts. I think Im gonna bring a frickin milk jug full of water and a sandwich or something to work everyday. Just go to the&quot;crew room&quot;while I go to get something from the freezer, take a bite of my sandwich and chug some water....Im pretty pumped for this. 
THat somehow seems illegal. If they bitch about water, say that it is needed to prevent dehyration and working in a hot kitchen, it can happen quickly, as such you feel it is dangerous to your health. I pull **** like this at work and I get left alone. Furthermore, you should, legally, get a lunch break on a 7 hr shift, or at leaSt a couple 10 minute breaks, you could eat on those. I am not trying to be better than you, just better than myself
BB jiu jitsu team 2009 09-23-2006, 08:38 PM #21 Dark Phoenix 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Jun 2004 Location: Ottawa Age: 29 Posts: 5,387 BodyPoints: 14103 Rep Power: 638 Originally Posted by SniperChick Yep, I agree. I started working at Wendy&apos;s when I was 14 going on 15 and at the time it was great. The summer before that I sold chocolate bars for some charity and while you actually -could- make good money (like $70 a day) it was the worst. So when I started working there I found the concept great --customers come to YOU wanting something! Lol, after a year of that I took some time off, then worked at The Body Shop for the holidays, and now just recently got hired at Mexx. Merivale and MEadowlands by chance? I am not trying to be better than you, just better than myself
BB jiu jitsu team 2009 09-23-2006, 08:40 PM #22 Mango7 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Banned Join Date: Jun 2006 Location: United States Posts: 2,485 BodyPoints: 3129 Rep Power: 0 I&apos;m not a Peta fanatic, but the animals that end up as food at fast food restaurants live in hellishly abysmal conditions. When you throw that patty on or crack that egg open realize there was an animal that was in forced submission to give there life for that food... 09-23-2006, 08:54 PM #23 Car_Freak 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2005 Location: Oshawa, Ontario, Canada Age: 20 Stats: 6&apos;1&quot;, 196 lbs Posts: 600 BodyPoints: 3211 Rep Power: 9 I worked in Tim Hortons for about 2 weeks my lieing bitch of a manager fired me (said I wasnt picking everything up fast enough) BULL ****ING **** I was pro she was such a racist bitch the first day I was there she had a shouting match with someone in the back of the store over like nothing.

But yeah theres never any relax time usualy unless its a monday.

stupid old buck toothed whore ~Meh~ 09-23-2006, 08:58 PM #24 jboyd1 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Feb 2006 Age: 27 Stats: 5&apos;10&quot;, 168 lbs Posts: 766 BodyPoints: 4632 Rep Power: 114 Originally Posted by Mango7 I&apos;m not a Peta fanatic, but the animals that end up as food at fast food restaurants live in hellishly abysmal conditions. When you throw that patty on or crack that egg open realize there was an animal that was in forced submission to give there life for that food... 
I got you on the patties of meat.......but you don&apos;t have to kill the chicken to get the egg, chickens lay eggs thats what they do. They don&apos;t say **** I have to lay an egg today those damn people. Ya hippy 09-23-2006, 09:10 PM #25 thek1d 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Gift Tax gives me a donor Join Date: Jul 2006 Location: Houston, Texas, United States Posts: 3,462 BodyPoints: 2993 Rep Power: 8271 Originally Posted by puppetzz Seriosly, I have worked at Wendys and McDonalds. I worked at Wendy&apos;s for 7 months and quit. I hated every month of it. I was without work for 6 months and really needed money so I got a job at McDonalds through a friends. This is my second week there and Im really hating it. For one, Fast food is extremely repetitive. Today I pretty much spent 7 hours doing the same thing over again. You always have multiple people yelling at you telling you to drop something in the fryer or laydown more meat. They say more nuggests and I run down to the fryer and drop a bag of nuggets. Or I need a tray of Reg meat. SO I drop 8 patties on the grill. Not only is it very repetitive but its very stressfull which is the worse part. I plan on being a pharmacists so I can handle repetitiveness. At fast food though you have to be VERY fast. Everybody is always bumping into each other and yelling and every 10 seconds a timer goes off and you have to hit the button and pull whatever went off. If you run out of meat or something people get mad. There is very little down time. You dont get any rest besides your break. Its constantly cracking eggs for breakfast and working the hot grill which you often burn yourself because you have to work so fast. Also your co-workers are complete retards. All of them pretty much have no future and sing to every fricken song on the radio that plays in the kitchen. There all a bunch of crappy college students. I think it actually helps to be dumb to work in fast food sometimes. Smart people tend to relize that the working envirement degrading. I need to have a job where I can sit down and actually use my head. Not just some boring repetitive job where I have to work my ass off and get minimum wage for it.

If you want a job go to a clothing store, or anything really. I would love to sit and stock or something and relax just a little bit. I think Mnimum wage is going up to 6.95 so I will try and hold out for as long as I can. I think Im going to continue to look for a job and quit when I find one even though Ive only been working for 2 weeks. I worked at McDonald&apos;s in high school. I thought it was an okay job. Sure it is repetitive, but so is going to school. Life is repetitive if you think about it. You just have to make it fun. When we closed I would crank up the music and work topless. My co-workers would laugh because I would&quot;shake it like a salt shaker&quot;but it made the time go by faster. I eventually got into banking, but I went back to fast food for a 2nd job that I work at on the weekends now. It&apos;s still easy as hell. You&apos;re still young. Work is suppose to suck for you. Use it as motivation to do well in school and to succeed in life. You have to start somewhere, and at least you have stuff to put on a resume.

P.S. Aren&apos;t you supposed to cook 9 reg patties at a time, in a 3x3 layout? No wonder you don&apos;t like it, you don&apos;t even know what the hell your doing. Just kidding bro, chill out. 09-23-2006, 09:10 PM #26 Rambo26 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Visit Homepage 
 Bulking to 350lbs Join Date: Jun 2006 Location: Somerset, United Kingdom (Great Britain) Age: 26 Stats: 5&apos;10&quot;, 224 lbs Posts: 14,010 BodyPoints: 10075 Rep Power: 2027 Originally Posted by Miz-Zou Cliffnotes: Kid found job at Wendys, didn&apos;t like it, got a job at McDonald&apos;s and is hating every minute of it! the end. kthx 09-23-2006, 09:12 PM #27 Man Whore 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nudist Camp Commandant Join Date: Apr 2006 Age: 27 Posts: 307 BodyPoints: 235 Rep Power: 0 Originally Posted by puppetzz Seriosly, I have worked at Wendys and McDonalds. I worked at Wendy&apos;s for 7 months and quit. I hated every month of it. I was without work for 6 months and really needed money so I got a job at McDonalds through a friends. This is my second week there and Im really hating it. For one, Fast food is extremely repetitive. Today I pretty much spent 7 hours doing the same thing over again. You always have multiple people yelling at you telling you to drop something in the fryer or laydown more meat. They say more nuggests and I run down to the fryer and drop a bag of nuggets. Or I need a tray of Reg meat. SO I drop 8 patties on the grill. Not only is it very repetitive but its very stressfull which is the worse part. I plan on being a pharmacists so I can handle repetitiveness. At fast food though you have to be VERY fast. Everybody is always bumping into each other and yelling and every 10 seconds a timer goes off and you have to hit the button and pull whatever went off. If you run out of meat or something people get mad. There is very little down time. You dont get any rest besides your break. Its constantly cracking eggs for breakfast and working the hot grill which you often burn yourself because you have to work so fast. Also your co-workers are complete retards. All of them pretty much have no future and sing to every fricken song on the radio that plays in the kitchen. There all a bunch of crappy college students. I think it actually helps to be dumb to work in fast food sometimes. Smart people tend to relize that the working envirement degrading. I need to have a job where I can sit down and actually use my head. Not just some boring repetitive job where I have to work my ass off and get minimum wage for it.

If you want a job go to a clothing store, or anything really. I would love to sit and stock or something and relax just a little bit. I think Mnimum wage is going up to 6.95 so I will try and hold out for as long as I can. I think Im going to continue to look for a job and quit when I find one even though Ive only been working for 2 weeks. use paragraphs numbnuts! 09-23-2006, 09:16 PM #28 thek1d 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Gift Tax gives me a donor Join Date: Jul 2006 Location: Houston, Texas, United States Posts: 3,462 BodyPoints: 2993 Rep Power: 8271 Originally Posted by Man Whore use paragraphs numbnuts! Why do you think he works at McDonald&apos;s? 09-23-2006, 09:17 PM #29 DangerDan 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Banned Join Date: Jul 2006 Location: Texas, United States Age: 22 Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 170 lbs Posts: 17,979 BodyPoints: 12669 Rep Power: 0 minimum wage is 6.95 up there!?!?!?!?!

its 5.50 here!!!! 09-23-2006, 09:21 PM #30 Whingman 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Jan 2004 Age: 25 Stats: 5&apos;6&quot;, 176 lbs Posts: 1,268 BodyPoints: 6143 Rep Power: 185 I start work at eight o&apos;clock I pick up 3 tiles weighing 10 pounds each, put them on a bundling machine, pick up two more tiles, put them on the machine, take straping insert in hole, pick up bundle of five tiles walk over to pallet, put bundle down, walk back to machine, pick up 3 tiles.......10:00 take break, 10:15 pick up 3 tiles weighing 10 pounds each..... I believe that anyone can conquer fear by doing the things they fear to do, provided they keep doing them until they get a record of successful experience behind themselves. 
 Page 1 of 3 1 2 3 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Quick Navigation Misc. Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums Main Forums 
 Supplements 
 Supplement Company Transformation Contests And More Product Reviews - Help Out! 
 Supplement Logs Sponsored Supplement Logs Company Promotion Supplement Misc. 
 Supplement Wars! Supplement Science 
 BodySpace Profiles And BodyBlogs Workout Programs 
 Advanced fat loss HELL RAISER TRAINING Workout Journals Derek Charlebois&apos; Contest Prep Section! 
 Exercises 
 Injury Recovery And Prevention 
 
 Specifically For You 
 Teen Bodybuilding 
 Teen Misc. Teen Workout Logs 
 Over Age 35 
 Over 35 Workout Journals Over 35 Misc 
 Female Bodybuilding 
 Nutrition and Supplements Training General Chat Journaling Fat Loss Female Misc. 
 Powerlifting/Strongman 
 Powerlifting Workouts - Training Journals MMA Fighting 
 MMA Training Logs 
 Olympic Lifting Powerlifting Video Library 
 For Personal Trainers 
 More General Categories 
 Post Your Pictures Post Your Own Articles! Sports Training 
 Sports Training Journals Outdoor Recreation 
 Fitness Competitions IFBB Pro Bodybuilding Nutrition 
 Nutrition Logs Nutrition Misc Keto 
 Keto Logs Keto Recipes 
 Advanced Nutrition 
 Contest Preparation 
 INBF-WNBF NPC Contest Prep Journals OCB-IFPA FAME 
 Losing Fat 
 Advanced fat loss Losing Fat Logs 
 Motivation Personals - Meet Other Bodybuilders Misc. 
 Science and Technology Sports 
 Fantasy Sports 
 WWE Wrestling Forum Religion / Politics Music Relationship Help 
 Workout Equipment 
 Latest Bodybuilding Issues 
 Topic Of The Week! 
 Workout Of The Week Wallpaper Of The Week - Create Your Own And Win! 
 BB.com - Give Us Your Ideas! Article Reviews! Careers At Bodybuilding.com 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google Facebook Twitter 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts 
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 -- BBcom Default -- BBcom Black -- BBcom Mobile 
 Contact Us Bodybuilding.com Archive Top 
 Member Login 
 Remember Me 
 
 Forgot Login Info? 
 
 
 All times are GMT -7. The time now is 02:24 PM . Archive Home Store Products Careers Help Contact Us Terms of Use Checkout
	</body>
</document>
