<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006809" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/678144" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="1" score="0.0030049163102728593" bingtitle="If you HAD to eat at a fast food chain... - Chains - Chowhound" webtitle="If you HAD to eat at a fast food chain... - Chains - Chowhound">
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="134"/>
	<description>I used to bring large cup fills of Bud&apos;s sauce to friends living out of town =) ... if i have to eat fast food, and sometimes i must, i choose taco bell. most of their stuff ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; Chains Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
If you HAD to eat at a fast food chain...
 
Fast food is junk, I know, but with my budget I can&apos;t eat out at too many places these days. If you had to eat at one of the major chains, which one would you choose?

I would pick Wendy&apos;s, hands down. The one in my neighborhood has good service and the fastest drive-thru around. They make decent salad and baked potatoes, the chili is pure awesomeness, and their burgers and fries aren&apos;t too bad either. I shy away from obscene stuff like the Baconator, but I think most of their menu is pretty good.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Revenant on Jan 4, 2010 10:52 AM 
Updated on Sep 22, 2010

 87 Replies 
 
 
You are pretty much right there. Whataburger is another one and the best one in my book is a chain that&apos;s only in NM called Blakes Lotaburger. I really can&apos;t understand the big deal about In-n-Out, They&apos;re OK, but that&apos;s about it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By mrbigshotno.1 on Jan 4, 2010 11:11 AM 
 re: mrbigshotno.1 
In-n-Out...sorry big
Popeye&apos;s
Del Taco
Steak and Shake
Chick-fil-A

I&apos;m looking to experience SmashBurger soon.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By fourunder on Jan 4, 2010 11:27 AM 

 re: mrbigshotno.1 
What it is about In-N-Out is that they do NOT use frozen pre-formed patties or frozen precut fries. Their patties are formed daily from fresh hamburger meat, and the fries are cut from fresh potatoes. At the risk of sounding too much like the oldfashioned Progressive that I am, I think the familial atmosphere within the restaurant&apos;s business structure has a lot to do with it, too. I firmly believe that happy staffers produce better food. So far they have deliberately resisted getting too big, and I hope they continue to do that.

McDonald&apos;s Filet-O-Fish is OK but weird - what&apos;s that piece of&quot;cheese&quot;doing in there? But That&apos;s my chain of choice up until 10:30AM; give me a couple of Sausage McMuffins and a hashbrowns cake and I&apos;m a happy if overfed boy.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Will Owen on Jan 4, 2010 01:17 PM 
 re: Will Owen 
For cheap breakfasts I would go to McD&apos;s for either a $1 sausage McMuffin or an egg burrito - with hot sauce, which it seriously needs, and get a couple of apple pies ($1 for 2) to go with it.

Then I discovered Burger King&apos;s super cheap breakfast possibilities, with ham and egg on an english muffin - which is quite good, and tater tots stuffed with cheese. Their apple pie ain&apos;t bad either.

BTW, both places sell coffee at a greatly reduced price to Seniors.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sharuf on Jan 5, 2010 12:10 AM 
 re: Sharuf 
I&apos;m slightly addicted to McD&apos;s sugar-free Vanilla Ice Coffee (We&apos;re in FL.) for breakfast. I can&apos;t stand any of their McMuffin items, but they make an above avergae bicuit.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By cavandre on Jan 5, 2010 03:35 AM 

 
 re: Will Owen 
I like In-n-Out&apos;s burgers okay, but their french fries are absolutely the best fast-food fries I&apos;ve ever had. They taste like potatoes, and they&apos;re not oversalted.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By jlafler on Jan 6, 2010 10:39 AM 

 
 
 
i find burger king in calgary my favorite.big king all the way.&quot;do ya want the crown or the clown&quot;
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By howlin on Jan 4, 2010 11:55 AM 

 
Agree, Wendy&apos;s chili is pretty good stuff.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By monku on Jan 4, 2010 12:04 PM 

 
First of all, fast food is not junk (at least not all of it).

That said, here are my choices:

McDonald&apos;s: Filet-O-Fish.
In-N-Out: Burgers
Which Wich: Sandwiches
Chipotle: Burritos (esp. the barbacoa)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Jan 4, 2010 12:18 PM 

 
Popeye&apos;s
Chipotle
Five Guys (since there are no In N Outs on the East coast, but if there was it would take the place of Five Guys)
Chick fil A
Bud&apos;s Broiler (if I was back home)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Jan 4, 2010 12:41 PM 
 re: roro1831 
Yum....Bud&apos;s Broiler! I used to bring large cup fills of Bud&apos;s sauce to friends living out of town =)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By GrayGoose on Jul 20, 2010 11:52 AM 

 re: roro1831 
I&apos;ll add Bojangles to my list, not as good as Popeye&apos;s but still very good. The biscuits are better IMHO, but the two sides I tried were not that good (dirty rice and cajun pinto beans). My wife&apos;s mashed taters were good with the white country gravy
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Jul 21, 2010 09:23 AM 

 
 
I love Mcdonalds fries, and every so often a McD&apos;s cheeseburger can be quite delicious and satisfying.
I used to love TacoBell when I was young, but it&apos;s been YEARS since I have had it and I&apos;m too afraid to try it now...

I can&apos;t remember ever having Wendy&apos;s..hmm I&apos;ll have to try it
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By NellyNel on Jan 4, 2010 12:47 PM 

 
Wendy&apos;s, b/c I can baked potatoes or chili (or both.) I don&apos;t normally eat much FF though.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By sisterfunkhaus on Jan 4, 2010 12:53 PM 

 
Arby&apos;s - There&apos;s something about the horsey sauce!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Den on Jan 4, 2010 01:05 PM 
 re: Den 
I am with you there...I think the roast beest sandwich is just a polite way to eat horsey sauce. About the only fast food I get an occaisional lust for.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sam at Novas on Jan 4, 2010 01:43 PM 
 re: Sam at Novas 
Back in my Arby&apos;s-eating days, I could never get into their beef-like substance, but I did like the equally fake turkey. My favorite lunch was the Super Turkey (that&apos;s how I ordered it, don&apos;t remember what the menu called it) with a potato cake on the side, and both of those things got liberally anointed with Horsey Sauce. Use to be able to get that for about $4...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Will Owen on Jan 4, 2010 02:00 PM 

 
 
 
Taco Villa for fast Tex-Mex. Their taco burgers and meat burritos are, as they say, da&apos; bomb.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Perilagu Khan on Jan 4, 2010 01:26 PM 

 
On our Weight Watcher days: McDonald&apos;s grilled southwest chicken salad; Subway roast chicken or roast beef 6&quot;subs.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By junescook on Jan 4, 2010 01:26 PM 
 re: junescook 
I&apos;m glad to see someone mention Subway. With their $5 footlong subs, you can make two meals . . . that is if you enjoy loads of veggies on your sandwich, which I do. It&apos;s also a great way to get more servings of veggies into your diet at a modest price! My fave is the oven-roasted chicken with a combination of ranch dressing and sweet onion sauce.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By chowdawggy on Jan 4, 2010 04:31 PM 
 re: chowdawggy 
Wow, that&apos;s exactly what I have when I go to Subway. Oven-roasted chicken on Monterey cheddar bread, pepper jack cheese, ranch, sweet onion and some veggies. Doesn&apos;t get much better than that.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Revenant on Jan 4, 2010 09:29 PM 

 
 
 
If I had a very tight budget, and I&apos;ve been through a few periods of that, I wouldn&apos;t spend my food dollars at fast food restaurants. I&apos;m sorry if that bothers you, but I felt it needed to be said. Now if the issue is time and convenience, that&apos;s another matter, but given that you want FF recs, I&apos;ll say this. There&apos;s a breakfast bar at Whole Foods that&apos;s 2.99/lb. for polenta, steel cut oats, or a mixed grain porridge with toppings bar. That&apos;d be my breakfast choice, or the local coffeehouse that gets croissants and sandwiches from a good baker. For lunch or dinner, I&apos;d likely head to the Mexican place where I can get a huge torta (sandwich) for $5-6, with drink, or get tacos for $1 each. Not a chain, yes, but good value, and most cities have similar options.

Chipotle&apos;s portions are big enough to make two meals of one burrito, etc. Wendy&apos;s for a baked potato at the beginning of the evening, when they haven&apos;t been overcooked, with some chili and cheese. In-n-Out when I&apos;m on the west coast, though the burgers are a total gut bomb. There&apos;s also a regional chain here called Winstead&apos;s that makes an edible grilled chicken sandwich with an overly sweet bun. Some of my friends love Culver&apos;s, but I find the food greasy and bland.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By amyzan on Jan 4, 2010 01:40 PM 

 
Love that McDonald&apos;s Double cheeseburger (loved it more on the dollar menu)
But overall I&apos;m really liking Panera these days.

This will likely get moved to the Chains board...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By iluvcookies on Jan 4, 2010 01:51 PM 
 re: iluvcookies 
&quot;Chipotle&apos;s portions are big enough to make two meals of one burrito, etc.&quot;

Interesting. I really like Chipotle, but up until recently I&apos;ve found their servings fall _short_ of a full meal, i.e., I&apos;m still hungry after eating there. However, the last couple of times, it seemed that my local branch had increased its meat servings, so it&apos;s now an adequate meal. Still can&apos;t imagine getting two meals out of it though. FWIW, I usually order the 3-taco meal, all barbacoa.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Steve Green on Jan 8, 2010 12:31 PM 
 re: Steve Green 
The barbacoa burrito fills me up pretty darn good, and the poster stated that it was the burrito. I agree with you, three tacos don&apos;t fill me up
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Jan 8, 2010 12:41 PM 
 re: roro1831 
The tacos usually don&apos;t have the rice in them, which accounts for a significant difference in the volume of food you get. The tacos are satisfying to me as a meal, but I can (and try to) get 2 meals out of a burrito bowl
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By weezycom on Jan 9, 2010 08:50 AM 

 
 re: Steve Green 
Steve, I must point out the obvious here. I am a woman and you are clearly a guy by your moniker. &apos;Nuff said.

While there are undoubtedly some men who only need the same caloric intake as an average woman, I&apos;d say that generally, men need more calories to feel satisfaction than a woman would.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By amyzan on Jan 10, 2010 07:49 AM 

 
 
 
Arby&apos;s for a Jamocha Shake. It&apos;s my yearly post-half-marathon treat.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By nofunlatte on Jan 4, 2010 02:38 PM 

 
White Castle
Sonic
Subway
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Cherylptw on Jan 4, 2010 04:18 PM 
 re: Cherylptw 
Wow - how did I forget White Castle?!
I haven&apos;t had it in years but man I still get a huge craving for them every once in a while....regular burger (not w/cheese) and onion rings! mmmm
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By NellyNel on Jan 5, 2010 05:54 AM 
 re: NellyNel 
I can get WC in the frozen section of the grocery her in NoCal. They MW great.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Jan 7, 2010 05:37 PM 

 re: NellyNel 
Yes, we do get them frozen here as well, but they just arent the same!

The best thing about WC is the texture of the bun...it gets kind of mushy...and the onions are soft and lovely as opposed tyo the onions on the frozen ones which are just annoying bits of yuck... plus you have to add your own ketchup which ruins the continuity of the whole thing...I cant even say for me they will due in a pinch...they arent the same at all :(

Sorry C - what does MW stand for? I have been tryin to figure it out!!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By NellyNel on Jan 8, 2010 09:44 AM 
 re: NellyNel 
microwave?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By fourunder on Jan 8, 2010 09:49 AM 
 re: fourunder 
oh!
yeah - I guess that&apos;s right!! LOL!!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By NellyNel on Jan 8, 2010 10:12 AM 

 
 
 
 
 
Chik-fil-A - freshest food in general and the best service. Good cole slaw and fruit
Bojangles - great chicken, biscuits and coleslaw
Five Guys - great burgers&amp;fries
Wendy&apos;s - decent salads. Did they change their buns recently? I got a burger and I always liked their buns and this one was different. It had seed-like things on the top bun that were never there before.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By lynnlato on Jan 4, 2010 04:32 PM 

 
Fast Food Restaurants I will eat at:

Quiznos’
Chipotle’s
Rubio’s
Au Bon Pain

Honorable Mentions:

Carl’s Jr.
Five Guys
Der Wienerschnitzel (sometimes you just have to have a chili dog)
Chick fil-A
El Pollo Loco
Taco Time (we all have our quirks)

Places I avoid like the plague:

In-N-Out – greasy burgers, pasty cheese, nasty fries, it’s all marketing hype.
Baja Fresh – dirty restaurants, highly inconsistent food, spoiled salsa on 3 out 5 trips to different locations.
Panera Bread – The nastiest surliest employees I have ever seen in any establishment (2 locations, 2 different franchisee’s, 2 different states), is this their gimmick, be rude?
Panda Express – greasy items topped with overly sweet canned sauces.
Long John Silvers – no comment needed.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RetiredChef on Jan 5, 2010 05:51 AM 
 re: RetiredChef 
While I am by no means of Panda Express, I do have to say that their food is not greasy (at least by Chinese fast food standards) and their sauces, while indeed very very sweet and cloyingly so, are not from cans.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Jan 5, 2010 05:57 AM 

 re: RetiredChef 
Chick-Fil-A is the best chicken sandwich, got to be the peanut oil.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By monku on Jan 5, 2010 07:18 AM 

 
 
For breakfast, easily McD&apos;s. Now serving oatmeal!

For the rest of the day, Wendy&apos;s is a good choice. McD&apos;s for McDoubles and fries. Chipotle. Chik-fil-A. Subway for a cheap, filling lunch. Sonic/Steak n Shake/Checkers if I&apos;m south of DC.

And about twice a year -- Taco Hell.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Bob W on Jan 5, 2010 09:01 AM 

 
I like Tropical Smoothie&apos;s sandwiches, and the lettuce in their salads has consistently fresh. Their Jamaican wrap actually has a decent kick to it by fast food standards.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By beachmouse on Jan 5, 2010 09:07 AM 

 
Chipotle makes an acceptable burrito. But if your main issue is price, and you have a good independent tacqueria nearby, then I wouldn&apos;t bother.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By jlafler on Jan 6, 2010 10:45 AM 

 
I guess I&apos;m lucky to live in an area where I can get a better lunch for cheaper than I would pay at a fast food place (i.e. a dosa and a lassi, or a torta with a bottle of jarritos, etc., all for around 6 bucks) but there are times where I will crave some good old fast food, and those times I&apos;m usually drawn to Nathan&apos;s. They make a quality dog, cooked on a flat top griddle, and their fries are among the best of all chains. Can&apos;t beat that.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By TongoRad on Jan 8, 2010 10:07 AM 

 
We live in urban, downtown SF, and fast food restaurants are few and far between, but I love certain chain fast food restaurants:

Subway (this is a go to, inexpensive, healthy meal nearby)

In N&apos; Out - so on board with the freshness and general vibe of this restaurant
(this is strictly our en route to Tahoe stop)

Panda Express- really pretty good, fresh ingredients and their Panda Bowls with a smart choice entree like broccoli beef are healthy and yummy.

Taco Bell/Del Taco/Jack In The Box Tacos - ONLY after a long night out in Vegas. But then, DELICIOUS!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By jdinsf on Jan 14, 2010 07:24 PM 

 
well i don&apos;t eat fast food unless someone else makes the decision&amp;leaves me no choice, but if i *had* to eat it, i&apos;d go somewhere that offered at least a few healthful menu items...like Au Bon Pain, Baja Fresh, El Pollo Loco, Chipotle and Rubio&apos;s.

standard burger, sandwich, pizza&amp;fried chicken places aren&apos;t really options for me because i can&apos;t have gluten, and their salads are usually pretty underwhelming.

i do remember liking Wendy&apos;s chili when i had it many years ago. and of course i could never resist a Frosty ;)

it also depends on where you live, since some fast food chains are regional.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By goodhealthgourmet on Jan 14, 2010 07:58 PM 
 re: goodhealthgourmet 
I agree about&quot;regionality&quot;. Here is the PNW we have Taco Time. It is by far my favorite FF option for their crispy burritos, soft tacos and their amazingly great hang over cure called a Taco Burger.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Befuness on Jan 20, 2010 11:51 AM 
 re: Befuness 
I&apos;ve been waiting for someone to mention Taco Time. We were down to one in town until one opened relatively close to me. I always get a soft combo burrito and crisp meat burrito. Yummmmm!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By tracylee on Jul 21, 2010 12:52 PM 

 
 
 
Not Your Average Joe&apos;s isn&apos;t bad. The 99 is decent, too, but that may be a New England chain.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Dinsdale45 on Jul 20, 2010 01:22 PM 
 re: Dinsdale45 
Actually, they&apos;re both New England chains, although both have expanded (a little) beyond the region. (In the case of NYAJ, one store in northern VA.) But neither is especially relevant to this thread, which specifically asks about fast-food restaurants.

That said, my vote would go to Bojangles or Church&apos;s for chicken (neither of which is plentiful in the Northeast), McD&apos;s if I need a quick breakfast (and, VERY infrequently, McNuggets, although I still haven&apos;t forgiven them for ditching dark meat), and Arby&apos;s, mainly for the Jamocha Shake mentioned upthread. I&apos;ve gotta try Chipotle&apos;s, now that they&apos;ve moved into my area.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By brandywiner on Jul 20, 2010 09:05 PM 

 
 
I&apos;m from Indianapolis, which may be chain restaurant ground zero, so I know what I&apos;m talking about when I say Hardee&apos;s is the best fast food chain. Alongside Hardee&apos;s, none of the other chains have a reason to exist. Their breakfast biscuits are made on-site, with real fried eggs, and right at this moment I can&apos;t remember if I&apos;ve had a better biscuit at a&quot;real&quot;restaurant or anywhere else. For lunch and dinner, stay away from their expensive flagship burger line and troll their specials menu which they are always changing, like spicy chicken sandwiches for $1 and two chili dogs for $3.

The fries are the only weak link but they are no more lousy than any other fast food fries.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RealMenJulienne on Jul 20, 2010 09:46 PM 
 re: RealMenJulienne 
The ones around here stopped serving their chili. Now that was good stuff, far better than what you can get at Wendy&apos;s or Tim Horton&apos;s. And plenty of local joints.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Fibber McGee on Jul 21, 2010 08:48 AM 

 
 
for burgers I like Culvers Butterburgers (midwest chain)

otherwise Chipotle hands down, unless you have an authentic local place

of course cooking at home is the best way to save $ on food IMO :D I prefer free range/air chilled chickens, but you can still make a .88 cent/lb supermarket water chilled bird yummy! :D make a 5lb on the weekend and it could last a long while

at any rate for the price of one chipotle buritto or burger value meal you could roast a free range bird :D or even buy a $5 sams club or costco rotisserie
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By DukeOfSuffolk on Jul 21, 2010 08:48 AM 
 re: DukeOfSuffolk 
Where on earth are you that you can get chicken for 88 cents/pound? I can&apos;t even get supermarket/no name whole chicken for less than $1.99/lb. :(

Anyway, as for this thread, Chipotle, hands down.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By irishnyc on Jul 23, 2010 04:51 AM 
 re: irishnyc 
Ralphs in southern californnia just had whole chickens on sale for 59 cents a pound.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By malibumike on Jul 26, 2010 07:50 AM 

 re: irishnyc 
I honestly have no idea where you could POSSIBLY be shopping to experiance whole chicken prices that high, I have personally never seen them higher than about $1.49, and that was during a nationwide shortage due to contamination. Now, organic is another matter, but I assume we are discussing regular chicken?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By aemrynna on Sep 2, 2010 07:23 PM 
 re: aemrynna 
Here in New Jersey, unless the stores are having a sale on poultry, it very common for the prices to be $2.99-3.99/lb. regularly. Extended, it&apos;s shocking for me to see the final price from $10-16 dollars. That alone is reason enough to join Costco, where the every day price is .89 cents.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By fourunder on Sep 3, 2010 08:23 AM 

 
 
 
 
If I must, Pollo Tropical. Their grilled chicken is pretty tasty - especially with the (fakey, neon yellow, delicious) curry sauce slathered over the chicken. Also - I have had luck with their salads - usually fresh and crisp, with grilled chicken. Not bad at all if I have to grab a quick bite somewhere.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Mothership on Jul 21, 2010 09:41 AM 
 re: Mothership 
I am here in Dallas and I want to put in a vote for Taco Cabana.
Not sure where else they have them but for fast food mexican I find it on par price wise with Taco Bell and the like and the quality much higher. Plus they have a fresh salsa bar with four or five different kinds at all times that makes all of the difference.
Popeyes for chicken.
For fast food burgers my choice is usually to spend a few extra bucks and move up to a chain restaurant. Fuddruckers my favorite but Red Robin, Outback and even Chilis has a decent burger if you can spend a little more time and a few bucks more. Usually well worth it and you can often take half to go even on a good size appetite. (at outback if you sit at he bar they wil often give you a oaf of their bread first which should make taking half the burger to go very doable for most.)
Also, join Costco or Samsclub and head in for the $1.50 1/4 hot dog with a drink. Best deal going IMHO...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ronaldpedwards on Jul 21, 2010 10:20 AM 
 re: ronaldpedwards 
I haven&apos;t had Taco Cabana in quite some time since I lived in TX, but I did like it. It was about the only option in College Station when I lived there, although now that Freebirds is a chain, that makes my list as well.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Jul 21, 2010 10:36 AM 

 re: ronaldpedwards 
What kind of hot dog is it at Sam&apos;s Club? They&apos;re not as good at Costco since they switched from Hebrew National but still a bargain.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Fibber McGee on Jul 21, 2010 12:13 PM 
 re: Fibber McGee 
At Sams here in Des Moines, they serve Nathans. Costco, Kirkland.
Sams wins.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Bobfrmia on Jul 22, 2010 08:01 PM 
 re: Bobfrmia 
I&apos;m inclined to agree.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Fibber McGee on Jul 23, 2010 04:20 AM 

 
 
 
 
 
Firehouse Subs - puts Subway to shame
Popeyes
Steak and Shake
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Wakeley Bridge on Jul 21, 2010 04:43 PM 
 re: Wakeley Bridge 
I hear good things about Firehouse. My friend has the rights to open up some locations in New Orleans and the surrounding area.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Jul 21, 2010 09:20 PM 
 re: roro1831 
Firehouse is pretty good, depending on what you order. My standby there is the Sweet&amp;Spicy Meatball, which even when they don&apos;t have on the menu, they can still make. It&apos;s basically just their regular meatball sub with a douse of the datil pepper sauce, but it makes it something special.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By TuteTibiImperes on Aug 9, 2010 07:40 PM 

 
 
 
Taco Cabana - when visiting Austin
Jimboys
El Pollo Loco
Sonic
Jack in the Box

I was thinking - can a place be considered fast food if it doesn’t have a drive-thru?? If so, then also:

Panera - those little breakfast quiches are fantastic
Chipotle
Quiznos
Panda Express
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By karrill on Jul 21, 2010 09:36 PM 
 re: karrill 
I had my first (two) Jimboy Tacos the other day and really liked them. My husband remembers going to their first location in Kings Beach/Lake Tahoe in the 50s.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Jul 22, 2010 08:10 AM 
 re: c oliver 
There is something about those crazy tacos that reels me in. I have a Jimboys two blocks from my house and I have to fight the urge to pull in the drive-thru (almost successfully) quite often. :)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By karrill on Jul 22, 2010 05:22 PM 
 re: karrill 
I want to go inside now and watch them&quot;do&quot;the tortillas. A little fried/crispy but only a little. Lard?????????
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Jul 22, 2010 06:22 PM 

 
 
 
 
Boston Market for Chicken
Quizno&apos;s for subs (though frankly would rather get a sub at Publix or one of the local italian delis, they run about the same price but give you a much better sub, but neither of those qulify as a fast chain)
Moe&apos;s southwest grill for burritos, would rather have Chipotle but they are not conveniently located for me.
If I have to have fast food burger its checkers, though I pretty much have to be dragged to a burger place by someone else, I will never pick it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By willdupre on Jul 24, 2010 07:51 PM 
 re: willdupre 
I like Quizno&apos;s specifically for that sauce they have on the fixings bar. I could eat that with a spoon.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By southernitalian on Aug 16, 2010 08:50 AM 

 
 
if i have to eat fast food, and sometimes i must, i choose taco bell. most of their stuff is actually boiled in a sealed prefrozen sack, so there is not frying or oils. i&apos;m vegan so i&apos;m really picky. they allow you to customize the order and their guacamole is great. i love the crunch wrap, i get it with just beans lettuce and tomato and sometimes just lettuce and tomato and of course i always add the guaco for extra flavor. they have fresco bean burrito that is good too. i always feel that i get what i want from the bell which is more than i can say for most the others, tho wendy&apos;s has the baked potato, plain is great, fulling and nutritious.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By enufizenuf on Jul 25, 2010 11:22 PM 

 
Carl&apos;s Jr., Five Guys, and Popeye&apos;s.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By cookingasshole on Jul 25, 2010 11:29 PM 

 
Well, I don&apos;t know if this is exactly a chain - but here goes - Pop Burgers in NYC! Had them the last time I was there and now I can&apos;t get them off my mind! There was just something about it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By boyzoma on Aug 8, 2010 04:22 PM 
 re: boyzoma 
I wasn&apos;t impressed at all with Pop Burger
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Aug 10, 2010 08:19 AM 

 
 
For burgers, Wendy&apos;s or Steak and Shake. I agree with the obscenity of the baconator, they accidentally gave me one instead of the regular apple wood smoked bacon burger the other day, which I didn&apos;t realize until I had driven back to work. I ate about half of it then had to throw the rest away - how can you eat that much meat and cheese without having some vegetables to cut the grease? I&apos;ve eaten at in&amp;Out once while visiting LA, and I thought it was good. Any burger served with thousand island is OK in my book.

How about WaWa? I&apos;m sure there are some mid-atlantic residents here who are familiar. Open 24 hours, very good subs and sandwiches fresh made at the in-store deli, plus all of the standard convenience store fare. WaWa is one of the things I miss most about Delaware, well, also Country Maid delis as far as good goes. I can&apos;t understand how things that awesome are a Northeast regional thing, the rest of the country would love to have it too.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By TuteTibiImperes on Aug 9, 2010 07:46 PM 

 
TACO BELL! Can&apos;t believe no one mentioned it yet. Even in San Diego, with the plethora of taco shops, I find myself drawn to TB every once in a while for their bean burritos and Nachos Bell Grande. Funny, of all the other fast food establishments I&apos;ve frequented in my childhood, adolescence, and adult years, TB is THE only place I&apos;ve never had a bad experience at!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By globocity on Aug 11, 2010 10:56 PM 
 re: globocity 
It was mentioned, just referred to as Taco Hell
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By roro1831 on Aug 12, 2010 08:14 AM 

 re: globocity 
I admit that I regularly crave a bean volcano crunch wrap.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By im_nomad on Aug 16, 2010 08:42 AM 

 
 
Wendy&apos;s - baked potato with sour cream and a chili. Dump the chili over the baked potato, and then add as much hot sauce/sour cream as you like. Tastes good, and is nearly healthy.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By FrankD on Aug 16, 2010 08:57 PM 
 re: FrankD 
Okay, I just gotta ask. What part of that is&quot;nearly healthy&quot;? The potato?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Sep 2, 2010 11:53 AM 

 
 
Whataburger or Church&apos;s Chicken.
Maybe an ocassional Whopper or a Chik-fil-A with extra pickles.

I lived in LA for 10 years and still do not understand the attraction of In-N-Out.
Once you&apos;ve had a Whataburger why would you ever want an In-N-Out burger? Makes no sense.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By CharlieKilo on Aug 22, 2010 03:00 PM 
 re: CharlieKilo 
I&apos;ve eaten at Whattaburger maybe 4 or 5 times, and have *never* thought it was any good, yet people on here are always saying how great it is. I must be ordering the wrong thing! What do you get there that is so good? I think that I usually just get the large style CB, whatever it is called...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Clarkafella on Aug 22, 2010 03:08 PM 

 
 
Every once in a while I like a Dairy Queen Cheese Burger. Our local DQ makes them pretty good and gooey!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By boyzoma on Sep 2, 2010 11:48 AM 

 
I grew up in Washington State, but now live in NC, so I have a unique view of both sides of the US.

Taco B(H)ell, especially in my 3rd trimester as my daughter decided even before birth that hot sauce was its own food group.
Wendy&apos;s-I love their nuggets, chili, and baked potatoes. BY THE WAY, ALL YOU WENDY&apos;S CHILI LOVERS OUT THERE, AM I THE ONLY ONE WHO ACTUALLY KNOWS HOW IT&apos;S MADE? I FIGURED SO MANY MORE OF YOU WOULD OBJECT TO THAT...
Mcdonalds-The best salads, hands down.
Subway-Best subs here in NC, since you can&apos;t seem to get a Port of Subs here.
Port Of Subs-Best Subs EVER!
Jack In the Box-Best dollar burgers, the Jumbo Jack is only $1.19 and has all the veggies the cheap ones at other places lack. Unfortunately, NC doesnt have JIB :(
Taco Time-Again, none in NC. GREAT mexican-american for the price, and its fast and fresh. Used to work there, so that is saying alot.
Arbys-Everytime I get tired of the grease fest, Which is alot lately now that I am 25 and not a teenager, I go there. The only thing greasy they have is their fries, so it&apos;s easy to get a healthy meal. And NOTHING on earth can beat Arby&apos;s Sauce!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By aemrynna on Sep 2, 2010 07:34 PM 
 re: aemrynna 
The thought of ANY chain makes me retch, so this is hard. I actually would rather go to a gas station and get a granola bar and beef jerkey.

Hmmm, but if we must. I&apos;d go to Subway and get some sort of veggie sub, if one exists.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By natewrites on Sep 6, 2010 10:56 AM 

 re: aemrynna 
I don&apos;t know what part of NC you are in but in the areas that I frequent I have seen plenty of JIB.

My fave fast food has to be Bojangles and Popeyes. Not really big fan of other fast food places. But then the restaurant that my family runs is actually a fast food concept. Japanese fast food actually and we are just as quick as McDonald&apos;s with much fresher food. So that is my other favorite fast food place.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By vttp926 on Sep 6, 2010 07:01 PM 

 
 
chic fil-a!
then wendys.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By carlee134 on Sep 22, 2010 04:32 PM 

 
 «Back to the Chains Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 Food Franchises That Don&apos;t Suck (373 replies) 1 Which fast food chain has the most cultish (and maybe even divisive) following? (157 replies) 2 Admit it... There&apos;s Some Dishes at Chain Restaurants You Like (329 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 44 

 Interesting article to share... 

26 minutes ago
 
 9 

 Recommendations for Things to... 

about 2 hours ago
 
 479 

 Your disappointing purchases... 

about 3 hours ago
 
 0 

 Friendly&apos;s lobster roll 

about 4 hours ago
 
 43 

 Trader Joe&apos;s Yea/Nay Thread... 

about 5 hours ago
 
 9 

 Has KFC&apos;s chicken pot pie changed... 

about 5 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 Healthy Make-Ahead Lunches See All 35 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » Supertaster Daily: Vegemite » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Blue Cheese and Chive Compound Butter 
 
 »Blogs » Quirky in Queens: Panorama of My Silence-Heart Café » All&apos;Angolo: Tasty Italian Pasta in LA&apos;s Koreatown » Should Lamb Have a Strong Taste? » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County 
 
 »Discussion » Persipan - where to find? » Macarons in Los Angeles? » Best place to buy whole lobsters. East Bay and coast. » Visiting LA. Restaurant recs? (Dietary restricitons) » Best Sichuan and Hunan in GTA? » Why do you drink milk? 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;If you HAD to eat at a fast food chain...&quot;
	</body>
</document>
