<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006741" url="http://wvschools.com/harrisoncounty/csos/alternative/alternative.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:44" support="2" score="0.003035810728183181" bingtitle="EXECUTIVE SUMMARY" webtitle="EXECUTIVE SUMMARY">
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>EX: Select descriptive words to convey which condiment he ... EX: Place picture cards in order of the events from ... and speakers (e.g. summarize and paraphrase to confirm ...</description>
	<body>
		TITLE 126 

 LEGISLATIVE
RULE 

 BOARD OF
EDUCATION 

   

 SERIES 44P 

 ALTERNATE
ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENT STANDARDS 

 FOR
WEST VIRGINIA SCHOOLS (2520.16) 

   

   

 126-44P-1. General. 

             1.1.   Scope .   West Virginia Board of Education 126CSR42, Policy 2510, Assuring the Quality of Education:
Regulations for Education Programs (hereinafter Policy 2510), provides a
definition of a delivery system for, and an assessment and accountability
system for, a thorough and efficient education for West Virginia public school
students.   Policy 2520.16 defines
the alternate academic achievement standards across grades    3–8 and 11 in
reading/language arts and in mathematics and science for grades 3–8 and
10 and 11 for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities and is
inclusive of existing content standards, extended standards, and performance
descriptors as required by Policy 2510. 

   

             1.2.   Authority.    W. Va. Constitution, Article XII, 2, W. Va. Code
18-2-5 and 18-9A-22. 

   

              1.3.   Filing Date.   -   July 11,
2008. 

   

 1.4.   Effective Date.   -   August 11, 2008. 

   

             1.5.   Repeal of former rule.   This legislative rule repeals and
replaces W. Va. 126CSR44P, West Virginia Board Policy 2520.16, Alternate Academic Achievement Standards for
West Virginia Schools filed March 19, 2007 and effective April 18, 2007. 

   

 126-44P-2.   Purpose. 

   

             2.1.   This policy defines the alternate
academic achievement standards for the program of study required by Policy 2510
for students with the most significant cognitive disabilities, i.e., those who
are typically assessed with the West Virginia Alternate Assessment. 

   

 126-44P-3.   Incorporation by Reference. 

             

            3.1.   The West Virginia
Extended Academic Content Standards and Performance Descriptors in
reading/language arts and in mathematics across grades 3–8 and 11 and
science across grades 3–8 and 10 and 11 is attached and incorporated by
reference into this policy.   Copies
may be obtained in the Office of the Secretary of State and in the West
Virginia Department of Education. 

   

   

 3.2.   Summary (of Alternate Academic
Achievement Standards.) The West Virginia Board of Education has the
responsibility for establishing high quality educational standards for all
education programs (W.Va. Code 18-9A-22). The alternate academic
achievement standards provide a framework for teachers of students with the
most significant cognitive disabilities to teach skills and competencies
essential for independent living, employment, and postsecondary
education. Policy 2520.16 links the existing content standards in reading/language
arts, in math and in science with the extended standards and includes
performance descriptors that are aligned with the extended standards. These
performance descriptors are the basis for cut scores for the Alternate
Assessment. The extended standards and performance descriptors included
in Policy 2520.16 are applicable for students with the most significant
cognitive disabilities, i.e., students who are assessed with the West Virginia
Alternate Performance Task Assessment 

   

 126-44P-4.   Severability. 

   

             4.1. If any provision of this rule or the application
thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, such invalidity shall
not affect other provisions or applications of this rule. 

   

   
 
 
 GRADE THREE
EXTENDED READING 

 CONTENT
STANDARDS AND PERFORMANCE DESCRIPTORS 

   

 Reading and English
Language Arts Content Standards and Objectives 

   

 Standard
1: Reading (RLA.S.3.1) 

 
 Students
 will apply reading skills and strategies to inform, to perform a task and to
 read for literacy experience by
	</body>
</document>
