<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006855" url="http://www.runza.com/runzatic/hall_of_fame" time="2012-07-12-23:50" support="18" score="0.034938075339579294" bingtitle="Runza® | Hall of Fame" webtitle="Runza| Hall of Fame">
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>When my sister and I were growing up our mother and father took us to the original Runza restaurant out on South and Van Dorn St...</description>
	<body>
		0 Items (USD0.00) 
 View Cart Online Store 
 
 About Menu Nutrition Jobs Franchise Community Kids Runzatic 
 Find a Runza ® 
 Map 
 
 Tast-e-mail Take the Quiz Hall Of Fame (Psst. Over Here) 
 
Our most famous fan? Let’s see, Larry the Cable Guy has professed his love for Runza®. Rocker Tommy Lee fell in love with our sandwiches while filming a TV show in Nebraska. But Bill Clinton might take the prize. In December of 2000, he became the only known sitting president to eat a Runza® Sandwich.
 
 

 Sign Up Now
 
 
Hall of Fame
 
 For a year I had been told about something called a Runza... 
For a year I had been told about something called a Runza...well last November my boyfriend took me to Nebraska where I got to experience 2 new things...the zoo and the Runza with fries!!! Ohhhh, my gosh I absolutely loved the zoo but I couldn&apos;t get over the best sandwich that I have ever had...yep...the Runza!!! Holy cow it was amazing! I have wanted one ever since and just recently they opened a new location in Kansas City that is only 15 minutes from my home. I have never been sooooo excited to go to a burger place in my life as I was to go enjoy the Runza like I did for the first time in Nebraska. Yes!!! It was even better than I remembered. Thank you Thank you Thank you for putting a Runza restaurant so close to where I live!
 My most memorable Runza experience just occurred last week... 
My most memorable Runza experience just occurred last week with the opening of the Shawnee Mission location. I was desperate for a Runza fix, but I mistakenly turned the wrong direction on Johnson Drive. I drove for 10 minutes....the wrong way....until I realized I wasn&apos;t going to find it. I debated skipping my trip to the Runza since I had been so erroneous, yet I knew I couldn&apos;t let my three-year-old son down, so I turned around and headed in the right direction. Fifteen minutes later, I pulled into the sparkly new Runza and smiled....we had made it! My son tried his first Runza ever, after only having chicken strips, and he shouted from the backseat, &quot;Yum! Yum! Yum! This is delicious!&quot; My son had finally experienced the deliciousness of a Runza! Definitely my most memorable experience!
 My daughter had recently had her training wheels removed from her bicycle... 
My daughter had recently had her training wheels removed from her bicycle and was showing the family how she could ride up and down the driveway. She ended up wiping out and scraped her leg and shoulder pretty bad. After we got her bandaged up we asked what would make her feel better and she said,&apos;Maybe a Runza would help&apos;! It was SO cute and of course we took the whole family to Runza right away :)
 I&apos;m usually out of town on business and arriving late at night and usually very hungry... 
I&apos;m usually out of town on business and arriving late at night and usually very hungry... Many times coming in late and looking for a good place to eat and fast too...I&apos;ve stopped many times coming in and stopped at our &quot;RUNZA&quot; on Broadway...These late visits have always been rewarding and tasty too !!! I appreciate their service as well as quality of the food products..Keep up the good work...Steven
 My name is Leigh and I am from the sunflower state of Kansas... 
My name is Leigh and I am from the sunflower state of Kansas. I had the pleasure of driving through Nebraska years ago and having my first glorious experience of the best cheese burger and fries my palate could imagine. I have many times over the years set in disappointment with all the other burgers out there. I have talked often of that glorious experience and how incredible the service was. I was treated not only to the best burger but true down home hospitality. I cannot tell you my sheer delight when watching the local news to hear a Runza was coming to town. My sheer delight then turned into euphoria to soon learn that Runza would be in walking distance from my home! I never have to dream of that unattainable, glorious, juicy, fresh, cheesy hamburger... I just walk to the most courteous, well-staffed, delicious place just around the corner. I have now made myself hungry so an evening walk to the Runza for an evening snack with the family sounds like a fantastic way to top off the day!
 I sent my husband to Lincoln Nebraska (200 miles) to bring back a dozen Runza sandwiches for me... 
I sent my husband to Lincoln Nebraska (200 miles) to bring back a dozen Runza sandwiches for me. I would then carefully pull one wrapped delight out of the freezer, put it in the microwave and anxiously wait to savor my treat. All too soon my Runza bag was empty and I would search the freezer to make sure none had fallen out. I was thrilled when a location opened up in Lawrence Kansas which was 45 miles away. Now my husband does not have to drive very far to make me happy because a new store opened up close to home.
 I LOVE RUNZA!!! 
I LOVE RUNZA!!! I was living out in California and continously craved Runza. I tried making the Runza casserole but it just wasn&apos;t the same. My husband was back in Omaha, NE and I begged him to freeze a ton of them and bring them to me. He did and I was in heaven : ) We just recently moved back to NE and I&apos;ve pretty much ate there everyday now for 2 weeks. I&apos;m a Runzatic and love it!!!
 I am somewhat embarrassed to share this, but I recall my mom once suggesting I invest in RUNZA... 
I am somewhat embarrassed to share this, but I recall my mom once suggesting I invest in RUNZA stock (if it even exists!) since I eat at RUNZA so much!! She had been helping me clean my apartment and my car when she uncovered several old RUNZA bags lying here and there. Oops!! I forgot to get rid of the evidence! Now with a RUNZA just down the street from my apartment complex, it is an even more frequent stop for me, especially for the divine fries and yummy Southwest Chicken Salads! Heck, you could even ask the employees about me!
 My daughter is 3 years old&amp;wanted to go to eat at the &quot;Dino resturant&quot;, better known as Runza... 
My daughter is 3 years old&amp;wanted to go to eat at the &quot;Dino resturant&quot;, better known as Runza. After the last visit to the David City, NE location, not only did she say she loved the &quot;bunny salads&quot; (the side salad), but for the last few weeks since, she will stand by our coffee table, wait on &quot;her customers&quot;&amp;turn around to face our couch, &quot;her Runza kitchen,&quot;&amp;talk into her microphione to call back the orders! It is so cute to have a positve experience&amp;her remember such great customer service! Not only does the David City location make good salads, but also great impressions on the younger customers!
 I was so excited when we finally moved to a town that had a Runza! 
I was so excited when we finally moved to a town that had a Runza! I just love the home-cooked taste of your Runza and Hamburgers, fries, and onion rings. We always go to Runza when we&apos;re out of town for a sporting event for one of our children. The first night after we moved to Broken Bow, Nebraska, we went to Runza for supper. It was a very friendly place and delicious food. We&apos;ve discovered that the owners, Kevin and Joyce Richardson, are members of our church, and are great supporters of this whole community. We visit the local Runza often and always enjoy the food.
 Small Town Senior Lady Learns Lesson from the Start... 
Small Town Senior Lady Learns Lesson from the Start. A &quot;what&quot; I asked? Me being from a small midwest town and not knowing about &quot;Runza&quot;....I thought I was too old and yes too set in my ways to learn something new, even when people were going in to the Runza restaurant....Okay, I will try &quot;this place&quot; since I seemed to be the only one missing out. I turned in and am I glad that I did!!! I went inside and was waited on by friendly service people (a bonus, compared to a lot of other places). It was a very clean place and then I ordered....Service was great!!! But the added bonus was the food was great!!! Not too high priced and guess what.....I have told others about &quot;the Place&quot;....Now I know what Runzas are plus all the other things on the menu...(good variety). Moral of the story----Don&apos;t be afraid to try something new so you can have a fuller life...
 My son, Brandon who is originally from Nebraska... 
My son, Brandon who is originally from Nebraska married a Missouri gal who never tasted or even heard of a Runza. Brandon drove to a Runza and convinced Erin to try one. After one bite she was hooked! That was six years ago and everytime they come back to visit she has to stop at a Runza (they currently live in Minnesota). This past Christmas I won the mother-in-law award when I served mini Runzas for our Christmas celebration. My two other children, one being my daughter who is also married to a Missourian) were very impressed that I splurged to buy Runzas as I enjoy cooking and believe I get more bang for my buck if I make the food myself! However, to continue to &quot;win over&quot; the &quot;in-laws&quot; I&apos;ve come to the realization that &quot;Runza&apos;s are Home made cooking&quot; and mini Runza&apos;s will continue to be on the holiday menu! Most likely more than just the Christmas holiday! Nancy
 As a lifelong Nebraskan, the move to South Dakota took some adjusting... 
As a lifelong Nebraskan, the move to South Dakota took some adjusting. Mostly as there is not a Runza anywhere close! Of course, then no one had even heard of a Runza. So during one trip home, I picked up some frozen Runzas. &quot;Oh, those are sooo Good!&quot; So the next trip I picked up some more and they were shared with more people. So of course, the next trip required more. And now it is just a standing order when I go home to not return without more Runzas. Knowing I am bringing a taste of home back with me to share with friends, makes the 5 hour drive so much more enjoyable. Besides, when I stop to get the Runzas, It is always time for a great Ice Cream cone. Thanks for a Great Tasting menu to share with new friends.
 I drive 50 miles from my small town to the closest city that has a Runza... 
I drive 50 miles from my small town to the closest city that has a Runza to purchase one of my favorite Runza entrees.....a cheeseburger and order of french fries. I tell everyone I know it&apos;s because the meat is always so fresh tasting and the french fries are always hot and done to a perfect crisp. I&apos;ve never once had a bad meal at Runza, which is not always true of other fast food places I&apos;ve been. Thank you Runza for your consistency.
 My most memorable experience is every time I eat at the Runza... 
My most memorable experience is every time I eat at the Runza in Gothenburg, Nebraska. My wife and I are partial to the superb potato bacon soup, but now and again we also order a hamburger -- the best in town in our estimation -- and now that the fish sandwich is again available, I order that (minus the cheese, however) every time. All in all we have never had a bad experience at Runza and the prices are very easy on our pocketbook, a vital item in today&apos;s economy. Thanks Runza, we&apos;ll be back again and again. Tot and Pearlie
 We just love the homey feeling when we go to Runza... 
We just love the homey feeling when we go to Runza after a family shopping trip. They always have what we are hungury for any time of year. You know their food will always be good, we never have had a bad experience and the staff are always friendly.
 While pregnant with my 5th child I got a massive craving for some Tasty Runzas... 
While pregnant with my 5th child I got a massive craving for some Tasty Runzas. I had my husband drive for 40 minutes ONE WAY to the nearest Runza in Ogallala, Nebraska to get me some. Later the same night the craving started again so once again off he went on his long journey to bring me some more Runza. When he had arrived back home I was sleeping of course. The next morning I asked where the Runza was. He had eaten it. I was a little emotional about this, so off he went again to get me Runza. HAHAHAHA Hope I win the Gift card!! MMMMMM Runza!!
 Runza is one reason we chose North Platte to retire in... 
Runza is one reason we chose North Platte to retire in. Clean dining, courteous and knowlegable help.
 I am a Runzatic!! 
I am a Runzatic!! My husband and I moved to Arizona in 1998. I come home 2-3 times a year and the 1st thing I do after leaving the airport is get a Runza!! Sometimes the last thing I do too!! I even offered to open a franchise here!! Many times I bring the frozen ones home also. I know you&apos;ve heard this story many times before and its not very original, but I really really miss my Runza&apos;s!!! You rock!!
 I&apos;m a native Nebraskan and moved to California 9 years ago... 
I&apos;m a native Nebraskan and moved to California 9 years ago. The last time I had a Runza was 3 years ago when I visited family. We are going back to Nebraska this July and the Very first meal is going to be a RUNZA!! I can&apos;t wait! I miss having them so much! My husband is from Virginia, and I told him all about Runza and he&apos;s like Run-wha??? I tried to explain it to him and I said.. you&apos;ll just need to taste it for yourself! I&apos;m almost more excited about getting to have a Runza than visiting family!! hahaha... Almost :D
 I go to school in Seward, Nebraska for two reasons: Runza and Runza! 
I go to school in Seward, Nebraska for two reasons: Runza and Runza! My closest college friends and I make a trip to Runza at least twice a week to enjoy the incredible chicken strips, corn dogs, hamburgers, onion rings, fries, and of course the Runzas!! When we leave for the summer life seems to come to halt because we are without Runza for over three months. This last summer we all missed Runza so much that we met back in Seward for a savory lunch date to enjoy our favorite food and all traveled from three different states just to enjoy Runza! Saying we are Runzatics may be the understatement of the year!
 As we were moving my niece on last Wednesday my husband decided to pick us up some food from Runza... 
As we were moving my niece on last Wednesday my husband decided to pick us up some food from Runza which is right by my workplace. This would save time and we enjoy the food. When we didn&apos;t finish all that needed to be done on Wednesday we did the same thing Thursday night also--ate at Runza. Then all of my family was in town for a celebration for my mom&apos;s birthday. The girls took dad out for supper on Friday and guess where he wanted to eat...Yup Runza. Then the following Tuesday I took my sister out for lunch and guess where we went ... and again may I say Runza. So this story ends like this not only do my husband and I enjoy Runza but my whole family does. I ended up eating there 4 times in less than a week.
 My friends and I are involved in our high school&apos;s pep band... 
My friends and I are involved in our high school&apos;s pep band. One time, we made a quick stop into Runza before a basketball game and ordered five medium fries to go (we&apos;re huge fans of those)! We took them up to the stands with us to eat, but the smell of fresh fries was so over-powering that soon others were crowding around to try to get some of their own!! We sat there eating fries just like one would eat popcorn. What can I say? We&apos;re Runzatics.
 When I was little we used to go out to Pioneer Park, on the way home we would stop to get a Runza... 
When I was little we used to go out to Pioneer Park, on the way home we would stop to get a Runza. That was when there was only one Runza, with only one Runza! Then the second Runza opened on 56th Street off of Holdrege. We went there in High School, there were carhops and they were dressed in Leiderhausen. For Real! When I was pregnant I always had to drive through Runza for a milk shake. (YUM) I guess I kind of grew up with Runza. I&apos;d hate to think of how many I&apos;ve eaten over all these years! I live in Gering now and still get the great Runza taste whenever I want it! Thanks good buddy! I love ya!!
 In 1983 I went to my first Nebraska Football game... 
In 1983 I went to my first Nebraska Football game. I was so excited to see the big time players I had watched for years on TV. It was a boys day out, just me and my dad. After our huskers beat up on an overmatched Kansas State team we left the stadium and headed back home. Dad stopped at a little place I had never been and we went in I found us a table and he went to order dinner. He brought me back this thing that I had never seen before. At first glance, it looked like a small loaf of bread, I was starving so I dug into my fries immediately, being 7 I was very leary of trying unfamiliar food. Finally, my fries were gone and I was still hungry, Dad tried to explain to me what a Runza was, but I wasn&apos;t hearing it. It was new, it was wierd, and it wasn&apos;t a burger. So after about 10 minutes of sitting there, my strange alien food getting cold, I broke down. I picked up this oblong mystery and took a small bite. The bread was good, I took another small bite. Finally, on my third small bite, I experienced a taste that I haven&apos;t seen matched to this day. I immediately fell in love with Runza. Dad and I stopped there together for the next 12 years after every Nebraska game. I went off to college in Arizona. Dad passed away 6 years ago. I&apos;m back in the Omaha area, and now, every Nebraska football Saturday, I take my two boys to Runza after the game.
 I love Runza, more specifically Runza&apos;s chili... 
I love Runza, more specifically Runza&apos;s chili, no one elses can compare. I purchased it almost every day this winter so much so that the employees in the drive thru window got to know me by name and reminded me this last week that the15th was the last day it would be available this season.
 We love and appreciate Runza because they use real ground beef... 
We love and appreciate Runza because they use real ground beef. So if you want a good hamburger you go to Runza everytime. We feed cattle and appreciate good beef. We do not go anywhere else for a great hamburger. Runza is always very clean too and we really appreciate that a lot.
 I have enjoyed eating Runzas for over 50 years... 
I have enjoyed eating Runzas for over 50 years! I grew up in central Kansas with a German background - my Grandmother made them when I was very young. Since then, my Grandmother has passed away and I moved to Colorado thinking that I would never have another Runza. But, I then discovered your restaurant. And now - my hunger for Runzas has been once again fulfilled. No better place in Colorado for a great lunch!
 My story is short and sweet, because that is what Runza is to me... 
My story is short and sweet, because that is what Runza is to me. First I can leave my door and be at Runza in about a 2 block walk, that&apos;s whats short about it. Just was there yesterday and used a coupon, (which I love coupons) and got the&quot; bestest&quot; hamburger I&apos;d ever had. Hamburger was so thick, everything on it, WOW. I use every coupon I can get my hands on. The ice cream is even as good as what I make here at home. Now that is saying a lot, honestly, I&apos;m known for the good homemade ice cream I make. That&apos;s whats sweet about it. We are so pleased to have a Runza in Clarinda, one of the best little towns in Southwest Iowa. Evelyn
 While studying abroad in Ghana... 
While studying abroad in Ghana, I was rooming with a girl from North Dakota. Just minutes after meeting, I discovered her love for Runza.(Because she knew that Nebraska is the only place to satisfy her cravings.) But being a Lincolnite myself, I have long taken for granted the great gift that is Runza. When we returned to the States she pestered and pestered me, along with her entire family in North Dakota, to hand deliver some fresh Runzas to them. So months later, I took a night off work to take my quite unreliable car all the way to Fargo, deliver two bags full of Runzas, and drive back home almost immediately. Was it worth it? Duh. I love me some Runzas. And I was so happy to deliver some (fairly fresh) goodness to our Northern friends.
 Hello, my name is Michael... and I&apos;m a Runzatic... 
Hello, my name is Michael... and I&apos;m a Runzatic. I live in New York City, just a few blocks from Times Square. My girlfriend lives in Lincoln,Nebraska, just a few blocks from Runza. At home, I have every type of food available to me at my doorstep, much of it 24 hours a day. And yet... I crave Runza. It&apos;s something about their commitment to real food, made fresh. I guess it&apos;s true... little differences really do make a big difference! My girlfriend thinks I come to Nebraska just to see her. Please don&apos;t tell her I have another love.
 I&apos;m retired from a college, and I stay in touch with alumni... 
I&apos;m retired from a college, and I stay in touch with alumni who were friends through Facebook. I&apos;ve noticed that over and over, if they don&apos;t live where they can buy Runza, they comment on how much they miss it and how they love Runza. Some of them even write that when they visit back home, they bring a cooler so they can buy Runzas to freeze and take back with them. Whenever I read one of those postings, I get hungry for Runza, so run right out to my nearest Runza for lunch!
 My name is Michael. I love my Runza Mushroom and Swiss Hamburger... 
My name is Michael. I love my Runza Mushroom and Swiss Hamburger. On special days, I enjoy it as a double. The other day I was enticed by another hamburger patron. I stopped. I looked. I considered. Who would know? Being fully aware of the potential for relapse &quot;to the other guys&quot;, and yet being hungry, I ate one. I had heard of the delightful taste; the flavor, that would keep one coming back for just one more sampling. I felt deceived! Zagat had failed me. I left the restaurant with a heavy heart and the realization that what I really, truly wanted and needed was my Runza Hamburger!! Please forgive my wandering ways. I have returned to the place that is my Eden.
 I had lived in NE for 10 years and only once in a while would I go out to eat fast food ... 
I had lived in NE for 10 years and only once in a while would I go out to eat fast food and some of those occasions would be at Runza. However after those 10 years my husband got a job out of state and we moved somewhere that did not have Runza anymore. I found that in the time we lived out of state I would crave it more and more and was so sad that I couldn&apos;t get it. Well, we ended up moving back to Lincoln back in 2005 and since the WEEK we moved back I have been coming to eat Runza at least once every week or two. I never again will take for granted how yummy your food is, how great of quality it is for a fast food establishment and how much I missed not being able to have it. I have friends who have also moved out of state say the same thing.....they don&apos;t realize how much they MISS Runza until it&apos;s gone. What a GREAT compliment for Runza to know that their &quot;Runzatics&quot; truly appreciate the food and service that your company provides and miss it terribly when they can&apos;t have it. Once you try it, you love it and once you love it you can never seem to get enough. :) Thanks Runza!!!!
 My fiance and I don&apos;t live in the same town so it is really hard for us to see each other... 
My fiance and I don&apos;t live in the same town so it is really hard for us to see each other. So while we were dating we came up with the Runza date. We would both drive to our nearby Runza and order our food. We would then take it back to our places and eat it while talking on the webcam. This was our was of going on a &quot;date&quot; while we are far away. Thanks Runza!
 Before I lived in Nebraska, I used to come here several times a year to camp and watch wildlife... 
Before I lived in Nebraska, I used to come here several times a year to camp and watch wildlife. I cooked most of my meals on a camping stove, but I also planned my trips around Runza locations such as Kearney (near the Sandhill Crane migration), Beatrice (near the Prairie Chicken lek at Burchard Lake) and Blair (near the Snow Geese migration at DeSoto National Wildlife Refuge). There is no better meal after a chilly spring or fall Nebraska day than a Runza!
 I grew up in rural Nebraska faithfully eating Runzas... 
I grew up in rural Nebraska faithfully eating Runzas on trips to Hastings and kept up my love of Runza while attending the University of Nebraska - Lincoln by visiting the Cornhusker Highway location. But then something tragic happened; I moved to Kansas City after graduating in 2000. No more Runza. Yes, yes, there is one in Lawrence, but it&apos;s not the same. I would fill my Runza craving (I prefer the cheese Runza, crinkle fries, and Mt. Dew -- actually, I&apos;ve never ordered anything other than this selection in my life) by stocking up during trips back to Nebraska. One trip specifically comes to mind. On the way back to Kansas City after leaving Fairfield, we stopped at a Runza in Hebron (it was attached to a gas station on Highway 81 and sadly is not there anymore). I ordered a bag of 6 Runzas. The lady thought I was crazy! We drove the rest of the way back to KC with the car filled with that delicious Runza smell. I popped them in the freezer when we got home and enjoyed them for weeks to come. You can imagine my delight to find out that a new Runza location is opening in Mission, Kansas only one mile from my work! I am couting down the days until I can order the cheese Runza, crinkle fries, and Mt. Dew again.
 I met my husband at Runza. We both worked at the Runza on 56th&amp;Holdrege in the late 90&apos;s... 
I met my husband at Runza. We both worked at the Runza on 56th&amp;Holdrege in the late 90&apos;s. He asked me out for our first date in&apos;97. Two years later in March of 1999 we had both started new jobs and with our busy schedules hadn&apos;t spent much time together so we had a date night planned. Little did I know what my then boyfriend had been up to that day. He had talked to one of his co-workers, put up a special sign on the marquis, went and bought a ring, and had our mother&apos;s waiting there. We pull into Runza and I see the sign that says, &quot;Carrie will you marry me?&quot; and instantly start crying. I barely get inside the door and he has the ring out and asking me my answer. We even made it on the news that night on 10/11. The news anchor said after our video clip, &quot;I wonder if the ring was inside the Runza?&quot; How is that for Hall of Fame? :) How many couples do you know get engaged at Runza. lol Obviously I said yes, and we have been married 11 years. Our kids love eating at this Runza and we have to tell them again about how we met and the proposal.
 My grandma&amp;I were going shopping when we passed by Runza... 
My grandma&amp;I were going shopping when we passed by Runza. I said, &quot;Let&apos;s go there!&quot; And my grandma said she had never been there in her entire life! I couldn&apos;t believe it! So I took my grandma to Runza,&amp;she loved it so much, that Runza is now her favorite restraunt. My name is Alexis,&amp;me&amp;my grandma are Runzatics.
 Runza just rules....Fresh beef... amazing chicken.....onion rings that are homemade and fresh... 
Runza just rules....Fresh beef... amazing chicken.....onion rings that are homemade and fresh...Miller and Paine cinnamon rolls and chilli like mom used to make...I&apos;m getting hungry...I&apos;m going now!!!!
 I was traveling for my job when my last stop was Clarinda, Iowa... 
I was traveling for my job when my last stop was Clarinda, Iowa. I had been on the road for 3 days eating out all meals. Then I saw a restaurant called Runza. Deceided that would be where I would go for lunch. Had a great Cheese Burger and fries and of course a cookie. Was sooooo good. Then I went there for supper again. Only this time I had cheese burger again and fries and then chili. My the chili had more meat than beans in it. Was sooo good again. Had to stay over and work on Saturday. Going to eat again before I left town but I was too early and they were not open yet. I wanted to try a Runza but not sure if I would like it so thought I would wait for a coupon in case I did not like it. When I asked people about the Runza I had pros and cons. Only bad thing about the restaurant there are only two in Iowa but I go to Omaha at least once a month and then my travels working may take me to a town where there is a Runza and that would make me happy. Have been doing my work for 16 years now and that cheeseburger was the BEST
 Having grown up in Nebraska, I&apos;ve been familiar with Runzas for quite some time... 
Having grown up in Nebraska, I&apos;ve been familiar with Runzas for quite some time. A few years ago I was living in Seattle and convinced my best west coast friend to fly to Nebraska with me for July 4th. While there, I introduced her to Runzas and she&apos;s been in love ever since. Every time I go back to NE I always get a Runza, take a quick photo of it and send it off to her. She is always VERY jealous but is a long distance Runza fan for life!!
 My father started me eating Runza when I was just a kid... 
My father started me eating Runza when I was just a kid. I can remember my first taste clear as day, it was a Husker football game in Lincoln and my dad took me to his favorite place to eat. I was the pickiest eater ever known, somehow I fell in love with the onion rings and dip that day. Now, at 31, my dad and I still are eating at Runza a minimum of 3 times a week. Whenever my wife is working or my dad has to fend for himself, we instinctively head to the runza closest to us. The taste always takes me back to my first meal. Whenever I &quot;forget&quot; my packed meal at home, Runza is there for my lunch or dinner! Thanks for keeping the tradition that my family fell in love with since the beginning! Kraus
 As soon as I was old enough to work I applied at Runza... 
As soon as I was old enough to work I applied at Runza. I worked there through most of high school and then when I went off to college I worked at another Runza. Great place to work. You can be proud of what you serve and how it is prepared. Not only is it a great place to work, but my absolutely favorite place to eat. Believe me if you work there and still want to eat there all the time that is telling you something.
 My wife and I love eating at your store in Lawrence, KS... 
My wife and I love eating at your store in Lawrence, KS. I like your hamburgers and my wife likes your Runza. But I work close to your location so it is easy for me to stop in more often. I also sell vehicles, and on test drives with customers, I frequently ask them if they have eaten their and tell them how much my wife and I like eating there.
 I&apos;ve actually hit 3 Runza resturants on a single trip from Lincoln, NE to Fremont, NE... 
I&apos;ve actually hit 3 Runza resturants on a single trip from Lincoln, NE to Fremont, NE to fulfill my lust for the famous fresh home made onion rings. Wahoo was the middle stop, I exceeded the speed limit to reach there before I went into withdrawls. Man, they are delicious, and they can&apos;t be bad for ya cause they are a vegatable, right!? OK, I think I may have a problem. I need to install red lights and a siren to get there faster!! Signed, distressed Malcolm in the middle.
 Sometimes I look for excuses to drive the 15 miles into town just to... 
Sometimes I look for excuses to drive the 15 miles into town just to enjoy that swiss mushroom burger. Sometimes there is no excuse, I just want it !
 My husband and I met while attending Kansas State University in Manhattan, KS... 
My husband and I met while attending Kansas State University in Manhattan, KS. He is from Omaha and introduced me to the Runza on one of our visits. Several years after we were married, I became pregnant. I couldn&apos;t sleep very well and had a habit of waking up very early in the mornings. On this particular Saturday morning I woke him up and told him that I really wanted a Runza. He shook his head and said, &quot;Do you know how far we have to go to get one?&quot; I assured him that I did know. Again he shook his head and said, &quot;Ok, let&apos;s go. I guess we can make a quick visit to my folks&quot;. The trip is about 194 miles, but I had to have a Runza and nothing else would have satisfied my craving.
 Our whole family LOVES Runza... 
Our whole family LOVES Runza. The kids just had Spring Break last week and that is where they picked to go out to eat. They love eating in and having refills of the wonderful slushies. Of course they love mixing the kinds of slushies. The food is always hot and delicious and you have the BEST fries in town!!!
 I love Runza because every time I bite into one of their fries they&apos;re crisp, warm... 
I love Runza because every time I bite into one of their fries they&apos;re crisp, warm, and I can&apos;t get enough of them. They also make my most favorite sandwhich just right, the swiss mushroom burger...makes my mouth water just typing about it. Runza&apos;s service is always up to par or beyond and their food is always fresh. :)
 Living in Indianapolis makes it difficult for Nebraskans to enjoy Runza&apos;s regularly... 
Living in Indianapolis makes it difficult for Nebraskans to enjoy Runza&apos;s regularly. Our local alumni chapter, Hoosiers for Huskers, decided to hold a Taste of Nebraska pitch in for our Founder&apos;s Day Celebration this year. Since I travel regularly to Lincoln I was tapped the &quot;Runza Guy&quot; and my mission was to get 55 Runzas back to Indianapolis any way I could. Well I called the Runza hotline and they directed me to Matt at the 33rd and Pioneers Runza shop. Matt gave me a great deal on 55 frozen runzas and the shipping store, Goin Coastal was just across the street. I had to get a cooler and about 14 lbs of dry ice but I can tell you there were 55 happy Huskers in Indianapolis on Founder&apos;s Day. We even had former Husker Coach Gene Huey there to share some old Husker stories. Thanks to Matt at the Runza shop and Chuck at the Goin Postal shipping store for all their help in creating this experience for some hungry Runza fans.
 It&apos;s pretty simple...my wife and I both trust and like Runza... 
It&apos;s pretty simple...my wife and I both trust and like Runza, especially Runza&apos;s burgers, onion rings, sweet berry chicken salad, and chili. So wherever we go in Omaha or travel in Runza states we look for Runza locations. They are always dependable and good.
 I moved to Virginia a few years back and I miss me some Runza like crazy!!! 
I moved to Virginia a few years back and I miss me some Runza like crazy!!! I used to eat there at least 3 to 4 days a week. I&apos;ve always had my favorites such as the soup which I dip the onion rings or fries in, the smothered chicken sandwich, a hamburger with some jalepeno ranch on it, and of course the cheese RUNZA!!! Every time I go home I eat Runza almost everyday! But the most important part... I buy and pack Runzas and bring home with me. There&apos;s nothing like walking into a Runza and ordering about 50 to 100 frozen Runzas! It tends to confuse TSA quite a bit when they are opening your bag to find frozen Runzas.... I refused to turn them over so I missed my flight and had to fly standby the rest of the day. (They eventually let me thru with them.) Oh silly TSA agent was new to Nebraska... I&apos;m sure he&apos;s well educated on the wonders that is Runza. In the end it was worth it because as I study for exams a warm Runza guarantees me what I need to pass!
 One night our roommate came home from work with Runza for dinner... 
One night our roommate came home from work with Runza for dinner. After 10 minutes of smelling Runza and watching him eat it, my sister asked if I wanted to go to Runza with her. Trying to save money, I declined. As soon as she walked in the door with fries and an original Runza sandwich I couldn&apos;t resist anymore and left to get my own. Now when someone comes home with Runza, it always sets off a chain reaction!
 I&apos;m Patrick, origanally from Burchard, Nebraska. But I am currently serving in the marine corps... 
I&apos;m Patrick, origanally from Burchard, Nebraska. But I am currently serving in the marine corps stationed in Jacksonville, NC. Any time I come back home, my first stop is Runza for a cheese Runza and a Fring. My mother would rather she be my first stop but boy I cant resist good ole cooking like runza. Thanks.
 There are very few hamburgers that I can eat from fast food restaurants... 
There are very few hamburgers that I can eat from fast food restaurants. Most chains have tiny hamburgers that don&apos;t even taste like hamburger. Runza&apos;s hamburgers are the BEST. They are big and juicy and well worth it. I hate going on vacation with the family and not having a Runza chain in other states. My kids like the Chicken and frings and the ice cream cones they get with kids meals. I also am a big fan of the Runza sandwhich. There is nothing in the world like it. So good! I love Runza and so does my ENTIRE family. My dad who has since passed away loved Runza too. I think of him everytime I eat there! Just writing this email is making me hungry for some RUNZAS!!!!
 I have been truck&apos;n for quite some time now... 
I have been truck&apos;n for quite some time now and have been numerous places throughout the United States. When people ask me what my favorite state to drive though is, I always say Nebraska. They ask why? The scenery, the people, the wildlife? They laugh when I say Runza. I love Runza, can&apos;t get enough of it! Even my yellow lab road companion gets excited when I make a stop for Runza. I have always scheduled my stops in Nebraska around Runza and will continue to in the future. I just wish I could fit my semi through the drive through! Keep up the good work Runza! - Bubba
 I worked for the Original Runza Place on West Van Dorn back in the 60&apos;s... 
I worked for the Original Runza Place on West Van Dorn back in the 60&apos;s. I was 14 and have always loved Runza&apos;s. I came from a German family and runza&apos;s were made by all family members. For me, it is so much easier to just go to Runza and buy&amp;eat them. Runza onion rings and fries are the best in town along of course with their Runza&apos;s. We frequent Runza a lot as our Grandsons also love Runza. When asked where they want to eat, they always say Runza!! We have out of state relatives that, when they come to Lincoln, want to eat Runza. We have also had to freeze and mail them some. We all love them - keep up the good work.
 As part of my job, I train people from all over the country... 
As part of my job, I train people from all over the country. While here, I am also responsible for feeding the group lunch and dinner. I collect a very impressive list of restaurants and give my opinion to the group. While they have great things to say about the fancy (and expensive) restaurants we go to, they are always really excited about a Runza lunch. Most of the folks have never had a Runza, (I usually tell them that it is &quot;the meal in a bunza!) so of course it is my top choice for lunch during the training sessions. Some of the groups have asked to go back over and over and those who make the trip more than once, ask for a return visit. I couldn&apos;t be happier, because I get to go eat with them!
 The closest Runza to where I live is 2 hours away... 
The closest Runza to where I live is 2 hours away in Loveland Colorado. Some of my favorite memories involve getting some girlfriends together in the car, getting overpriced lattes for the road, blasting the stereo with the windows down and driving across the state for a Runza. As a bonus, if I manage to remember to call ahead I can bring frozen ones home and savor them slowly and deliberately like a dying man in the desert savors the last droplets of water in an empty canteen.
 Growing up in South Omaha, I used to have to babysit for my little brother all summer... 
Growing up in South Omaha, I used to have to babysit for my little brother all summer. We had a Runza less than a mile from our house, off 25th&amp;Chandler Road. My mother was brilliant! She made us a deal, if we got all our chores done and there were no terrible fights during the week, on Friday&apos;s she would leave us money to walk to Runza Hut for lunch! We always saw lots of our friends there and it was the highlight of our week! The only thing that got me through the late 70&apos;s! When I moved from Nebraska to Colorado in 2009 - I made sure there was a Runza within a mile of my new home and all is right with the world!
 I have many experiences I could write about... 
I have many experiences I could write about - so don&apos;t know where to start. I helped open the Grand Island store on Webb Road - and worked there for several years- and loved it!!! - Anyway, we would make the Runza&apos;s (didn&apos;t know what they were when I started working there) and over the noon hour I would run the Drive-thru. Don would come out from Lincoln and we wouldn&apos;t know he was there. He would sit at the Pizza Hut next door and time us from when customers would drive in and when they would drive out with their orders. After the noon rush, he would walk in the back door and surprise us - and we usually did a very good job - so he was satisified!!. My husband and I have been going there every Tuesday for Temp. Tues. That&apos;s one place our daughter from California always wants to go when she and her family get back here - and our 2 families in Texas had to take some back with them. They got very used to having them when they were home and Mom worked there. Just fun years!!!!
 You know when you get that craving for something special... 
You know when you get that craving for something special - you just have to have a &quot;Swiss Mushroom Runza Hamburger&quot;. I was first introduced to them in Lincoln in 1989. I have craved them ever since.
 Runza has the BEST french fries in the world! 
Runza has the BEST french fries in the world! They are always hot and crisp, I love them! Runza&apos;s are such a unique sandwich, you can&apos;t go to any other fast food restaurant and get a sandwich like a Runza...they are just great! My family has always loved Runza, in fact my uncle, who grew up in Nebraska, moved to Arizona and my grandparents buy Runzas and freeze them and ship them to him in Arizona, or when he comes to visit he eats Runza the whole time he is here! LOVE THEM!
 A few years ago, my daughter, my bff and I took a road trip... 
A few years ago, my daughter, my bff and I took a road trip from Omaha to Kansas City to meet up with my bff&apos;s daughter who was flying in from Atlanta, GA. She wanted us to meet her with Runza&apos;s. So we bought several Runza&apos;s in Omaha and drove to KC. She was delighted to get her long missed Runza&apos;s. So delighted she decided to take more vacation time and ride home with us to Omaha&amp;fly out from there. The first thing we did when pulling in to Omaha was find a Runza. We had a great trip and a great ending to the trip. We are all Runzatic&apos;s and couldn&apos;t imagine living in an area without a Runza Restaurant nearby.
 I have lived in Lincoln all 25 years of my life... 
I have lived in Lincoln all 25 years of my life... and I must say I am a Runza fan!!! Any time my husband and I decide to get fast food... my vote is always Runza!!!! (and I always win!!!) Growing up, my family had a tradition of going to Runza, what seemed like every Sunday for lunch. One of my fondest memories of Runza is when my family and I got back from a month long trip overseas to Southeast Asia... and after one whole month with no Runza.... as soon as we landed we were headed to get our Runza fix!!!! It was the best tasting Runza I had ever had!!!!! I inhaled it in moments!!!! I am pretty sure we ate Runza&apos;s for weeks straight after that! :)
 In 2008, I moved from Iowa leaving friends and family behind... 
In 2008, I moved from Iowa leaving friends and family behind. I was prepared and dealt with it but nothing prepared me for the yearning and desire I felt for a Mushroom Swiss Runza. How can Texas call themselves a state and not have a Runza&apos;s? I just relocated back to Nebraska and within 72 hours have eaten at Runza&apos;s 4 times. You can make new friends, you can Skype your Family, but NOTHING replaces a Runza!
 I lived in Minnesota for over 6 years, and had to move back to Nebraska... 
I lived in Minnesota for over 6 years, and had to move back to Nebraska when I couldn&apos;t stand it any longer. I HAD to have my Cheese Runza&apos;s, and coming back to Nebraska once a year wasn&apos;t enough. I just can&apos;t live without Runza!
 I&apos;m here to tell you... those &quot;copycat&quot; recipes that say they are just like the real thing... THEY LIE! 
I&apos;m here to tell you... those &quot;copycat&quot; recipes that say they are just like the real thing... THEY LIE! I grew up in Omaha, but moved to Texas in 1990, where there are NO Runzas (guess I should have looked into that before I moved!). I met my husband in Texas and, on his first trip to Nebraska with me, I introduced him to Runzas and he was was immediately HOOKED! He didn&apos;t stop talking about them for what seemed like forever. Finally, my brother sent him a box of frozen Runzas for his Christmas gift! Note that I didn&apos;t receive a gift... except to see my husband&apos;s smiling face... ear to ear! Whenever I go to Nebraska, I have to make sure to pack an extra bag so I can bring back some Runzas on the plane with me. But that can be an expensive meal, so I decided to try one of those copycat recipes. Granted, they were good, but there is no comparison to a GENUINE Runza! They have a special magic touch that just makes your mouth water thinking about it... like mine is now! Thanks, Runza, for giving us such a fabulous treat! ( If I win a $25 gift card, mail order Runzas, here I come! :o) )
 Our most memorable Runza experience happened just this week... 
Our most memorable Runza experience happened just this week, when we left in a snowstorm to drive 18 miles to the nearest Runza. We were all craving Runza and were stupid enough to go out in the terrible weather to get some. We got our Runza, and thoroughly enjoyed it, and on our way home, ended up in the ditch with a totaled vehicle. Boy, Runza was good that day!! =) Runza will forever be in our minds because of that experience that we&apos;ll never forget!!!
 My husband and I discovered Runza while attending UNL... 
My husband and I discovered Runza while attending UNL in Lincoln Nebraska. From the first bite we were hooked. The swiss cheese mushroom runza combined with a large ring and drink are our standard orders. It is fast food that tastes like homemade! We appreciate the friendly workers and the quick service too!
 I love Runza and its amazing french fries and ranch dressing... 
I love Runza and its amazing french fries and ranch dressing. My fiance was not the biggest fan of Runza until I kept insisting that was the only place I wanted to eat, so we&apos;d grab Runza for dinner. Now he&apos;s currently working in Pennsylvania and he&apos;s told me that all he craves a Runza burger! I knew I could convert him to amazing food!
 My wife worked for Runza for 2 years while we were in college... 
My wife worked for Runza for 2 years while we were in college. I grew up in Iowa and never really ate at Runza much because we didn&apos;t have a Runza near by. She worked there almost every day and would come home and tell me how impressed she was to see how everything really was homemade. Even the salads were put together by hand! I ate there often and really loved trying all of their seasonal Runza sandwiches. We still eat at Runza all of the time and thankfully we have one right down the street. When we have out of town guests visit us, we ALWAYS recommend Runza as a place they have to eat while they are in town, it is the best fast food you can get!! So far, no one has dissagreed with us :)
 Southwest Chicken Salad, Large Ice Tea Extra Lemon... 
Southwest Chicken Salad, Large Ice Tea Extra Lemon....a MUST everyday lunch during the summer! Can&apos;t get enough of the good stuff :)
 I love Runzas. I like the bread especially... 
I love Runzas. I like the bread especially. My family eats at Runza the most out of all the other fast food restaurants. I usually have your tasty onion rings with my Runza sandwich. Thank you.
 My boys, age 12&amp;10, love the Runza on 132nd&amp;Center in Omaha... 
My boys, age 12&amp;10, love the Runza on 132nd&amp;Center in Omaha. Every Thursday afternoon we have about an hour after school before our next activity starts. It seems silly to go all the way home and turn around and come right back to the same area. So 9 times out of 10 when I ask the kids where they want to go for their afternoon snack they say R-U-N-Z-A. Snack usually turns into a meal but it&apos;s worth every bite. We are always greeted by friendly faces who recognize us and usually know what we&apos;re going to order. But of course we throw them for a loop by ordering something else once in a while. Because it&apos;s not a particularly busy time of day we spread out at two tables and while the boys eat they do their homework, sing, or play games for 45 minutes before we have to move on. Thank you Runza for not only being such a wonderful place to eat but also for having such a family friendly atmosphere where this mom and two boys always feel welcome.
 I don&apos;t know if I really have a story, but I fell in love with Runza... 
I don&apos;t know if I really have a story, but I fell in love with Runza when they first hit Omaha. My husband&amp;I have 6 children.  They are all grown now with their own children. When our children were young, every Wed. was my husbands pay day so off to Runza we went. To tell you the truth I love your cheeseburgers&amp;fries. If someone suggests going out for burgers, it&apos;s &quot;Runza.&quot; I can not eat other burgers. I do have to give in from time to time. I do like the Runzas but I feel I am missing out if I don&apos;t get my usual. Now I take my grandkids to Runza&amp;I loaded all 10 up with gift cards for their Christmas Stockings~they seemed pretty pleased. My most memorable Runza experience was when we ate as a family at Runza all those years.
 My Mother had had knee replacement surgery and was in the hospital for 2 weeks... 
My Mother had had knee replacement surgery and was in the hospital for 2 weeks. During that time, my husband would drive clear across town to bring me what I wanted most--a Runza Sweet Berry Chicken Salad! Yum! The three of us have them almost weekly! Thanks, Runza. Their other salads are good, too, as well as their hamburgers and Runzas.
 This a rather short story but it sums up how well I love Runza... 
This a rather short story but it sums up how well I love Runza. I have a terrific friend in Missouri, he had never heard of a runza before I took him two of each kind, now he begs me to bring him more all the time. If I know of someone that has never had a runza I am sure to make it happen for them, to enjoy an amazing food that I love myself.
 Hi! My name is Mikaela and I am 5 years old. Do you know what I like to eat at Runza? 
Hi! My name is Mikaela and I am 5 years old. Do you know what I like to eat at Runza? Chicken strips and fries. Do you know what I like to drink? I like fruit punch. My mom is a teacher. I like to go with her to work at her school on the weekends. My mom always takes me to Runza to get our lunches. I love eating my kids meal at school while I help my mom. My mom says she loves having Runza lunches with me at school. Runza is special to my mom and me.
 I love Runzas and had one at every Husker home game I went to during the late 90&apos;s... 
I love Runzas and had one at every Husker home game I went to during the late 90&apos;s.  The Huskers always won, so of course, I attributed the wins to my attending the games and eating a Runza. Everyone knew the Huskers would win if I ate a Runza. Well, we went to the Rose Bowl to play Miami and although 5000 Runzas were flown in, I didn&apos;t get there in time to get one. AND.... the Huskers lost that game!! All my friends and family blamed me for not eating a Runza!! I still eat Runzas every chance I get!!
 Native Nebraskans, we live in Loveland, CO so getting our Runza fix isn&apos;t too hard for us... 
Native Nebraskans, we live in Loveland, CO so getting our Runza fix isn&apos;t too hard for us. For our kids that’s a different story. We would often take frozen Runza&apos;s when we would visit our kids, our son Casey in Las Vegas&amp;daughter Emily in Nashville. Emily graduated from the University of Nebraska, and a couple years after graduation moved to Nashville, TN. Longing for the Huskers, she started a football watch party at one of the local bars. The games were fun to watch together, but there was something missing that everyone in this group of 20 to 30 hungered for. So, when we drove back at Thanksgiving last year we delivered 6 dozen frozen mini Runza&apos;s. They were a HUGE hit at the final game last year where about 80 Nebraskans showed up. Emily served the Runza&apos;s from the trunk of her car, since the bar wouldn&apos;t let her bring them in. Many people thanked her for bringing one of the best parts of the game to them! Emily moved the watch parties to another bar. There she had up to 145 people attend the Cornhusker football games. At Thanksgiving, we again drove to Nashville, and this time, in the back of our car was 14 DOZEN frozen regular sized Runza&apos;s. Emily recruited several of her neighbors to help bake&amp;she served Runza’s (inside the bar this year) to the loyal Nebraskans who were craving the taste all year. Even though it was not a successful Big 12 Championship game, the Runza&apos;s were! I wonder how many we&apos;ll have to take back next year?
 My most memorable Runza experience happened today... 
My most memorable Runza experience happened today during my first ever visit! I had been craving Runza since I smelt it from the fans in front of us at the Nebraska football game. Luckily, there is a Runza in Lawrence, Kansas! I hurried to Runza after my afternoon class and enjoyed the delicious number 1 combo and my oh my was it amazing. My mouth is watering just thinking of Runza and I can&apos;t wait to try them all! I am a Runzatic already!
 I&apos;m not sure if this is the best way to give this feedback, but here it goes... 
I&apos;m not sure if this is the best way to give this feedback, but here it goes. I just had the most amazing service from a young man at the 48th and O Street Runza in Lincoln, Nebraska. I realized when I pulled up to the window that I forgot to ask for my cheeseburger meal to have no cheese and only ketchup on the burger. I asked if I could change that when I got to the window and the young man said it was no problem. My food came out hot, fresh and according to my order, even though I messed up giving the right order the first time. I really appreciate good service. It seems so simple, yet it is hard to find. Thanks Runza! You made my day.
 I was born and grew up just south of Lincoln... 
I was born and grew up just south of Lincoln. Every chance we got to have Runza, we did. After college, I moved to Lake Tahoe, Nevada. During one of our trips back to Nebraska for the holidays, we decided to pick up several boxes of frozen Runzas for the people back in Nevada. Well, we left Lincoln that afternoon and it was just starting to snow. As we approached Grand Island, it was a full-blown blizzard. I had called the Runza in Gothenburg (we were trying to get there to spend the night with family) and told them I wanted their last two boxes of frozen Runzas. They said they were closing at 8pm due to the weather. I fought the blowing winds, ice-covered interstate, snow drifts, and cold for the final 100 miles. That 100 miles took nearly 4 hours. I made it to Runza in Gothenburg at 7:54. It was cold, my knuckles were white, but when I got my hands on those boxes of Runzas......my holidays were complete. Since that day, we&apos;ve moved back to the midwest (Kansas City) and every trip to Nebraska includes a DAILY stop at Runza. The best news of all? They are finally opening a Runza right here in Kansas City!!!! You can bet that I will be standing at the door the very first day they are open.
 My granddaughter just turned one... 
My granddaughter just turned one. It is so much fun as we were driving down the street she saw a Runza sign. She laughed and clapped then made anxious noises. So funny that she recognized the sign. To make a long story short we started given her Runza Crinkle fries at about 10 months old. She is hooked hooked hooked. My memory of Runza will be the many special trips that we pull in so she can enjoy more fries.
 The first time I had Runza I was amazed by the quality of their french fries... 
The first time I had Runza I was amazed by the quality of their french fries. It&apos;s a simple thing, but you can never get fries like that anywhere else. I started working there a few years later, and being on the inside only reaffirmed my high opinion of the franchise. I see how everything is cooked fresh, customers are treated with respect, and everyone does their part to uphold the Runza reputation. I have moved away since, but still get Runza whenever I can.
 I have been enjoying Runza food since the opening of the Scottsbluff location... 
I have been enjoying Runza food since the opening of the Scottsbluff location. The food is always of excellent quality and at a fair price. Served with the speed of a fast food restaurant but with a quality of home made (if we only had the time). It appeals to all ages with various tastes with something for everyone. Now that the Gering location has opened I have more options with both locations. The original Runza reminds me of food my grandmother and my mother once made. Keep up the great service and continue to grow throughout the community its great having Runza here in western Nebraska.
 My first job was at Runza. I loved the smell of fresh baking in the morning... 
My first job was at Runza. I loved the smell of fresh baking in the morning. To this day, I have no doubt that the freshest ingredients are used daily. I love Runza so much that when I lived in California, I would pack them on ice as my carry-on and bring them back for those who never experienced the delights of Runza.
 Well there was this time that I was broke and I wanted to take my boyfriend out for supper... 
Well there was this time that I was broke and I wanted to take my boyfriend out for supper. So I ended up selling my TV to get money to take him out and have a good time... I sure do miss that TV but the FOOD was AMAZING!!!
 If you know the feeling of &quot;warm fuzzies&quot; from your head to your toes... 
If you know the feeling of &quot;warm fuzzies&quot; from your head to your toes, then just try a Swiss Mushroom Runza, an order of onion rings, and a chocolate shake and experience the most &quot;yummiest warm fuzzies&quot; ever!  It&apos;s a promise!
 My son lives in Ozark, MO. We will be traveling to his home for Thanksgiving this year... 
My son lives in Ozark, MO.  We will be traveling to his home for Thanksgiving this year. When I asked what he would like us to bring to contribute to the Thanksgiving meal his reply was, &quot;Runzas.&quot;  All types,  especially the new Italian mini Runza so his new bride and her family can taste the best sandwich ever made. We will give thanks and bless our Runza Thanksgiving dinner this year.  Too bad the fries and onion rings won&apos;t make the trip.  Bonny.
 I&apos;m from Lincoln, Nebraska, and I&apos;ve grown up loving Runza all of my life... 
I&apos;m from Lincoln, Nebraska, and I&apos;ve grown up loving Runza all of my life. Every time I go (which is about three times a week), I order the exact same thing. One day, I walked in to Runza, and prepared to order my meal, when I noticed the boy working the cash register. I&apos;d seen him there the past two days when I&apos;d eaten Runza, and there he was again. I open my mouth to spout out, &quot;I&apos;ll have a number 9 with a large fry instead of a medium, but still a medium drink, and ranch dipping sauce.&quot; But I didn&apos;t have to say all that, because before I could get a word out, he politely said, &quot;Hey! The usual today?&quot; It was so exciting, and reminded me that I could think of Runza as a second family. :)
 6 years ago we started having &quot;Runza Fridays&quot;... 
6 years ago we started having &quot;Runza Fridays.&quot;  Every day I picked up my 3 kids from school along with 2 others.  Every friday we had to go thru the drive thru at the Runza on 70th and Van Dorn. This went on for 2 years!!! The tradition started up again this school year with carpooling and we again have Runza Fridays. The kids are so funny, they may not remember to do homework but the always remember what happens on fridays!!
 I was traveling home on I-80. I was getting very hungry and craving a Cheese Runza and fries... 
I was traveling home on I-80. I was getting very hungry and craving a Cheese Runza and fries. As I passed several tempting restaurants along the way I was determined to get home and get my Runza. I drove (a little) above the speed limit and avoided any bathroom breaks. I finally made it there 2 hours later and the long journey was well worth it. The Cheese Runza and fries were so delicious and warm. They were calling my name and waiting patiently for my teeth to sink into them. I love Runza!
 My name is Cecilia. I am a Runza fan... 
My name is Cecilia. I am a Runza fan. I love the fresh, never frozen beef and the perfectly cooked crinkle cut fries and fresh handmade onion rings. In the winter I enjoy the tastey homemade chili. I had the pleasure of working at Runza for a year. As I live in the Omaha area, I have access to the tasty Runza menu any time the craving hits. However, my sister and brother living in Austin, Texas are not so fortunate. They expressed a great craving for the unique Runza sandwich experience, so I bought a couple of frozen Runzas and mailed them to Texas. They were eternally gratefull.
 I was at a sportsbar in Chicago this September when the Huskers played at Washington... 
I was at a sportsbar in Chicago this September when the Huskers played at Washington. This bar is a gathering place for Husker fans, and to my delight and surprise, one loyal fan and kind fellow Nebraskan had enough Runza&apos;s shipped in to feed the whole bar! While I live in Omaha&amp;am not deprived of my frequent Runza fixes, it was great to enjoy a hot Runza sandwhich while watching the Huskers defeat the Huskies, much like I do in Memorial Stadium during every Nebraska home game.
 Like most children, my kids love to eat out... 
Like most children, my kids love to eat out, especially if there are cheeseburgers or chicken fingers and fries involved. However, at their young ages of only 2 and 4 years old, my little ones are able to differentiate the difference between the good fast food (RUNZA) and the others (we won&apos;t name any names). So every time our family van passes a RUNZA restaurant, my 2-year-old, who does not talk much yet, points from his car seat and screams: &quot;HUNGRY!!!&quot; While, I know he is not always hungry, I do appreciate his effort to convince us to turn in to your restaurant to have a bite to eat. And to his credit, sometimes it works!
 I used to work at Runza while in high school in Scottsbluff, Nebraska... 
I used to work at Runza while in high school in Scottsbluff, Nebraska, many, many years ago. Now my family and I live in Texas but travel to Nebraska a few times a year for business.  The first thing we do when we cross the border into Nebraska is look for a Runza. We may only be in Nebraska for two or three days but we can eat there 2 or three times. My kids are almost as hooked as I am! My pharmacist saw my Nebraska t-shirt which led us to discussing Runza. When it was mentioned my kids would like to open a Runza in Texas he said he&apos;d be the first one there. We never know what the future of Runza in Texas is; but for now, we look forward to every trip to Nebraska with numerous trips to Runza!
 My son was going to college at Kansas State and I was going there to watch Nebraska play... 
My son was going to college at Kansas State and I was going there to watch Nebraska play. I was supposed to bring Runza&apos;s to Kansas State game so we could sit in the stadium and watch Kansas State play Nebraska eating our Runza&apos;s. I realized that I forgot to pick them up when I was in Maryville so I turned around and went back to Beatrice to get the sandwiches because it wouldn&apos;t be a game without our Runza&apos;s. Nebraska won the game and it felt great to eat our Runza&apos;s in Kansas State Stadium. Each time we went to a game my family asked if I got the Runza&apos;s. Of course my answer is always yes. A Nebraska game is not a game unless you have your Nebraska shirt and Runza.
 Growing up in Nebraska, I have been spoiled by all of my Runza experiences... 
Growing up in Nebraska, I have been spoiled by all of my Runza experiences. I go to college at Creighton University in Omaha, and there are many people here who have never tried Runza!! This weekend, I am loading up my car and taking people from Chicago, Denver, Kansas City, and Boston to Runza for some delicious food. I hope to turn them into Runzatics like me!
 I grew up in Nebraska and when I moved to Kansas I realized there were not any Runza... 
I grew up in Nebraska and when I moved to Kansas I realized there were not any Runza Restaraunts nearby. After 5 years without a Runza we went on vacation to North Dakota and discovered a Runza restaurant only 90 miles away from our home. We decided to stop and bring some home on our way back. When heading home from vacation we stopped only to discover that they were out of Runza&apos;s, we back tracked 40 more miles to another Runza and started back towards home. Sometimes we drive to the nearest Runza 127 miles away on a weekend to get a Runza fix. I have their phone number on speed dial and I always call before we go to be sure they will have enough for us. I also bring back several for friends who love Runza&apos;s too and I always tell them that I can smuggle Runza&apos;s across the border for them but if I get caught I am not responsible for what happens their Runza&apos;s.
 I&apos;ll never forget driving by Runza when my son (at 18 months of age) yells out &quot;RUNZA&quot;... 
I&apos;ll never forget driving by Runza when my son (at 18 months of age) yells out &quot;RUNZA&quot; - he was an early talker, but this was still a pretty impressive shout out. He is now almost 3 and still points them out every time we drive by and it&apos;s always his pick when we decide to grab a quick bite to eat!
 My most memorable &quot;Runza experience&quot; was in college over 20 years ago... 
My most memorable &quot;Runza experience&quot; was in college over 20 years ago. I was a freshman, experiencing a bout of homesickness, and I had been craving a Runza. I bought one, a cheese Runza, in the late, Fall afternoon and to keep it warm I put it on the radiator in my dorm room. My roommate came in half an hour later and said she could smell it throughout the halls and stairways! I have had so many Runza&apos;s in the last 20+ years, too many to count, but that memory, thoughts of home and more of the smell of a warm, fresh-baked Runza, tops them all. My kids are now Runaztics, too! Thanks for all the memories!
 Well to be quite honest, this is how much I love Runza... 
Well to be quite honest, this is how much I love Runza. I work 2 blocks from the south Runza in Kearney and was going to Runza for my daily fix of Runza, onions rings and pepsi when, a block from work, I had a flat tire. I said, &quot;Well, fix thr tire and lunch hour will be over and miss my Runza, or walk and have my Runza and goodies and worry about my car at a later date.&quot; My Runza won out and walked to Runza. When I, walked back to my car there was a ticket and still a flat tire. But I had my Runza ,Onion rings and Pepsi - and even getting a ticket was worth having my lunch at Runza!
 Hey there, I am an Over the Road Truck driver... 
Hey there, I am an Over the Road Truck driver, every other month I tell my Dispatcher I need a Load out West to California or Washington so I can get My Runza! My familly is German and they all decended to Nebraska. My Grandmother used to make Homemade Kraut-Runzas. Yours, are pretty close to her Great reciepes. We Just wanted to let you know how much we Love them.
 I joined the Runza Club on Facebook while working in Afghanistan... 
I joined the Runza Club on Facebook while working in Afghanistan. Runza&apos;s were one of the foods I most craved in my 11 years of living and working in Afghanistan. Was so fun to hear others such in Tacoma, Washington say that they order them frozen and sent to them. I didn&apos;t know that could be done! I am now back in the US and am glad to say I can have my Runza anytime I want! YEA!!!
 A few years ago I worked at the airport renting cars. I used to have people ask me... 
A few years ago I worked at the airport renting cars. I used to have people ask me after I gave them the keys to their car where the nearest Runza was. I know of Runzas but had never had one. It turned out there were so many requests for where a Runza was I finally asked, &quot;what&apos;s the attraction?&quot; They said they stop in Omaha just to get a Runza, the best thing they ever made. So after work that same day, I went for a Runza, and I&apos;ve been hooked ever since, and now have my family hooked. We love Runza.
 Okay, this goes back to when I went to college at the Univeristy of Northern Colorado... 
Okay, this goes back to when I went to college at the Univeristy of Northern Colorado back in 2000. Location was in Greeley, CO. I didn&apos;t think of looking around for a Runza because I didn&apos;t think there would be one in my area. However, the day came that I was talking to my aunt and I mentioned that I missed Runzas. She immediately told me that there was one 20 minutes away in Loveland. Within 15 minutes I had grabbed my girlfriend, who at this time thought I was crazy. She, being the only one I knew at the time with a car, was driving us to Loveland. When we arrived I ordered one cheese and one mushroom and swiss. I was in heaven!!! From there on out, anytime I needed a pick me up, it was a trip to Loveland. Unfortunately, the relationship didn&apos;t last more than a few months longer. I don&apos;t think I lost much as she wasn&apos;t that impressed with Runza. Probably due to the fact that I made them out to be what they are, amazing!!!! Thank you Runza for helping me keep away women who probably aren&apos;t right for me. Haha
 So I live in lincoln NE, where Runza is always at your fingertips... 
So I live in lincoln NE, where Runza is always at your fingertips (I can walk to the one that is closet to my house). However when I was pregnant I CRaVED Runza. Thats all I wanted everytime I thought about food it was Runza fries with their amazing ranch.... so here comes the Runzatic part, when I was 8months pregnant I got put on bedrest at the hospital becuase I was at risk for some complications.  It was about 8 at night and my family had gone home to get some rest.  I was again craving a #2 combo with ketchup only and fries with ranch. My nurse, who had been sitting in with me all day, her shift was ending and the next nurse was coming in.  I wanted my Runza so bad I gave her money for her and I BOTH to get a Runza meal.  She went out and got me my Runza and brought it back to the hospital! Its no wonder my now 15 month old is a Runza lover too.  He gets excited about his kids meals!
 I would always make a run for Runzas--by driving all the way to Lincoln... 
I would always make a run for Runzas--by driving all the way to Lincoln even after Runzas were being built here in Omaha. I always went to the original location in west Lincoln out by Pioneer Park, since I grew up in Lincoln and had always gone there to eat. There was nothing like getting the food from the &quot;rustic&quot; building. (Yes, I guess that dates me--I just turned 58, so I&apos;m rustic too!) I&apos;d eat the meal with fries on the way back to Omaha and would always bring extra Runzas back for the freezer. I was so disappointed when that location was torn down!
 My best friend lives in another state, one that does not have a Runza (GASP)... 
My best friend lives in another state, one that does not have a Runza (GASP) and we keep in touch through text and send each other our thoughts, as if we were in same room, throughout the day. One day she sent me, &quot;Hey lets go to lunch, let&apos;s do McDonalds!&quot; I replied, &quot;No way!! Runza!&quot; She informed me that she was &quot;mad&quot; at me now because that would be all she would be able to think about, non stop, and she could not have any Runza, because it was impossible, as there was no Runza for hundreds of miles from her. Well, nothing is impossible! So I went to Runza and bought her 10 frozen Runza sandwiches and packed them in ice packs and sent them to her as a surprise. Upon recieving them, and then cooking them and sharing them with her family she informed me that it reminded her of Christmas dinner with her folks (that passed last year). It had brought her that special of a feeling.
 Runza food is the best &quot;fast food&quot; without the fast food taste... 
Runza food is the best &quot;fast food&quot; without the fast food taste. I love the pepper on my hamburgers; the crinkles in the fries holds the salt and the polish dogs are the best in town. It doesn&apos;t take long to get my food at Runza, but when I sit down to eat it tastes and feels like it was made in my mom&apos;s kitchen. GO RUNZA!!!
 Although not a particular experience, I just wanted to share anyway... 
Although not a particular experience, I just wanted to share anyway. I grew up in Omaha, and Loved eating at Runza. As I got older my family moved to an area that is at least 100 miles away from the nearest one. Every time I get the chance to go back to my home town I HAVE to have Runza when we go, I also suggest it to ALL of my friends...The Original Runza is just amazing and there is Nothing like it anywhere!
 I grew up on Runza and it has been a family favorite for as long as I can remember... 
I grew up on Runza and it has been a family favorite for as long as I can remember. But the REAL runza fanatic is my niece, Bethany. She has spent the last 10 months serving her country in Iraq. When she talked about home, Runza was always involved! She said she even dreamed about eating at Runza (a #2, ketchup and mustard only, frings, a pepsi and onion ring dip.) I would tell her every time we went out to have Runza and she was soooo jealous! Well, she doesn&apos;t have to wait any longer. Her unit (the 313th Medical Company) returns today and the first place we&apos;re taking her when she leaves the base is to get her &quot;beloved&quot; Runza. I&apos;m sure she will be eating there for days!! Runza will always be part of home for her no matter where she goes.
 Well one time I went to the local &quot;free fest,&quot; which is a festival where youth... 
Well one time I went to the local &quot;free fest,&quot; which is a festival where youth come and get free things as long as they pledge to be drug and alcohol free. Many of my friends were going so I thought to myself, why not go? When we got there the people volunteering had us fill out papers on smoking and such but all I wanted to know was what free things we got! So I quickly filled it out and was on my way to getting free things. Then all the sudden I go up to this table full of Runzas. Oh great, I thought to myself. I never really liked the &quot;Runza.&quot; (Back then I must have had different taste buds because now, Runzas are like heaven!) So I pass by, but before I get too far, my friend calls me back cause she was one of the people volunteering at the Runza station. She decided to give me a Runza no matter what I said. haha. She was a very good worker. When she gave me that food, I realized, why not? It&apos;s not like I have anything to loose if I try a Runza again. I bit into the warm crust to find a very good sensation of taste, that I couldn&apos;t stop getting enough of. As I took another bite, my mouth started to water and I yearned for more. After my first Runza at the free fest, many other people let me have theirs and by the end of the festival, I had about three Runzas. I hope you read this and smile because it was you guys that gave food to the free fest to better the children and help them explore new foods, like the Runza!
 My most memorable Runza experience was Christmas 09... 
My most memorable Runza experience was Christmas 09. We drove home for Christmas all the way from Clearwater, Florida. We had a blizzard for Christmas and warm Runza&apos;s all in the same week! When you live where it&apos;s sunshine and beach ALL the time, it&apos;s so nice to get back to the &quot;Good Life&quot; and have snow and Runza&apos;s. =) We are going to be there in a week and can&apos;t wait to have more!
 Both me and my husband were living in Kuwait for the last 3 years... 
Both me and my husband were living in Kuwait for the last 3 years and when I came back on a 2 week leave I think I ate at Runza at least 6 times. I took pictures on my phone and sent them to my poor husband back in Kuwait. So when I went back to Kuwait I decided to take 6 of the frozen Runzas back to him. Talk about being excited! Well, he let a friend at work try one that has never even heard of a Runza and now I am back in Nebraska and shipping monthly Runzas to Kuwait to my husband and ALL his friends. I have a weekly order of 20 frozen Runzas to be shipped to Kuwait. Yes Runza has reached Kuwait!
 We as young parents used to go to the first Runza hut in Lincoln... 
We as young parents used to go to the first Runza hut in Lincoln when it first opened in the 1950&apos;s with our 4 little people and we all loved it. We are in our eightys and still love the fantastic Runzas.
 I am originally from NE, but haven&apos;t lived there since 1998... 
I am originally from NE, but haven&apos;t lived there since 1998. I now live in Georgia and every time I go to NE I have to eat at Runza!!! And not just once!!!! One time, I was in Nebraska for 3 days and ate at Runza 6 times!!!! I just can&apos;t seem to get enough Runzas!!
 Last month I came to visit some friends who live in Nebraska. As I arrived at the airport... 
Last month I came to visit some friends who live in Nebraska. As I arrived at the airport from Ohio, I immediately told them we needed to find a Runza restaurant to eat. It had been 4 years since I had a Runza sandwhich! I order my favorite which was still the #1 cheese Runza with perfectly cooked golden brown crinkly fries. My friends thought I was going to have a melt down but I explained that I was just so excited to finally enjoy such a long-lost meal. I ended up getting another sandwhich &quot;for the road&quot; and even took pictures to show my friends back in Ohio the awesomeness of Runza.
 As a little girl I remember my dad taking us to Runza... 
As a little girl I remember my dad taking us to Runza, we usually went through the drive-thru. I always got an Original Runza-licious and an order of fantastical french fries. Crunchy. Delicious. We would grab them out of the bag and they would be hot - &quot;bounce back and forth between your hands&quot; hot. That didn&apos;t matter, they were too yummy to wait for. :) To this day I take my children there and they do the same thing with their french fries. The only things that have changed are now I order a Cheese Runza-licious and my kids are enjoying it with me. Thank you dad and thank you Runza!
 Your mushroom swiss burgers make me want to yodle... 
Your mushroom swiss burgers make me want to yodle and your onion rings are the cats&apos; meow; my fave place.
 You&apos;ve heard the phrase, &quot;I&apos;d walk a mile for a camel.&quot; But I don&apos;t need a camel. I need a Runza... 
You&apos;ve heard the phrase, &quot;I&apos;d walk a mile for a camel.&quot; But I don&apos;t need a camel. I need a Runza, so I&apos;d walk a mile for a Runza!!! We were heading for Norfolk a couple weeks ago to do some shopping and, of course, eat at our favorite Runza when we had car trouble a mile or so out of Norfolk. We called a garage to get the car fixed. While we were getting it fixed (it took a while), I walked to Runza,to enjoy my delicious Runza. I just couldn&apos;t wait any longer!!
 After living in Almaty, Kazakhstan for eleven and a half years... 
After living in Almaty, Kazakhstan for eleven and a half years, I came halfway around the world, back &quot;home&quot; to Nebraska. There are no tasty Runzas in Almaty-- the beef is range-fed and tastes like liver, so even if there WAS a Runza, it wouldn&apos;t taste right. So, a couple of days after coming home, we made our pilgrimage to Runza Drive-In. Oh my! What a discovery! I had only had &quot;classic&quot; runzas before, but now-- swiss cheese and mushrooms added into that delicious Runza sandwich. Wow! My mouth was in heaven. There&apos;s no place like home.
 My most memorable Runza experience was when my family and I... 
My most memorable Runza experience was when my family and I were at the last Nebraska game of the season in Lincoln. The snow was falling and so was the temperature. Never enough to leave the Husker game though. My husband had the perfect solution to warm our &quot;HEARTS&quot;! Forget the hot cocoa. This man was on a real mission. He came back with steaming RUNZA&apos;S! That did the trick. We stayed warm until the game ended. My daughter still remembers that day when she was a little girl.
 I worked for Runza for 2 1/2 years during college and I loved making and eating all of the food... 
I worked for Runza for 2 1/2 years during college and I loved making and eating all of the food we prepared. I think working there made me like it even more, which is not true for other fast food places I have worked. It took me a while to try a Runza, but once I tried one, that is all I ever get. I love the cheese runzas and the french fries are the best around. After college I moved to Des Moines, IA and there is not a Runza located there. Every time I came back to Omaha, all I ever wanted to eat was Runza. Today, 9 years after graduating from college, I&apos;m back in Omaha and loving Runza!!
 Growing up in Lincoln, my husband and I loved Runza... 
Growing up in Lincoln, my husband and I loved Runza. We moved to Madison, WI and would pack a cooler full of Runzas to freeze when we came home to bring back to WI with us. We were really excited when we found out my husband was transferred back to Omaha. Now we get Runza at least weekly and any time a job relocation idea comes to the table, we always look to see if there is a Runza in the town. If not, we don&apos;t consider it.
 My Grandfather LOVES to tell the story of the time... 
My Grandfather LOVES to tell the story of the time that my Grandparents came to town and wanted to take me out to dinner. I was 13 or 14 years old, and he told me, &quot; You can chose anywhere you want to go&quot;. He figured I was going to pick someplace like Red Lobster or Olive Garden, but without missing a beat, I said &quot;Runza!&quot; A little taken back by my choice, they reluctantly headed to the closest location and tried their first Runza. Now every time they come back to town, one of the first meals my Grandparents and I have together is Runza!
 As a man, I try to stay away from the fu fu stuff my wife sometimes has me sample... 
As a man, I try to stay away from the fu fu stuff my wife sometimes has me sample. I don&apos;t like my salads all fancy with a bunch of this and a bunch of that in it. But she said the Sweet Berry chicken salad was really terrific. The next time we went to lunch I opted out of the Runza and tried the Sweet berry chicken salad. It is really an amazing product. I have turned other people on to to the salad and they love it! The product is also very consistent from location to location.
 A good friend of mine was getting married back in Texas... 
A good friend of mine was getting married back in Texas. She has traveled to Nebraska several times and absolutely LOVES Runzas. The first place she always stops after getting off the plane in Nebraska is a Runza Restaurant. She has even tried making them several times being that there are no Runza restaurants in Texas. To surprise her I got several frozen runzas from the restaurant by my house, some dry ice, packed them up and brought them when I flew down for her wedding. The girls all hung out and ate Runzas and drank Nebraska wine by the pool the night before her wedding. A &quot;Runza experience&quot; we will never forget!
 For years I have been trying to get my wife to try Runza. She would not do it... 
For years I have been trying to get my wife to try Runza. She would not do it. We have just had our 3rd child and a wonderful woman came by the house and gave us a &quot;welcome package&quot; consisting of various coupons and free items from several of the retailers in the Lawrence, KS area. Thankfully, one of those was a free dinner for 2 from Runza. Last night we loaded up our 3 children and went to the Lawrence Runza. We ordered our 2 older children kid&apos;s meals and took advantage of the free meal for 2, which consisted of 2 drinks, 1 Runza, 1 burger, 1 O-ring, and 1 fry. One bite into my wife&apos;s burger was all it took for her to admit that I was right. She wished I had pushed harder to try Runza earlier. The restaurant was clean. The people working were polite, happy, and professional. It was a wonderful experience. So much so, that my wife ordered the Aztec Salad to go so I could have it for lunch today. Well, I have just finished my lunch and felt compelled to contact the manager of the store and tell him what a great experience we had. I certainly hope this email finds Doug Nation. Last night was the first time I&apos;ve been in a Runza Restaurant in several years. I promise my family will be eating at the Lawrence Runza much more in the future. Thank you so much for living up to your promise of fresh food made right. Conner
 HI. I AM SO HAPPY TO TELL YOU HOW MUCH WE LOVE RUNZA!! 
HI.  I AM SO HAPPY TO TELL YOU HOW MUCH WE LOVE RUNZA!!  WE GO TO CALIFORNIA FOR THE WINTER EVERY YEAR AND WE MISS RUNZA MORE THAN ANYTHING ELSE WHILE WE ARE GONE.  WHEN WE HAVE COMPANY COME DURING THE SUMMER WE MAKE SURE THAT EVERYONE GETS THE CHANCE TO SHARE OUR PASSION FOR RUNZA!
 I love Runza food! I worked at Runza for 4 years while going to college in Kearney, NE... 
I love Runza food! I worked at Runza for 4 years while going to college in Kearney, NE. People would ask me how I can eat there after working there. It&apos;s simple! I know the quality of food and everything is made in the kitchen. Beef is Nebraska raised. How could I not eat at Runza! My most memorable experience was when I found out I was pregnant with twins! I went from the Doctors office to Runza. I&apos;d heard that pregnant women sometimes get sick and can&apos;t eat their favorite foods, so I went to Runza and got a Swiss Cheese Mushroom Runza, onion rings and dip just to make sure I was going to be able to eat at my favorite restaurant while I was pregnant. I never had a problem, and now my kids request eating at Runza all the time. I guess we created Runza monsters!!!
 When I was in high school I would always go get onion rings and a chocolate shake at my favorite restaurant - Runza! 
When I was in high school I would always go get onion rings and a chocolate shake at my favorite restaurant - Runza! One day after sitting down I noticed a cute guy come in. He ordered fries and a chocolate shake. He sat at the table next to me and when we got our orders they had us switched. He got my onion rings and I got his fries! We noticed and had a laugh about it and then he asked me to join him. That was 5 years ago! Now we have been married for three years and have a son! We always go to Runza, but now we get the frings to share. He eats the fries and I eat the onion rings! It is our favorite thing to do on date night!
 Well, as ALWAYS, the Runza employees always sound like they want to be there... 
Well, as ALWAYS, the Runza employees always sound like they want to be there. My family and I go to Lincoln, NE a lot so we always look forward to eating at the Runza in North Platte, NE. We are from Colorado Springs, so we NEVER get to eat at Runza. It is a treat! When we go though, the employees stop whatever they are doing and welcome us! Their food is very good and the restraunt/bathrooms are always clean! Did I mention their cute T-Shirts? ADORABLE!
 Runza fries are the only fries I enjoy eating and they were the first fries I that I allowed both of my children to eat... 
Runza fries are the only fries I enjoy eating and they were the first fries I that I allowed both of my children to eat. Years later, Runza remains our family&apos;s favored choice for fast food. Two (of many) memory making examples include: Every week in the summer when our daughter is volunteering overnight at Y camp, my husband makes an hour+ round trip to deliver a Runza cheeseburger (the Runza way) and fries to her. Secondly, her trips to the mall most always include spending babysitting money on large Runza fries the food court. (Her friend gets them now, too, since we introduced her to them!) So many memories - so many fries - so worth it!
 How much more does it reveal that I love Runza (copyright!) that when I walk into mine in Gretna... 
How much more does it reveal that I love Runza (copyright!) that when I walk into mine in Gretna and the teenager working the grill nods to me then holds up one or two fingers to inquire if I am in for a single or a double that particular day, then I hold up the corresponding finger(s) to indicate how hungry I am...next thing I know, I am being served with a single hamburger plain or a double, while the counterperson that day rings me up accordingly after seeing the finger(s). Know thy customer, that is the creed of the Gretna Runza! Kudos to Mike Ziebarth, manager extraordinare, Patrick and Chelsea, and the rest of the great staff! Ironically, I lived in Nebraska for nine years before discovering that Runza makes not only regular hamburgers in addition to Runzas, but also the finest and most delicious &quot;fast-food&quot; hamburgers as well!
 When I visited NE last year for a relatives&apos; wedding, I noticed there were lots of Runza restaurants out there... 
When I visited NE last year for a relatives&apos; wedding, I noticed there were lots of Runza restaurants out there.  I just thought Nebraskans must love Runza back then.  This afternoon I finally decided to try Runza in my town (Ft Collins, CO) and was truly amazed how delicious the original Runza sandwich was!  Runza tastes like homemade and I cannot wait to go back again for more. :)  The restaurant (on Lemay Ave) was very clean and all the staff members treated me and my daughter so kind.  My daughter also got a free ice cream cone and we were extremely satisfied.
 I grew up in Nebraska, so naturally Runzas were a way of life... 
I grew up in Nebraska, so naturally Runzas were a way of life. I moved to Kansas City and found that I couldn&apos;t find a Runza anywhere....Then one day I was driving in Lawrence Kansas and...BOOM...there was that beautiful Green and Yellow sign.  I almost crashed my car.  I went in and ordered three runzas...one for the drive home and two to put in the freezer back home for later.  Once back home I told my dad about the Runza I had found (he is from Nebraska too) and now we make sure on Fathers day we make the drive from KC to Lawrence to get a Runza!!!!
 Mine isn&apos;t a &quot;most memorable&quot; experience but an on-going one... 
Mine isn&apos;t a &quot;most memorable&quot; experience but an on-going one...we live about 1/2 mile from our local Runza. We also have one about 10 miles away in the town where we work. I have ALWAYS ALWAYS ALWAYS found both stores to be very clean, the food consistently great and the employess outgoing and very enthusiastic. I have often witnessed employees going out of their way for a customer and genuinely wanting to. Our Runza&apos;s are ran by a local family and I have heard the best things about how great they are to work for (especially their willingness to work with high-school schedules) and the things they do for our community. This, to me, along with their excellent food, encourages me to continue to support their franchise with my business.
 My most memorable Runza moment occured on my wedding day... 
My most memorable Runza moment occured on my wedding day... after being with friends and family all day, my new husband and I took a horse and buggy through the drive-in on 56th and Holdrege in Lincoln.  Being from another state, he had never been OR experienced a Runza.  It was his first and my most memorable.
 When I tasted my first Runza I was hooked. This was back in 1949 when there was a little stand... 
When I tasted my first Runza I was hooked. This was back in 1949 when there was a little stand on Park Blvd. on the way to Pioneers Park.  I was in one of the operettas at the time and was hungry.  We didn&apos;t get to eat at many drive-ins in those days so it was a real treat to do so.  And they weren&apos;t as expensive as today but that doesn&apos;t stop me from craving one ever so often.  Also, anytime friends come to visit, they must have a Runza to satisfy their cravings and we are happy to comply.  Judy
 There is an employee at Runza that gets along really well with my onry grandpa... 
There is an employee at Runza that gets along really well with my onry grandpa. They are really silly and pick on each other all the time. She really makes him feel welcome and makes my grandparents have a good laugh for the day. Everyone could use such a day. My grandma likes it because she can have a salad, soup, or a sandwhich. Thanks to the Grand Island Runza.
 I came all the way from NY and heard about Runza and decided to give it a try. OMG I can&apos;t stop eating it... 
I came all the way from NY and heard about Runza and decided to give it a try. OMG I can&apos;t stop eating it. Every time I get hungry I think... what can I get from Runza today!  The quality of food is outstanding!  Hamburgers are fresh and juicy, fries and onion rings are crisp, hot, and tasty!  So much better than any fast food joint around!  I&apos;d say they should have Runza all over the country but ...... It&apos;s mine, all mine, hahahaha, and they can&apos;t get any.  Runza is like home cooked food!  The workers are kind and happy to see you... and I am sure happy to see them!  I wish there was a Runza closer to me as I think I would eat it every day YUMMMMMM!!!!!  So glad I found you Runza.  You are the best of the best.  I wish I could send you to my son and his friends (The Marines) over in Afganastan.  BOY WOULD THEY LOVE TO HAVE YOU TOO!!!!!!  MY SON THOUGHT SONIC WAS GOOD BUT YOU BEAT THEM BY MILES.  CAN&apos;T WAIT TILL HE COMES HOME AND I CAN TREAT HIM TO YOUR FOOD! THANKS FOR SUCH A GREAT PRODUCT, RUNZA.  KEEP UP THE GREAT WORK.  Eileen
 Everyone at work, family, friends and the staff at my Runza know how much I love to eat the Hamburger meal with ketchup and onion... 
Everyone at work, family, friends and the staff at my Runza know how much I love to eat the Hamburger meal with ketchup and onion. I walk into Runza and my food is ready before I give my order and pay. My kids wanted to take me out for Mother&apos;s Day and said to pick someplace other than Runza. What?? I eat there two nights a week and every Sat and Sun for lunch. The staff is awesome. We know each other by name. My husband and I once had our anniversary dinner at Runza. My Runza store is the best one in Omaha.
 We live in a remote area of Kansas where there are no Runzas... 
We live in a remote area of Kansas where there are no Runzas.  However we are located about 90 miles from Kearney, NE which has one.  One of our sons had someone from Nebraska ask him if he had ever eaten at Runza, which we had not.  He highly recommended it because of the onion rings and the buns on the burgers, plus the burgers had never been frozen.  So we decided to check it out.  All I can say is WOW!  That was the best burger and onion rings we had ever had!!!  Now when we go to Kearney on a shopping or business trip, guess where we eat out?  Yep, Runza!  We have yet to be tired of the great food there.  We recommend it to everyone we hear is going to that town.  Thanks! Linda
 Our love for Runza is strong....This is our 10&amp;6 year olds FAVORITE place to go... 
Our love for Runza is strong....This is our 10&amp;6 year olds FAVORITE place to go. On our last day of school we always go out for a treat...guess what they chose?  RUNZA french fries! Our closest one is 25 miles away and that didn&apos;t stop us - we went. Although dad was a little jealous (he had to work). So we all went out to eat the next day and guess where we went?  RUNZA!  We all thought we were in heaven. Lisa
 I worked for Runza in Schuyler, NE. I got to eat the great food every day&amp;know that it is made fresh daily... 
I worked for Runza in Schuyler, NE.  I got to eat the great food every day&amp;know that it is made fresh daily so I love to still eat there all the time. Keep up the good work!!
 The first place my son had to visit when he came home to visit was RUNZA. He was stationed in Germany... 
The first place my son had to visit when he came home to visit was RUNZA. He was stationed in Germany and deployed 4 times. The longest he was away from home was 3 years. That is a long time to go without a RUNZA!!! He just moved back to Nebraska along with his German wife and the first place we took them, after picking them up at the airport, was the SEWARD RUNZA. I also bought him a RUNZA gift card as a welcome home gift.
 When my husband&apos;s sisters from Seattle come to visit us in our little town, eating at Runza is the first thing we do... 
When my husband&apos;s sisters from Seattle come to visit us in our little town, eating at Runza is the first thing we do. They miss that down-home Runza taste and can&apos;t wait to place their order. Are they really coming to visit us, or, are they coming back home for the Runza food?
 Many times I will go into the local Runza to sit down and eat my meal, and I always think I should pick up an extra Runza for lunch... 
Many times I will go into the local Runza to sit down and eat my meal, and I always think I should pick up an extra Runza for lunch the next day, but usually don&apos;t. But as I get into my car, I normally find myself in the drive thru picking up an extra Runza any way!
 Being a Grandmother to 10 active kids requires me to babysit often... 
Being a Grandmother to 10 active kids requires me to babysit often, transport them to ballgames, and take them along shopping. There&apos;s never a doubt, when any of them are out with Grandma, where we will eat! NEVER! It&apos;s always Runza!  Even the picky eaters have caved in and now chant from the backseat &quot;RUNZA! RUNZA! RUNZA!&quot;  Some may call that brainwashing...........I call it effective grandmothering!
 Hi, our family was a typical family who ate at McDonalds and Burger King. My girlfriend convinced me to try Runza... 
Hi, our family was a typical family who ate at McDonalds and Burger King. My girlfriend convinced me to try Runza. I was thrilled with the quality of Runza&apos;s food. I love burgers and onion rings and have found they are the best around. Our Friday treat at the end of the week is to go out and get food. I look forward to my Friday visits to Runza. The onion rings are the best around and I can tell the burgers are hand made patties (they look like patties I would make at home). My 13 year old loves the oringinal Runza and your wonderful fries. Even if my youngest wants to go to McDonalds for his Friday treat I always go to Runza to get my dinner. The extra stop is definately worth is to me. The staff is always friendly and I wouldn&apos;t give up my burger and onion rings for anything. A true Runza convert for life. Thanks again for the quality food and the great service. Keep up the great work!
 My husband took me to Runza on our FIRST DATE! 
My husband took me to Runza on our FIRST DATE! We both grew up in very small towns in northeast Nebraska...and when he moved to Lincoln, Runza was his restaurant of choice! Now our youngest daughter lives in California, and I never have to plan for the first and last meals of her visit...the first place we stop after picking her up from the airport is Runza...and the last place she stops before heading to the airport is Runza. We are a &quot;Runzatic&quot; family! Note: She just told me last evening on the phone that we would be eating at Runza tomorrow when she arrives--now with her family (husband is from west coast--no Runzas there!).
 Must I scheme to eat at Runza? 
Must I scheme to eat at Runza? We are 35 miles from the nearest Runza so I &apos;plan&apos; my shopping trips to arrive in town at noon&amp;of course it&apos;s time to eat!!  RUNZA!!  I take my time shopping&amp;wouldn&apos;t you know it,  it&apos;s time to eat our evenng meal before heading back to our country home. This has worked so many times I do hope I don&apos;t have to change my tactic to eat at RUNZA 2 X&apos;s in one day.
 We love Runzas so much, but the closest Runza is 60 miles away... 
We love Runzas so much, but the closest Runza is 60 miles away. Needless to say, we have to make the trip at least once a month where we stock up on Runzas and freeze them. It is so nice to go to the freezer and get my Runza fix. I eat them for breakfast, take them to work for lunch (where everyone is jealous of me) and eat them for dinner, or a snack later. I could eat Runzas every day if I had them.
 I am so in love with Runzas. I had planned on visiting my brother&amp;his family in Oceanside, CA... 
I am so in love with Runzas.  I had planned on visiting my brother&amp;his family in Oceanside, CA. Since there are no Runzas there, I decided to call&amp;order some made up, froze,&amp;I mailed them out to his house so we could enjoy them together when I got there. You can&apos;t imagine how thrilled everyone was. Your sandwiches were a great hit with all&amp;it was a little bit of Heaven for all of us.
 When my sister and I were growing up our mother and father took us to the original Runza restaurant out on South and Van Dorn St... 
When my sister and I were growing up our mother and father took us to the original Runza restaurant out on South and Van Dorn St. weekly, usually on Friday nights.  I can still remember my father to this day saying, &quot;Come on kids were going to Runza tonight.&quot;  My sister and I would just jumped up and down with joy - we just loved the Runzas and french fries so much.  Yhey had the best food in town.  Ican still remember the long lines of cars waiting to get into the parking lot.  It reminds me of going to a football game on Friday nights.  My sister and I would usually go play games behind the restaurant waiting for our parents to get into the parking lot so we could stand in line to order our food.  The older couple that owned the restaurant were the nicest people in the world they always had a big smile on there faces no matter how busy they were.  And boy the Runzas and french fries tasted so good.  You know, if I could go back in time I would spend hours waiting in line at the original Runza to experience the taste of the original Runza and French fries all over again. This is one thing from my childhood that I always will remember. Thanks for making that experience happen.
 A couple of months ago we moved back to Kearney after living in Scottsdale, AZ for nearly six years... 
A couple of months ago we moved back to Kearney after living in Scottsdale, AZ for nearly six years. During that time, one of the things we missed most was your onion rings and hamburgers. I don&apos;t know how many times we talked about that. Sure glad to be back and enjoying your products. We visit you often, and have forgotten that your competition exists.
 We are so lucky to have a Runza restaurant in our smaller city... 
We are so lucky to have a Runza restaurant in our smaller city. I can not go one day without going to Runza -- my husband thinks I am crazy--but we basically have lunch there every day!! If I miss a day, I start having withdrawal symptoms : ) The people that work at our Runza certainly recognize me and pretty much know what I am going to order. Some of them even know my name. Yay!! for Runza.
 So, here I sit in Virginia where there are NO Runzas available... 
So, here I sit in Virginia where there are NO Runzas available. My daughter, who still lives in Lincoln, came for a visit last year. As soon as she got off the plane, after the obligatory greetings, I asked if she brought any Runzas for us. Unfortunately, she said the dreaded &quot;NO.&quot; I threatened to send her back to get some..... She will HOPEFULLY will be coming for a visit again SOMETIME this summer. It&apos;s been about three years since I have tasted one of these and hope to have the craving satisfied before too long!!!!!! Thanks for the MANY years of memories. I doubt there are many restaurants that have the kind of and effect on people!!!!!
 I love Runza! My favorites are the chicken wrap and a cheese Runza... 
I love Runza! My favorites are the chicken wrap and a cheese Runza. Today I was sick and could not go to school, so I made dad take me to Runza for lunch. He loves the onion rings and the pepsi products. I am eight years old and I like reading the stories on the back of the receipts. You rock Runza! Mackensie
 After 12 months serving in the deserts of Iraq I have never been happier to see the Nebraska sign... 
After 12 months serving in the deserts of Iraq I have never been happier to see the Nebraska sign at the west edge of the state on interstate 80. It was the middle of December. I was sunburnt, sore and glad to be home. I convinced my friends to push on to Sidney, NE and loaded up on Runzas of all flavors, chili and cinnamon rolls. By the time I got to my house I was stuffed beyond belief. That was right before Christmas of 05, and I still go to that same Runza and enjoy it just as much every time I am in Sidney.
 I live in Edwardsville, IL with most of our very large family living in the Omaha area... 
I live in Edwardsville, IL with most of our very large family living in the Omaha area. My wife and I always make the journey to Runza on every trip north. (Sometimes twice in our visit.) Our St. Louis friend has even brought down to us frozen runzas. You are the best and we should know because we are about as old as dirt!
 I&apos;m a Sgt in the Marine Corps, and I absolutely love Runza sandwiches... 
I&apos;m a Sgt in the Marine Corps, and I absolutely love Runza sandwiches. Unfortunately, I&apos;m stationed out in Virginia Beach, Virginia, and there&apos;s no Runza restaurants nearby. On the very last day of September last year, I fell seriously ill when I experienced kidney failure due to an allergic reaction from an antibiotic I had taken a few weeks earlier. I was rushed to the hospital in an ambulance and everything. I was in extreme pain, it felt like my insides were being squeezed together. While at the hospital, my older brother called my mother back in Lincoln to let her know what was going on. She told him that she was going to come to Virginia to be with me. All of a sudden, a brilliant idea sprang into my head. Despite the pain I was in, I took the phone from my brother and managed to croak out to her my biggest desire: &quot;Mom, bring some frozen cheese Runza&apos;s when you come out here&quot;. Luckily I got better within a few days, and when she finally made it out here, we celebrated my release from the hospital by feasting on cheese Runzas!
 I am a born and raised, native Nebraskan. Therefore, I LOVE Runza... 
I am a born and raised, native Nebraskan. Therefore, I LOVE Runza. I go to school now at Northwest Missouri State, about two hours southeast of Omaha. One night a couple of fellow Nebraskans and I were ranting and raving about Runza. My roommate, who is from Southern California, said he was sick of us talking about stuff that he knows nothing about. He even went as far as to say &quot;It&apos;s no In &apos;n Out Burger!&quot; This didn&apos;t go over well with us, so we all got into a car and drove just over an hour to Nebraska City. There, we ordered my roommate his first ever cheese Runza and he fell in love! Now he even brags about Runza to others that have never been. This just goes to show that nothing can truly replace a Runza Sandwich! Best on earth!
 Our family definitely falls in the Runzatic category! 
Our family definitely falls in the Runzatic category! In fact, when we had to move from Lincoln, Nebraska to Bakersfield, California, several years ago, we were so disappointed that we would be leaving behind our beloved Runza (and family too)! So, when my in-laws come to visit, we beg them to bring us a ton of Runzas! And, fortunately, they have on several occasions! My mother-in-law packs them in a soft cooler and carries them on the plane with her! They don&apos;t last long, and once in awhile we&apos;ll share with our California friends who have never heard of a Runza! When we come back to Lincoln, Runza is one of the first places we stop!
 Once at a campout, I asked my friends if they ever heard of Runza... 
Once at a campout, I asked my friends if they ever heard of Runza. They said no (figures- we live in Kansas City!) and I said that was crazy that something so yummy, tasty, and delicious could not be known world-wide. So we made the longest &quot;fast food run&quot; anyone&apos;s probably ever taken, and we drove 45 minutes over to Lawrence so all of us could enjoy a hot, tasty Runza. Now, all my friends love Runza!
 Yes, we are Runzatics. We love Runza all year round, but when I saw the sign... 
Yes, we are Runzatics. We love Runza all year round, but when I saw the sign with &quot;CHILI IS HERE SEPT. 15TH&quot; I knew what was for supper on that night. We had to wait 5 days, but how happy my wife was.  Summer is too long to wait for excellent chili. She loves the chili soooo much, she says even her moms chili isn&apos;t as good and she is a fantastic cook. Every week during chili season we go for supper after work is done. I get my original Runza, cheese burger and onion rings (sometimes a polish dog) and she gets chili and fries. She says you have to dip the fries in the chili, it&apos;s delicious. This is the best supper of the week!!!
 On January 21, 2010, I had foot surgery and was relegated to getting around using crutches... 
On January 21, 2010, I had foot surgery and was relegated to getting around using crutches. I pretty much just stayed home as I hate using crutches. On Wednesday, January 27th I could no longer stand not having my weekly #2 Runza meal. I got in the car, crutches and all, and drove to my closest Runza at 40th&amp;Randolph to satisfy my craving. My husband wasn&apos;t happy that I had driven, but hey, I didn&apos;t even have to get out of the car to get my meal. I&apos;m good for another week now.
 I remember when the first Runza opened in Omaha. It was the only fast food place my dad would take us to... 
I remember when the first Runza opened in Omaha. It was the only fast food place my dad would take us to because they served real hamburgers, great onion rings and the Runza was fantastic. I&apos;m 48 now and I&apos;m still hooked on Runza&apos;s. The food is just as good now as it was then.
 In 1957 I immigrated from Germany to Lincoln, Nebraska . I missed the German breads... 
In 1957 I immigrated from Germany to Lincoln, Nebraska . I missed the German breads --- but--- there were those marvellous Runzas!!!! Luckily we lived close to Pioneers Park. Then, in 1970 we moved to the East Coast --- away from my Runzas ---! In 1985 we drove to Lincoln to attend my mother-in-law&apos;s funeral , but first stopped on O Street for my Runza ( I am sure my understanding and patient mother-in-law forgave me!). Since then I have been thinking: Runza, Runza, Runza. Last year we planned a trip to Arizona and wanted to make a detour via Lincoln for a Runza stop - but we couldn&apos;t work it out. So this year we are planning a drive to Lincoln to quelch our craving. How far are 2 &quot;crazy&quot; elderly people in their mid-seventies willing to drive for a Runza? Delaware, Pennsylvania, Ohio, Indiana, Illinois, Iowa and finally Lincoln!
 As native Nebraskans tranplanted to Olathe Kansas for 3 years, we were so excited to learn there is a Runza in Lawrence... 
As native Nebraskans tranplanted to Olathe Kansas for 3 years, we were so excited to learn there is a Runza in Lawrence! Being avid Harley riders, and always looking for an excuse to ride, we often chose Lawrence as our desitnation! Nothing sastisfies hard core bikers like hot Runzas on a cool fall day!  Sincerely, Kim&amp;Cindy (now back in the motherland) Omaha, NE
 I needed my Runza fix today so I bundled up and jumped in the frozen pickup and drove over to Lawrence from Kansas City... 
I needed my Runza fix today so I bundled up and jumped in the frozen pickup and drove over to Lawrence from Kansas City to get a cheese Runza. I do this about once a month. Today it was about 3 degrees and the threat of snow on the way but I was not concerned. I got hooked on Runza when I lived in Lincoln and now I make the 35 mile drive on K-10 for one. How I wish there were one in KC!!!!
 After two snow days of being stuck in our dorm room and bored, my roommate and I were craving Runza so bad... 
After two snow days of being stuck in our dorm room and bored, my roommate and I were craving Runza so bad, we just couldn&apos;t stand it. We ventured out into into the white abyss, where the roads were terrible and we couldn&apos;t see a thing. It was dangerous, but we couldn&apos;t stand another second without the savory, perfect crinkle cut fries and delicious, authentic burgers. Luckily, after sliding and skidding on the roads and driving by numerous accidents, we made it across town to Runza!  After two long, Runza-less days, we finally got our fix!
 I went to Lincoln Northeast and (luckily) there was a Runza within a short driving distance from school... 
I went to Lincoln Northeast and (luckily) there was a Runza within a short driving distance from school. It wasn&apos;t uncommon to gather a group of friends for lunch, grab some Runzas and eat them on the way back to school. One time, for whatever reason, I wasn&apos;t done eating my cheese Runza before I started back into the school. I was in the hallway, finishing my sandwich at my locker when a substitute teacher told me to throw my Runza in the trash. Was he insane?! This was a Runza! And my lunch! Throw it in the trash? Never. Rather, I politely refused, excused myself to finish my meal...and received a detention. Twenty-three years later, I still think it was worth it.
 We are all college students who used to live in Nebraska so we have enjoyed Runza our entire life until now... 
We are all college students who used to live in Nebraska so we have enjoyed Runza our entire life until now. This weekend, we drove 3 hours to from Northern Iowa to eat Runza and it was delicious! I can&apos;t wait for Christmas break so that we can eat some more.
 Hi, I work in North Platte, NE 3 blocks from Runza. Everyday, Monday-Friday I walk over to Runza... 
Hi, I work in North Platte, NE 3 blocks from Runza. Everyday, Monday-Friday I walk over to Runza for my Aztec Salad (in season) or Southwest Chicken Salad (grilled chicken with 2 jalepeno salad dressings) and a glass of water with lemon. I get the best service in the world!! When they see me coming across the street they order my salad and almost have it ready before I walk in the door. Not only do I enjoy the best salad in town, but also the best service in town. I am always anxious to get back to work on Monday so I can go to Runza!  Thanks, Lucy
 As I entered the Columbus Runza the aroma of the food being cooked was out of this world... 
As I entered the Columbus Runza the aroma of the food being cooked was out of this world. I ordered the cheese Runza meal. Runzas fries are by far the best fry around as they have a slight crunchy taste to them. The cheese on the delicious Runza just melted in my mouth. All you need is just one Runza meal and you are so fulfilled. I&apos;d eat the Runza meal every day, every week of the year.  Lorie
 My best friend is from Nebraska. We recently had to make a trip back to his home town from Denver... 
My best friend is from Nebraska. We recently had to make a trip back to his home town from Denver and thus made many Runza stops along the way there and back. I had never had one, but became hooked. He grew up eating them. We live in Lakewood, Colorado, which is a suburb just to the west of Denver. We never knew that there were any Runza restaurants in Colorado until recently when another friend told us about the Runza in Loveland. Loveland is about 60 miles north of Denver. Well, last Saturday at noon, my friend picked me up and we drove the 60 miles north to Runza in Loveland for &apos;lunch.&apos; It was about an hour and 15 minute drive, but well worth it. We each ordered a cheese Runza meal. We quickly finished those and then ordered 3 more each to take home. Only 2 made it home and into the fridge as planned. Our plan is to go back again this weekend! Mmmmmmmm.
 One Saturday during the summertime, I was watching TV around lunch time... 
One Saturday during the summertime, I was watching TV around lunch time. During commercials, a Runza commercial was on. I remember it was a commercial advertising the different kinds of runzas there are. I immediately thought to myself how amazing Runza would be for lunch, and made it a goal to get some to gorge myself with the luxury I sought after. So, since I couldn&apos;t drive to Runza, due to the fact that I&apos;m not of age, I walked the 22 blocks it took to satisfy my hungry soul. When I arrived at the restaurant from the pouring rain -- oh yeah, I forgot to mention it was raining... a lot -- I ordered a mushroom and Swiss Runza combo with Frings. I staked myself at the nearest table in wait for my food. When my order was ready, I got my food, and decimated the doubts I had about walking 2 miles for fast-food by swallowing the first decadent bite of my delicious runza. Truly a Saturday to remember.
 I was at home (Grand Island) for a week over Thanksgiving last year, I stopped at Runza every day to get my fill... 
I was at home (Grand Island) for a week over Thanksgiving last year, I stopped at Runza every day to get my fill. The last day I bought a dozen, froze them and packed them for my trip back to Vermont. I made it back to Burlington in time to see the Husker / Colorado game and enjoyed my Runzas with my New England friends. I just wish there was some way to get Runzas mailed to me.
 I too am from Nebraska like Larry the Cable Guy. Actually I am from Sutton, NE... 
I too am from Nebraska like Larry the Cable Guy. Actually I am from Sutton, NE where I believe the first runzas were made many, many years ago. Last Wednesday I accidentally crashed into a Runza restaurant. I was looking to see if they were open and put my foot on the gas pedal instead of the brake. It was a very unfortunate accident but no one was seated in the restaurant and I was not hurt. They were able to open on time but with plywood in the one window. They assured me that my name would not appear in the newspaper but the next day an article read Runza Rammed by Chevrolet. It identified the driver as a 66 year old woman from Sutton, NE driving a 2010 Chevrolet Equinox. Needless to say the minute the morning paper was delivered the phone started ringing. In a town of 1,400 everyone knew exactly who the driver was. I was going to meet my daughter and little grandson at 11:00 and had arrived early. All my grandson could say was, &quot;grandma why did you have to hit the Runza Rex one?&quot; Anyway that is my story and I do not know if I will return to that particular location for awhile.
 I have a Runzatic story for you….My husband is from Lincoln and he introduced me to Runzas... 
I have a Runzatic story for you….My husband is from Lincoln and he introduced me to Runzas when we first started dating in 1986. We live in Minneapolis, Minnesota and every time we are in Lincoln the first place we stop, even before connecting up with family, is at a Runza Restaurant for our fix. This last visit we stopped and picked up 3 dozen frozen Runzas to take home until we can come back. We have been known to make a Runza Run just for our Runza fix. A quick trip down to the closest Runza we can find which is in Blair, Nebraska. We take off for a quick trip have supper and to purchase frozen Runzas and the turn around and head home. This last batch I shared some with my co-workers and they LOVED them, and have asked when we will make our next Runza Run, because they want to order their own supply!!! I guess we have started the underground Runza Pipeline. We really need a Runza in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Your crazy and devoted Minneapolis, Minnesota Runzatic Fans! Cindy and Jack
 Ever since I was real little, I&apos;ve LOVED Runza french fries... 
Ever since I was real little, I&apos;ve LOVED Runza french fries. Whenever me and my mom go to Runza, she asks what I want, and I just say, &quot;A large order of fries&quot; before my main meal. After my volleyball tournaments we always go to Runza in celebration. I love it!!
 Whenever I ask my fiance where she wants to go for a nice dinner, she answers, &quot;Runza!&quot; 
Whenever I ask my fiance where she wants to go for a nice dinner, she answers, &quot;Runza!&quot; For many months, I would chuckle at the fact that I gave her the choice of any restaurant and she would come up with Runza everytime. None the less, I gave in everytime. When we go to Runza we enjoy the time together and the delicious Runza sandwich! Now, when she asks me where I want to go for dinner, I answer, &quot;Runza!&quot; Runza has become our special thing and we absolutely love it - there is nothing better.
 You have just the best food for the whole family... 
You have just the best food for the whole family. Our little ones, Ma and Pa and even Grandpa and Grandma. Twenty four grandchildren - 12 girls and 12 boys all love to eat at the family Runza.
 I recently moved to Columbus, Ohio where there are no Runzas... 
I recently moved to Columbus, Ohio where there are no Runzas and I have been going absolutely crazy!! I have been having dreams almost every night about Runza food - especially your frings! I am also currently pregnant and have been craving Runza even more. The first place I am going to go the next time I am in Nebraska is RUNZA!! I want my baby to know what good food is!!!
 I lived in Nebraska my whole life so I grew up on Runza... 
I lived in Nebraska my whole life so I grew up on Runza. However after college I moved out to Denver where I sadly learned that there are no Runzas. One day I had such a craving for a Runza that I checked out your website for the first time. I entered in my zip code in the store locator and was shocked when I learned that there was a Runza in Loveland, CO. Loveland is about a 2 and a half hour round trip from where I live. But I wanted a Runza so badly that I drove all the way there just to get one. I ended up buying 12 Runzas so I could have some throughout the week. I also ended up giving one to a fellow Nebraskan I know also living out here in Denver. He is planning on making the trip up to Loveland in the near future to not only get more Runza for himself but also for me.
 I worked at Runza when I was 16 years old. I know first hand that it was always made that day and they use quality ingredients... 
I worked at Runza when I was 16 years old. I know first hand that it was always made that day and they use quality ingredients. I stopped working there a long time ago,yet still now, at age 33, I still crave it!
 As singers, we are traveling on the road all the time. And a lot of times we&apos;re hungry... 
As singers, we are traveling on the road all the time. And a lot of times we&apos;re hungry, but don&apos;t have much time. Of course that doesn&apos;t matter, because Runza is fast, friendly and the food is GREAT! With four girls, deciding where to eat could be time-consuming, but not if there is a Runza around! That is the restaurant all four of us will pick, hands down. In fact, every town we&apos;ve been to, if there is a Runza; we&apos;ve eaten there. So I guess you could say, &quot;We&apos;re Runzatics!&quot; ~ McClellan Singing Sisters
 I was born in Omaha and moved to Kansas at a very young age... 
I was born in Omaha and moved to Kansas at a very young age. We still had family in Lincoln and so we would visit often for football games and holidays. Every time we came up, my family and I always stopped at the Runza in Neb City on the way to Lincoln and would eat there on the way home also.  If it was a long visit we would even convince our mom to eat Runza in Lincoln. I love Runza so much it may have had a small influence on where I went to school, but don&apos;t tell my parents. I am now a proud student at UNL and my friends and I eat there at least once a week. I love the fries and hamburgers and I will never pass up a great cheese Runza!!!
 For as long as I can remember, my family always went out to eat at our local Runza restaurant... 
For as long as I can remember, my family always went out to eat at our local Runza restaurant. I remember getting a cheeseburger while the rest of my family ate Runza sandwiches. I loved those crinkly fries, too! Many years later, I decided to try a Runza. I loved it at first bite! I realized what my family loved so much about them. Now that I&apos;m an adult, I cherrish those special family moments we had, and the memories will last me a lifetime. Now, I take my kids to Runza to eat, like a family tradition.
 I went out last Saturday night for a drive around town and had a sudden craving for some french fries... 
I went out last Saturday night for a drive around town and had a sudden craving for some french fries. Unfortunately, I didn&apos;t take the time to find a Runza resturant, and stopped at a competitors out of convience. BIG Mistake! The fries were horrible! Soggy, under-cooked, and oversalted, or in other words, just plain yucky! Today while out and about I took the time and went out of my way to go to a Runza, and man was it worth it! The fries were wonderful! I have always told my friends, and I will continue to, Runza&apos;s Fries are The Best!
 My husband and I were watching the Food Network and the Runza Sandwich was profiled... 
My husband and I were watching the Food Network and the Runza Sandwich was profiled. We just had to try this sandwich so we left Michigan the next morning and drove all the way to Lincoln, Nebraska to have our fix. It was the best tasting sandwich we had ever had. We are actually thinking about doing it again this summer because there are no Runza&apos;s in our area, but we sure wish there was.
 I was born and raised in Lincoln, Nebraska and so I can remember going to Runza... 
I was born and raised in Lincoln, Nebraska and so I can remember going to Runza when the very first one appeared on the road to Pioneer Park. Obviously, I am dating myself here, but I have loved them since the doors first opened. In 2004 I moved to Seattle, WA where they, unfortunately, do not have nor have they heard of Runzas. (Marketing should look into this.) Since the day I moved here I have been craving Runzas and had actually called to see if you would ship any to me on dry ice, but unfortunately that isn&apos;t your policy. Throughout time I have mentioned to friends how I am missing my Runzas and everyone said you can &quot;fill up&quot; when you&apos;re back again. Well, my very good friend, Kay, heard the hunger in my voice and for my birthday this year she purchased 20 Runzas, packed them in dry ice and sent them to me in Seattle. To say I was thrilled and excited is putting it mildly! I would surmise that I hit a world record of just how fast I could get them from the cooler to the oven so that I could enjoy those tasty treats. And, YES, they are still just as wonderful as I remember them from many years gone by! I will be back to Nebraska this fall and rest assured, I will be a steady customer while there and packing them up to bring back home.
 Being from Iowa, never ever hearing of a Runza restaurant before... 
Being from Iowa, never ever hearing of a Runza restaurant before or even a Runza sandwich. So one night at college my friends wanted to go to Runza. I had no idea what they were talking about so I asked them what it was. They looked at me like I was crazy. They said that Runza was the best tasting sandwich in town, they had great service and the atmosphere was amazing. I had a Runza and it was the best tasting thing I ever tried. The cheese was melted the meat was amazing and the dough was so fresh right from the oven taste. Now some people might say that their freshman year of college they gained the ‘freshman fifteen’ from the cafeteria food, but I’m pretty sure I got mine from eating at Runza all the time!  Leanne
 I decided to move to Colorado from Nebraska after college... 
I decided to move to Colorado from Nebraska after college. I was excited to go, but worried about missing two things: Husker football and Runza. For the first year, I satisfied both cravings together when I went back to Nebraska. Then I discovered Runza was in Fort Collins AND Loveland! Excited doesn&apos;t even begin to describe how I felt! Now my Runza road trips are much shorter!
 I grew up in Omaha. My earliest memory is the smell of Runzas... 
I grew up in Omaha. My earliest memory is the smell of Runzas in the bag on the front seat of my mother&apos;s car. Even at three years old, I enjoyed a Runza. In high school, one of my best friends had a summer job at Runza. I had the privilege of seeing how they were made. During my college years out-of-state, I would stock my freezer with the half-baked Runzas. Now that I live in Texas, my family and I visit Omaha every summer. The first meal I want when we cross the state line is a cheese Runza. My husband and children now get to experience the taste that I have enjoyed for over forty years.  Lisa   Austin, TX
 Recently went on a storm chasing tour in Nebraska and our guide introduced me to your ONION RINGS!!!! 
Recently went on a storm chasing tour in Nebraska and our guide introduced me to your ONION RINGS!!!! Oh, that the dastardly deed could be undone... Now I&apos;m stuck in Mississippi in Runza withdrawal! Food good enough to make you move to Nebraska!!!!!
 We love Runza....and go out of our way to get them... 
We love Runza....and go out of our way to get them. One day we went to Norfolk, NE, did some shopping and were on our way home when we realized we forgot to get our &quot;Runza fix&quot;. We were about 20 miles out of town, but we turned around, went back, and enjoyed a delicious Runza. We also took some home with us because we don&apos;t get the chance to get them very often.
 Each year while traveling, I&apos;ll go out of my way to find a Runza restaurant in the heartland of the country... 
Each year while traveling, I&apos;ll go out of my way to find a Runza restaurant in the heartland of the country. Keep in mind I live in Phoenix, Az,,,,but grew up on Runza&apos;s in Lincoln, NE. 1500 miles is NOT too far to travel to enjoy a Runza sandwich!! When in the area of a Runza location, I&apos;ll stop by for lunch or dinner every day to get my fill of the best sandwich there is! Truly the BEST! Larry
 I first had a Runza when I was little, on vacation with my mom... 
I first had a Runza when I was little, on vacation with my mom. We would travel to North Platte, Neb. to see my Aunt, Uncle and cousins. We ate at Runza one day and I fell in love with it. This is the first time I remember ever craving a certain food. Since that day, I wait all year to have one when we go up. Now, I&apos;m a mom and my babies crave them too. We are heading to North Platte this summer to get more and visit family. We always buy frozen ones by the case to take home to eat and share with people who have not ever had the pleasure of eating one! Thanks Runza!!
 Yes, it&apos;s true. When we go to town and its time to eat what do you hear? &quot;RUNZA!&quot; 
Yes, it&apos;s true. When we go to town and its time to eat what do you hear? &quot;RUNZA!&quot; Just ask my 5&amp;10 year old...They like everything at RUNZA! You can always count on a good meal. Everything from salads, to burgers, to french fries to the slushies. You have our family covered.
 We own a cabin in Berwil, Nebraska. Every other weekend we take a drive up... 
We own a cabin in Berwil, Nebraska. Every other weekend we take a drive up and stop at your fantastic restaurant along the way. We just love the burgers and fries and a shake to top it off. I look forward to enjoying the fantastic food. It&apos;s always hot and fresh.
 I&apos;m a really picky eater. When I go to fast food restaurants I like my hamburgers plain, and my french fries hot and fresh... 
I&apos;m a really picky eater. When I go to fast food restaurants I like my hamburgers plain, and my french fries hot and fresh. I have always had a problem with most fast food restaurants not getting my order correct or the food not being fresh except for RUNZA. RUNZA has the best fries ever and the best hamburgers, and they always get my order right. Keep up the good work. Noah
 I am originally from NE where we have loads of Runza&apos;s! My family&amp;I moved to Barr Nunn, WY 3 yrs ago... 
I am originally from NE where we have loads of Runza&apos;s! My family&amp;I moved to Barr Nunn, WY 3 yrs ago&amp;we&apos;ve been craving them! I had to make a quick trip to Scottsbluff over memorial weekend. I called ahead&amp;had them freeze me a dozen half-baked ones! If I had had more room in the cooler I would have taken back more! By Sunday they were all gone! Same fantastic flavor&amp;taste that we remembered ! Hows about opening a Runza in Casper!
 Rushing around all day long, not enough time to even think or relax a minute... 
Rushing around all day long, not enough time to even think or relax a minute. Time to drive home through all the traffic and I was running late. I had talked to my husband earlier in the day and we both had the same type of day. We both said, &quot;Eat dinner when you can and don&apos;t wait for me.&quot; I pulled into Runza which was sort of on the way home and there was my husband doing the same thing. So funny!! We both thought the same thing!! Runza!!
 Well, I worked for Runza during my years of High School and then came back for breaks during college... 
Well, I worked for Runza during my years of High School and then came back for breaks during college. And I still love it! Currently I work for a college as an Admissions Counselor that brings prospective students to our school. Of the students that are visiting 90% of them are from out of state. While they are in town I always bring them to Runza (over the summer when our cafeteria is closed) so that they get to experience something from Nebraska while they are here, and I ALWAYS make them try a Runza! The positives of this is 1. They get the &quot;Runza Experience&quot; and 2. The school pays for me to get this fantasic food. Shannon
 I admit it, I&apos;m a Runzatic! 
I admit it, I&apos;m a Runzatic! Every week, I enjoy going to the YMCA in Blair, NE. I join a great group of ladies in the &quot;water aerobics&quot; class. We come together from miles around, working towards a common goal of good health! There is nothing like a vigorus swim class to get your appetite going. Our Runza is just down the street from the &quot;Y&quot; and I enjoy stopping there after class every night. To keep my diet in check, I order up one of Runza&apos;s great tasting salads. After swimming, me and my &quot;Y&quot; buddies are at Runza, enjoying great food and conversations. Make mine a &quot;Southwest Chicken Salad&quot; please! Oh, could you make that &quot;grilled chicken &quot;? YES!! Runza you are awesome!
 I have been eating Runza since I was a little girl. It always tastes great... 
I have been eating Runza since I was a little girl. It always tastes great and I crave it daily. When I was pregnant with my daughter I would order a Runza with Onion Rings and Onion Ring dipping sauce about 4-5 times a week for lunch or dinner. The onion rings are always so fresh and crispy! I know they are made fresh every morning and that care and attention to quality comes through in every delicious bite. I fed my daughter Runza as soon as she was old enough to eat it, and she loves your food just as much as I do. My mom is a big Runza fan too. So there are 3 generations of Runzatics in my family alone, and Runza will be a favorite fast food restaurant for more to come!
 The food is great. My favorites are the onion rings, cheeseburgers and french fries... 
The food is great. My favorites are the onion rings, cheeseburgers and french fries. There just aren&apos;t any other places that can beat the taste. Anytime is a great experience to eat at Runza.
 I was born and raised in Nebraska and ate Runzas regularly for 28 years until I moved in 1998... 
I was born and raised in Nebraska and ate Runzas regularly for 28 years until I moved in 1998. Now my husband and kids and I focus on the first thing we eat when we get off the plane when visiting - RUNZAs. If we drive we know where every Runza is in western Nebraska so we can time it right to hit it for our lunch or dinner or last lunch or dinner at Runza. We eat there every day we are there also! I also make them homemade (not as good and very labor intensive!) for an afternoon once a month so we have them on hand in the freezer! Wish we had Runzas here in Las Vegas!
 Well, my daughter and family moved to Grand Island... 
Well, my daughter and family moved to Grand Island. I had never been to Grand Island and am from Jacksonville, Fl. You can&apos;t get too much farther away :) Anyway, I tried Runza and fell in love with their food. The burgers are real meat and the chicken is cooked moist and wonderful, fresh bread and veggies, WOW what a concept!!!!! Well, I have tried to get my daughter to mail me some burgers and chicken sandwiches but she said they would go bad before I got them. So, I came to Grand Island to visit them, but I had to stop at Runza immediately after we left the airport. My daughter said I didn&apos;t come to see her but to eat at Runza. Should I tell her she is wrong or tell her that she might be a little right?!?!?
 One time I was with all my friends in high school and we couldn&apos;t decide on what to eat... 
One time I was with all my friends in high school and we couldn&apos;t decide on what to eat. Someone said, &quot;I want frys.&quot; I then insisted that we had to go to Runza because they have the best frys and ranch. With the greatest sandwich around. All that fresh ground beef, cabbage, onion and special spieces all baked inside that warm homemade bread! I love Runza and always will.
 Runza is the only food I will wait to eat until I get home... 
Runza is the only food I will wait to eat until I get home.  All other fast food meals I eat right away, but I always wait to savor my Runza sandwich at my kitchen table.
 I grew up in Fairbury, NE and have been a Runza nut for as long as I can recall... 
I grew up in Fairbury, NE and have been a Runza nut for as long as I can recall. I moved to Northwest Colorado in 2000 and have been in &quot;Runza Crave&quot; mode since. I make it back to Nebraska occasionally and make sure I stop and get a Runza. It was a great thing to learn that Fairbury had recently opened up a store! Back in November 2008, my husband and I made a road trip all the way to Scottsbluff, NE. The first thing I asked when we arrived is if there was a Runza in town. Sure enough, there was! We stopped and ate lunch there on the way back to Colorado. I called my folks back in Fairbury and told them I was eating a Runza. My mom couldn&apos;t believe I drove all the way to Scottsbluff just to eat Runza!
 My first job was at the Runza in Norfolk, Nebraska. I loved working there... 
My first job was at the Runza in Norfolk, Nebraska. I loved working there and look forward to eating there every time I&apos;m back home. I now live in Minnesota and crave them on a regular basis. I love the Runza&apos;s, the burgers and of course the chicken sandwiches. I am passing my love for the restaurant onto my 3 children and they know that for every special ocassion whether it&apos;s birthday, Christmas or Easter they are going to be getting Runza gift cards. Thank you for making a quality product, I saw first hand how they were made and I love knowing the in&apos;s and out&apos;s of the wonderful food that you make. Sincerely, Justine a.k.a. your biggest fan from Minnesota.
 As Lincoln, NE natives my husband and I grew up on Runzas! 
As Lincoln, NE natives my husband and I grew up on Runzas! We moved out of state 4 years ago, but make regular trips back to Omaha and Lincoln, sometimes just to eat at Runza! The hot, fresh sandwiches, crisp fries and perfectly seasoned onion rings are the perfect excuse for a 3 hour road trip!
 My roommate and I are both from Nebraska so we grew to love (or obsess over) Runza at an early age... 
My roommate and I are both from Nebraska so we grew to love (or obsess over) Runza at an early age. We, however, live in Kansas City for school right now and there are no Runzas to be found for many miles. One day, an overwhelming craving hit us and we needed to have some of the famous runzas and delicious crinkle fries. So, we did what any self-respecting, runza-loving Nebraskan would do. We roadtripped to the nearest Runza in Lawrence, KS. Best roadtrip... EVER.
 So, I&apos;m from Texas, and never actually BEEN to a Runza restaurant. But... 
So, I&apos;m from Texas, and never actually BEEN to a Runza restaurant. But my Dad is from Kansas and my stepfather from Nebraska, and they both talk about Runza sandwiches. My friend who goes to college with me in Texas is from Nebraska, and I told her to bring me down a Runza sandwich to try, because she raves about them as well. She brought down four, and we ate them within the week. Ever since then, each time she goes back, I give her money for her to bring back Runza sandwiches. It&apos;s an addiction from 550 miles away!
 My latest Runza experience happened yesterday on my birthday! 
My latest Runza experience happened yesterday on my birthday! My sweet dumplin&apos; husband took me out for a Mushroom and Swiss Runza in Fremont NE. He knows me so well! We have been married for 32 years and for all of those years Runza has been my favorite place to eat! I guess now that I think of it, after 32 years of hearing how I love RUNZAS how could he get it wrong?!?!?! Thanks for helping him make my 51st birthday a perfect day! Sheryl
 I used to live in Omaha for 20 some years... 
I used to live in Omaha for 20 some years. I ate at Runza regularly as I really enjoyed the Runza and the Mushroom Cheese Burgers. During the time I was there I would introduce people to Runza and any time someone was passing through, we would always stop and get a good meal and half a dozen frozen Runzas to go. 10 years ago I moved to Kansas City. Not a Runza in sight until one day my mother was passing through Lawrence and spotted a Runza. She stopped and bought some frozen Runzas and now I travel over 20 miles just to get a meal and another bag of frozen Runzas. Obviously I don&apos;t have Runzas as often as I might like, but I would consider myself a true Runzatic. Let&apos;s face it, I have been eating them for over a quarter of a century! That has got to say something about my devotion to the Runza. In fact, my family and I are about to make another trip to Lawrence, just to have lunch at Runza. Just wish one was a little closer.
 A few years ago, my son Luke and I were... 
A few years ago, my son Luke and I were planning a fishing trip with a large group to Canada. We thought we&apos;d be cool and &quot;smuggle&quot; a few Runzas north of the border to make our friends jealous. One day during a cold and rainy break in the fishing action, we secretly heated the Runzas up and suddenly someone said they thought it smelled like Runza. Imagine the look on their faces when we pulled them out of the oven, sat down in front of them and began feasting on a hot Runza. They still talk about the unfairness of that day.  Mike
 A very, very sad story... 
A very, very sad story...... I moved to Milwaukee, WI 3 years ago, after being born and raised in Grand Island. I never realized that Runza was not a nationwide franchise until I drove around Milwaukee looking for my Runza fix, to find out the nearest one was over 500 miles away. A very sad day. However, since I did work for Midwest Airlines which provides non-stop service to Eppley Air Field, I hopped on Flight #151 to Omaha one afternoon to fulfill my Runza fix on my day off.  I had preordered a dozen Runza&apos;s to kidnap and bring back to Milwaukee to enjoy when I was going through my most extreme withdrawals from my Runza&apos;s! When I was back for the Nebraska/Colorado game over Thanksgiving, I found the closest Runza vendor and ate 3 of them without taking a single drink of pop. I couldn&apos;t tell you if I was more excited for the Runza&apos;s I enjoyed that day, or the win we pulled off against the Buffs.
 We were heading back from Lincoln to Denver... 
We were heading back from Lincoln to Denver after watching the Huskers dismantle my Huskies. We got off 80 to head for McCook,&amp;I saw the Runza sign. I&apos;d read about &quot;a heap of Husker hospitality&quot; on the Huskerpedia website, so I stopped. My buddy ordered a mushroom Runza&amp;fries,&amp;went to the mens room. I ordered a BBQ&amp;a mushroom Runza (and a GREAT cookie), paid for our food,&amp;went out to our RV. I was driving as we headed south for Hwy 34, when my buddy exclaims &quot;Oh, my God! This is great!&quot; We Runza&apos;d down the road,&amp;when my buddy finished his, he said &quot;Dang, I should have gotten two!&quot; I replied, &quot;I did.&quot; He was less than happy. Now, whenever I&apos;m in Colorado, I usually jump up to Loveland or Ft Collins for Runza, sometimes to freeze&amp;take home to Seattle. When I took my best friend to Ft Collins last year, she declined a Runza, not knowing what it was,&amp;went for a burger&amp;she said it was absolutely great, but I stick with Runza. I make runza myself from a recipe I got on the &apos;net for special occasions, and while they&apos;re good, it ain&apos;t the same.
 Hello, I am originally from Ralston... 
Hello, I am originally from Ralston, Nebraska and have lived in Portland, OR for about 8 years. I often talk to friends about Runzas, but they really have no idea how yummy they really are. Since Runzas are no where close to me, I always look forward to coming home. Anytime I do go home, Runza is the first place I stop after picking up my luggage. My own ritual!! I will be heading to Omaha for Christmas and will be stopping by to have one or two. This year I plan on ordering a couple cases and bringing them back home to share with my friends. Oh, and you can&apos;t pass up those awesome french fries!! No other place has come close to those. Erin
 This really isn&apos;t about me... 
This really isn&apos;t about me--even though I am a true lifetime Runza follower!! In my family--there are 6 adult siblings--5 of us live here in Lincoln--the 6th one--Marci--lives in Wasilla, Alaska. (Yes--actually neighbors with Sarah Palin!!) We draw names yearly and try to out do each other with the &quot;perfect&quot; gift. Well, you probably know where this is headed... I have Marci&apos;s name this year--and I am sending her 12 Runzas for Christmas!! She will absolutely LOVE it!! Marci has tried to get a Runza Restaurant in Alaska--but so far--no luck!! Julia
 My mother grew up in Nebraska and each time... 
My mother grew up in Nebraska and each time we visit our grandfather in Lincoln, we look forward to the delectable Runza that we eat each day for lunch. My wife and I now travel out to Nebraska each year for Thanksgiving to be with my grandfather. He&apos;s 97 years old and looks forward to taking his grandson to Runza every day for lunch. My co-workers think I&apos;m crazy when I send them cell phone pictures of me eating a Runza!
 Our football team loves Runza! Every Saturday morning... 
Our football team loves Runza! Every Saturday morning, about six of us daydream about Runza&apos;s during practice. As soon as we get into the locker room, the &quot;Runza Guys&quot; head over to the local Runza. We love the homestyle atmosphere, and the service is great! Nothing is better on a brisk Saturday morning than a hot steamy Runza!
 I raised my family in Nebraska and moved to... 
I raised my family in Nebraska and moved to Colorado about 25 years ago. During my years in Nebraska, we had many wonderful meals of Runzas and fries and onion rings and shakes. My oldest son, Monty, introduced us to these unique sandwiches that he got from the stand at 6th and Van Dorn in 1959. After our move, we found out that Runzas are not available in our area. Therefore, everytime I return to visit family and friends in Nebraska, I make it a point to have a Runza meal a couple of times during my visit. Then, my son suggested that I take home some frozen Runzas to share with my family in Colorado. So, now every visit results in a dozen frozen Runzas making the trip back to Colorado with me. My Lincolnite son also brings a dozen frozen Runzas when he comes to visit. The whole family (2 sons, 2 daughters-in-law and one dauther-in-law&apos;s sister) gather around my dining room table and share Runzas, french fries, onion rings and shakes--just like some of the best times of my life in Nebraska.
 I was born in Omaha and lived there until... 
I was born in Omaha and lived there until I was 7 years old, and then we moved to Texas. Our whole extended family still lives in Nebraska, though, so just about every year since 1989, we&apos;ve been back to Nebraska to visit them for the Christmas holidays or the summer. Despite being a Nebraska native, I never experienced the joy of a Runza Oven-Stuffed Sandwich until I was a teenager. My parents would always make a beeline for Runza as soon as we&apos;d get to Nebraska, but I never understood the fascination. &quot;Cabbage and beef? Really?&quot; I thought. But then, on one fateful trip, my parents said &quot;Just try it.&quot; I did, and it was a tasty party in my mouth. Ever since then (and that was about 13 years ago), I have become a rabid Runza fanatic. Whenever we go to Nebraska, I immediately head for the nearest Runza and make a point of eating there as often as possible during our trips. If possible, I purchase frozen Runzas from the stores and take them home with me. My husband, a Texas native, tried his first Runza a few years ago and now he&apos;s hooked too. Currently, we live in Indiana, but we&apos;re going to Omaha for Thanksgiving and I can&apos;t wait to get there. I&apos;m jonesing for a cheese Runza in a bad way! Viva la Runza!
 We love Runza soooooo much... 
We love Runza soooooo much. We moved away 7 years ago but think nothing of driving 1 1/2 hrs to eat at Runza. We have it down to a science, we can drive to Wayne, NE (little over an hour); Fremont, NE (1hr 20 min); or Omaha, NE (1hr 30 min). This is usually what we do. We love eating at the 108th&amp;Q location. I wish Runza would come on up Interstate 29 to Sioux City. We miss you.
 My wife Jillian and I love to go to our local Runza regularly... 
My wife Jillian and I love to go to our local Runza regularly for the delicious Runzas and fries, but we didn&apos;t realize just how often we go until this one time, when a new cashier was ringing up our order. She was having a hard time punching our order into the register, so she went to get the manager for help. As the manager was showing her the right buttons to push, she told the new employee, &quot;Oh, these two are here all the time!&quot; referring to my wife and me. It was at that moment that we realized that we must truly be like the Runzatics that we read about on the back of the receipts all the time. ~~Justin
 I come from Newcastle which is in North East England... 
I come from Newcastle which is in North East England and moved to Nebraska two years ago. Newcastle is famed for its meat based pasties. When I moved to Nebraska I missed the pasties and couldn&apos;t find a good substitute. My wife, persudaded me to go to Runza. I wasn&apos;t too fond of fast food so I was reluctant to go. However, when I got there I realized Runza isn&apos;t fast food. The first time I had a Runza I immediately fell in love with it. The hot beef and warm fresh bread reminded me of the pasties of home. Everytime we have a visitor from England we always take them to Runza, for a real taste of Nebraska!
 I was born in Omaha and moved to Texas in 1986... 
I was born in Omaha and moved to Texas in 1986. Last week I was randomly driving around Loveland, Colorado visiting my grandparents. By some miracle, we passed one of the two Runza&apos;s in the state of Colorado. My husband was driving, and I started screaming and banging on the window when I saw the Runza and made him turn around so I could get a Runza. It had been 10 years since my last Runza, and boy was it good. My grandparents didn&apos;t even know there was a Runza in Loveland, and they have lived in the area 10 years.
 I just have to say that all my friends know that we have a family of Runzatics... 
 I just have to say that all my friends know that we have a family of Runzatics. I really fell hard for Runza&apos;s food when I was pregnant with my first child, and I had terrible morning sickness (all-day sickness, really). My husband and I ventured to a fairly new Runza, and I ordered the only thing I thought I could handle... Runza&apos;s chicken strips. Oh...My...Goodness. I was hooked. They became a serious craving, and if there was a food that sounded good during that difficult time, I HAD to have it. And so it began. My husband had already been a fan of Runza, but I was new to the game, so to speak. Throughout my pregnancy and about a year later, another pregnancy, we made Runza a special place. Our family ate there after church, for lunches with my husband during the work day, and some dinners when I just needed those onion rings. I ventured out in trying different Runza foods. The burgers are by far, the BEST, and now I am hooked on the smothered grilled chicken sandwich. My entire family loves the food. It raises the bar on &quot;fast food&quot; eateries. The icing on the cake is the warm, homey atmosphere that Runza is known for. If I am talking to my friends and tell them I took the kids and met the hubby for lunch, they just smile at me and say, &quot;Let me guess, Runza?&quot; One last thing I have to admit, I have the Runzatic promo posted on my Facebook page. Am I a Runzatic, or what?! 
 I was eating in at Runza and I really didn’t want to eat there... 
 I was eating in at Runza and I really didn’t want to eat there and I had one of the Kansas City cheeseburgers and it changed my whole mind about Runza. It was the best cheeseburger in the world and now every chance I can I am always eating at Runza. Runza is the best place and maybe the healthiest if I had to pick from any other restaurant. 
 My wife and I first met inside a wonderful Runza establishment... 
 My wife and I first met inside a wonderful Runza establishment in Lincoln, Nebraska. We dated for a couple years and each anniversary we would return to the birthplace of our relationship. Last year while I convinced her to sit down while I got our order I slipped an engagement ring into her crinkle fries. When I returned her face lit up, I don’t know if it was the fries or the ring; needless to say we are now happily married and love Runza. Thank you Runza!!!! - Jake 
 I lived in South Georgia after college... 
 I lived in South Georgia after college, and would fly home to visit my family. The first place my Dad would take me after we left the airport in Lincoln would be Runza. I couldn&apos;t wait to have my favorite cheese Runza on Nebraska soil! 
 Last week my family came in from California... 
 Last week my family came in from California.  They said they never had Runza so I took them to my favorite spot &quot;Runza&quot; and we had a delicious meal.  My cousin said that it was the best burger he has ever had!!!   Thank you Runza! 
 Seven years ago I met the most wonderful man alive... 
 Seven years ago I met the most wonderful man alive. On our first date, he took me to a Runza where I enjoyed my first ever Cheese Runza! I enjoyed every savory bite of that sandwich and every crinkle of those fries! I demanded that we make Runza a regular date occasion for us. Well, it worked out. Three years later (to the date) he bought me my last Cheese Runza as a single woman and proposed right there in the dining room. Of course I said Yes! We had a small wedding, family and close friends only, and guess what we served... that’s right, Cheese Runza minis! Everyone loved it. We have now been married for four years and still keep that once a week date night at Runza! Thanks for all the great memories! :) 
 I am originally from England... 
 I am originally from England. Back in 2000, I met a beautiful Nebraskan lady who was on vacation in England. We kept in touch after she returned home and I came over to visit her over Christmas/New Year 2000/2001. I had never been to the USA before, yet alone Nebraska. On my first day over here she took me to Runza for lunch. She told me that I had to try the Runza sandwich, which I did. I instantly fell in love with Runza, and her of course, and returned later in 2001 and married her. Since then I have visited Runza several times and eaten many Runza sandwiches. 
 I am a nurse at Madonna Rehabilitation Hospital in Lincoln... 
 I am a nurse at Madonna Rehabilitation Hospital in Lincoln, Nebraska. We frequently get younger individuals from Kansas that have had an accident or event happen to them that they need rehab for. Once I find out that they are not from Nebraksa, I tell them that they cannot EVEN go home without trying Runza! I then make a trip to the closet Runza when I get off work and get them a Runza and fries on my dime. I always tell them that Runza has the best fries EVER!!!! Not only do they love the Runza&apos;s but are tickeled to get &quot;non-hospital&quot; food for a change. Pretty soon you will need to have franchises all over in Kansas because I am getting all those Kansans hooked on your food. Thanks for making a great product.  -  Jody 
 My most memorable RUNZA story would have to be the day... 
 My most memorable RUNZA story would have to be the day I went there for lunch to meet my realtor and signed the papers on my first house. YEAH! It was a very good day and a very good lunch. Thanks..... 
 My most memorable Runza experience is tasting their delicious Smoothies... 
 My most memorable Runza experience is tasting their delicious Smoothies. 
 Hello, Runza girl speaking... 
 Hello, Runza girl speaking. I go to school at Baylor down in Waco, Texas. But I&apos;ve grown up all my life in Lincoln, and on the deliciousness that is the Runza. At first, it was hard for me to make freinds at Baylor. But when I came back from my first break in college, I brought back a couple Runzas, and lo and behold people loved them. Ever since I&apos;ve been bringing them back by the box fulls. And lucky for me, the new friends just keep coming. Thank you Runza, I sure do love you! 
 Actually taking frozen Runza&apos;s on an airplane to North Carolina... 
 Actually taking frozen Runza&apos;s on an airplane to North Carolina for a friends one year wedding anniversary gift (per request)! 
 While my sister now lives in Rapid City, SD... 
 While my sister now lives in Rapid City, SD, she grew up here in Lincoln and loves regular Runza sandwiches. Since there is NO Runza in Rapid City (hint hint) she often craves them. We have several Runza memories together such as taking frozen Runza&apos;s up to her every time I go to Rapid to visit, or when she visits here,driving through very late at night to get one more &quot;fix&quot; before she goes back home. Our favorite memory however, would have to be meeting in Sidney, NE to enjoy a Runza together! There is nothing quite like enjoying a fresh, hot Runza sandwich and fries with your sister. The pleasure is only enhanced after the aniticpation when driving 4 or 5 hours for this savory treat. While we enjoy these special sporadic Runzatic moments we could never have too many.....so please consider opening a Runza in Rapid City!! 
 My father took me to my first Nebraska Football game as a boy... 
 My father took me to my first Nebraska Football game as a boy. When we reached Lincoln that windy autumn Saturday, we were both hungry and we joined the crowd heading to Runza. After each having a Runza and french fries, my father asked if I was still hungry. I said, &quot;sure&quot; and he ordered us some onion rings, which we shared and finished as quickly considering how hot they were. Each year, we would return to Lincoln for our whatever game we could get tickets to and we always included Runza as our pregame meal. When I was a college student at UNL, my dad was more frequent in his attendence of games. And we always reconnected over a meal at Runza (his treat) and, of course, we topped it off with an order of onion rings. - Jeff/Omaha 
 I live in Iowa and travel to Nebraska for my job... 
 I live in Iowa and travel to Nebraska for my job one week every month. In typical fashion I was running late for an appointment but of course was hungry.....the only restaurant I saw was a Runza that I happened to passing by or a McDonalds....I stopped at Runza...I had NO IDEA.....now every time I am in Nebraska, the highlight of my day is to drive through Runza and get the Banana smoothie, the Cheeseburger Runza and the fries or rings....it never varies....I have been known to eat Runza every single evening when my day is done....and then take one home just in case....did not know you can order them frozen and have delivered....have you thought of moving more into Iowa?????? Please?????? 
 My most memorable Runza experience is riding bikes... 
 My most memorable Runza experience is riding bikes with my son to Runza for lunch and ice-cream.  We enjoy the burgers as much as the bike ride! 
 I studied abroad in Limerick, Ireland last semester... 
 I studied abroad in Limerick, Ireland last semester and couldn&apos;t wait to get home to eat Runza. It was the first meal I ate when I got back from abroad. It was just as delicious as I remembered it! 
 My mom used to take me and my brother... 
 My mom used to take me and my brother to Runza every week after my piano lessons. I would look forward to it every week because I LOVE the french fries and onion rings. That was probably one of the only times my brother and I got along and agreed on as our favorite place to go eat. 
 When I was much younger... 
 When I was much younger, I was stationed in Okindawa, Japan. I was on the island for 3 years, and everytime I called home to speak to my parents I would mention to them how much I missed the food at Runza. You can imagine my suprise when at Christmas one year when I picked up a package from the PO box and inside packed in dry ice was a few Runza&apos;s and a message that said, &quot;To carry you over until you can go to Runza yourself, love Mom&amp;Dad!&quot; 
 I was trying to decide on two different colleges... 
 I was trying to decide on two different colleges. They were both really equal which made it a tough decision. What it came down to was one town had a Runza and the other didn&apos;t. Easy choice, the Runza town! I even got a girlfriend at Runza!! I LOVE RUNZA!! 
 Since we were getting married... 
 Since we were getting married back in our hometown, my fiancee and I had to make several trips back home to Norfolk to plan for the big day. As the weekends approaced closer to our wedding date we would dread the trip more. The one thing that we did look forward to was stopping at the new Runza in David City, NE for a tasty burger and a grilled chicken sandwich. We looked forward to that visit to Runza every weekend and now that we are married we remember how important our stop in David City was every weekend leading up to that big moment in our lives. Thank you! 
 My most memorable experience was... 
 My most memorable experience was when I had my wisdom teeth taken out. I could not eat anything for weeks except for soup. So I went to Runza and got a different flavor of soup each day for 2 weeks. It really got me through a tough time. To this day I still love Runza. 
 When I was a little girl I stayed with my grandma... 
 When I was a little girl I stayed with my grandma after school was out each day and during the summer.  At least once a week Grandma, my brother Shawn and I would walk to Runza and get a meal. Now I live in Springfield, Missouri and don&apos;t get the chance to eat there once a week. So once a month I get the chance to go to Kansas City, Missouri for buisness and each time I go, I make the 45 minute drive (one way) to Lawrence, Kansas to get a Cheese Runza and fries.  Then I get an extra one (or two or three, etc..) to go and extra fries for the drive back and eat the others as spread out as I can. I don&apos;t even let my husband have one when I get home. My friends here in Missouri make fun of me driving an hour and a half for some sandwich. I am sure they would change their minds if they ever tried one but I have never been able to give one up! It is even worse when I visit Lincoln. I eat at Runza at least once a day and would eat every meal there if I was allowed. I love the food at Runza. I really wish we had one here in Springfield. - Jenifer 
 I happened to be talking to an out of town friend... 
 I happened to be talking to an out of town friend who moved away from Omaha while I was on my way to Runza. I told her I was headed to get Frings - she just laughed so hard I had to pull over as I started laughing so hard. She wanted Runza so bad that she said I had to keep her on the phone when I ordered and she wanted to hear the crunch of the onion rings. Oh my gosh. She doesn&apos;t have a Runza in KC where she lives so she decided she had to live through me and listen to me eat the Frings - haha!! I did it just for her. 
 My most memorable Runza experience just occured recently when my wife... 
 My most memorable Runza experience just occured recently when my wife, son&amp;I met up with some of our family for a skiing vacation in Colorado. We live in St. Louis, my brother lives in Las Vegas, and my sister and brother-in-law live in Papillion, so you can see that some of us don&apos;t have the convenience of going to Runza any time we want. To our surprise, my sister (who lives in Papillion) brought along a dozen frozen runzas for us to share while up in the mountains! It took my brother and I less than a few hours to forget about skiing and concentrate on baking the runzas at just the perfect time and temp in the unfamiliar altitude of the rockies. Needless to say, our family vacation was made even more memorable (and enjoyable) thanks to Runza!!! 
 We just love Runza&apos;s so much... 
&quot;We just love Runza&apos;s so much, but we live so far away from them. When we go to Omaha to get them, we buy about 3 or 4 DOZEN frozen Runzas and put them in the freezer at home so we can have a Runza whenever we want for a long time. Nothing satisfies like a Runza.&quot;
 When our son was 14... 
&quot;When our son was 14, he got a job at North Forty Golf Course. At that time my husband and I started a &quot;date night&quot; by eating out at Runza (on 56th and Holdrege) on Thursday Nights while our son was working. That was 12 years ago. We still eat out each Thursday night, but now we eat at the Runza at 84th and Holdrege. We are now joined by my husband&apos;s brother and his wife, a friend and his wife from my husband&apos;s work, their son and daughter-in-law and my husband&apos;s cousin. Each Thursday night the 9 of us meet and dine together. So our &quot;date night&quot; has turned into a friendly gathering of friends. Thank You Runza!!&quot;
 My most memorable story was when I was coming home on leave to Nebraska from the Navy... 
&quot;My most memorable story was when I was coming home on leave to Nebraska from the Navy (there are 3 Runzas in my hometown of Hastings). I asked my best friend to bring me three Runzas to the airport so Runza would be the first thing I saw/ate when I got off the plane in Omaha, NE. It was the greatest thing ever. I had been gone from Nebraska for 8 months and that was the best welcome home gift I could ever think of. Thank you Runza for making my coming home memorable! I am stationed out in Washington and thinking right now of how I can get some frozen Runzas shipped out to me!&quot;
 My most memorable Runza experience involves Husker football and of course Runza!... 
&quot;My most memorable Runza experience involves Husker football and of course Runza! About eight months ago I moved to the warm state of Arizona and started to crave Runza sandwiches. I was so sad that I could not get one in Arizona. However, I knew that I would be attending a Husker football game in the following month and that I could get a Runza at the game! When I got to Memorial Stadium I rushed to the first Runza stand I saw and bit into a fresh, hot sandwich. I honestly would have paid $10 for that sandwich :) My day kept getting better when the Huskers won the game! Now that I am living in Nebraska once again, I eat at Runza often and have always had a great experience.&quot;
 I took my 13 month old son to Runza one day. I ordered him chicken strips... 
&quot;I took my 13 month old son to Runza one day. I ordered him chicken strips and myself a Swiss mushroom Runza. I began feeding him first and got him situated. Then I began eating and, of course, he had to have some of my food. I gave him a piece of my Runza and he loved it, mushrooms and all! He wouldn&apos;t eat any of his chicken strips! He loved it so much he took he finger and got some of the swiss cheese off my wrapper!&quot;
 My most memorable Runza memory was when I was pregnant with my 2nd child... 
&quot;My most memorable Runza memory was when I was pregnant with my 2nd child and I was craving vanilla ice cream. It was closing time and they had already shut down the machine. The manager was nice enough to start it back up to give me my ice cream fresh!!!&quot;
 I&apos;ve loved Runza all my life. Over the years... 
&quot;I&apos;ve loved Runza all my life. Over the years I still eat there at least twice a week. If I go out of town, Runza is my first stop on the way home. I&apos;ve even planned road trips so that we hit at least one Runza on the way. It may make for a longer trip, but it is worth it for my Runza&apos;s!&quot;
 For me the story starts in the third grade... 
&quot;For me the story starts in the third grade - I went to my first Nebraska Cornhusker football game at Memorial Stadium. You see I grew up in Oakland Nebraska and fast food restaurants where one of the perks of visiting the city&apos;s shopping mall food court. Runza wasn&apos;t my first choice or even on my radar. At half time of the Husker beat down of Northern Illinois that fall Saturday afternoon while walking with my Dad I ordered the familiar slice of sausage pizza. My father decided he was in the mood for a Runza. I asked, &quot;What is a Runza?&quot; My father described the ingredients and I made a funny face. I thought a Runza sounded terrible. Thanks for the pizza. My dad ordered a Runza from the vendor and offered a bite. I tried it and immediately asked for another. Instead my dad ordered another for me. The pizza ended up in the garbage. I will always remember the day because of my first Husker football experience but the Runza is a detail of the day as important as any other. I can&apos;t wait for the days when my son and I can create the same experiences. - Chris&quot;
 Coming from Chicago, I obviously never experienced... 
&quot;Coming from Chicago, I obviously never experienced Runza. But once I was introduced by a friend, I couldn&apos;t stop. When my family came to visit me, Runza was one of the first places I took them and giving them that first-time experience was priceless. Nothing like chowing down on cheese Runzas with my dad!&quot;
 My husband is from France and when we first met... 
&quot;My husband is from France and when we first met, we went to Runza so I could show him my favorite place for french fries (as it&apos;s so American). We went and he loved the fries too. So now, whenever we go, we call Runza &quot;our place&quot; because that is the place we shared a meal together and my husband&apos;s first meal in the USA.&quot;
 When I was little we lived close to the Runza @ 56th&amp;Holdrege... 
&quot;When I was little we lived close to the Runza @ 56th&amp;Holdrege and at the time there was a laundromat next door. Well my poor mom had to drag us there once a week to do the laundry and the &apos;bribe&apos; was always, &apos;If you&apos;re good... you can get some French fries!&apos; Let me tell you, we were always good. Still to this day my favorite thing is Runza fries with onion ring dip :)&quot;
 After a full day mountain bike ride in the beautiful Colorado mountains... 
&quot;After a full day mountain bike ride in the beautiful Colorado mountains I was really hungry! I had only eaten cereal and some waxy tasting energy bars. I needed real food, and I craved Runza. I ordered my favorite Swiss Mushroom Burger Meal Deal with Onion Rings. It satisfied my hunger. Now, going to Runza is a tradition after a long mountain bike ride. We were starving.&quot;
 On Valentines day my mom my dad and I had Runza. We got it take out and we came home... 
&quot;On Valentines day my mom my dad and I had Runza. We got it take out and we came home. When we got home we pulled the table out and lit some candles. We dimmed the light and tried to make it seam like an expensive restaurant. We dumped all the fries out on a fancy plate in the center of the table and got all our food in our section. That night was really fun because we got to eat Runza and we ate it together in a candle light dinner. I will never forget that memory because it was a great experience.&quot;
 I just moved here from Massachusetts, and WOW... 
&quot;I just moved here from Massachusetts, and WOW, I love Runza! I don&apos;t know how other burger places keep their doors open with Runza in town!&quot;
 My first experience with Runza was when my daughter started attending the University of Nebraska - Lincoln... 
&quot;My first experience with Runza was when my daughter started attending the University of Nebraska - Lincoln. Being from outside the &apos;Runza Territory,&apos; I had never heard of it. During one of my daughter&apos;s first calls home, she just raved about this new drive-in restaurant she had &apos;discovered&apos; and their wonderful Runza Original Sandwich. On my first visit to Lincoln, she insisted that we go to Runza for dinner. I could definitely understand why. Now, every time she comes home for a visit, she brings a sack of goodies from Runza. For Christmas this year, I&apos;m going to drive to the nearest Runza (over an hour away) to buy her Runza Gift Cards for her stocking. I know she&apos;ll love that. Thanks, Runza, for a Christmas gift idea that I know will be a big hit!!!&quot;
 
 
 Privacy Legal Contact
	</body>
</document>
