<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006356" url="http://www.whattoexpect.com/forums/january-2012-babies/topic/is-he-cheating-27" time="2012-07-12-23:03" support="1" score="0.001128456498456152" bingtitle="Is he cheating? - January 2012 Babies - What to Expect.com" webtitle="Is he cheating? - January 2012 Babies - What to Expect.com">
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="36"/>
	<description>... he&apos;s having some trouble with the alarm of his car. ... No idea but I never eat inside a fast food restaurant during a work ... eats inside bk is a cheater, Especially if you order ...</description>
	<body>
		3 Things To Do Today » Save on baby accessories » Introduce new foods to your baby » Get prepared for childbirth 
 
Follow Us On
 Sign in Close Register 
Log-in to What To Expect with one click!
 
 OR 
 Log-in with your What To Expect Account: 
E-Mail Address:
 
Password:
 Forgot Your Password? That&apos;s ok, we can send you a new one. Click Here 
 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler 
 
 Community Groups 
 Community Find a Group Start a Group My Preferences 
 Blogs 
 Word of Mom 
 Members&amp;Friends 
 Meet Members 
 Photos 
 Recent Photos Popular Photos 
 Local Resources 
 New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Find Groups Near You 
 Contests&amp;Deals 
 Diaper Deals Feeding Deals Wipes Deals More Family Deals Photo Contests Group Giveaways The WTE Bookstore 
 
 
 
 Group Main Page Message Board Events Meet Group Members Email Group Members Group Settings Browse All Groups My Preferences 
Related Articles
 
 Baby Shower Hostess Gifts Baby Shower Etiquette Evenflo Playtime Fun Giveaway Baby Shower Gift List Decorating Ideas For A Baby Shower – Gifts You Already Have 
 
 Get great deals up to 90% off 
 for mom, baby, and the whole family 
 
 Featured Deal 

 55% Off Comfy (and Cool) Baby Carriers 
Show off your baby and your sense of style with this adjustable baby carrier from Hotslings.

 Get This Deal 
 
 Advertisement 


 Find a Group Whether you&apos;re looking for support from other expecting moms, a playgroup in your hometown, or even a Glee fan club, WTE has groups you&apos;ll love. Find a group now or start your own group . Advertisement Community » Groups » January 2012 Babies » Archives »Is he cheating? Hide Signatures Share this discussion: 
Is he cheating?
 Next Discussion» From: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 10:23 PM (1 of 102) 
 My husband calls me because
 he&apos;s having some trouble with the alarm of his car. He called me at 
11:00 a.m. from a Burger King. When i reached there I asked him don&apos;t 
tell me you are having breakfast at this time( since this day we have a 
routine of eating out at around 2pm). He gets angry at me! CAN YOU 
BELIEVE IT? He says,&apos;you didn&apos;t make breakfast and I was hungry. What
 is wrong with eating since I make all our money?&apos;I said yes you can be
 hungry but we are going to eat a little later. That saves money so I 
can stay at home with our kids and take care of your needs. How will 
you eat again? He got more agitated and said&apos;I knew I shouldn&apos;t have 
called you. So suspicious it&apos;s just a little sandwich. I am able to eat 
more than the twice a day you think is necessary.&apos;And by this time he 
was yelling, so I got mad too and told him to never speak to me again. 
He kept calling and apologizing. But to me he acted like someone who got
 caught. I don&apos;t know if this is because of guilty feelings or just to 
keep the suspicion away. It&apos;s hard for me to know, since he has his own 
business and is in contact with different women.Please help!
 
 From: MempMom To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 10:35 PM via the iPhone app (2 of 102) 
No idea but I never eat inside a fast food restaurant during a work day. But... My mind would think more that he had to go potty. Men don&apos;t normally like talking about their bowels. My dh just started twitting and I just out right asked him, and he was telling me its for bonuses on his apps and showed me. So maybe just out right ask?
 From: NachoBabyMomma To: MempMom Posted: Sep-11 10:38 PM (3 of 102) 
ok thx MempMom but he must have something to 
hide, otherwise he wouldn&apos;t be so defensive.I dunno or he just wants
 something not from a leftover or what was on sale that week.
 
 From: MempMom To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 10:45 PM via the iPhone app (4 of 102) 
Could be. My dh sneaks mcdonalds alot. I hate it cause he is suppose to be dieting. But would rather him cheat on me with food that a chick. Dh just needs hot breakfast sometimes. I think since he was so apologetic to you and he called you; he isn&apos;t cheating but like you said just wanted something different.
 From: lobr84 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 10:48 PM (5 of 102) 
I am not trying to be rude or judgmental,but you are asking for opinion and i will give mine... First of all i had to read more than twice to really understand whats going on, it very confusing but i think i got it, and to be honest i couldnt even believe what i read..sounds very childish to me. I mean seriously..what is the matter if he didnt have breakfast and was getting something small to hold until 2pm when he was suposed to be having lunch with you? He was probably starving and got something small cause he was too hungry to wait until 2pm...it doesnt mean he cant eat again.. Men have a very big appetite...
Another thing is that it sounds ridiculous for you to think he cheating because of that...what is the connection with one thing to another? He probably got mad because of the questioning...like, it is simply ridiculous to question that, but maybe you said in a tone he didnt like and got upset because he feel he was being questioned for no reason and controlled, plus he was probably also stressed with the car situation andnhaving to deal with questioning for no reason probably made him more upset...also why wold u tell ur husband nkt to speak to you again? How wold that happen if he is your husband?
I think the hormones are getting the best out of you, but really see no connection with cheating...i would have been mad too if i was him...take a deep breath, relax and then you will see what u did and u will end up laughing at yourself... ;-)
 From: GeekProgenitor To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 10:51 PM via the iPhone app (6 of 102) 
I don&apos;t understand. Why did you think he cheated? Has he cheated before?
 From: StephieK82 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 11:28 PM via the iPhone app (7 of 102) 
I don&apos;t get it either. You think he&apos;s cheating because he was at BK sneaking a bite to eat? Do you really think if he was cheating he&apos;d call YOU to come help him? Think about it, it sounds very silly and I don&apos;t blame him for being upset about you attacking him over his eating habits. If he hadn&apos;t eaten all day, then maybe he was hungry and didn&apos;t want to wait 3 more hours just to save a few bucks.
 

 


 
 From: Tattooedmommy30 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-11 11:59 PM (8 of 102) 
I don&apos;t think he was cheating and if he was I wouldn&apos;t be impressed if I were the other woman being taken to burger king (not that BK is bad but I would think he would be trying to impress the other woman)...and I would think if he were going to cheat he probably wouldn&apos;t be out hanging with the girl on the day you are gonna be having lunch together in a bit...
 
 Make a pregnancy ticker From: allik527 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 12:32 AM via the Android app (9 of 102) 
do you guys really only eat once a day or was he just saying that?
 From: hahunter To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 12:53 AM (10 of 102) 
I&apos;m still trying to figure out how eating at Burger King = cheating?


 From: Mommynue To: ALL Posted: Sep-12 01:01 AM via the iPhone app (11 of 102) 
Lol, you didn&apos;t know, anyone that eats inside bk is a cheater, Especially if you order a value meal!!! Seriously though he isn&apos;t over reacting for being mad at you because your being silly. Unless there is more to this story then you should apologize to him for spazzing.
 From: thinkblue To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 01:46 AM via the Android app (12 of 102) 
I think he cheated on you with food...;)
 From: AlyssaJ2011 To: ALL Posted: Sep-12 03:35 AM via the iPhone app (13 of 102) 
Many men feel it&apos;s dumb that a woman had to come help them with a car oproblem. Also when I get upset at my husband for something stupid and I get really defensive it&apos;s because I have some thing bothering me and the littlest and stupidest things set me off. Sit down with him and see if he is upset or worried that the little time he has with you is going to be gone forever because of this new baby. It doesn&apos;t sound like cheating sounds like he is upset.
 From: Maz_Jo To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 03:42 AM via the Android app (14 of 102) 
I&apos;m not understanding you very well. You think he is cheating cause he got annoyed at you being at him for eating a Burger King?
 
 
 
 
 
 Arrogance? Try to think of it as&quot;being aware of one&apos;s awesomeness&quot; 

 
 
 From: jentru To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 05:36 AM via the iPhone app (15 of 102) 
Sounds to me that he was just hungry. I could go for a BK breakfast sandwich now! Yummy sausage egg and cheese crossiant. I would be pissed snd defensive if I was accused of cheating especially since it was just something so small as BK.
 From: Maz_Jo To: jentru Posted: Sep-12 06:08 AM via the Android app (16 of 102) 
Yup, I have to agree with you there!
 
 
 
 
 
 Arrogance? Try to think of it as&quot;being aware of one&apos;s awesomeness&quot; 

 
 
 From: cindyy00 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 07:58 AM via the iPhone app (17 of 102) 
I agree 100% with lobr84
 From: Maz_Jo To: ALL Posted: Sep-12 08:01 AM via the Android app (18 of 102) 
Damn this thread!! Now I want Burger King! ;)
 
 
 
 
 
 Arrogance? Try to think of it as&quot;being aware of one&apos;s awesomeness&quot; 

 
 
 From: IntlMommy311 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 09:30 AM via the iPhone app (19 of 102) 
Yeah I agree with a few pp... sounds like pregnancy hormones are getting the best of you...you sound a little silly... ;)
 From: AddisonsMommy2012 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 09:38 AM (20 of 102) 
It sounds like he was hungry, not horny. You need to put a little faith in your husband. Unless he has cheated in the past there is no reason to jump to conclusions.

I just don&apos;t understand how eating at Burger King can be linked to cheating. If he was cheating don&apos;t you think he would have called a buddy to come help him instead of you? Just relax.


 
 
   From: MeganV2012 To: NachoBabyMomma Posted: Sep-12 09:42 AM via the iPhone app (21 of 102) 
Not to be mean and maybe I&apos;m confused but why the insecurity thinking he&apos;s cheating? I don&apos;t understand how you came to the conclusion maybe I&apos;m missing something I would just think he&apos;s a hungry man.
 Back to January 2012 Babies Archives «Previous 1 2 3 4 5 6 Next» 
 
 
Browse

 Preconception Pregnancy First Year Toddler Community Family Deals 
 
About

 About What to Expect What to Expect Foundation What to Expect Bookstore Everyday Health Network Contact Us Word of Mom 

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Advertising/Editorial Policy Advertise With Us Partnerships Press Room 

 Facebook Twitter Pinterest Help Feedback Careers 
 The material on this website is provided for educational purposes only and is not to be used for medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment, or in place of therapy or medical care. See additional information . Use of this site is subject to our terms of use and privacy policy. Advertising Notice 
This Site and third parties who place advertisements on this Site may collect and use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like to obtain more information about these advertising practices and to make choices about online behavioral advertising, please click here
	</body>
</document>
