<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006641" url="http://becksprime.com/" time="2012-07-12-23:37" support="20" score="0.06522555409540044" bingtitle="Becks Prime" webtitle="Becks Prime">
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001502" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000559" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000110" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000122" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000890" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>Always Made to Order. We’re all about fresh, great-tasting food ... Gift Cards Available to purchase online . Buy Now</description>
	<body>
		Beck&apos;s Prime 
 Menu Hamburgers&amp;Hot Dogs Mesquite Grilled Sandwiches Salads, Chili&amp;Potatoes Hot Plates Prime Time Dinners Fries&amp;Sides Shakes&amp;Drinks Kids Prime Meals Sportatorium Menu Nutritional Menu Prime Packs Menu Locations Augusta Dairy Ashford Downtown Kirby The Heights Memorial City Mall Memorial Park Meyerland Plaza Sugar Land Wilcrest Willowbrook The Woodlands Catering Catering Menu Prime Packs Gift Cards About Us The Team Careers Becks Buzz Contact Us Blog Smoke Signals 
 Contact Us Careers 
 
 
 

The Finer Side of Fast

Always Fresh. Always Fast. Always Made to Order.

We’re all about fresh, great-tasting food. Which is why each of our award winning burgers, hot dogs and sandwiches are made-to-order, grilled to perfection and prepared with the freshest ingredients available. With so many mouthwatering options, it’ll be hard to pick a favorite!
 
 

5 Stars on 4 Wheels

Prime Steak Dinners, Only a Drive-Through Away

Ditch the dress code for a perfectly grilled certified Angus prime steak at your place. Pair with your choice of a baked potato, wild rice, fresh-cut fries, grilled vegetables or a salad.
 
 

eat right, make it light

Seven Healthy Entrees You&apos;ll Fall in Love With

We start fresh every morning with the highest quality ingredients to create our healthy entrees. They are grilled to perfection over Mesquite and served with fresh vegetables. It&apos;s a delicious, heart-healthy meal served up fast.
 
 

Fresh&amp;Fit, Just For You

Great Tasting and Healthy Salads

Enjoy six made-to-order crisp and very healthy salads topped with your choice of mesquite grilled Ahi Tuna or grilled chicken breast. Served up fresh with our signature house-made dressings.
 
 

Celebrate Fresh!

A Delicious New Salad from the World&apos;s Freshest
Fast Food Company

Introducing the all new Kirby salad! A fresh combination of mixed field greens with homemade spiced pecans, dried cranberries, cherry tomatoes, crumbled aged blue cheese, crisp bacon,and homemade raspberry vinaigrette.
 
 
We came. We cooked.
You conquered
 
 BECKS PRIME CATERING,
 always hot, fresh and enticing.

 More Info 
 
The Gift Card
Everyone Wants
 
 Gift Cards Available to 
purchase online 
 

 Buy Now 
 
Join Our
Mailing List
 
Join SMOKE SIGNALS and get
a free appetizer for signing up!

 Sign Up 
 
 
What&apos;s Cooking

 
New Dallas Location
 June 26, 2012 
Driving by Forest Lane and Preston Road in Dallas, you may have noticed the new Becks Prime sign going up. It will be exciting to watch as this new location comes together and begins to take shape in the community. read more&gt; 
 
 
Tweets
	</body>
</document>
