<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006625" url="http://www.healthhabits.ca/2010/08/19/u-s-government-subsidizes-healthy-food/" time="2012-07-12-23:34" support="2" score="0.0017379473166993275" bingtitle="U.S. Government Subsidizes Healthy Food - Health &amp; Fitness Tips ..." webtitle="U.S. Government Subsidizes Healthy Food">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>... Incentives Pilot will enroll 7,500 randomly selected SNAP (aka Food Stamps) households to receive the ... that adding 30 cents on the Dollar won&apos;t even make a dent in the bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Health Habits 

Fitter, Stronger, Healthier
 
 Contact 
 About Doug 
 Sitemap 
 
Connect with us:

 
 
 Contact 
 About Doug 
 Archives 
 Sitemap Popular Posts Best Body Workouts–2012 Best Body Workouts–2011 Exercise Diet/Nutrition I Wanna Look Great I Wanna Be Healthy fat loss 
 FREE Paleo Diet eBook Awesome Health/Fitness/Nutrition Blogs Posts Comments 
 WRITE
FOR US Tweet 
U.S. Government Subsidizes Healthy Food
 August 19, 2010 By healthhabits 4 Comments 
 

Every year, the U.S. federal government subsidizes America’s junk food habit with bazillions of dollars in tax breaks&amp;subsidies.

But today, in a shocking turn of events, the USDA has announced the creation of a new “healthy eating”program . 

Or, in other words… The U.S. government is subsidizing healthy food. 

 The $20 million program is being tested in Hampden County, Mass. and is designed to encourage healthy eating among low income families.

Specifically, The Healthy Incentives Pilot will enroll 7,500 randomly selected SNAP (aka Food Stamps) households to receive the HIP incentives.

For every dollar that participants spend on fruits and vegetables using their SNAP Electronic Benefit Transfer cards, 30 cents will be added to their benefit balance–thus cutting the cost of fruits and vegetables by almost one-third .

And if this Dutch research is correct, this cost cutting measure will result in the higher consumption of fruits&amp;vegetables.



And to make things even better, this program will operate in tandem with the Food Bank Farm program already being sponsored by the Food bank of Western Mass. (The FB Farm program promotes local food consumption)

 Conclusion 

This program seems pretty great to me.

 It reduces the cost of fruits&amp;vegetables It increases the consumption of fruits&amp;vegetables It increases the consumption of local fruits&amp;vegetables 

The only drawback seems to be the $20 million.

 Maybe the USDA should raise the cash by slashing some of the current USDA junk food subsidies. 

 . 
 
Related posts:

 “Healthy”Food Makes You Hungrier The Future of Fast Food Eating Healthy on a Budget Can Big Government“Cure”Obesity? Bye Bye Healthy Lifestyle : Hello Qnexa 
 Tweet About healthhabits 

 Doug Robb is a personal trainer , a fitness blogger and author, a competitive athlete, and a student of nutrition and exercise science. Since 2008, Doug has expanded his impact by bringing his real-world experience online via his health&amp;fitness blog, Health Habits . Read more posts by Doug at Hive Health Media.
 View all posts by author: healthhabits 
Enter your email address below to receive updates each time we publish new content.
 
Related Posts
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 4 comments 0 people listening Sign in 
 Comment help Get Livefyre 
 Post comment as + Follow conversation Following - Unfollow Post to Sort: Newest | Oldest Callie DiBenedetto 
Heirloom seed banks would be cheaper and make our people self sufficient instead of weak and dependent.....
 
Fresh fruit and vegetables are relatively so expensive when you compare calorie for calorie and gram for gram of protein that adding 30 cents on the Dollar won&apos;t even make a dent in the bill of the average American family that wants to start eating healthy.
The government subsidizes the junk food and GMO related farming industries with Fed bailouts and other hidden waivers and incentives in the tens or even hundreds of billions. They have illegal immigrants bussed in from Mexico that do not have to go through Customs for goodness sake.
When the government does something that favors We the People instead of corporate lobbies...well...I&apos;ll believe it when I believe it :-P
 
I thought Harvard did a study about a year ago saying that decreasing the cost of healthy food didn&apos;t necessarily increase the consumption of such food. People just spend the extra savings on junk food. The key was to increase the cost of junk. Maybe a two pronged approach as you imply of decreasing subsidies to junk (i.e. raise the cost) and decrease healthy?
 
There are also studies which show that small increases in the price of junk food doesn&apos;t affect purchasing decisions...large tax increases yes.
How about slapping a 25% tax on junk food and applying all of that tax revenue to reduce the price of &quot;real food&quot; - fruit, vegetables, animal protein, etc...
	</body>
</document>
