<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006757" url="http://www.allergiesandalternativemedicine.com/fruits-and-vegetables.html" time="2012-07-12-23:45" support="1" score="0.0006666867714871548" bingtitle="Fruits and Vegetables: Types Of Alternative Medicine" webtitle="Fruits and Vegetables: Types Of Alternative Medicine">
			<query id="001245" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>top a baked potato with a cup of non-fat yogurt ... extra fruits or vegetables of your choice, and throw ... If you do stop at the fast food restaurant, make it a new rule that ...</description>
	<body>
		Subscribe To This Site 
 
 
 
 
 
Fresh Fruits and Vegetables:

Nature&apos;s Maintenance Plan For Good Health
Offered By Many Types Of Alternative Medicine

In your own mind, you know you do not eat enough fresh fruits and vegetables, but boosting your daily intake of something you are not that fond of eating just does not seem like it is worth the effort. Sure you have heard many types of alternative medicine fashion their therapy programs off of the benefits of raw and cooked fruits and vegetables but have you ever actually stopped to think of any of their list of advantages?


 good for weight control because most are low in calories

 there is an abundance of vitamins, minerals and the nutrients your body needs to perform properly. With a diverse assortment added to your diet, you generally never need to rely on supplements.

 use an assortment of fruits, vegetables, a few basic ingredients like low-fat milk or yogurt and some ice cubes and prepare a quick and easy meal right out of your blender

 their antioxidant power

 fewer diabetic complications for type 2 and gestational diabetes

 adds variety to your diet so you reduce your chances of a food allergy or food sensitivity


Actually, this list can stretch on and on depending which health concern you and your body is having difficulty battling with.


Getting Fruits and Vegetables Into Your Diet
To increase your intake of fresh produce, with a few simple tricks, you can add some to your daily diet and never even know it if you aren&apos;t the cook. All it takes is a few simple changes to your method of cooking and shopping habits.


 when preparing meat loaf, meatballs, ham loaf, chili, taco meat, pork sausage or almost any kind of ground meat dish, add some quick and easy vegetable fillings. Diced onions, green peppers, hot chili peppers, grated carrots, garlic cloves etc. can easily be added to your meat mixture, mix and prepare as usual.

 homemade soups and gravies do not need to be thickened with flour or cornstarch. Add some quick pureed vegetables such as cauliflower, broccoli, carrots or any of your favorites. These not only add bulk but more flavor.

 when baking, almost all types of baked goods can be prepared with mashed bananas or applesauce to replace the fats and oil in a recipe. Or add finely shredded carrots or zucchini to make your baked treat extra sweet and moist without the added sweeteners.

 cream or milk-based recipes can often be prepared with 100% fruit juices (eliminate the milk) with equally good and tasty results.


Experiment a little with some of your recipes and you can come up with a whole new recipe box of family favorites.


Adding Some Fresh Produce During Meals
Start some of these super simple grab and go alternatives each day to get some fresh fruits and vegetables into your meals:


 Breakfast

 never buy fruit on the bottom yogurt cups. Instead purchase plain yogurt, add a small amount of honey or stevia to your taste and then stir in 1/2 cup fresh fruit of your choice.

 make your western omelette go a little wild. Add some diced tomatoes or mushrooms into it with the green peppers and ham.

 stir in diced fruits or vegetables into your waffle or pancake batter. Or add some blueberries, blackberries etc. to a bowl of fresh-cooked oatmeal.




 Lunch

 fall in love with exotic fruit salad the easy way - pick up all the already prepared fruits off the buffet from the grocery store.

 dark green lettuces or spinach salads can also easily be prepared differently everyday by just changing up your toppings from that same salad bar.

 top a baked potato with a cup of non-fat yogurt, diced vegetables (of your choice) and a few of your favorite seasonings mixed in. This is an excellent way to sneak in some more vegetables without using the standard sour cream or butter.




 Dinner
The main meal of your day is the ideal time to fix some fruits and vegetables without just opening a can of corn or peas. Some quick additions to your dinner meal could include:
 homemade soup or stew filling a pot with an assortment of vegetables and a meat of your choice is a one-pan meal which is guaranteed to be loaded with a nutritional punch.

 for a new flavor twist for meats, dredge your chicken or pork pieces in non-fat yogurt and then top with diced onion, shredded carrots or any kind of shredded vegetable of your choice. Season this with garlic powder, curry powder, fresh rosemary or any of your favorites and bake until done.

 experiment with salsa as a sauce for your meats. Purchase or prepare your own recipe of basic salsa, add some extra fruits or vegetables of your choice, and throw in your favorite seasonings.Seasonings don&apos;t always have to be the standard salt and pepper, garlic powder etc.. Try adding some 100% apple, grape or orange juice, hot chili peppers or some fresh herbs like basil and oregano. Or go tropical and go for the citrus blends of limes and lemons. Make up your own combination of favorites depending what type of cut of meat you will be using.




 Snacks and Treats
Snack times come and go also, so it is easy to fit some extra fruits and vegetables in during them also. Keep a container of homemade trail mix at your desk. Just be sure to add plenty of dried fruits, nuts and seeds to the mix also.

If you do stop at the fast food restaurant, make it a new rule that you will always order the additional lettuce, tomato and onion (if possible) to top off your sandwich.


So as you can tell, adding fruits and vegetables to your daily diet is not as difficult as much as you assumed it would be. Be smart, keep a few basics in your refrigerator and then avail yourself of the convenience of the buffet or salad bar at your local store or restaurant for the unusual offerings as the need arises.

 

 Return to &quot;Digestive Health Care&quot; 

 ©2010 - 2012 Allergies and Alternative Medicine - All Rights Reserved 
 
 SBI!
	</body>
</document>
