<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006851" url="http://www.healthkicker.com/693212575/have-a-problem-with-your-food-touching-other-food-on-a-plate/" time="2012-07-12-23:50" support="2" score="0.004594804379381913" bingtitle="Have A Problem With Your Food Touching Other Food On a Plate ..." webtitle="Have A Problem With Your Food Touching Other Food On a Plate? | healthkicker">
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>I prefer my food dry, no types of sauce! They just run into other food, and if there ... used to have to eat my frieds first before i ate my cheesburger from any fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		blogs about trying to live healthier 
 Want automatic updates
with all the latest posts?
 Subscribe to Healthkicker! 
 
 Home 
 
 Start a Blog! 
 
 Submit a Post! 
 
 Random Post 
 
 Advice 
 
 
 « newer healthkicker&apos;s weblog older » 
 
 Thursday, 19 February 2009 

 
 Have A Problem With Your Food Touching Other Food On a Plate? 
 Healthkicker 
 Question Of The Day: 

 
 
This isn&apos;t a health question but we were still curious about this one. Last night we heard Jay Leno say he hates his food touching other food on a plate or bowl. He likes his &quot;peas separate from his steak&quot;. 

To our surprise many in the crowd agreed with him.

Do people really have a problem with food touching other food on a plate? If so, how come?
 
mancouch.com 
 
 9:45 AM 12675 Views 142 eProps 75 Comments 
 
 
 
 0 
 Recommend 
 0 
 Recommend 
 0 
 Recommend 
 
 Recommend 
 
 Recommend 
 
 « newer healthkicker&apos;s weblog older » 
 
 Related Posts 
 
 
 Summer Barbecue Belly-Burners 
 
 A 9-Year-Old Boy is Allergic to Food 
 
 Rough Night? Recover with These Hangover Foods 
 
 My Weight GAIN Journey 
 
 
 
 
 Comments (75) 
 
 browse comments: next  last » 

 
No, unless one runny food is making another, more solid food soggy or nasty tasting.  Solid foods touching each other is a nonissue.
 
 2/19/2009 9:49 AM methodElevated@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
It depends on what kind of food it is. Like, if it rice&amp;some sort of veggies, I don&apos;t care, in fact, I mix them together. But if there is a dressing or a sauce with it, no, I don&apos;t want it to touch. My whole family makes fun of me because when we do big dinner&apos;s, I have to have a salad bowl because I don&apos;t want any other food touching my salad.
 
 2/19/2009 9:55 AM tiny___dreams@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
I hate it. I always have. I hate it so much that I often lose my appetite when I see it. How come? I really don&apos;t have an answer for that....although I do have exceptions too. Generally though, I can&apos;t stand it, especially if the food is runny. I hate watery food! I prefer my food dry, no types of sauce! They just run into other food, and if there&apos;s bread, it becomes soggy. Gross!
 
 2/19/2009 9:58 AM PlasticPill@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
I think it&apos;s super annoying when people get bothered by this.
 
 2/19/2009 10:16 AM deprivation_now@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
Depends on the food. I have to have my pancakes on a separate plate then my other food cuz I don&apos;t&apos; want the syrup touching my eggs or anything else. But I don&apos;t mind if my corn touches my steak or whatever.
 
 2/19/2009 10:31 AM Bluekiller2025@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
It depends on the food. Some foods would taste awful if they touched other foods. I don&apos;t like any of my other food touching my mashed potatoes (just an example)...esp. if it&apos;s watery or juicyfood/food with sauce.
 
 2/19/2009 10:34 AM skinnychic8@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
It depends on what food.
 
 2/19/2009 10:40 AM TakingxOverxMe@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
I don&apos;t like my foods touching unless they are supposed to. I don&apos;t want peas in my mashed potatoes or salad on my burrito. It makes things taste different and changes the texture at times. I am kind of weird too because I eat one thing at a time. So if I have a plate with green beans, chicken, and rice I will eat the chicken first probably, green beans and then the rice. I don&apos;t mix bites of food because then the flavors mix and I like the individual food item&apos;s flavor by itself.
 
 2/19/2009 11:17 AM The_Megster86@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
It depends, if it tastes good together I don&apos;t care ^_^
 
 2/19/2009 11:24 AM daretobe_healthy@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
This is still one of my biggest problems.. I suffered from Anorexia for a long time. If my food touched it was an excuse to not have to eat that part of it. Something about it just always revolted me. Also, it made it so I fit less food on my plate because I needed the space between the food. I no longer suffer from the disease; However, my food is still not allowed to touch.
 
 2/19/2009 11:25 AM worn_and_beaten@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
haha..i thought I was the only one that hates my food to be touching with each other in the plate. Yeah, sure my husband laughs and make fun of me for being like that. But, I can&apos; help it I can be very picky about it...So, when I usually eat in a buffet style, I usually not stufffed my plate piled up with food bc it grosses me out. So, what I do was picked probably 6 diffrent foods so it won&apos;t have to touch each other...


Same thing with the utensils, when I have to use plastic forks or spoon if it is for dessert I can&apos;t use the same utensil as what I have used to eat my entree...i&apos;m just weird like that.
 
 2/19/2009 11:32 AM ChefCherryl@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
Yeah, I don&apos;t like it either. It mixes flavors. Of course, this is coming from someone who used to mix mashed potatoes and applesauce together...but I went through stages, really. As a kid, I wouldn&apos;t let anything touch (except, of course, for the combination of mashed potatoes and applesauce). I got worse through high school, when I would actually pull apart foods that were supposed to be together so they wouldn&apos;t touch. I&apos;ve gotten better about it since coming to college, because when you ask for gravy on your turkey and the lady in the diner serving it doesn&apos;t speak English all that hot, you&apos;re getting gravy on your turkey, potatoes, vegetables, and roll.
 
 2/19/2009 11:32 AM jupiter312@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
i assume it&apos;s some kinda control isssue, maybe, i have various mental problems.. i&apos;m really picky about food.. foods can&apos;t touch, certain things get eaten first or picked out, some things get mixed together, depends on what it is and i don&apos;t drink anything during the meal, only before or after.. some peeps get annoyed at me cause i can take forever to eat and others thing it&apos;s cute.. personally i wish i wasn&apos;t so picky and could eat like a &quot;normal&quot; person.. i try, but it causes anxiety when i don&apos;t follow my rituals..
 
 2/19/2009 11:48 AM shel@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
It only really matters if the foods don&apos;t go together. I don&apos;t like cold stuff touching hot stuff because the cold stuff makes the hot stuff cold and the hot stuff makes the cold stuff hot. I don&apos;t really like having salad dressing on my mashed potatoes, either, so I try to keep runny stuff separate.

But I wouldn&apos;t not eat food just because it was merely touching another food.
 
 2/19/2009 12:04 PM LadyLibellule@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
I don&apos;t have a problem with it, but I do think that foods being separate on a plate looks more appetizing. I just like the presentation to be neat, ya know? lol
 
 2/19/2009 12:16 PM aznbunny604@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
Depends on whats touching. I usually love combining grains and roots, like corn and potatoes. and peas and potatoes. and stuff. If it has too much fluid then I dont like combining. I cant stand ketchup touching stuff its not supposed to! 
 
 2/19/2009 12:26 PM peacelove__CALLIE@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
No sauce with chips. if its a liquidy food then it should be in a bowl and the soilds on a plate |:
i&apos;m not too keen on gravy either.
 
 2/19/2009 12:38 PM jazikaissafe@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
i love to mix my food. mmmm
 
 2/19/2009 12:59 PM Pcgecko85@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
haha i have this disorder..er problem. but it&apos;s gotten better as i grew older. i mainly don&apos;t like food juices and sauces running to each other, and if a food i don&apos;t like touches a food i DO like. I prefer to eat the food i don&apos;t like first, so i can enjoy the food i DO like afterwards. if it&apos;s a carb like rice or mashed potatoes, i don&apos;t mind cuz it adds flavor to it!

i use to want those separate compartment plates like in cafeterias...and when i see those, i have this weird happiness inside of me. i think it&apos;s a form of OCD haha

im hungry now.
 
 2/19/2009 1:28 PM pheeb_s@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
I&apos;m a very picky eater so yes, I do separate my food sometimes but it depends on what it is. For example, I hate chinese mushrooms so I don&apos;t like it touching other foods on my plate. Same goes for those little tiny strips of carrot (even though I don&apos;t mind eating raw baby carrots.. yeah, I&apos;m complicated, whatever).
 
 2/19/2009 1:59 PM tubbz87@datingish ( message ) recommend reply 
 
I am a picky eater as well,  no sauces, I prefer to see what I am eating. People think I am weird because I dont like gravy on my Sunday lunch, not even on Yorkshire puddings.


Mash potato and garden peas, I am fine with this as I can mixed them
 
 2/19/2009 2:53 PM my_final_username@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
when i was younger...like 1 year ago younger, lol...i used to hate when my food touched any other food on my plate. thanksgiving and christmas dinner used to be nightmares in my head, lol...but i&apos;ve gotten over that...mainly because food got cold when i had to eat the peas first and then the mashed potatoes and then the etc., so that food wouldn&apos;t touch each other. i even used to have to eat my frieds first before i ate my cheesburger from any fast food restaurant...but that all sounds a bit crazy now, so i&apos;m glad i&apos;ve gotten over the food touching other food issue...and now you all think i&apos;m crazy o_O lol.
 
 2/19/2009 3:08 PM zubes5806@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
Nope, I usually mis everything into a massive pile of yumminess. xD
 
 2/19/2009 3:08 PM SilentScream121@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
If it&apos;s runny/wet/consists of sauces, I don&apos;t want them to touch because then one thing tastes like another. Now if the sauce is uber yummy, then I don&apos;t care. Example: A salad with italian dressing next to tuna casserole. I&apos;ll still eat it, but I&apos;ll cringe a little when the italian dressing is mixed with the fish cause it tases funny to me.

But overall, I don&apos;t care when foods touch. Some people must be turned off by chex mix or other part mix foods. LOL
 
 2/19/2009 3:29 PM Usuratonkachi_san@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 
lol... Americans are funny
 
 2/19/2009 3:55 PM Neurotically_Mine@xanga ( message ) recommend reply 
 

 browse comments: next  last » 
 
 Post a Comment 
 
 
Sign in to Comment
 
 Xanga Network Facebook Twitter Other (guest) 
 
 ! name required name (required) ! email not valid email (required) email not publicly displayed website 
 
You are signed in as 
 
Give eProps ( ? ) 
 
 2 eProps 1 eProp 0 eProps Comment Only 
 

 
Post a Comment
 
Say it with Minis! ( ? ) 
 
 You&apos;ve changed man I&apos;m gonna hurl Good night! Party over here, party over there... 
 View All Minis» [mini text] [mini credits] reset 
Profile Pic
 Default | Choose» ( ? ) 
 reset 

 
Code You See Below
 ! incorrect code 
 
 

 Submitting… try again? Share this comment ( ? ) or Cancel 
 
 Back to healthkicker&apos;s Healthkicker Site! Note: your comment will appear in healthkicker&apos;s local time zone: GMT -05:00 (Eastern Standard - US, Canada) 
 
 
 
 About this Entry 
 
 
 From: healthkicker Posted: 2/19/2009 9:45 AM 
 

 Read Comments Post a Comment Subscribe to healthkicker 

 Back to healthkicker&apos;s Weblog 
 
 Tags 
 
 (all) food (all) plate (all) qotd 
 
 Who recommended? 
 

 
 Who gave the eProps? 
 
 2 eProps from: 

 methodElevated@xanga tiny___dreams@xanga deprivation_now@xanga Bluekiller2025@xanga skinnychic8@xanga TakingxOverxMe@xanga The_Megster86@xanga daretobe_healthy@xanga worn_and_beaten@xanga ChefCherryl@xanga jupiter312@xanga shel@xanga LadyLibellule@xanga aznbunny604@xanga peacelove__CALLIE@xanga jazikaissafe@xanga Pcgecko85@xanga pheeb_s@xanga tubbz87@datingish my_final_username@xanga zubes5806@xanga SilentScream121@xanga Usuratonkachi_san@xanga Neurotically_Mine@xanga Erin1022@xanga Catamaran18@xanga bekaaahblastoff@xanga SeitekiChibiNeko@xanga insoMINAk@xanga peanutbuttercuppie@xanga chittyglamour@xanga PaintedTooThin@xanga crh08 incoherent__ramblings@xanga mayanao@xanga TiRocKiinPiinK@xanga elli_monkey@xanga seedsower@xanga heathursaurus@xanga Worshipping_Nettles@xanga steph843@xanga Courtesy_Of_Her_Dreams@xanga pretty_glam_photos@xanga sungoesround@xanga LGailGarrett@xanga At_Sixes_And_Sevens@xanga black_lie@xanga bandopoet@xanga NowAndForeverTonight@xanga kaleyrae90@xanga J4MIE_YUN@xanga mileyfan08@xanga BrothaPaco@xanga inspireothers@xanga sfamylou@xanga TequilaKisses@xanga KassieintheSkywithDiamonds@xanga blah_blah809@xanga blowcaine@xanga relinquishing_junk@xanga DanzInRealLife@xanga Miss_Suejung@xanga littleappleblossom89@xanga wholefoodsMum@xanga Horn_of_Plenty@xanga oneirical@xanga gloria_0418@xanga little_greenleaf@xanga DarcKleer@xanga BlobOfGoo@xanga MizBoonie 
 
 Popular Tags 
 
 advice authormsenergydrink diet eating exercise fitness food health healthkicker healthy mentalhealth qotd recipes running tips vegan weight weightloss workingout workout 

 View all tags 
 
 Hungry for More? Check out these Recent Posts! 
 
 
 Metabolism All Outta Wack! Help! 
 
 7/11/2012 11:00 PM 485 Views 4 comments 
 
 Diabetes Apps to Keep You Healthy 
 
 7/11/2012 8:00 PM 1244 Views add comments 
 
 I&apos;m Starting a Gluten&amp;Casein Free Diet - Where Do I Begin? 
 
 7/11/2012 5:00 PM 486 Views 2 comments 
 
 3 Insane Workout Moves 
 
 7/10/2012 9:00 PM 1447 Views 8 comments 
 
 My Potluck Staple: Rainbow Couscous Balsamic Salad 
 
 7/10/2012 6:30 PM 411 Views 3 comments 
 
 Fast Food: What Not To Order 
 
 7/10/2012 4:30 PM 4253 Views 29 comments 
 
 When Your Dreams and Reality Collide 
 
 7/9/2012 11:30 PM 1765 Views 9 comments 
 
 The Importance of Good Posture 
 
 7/9/2012 7:00 PM 1920 Views 1 comment 
 
 Product Review: Celiac Safe GF Pastas 
 
 7/9/2012 6:29 PM 889 Views 6 comments 
 
 Physiological Reasons Behind the Urge to Binge Eat 
 
 7/8/2012 10:00 PM 1337 Views 2 comments 
 

 View all weblog entries 
 
 

 
 Main Page Weblog Photos Videos Audio Albums Pulse Profile Chatboard 
 visiting: healthkicker 
 Subscribe to healthkicker Add to friends Send a message 
 subscribe 
 Click to see options 
 ratings 
 Click to see options 
 flag 

 join healthkicker 
 Weblog Add Edit Photos Add Edit Videos Add Edit Audio Add Edit Pulse Add Edit 
 update help sign in 
 
 Xanga RSS subscribe 
 
 
 One ***** Critter 
 
 How Much Money 
 
 SaeMonster Spotted In the Little Hoquiam River 
 
 In The Garden 
 
 
 Revelife RSS subscribe 
 
 
 Sometimes I&apos;m my Own Worst Enemy 
 
 Unhappy Christians 
 
 Brief Thoughts on the Spirit of Truth 
 
 Body Image: A Hopelessly Broken Vessel 
 
 
 Momaroo RSS subscribe 
 
 
 A Reality Show About Extended Breastfeeding? 
 
 She&apos;s Here! Introducing Hannah! 
 
 June $50 Winner! 
 
 What Girls Will Do To A Guy {Funny} 
 
 
 Datingish RSS subscribe 
 
 
 High Five for Friend Request 
 
 Hating Your Friend&apos;s S/O 
 
 Are You Frightened of Handsome Men? 
 
 Homie? Lover? Friend? 
 
 
 Healthkicker RSS subscribe 
 
 
 Metabolism All Outta Wack! Help! 
 
 Diabetes Apps to Keep You Healthy 
 
 I&apos;m Starting a Gluten&amp;Casein Free Diet - Where Do I Begin? 
 
 3 Insane Workout Moves 
 
 
 Lovelyish RSS subscribe 
 
 
 Yet Another Awesome Tumblr: Ghetto Hikes 
 
 How To Stay Happy During Weird Summer Weather 
 
 Rihanna&apos;s Fashion Reality Show Only To Debut In UK 
 
 The 5 Best Shoes to Thrift 
 
 
 IReallyLikeFood RSS subscribe 
 
 
 My Favorite Starbucks Locations 
 
 Eating A Day in the Life of: Dane 
 
 Pepperoni Pizza Cones 
 
 Panera Bread, I love you! 
 
 
 Autisable RSS subscribe 
 
 
 Special Free Schools 
 
 Autism Light: Alex Herrmann 
 
 The Ryanica Encyclopedia 
 
 It Was The Best Day Ever 
 
 
 

 
 view all themes! 
 about this theme 

 terms privacy 

 safety parents law enforcement report inappropriate content 

 join healthkicker help sign in 
 
 Choose a Profile Pic 
 
 close 
 
 Welcome to Healthkicker! 
 
 close 
 
 Stay connected! 
 
 close 
 
 Click smiley or type html to insert… 
 
 close 
 
 Say it with Minis! 
 
 close
	</body>
</document>
