<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006716" url="http://occupations.careers.org/35-2011.00/cooks-fast-food" time="2012-07-12-23:42" support="3" score="0.004117437091965898" bingtitle="Cooks, Fast Food - Occupational Profile and Resources - Careers.org" webtitle="Cooks, Fast Food - Occupational Profile and Resources  - Careers.org">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="240"/>
	<description>Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant with a limited menu. Duties of the cooks are limited to preparation of a few basic items and normally involve ...</description>
	<body>
		Colleges Online School Finder Colleges by State Colleges by Topic Online Colleges Academic Programs Tuition and Financial Aid Education Topics   Job Resources Job Search Occupation Profiles Industry Profiles Job Resource Topics   Regional Resources U.S. Career Directory Canada Career Directory International Career Directory   Career Planning Home Business&amp;Entrepreneur Employers Career Advice Career Services Career Research   Online School Finder   Cooks, Fast Food - Occupational Profile and Resources 
 Job Seekers Recruiters 
 
 Job Seekers Login * Mandatory Field 
 
 
 * User Name * Password 
 Forgot Password        Create Your Account 
 
 Recruiters Login * Mandatory Field 
 * User Name * Password 
 Forgot Password        Create Your Account 
 Cooks, Fast Food Jobs Employers - post your job here   Salary Wizard
Find Out What You&apos;re Worth... 
 
 
 Job Title     All 
 titles ZIP Code Select State/Metro ------------------------&gt; Alabama -- Birmingham Alabama -- Dothan Alabama -- Florence Alabama -- Huntsville Alabama -- Mobile Alabama -- Montgomery Alabama -- Tuscaloosa Alaska -- Anchorage Alaska -- Fairbanks Alaska -- Juneau Arizona -- Flagstaff Arizona -- Mesa Arizona -- Phoenix Arizona -- Tucson Arkansas -- Fayetteville Arkansas -- Fort Smith Arkansas -- Little Rock Arkansas -- Pine Bluff California -- Anaheim California -- Bakersfield California -- Chico California -- Fresno California -- Lompoc California -- Long Beach California -- Los Angeles California -- Modesto California -- Monterey California -- Oakland California -- Orange County California -- Petaluma California -- Riverside California -- Sacramento California -- San Bernardino California -- San Diego California -- San Francisco California -- San Jose California -- Santa Ana California -- Santa Barbara California -- Santa Cruz California -- Santa Maria California -- Santa Rosa California -- Stockton California -- Vallejo California -- Ventura Colorado -- Boulder Colorado -- Colorado Springs Colorado -- Denver Colorado -- Fort Collins Colorado -- Pueblo Connecticut -- Bridgeport Connecticut -- Danbury Connecticut -- Hartford Connecticut -- New Britain Connecticut -- New Haven Connecticut -- New London Connecticut -- Norwich Connecticut -- Stamford Delaware -- Wilmington District of Columbia -- Washington Florida -- Boca Raton Florida -- Bradenton Florida -- Clearwater Florida -- Daytona Beach Florida -- Fort Lauderdale Florida -- Fort Myers Florida -- Gainesville Florida -- Hialeah Florida -- Jacksonville Florida -- Melbourne Florida -- Miami Florida -- Orlando Florida -- Pensacola Florida -- Sarasota Florida -- St. Petersburg Florida -- Tallahassee Florida -- Tampa Georgia -- Albany Georgia -- Atlanta Georgia -- Augusta Georgia -- Columbus Georgia -- Macon Georgia -- Savannah Hawaii -- Honolulu Idaho -- Boise Idaho -- Idaho Falls Idaho -- Pocatello Idaho -- Twin Falls Illinois -- Champaign Illinois -- Chicago Illinois -- Moline Illinois -- Peoria Illinois -- Rock Island Illinois -- Rockford Illinois -- Springfield Indiana -- Anderson Indiana -- Bloomington Indiana -- Elkhart Indiana -- Evansville Indiana -- Fort Wayne Indiana -- Gary Indiana -- Indianapolis Indiana -- South Bend Indiana -- Terre Haute Indiana -- Vincennes Iowa -- Cedar Falls Iowa -- Cedar Rapids Iowa -- Davenport Iowa -- Des Moines Iowa -- Sioux City Iowa -- Waterloo Kansas -- Kansas City Kansas -- Topeka Kansas -- Wichita Kentucky -- Frankfort Kentucky -- Hopkinsville Kentucky -- Lexington Kentucky -- Louisville Louisiana -- Alexandria Louisiana -- Baton Rouge Louisiana -- Lafayette Louisiana -- Lake Charles Louisiana -- Monroe Louisiana -- New Orleans Louisiana -- Shreveport Maine -- Bangor Maine -- Portland Maryland -- Baltimore Massachusetts -- Boston Massachusetts -- Brockton Massachusetts -- Lawrence Massachusetts -- Lowell Massachusetts -- New Bedford Massachusetts -- Pittsfield Massachusetts -- Springfield Massachusetts -- Worcester Michigan -- Ann Arbor Michigan -- Battle Creek Michigan -- Benton Harbor Michigan -- Detroit Michigan -- Grand Rapids Michigan -- Lansing Michigan -- Muskegon Michigan -- Saginaw Minnesota -- Duluth Minnesota -- Minneapolis-St. Paul Minnesota -- Rochester Minnesota -- St. Cloud Mississippi -- Biloxi Mississippi -- Columbus Mississippi -- Greenville Mississippi -- Gulfport Mississippi -- Jackson Mississippi -- Pascagoula Missouri -- Kansas City Missouri -- Springfield Missouri -- St. Louis Montana -- Billings Montana -- Great Falls Montana -- Helena Nebraska -- Lincoln Nebraska -- Omaha Nevada -- Carson City Nevada -- Las Vegas Nevada -- Reno New Hampshire -- Concord New Hampshire -- Manchester New Hampshire -- Nashua New Hampshire -- Portsmouth New Jersey -- Atlantic City New Jersey -- Bergen New Jersey -- Middlesex New Jersey -- New Brunswick New Jersey -- Newark New Jersey -- Paramus New Jersey -- Passaic New Jersey -- Somerset New Jersey -- Trenton New Jersey -- Vineland New Mexico -- Alamogordo New Mexico -- Albuquerque New Mexico -- Las Cruces New Mexico -- Santa Fe New York -- Albany New York -- Binghamton New York -- Buffalo New York -- Huntington New York -- Jamestown New York -- Nassau New York -- New York New York -- Poughkeepsie New York -- Queens New York -- Rochester New York -- Schenectady New York -- Suffolk New York -- Syracuse New York -- Troy New York -- Utica North Carolina -- Asheville North Carolina -- Charlotte North Carolina -- Fayetteville North Carolina -- Gastonia North Carolina -- Greensboro North Carolina -- High Point North Carolina -- Raleigh-Durham North Carolina -- Salisbury North Carolina -- Wilmington North Carolina -- Winston-Salem North Dakota -- Bismarck North Dakota -- Fargo North Dakota -- Grand Forks Ohio -- Akron Ohio -- Canton Ohio -- Chillicothe Ohio -- Cincinnati Ohio -- Cleveland Ohio -- Columbus Ohio -- Dayton Ohio -- Elyria Ohio -- Lima Ohio -- Lorain Ohio -- Portsmouth Ohio -- Springfield Ohio -- Toledo Ohio -- Youngstown Oklahoma -- Altus Oklahoma -- Lawton Oklahoma -- Oklahoma City Oklahoma -- Tulsa Oregon -- Eugene Oregon -- Medford Oregon -- Portland Oregon -- Salem Oregon -- Springfield Pennsylvania -- Allentown Pennsylvania -- Altoona Pennsylvania -- Erie Pennsylvania -- Harrisburg Pennsylvania -- Johnstown Pennsylvania -- Lancaster Pennsylvania -- Lebanon Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh Pennsylvania -- Reading Pennsylvania -- Scranton Pennsylvania -- York Puerto Rico -- San Juan Rhode Island -- Providence South Carolina -- Charleston South Carolina -- Columbia South Carolina -- Florence South Carolina -- Greenville South Carolina -- Rock Hill South Carolina -- Spartanburg South Carolina -- Sumter South Dakota -- Pierre South Dakota -- Rapid City South Dakota -- Sioux Falls Tennessee -- Chattanooga Tennessee -- Clarksville Tennessee -- Kingsport Tennessee -- Knoxville Tennessee -- Memphis Tennessee -- Nashville Texas -- Abilene Texas -- Amarillo Texas -- Austin Texas -- Beaumont Texas -- Brownsville Texas -- Corpus Christi Texas -- Dallas Texas -- El Paso Texas -- Fort Worth Texas -- Galveston Texas -- Harlingen Texas -- Houston Texas -- Killeen Texas -- Longview Texas -- Lubbock Texas -- McAllen Texas -- Port Arthur Texas -- San Antonio Texas -- Temple Texas -- Waco Texas -- Wichita Falls Utah -- Ogden Utah -- Provo Utah -- Salt Lake City Vermont -- Burlington Virginia -- Lynchburg Virginia -- Newport News Virginia -- Norfolk Virginia -- Petersburg Virginia -- Richmond Virginia -- Roanoke Virginia -- Virginia Beach Washington -- Bellingham Washington -- Bremerton Washington -- Everett Washington -- Kennewick Washington -- Olympia Washington -- Richland Washington -- Seattle Washington -- Spokane Washington -- Tacoma Washington -- Yakima West Virginia -- Charleston West Virginia -- Huntington West Virginia -- Parkersburg Wisconsin -- Appleton Wisconsin -- Green Bay Wisconsin -- La Crosse Wisconsin -- Madison Wisconsin -- Milwaukee Wisconsin -- Racine Wyoming -- Casper Wyoming -- Cheyenne Wyoming -- Laramie 
 
 
     home  &gt;  occupations  &gt;  food preparation and serving related  &gt;  cooks, fast food 
Occupation Profile for Cooks, Fast Food
 opportunity | video 
Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant with a limited menu. Duties of the cooks are limited to preparation of a few basic items and normally involve operating large-volume single-purpose cooking equipment.

Signficant Points

 Many cooks and food preparation workers are young37 percent are below the age of 24. One-third of these workers are employed part time. Job openings are expected to be plentiful because many of these workers will leave the occupation for full-time employment or better wages. 
   Overview Overview Earnings/Outlook Earnings/Outlook Skills Skills Tasks Tasks Colleges Colleges Jobs Jobs     Overview 
 $15,410.00 Median Annual Wage 22,000 Average Job Openings Per Year 8.7 Average Unemployment Percentage 76.5 Percentage That Completed High School 629,000 Employment Numbers in 2006 18.7 Percentage That Had Some College 681,000 Employment Numbers in 2016 (est.) 4.8 Percentage That Went Beyond College Degree 

 Sample Job Titles 
 Baker, Pizza 
 Cook 
 Cook, Specialty 
 Crew Person 
 Crew Trainer 
 Fry Cook 
 Fryline Attendant 
 Grill Cook 
 Line Cook 
 Pizza Baker 
 Pizza Chef 
 Pizza Cook 
 Pizza Maker 
 Restaurant Worker 
 

 Training 
 These occupations involve following instructions and helping others. Examples include taxi drivers, amusement and recreation attendants, counter and rental clerks, cashiers, and waiters/waitresses. These occupations may require a high school diploma or GED certificate. Some may require a formal training course to obtain a license. No previous work-related skill, knowledge, or experience is needed for these occupations. For example, a person can become a cashier even if he/she has never worked before. Employees in these occupations need anywhere from a few days to a few months of training. Usually, an experienced worker could show you how to do the job. 

On-the-job training is most common for fast-food cooks, short-order cooks, and food preparation workers. Chefs and others with more advanced cooking duties often attend cooking school. Vocational training programs are available to many high school students, but advanced positions usually require training after high school. Experience, an ability to develop and enhance cooking skills, and a strong desire to cook are the most common requirements for advancement.

 Education and training. A high school diploma is not required for beginning jobs, but it is recommended for those planning a career as a cook or chef. Most fast-food or short-order cooks and food preparation workers require little education or training to start because most skills are learned on the job. Training generally starts with basic sanitation and workplace safety and continues with instruction on food handling, preparation, and cooking procedures. Training in food handling, sanitation, and health and safety procedures are mandatory in most jurisdictions for all workers. Those who become proficient and who show an interest in learning complicated cooking techniques may advance to more demanding cooking positions or into supervisory positions.

Some high school or vocational school programs offer courses in basic food safety and handling procedures, cooking, and general business and computer classes that can be helpful for those who might someday want to be a chef or to open their own restaurant. Many school districts, in cooperation with State departments of education, provide on-the-job training and summer workshops for cafeteria kitchen workers who aspire to become cooks. Food service management companies or hotel and restaurant chains, also offer paid internships and summer jobs to those starting out in the field. Internships provide valuable experience and can lead to placement in more formal chef training programs.

When hiring chefs and others in advanced cooking positions, however, employers usually prefer applicants who have training after high school. These training programs range from a few months to 2 years or more. Vocational or trade-school programs typically offer basic training in food handling and sanitation procedures, nutrition, slicing and dicing methods for various kinds of meats and vegetables, and basic cooking methods, such as baking, broiling, and grilling. Longer programs leading to a certificate or a 2- or 4-year degree train chefs for fine-dining or upscale restaurants. They offer a wider array of training specialties, such as advanced cooking techniques; cooking for banquets, buffets, or parties; and cuisines and cooking styles from around the world.

A growing number of chefs participate in these longer training programs through independent cooking schools, professional culinary institutes, 2- or 4-year college degree programs in hospitality or culinary arts, or in the armed forces. Some large hotels and restaurants also operate their own training and job-placement programs for chefs and cooks. Executive chefs and head cooks who work in fine-dining restaurants require many years of training and experience and an intense desire to cook.

Although curricula may vary, students in culinary training programs spend most of their time in kitchens learning to prepare meals by practicing cooking skills. They learn good knife techniques and proper use and care of kitchen equipment. Training programs also include courses in nutrition, menu planning, portion control, purchasing and inventory methods, proper food storage procedures, and use of leftover food to minimize waste. Students also learn sanitation and public health rules for handling food. Training in food service management, computer accounting and inventory software, and banquet service are featured in some training programs. Most formal training programs also require students to get experience in a commercial kitchen through an internship, apprenticeship, or out-placement program.

Many chefs are trained on the job, receiving real work experience and training from chef-mentors in the restaurants where they work. Professional culinary institutes, industry associations, and trade unions sponsor formal apprenticeship programs in coordination with the U.S. Department of Labor.

The American Culinary Federation accredits more than 200 formal academic training programs and sponsors apprenticeship programs around the country. Typical apprenticeships last 2 years and combine classroom training and work experience. Accreditation is an indication that a culinary program meets recognized standards regarding course content, facilities, and quality of instruction.

 Other qualifications. Chefs, cooks, and food preparation workers must be efficient, quick, and work well as part of a team. Manual dexterity is helpful for cutting, chopping, and plating. These workers also need creativity and a keen sense of taste and smell. Personal cleanliness is essential because most States require health certificates indicating that workers are free from communicable diseases. Knowledge of a foreign language can be an asset because it may improve communication with other restaurant staff, vendors, and the restaurant’s clientele.

 Certification and advancement. The American Culinary Federation certifies pastry professionals, personal chefs, and culinary educators in addition to various levels of chefs. Certification standards are based primarily on experience and formal training. Although certification is not required, it can help to prove accomplishment and lead to advancement and higher-paying positions.

Advancement opportunities for chefs, cooks, and food preparation workers depend on their training, work experience, and ability to perform more responsible and sophisticated tasks. Many food preparation workers, for example, may move into assistant or line cook positions. Chefs and cooks who demonstrate an eagerness to learn new cooking skills and to accept greater responsibility may also move up and be asked to train or supervise lesser skilled kitchen staff. Others may move to larger or more prestigious kitchens and restaurants.

Some chefs and cooks go into business as caterers or personal chefs or open their own restaurant. Others become instructors in culinary training programs. A number of cooks and chefs advance to executive chef positions or food service management positions, particularly in hotels, clubs, or larger, more elegant restaurants.
 Nature of Work 
Chefs, cooks, and food preparation workers prepare, season, and cook a wide range of foodsfrom soups, snacks, and salads to entrees, side dishes, and desserts. They work in a variety of restaurants and other food services establishments. Chefs and cooks create recipes and prepare meals, while food preparation workers peel and cut vegetables, trim meat, prepare poultry, and perform other duties, such as keeping work areas clean and monitoring temperatures of ovens and stovetops.

Specifically, chefs and cooks measure, mix, and cook ingredients according to recipes, using a variety of equipment, including pots, pans, cutlery, ovens, broilers, grills, slicers, grinders, and blenders. Chefs and head cooks also are responsible for directing the work of other kitchen workers, estimating food requirements, and ordering food supplies.

 Food preparation workers perform routine, repetitive tasks under the direction of chefs and cooks. These workers ready the ingredients for complex dishes by slicing and dicing vegetables, and composing salads and cold items. They weigh and measure ingredients, go after pots and pans, and stir and strain soups and sauces. Food preparation workers may cut and grind meats, poultry, and seafood in preparation for cooking. They also clean work areas, equipment, utensils, dishes, and silverware.

Larger restaurants and food services establishments tend to have varied menus and larger kitchen staffs. Staffs often include several chefs and cooks, sometimes called assistant or line cooks. Each chef or cook works an assigned station that is equipped with the types of stoves, grills, pans, and ingredients needed for the foods prepared at that station. Job titles often reflect the principal ingredient prepared or the type of cooking performedvegetable cook, fry cook, or grill cook, for example. These cooks also may direct or work with other food preparation workers.

 Executive chefs and head cooks coordinate the work of the kitchen staff and direct the preparation of meals. They determine serving sizes, plan menus, order food supplies, and oversee kitchen operations to ensure uniform quality and presentation of meals. An executive chef, for example, is in charge of all food service operations and also may supervise the many kitchens of a hotel, restaurant group, or corporate dining operation. A chef de cuisine reports to an executive chef and is responsible for the daily operations of a single kitchen. A sous chef , or sub chef, is the second-in-command and runs the kitchen in the absence of the chef. Many chefs earn fame both for themselves and for their kitchens because of the quality and distinctive nature of the food they serve.

Responsibilities depend on where cooks work. Institution and cafeteria cooks , for example, work in the kitchens of schools, cafeterias, businesses, hospitals, and other institutions. For each meal, they prepare a large quantity of a limited number of entrees, vegetables, and desserts according to preset menus. Meals generally are prepared in advance so diners seldom get the opportunity to special order a meal. Restaurant cooks usually prepare a wider selection of dishes, cooking most orders individually. Short-order cooks prepare foods in restaurants and coffee shops that emphasize fast service and quick food preparation. They grill and garnish hamburgers, prepare sandwiches, fry eggs, and cook French fries, often working on several orders at the same time. Fast-food cooks prepare a limited selection of menu items in fast-food restaurants. They cook and package batches of food, such as hamburgers and fried chicken, to be kept warm until served. (Combined food preparation and service workers, who both prepare and serve items in fast-food restaurants, are included with the material on food and beverage serving and related workers elsewhere in the Handbook .)

The number and types of workers employed in kitchens also depends on the type of establishment. Small, full-service restaurants offering casual dining often feature a limited number of easy-to-prepare items supplemented by short-order specialties and ready-made desserts. Typically, one cook prepares all the food with the help of a short-order cook and one or two other kitchen workers.

Grocery and specialty food stores employ chefs, cooks, and food preparation workers to develop recipes and prepare meals for customers to carry out. Typically, entrees, side dishes, salads, or other items are prepared in large quantities and stored at an appropriate temperature. Counter assistants portion and package items according to customer orders for serving at home.

Some cooks, called research chefs, combine culinary skills with knowledge of food science to develop recipes for chain restaurants and food processors and manufacturers. They test new formulas and flavors for prepared foods and determine the most efficient and safest way to prepare new foods.

Some cooks work for individuals rather than for restaurants, cafeterias, or food manufacturers. These private household cooks plan and prepare meals in private homes according to the client’s tastes or dietary needs. They order groceries and supplies, clean the kitchen, and wash dishes and utensils. They also may serve meals. Private chefs are employed directly by a single individual or family or sometimes by corporations or institutions, such as universities and embassies, to perform cooking and entertaining tasks. These chefs usually live in and may travel with their employer. Because of the sensitive nature of their employment, they are usually required to sign confidentiality agreements. As part of the job, private chefs often perform additional services, such as paying bills, coordinating schedules, and planning events.

Another type of private household cooks, called personal chefs, usually prepare a week’s worth of meals in the client’s home for the client to heat and serve according to directions throughout the week. Personal chefs are self-employed or employed by a company that provides this service.

 Work environment. Many restaurant and institutional kitchens have modern equipment, convenient work areas, and air conditioning, but kitchens in older and smaller eating places are often not as well designed. Kitchen staffs invariably work in small quarters against hot stoves and ovens. They are under constant pressure to prepare meals quickly, while ensuring quality is maintained and safety and sanitation guidelines are observed. Because the pace can be hectic during peak dining times, workers must be able to communicate clearly so that food orders are completed correctly.

Working conditions vary with the type and quantity of food prepared and the local laws governing food service operations. Workers usually must stand for hours at a time, lifting heavy pots and kettles, and working near hot ovens and grills. Job hazards include slips and falls, cuts, and burns, but injuries are seldom serious.

Work hours in restaurants may include early mornings, late evenings, holidays, and weekends. Work schedules of chefs, cooks and other kitchen workers in factory and school cafeterias may be more regular. In 2006, about 29 percent of cooks and 44 percent of food preparation workers had part-time schedules, compared to 15 percent of workers throughout the economy. Work schedules in fine-dining restaurants, however, tend to be longer because of the time required to prepare ingredients in advance. Many executive chefs regularly work 12-hour days because they oversee the delivery of foodstuffs early in the day, plan the menu, and prepare those menu items that take the most skill.

The wide range in dining hours and the need for fully-staffed kitchens during all open hours creates work opportunities for students, youth, and other individuals seeking supplemental income, flexible work hours, or variable schedules. Eighteen percent of cooks and food preparation workers were 16 to 19 years old in 2006; nineteen percent were age 20 to 24. Ten percent had variable schedules. Kitchen workers employed by schools may work during the school year only, usually for 9 or 10 months. Similarly, resort establishments usually only offer seasonal employment.
 Related Occupations 
 Chefs and Head Cooks Cooks, Short Order Counter Attendants, Cafeteria, Food Concession, and Coffee Shop Dining Room and Cafeteria Attendants and Bartender Helpers Maids and Housekeeping Cleaners Butchers and Meat Cutters Pressers, Textile, Garment, and Related Materials 

 Sources: Career Guide to Industries (CGI), Occupational Information Network (O*Net), Occupation Outlook Handbook (OOH) Earnings 
Earnings of chefs, cooks, and food preparation workers vary greatly by region and the type of employer. Earnings usually are highest in elegant restaurants and hotels, where many executive chefs are employed, and in major metropolitan and resort areas.

Median annual wage-and-salary earnings of chefs and head cooks were $34,370 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $25,910 and $46,040. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $20,160, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $60,730. Median annual earnings in the industries employing the largest number of chefs and head cooks were:



 
 Other amusement and recreations industries $46,460 Traveler accommodation 40,020 Special food services 36,450 Full-service restaurants 32,360 Limited-service eating places 27,560 
 



Median annual wage-and-salary earnings of cooks, private household were $22,870 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $17,960 and $31,050. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $14,690, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $55,040.

Median annual wage-and-and salary earnings of institution and cafeteria cooks were $20,410 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $16,280 and $25,280. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $13,450, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $30,770. Median annual earnings in the industries employing the largest numbers of institution and cafeteria cooks were:



 
 General medical and surgical hospitals $22,980 Special food services 21,650 Community care facilities for the elderly 20,910 Nursing care facilities 20,470 Elementary and secondary schools 18,770 
 



Median annual wage-and-salary earnings of restaurant cooks were $20,340 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $16,860 and $24,260. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $14,370, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $28,850. Median annual earnings in the industries employing the largest numbers of restaurant cooks were:



 
 Traveler accommodations $23,400 Full-service restaurants 20,100 Limited-service eating places 18,200 
 



Median annual wage-and-salary earnings of short-order cooks were $17,880 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $14,960 and $21,820. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $12,930, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $26,110. Median annual earnings in full-service restaurants were $18,340.

Median annual wage-and-salary earnings of food preparation workers were $17,410 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $14,920 and $21,230. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $13,190, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $25,940. Median annual earnings in the industries employing the largest number of food preparation workers were:



 
 Grocery stores $18,920 Full-service restaurants 17,390 Limited-service eating places 15,550 
 



Median annual wage-and-salary earnings of fast-food cooks were $15,410 in May 2006. The middle 50 percent earned between $13,730 and $17,700. The lowest 10 percent earned less than $12,170, and the highest 10 percent earned more than $20,770. Median annual earnings were $15,360 in full-service restaurants and $15,350 in limited-service eating places.

Some employers provide employees with uniforms and free meals, but Federal law permits employers to deduct from their employees’wages the cost or fair value of any meals or lodging provided, and some employers do so. Chefs, cooks, and food preparation workers who work full time often receive typical benefits, but part-time and hourly workers usually do not.

In some large hotels and restaurants, kitchen workers belong to unions. The principal unions are the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union and the Service Employees International Union.

 For the latest wage information: 
 
The above wage data are from the
	</body>
</document>
