<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006693" url="http://www.marlerblog.com/tags/food-safety/" time="2012-07-12-23:41" support="24" score="0.034477843750318614" bingtitle=": food safety : Marler Blog" webtitle=": food safety : Marler Blog">
			<query id="001525" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001463" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001022" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001431" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000396" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000739" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001306" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001211" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000614" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000897" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000240" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001494" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000177" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000991" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001054" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000426" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000929" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001117" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000302" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001179" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>“Bill Marler: Food Safety Czar” does have a nice ... uncooked) of a finger found in the chili at a fast-food ... I still have my receipt. I had not eaten anything prior to ...</description>
	<body>
		Marler Blog : Food Poisoning Lawyer&amp;Attorney : Bill Marler : Marler Clark 

 Published By
 Marler Clark - Attorneys at law L.L.P., P.S. 
 Bill Marler is an accomplished personal injury and products liability attorney. He began litigating foodborne illness cases in 1993, when More... 
 Providing commentary on food poisoning outbreaks&amp;litigation 
 
 Home About Bill Marler Services Contact Archives 
 
The Best of Bill Marler Op Ed posts that 
shouldn’t be missed 

 Awards for lawyering, blogging and just surviving KCTS 9 Series April 16, 2010 Lead Story - How Safe is your Burger? Is E. coli O157:H7 really down since 2004, or is it &quot;Fuzzy Math?&quot; Rotten Tomatoes? What do They Really Tell Us About the Safety of Our Food? Wyoming Legislature set to pass House Bill 54 - The &quot;Bill Marler Full Employment Act&quot; - Thank you Sue Wallis. 
 Archives Home &gt; food safety &gt; 
 FOOD SAFETY premieres on KCTS this Friday night 
 
  I had the honor of talking extensively with KCTS producer Terry Murphy about food safety. I&apos;m looking forward to seeing the piece, which airs this Friday in the Seattle area, and will then be online. 

On Friday, April 16, Seattle’s public television station, KCTS 9, will premiere an original report on food safety. The piece is the culmination of months of research, and includes interviews with prominent voices in food safety, including Bill Marler and Mansour Samadapour.  The report will air on KCTS Connects with Enrique Cerna at 7:30 PM. After the broadcast, the report will be available for online viewing by visiting the station’s website .

 KCTS 9 Connects with Enrique Cerna is a weekly exploration of news, politics and culture.  The show tackles“provocative and emotional topics important to people in the Northwest and British Columbia.” This is the 10 th season for award-winning journalist Enrique Cerna. The report is produced by Terry Murphy.
 Posted on April 13, 2010 by Bill Marler Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , Bill Marler , KCTS , food safety 
 Email This Print Comments Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 Up Early - Talking Salmonella Peanut Butter at 3:00 AM 
 
 

Had the pleasure to join John Hockenberry, Adaora Udoji and Nadia Zonis to talk about - &quot;How to make our food safety system stronger&quot; 
 
 Salmonella-tainted peanut butter has sickened close to five hundred people in 43 states, and killed six. People started getting sick back in September, but the FDA has only recently pinpointed the source of the infection - King Nut brand peanut butter manufactured by Peanut Corporation of America in Blakely, Georgia. Bill Marler, a Seattle lawyer who represents victims of food poisoning and advises companies on food safety joins John and Adaora to explain why it takes so long to trace foodborne illnesses and how the system could be improved.  
 
 Audio should be online soon.  I&apos;m going back to bed for a few hours.
 Posted on January 23, 2009 by Bill Marler Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , food safety , interview , thetakeaway.org 
 Email This Print Comments Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 E. coli Outbreaks still a Risk in Leafy Greens 
 
 I spent the day is a well-run, informative, conference sponsored by Fresh Express (never sued them). The science was interesting and well presented. The bottom line however is there is far more research needed and the risks to consumers are still quite real in the consumption of“ready-to-eat”products. Here are some of the highlights from the scientists:

1. Contamination can spread during washing, cutting in the fields and the tumble drying of greens

2. Chlorinated water alone isn&apos;t enough to kill the pathogens.

3. Some varieties of spinach with textured leaves have greater potential for harboring pathogens than smooth-leaf varieties.

4. E. coli can paralyze pore closures (somata) on spinach leaves and allow bacteria into the plant.

5. Compost used inorganic operations can retain traces of live E. coli cells that can reconstitute under the right conditions.

6. Spinach and lettuce harvested on hotter days are more likely to create an environment for pathogen growth.

7. Lower product temperature, especially during transportation, lowers risk of bacterial growth.

8. Flies or other insects can excrete bacteria in their fecal droplets.

9. It seems apparent that the E. coli bacteria is not absorbed by the roots into the plant structure.

OK, not much good news here. The only two areas that seemed hopeful was that some research on E. coli transmission found ozone gas is faster and more effective than chlorinated water at sanitizing leafy greens. And, although not mentioned until the last hour, irradiation of leafy greens can make food safer.

Bottom line–more work to do.
 
 Posted on September 12, 2008 by Food Poisoning Attorney Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , Fresh Express conference , chlorine gas , food safety , irradiation 
 Email This Print Comments (3) Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 Grass-Fed vs Grain-Fed Beef and the Holy Grail: A Literature Review 
 
Several people have commented that switching from grain to grass feeding could be one of the solutions to the problem with foodborne pathogens in cattle and other livestock. Quotes like these are becoming more common on the Internet and in recent media reports:

 “Products from grass-fed animals are safer than food from conventionally-raised animals.” Eatwild, 2008

“Research has shown that the strains of E. coli most devastating to humans are the product of feedlots, not cows. This is due to the animals being forced to eat an unnatural diet, and not their natural choice, grass.” Grass-Fed Beef: Safer and Healthier, Animal Welfare Approved, June 15, 2008 

If true, changing the cow’s diet would be such a simple and cheap management practice to implement. Have we found the Holy Grail for food safety? Below is some research I did on the topic.

 OVERVIEW 

•Identification of on-farm management practices that would reduce or eliminate foodborne pathogens in cattle and other livestock (including diet changes) is an active area of research, but many study results are inconclusive. E. coli O157:H7, Campylobacter, Salmonella, and other dangerous pathogens have been repeatedly isolated from both grass and grain fed livestock, and the studies show conflicting results regarding whether the levels of pathogens are higher, lower, or the same when animals are fed grass- or grain-based diets.

•There is no clear and consistent definition in the literature of“grass-fed,”but the majority of papers describe animals that are on pasture or confined, but receiving only hay-based diets. Last year, the USDA Agricultural Marketing Service issued a standard for grass (forage) fed marketing claims. More research on this topic is needed that compares rates of foodborne pathogens among grain and grass fed animals using a specific definition such as the USDA standard or other accepted definition.

•The original study by Diez-Gonzalez published in Science in 1998, and since cited numerous times in the literature and media, suggested that cattle could be fed hay for a brief period before slaughter to significantly reduce the risk of foodborne E. coli infection. They based this conclusion on a hypothesis that grain feeding increases acid resistance of E. coli in cattle. Although they showed increased acid resistance in E. coli from grain-fed cattle, but the sample size was small, and they used“generic”E. coli stains, not E. coli O157:H7.

•Studies by other researchers worldwide have since found little difference in acid resistant E. coli O157:H7 among grain- verses grass-fed cattle, and some even found more E. coli O157:H7 shed by grass-fed animals.

•It has been discovered that E. coli O157:H7 and Salmonella can rapidly switch from being“acid sensitive”to“acid resistant”within minutes after entering an acidic environment (such as the human stomach). Thus, even if the grass-fed/E. coli acid-resistance hypothesis were true, manipulating the diet may not have any effect since pathogens can adapt quickly to new environments like the human stomach.

•Outbreaks have traced back to grass-fed and pastured animals, as well as animals in feedlots. Notably, the E. coli O157:H7 spinach outbreak strain in 2006 was isolated from grass-fed cattle. Another outbreak of E. coli O157:H7 was linked recently to raw milk and colostrum from cattle raised organically on grass.

•In summary, the scientific evidence at this time does not support a broad conclusion that grass feeding significantly and consistently reduces the risk of E. coli O157:H7 or other dangerous foodborne pathogens entering the food chain. However, more research is needed into the influence of food animal diets. For example, preliminary experimental data shows a possible association between feeding dried distiller’s grains and shedding of E. coli O157:H7 in cattle feces.

 INTRODUCTION 

A systematic approach is necessary to combat the emerging challenges in food safety such as the unexplained“uptick”of E. coli O157:H7 outbreaks and recalls linked to beef products. Interventions to protect the food supply should ideally occur across the continuum from“farm to fork.”The“Holy Grail”of pre-harvest (farm-level) food safety would be to find an effective, affordable, and practical means to prevent or reduce food animals from shedding foodborne pathogens in the first place so the dangerous bacteria never enter the human food chain. Since cattle or other livestock may be located near drinking water sources or vegetable crops, a farm-level intervention could also help to protect nearby water and crops from contamination by manure via runoff, transport by wildlife/insects, or other mechanisms.

Oliver et al (2008) published a comprehensive review of developments and future outlooks for pre-harvest food safety this month. Examples of potential farm-level management practices that have been studied for E. coli O157:H7 and other foodborne pathogens in livestock include:

•Antibiotics
•Bacteriophages (viruses of bacteria)
•Dietary changes
•Immunization
•Probiotics or prebiotics in animal rations
•Sanitation/hygiene (feed, water, environment)
•Wildlife and insect control

Unfortunately, the best approaches for on-farm control of foodborne pathogens in livestock remain elusive. No single management practice, or even a combination of methods, has proven to be very effective or reliable in preventing foodborne pathogen colonization in livestock. Clearly, sanitation including clean feed/water sources and insect control are important, but difficult to maintain in a farm environment. Livestock immunizations are not available for most foodborne pathogens with the exception of an E. coli O157:H7 vaccine under development (and some ask“who would pay for such a program?”since cattle do not become ill from E. coli O157). Use of antibiotics is problematic because it can lead to resistance.

 GRASS VERSUS GRAIN FEEDING

Definition of“Grass-Fed” 

The majority of cattle are fed grass or other forage at some time during their lives. For the purpose of marketing, the USDA Agricultural Marketing Service issued a voluntary standard for grass (forage) fed marketing claims last year that states:“grass fed standard states that grass and/or forage shall be the feed source consumed for the lifetime of the ruminant animal, with the exception of milk consumed prior to weaning. The diet shall be derived solely from forage and animals cannot be fed grain or grain by-products and must have continuous access to pasture during the growing season.”

Note that most papers in the literature do not specifically define grass-fed using this new standard or any other specific definition, but differentiate, in general, between animals on forage (grass) only verses diets containing grain.
 
The Study that Started the Controversy 

The original study that launched the controversy over grain feeding was published in Science in 1998 by researchers from Cornell (Diez-Gonzalez et al). They described potential dietary effects on the acid resistance of E. coli in cattle fed grain- versus hay-based diets. This study has since been cited numerous times in the literature and media, but later studies have not been able to reproduce the findings. This may be due, in part, to several limitations in the original study design including: 1) small sample size and 2)“Generic”E. coli levels were measured, not E. coli O157:H7.

In 2006, Hancock and Besser wrote a summary of the evidence surrounding the hypothesis that feeding hay instead of grain would reduce the problem with E. coli O157:H7, purportedly because the stomachs of grain-fed cattle are more acidic. They concluded:“while one cannot rule out a role of cattle diet on affecting exposure and infectivity of E. coli O157:H7 to humans, the data available at present demonstrate that cattle on a wide variety of diets (including 100% forage diets) are regularly and similarly colonized with this pathogen.”

Another interesting study from a research group in The Netherlands discovered that E. coli O157:H7 and Salmonella can rapidly switch from being“acid sensitive”to“acid resistant”within minutes after entering an environment with reduced pH (such as the human stomach). Thus, even if the grass-fed hypothesis were true, manipulating the diet may not have any effect since E. coli O157:H7 can adapt quickly to new environments like the human stomach.

 Recent Findings in the Literature 

In searching through the literature since Hancock and Besser’s review, several new papers relevant to the discussion were found.

 1. Nutritional aspects of grass-fed beef. 

Leheska, J. M., L. D. Thompson, J. C. Howe, E. Hentges, J. Boyce, J. C. Brooks, B. Shriver, L. Hoover, and M. F. Miller. 2008. Effects of conventional and grass feeding systems on the nutrient composition of beef. J Anim Sci.

•This paper explores the question about whether there are differences in nutrient composition of grass-fed beef compared with conventional (grain)-fed beef. Researchers have previously found higher omega-3 fatty acids and CLA (conjugated linoleic acid) in forage-fed beef, and lower fat content overall. Some consumers prefer eating grass-fed meat because they believe it is“healthier,”and/or tastes better than conventional beef.

•The authors of this study enrolled only producers that were marketing grass-fed beef and confirmed that“100% of the diets were made up of native grasses, forages, or cut grasses or forages.”

•Fatty acid composition of grass-fed and conventional-fed beef was found to be different, but the authors conclude“the effects of the lipid differences between grass-fed and conventional raised beef, on human health, remains to be investigated.”

 2. Papers continue to be published about possible effects of diet on E. coli O157:H7 prevalence and concentration. 

For example, a research team from Kansas State University reported that feeding distillers grains, a co-product of ethanol production, to feedlot cattle may have a positive association with fecal shedding of E. coli O157. The mechanism is unknown, but they hypothesize that the grains change the ecology of the hindgut where E. coli O157 is most likely to colonize cattle. The authors report that larger studies are underway to investigate this possible link.
 
CONCLUSIONS 

In summary, the scientific evidence at this time does not support a broad conclusion that grass feeding significantly reduces the risk of E. coli O157:H7 or other dangerous foodborne pathogens from entering the food chain. However, more research is needed to better understand the influence of diet, especially the use of different types of grains in animal feed.

 REFERENCES BELOW 
 
1. Bach, S. J., L. J. Selinger, K. Stanford, and T. A. McAllister. 2005. Effect of supplementing corn- or barley-based feedlot diets with canola oil on faecal shedding of Escherichia coli O157:H7 by steers. J Appl Microbiol 98:464-75.

2. Bailey, G. D., B. A. Vanselow, M. A. Hornitzky, S. I. Hum, G. J. Eamens, P. A. Gill, K. H. Walker, and J. P. Cronin. 2003. A study of the foodborne pathogens: Campylobacter, Listeria and Yersinia, in faeces from slaughter-age cattle and sheep in Australia. Commun Dis Intell 27:249-57.

3. Berg, J., T. McAllister, S. Bach, R. Stilborn, D. Hancock, and J. LeJeune. 2004. Escherichia coli O157:H7 excretion by commercial feedlot cattle fed either barley- or corn-based finishing diets. J Food Prot 67:666-71.

4. Brownlie, L. E., and F. H. Grau. 1967. Effect of food intake on growth and survival of salmonellas and Escherichia coli in the bovine rumen. J Gen Microbiol 46:125-34.

5. Buchko, S. J., R. A. Holley, W. O. Olson, V. P. Gannon, and D. M. Veira. 2000. The effect of different grain diets on fecal shedding of Escherichia coli O157:H7 by steers. J Food Prot 63:1467-74.

6. Callaway, T. R., R. O. Elder, J. E. Keen, R. C. Anderson, and D. J. Nisbet. 2003. Forage feeding to reduce preharvest Escherichia coli populations in cattle, a review. J Dairy Sci 86:852-60.

7. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 2008. Escherichia coli 0157:H7 infections in children associated with raw milk and raw colostrum from cows--California, 2006. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 57:625-8.

8. Cray, W. C., Jr., T. A. Casey, B. T. Bosworth, and M. A. Rasmussen. 1998. Effect of dietary stress on fecal shedding of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in calves. Appl Environ Microbiol 64:1975-9.

9. de Jonge, R., K. Takumi, W. S. Ritmeester, F. M. van Leusden. 2003. The adaptive response of Escherichia coli O157 in an environment with changing pH. J Appl Microbiol. 94:555-60.

10. Depenbusch, B. E., T. G. Nagaraja, J. M. Sargeant, J. S. Drouillard, E. R. Loe, and M. E. Corrigan. 2008. Influence of processed grains on fecal pH, starch concentration, and shedding of Escherichia coli O157 in feedlot cattle. J Anim Sci 86:632-9.

11. Diez-Gonzalez, F., T. R. Callaway, M. G. Kizoulis, and J. B. Russell. 1998. Grain feeding and the dissemination of acid-resistant Escherichia coli from cattle. Science 281:1666-8.

12. Djordjevic, S. P., V. Ramachandran, K. A. Bettelheim, B. A. Vanselow, P. Holst, G. Bailey, and M. A. Hornitzky. 2004. Serotypes and virulence gene profiles of shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli strains isolated from feces of pasture-fed and lot-fed sheep. Appl Environ Microbiol 70:3910-7.

13. Doyle, M. P., and M. C. Erickson. 2006. Reducing the carriage of foodborne pathogens in livestock and poultry. Poult Sci 85:960-73.

14. Fegan, N., P. Vanderlinde, G. Higgs, and P. Desmarchelier. 2004. The prevalence and concentration of Escherichia coli O157 in faeces of cattle from different production systems at slaughter. J Appl Microbiol 97:362-70.

15. Fox, J. T., B. E. Depenbusch, J. S. Drouillard, and T. G. Nagaraja. 2007. Dry-rolled or steam-flaked grain-based diets and fecal shedding of Escherichia coli O157 in feedlot cattle. J Anim Sci 85:1207-12.

16. Franz, E., A. D. van Diepeningen, O. J. de Vos, and A. H. van Bruggen. 2005. Effects of cattle feeding regimen and soil management type on the fate of Escherichia coli O157:H7 and salmonella enterica serovar typhimurium in manure, manure-amended soil, and lettuce. Appl Environ Microbiol 71:6165-74.

17. Fu, C. J., J. H. Porter, E. E. Felton, J. W. Lehmkuhler, and M. S. Kerley. 2003. Pre-harvest factors influencing the acid resistance of Escherichia coli and E. coli O157:H7. J Anim Sci 81:1080-7.

18. Gilbert, R. A., S. E. Denman, J. Padmanabha, N. Fegan, D. Al Ajmi, and C. S. McSweeney. 2008. Effect of diet on the concentration of complex Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli and EHEC virulence genes in bovine faeces, hide and carcass. Int J Food Microbiol 121:208-16.

19. Gilbert, R. A., N. Tomkins, J. Padmanabha, J. M. Gough, D. O. Krause, and C. S. McSweeney. 2005. Effect of finishing diets on Escherichia coli populations and prevalence of enterohaemorrhagic E. coli virulence genes in cattle faeces. J Appl Microbiol 99:885-94.

20. Grauke, L. J., S. A. Wynia, H. Q. Sheng, J. W. Yoon, C. J. Williams, C. W. Hunt, and C. J. Hovde. 2003. Acid resistance of Escherichia coli O157:H7 from the gastrointestinal tract of cattle fed hay or grain. Vet Microbiol 95:211-25.

21. Hancock, D. and T. Besser. 2006. E. coli O157:H7 in hay- or grain-fed cattle. Accessed at: http://www.puyallup.wsu.edu/dairy/nutrient-management/data/publications/E%20coli%20O157%20in%20hay-%20or%20grain-fed%20cattle%20Hancock%20and%20Besser%2011%2006.pdf 

22. Hovde, C. J., P. R. Austin, K. A. Cloud, C. J. Williams, and C. W. Hunt. 1999. Effect of cattle diet on Escherichia coli O157:H7 acid resistance. Appl Environ Microbiol 65:3233-5.

23. Hussein, H. S. 2007. Prevalence and pathogenicity of Shiga toxin-producing Escherichia coli in beef cattle and their products. J Anim Sci 85:E63-72.

24. Jacob, M. E., J. T. Fox, J. S. Drouillard, D. G. Renter, and T. G. Nagaraja. 2008. Effects of dried distillers&apos; grain on fecal prevalence and growth of Escherichia coli O157 in batch culture fermentations from cattle. Appl Environ Microbiol 74:38-43.

25. Jacob, M. E., J. T. Fox, S. K. Narayanan, J. S. Drouillard, D. G. Renter, and T. G. Nagaraja. 2008. Effects of feeding wet corn distillers grains with solubles with or without monensin and tylosin on the prevalence and antimicrobial susceptibilities of fecal foodborne pathogenic and commensal bacteria in feedlot cattle. J Anim Sci 86:1182-90.

26. Jacob, M. E., G. L. Parsons, M. K. Shelor, J. T. Fox, J. S. Drouillard, D. U. Thomson, D. G. Renter, and T. G. Nagaraja. 2008. Feeding supplemental dried distiller&apos;s grains increases faecal shedding of Escherichia coli O157 in experimentally inoculated calves. Zoonoses Public Health 55:125-32.

27. Jay, M. T., M. Cooley, D. Carychao, G. W. Wiscomb, R. A. Sweitzer, L. Crawford-Miksza, J. A. Farrar, D. K. Lau, J. O&apos;Connell, A. Millington, R. V. Asmundson, E. R. Atwill, and R. E. Mandrell. 2007. Escherichia coli O157:H7 in feral swine near spinach fields and cattle, central California coast. Emerg Infect Dis 13:1908-11.

28. Krueger, N. A., R. C. Anderson, W. K. Krueger, W. J. Horne, I. V. Wesley, T. R. Callaway, T. S. Edrington, G. E. Carstens, R. B. Harvey, and D. J. Nisbet. 2008. Prevalence and Concentration of Campylobacter in Rumen Contents and Feces in Pasture and Feedlot-Fed Cattle. Foodborne Pathog Dis.

29. Kudva, I. T., P. G. Hatfield, and C. J. Hovde. 1995. Effect of diet on the shedding of Escherichia coli O157:H7 in a sheep model. Appl Environ Microbiol 61:1363-70.

30. Leheska, J. M., L. D. Thompson, J. C. Howe, E. Hentges, J. Boyce, J. C. Brooks, B. Shriver, L. Hoover, and M. F. Miller. 2008. Effects of conventional and grass feeding systems on the nutrient composition of beef. J Anim Sci.

31. Looper, M. L., T. S. Edrington, R. Flores, J. M. Burke, T. R. Callaway, G. E. Aiken, F. N. Schrick, and C. F. Rosenkrans, Jr. 2007. Influence of dietary endophyte (Neotyphodium coenophialum)-infected tall fescue (Festuca arundinacea) seed on fecal shedding of antibiotic resistance-selected Escherichia coli O157:H7 in ewes. J Anim Sci 85:1102-8.

32. Looper, M. L., T. S. Edrington, R. Flores, C. F. Rosenkrans, Jr., M. E. Nihsen, and G. E. Aiken. 2006. Prevalence of Escherichia coli O157:H7 and Salmonella in beef steers consuming different forage diets. Lett Appl Microbiol 42:583-8.

33. Oliver, S. P., D. A. Patel, T. R. Callaway, and M. E. Torrence. 2008. ASAS Centennial Paper: Developments and future outlook for preharvest food safety. J Anim Sci.

34. Renter, D. G., J. M. Sargeant, and L. L. Hungerford. 2004. Distribution of Escherichia coli O157:H7 within and among cattle operations in pasture-based agricultural areas. Am J Vet Res 65:1367-76.

35. Renter, D. G., J. M. Sargeant, R. D. Oberst, and M. Samadpour. 2003. Diversity, frequency, and persistence of Escherichia coli O157 strains from range cattle environments. Appl Environ Microbiol 69:542-7.

36. Russell, J. B., F. Diez-Gonzalez, and G. N. Jarvis. 2000. Invited review: effects of diet shifts on Escherichia coli in cattle. J Dairy Sci 83:863-73.

37. Russell, J. B., F. Diez-Gonzalez, and G. N. Jarvis. 2000. Potential effect of cattle diets on the transmission of pathogenic Escherichia coli to humans. Microbes Infect 2:45-53.

38. Sargeant, J. M., J. R. Gillespie, R. D. Oberst, R. K. Phebus, D. R. Hyatt, L. K. Bohra, and J. C. Galland. 2000. Results of a longitudinal study of the prevalence of Escherichia coli O157:H7 on cow-calf farms. Am J Vet Res 61:1375-9.

39. Tkalcic, S., C. A. Brown, B. G. Harmon, A. V. Jain, E. P. Mueller, A. Parks, K. L. Jacobsen, S. A. Martin, T. Zhao, and M. P. Doyle. 2000. Effects of diet on rumen proliferation and fecal shedding of Escherichia coil O157:H7 in calves. J Food Prot 63:1630-6.

40. Van Baale, M. J., J. M. Sargeant, D. P. Gnad, B. M. DeBey, K. F. Lechtenberg, and T. G. Nagaraja. 2004. Effect of forage or grain diets with or without monensin on ruminal persistence and fecal Escherichia coli O157:H7 in cattle. Appl Environ Microbiol 70:5336-42.
 Posted on August 30, 2008 by Bill Marler Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , cattle , feedlots , food safety , grain-fed , grass-fed 
 Email This Print Comments (9) Trackbacks (1) Share Link 
 
 My interview on Progressive Talk Radio 
 I recently did an interview with Don Riggs, the host of Introspect Northwest, which airs on KMPS-FM 94.1 at 6:00 a.m. on Sunday, and on KPTK-AM 1090 at 9:00 a.m. on Sunday. Don and I talked about food poisoning lawsuits during our interview. You can listen in on Sunday at 9 a.m. here:  radiotime .com 
 Posted on December 13, 2007 by Bill Marler Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , food safety 
 Email This Print Comments (1) Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 Bill Marler: Food Safety Czar? 
 Speechwriter/Ghostwriter Jane Genova recently posted on her blog that she thinks Hillary Clinton will win the Whitehouse and when she does, I should be appointed Food Safety Czar:  
 I have someone in mind for the job of food-safety czar. It&apos;s Bill Marler of Marler Clark Law firm. Actually Hillary might already know Marler, a plaintiff attorney specializing in food-borne diseases. Marler was among the coalition of experts who helped create a new system after the E-Coli outbreak early in Bill Clinton&apos;s first administration. The new president was delivering a televised town meeting when a couple whose child ate some of that contaminated meat spoke up. That child later died. 
 
I worked with former President Bill Clinton to arrange congressional hearings and victim testimony after the Jack in the Box E. coli outbreak in 1993. What we needed–and still need–was change in our food safety system. Significant change. 

What we got then was a classification of E. coli O157:H7 as an adulterant in meat products. A good step in the right direction. What we need now is a single agency responsible for food safety–one that has the power to shut down processing plants and recall contaminated food products, among other things.

 “Bill Marler: Food Safety Czar” does have a nice ring to it, but since I don’t think my wife and kids would let me move them to Washington, D.C. here’s my offer: When the Democrats win the Whitehouse and create a single food safety agency, and when companies stop poisoning people, I’ll stop calling for Congressional hearings on food safety and asking the food industry to“ put me out of business .” 
 Posted on October 11, 2007 by Bill Marler Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , food safety 
 Email This Print Comments (2) Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 Seminar: Food Safety in the U.S. - Does Litigation Help? 
 
On June 16, 2005, I discussed during a seminar at the University of Guelph why processors, ingredient suppliers, restaurant operators, and any operations involved in the growth, processing, and distribution of food products should understand the legal consequences and dangers of what may happen when foodborne illness strikes as a result of one of their products sold in the U.S. I discussed issues such as liability and how it is determined, the discovery process, and the importance of open communications in the event of an outbreak.

A copy of the Powerpoint presentation is available at http://www.foodsafetynetwork.ca/food/fslitigation.pdf 
 Posted on July 15, 2005 by Marler Lawyer Tags: Case News , University of Guelph , William Marler , food safety , seminar 
 Email This Print Comments Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 Foodborne Illness 
 
 The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) estimates that each year 76 million - or one out of every four - Americans are sickened as a result of consuming contaminated foods or beverages. Some become seriously ill; 325,000 require hospitalization and 5,000 die. Older adults, young children, and those who have weakened immune systems are particularly vulnerable.

More than 250 different foodborne diseases have been identified. Most of these diseases are infections caused by a variety of bacteria, viruses, and parasites.

Foods that are contaminated with poisonous chemicals or harmful substances can also cause illness. Symptoms of foodborne illness vary by disease but the most common are nausea, vomiting, abdominal cramps, and diarrhea.
 
I have some of the symptoms described. Do I have a foodborne illness?

Possibly. For example, scientists estimate that 35% of diarrheal illness is caused by a foodborne pathogen. Diarrhea that is caused by food poisoning usually lasts one week or less. Symptoms that appear suddenly are a sign of foodborne illness, although the last food consumed is not necessarily the cause of illness. Different microbes have different incubation periods. The incubation period refers to the time between ingestion and onset of symptoms.

 Incubation Periods of Common Foodborne Pathogens 

PATHOGEN INCUBATION PERIOD
Staphylococcus aureus1 to 8 hours, typically 2 to 4 hours.
Campylobacter 2 to 7 days, typically 3 to 5 days.
E. coli O157:H7 1 to 10 days, typically 2 to 5 days.
Salmonella 6 to 72 hours, typically 18-36 hours.
Shigella 12 hours to 7 days, typically 1-3 days.
Hepatitis A 15 to 50 days, typically 25-30 days.
Listeria 3 to 20 days, typically 14 days
Norovirus 24 to 72 hours, typically 36 hours.
 
How can I find out if I am sick because of something I ate or drank? 

Foodborne infections are usually diagnosed by laboratory tests that identify the organism. Bacteria such as E. coli O157:H7, Salmonella, Shigella, and Campylobacter are found by microbiologic testing of the ill person&apos;s stool. Parasites can be identified by examining stool specimens under the microscope. Laboratory testing to detect viruses requires stool specimens or serum derived from blood samples. Many foodborne infections are not detected through routine laboratory procedures and health care providers must order appropriate testing before the cause can be identified.

 Should I see a doctor if I think I have a foodborne illness? 

A person with symptoms of a foodborne illness should seek prompt medical attention if there is blood in the stools, if they are experiencing prolonged vomiting or show signs of dehydration, if diarrhea last 3 days or more or if diarrhea lasts more than 3 days. Anyone at risk for serious consequences - the very young, the very old, or those with immune impairment - should consult a health care provider if symptoms do not improve after 24 hours.

 What else should I do? 

If you think you have a foodborne illness contact your local health department. They will ask you questions about your symptoms, when they started, and what you have eaten for several days prior to symptom onset. Because some of the organisms that cause illness can be spread by ways other than food, they will ask you about other potential sources such as contact with others with similar symptoms or exposure to animals. This distinction is important so that public health authorities can if necessary, take steps to stop others from becoming ill.

If you know others who have similar symptoms, urge them to contact the health department. Oftentimes, information compiled from a group of individuals provides clues to the source of illness that can be missed when only one person reports to the health department.

If you suspect that your illness is food related, keep any left over food for possible testing. If laboratory tests show the food was contaminated, you will have powerful evidence that the food is the likely cause of your illness. The health department will advise you about any laboratory tests that should be conducted and how long food should be kept. Similarly, keep retail or restaurant receipts showing that you purchased the suspected food. Receipts often contain valuable pieces of information about a food product that the consumer does not know or cannot recall.

 Common myths of foodborne illness 

As you attempt to determine if you have a foodborne illness and what the potential source could be, avoid these common misconceptions.

 The last thing I ate is what made me sick. 

Not necessarily. Refer to the table that shows how long it takes for certain microbes to grow inside your body and cause illness. Write down what you ate, where you ate, and when you ate in as much detail as possible. Health department investigators will ask you for this information and accurate recall is critical.

 If other people ate what I ate and did not become ill, that particular meal could not be the source of my illness. 

Not necessarily. It is well documented that microbes that cause foodborne illness are not always uniformly distributed in a food item. Also, people have different immune systems. One person may consume hamburger prepared from a package of ground beef and become seriously ill with E. coli O157:H7 or Salmonella while his dining companion consumes ground beef from the same package and remains healthy.
 Posted on July 6, 2005 by Marler Lawyer Tags: Case News , Campylobacter , E. coli , Hepatitis A , Norovirus , Shigella , Staphylococcus aureus , diarrhea , food safety , foodborne illness , listeria , salmonella 
 Email This Print Comments (1) Trackbacks Share Link 
 
 What to do about the &quot;Mad Cow&quot; 
 
 According to a recent article written by the Associated Press, The Food and Drug Administration had promised in January 2004 to close loopholes in a ban on putting cattle remains in cattle feed. However, according to the article, the loopholes seem to remain:

 Ground-up cattle remains can be fed to chicken, and chicken litter is fed back to cattle. Poultry feed that spills from cages mixes with chicken waste on the ground, then is swept up for use in cattle feed. 
 Cattle blood can be fed to cattle and often comes in the form of milk replacement for calves. 
 Restaurant leftovers, called &quot;plate waste,&quot; are allowed in cattle feed. 
 Factories are not required to use separate production lines and equipment for feed that contains cattle remains and feed that does not, creating the risk that cattle remains could accidentally go into cattle feed. 
 Besides being fed to poultry, cattle protein is allowed in feed for pigs and household pets, creating the possibility it could mistakenly be fed to cattle. 
 Unfiltered tallow, or fat, is allowed in cattle feed, yet it has protein impurities that could be a source of mad cow disease. 

One would think tough enforcement is in order on the feeding of animal parts to other animals that are eventually consumed by humans. This should be a &quot;no brainer.&quot;
 
While the incubation period for most food borne pathogens is a matter of days, and human symptoms of hepatitis-A infection frequently do not show up for over a month, symptoms of &quot;Mad Cow,&quot; or the human variant known as Creutzfeldt-Jakob Disease, may not appear for decades. Because we should not have to worry about the meat we eat today, and the impact that it could have on us days or decades from now, we need stronger and more aggressive regulation and enforcement by the Government, specifically the USDA. This arm of the government must do everything it can to protect the consuming public from tainted product and to protect the US meat industry from economic suicide.

While European countries have resorted to testing massive numbers of cows to both establish the prevalence of BSE and to eradicate the disease, the has USDA limited testing to less than 20,000 animals out of a US herd of millions. We also have the ability to cheaply and scientifically test meat for a whole host of contaminates before it hits our plate. Europe requires testing for &quot;Mad Cow&quot; for nearly every cow slaughtered. Testing for all pathogens should happen at every stage of production - from &quot;farm to fork.&quot;

We have the ability to live up to the billing of the safest food supply in the world. The question is whether another &quot;Mad Cow&quot; crisis will be the catalyst that finally starts the reform necessary to stop making US consumers ill and to regain the confidence of the World in our food supply.
 Posted on June 20, 2005 by Marler Lawyer Tags: Lawyer Op-Ed , food safety , mad cow disease 
 Email This Print Comments Trackbacks
	</body>
</document>
