<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006975" url="http://www.sweetpotatoes.ws/" time="2012-07-12-23:57" support="2" score="0.003729304369418835" bingtitle="Sweet Potatoes: Menu | An award-winning restaurant on Trade Street ..." webtitle="Sweet Potatoes: Menu | An award-winning restaurant on Trade Street in downtown Winston Salem Arts District.  Sweet Potatoes">
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>A business lunch, A day out with the girls, A mid-day get-a-way.... Any excuse ... Brews, Specialty Cocktails and Martinis Click here to peruse the current Drink Menu</description>
	<body>
		Sweet Potatoes

Changing the world, one bite at a time…
 
 Menus 
 Lunch Dinner Sunday Brunch Burger Night Wine List Drinks Desserts 
 What&apos;s Cookin&apos; ? Products 
 Watch Stephanie in her new video:
 Fried Chicken, at least on Sunday! 

 Watch Now! &quot;Friends have been made and relationships forged over a basket of fried green tomatoes and okra.&quot; 
 Stephanie Tyson and Vivián Joiner,

 owners, chef and hostess welcome you to the AWARD WINNING Sweet Potatoes Restaurant in the Downtown Arts District of Winston Salem, where they serve unique, southern inspired uptown, down - home cooking.

 Learn more about Stephanie and Vivián.
 
 Stephanie Tyson
 
 Stephanie is a creative chef who has turned growing up in the South into the soul of her restaurant, Sweet Potatoes.

Born in North Carolina, Chef Tyson spent countless hours dreaming of leaving for the bright lights of anywhere else. But once she left to travel and cook around the world, she could not believe what a relief it was to come home again. Trained in culinary arts at Baltimore International College, Chef Tyson and Vivián opened their award- winning restaurant in 2003 in the downtown Arts District of Winston-Salem, where they live.
 
Vivián Joiner

 Vivián has a strong background in guest relations, spending more than twenty combined years in retail and restaurant service. Her genuine care and concern for people helped to strengthen her eye for detail allowing her to function well in many aspects of guest service. Vivián has managed restaurants from fast food, independent, casual to extremely high volume all helping add to her success in the industry. Close Window 

 L
U
N
C
H 

 A business lunch, A day out with the girls, A mid-day get-a-way....
Any excuse will do for doin&apos; Sweet Potatoes for Lunch

Served 11:00 - 3:00 Monday through Saturday

 Click here to peruse the current Lunch Menu 
 
D
I
N
N
E
R 

 On the dinner menu you will find such mouth-watering entree&apos;s such as Barbecued Duck and Drunken Pork Chops.
 
Served 5:00 to 10:00 PM Tuesday through Saturday

 Click here to peruse the current Dinner Menu 
 
B
R
U
N
C
H 
 It&apos;s a Sunday THING!

Served Sunday 10:30 AM to 3 PM

 Click here to peruse the current Sunday Brunch Menu 
 
B
U
R
G
E
R

N
I
G
H
T
 
 

Wednesday Nights from 5 - 10 PM

 Click here to peruse the current Burger menu 
 
W
I
N
E
L
I
S
T 
 Local, Domestic and Imported Wines round off your favorite meal


Served during business hours Monday through Saturday, and Sunday after Noon.

 Click here to peruse the current Wine List 
 
D
R
I
N
K
S
 
 Beverages, Imported, and Domestic Brews, Specialty Cocktails and Martinis

 Click here to peruse the current Drink Menu 
 
D
E
S
S
E
R
T
S
 
 There are some who come for the desserts alone. And for others, that&apos;s just where it starts.

 Click here to peruse the Dessert Menu HOURS:
Lunch : 11:00 - 3:00 Mon - Sat
Dinner: 5:00 - 10:00 Tue - Sat
Brunch: 10:30 - 3:00 Sunday
 NO RESERVATIONS ACCEPTED

 Phone: 336-727-4844
Fax: 336-727-4808

LOCATION:
529 North Trade Street
Winston- Salem, North Carolina
 
 
 View Larger Map 

 

 Gift Certificates and Merchandise available at restaurant or online
 Visit our online store Now! 

 Now Available 
 ©2011 Sweet Potatoes Contact Me
	</body>
</document>
