<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006539" url="http://qmato.com/restaurant/huntley-dairy-mart-huntley" time="2012-07-12-23:28" support="4" score="0.008367616415904316" bingtitle="Huntley Dairy Mart, Huntley, IL - Qmato" webtitle="Huntley Dairy Mart, Huntley, IL - Qmato">
			<query id="000100" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>This year I have found the cashier staff is ... is a rare occurence, a non-franchised fast food restaurant ... into to order and waited over 20 min. to place this order ...</description>
	<body>
		Huntley, IL 
 Address or place name (optional) 
 City, State, or ZIP Enter an address or place name 
 Find my current location No recent locations 
 
 
 Restaurant guide Qmato mobile Share Qmato 

 Sign in Join 
 
 Write a review Favorite Add to list Suggest to… 
 
Huntley Dairy Mart

 4.7 Saving… 4.7 stars from 13 votes

 Ice Cream 
 10706 N Il Route 47 
 Huntley , IL 
 Overview Large map Write a review 
 This restaurant has closed. 

 
 Write a review Directions   
 
Reviews

Sort by: date | rating 
 First reviewed by dschmi88 
 

Great service, great food!
 This is the best place anywhere around Huntley to get food and/or ice cream. Whoever said that the service was horrible must have been a bad customer for the crew to work with, because everytime I go there they are the kindest bunch and aren&apos;t rude to anyone. Also, there are signs posted saying that ice cream orders are to be placed outside, so that isn&apos;t anyone&apos;s fault but the customers in my opinion. Anyways, this place is the best. The owner has been there for a long time and when it&apos;s not busy he&apos;ll often come up front and talk to customers and get to know them. It&apos;s very rare to see that nowadays.

I would recommend Dairy Mart to anyone. hotmail • Aug 21, 2011 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

best place ever
 the best food ever and when i took my very first bite of their burgers my eyes got bigger and i loved it never going back to mcdonalds or bugerking and absolutely love the shirts Feb 25, 2011 • Report this review 
 

How old do you have to be to work there??
 How old do you have to be to work there??I am 13 1/2 (girl) i work very hard at any job i get (ex. babysitting) i will be 14 in june and would love (LOVE) to work at dairy mart. jellybean3917 • Nov 21, 2010 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

One of the best places there is
 places like the Huntley Dairy Mart don&apos;t exist today like they did back then. Impeccable service, food that makes your mouth water, and ice cream that keeps you coming back for more, the Dairy Mart truly has it all. The staff is friendly, not the mindless drones that you&apos;ll find at Mcdonald&apos;s and Burger King, they have personality and aren&apos;t afraid to strike up a conversation with you while you wait for your food. This adds to the overall atmosphere of that old school drive-up that you know and love. I go to the dairy mart whenever i&apos;m driving on 47, i love that place, and you will too.

So, i recommend the Dairy Mart to anyone driving on 47, or passing through the town of Huntley, go ahead and give it a try, you won&apos;t be dissapointed. toast186 • Feb 20, 2010 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Perfect Family Place
 My family and I have lived here for five years now, and Dairy Mart is the first place my family vote to go. They have great service, and the food rocks! Aug 10, 2009 • Report this review 
 

Amazing
 I love this place, i would recomend this resturaunt to anyone. go there as soon as possible May 17, 2009 • Report this review 
 

Replace the staff
 I have been going to the Dairy Mart for almost 3 years now a couple times a week, I work close by so we ordered pretty often. This year I have found the cashier staff is absolutely miserable, they act as if you are bothering them. I am always polite and respectful I dont order anything out of the ordinary-meaning no extra effort on their part, I just dont get it. Everyone has a bad day, but I am talking the last 6 times I was there- same crap. I always order Oreo Frenzys, I dont know how to describe it but they mix Oreo with vanilla ice cream, not cookie pieces like most places but Oreo dust. I will find someone new to bother and give my money to at lunch time. Hungry4669 • Apr 30, 2009 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

love dairy mart!
 my whole family and i love dairy mart. the food is great, the service is always awesome. but what i love most about it? you can call ahead and just pick up your food. no long waiting or anything! everything is delicious! you gotta try it. even for the ice cream. Feb 21, 2008 • Report this review 
 

Freshly cooked fast food
 This is a rare occurence, a non-franchised fast food restaurant owned by a family. The owner has been there for over 35 years. Food is cooked to order so it is hot and fresh, so do not expect it as fast as a restaurant that cooks ahead and keeps food under heat lights, but it is worth it! Fish fry is amazing with huge portions and the boston shakes are to die for! Nov 14, 2007 • Report this review 
 

Our Dairy Mart
 Just a short not regarding the Huntley Resident who is not happy with the service. I would guess you have not lived here very long. Perhaps a Del Webber? I have lived in the area for over 40 years and can say thumbs up to the Dairy Mart crew.
Folks that dont like the Mart can go to some other town as far as I&apos;m concerned. Dec 22, 2006 • Report this review 
 

Dairy Mart
 The huntley Dairy Mart is awesome, the food is great and I have never had a problem with the service. Although I did know that ice cream orders are outside, I have seen signs that said so. All in all great place to stop for a bite.

Things to try.. Mozzarella Sticks, DOughboys with cinnamon and sugar, buffolo frys and of course the famous Cheesfrys. Yum!!! Oct 26, 2006 • Report this review 
 

Blast From The Past
 This is a place you dont want to miss while passing through Huntley Illinois. The Food is outstanding and the prices are right. It&apos;s like stepping back in time, the way
things used to be, and the way things should still be. DON&apos;T MISS THIS CUTE LITTLE PLACE. I give it 10 stars for sure. kates00 • Jun 03, 2006 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
 

Awful Service
 My family and I went to Dairy Mart for Ice Cream Sunday and they were fairly busy. This place is almost always busy. They have reciently added an enclosed order taking facility. My family and I went into to order and waited over 20 min. to place this order for ice cream only to be told that we need to place those orders outside, after taking 2 ice cream orders in-front of us. Needless to say I was very upset and voiced it, at which point my family and I promptly left. It will be a VERY VERY LONG TIME before I elect to stop in there for food or Ice Cream.

Be sure to place Ice Cream ONLY orders outside, and food orders inside so you don&apos;t fall into the same problem we did. Also, note, if busy, be prepared to be very paient, the staff really doesn&apos;t care how long you wait, and show it in there actions.

Regards, Huntley IL, Resident dschmi88 • Apr 25, 2006 • Follow this reviewer • Report this review 
More information
 
 Search Google or Bing 

Know more? Update or add to this information 

Or, let us know if this restaurant has closed 
 

 
Similar cuisine
 
 Cold Stone Creamery 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Colonial Cafe&amp;Ice Cream 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Culver&apos;s 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Dairy Queen 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Dairy Queen 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Baskin-Robbins 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Marble Slab Creamery 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Baskin-Robbins 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 Baskin-Robbins 

Ice Cream • $ $$$ 
 
 
Nearby guide
 
 Meal with the kids Have a drink Creative food Best for dinner Best for breakfast Good food, good value Hidden gem Best for lunch Fast counter service 
 
 Add a restaurant About Blog Mobile Contact Sitemap Terms and Privacy policy 

Copyright©2012 RestaurantDB.
 This page was served to you in 0.283 sec.
	</body>
</document>
