<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006003" url="http://badgerherald.com/special/" time="2012-07-12-22:41" support="2" score="0.002279093901073008" bingtitle="The Badger Herald - Special Issues" webtitle="The Badger Herald - Special Issues">
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>Its bleak white interior resembles a bar fast-food restaurant ... I must confess I don&apos;t stray too far from my order ... soups, salad dressings and a unique selection of ...</description>
	<body>
		Currently: Partly Cloudy and 89.0°F
 
 Archives 
 
The Badger Herald
 
What&apos;s new in The Beat Goes On :

 Review: Jason Mraz concert 
 
Stories for Wednesday, March 25, 2009 

2008 Bar&amp;Dining Guide
 
 

 Best Takeout Food: Asian Kitchen 

Won by 44% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Burger in Town: The Old Fashioned 

When looking for a good burger, students typically turn to the traditional Frances Street establishments of the Nitty Gritty and Dotty Dumpling’s Dowry. But, if you are in the mood for a good meal that actually comes with fries and without a mystery sauce, you need to walk the extra couple of blocks toward the Old Fashioned on the Capitol… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Cafe: Capital Café 

Fitting in accordingly with the brand new Business School, The Capital Café mirrors the renovation and innovation that the building was constructed upon. Centrally located on campus on the corner of Park and Johnson, The Capital Café provides local convenience and comfort. Amid the lush round booths and ample bright lights, the Capital Café offers a variety of meal options… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Cookies?: Insomnia 

Perhaps one of the most notorious restaurant battles in the greater State Street area occurs between Chipotle and Qdoba, and one of the main arguments many people in favor of Qdoba will make is that it is open late. Timing is the quintessential issue regarding many downtown eateries, and Insomnia Cookies is no exception. Insomnia caters specifically to the ever-present… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Ethnic Eatery: Kabul 

Won by 35% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Place to Get Funky: The Majestic 

Won by 36% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Homegrown Restaurant: Mickies Dairy Bar 

Won by 49% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Haircuts: Nogginz 

Won by 55% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Place for that Special Gift: Pop Deluxe 

Won by 36% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Newcomer: Sonic Drive-In 

Won by 50% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Live Tunes: The Terrace 

Won by 65% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Pizza Joint: Topper’s Pizza 

Won with 54% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Place for Romance: Tutto Pasta 

Won with 46% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Clothing Store: Urban Outfitters 

With 73% of vote. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best Campus Bar: Wando’s 

My Tuesday nights have become pretty standard. After a long day of class and a few Herald meetings, I head home and try to get some of my mountains of reading done. Then, as the clock strikes 10, my annoying text message ringer sounds. It’s from Sports Editor Emeritus Tyler Mason.“Bacon?”After successfully convincing my roommate to tag along,… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 The Weary Traveler 

The waitresses wear cowboy boots, a back wall is lined with board games and the music is just the right volume so you can still carry a conversation with friends. The Weary Traveler on the corner of Williamson and South Few streets, is home to this and so much more. When opening the pub in January 2002, co-owner and… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Cafe Soleil 
 
If you deem the ritzy French restaurant L’Etoile overly extravagant for your student budget, do not fret. Your epicurean taste will be just as well tended to at the equally satisfying, albeit more casual, Cafe Soleil that occupies the lower street level space of the fancier and pricier L’Etoile. Located on the Capitol Square at 25 N. Pinckney St.,… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Myles Teddywedger’s Cornish Pasty 
 
What exactly is a pasty? Many students have never heard of such a thing, and those who have are unsure of how to say it—though“pasty experts”all tend to agree it is pronounced“past-ee”with a soft“a.”These pies are commonly associated with miners in Cornwall, but they are also popular in the Upper Peninsula…. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Taqueria el Pastor 

Taqueria El Pastor, or“The Shepard’s Taco Place”in Spanish, is a family-run restaurant that opened five years ago. It is located on 2010 S. Park St. and is a bit of a drive, so students may want to get a bus pass or find a ride. This authentic Mexican restaurant is complete with a bar full of Mexican… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Takara 

Living in Madison, different cultures, beliefs and traditions expose themselves in a variety of ways to people daily. More specifically, when walking down State Street, choices of restaurants can overwhelm any number of senses. This past week, I kicked up my adventurous state of mind, and for the first time, I dipped some chopsticks into sushi. Opening in 2001,… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Brocach 
 
With Madison’s colorful array of restaurants serving up a virtual United Nations in terms of international cuisine choices, it is surprising to realize one of Madison’s best eateries is not representing some exotic culinary corner of the globe but rather Western Europe, specifically Ireland. Brocach (pronounced rather like Tom Brokaw’s last name) is the restaurant themed to perfection, and… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Rising Sons Deli 
 
Every time I walk down State Street, I peer through the windows of dozens of restaurants I have yet to set foot in. Rising Sons Deli (617 State St.) was one such restaurant until recently when it became one of my favorite dinner spots. Inside the door, Rising Sons looks like a’50s-style diner, complete with high tables, swivel… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Pasqual’s 

Although Pasqual’s may go unnoticed and unappreciated by members of the campus community due to its out-of-the-way location, this Madison institution truly stands out when it comes to quality Southwestern food. Restaurants that offer Mexican or Tex-Mex specialties are all over town, but Pasqual’s finds a way to carve its own niche among the countless burrito and taco joints…. View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Parthenon 
 
The outside of Parthenon Gyros provides people with a“Greek feel”due to its blue and white awning and decorative columns. The inside of the restaurant, however, is another story. Its bleak white interior resembles a bar fast-food restaurant rather than an establishment which boasts quality Greek food. Although its walls are decorated with pictures of Greece, this did… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Mickie’s Dairy Bar 

Finally, a bar exists in Madison where college students want to go to nurse the morning-after munchies. The Madison favorite serves generous portions from the extensive menu including lunch, dinner and all-day breakfast specials. For those days when a hot dog sounds good at 9 in the morning, a better deal won’t come around than Mickie’s $1.50 wiener. The word… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Madhatter 

After more than a two-year hiatus, the Madhatter bar has made a triumphant return to downtown Madison. After closing its doors to make room for the new University Square, the new Madhatter opened last month at 328 W. Gorham St.—which happens to be right below The Badger Herald, next to Silver Mine Subs. Madhatter was intensely popular… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Lazy Jane’s Cafe 

Daytime dining is often underestimated in its ability to win over foodies—simple soup and salad combinations tend to get a little boring. Sure, there are tons of different ways to have your morning and afternoon meals, but sometimes it can just be a variation on the same old story. Lazy Jane’s, located on the 1300 block of… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 King of Falafel 
 
With an abundance of Mediterranean and Middle Eastern restaurants in the Madison area, one only needs to step just off State Street to find the perfect setting for a delicious and enjoyable dining experience at King of Falafel (453 W. Gilman St.). With both a carryout section and a dining area, King of Falafel offers traditional Arabic cuisine for… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Cafe Montmartre 

Just because it’s French doesn’t mean it’s pretentious. In fact, the class of patrons of the East Mifflin bar is probably the furthest thing from your mind when you walk into the low-lit wine bar. Although the name and varied wine selection may intimidate the average University of Wisconsin student, have no fear; there is no pretension here. Or… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Himal Chuli 
 
Himal Chuli, one of State Street’s best-kept secrets, offers a dining experience worth talking about. Discreetly located on the 300 block of State Street, the authentic Nepali restaurant transports diners from a college town to a Himalayan kitchen. Adorned in Nepali tapestries, statues and photographs, and accompanied by Indian music, this hole-in-the-wall restaurant could easily be found in the… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Hawk’s 

With jazz playing in the background and contemporary art on the exposed brick walls, Hawk’s Bar and Grill offers an atmosphere perfect for grabbing dinner with some girlfriends or catching the Brewer game with a couple buddies. Located on State Street, it is hard to miss the black awning and the chalkboard announcing the daily specials. The ambience is… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Great Dane 

A Madison favorite since its opening in 1993, The Great Dane provides a casual yet lively atmosphere to have a sit down dinner, a glass of fresh, hand-crafted beers or play a few rounds of pool in the Billiards Lounge. According to Rob LoBreglio, the Great Dane Brewery vice president, the pub’s rapid growth and success ranks it among… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Dotty Dumpling’s Dowry 
 
When a gold medal is awarded, foul play is often creeping along with it. When Dotty’s Dumpling Dowry was named the Gold Winner for Best Burger 2008 in Madison’s Best of Madison, naturally suspicions arose. Could a simple burger really achieve the greatness that a golden award signifies? I felt an investigation was in order. Upon arriving at the… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Crave 
 
Would you eat dessert before an entree? If so, then Crave Restaurant&amp;Lounge is your calling. The first page of the menu, which is desserts, quotes:“Life is short…order dessert first!”Besides having mouthwatering desserts, Crave represents its namesake well and has one craving for more food—a wide variety of soups, salads, sandwiches, burgers and… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Chocolate Shoppe 
 
Nothing beats fresh, locally made ice cream from the heart of America’s Dairyland. Chocolate Shoppe Ice Cream has an amazing inventory of unique, delectable ice cream flavors that are top-notch. Chocolate Shoppe worker Sarah Bewitz said the two most popular flavors of Chocolate Shoppe ice cream are Zanzibar Chocolate and Heaps of Love. The only way to describe Zanzibar… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Chautara 
 
Sure, Five Guys and Taco Bell satisfy the standard American hunger or that late night drunken craving, but if you are looking to expand your horizons and avoid indigestion, Chautara on State Street is a superior choice. A mixture of Indian, Tibetan and Nepali food, Chautara’s cuisine is unique and health-friendly. Don’t be intimidated or disgusted by the word… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Casa de Lara 
 
If you can sum up the willpower to hold on to your stomach past classic temptations like Potbelly’s, Chipotle and Jamba Juice as you peruse State Street, Madison’s busiest and most famed retail stretch, you will come across 341 State St., otherwise known as the home of Mexican restaurant Casa de Lara. Inside, the hostess will usher you to… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Cargo Coffee 

You do not have to travel too far off the beaten paths of the UW campus to find a locally-owned coffee shop that is unique, to say the least. A friendly staff, comfortable atmosphere, and inexpensive, tasty snacks make Cargo Coffee, located at 1309 S. Park St., the perfect place to study, chat with friends or just relax and… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Brasserie V 

If Sam Adams, Coors, Bud and Miller no longer quench your of-age thirst, mix it up and try the imported ales at Brasserie V on 1923 Monroe St. This spot is ideal for a post-Badger game bite—not that the stadium hot dogs aren’t delicious.Brasserie V’s food is as sophisticated as its name suggests. According to Brasseriev.com, a brasserie… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Biaggi’s 

Though“Biaggi’s”sounds like a shady crime mob surname, this Italian restaurant’s food is far from criminal. Chain restaurants may be the bane of small businesses’existences, as they usually lack uniqueness, but Biaggi’s takes a realistic approach to traditional Italian food.Originally started in Bloomington, Ill., Biaggi’s offers a unique look at corporate restaurant strategy. They want to make diners… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Bunky’s 

Bunky’s Café on Madison’s near East side is one of the city’s most inspired ethnic dining locations. Originating primarily as an Italian restaurant in the Italian-American Greenbush neighborhood of Madison in the 1930s, it has transformed into an eatery unlike anything else. Owners Teresa Pullara and Rachid Ouabel have crafted a menu which represents a fusion of Italian and Mediterranean… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best“quick-stop”shop 

The appeal of State Street’s Walgreens has to come from its convenient location. The pharmacy-without-a-pharmacist on the corner of Lake and State streets frequently runs out of milk, is excruciatingly crowded during passing-times and usually leaves me with the urge to apply hand-sanitizer upon exiting. Despite its downfalls, Walgreens continues to act as a shopping mecca for UW students. Between… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Cushiest student job 
 
Wanna know if a job is easy? Check the job description. If it mentions the word“kiosk,”chances are you’re on easy street. Case in point: Have you ever seen anyone occupying those Downtown Madison Inc. kiosks on the Capitol Square doing any actual work? I haven’t. The people who swipe student ID cards at the SERF also work in… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Dirtiest dive bar 

Maybe the least surprising winner of an award since Wilt Chamberlain was being named MVP by averaging a million points and a million rebounds a game (still a record), the Red Shed has pretty much locked up the Best/Dirtiest Dive Bar honors for the rest of the millennia, or at least until some brothel sets up shop in the spot… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best campus people-watching spot 

For most University of Wisconsin students, the views of sunny, sailboat-carpeted Lake Mendota from the Memorial Union Terrace can radiate enough pure joy to last a good several minutes. However, once out of the daze evoked by the unbridled glory of a glistening lake, students recognize the Terrace as the best people-watching spot on campus. The sheer volume of human… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best haircut 
 
Downtown Madison residents often complain they have to spend $20 on a haircut—not true! If you’re really on a budget, you have two options—develop sudden male pattern baldness or donate your scalp to science at Madison Area Technical College. On the other hand, while being at the mercy of the MATC beauticians-in-training means a great free… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Morning-after breakfast 
 
Those that live in the Camp Randall area of campus know best just how good Mickies Dairy Bar really is. If you live east of the stadium and have never made the trip to Mickies, you’ve been missing out. It’s worth the walk. Mickies can satisfy Badger offensive lineman-sized appetites, as the portions are everything but skimpy. A hearty Mickies… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best campus building 
 
Was there really any doubt? While late-night refugees may collapse on stray bean bags or strip the late night café of every plastic-wrapped stale cookie under the florescent light, residents of Helen C. White will eventually grow tired of the fairly non-descript study rooms and trench warfare against their studies and shuffle across the street to Memorial Union, the vibrant… View story» 

 Feedback: Add yours 

 Best“alone time”library
	</body>
</document>
