<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006825" url="http://www.azfranchises.com/Franchise_Categories/fastfoodfranchises.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:49" support="3" score="0.010830546083156575" bingtitle="Fast Food Franchises For Sale | Food Service Franchise Opportunities." webtitle="Fast Food Franchises For Sale | Food Service Franchise Opportunities.">
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="42"/>
	<description>Pet Butler - Start a low cost pet waste clean up franchise in 2012! Lawn Army - A ... TacoTime - Mexican fast food restaurant franchise opportunities..... Manny ...</description>
	<body>
		-- All Franchise Categories -- Advertising Absentee-opportunities Affordable Franchises Automotive Assisted Living Gourmet Buger Franchises Business Opportunities Business Services Car Care Franchises Car Wash Cheap Franchises Children&apos;s Franchises Cleaning Franchises Commercial Cleaning Coffee Franchises Consulting Opportunities Distribution Opps Distribution Businesses Day Spa Franchises Disaster Restoration Dog Care Franchises Easy Franchises Education Center Franchises Embroidery Franchises Existing Franchises Extra Income Fast-Casual Restaurants Fast Food Food Distribution Businesses Financial Services Franchises With Financing Franchise Consultant Franchises Under 5k Franchises Under 10k Franchises Under 15k Franchises Under 25k Franchises Under 50k Franchises Under 100k Franchises For Doctors Franchises For Nurses Frozen Yogurt Green Franchises Grey Franchises Hair or Salons Healthcare Franchises Health Food Franchises Healthy Fast Food Health Food Stores Health&amp;Fitness High Profit Margin Franchises High Growth Franchises Home Based Home Construction Services Home Health Care Home Improvement Home Services Ice Cream Insurance Agency Franchises Internet Franchises Italian Restaurant Janitorial/Maid Franchises Japanese Fast Food Kiosk Opportunities Juice Franchises Low Cost Franchises Low Cost Food Franchises Low Cost Coffee Franchises Low Overhead Low Cost Pizza Franchises Mail&amp;Shipping Franchises Massage Franchises Med Spas Medical Testing Medical Related Franchises Medical Blood Lab Men&apos;s Hair Care Mexican Food Mobile Franchises Mobile Car Care Franchises Online Business Opportunities Passive Income Franchises Pet Related Pizza Franchises Physical Therapy Franchises Proven Franchises Recession Proof Franchises Recession Proof Businesses Residential Real Estate Residual Income Franchises Restaurant Franchises Retail Restoration Franchises Security Franchises Service Franchises Senior Care Senior Caregiver Senior Fitness Sign Franchises Skin Care Smoothies&amp;Juice Bars Sports Bar Franchises Solar Power Franchises Take-Out Food Restaurants Tax Franchises Top Franchises Training Tutoring Franchises Unique Franchises Vending Opportunities Vending Machine Businesses Wine Bar Franchises Women&apos;s Only Fitness Franchises By State 
 
 Home | Franchise Directory | Advertising  | Contact 
 
 
 
 
 
Popular Franchise Categories
 
 A to Z List Of Franchises 
 
 Top Franchises For Sale 
 
 Search Franchises By States 
   -- Select By State -- Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
 Search All Categories 
 
 New Franchises For Sale 
 
 Auto Franchise Opportunities 
 
 Extra Income Opportunities 
 
 Existing Franchises 
 
 Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Green Franchises 
 
 Home Based Opportunities 
 
 Health&amp;Fitness Related 
 
 Internet Franchises 
 
 Low Cost Franchises 
 
 Low Cost Business Opportunities 
 
 Medical Franchises 
 
 Part-Time Franchises 
 
 Pizza Franchises 
 
 Recession Proof Franchises 
 
 Residual Income Franchises 
 
 Restaurant Franchises 
 
 Retail Franchises 
 
 Senior Care 
 
 Service Franchises 
 
 Top Franchises To Own 
 
 Top Franchises To Open 
 
 Top Low Cost Franchises 
 
 Business Opportunities 
 
 Biz Opportunities By States 
 
 Distribution Opportunities 
 
 Distributorships 
 
Franchise Buyer Information
 
 Special Franchise Buyer Offers 
 
 Franchises Offering Financing 
 
 Free Franchise Buyer Advice 
 
 Why Buy A Franchise Business 
 
 Franchise Financing Options 
 
 Franchise Articles 
 
 Franchising Facts&amp;Statistics 
 
 Franchise FAQS 
 
 Franchise FAQS 2 
 
 Get Our Franchise Newsletter 
 
 Franchise Links&amp;Resources 
 
Master&amp;Multi-Unit 
 Opportunities
 
 Why Buy A Master Franchise? 
 
 Master Franchises Available 
 
 Multi-Unit Franchise Opportunities 
 
 Area Development Opportunities 
 
Franchise Opportunities 
 Spotlight
 
 Doctors Express - Urgent medical care franchise opportunity for sale. Manny&amp;Olga&apos;s Pizza - Hot pizza franchise for sale! Pet Butler - Start a low cost pet waste clean up franchise in 2012! Lawn Army - A Low cost lawn mowing services franchise! 
 
 News&amp;Articles: View current franchising press releases and 
 industry articles&amp;reports. 
 
 Franchise Press Releases 
 
 Franchising Articles&amp;Reports 
 
 Franchise Press Release&amp;Article Submission Service: Request free inclusion in our franchise 
 press release or article directories. 
 
 Submit Free Press Release 
 
 Submit Free Article 
 
 Franchise Advertising Options: View 
 advertising rates and custom marketing&amp; buyer lead generation programs for 
 franchises and business opportunity companies. Advertise a 
 franchise for less than $3.25 a day! 
 
 Advertising information 
 
 Advertiser Testimonials 
 
 Lead Generation Services 
 
Franchisor Services:
 
 Franchise A Business : Franchise development services and consulting. 
 
Small Business Resources:
 
 New Franchises 
 
 Franchise Opportunities Blog 
           
 
 
 Fast Food&amp;Food Service Franchises For 
 Sale: 
 Research the opportunities below to access more 
 franchise information about these fast food and and food service franchises 
 for sale including food categories such as pizza, 
 deli, chicken, barbecue, hot dogs, health food, Mexican food, cafes, 
 bakery goods, and sub sandwich opportunities. 
 
 TacoTime - Mexican fast food restaurant franchise opportunities...... 
 Manny&amp;Olga&apos;s Pizza - Hot pizza franchise with 
 takeout/Delivery service 
  
 
 
 BullChicks - New fast food franchise with affordable menu options.. Express Cafe 2 Go - New Low cost ($15k) food vending 
 biz opportunity! 
 Other Food&amp;Restaurant Related 
 Franchise Business Category Links: Asian Food 
 Restaurants Chicken Franchises Fast Casual 
 Restaurants Health Food Low Cost Food Franchises Mexican Food Pizza Franchises Pizza Business Opportunities Vending Machine Businesses     
 
 
  Click here to view 
 information on Franchise advertising opportunities on this directory 
 
 
 
 A to Z Franchise List | Franchise Buying Advice | Franchising Resources |  Advertising | Site Map | Contact | Privacy Policy 
AZfranchises.com - A Franchise Opportunities Information Directory 
 that is part of the Redstone Advertising Network
2000-2012 Redstone Advertising, Inc. 
 
 Disclaimer: This website and directory is 
 designed to provide information only to prospective business and franchise 
 opportunity buyers. The prospective business buyer is responsible to 
 thoroughly investigate any franchise or business opportunity listed on 
 this web site, obtain all appropriate disclosure documents, and seek 
 expert consultation prior to making any investment decision. The 
 representations, views, and opinions expressed or implied in any 
 document or image included in, or linked to or from this site, do not 
 necessarily state or reflect those of azfranchises.com
	</body>
</document>
