<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006391" url="http://www.green-talk.com/2012/04/08/organic-fast-food-not-feeling-the-guilt-at-vegheads/" time="2012-07-12-23:15" support="7" score="0.021828678771524192" bingtitle="Organic Fast Food: Not Feeling the Guilt at VegHeads | Green Talk®" webtitle="Organic Fast Food: Not Feeling the Guilt at VegHeads | Green Talk®">
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>Subscribe to GT&apos;s Free Weekly Email Newsletter or RSS Feed to receive instant updates. ... I would absolutely love having a vegan fast food restaurant in Saugerties, NY.</description>
	<body>
		Home About 
 Guest Posting Guidelines Press Terms of Use 
 Advertise! Contacting Me! Blogging Tools I love! Forum Green Job Board Hire Me. How Do I Subscribe? Links Shop Green! 
   
 Build Green Gardening Green Business Green Living Home Products NJ Green Recycling Tech 
 
Organic Fast Food: Not Feeling the Guilt at VegHeads

by Anna@Green Talk on April 8, 2012 
 

 
VegHeads Restaurant
 
I have longed for an organic fast food place forever.  And no, a veggie burger from Burger King doesn’t cut it.   My fairy godmother made my dream come true when I ate at VegHeads in Ashville, NC , an organic drive-through restaurant.

Why am I so excited about their concept? Many times, I am out and about and would love to sink my teeth into an organic fast food wholesome veggie meal. Well, VegHeads didn’t disappoint. I LOVED their lentil burger with sprouts and a smear of homemade vegan mayo on a hearty whole wheat bun. In fact, I insisted that we go back for lunch twice while in Ashville visiting. 
 
Can&apos;t You See it Dripping with Awesome Lentils and Sprouts?
 
Now, we aren’t talking about a wimpy lentil burger. It was thick and juicy and for the first time in awhile, I felt full.  (Sorry about the half eaten burger picture.  I was starving.)

Lately, I have been so hungry a couple of hours after eating a vegetarian meal. (That’s another story for another day.)  Now, just because I am a creature of habit and tend to eat the same things over and over, you don’t have to.  Here are some of the  items they serve:

Philly Cheese Seitan
Korean BBQ Tempeh Wrap
Quiona Veggie Wrap
Vegan Caesar Salad
Thai Cabbage Slaw
Black Bean Brownie

Be sure to check out their menu on their Facebook page.  Some items are marked vegan as well as gluten free. What I also love is that the organic tempeh and the breads are sourced locally.

My burger came in a compostable container. I wish that I could have returned it to them so they could compost it properly.

The best part was the food was incredibly reasonable. My burger cost about $6. Before you jump up and down and say it’s the South, we found that food prices in Ashville weren’t really that much cheaper than New Jersey.

Will they be expanding to other parts of the US?   The woman who took my order said they hoped to expand.  I am hoping that every town will have a VegHeads in their city so eating gross fast food will be a thing of the past.

Join the Conversation:

 Does your town have a similar veggie fast food place? Would your town support it? How do you feel about eating veggie fast food? 



Similar Posts:

 Vegan Soy Free Meatballs Recipe for Meatless Monday Roasted Almond Butter, Sliced Pear, Agave Sandwich for Meatless Monday Turn Old Favorites Recipes into Healthy, Low Fat Vegan Dishes Chickpea Tagine From Vegetarian Times For Meatless Monday Tempeh, Fried Brown Rice, and Pineapple Recipe for Meatless Monday 



Tagged as: organic fast food , Vegheads 
 
Article by Anna Hackman 

Anna is a sustainability consultant and green living expert, and has written and edited 736 awesome articles, videos and podcasts.

Didn&apos;t you just love this Post? Call me psychic, but I knew you would. Subscribe to GT&apos;s Free Weekly Email Newsletter or RSS Feed to receive instant updates. Don&apos;t miss one drop of green goodness. Go ahead. Subscribe below.



Want to keep the conversation flowing? Chat with Anna on TWITTER or FACEBOOK. As you can tell, she loves to talk!
 
 { 5 comments…read them below or add one } 
 1 Jaesi April 9, 2012 at 2:32 pm 
OMG!! I’ve been waiting for this forever! Now it just needs to come to southern utah. All we have here is pizza, hamburgers, mexican food, pizza, and more pizza. We used to have a good place called the“Health Deli”, but the owners retired. I love to cook, but sometimes I just want to eat out with my friends without having to order a salad full of tasteless iceburg lettuce.
 Jaesi´s last [type] .. Winner of the Facebook Contest! 

 Reply 
 2 Anna@GreenTalk April 9, 2012 at 2:53 pm 
I am with you. I am so sick of eating pizza or a salad with the“hold the chicken.”Keep your fingers crossed! Anna
 Anna@GreenTalk´s last [type] .. Organic Fast Food: Not Feeling the Guilt at VegHeads 

 Reply 
 3 KC Grapes April 11, 2012 at 12:50 pm 
My husband and I argue about this all the time. He keeps saying a good food chemist will come up with healthy foods that taste good. I keep telling him,“God already DID that! It’s called plants!”The minute a whole food is tinkered with it’s being destroyed. I’ve been vegan for over 10 years now and feel younger now than back then. I’m so grateful that today most restaurants will comply with my propensity to“build a meal”out of vegetable sides. But forget that thinking at a fast food joint. I would absolutely love having a vegan fast food restaurant in Saugerties, NY.

 Reply 
 4 Anna@Green Talk April 11, 2012 at 12:53 pm 
KC, well stated! How do you stay full? I am having trouble as vegetarian and actually gained weight.

 Reply 
 5 Alexarrie April 12, 2012 at 10:13 pm 
I have never heard about organic fast food before and it really intrigues me a lot.. I am not sure a lot of people have already tried this…
 Alexarrie´s last [type] .. Gout Natural Remedies 

 Reply 
 Cancel reply 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name * 

 E-mail * 

 Website 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 

 

 
 
 { 1 trackback } 
 
 Healthy Eats and Food Rituals«gordopdx 
 
Previous post: Chimney Water Leaks Can Be Mistaken for Roof Leaks. 

Next post: Green Gal Next Door Practically Green’s Founder: Game On for Change 
 
 

 Change.org | Start an Online Petition » 
Connect with Me!
 
 

 
 
 
 
Support our Advertisers!
 
 

Find straightforward Texas electricity plans from TXU Energy
 
Browse by Category
 Select Category accessories  (1) activism  (22) advertising  (1) alternative fuels  (2) animals&amp;nature  (11) appliances  (1) automobiles  (22) awards  (1) Beauty products  (17) berries and fruit trees  (2) biobased products  (2) books&amp;magazines  (15) Build Green  (86) CD recycling  (1) cell phones  (3) cement  (3) checks  (2) children  (52) cleaning  (6) climate change  (13) closet systems  (3) clothing  (6) clothing&amp;accessories  (16) clothing and shoes  (9) coal  (2) college  (1) compost  (1) computers and cloud tech  (3) cooking  (23) countertops  (5) crafts  (3) discounts  (1) dishware  (1) doors and windows  (3) DVD recycling  (2) education  (12) electricity  (1) electricity  (1) electronic  (3) Electronics  (21) employees  (1) energy efficiency  (7) energy efficient products  (19) enviromental news  (9) environmental websites  (20) events and expos  (4) exercise equipment  (1) fabric  (13) fair trade  (4) fertilizer  (6) flooring  (3) food  (76) food  (1) Food packaging  (1) food waste  (1) food waste  (1) Forum Discussions  (3) Freight  (1) fundraising  (7) furniture  (28) Garage doors  (1) Gardening  (91) genetically modified crops  (2) gifts  (10) giveaways  (27) grains  (3) Green Bar Mitzvah  (5) Green Business  (17) green funerals  (2) Green Gal  (3) Green Living  (35) green moms carnival  (1) green roofs and facades  (8) Green Talk News  (5) green tips  (18) green weddings  (1) greeting cards  (1) hardscapes  (2) health  (53) high fructose corn sryup  (1) historic renovations  (1) holidays  (37) home decor  (36) Home Products  (72) hot water heaters  (1) Humor  (1) HVAC Systems  (4) If I only knew building stories  (3) Insulation  (13) jobs  (1) junk mail  (3) kids items  (2) LEED  (4) legal exposure  (1) lighting  (19) marketing  (2) medicine  (2) Microturbines and Fuel Cells  (1) miscellaneous  (4) modular  (1) nanotechnology  (1) natural cures&amp;treatments  (3) natural gas  (1) NJ Green  (23) oil spill  (1) packaging  (4) paint  (2) paper  (6) parties  (8) pest problems  (2) PLA and biobased products  (2) plastic  (21) rainwater harvesting  (2) raised beds  (2) Recycling  (73) renewable energy  (22) renewable energy  (1) renting/borrowing  (1) reusable bags  (2) reusable containers  (1) Reuse Tips  (17) romance  (4) Schools  (8) search engines  (2) seedlings  (10) sex  (2) showerheads  (3) ski equipment  (1) smart grid  (1) smart meters  (1) solar hot water  (3) solar pool heat  (1) Solar PV panels  (15) sport equipment  (1) sports  (1) swapping  (3) swimming caps  (1) Tech  (10) toilets  (5) tools  (1) toys  (5) travel  (8) Uncategorized  (10) vintage  (3) wastewater  (1) water  (9) water  (1) water  (2) wind  (2) yoga mats  (2) 
Green Talk Green Jobs
	</body>
</document>
