<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006088" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/the-brighton-hot-dog-shoppe-400889.html" time="2012-07-12-22:46" support="7" score="0.018444398688425487" bingtitle="The BRIGHTON Hot Dog Shoppe - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com" webtitle="The BRIGHTON Hot Dog Shoppe - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001331" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>A little about this area specific fast food restaurant. ... where you can sit down, and a waitress will come and take your order, get your drinks ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
The BRIGHTON Hot Dog Shoppe

Local Fast Food Restaurant Review
 Wendy Cheuvront , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Jun 25, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Hot Dogs Fast Food Restaurants 
 Flag Close Post a comment BRIGHTON Hot Dog Shoppe Neighborhood: Rochester
Rochester, PA 15074
United States of America Looking for new places to eat? Want to try a new great restaurant? If you ever happen to come to Pennsylvania and your travels happen to take you north of Pittsburgh, there is one great little fast food restaurant you just HAVE to stop at. The BRIGHTON Hot Dog Shoppe has very unique items, including decorative plastic cups (that may come with your drink), t-shirts, mugs and a variety of other name specific items.
The food there is the BEST. If I have to go out and get a hot dog anywhere, there is positively no better option than the BRIGHTON Hot Dog Shoppe. They currently have 9 locations, some with drive-thrus and some without. Another unique thing about this &quot;fast food&quot; restaurant, is the waitress service. I haven&apos;t found any other fast food restaurants to provide an area where you can sit down, and a waitress will come and take your order, get your drinks and bring your food out to you when it is ready. This can be really nice for those who don&apos;t like to wait in a long line to order their food, and for parents who have a hard time keeping young children under control while waiting and trying to order.

Prices are comparable to most fast food restaurants, which makes it a good option for families even on a budget. They make it up the way you want it. They have hot dogs with a variety of toppings, including the chili&amp;cheese dog they are famous for. They also serve skin on, fresh cut fries with chili&amp;cheese options. Other items, such as burgers, fish sandwiches, soda, shakes, etc. make it a delight for the whole family. A large order of fries is usually enough for me and the kids to share.

Our usual order consists of two chili, cheese and onion dogs for me. A plain hot dog for each of the kids (with a side of cheese for my daughter to &quot;dip&quot;), two hot dogs with chili and cheese for my mother. A regular size fry with chili and cheese for my mother. A large order of fries for me and the kids to share...with a side of chili and cheese for me to dip them, since the kids like theirs plain.

When your done, they even take care of the mess for you. Whether you&apos;ve taken advantage of the waitress service, or have visited a restaurant that also offers the line order and find a seat option, when you&apos;re done, you don&apos;t have to try to manage carrying a tray full of garbage with one arm,while balancing a baby with the other. They take care of the mess for you.

So stop by with the kids...bring the WHOLE family in for some great eats. There is something for everyone and will surely be enjoyed by one and all. Prices may vary by location. Small dinner type restaurant, with nice atmosphere...always welcoming.

Stop by if you&apos;re ever in the area...you won&apos;t be disappointed!
 
Published by Wendy Cheuvront 

I am a 36 year old, single mom of two. My childhood and young adult life was a very trying time for me. I am recently learning to cope with and love life in it&apos;s fullest.  View profile 
 
 Best Fast Food Restaurants in Antioch, California If you like fast food restaurants and you live in the East Bay area of Contra Costa County, you should check out all the cool fast food restaurants just off the Somersville Road... Could Living Near a Fast Food Restaurant Be as Bad as Second Hand Smoke? A study at the University of michigan showed that the risk of a stroke in a neighborhood increased by 1 percent for every fast food restaurant that was located there. Should Fast Food Restaurants Have to Wear Gloves While Preparing Your Food? should fast food restaurants have to wear gloves while preparing your food i think so New York City Councilman Has Proposed Limiting Fast Food Restaurants City Councilman and Chair of the Health Committee Joel Rivera has proposed a radical idea that would limit the number of fast food restaurants that can exist in a given area particularly low income areas that house th... Low-Calorie Foods at Your Favorite Fast Food Restaurants Here are some low-calorie foods at your favorite fast food restaurants. 
 
 Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants How to Stay Safe and Clean in Fast Food Restaurants Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants A Review of Chili Cheese Fritos How to Make Delicious Chili : An Easy, Flavorful, Colorful Recipe It is Possible to Order Healthy Items at a Fast Food Restaurant Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 
 Resources 
 
 www.hotdogshoppe.com/ 
 
2 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 james 2/29/2012 
Having grown up in New Brighton, I can honestly say ALL my friends (and even those I was not friendly with) will ALWAYS visit the Hot Dog Shop anytime we come home or anywhere near home. It is mostly the chili, but the steamed buns seem just right and the dogs make a perfect combination.
 Afzal Hussain 7/27/2007 
Thanks for sharing .
 
 Displaying Comments 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
