<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006679" url="http://www.freewebs.com/liverpoolairport/theairportterminal.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:39" support="4" score="0.00253371825244338" bingtitle="Liverpool Airport | &quot;Above us only sky&quot;" webtitle="Liverpool Airport |Above us only sky">
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>Burger King - fast food restaurant Caffè Ritazza - coffee shop ... the right of the Check In desks (in the same place ... per person and this includes car parking and a cup ...</description>
	<body>
		Liverpool Airport

&quot;Above us only sky&quot;
 Home 
 Home The Airport Terminal Aircraft Viewing Airline Information Freight&amp;Royal Mail Resident Aircraft Residents List Technical Information Current Developments Travel Connections Anniversary Events Classic Airport Liverpool Airport News Related Web Sites Guestbook 
 
 The new terminal building which was completed in 2002
 
 Airport Ownership:
 Liverpool Airport plc is wholly owned by Peel Airports plc, a subsidiary of Peel Holdings, a large property and transport company who also own the Manchester Ship Canal and the Trafford Shopping Centre in Manchester. The Chairman of Liverpool John Lennon Airport is Robert Hough and the Managing Director is Neil Pakey. Peel&apos;s airports division also owns a majority holding in Teesside Airport and a 50% stake in Sheffield City Airport. The company has recently secured planning approval to develop the former RAF Finningley airbase near Doncaster, Yorkshire into a civilian airport. Links to the websites of these three airports can be made from our Links page. 
 
 
 Address: 
Liverpool John Lennon Airport
LIVERPOOL
L24 1YD
 Telephone: 
0870 750 8484
 Facsimile: 
0151 288 4004
 
   
 The following concessionaires and facilities are present at the Airport:
 

 
 Car Hire - Reservation Desks: Alamo
 0151 486 8303 easyRentacar.com*
 0906 586 0586 Enterprise Rent A Car
 0870 350 3000 Europcar Car Hire 0151 448 1652 Hertz Car Hire 0151 486 1999/7444 Mersey Hire** 0151 486 7111 National
 0151 486 8303 Skydrive UK Ltd
 0151 448 0000 
 * Depot on exit road just beyond airport boundary. Phone bookings for cars required within one week, otherwise use internet.

** Franchisee for Europcar - shares same desk. 
 Car Hire - Prior Reservations and Key Drop Facilities: 
 Arnold Clark 0151 709 5001 Avis 0151 709 4737 Bentley&apos;s Car Hire 0151 298 1888 Budget 0151 298 1888 Global Leisure Cars 0870 241 1986 Kenning 0151 521 6150 
 
 
 Agency Offices: Co-operative Travel 0151 486 6747 Direct Holidays 0151 486 8886 europropertyguide.com 0800 085 5419 lastminute.com Reservations: 0800 371 321
Local Office: 0151 907 1185 Travelex Bureau de Change 0151 551 1500 
 
 Information Desk:
 
 This is located on the ground floor (Level 1) concourse and is open up to 20 hours per day. It operates as a comprehensive &quot;one-stop-shop&quot;, providing all airport, tourism and public transport information. 

 
 
 Shops, Food and Drink outlets:
 Level 1 Arrivals area:
O&apos;Briens Coffee Shop
Serendipity Games - amusement arcade
Whistle Stop - small grocery and convenience store
W H Smith - books, magazines, newspapers, etc.
 
 Level 1 Check-in Hall:
Travelex Bureau de Change - currency and travel insurance
plus: airline and tour company ticket desks
 
 Level 3 Landside retail area:
Aintree Village - self service buffet
Boots - chemist, toiletries, sandwiches, etc.
Burger King - fast food restaurant
Caff Ritazza - coffee shop
Caff Ritazza - refreshment kiosk
Casino Bet - amusements and betting shop
Dorothy Perkins - female clothes and accessories
Impressions of Liverpool - souvenirs, Beatles memorabilia, football kits, etc.
Serendipity Games - amusement arcade
Soft Shoe Co - shoes, handbags, etc.
Spar - grocery and convenience store
Superdrug - chemist and toiletries
Travelex Bureau de Change - currency and travel insurance (peak periods only)
Wandering Monkey - gadgets and gifts
Weatherspoons &quot;Argosy Bar&quot; - snacks and drinks
W H Smith - books, magazines, newspapers, etc.
 
 Level 2 Airside Departure Lounge:
Alpha Airport Services - Tax and Duty Free shop
Boots - chemist, toiletries, sandwiches, etc.
Alpha Sunglasses - sunglasses and accessories
Day Tripper Bar
Self Service Buffet
Serendipity Games
Starbucks Coffee Lounge.
Travelex Bureau de Change - currency and travel insurance
W H Smith - newspapers, magazines, etc.
 
 Level 1 Departure Gate area:
Terrace Bar - drinks and snacks (peak times only). 
 
 Car Parking:
 Parking in front of the terminal is limited to pick up and set down of disabled passengers. Other drivers may set down in front of the terminal but must not leave their cars unattended or wait longer than is necessary to unload . Drivers wishing to leave their cars must park in the Short Stay car park facing the terminal building. The first 20 minutes are free and the entry ticket can be inserted directly into the exit machine provided your stay is not more than 20 minutes. Stays in excess of 20 minutes must be paid for by using the ticket machines located inside the terminal building. 
 The main car park is divided into Long and Short Term and details of the tariffs in both car parks can be obtained by ringing 0151 288 4000 or by visiting the airport&apos;s website (see our Links page). 
 Long Stay: Accessed through the first entrance on the left, obtain ticket on entry and pay at machines inside the terminal before returning to your car. There are also plenty of spaces available beyond the old control tower and this section of the Long Stay car park is accessed via an underpass. Follow &quot;Additional Parking&quot; signs. Exit from all areas is alongside the original entry point. This car park is cheaper for stays in excess of 6 hours and is subject to a minimum charge of 16.20. 
 A new long stay car park is now open on the right hand side of the last section of dual carriageway leading to the airport. This is clearly visible - turn right at the roundabout as you approach the airport. Illuminated signs on the approach to the airport state which of the car parks have spaces available. 
 Short Stay: Accessed through the second entrance on the left, obtain ticket on entry and pay at machines inside the terminal before returning to your car. The first 20 minutes are free. Length of stay is not restricted but becomes more expensive than the Long Stay after 6 hours. Exit the Short Stay car park via a barrier close to, then through, the Long Stay exit point. 

 Cycle Parking:
 Bicycle storage bins are located in the short stay car park. A 50 deposit is required but there is no charge for their use. 
 
 Left Luggage:
 A left luggage facility is available on the ground floor (Level 1) to the right of the Check In desks (in the same place as passengers check in oversize baggage). Charges are payable, depending on the number of items and duration of storage. All luggage deposited will be will be subject to screening by X-ray machines before acceptance. 
 Executive Lounge:
 The Halewood International Business Lounge is available for use at a cost of 12.95 per person but is free to members of the British Airways Gold and Silver Clubs and the One World Alliance Club. These members can also bring one guest with them free of charge. Priority Pass Holders are also admitted free of charge. Free newspapers and refreshments are available. Other facilities include payphones and internet laptop connections. Open from 0530 to 2000 every day, the lounge is situated airside beyond security control. Prior booking can be made, if required, on the airport&apos;s website. For further information ring 0151 907 1002 during opening hours. 
 Cavern Suite:
 This room will accommodate up to about 80 persons sitting in rows and is available to hire for meetings, seminars and other presentations. Contact the airport&apos;s marketing department for further information. The room is located in the main terminal building. 
 Prayer Room:
 A multi-denominational Prayer Room is available opposite the lifts on level 3, landside. The airport has a full-time Chaplain - ask at the Information Desk to see of she is on duty. 
 Airport Tours:
 The airport will shortly be offering tours of the landside area of the airport to groups of up to 30 persons. There is a charge of 5 per person and this includes car parking and a cup of tea or coffee. A selection from four buffet menus can be made available, if required, at an extra cost ranging from 2.30 to 6. These tours will have either airport staff or members of the Friends of Liverpool Airport as guides. A presentation entitled &quot; Past, Present and Future&quot; will be given in the Cavern Suite - a room not normally open to the public and which contains many photographs from Liverpool&apos;s Beatles era. Further information and an Application Form can be obtained by writing to Julie Scott, Customer Services Co-ordinator, Liverpool John Lennon Airport, Liverpool L24 1YD or contact her on 0151 907 1631. 
 Special Facilities:
 Parent, Children and Baby Rooms - separate facilities are available in the terminal for parents to accompany small children to use toilets in private cubicles and for nappy changing. Private cubicles are also available for baby feeding. The Information Desk will advise on the nearest location. Shower Room - located in Departure Lounge on Level 2. Disabled facilities:
- low level telephone on Level 3 (landside) opposite toilets.
- toilets available in all areas.
- reserved car parking spaces in both short and long stay.
- wheelchairs available from near Information Desk.
- lifts available to all levels.
- ambulift vehicle to gain access to aircraft without having to use steps. Please
. make your special needs known when booking your ticket. 
 General Information:
 
 Cash Dispensers and Telephones: 
There are four cash dispensers in the terminal - two on Level 1 and two just to the right of the top of the escalator and stairs leading to the Level 3 &quot;Quadrant&quot; area. Please note that some of these machines might make a transaction charge if they are not owned by your bank or have no reciprocal arrangements with them. 
 Telephones, including a low level one for wheelchair users (on Level 3, landside, opposite toilets), are located throughout the terminal.
 
 Internet and E-mail facilities: 
Workstations are available airside in the Departure Lounge, near W H Smith and on Level 3 landside, near Wetherspoon. Stand-up, telephone type workstations are located on Level 1 near the Information Desk and in the area near the exit from the Arrivals Hall. 
 Photo Booths: 
Located on Levels 1 and 3 (landside), the machine produces four passport size colour photographs while you wait.
 
 Miscellaneous: 
Drinks and snacks vending machines are located throughout the terminal. A Royal Mail post-box and postage stamp machine is situated near the Departures entrance door on Level 1, adjacent to the Travelex Exchange Bureau. 
 Viewing Area: 
Landside (i.e. the area before the security control search and x-ray area), the apron can be seen from the Burger King restaurant and the Caff Ritazza coffee shop. Airside (i.e. passengers only), the apron can be seen from the central area of the Departure Lounge. 
 Police: 
Merseyside Police have police officers stationed at the airport. Their office is on the Level 2 walkway between the John Lennon statue and the escalator going up to Level 3, near the Cavern Suite. If you wish to speak to one of them please ask at the Information Desk to check if they are on duty if you cannot see anyone on their rounds or in their office. 
 
 
 Hotel:
 
 The four star Liverpool Marriott Hotel South is located about a mile from the present terminal and occupies the old airport terminal building. This listed building has been converted and retains its original 1930s art deco style (see photo below). Hotel guests have complimentary use of the David Lloyd Sports and Leisure Centre located adjacent to the hotel. A shuttle vehicle operates between the airport and the hotel. Overnight hotel accommodation and car parking packages are available. Telephone 0151 494 5000. 

 

 This replica of a Dragon Rapide aircraft stands in front of the main entrance of the Marriott Hotel 
 
Pleaseleaveamessageintheguestbook!
 
 Create a Free Website
	</body>
</document>
