<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006821" url="http://www.blurtit.com/q3103441.html" time="2012-07-12-23:48" support="1" score="0.0018692842696633857" bingtitle="When Will The Naruto Manga End? - Ask Questions, Get Free Answers ..." webtitle="When Will The Naruto Manga End? - Blurtit">
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>Naruto will end near 2012-2013 if and it will come next skip time like from naruto ... organization like akuatski if that happens 3-4 years more of manga and anime near 5-6 ...</description>
	<body>
		Blurt !t 
 Ask Answer Sign in Sign up 
 GO 
When Will The Naruto Manga End?
 
 Tweet Bookmark 
 

 
 Anonymous 60% helpful 
 Naruto will end near 2012-2013 if and it will come next skip time like from naruto to naruto shippuden so dont worry in that skip time new organization of bad ppl could show up example look at dragon ballz it didnt have so many enemyes and it had 280 or so episodes + kai... So near 400 huh ...i think kabuto will become like orochimaru and he will have new organization like akuatski if that happens 3-4 years more of manga and anime near 5-6 years or more 
 Helpful   Not helpful 
 

 
Related reading
 Who Does Naruto End Up With In The Manga? Actually it hasn&apos;t really stated who Naruto will end up with, even in the manga. But there... When Will Naruto Shippuden Manga End? Amazing cause they are getting close! A war has been sparked by Madara Uch-iha. The people... When Will The Naruto Manga End? Naruto will end near 2012-2013 if and it will come next skip time like from naruto to naruto... When Did Naruto Come Out? Ahhh...look naruto was first debuted in 2002 on tokyo tv,was made in 1997 in weekly shonen... What Does The Name Naruto Mean? Naruto is usually used as a first name. This is a boy&apos;s name and has a Japanese origin. In... 
Add Your Answer - Add Community Answer 
 When Will The Naruto Manga End? Submit Answer 
 

 

 Tweet 

 Bookmark 
 
Related Ads
 
 Manga torrents Naruto manga returns Naruto msn Naruto online manga Naruto ringtone Naruto ringtones 
 
You might also like

 
 What is the best diet? 
 
 What Do Dreams Mean? 
 
 What happens when we run out of crude oil? 
 
 When Will The World End? 
 
 Why does the Universe exist? 
 

Topics

 television entertainment manga naruto 

 Further Reading 

 Where Can I Watch The First Season Of Chuck Online For Free? Where Can I Watch Full Length Episodes For Free Of NCIS? Is Prank Patrol Real Or Is It Just A TV Show? Also, Is It Just In The States? What Are The Real Names Of Slipknot Members? Where Can I See Full-length Episodes Online For &quot;The Big Bang&quot; Theory? My Dog Has Milk And Her Chest Is Big And Her Vulva Has Been Large For A Few Days Now, Is She Pregnant? 
 
 ©Blurtit ltd. Advertise with us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Content Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
