<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006114" url="http://ourfaves.com/place/1037119/lick-s-homeburgers-ice-cream-burlington" time="2012-07-12-22:47" support="3" score="0.006125310426518579" bingtitle="Lick&apos;s Homeburgers &amp; Ice Cream - Burlington - Burlington - Burgers ..." webtitle="Lick&apos;s Homeburgers&amp;Ice Cream - Burlington - Burlington - Burgers Restaurants | OurFaves.com">
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000277" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="148"/>
	<description>... tasted thus far... for a what I would consider fast food restaurant. ... The ice cream is creamy and if you are having a ... They&apos;re huge, made fresh to order, generous with ...</description>
	<body>
		Toronto 
 Choose a City Toronto Montréal Vancouver Ontario See All 
 

 Become our fan on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Sign-in with Facebook Login Register 
 
 Our Faves 

 Find faves by: Category 
 Category Active Life Arts&amp;Entertainment Food&amp;Grocery Health&amp;Medical Local Highlights Local Services Nightlife Personal Care Restaurants Shopping Travel&amp;Attractions 
 Neighbourhood 
 Neighbourhood Bloor Yorkville Financial District Greektown Kensington Market Leslieville Little Italy The Annex The Beaches Queen Street West West Queen West See All 
 Groups 
 Groups Foodies Young&amp;Single Trendsetters Fit&amp;Healthy Eco-Friendly Family Deal Seekers 
 
 Create a Fave Search for Near 
 Home Restaurants Burgers Lick&apos;s Homeburgers&amp;Ice Cream 

 Bookmark or Share 
 
Lick&apos;s Homeburgers&amp;Ice Cream

Rate it:
 
 current rating 1 2 3 4 5 
 
25 reviews

 3315 Fairview Burlington, ON, L7N3N9 Website (905) 631-6215 
 add to list Share   Edit business information 
Tell us your favourite things about this place
 I&apos;ll do this later 
Click on an item below to add it or use the text field to add your own favourite things.

 Burger Joints 2008 ( 5 ) Hamburger ( 4 ) nature burger ( 4 ) Veggie burger ( 3 ) fast food burger ( 2 ) Burger ( 2 ) vegetarian lunch special ( 1 ) lunch time restaurant ( 1 ) Grilled Chicken ( 1 ) 
 add tag save&amp;continue 
Who would enjoy this place?
 I&apos;ll do this later 
 Foodies Young&amp;Single Trendsetters Fit&amp;Healthy Eco-Friendly Family Deal Seekers 
 save&amp;continue 
 user reviews (25) photos 
 
posted Feb 11 2009
 
 MarkMoyes 



DealSeekers from Yonge and St. Clair
 
Best burger in Toronto

Rated this place:
 
There&apos;s nothing quite so delicious (and uncomfortably filling) as a Lick&apos;s burger and a side of poutine. The secret to the burger is in their soft buns, shredded cheese and special mayo sauce -- not to mention that for reasons that no one truly understands, their veggie burger tastes almost exactly like their beef burger. The poutine is small for the price, and comes with shredded cheddar not curds, but is still surprisingly tasty. Sweet, delicious heart attack.
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Aug 26 2008
 
 JBright 




 
Nature burger

Rated this place:
 
Nature Burgers are the best vegetarian burgers I have tasted thus far... for a what I would consider fast food restaurant. Though Fresh - by Juice For Life has arguably the best veggie burgers in Toronto... but I don&apos;t consider that fast food per se. Maybe if they open a few more and make me feel less comfortable there!!!



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: nature burger 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Aug 22 2008
 
 kweenshaker 




 
Veggie burger

Rated this place:
 
Fantastic vegan burger that doesn&apos;t taste bland or have a mushy texture like so many other veggie burgers. Lick&apos;s is also good and grills the nature burgers on a seperate grill. So so good to have as a treat with ketchup, mustard, pickles and guk! They&apos;re pretty big too, so I rarely have room for fries.



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: Veggie burger 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Aug 4 2008
 
 larazhivago 




 
Burger joints 2008

Rated this place:
 
For a vegetarian the Nature Burger is a Godsend. The portion sizes are generous and definitley shareable with freinds or a date. The ice cream is creamy and if you are having a bad day, well, they sing to you.



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: Burger Joints 2008 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Jul 23 2008
 
 forlk7370 




 
Nature burger

Rated this place:
 
Im not sure how they do it, but licks sure has made it to my top 3 with their nature burger. it&apos;s as big as your face and it tastes amazing compared to some i have tried ... which are about as appetizing as eating the cute little box they come in! now available at grocers such as: a&amp;p;, dominion, food basics and ultra.



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: nature burger 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Jul 2 2008
 
 jay416 




 
Burger joints 2008

Rated this place:
 
It has vegetarian burgers that taste great



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: Burger Joints 2008 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Jun 19 2008
 
 ndonne 




 
Burger joints 2008

Rated this place:
 
The veggie burger is just as good (if not better) than the meat one!



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: Burger Joints 2008 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Jun 16 2008
 
 mcmc 




 
Burger joints 2008

Rated this place:
 
Delicious ice-cream



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: Burger Joints 2008 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Jun 16 2008
 
 patio 




 
Burger joints 2008

Rated this place:
 
Great burger every single time



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: Burger Joints 2008 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
posted Dec 29 2007
 
 Goldenhawk99 




 
Fast food burger

Rated this place:
 
They&apos;re huge, made fresh to order, generous with toppings. Get one with a side of onion rings, and it&apos;s all good.



 Favourite thing(s) at this place: fast food burger 
 
Was this helpful? Yes ( 0 found this review helpful) | Link 

 
 write a review 
 Review Post this 

 
Before we confirm your review, we need you to rate this place:

Rate it:
 
 current rating 1 2 3 4 5 
 
Would you like to upload an image?
 Upload an image Maybe later... 
1-10 of 25 reviews

 1 2 3 Next 
 
 Uploaded by: MarkMoyes 
 
 Uploaded by: forlk7370 
 
 Uploaded by: JBright 
 
 Uploaded by: bswitzer 
 
 Uploaded by: bbowden 
 

 
this place has multiple locations 
 
See more places in:
 Burlington 
things people love about this place:
 

 Burger Joints 2008 (5) Hamburger (4) nature burger (4) Veggie burger (3) fast food burger (2) Burger (2) vegetarian lunch special (1) lunch time restaurant (1) Grilled Chicken (1)
 add your own 

 
categories

 Active Life Arts&amp;Entertainment Food&amp;Grocery Health&amp;Medical Local Highlights Local Services Nightlife Personal Care Restaurants Shopping Travel&amp;Attractions 
 
neighborhoods

 Bloor Yorkville Financial District Greektown Kensington Market Leslieville Little Italy The Annex The Beaches Queen Street West West Queen West See All... 
 
community activity

 waiyinwhitney... 
just reviewed Fred&apos;s Not Here Restaurant waiyinwhitney... 
just reviewed Windsor Arms Hotel yaz28... 
just reviewed The Well Adjusted Chiropractic Centre Josefine... 
just reviewed Taz Hair Co OliviaBarks... 
just reviewed Sparks on King 
 
more

 Ourfaves Blog About Us Feedback Ourfaves Twitter 
 
more

 Recent Reviews Recent Lists Recent Fave Tags Popular Searches 
 
more

 Cities Directory Terms of Service FAQ 
 
what is ourfaves?

OurFaves is an interactive city guide that lets you discover and share the best, as chosen by you and local experts. Search, review, and learn more about places in your community.
 Join Today! Learn more 
OurFaves.com

 OurFaves About Us Internships Cities Directory Terms and Conditions FAQ Work For Us Corporate Sales 

 Our Community Ourfaves Blog Feedback Ourfaves Twitter Recent Reviews Recent Lists Recent Fave Tags Popular Searches 

 Regional Sites DurhamRegion.com InsideHalton.com InsideToronto.com MyKawartha.com Mississauga.com NiagaraThisWeek.com Simcoe.com YorkRegion.com 

 Affiliates InsuranceHotline.com Save.ca Workopolis.com Toronto.com Leasebusters.com 

 Partners/Daily Newspapers The Guelph Mercury The Hamilton Spectator The Toronto Star The Waterloo Region Record DailyWebTV.com MyHolidayHomeRental.com OurFaves.com Goldbook.ca 
 ©Copyright Metroland 2010 |  Metroland Media Group Ltd.  |  Corporate Privacy Policy close Please log in or create a new account to continue. We love hearing your take on the best! login join
	</body>
</document>
