<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0006548" url="http://www.adashofpanache.com/Lunch%20Cafe.htm" time="2012-07-12-23:28" support="4" score="0.012160773544397926" bingtitle="Lunch Cafe, Restaurant, Vernon Street, Downtown Roseville, Where ..." webtitle="Lunch Cafe, Restaurant, Vernon Street, Downtown Roseville, Where to eat in Roseville">
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>We&apos;re not a fast-food restaurant but if you call in ahead of ... name and phone number (so we can find your order ... To top them, our selection of dressings are very ...</description>
	<body>
		Make reservations for our Annual Easter High Tea!........... 
 
 

 
 

 
 

 Time to VOTE again!
Please click here! 
 
 
 Home &gt; Lunch Cafe 

 Although Vernon Street offers a variety of restaurants, A Dash of Panache offers a very unique, upscale lunch cafe (and early dinner destination) featuring gourmet soups, salads, and 
sandwiches at a very reasonable price . You do NOT need reservations for this 
Family-oreitned Cafe but there are times we can be quite busy so if you plan to come with a 
larger group, it will be a good idea to give us advanced notice so we can be 
prepared. 

 We&apos;re now offering FREE Wireless Internet access to our 
guests (yes, we&apos;re now an Internet Cafe if you&apos;d like). 

 In a hurry? We&apos;re not a fast-food restaurant but if you call in ahead of time , we&apos;ll have it ready for you to Take Out or eat in without a wait . Simply download our menu below and call in 
your order. We&apos;ll need 
your first and last name and phone number (so we can find your order quickly 
when you arrive and so we can call you if we need to contact you with questions 
about your order). 

 Looking 
for information on our Afternoon Tea Sittings (in our French-deco Tea Parlor)? Click here ! 

 
 Download our menu here : 

 Our cafe offers you a variety of options including: 

 Gourmet Salads . Not shredded iceberg! All of our 
 salads contain quality produce. Options include a Seasonal Salad (check our Specials board), Stuffed 
 Apple Chicken Salad (Voted Best Salad in Style Magazine&apos;s Reader&apos;s Choice Awards !), Caesar with homemade croutons, and several other 
 selections. To top them, our selection of dressings are 
 very high-quality and mouth-watering. Unique Sandwiches . If you haven&apos;t heard about our Tuscan Grilled Chicken Sandwich , you haven&apos;t been on Vernon Street! This sandwich is something to talk 
 about. Be careful, you may end up with an addiction (we are thinking of 
 starting a Tuscan Chicken Rehab Center). For the vegetarians out there, we 
 have an equally addictive Veggie Tuscan that is catching on like wildfire! 
 Our Chicken Salad Sandwich uses a recipe that includes slivered almonds 
 and sliced grapes! Our Gourmet Veggie Sandwich also has 
 a band of devoted followers, may of which like to get it on a wrap. Other 
 popular sandwiches include Roasted Turkey , Egg Salad with Dill , Albacore Tuna Salad , Gourmet Cheese , etc. Our specials change 
 frequently but you&apos;ll find some pretty great deals at times. Quality Soups . We pride ourselves in the quality and 
 taste of our soups. We change the selection often so be sure to ask what&apos;s 
 available. A few of our great signature soups include Harvest Grain with 
 Portobello Mushroom , Chicken Tortilla Soup , Creamy Asparagus , and Chilled Strawberry Cream Soup . Note: 
 In very warm weather, we may not have hot soup available so be sure to ask. What&apos;s a Haystack ??? Want a new taste sensation? You 
 are gonna love this! Our Ice Cream and Refreshment Parlor (part of our cafe) 
 will top off your meal with a treat! From our huge selection of beverages to 
 awesome ice cream dishes to baked goods. It&apos;s a fact that your memory is best 
 linked to taste and smell than any other sense. Your visit with us will 
 definitely be memorable! We offer a large variety of coffee 
 and espresso products including lattes, cappuccinos, espresso, blended 
 coffee smoothies, iced and hot coffee beverages, etc. Our Frothy Coffee is 
 awesome! 

 The atmosphere is family-oriented and stylish . The quality of the handmade 
ice cream and the reasonable prices will make this spot a favorite for your 
friends, family, sports team , office group , or social club . 

 If you frequent one 
or both of Vernon Street&apos;s live theatres (just a few doors away on the same side 
of the street), be sure to swing by A Dash of Panache before or after the show! 
(see our Hours of Operation before planning 
a visit). 

 
 Time-Saving Solutions for 
 downtown employees, large groups, and folks in a hurry: 
 
 Call ahead with your order and save yourself some time! If you print our Menu and keep it at your desk, 
 you can save even more time! Our phone number is 788-4386. 
 Large Group ? To save time 
 and help your event run smooth, please follow these steps: 
 
 Please call us well ahead of time 
 to make reservations and to be sure we can accommodate your group! 
 Sometimes we have to add additional staff to meet your needs and sometimes 
 we might not have room for you if we don&apos;t know you&apos;re coming! 
 Download our Quick Order 
 Menu Form and give a copy of it to everyone in 
 your group who is planning to attend. Then collect them all back 
 (double check to ensure they selected things like bread types and 
 dressings). Note : this form is designed for quick ordering and does 
 not have helpful descriptions of menu items (you might want to download a 
 regular menu and send 
 it along as well so guests can read about what they are ordering). 
 Bring us the above forms at 
 least an hour before your group arrives so we can begin preparation of 
 your meals. 
 If your group is going to be 
 early or late , please call us so we can adjust as much as possible. 
 
 Got the Parking Space Blues ? We&apos;ve got a great solution for 
 you! We can often deliver your order in person if it&apos;s over $20
(delivery depends on staffing and your proximity to the 200 block of Vernon 
 Street) 
 

 Our Vernon Street location in Downtown Roseville, California (CA) location is conveniently located 
in Placer County near the I-80 
Corridor (Sacramento, Roseville, Rocklin, Antelope, North Highlands, Citrus 
Heights, Orangevale, Loomis, Penryn, Auburn) and only a short drive for other neighboring 
California cities (Folsom, Rancho Cordova, Carmichael, Orangevale, Lincoln, El Dorado 
Hills). Need Driving Directions ?
  
 

 
 
 [  Home  ] [ Fine Print ] 

 
 Hours of 
 Operation                          Signup for our Private Mailing List (event 
 notification, coupons, etc.) 

 A Dash of Panache is located at 217 Vernon Street, Roseville, CA 95678 . Phone: (916) 788-4FUN (788-4386) 
Copyright 2003-2012 A Dash of Panache , All rights Reserved. Privacy Policy (Fine Print) 
 (This website has been designed and developed by Advanced Development Concepts )
	</body>
</document>
